<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1407586" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-08-02</date>
    <companies>
      <company>186</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Director-Investor Relations">Lynne Maxeiner</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">David N. Farr</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (United States)">Julian C. Mitchell</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co., Inc.">Steven E. Winoker</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Oppenheimer Securities">Christopher Glynn</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Longbow Research LLC">Eli S. Lustgarten</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Senior Vice President">Frank J. Dellaquila</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Terry Darling</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Securities International, Inc.">Shannon O'Callaghan</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Wells Fargo Advisors LLC">Richard M. Kwas</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Deane M. Dray</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Vertical Research Partners LLC">Nicole M. Parent</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Neuberger Berman LLC">Martin A. Sankey</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you for standing by. Welcome to the Emerson third quarter fiscal 2011 results conference call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> This conference is being recorded today, Tuesday, August 2, 2011.</p>
          <p>Emerson's commentary and responses to your questions may contain forward-looking statements, including the company's outlook for the remainder of the year. Information on factors that could cause actual results to vary materially from those discussed today is available at Emerson's recent annual report on Form 10-K as filed with the SEC.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to our host, Ms. Lynne Maxeiner, Director of Investor Relations. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Brittany. I am joined today by David Farr, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of Emerson; and Frank Dellaquila, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer.</p>
          <p>Today's call will summarize Emerson's third quarter 2011 results. A conference call slide presentation will accompany my comments and is available in the Investor Relations section of Emerson's corporate website at emerson.com. A replay of this conference call and slide presentation will be available on the website after the call for the next three months.</p>
          <p>I will start with the highlights of the quarter as shown on page two of the conference call slide presentation. Third quarter sales were up 16% to $6.3 billion, with increases in all segments. Underlying sales growth was 10%, led by strong emerging market growth. Operating profit margin declined 30 basis points to 18.1%, and was negatively impacted by acquisitions made in the last 12 months and growth investments versus minimal levels in the prior-year quarter.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share was $0.90, up 17% compared to $0.77 in the prior-year quarter.</p>
          <p>Strong operating cash flow of $903 million and free cash flow was $708 million. Our free cash flow to net earnings converged in with 104%.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet continues to strengthen. Operating cash flow to total debt is strong at 62%, and we've increased the pace of share repurchase in Q3. Emerson is well positioned as the global economic becomes more uncertain, and we will deliver record operating margin and earnings in fiscal 2011.</p>
          <p>Slide three, the P&amp;L; again, sales increased 16% with underlining sales up 10%. Currency added four points and acquisitions added two points. Operating profit up 14% to $1.135 billion or 18.1% of sales; the increase driven by volume leverage and cost reduction benefits, partially offset by higher material costs, acquisitions, and growth investments. Earnings from continuing ops up 18% to $683 million; we repurchased 6 million shares for $329 million in the quarter, which gets you to an EPS of $0.90.</p>
          <p>Next slide, underlying growth by geography; in the third quarter, the U.S. was up 6%. And total international increased 13%, with Europe up 9%, Asia up 12%, Latin America up 17%, and Middle East-Africa up 26%. Again, total underlying sales up 10%; currency adding four points, acquisitions adding two points gets you to the consolidated sales up 16%.</p>
          <p>Slide five, some income statement detail; gross profit up $2.498 billion or 39.7% of sales; higher material costs were partially offset by cost reductions, price increases, and volume leverage. SG&amp;A of 21.6% gets you to operating profit of $1.135 billion, which includes the impact of acquisitions and growth investments. Other deductions net of $87 million includes increased amortization of $20 million. Interest expense of $56 million gets you to pre-tax earnings of $992 million or 15.8% of sales. Taxes of $294 million for a tax rate of 29.6%; we still expect full-year fiscal 2011 tax rate of approximately 31%.</p>
          <p>Slide Six, cash flow and balance sheet; operating cash flow of $903 million, up 29%, driven by higher earnings. Capital spending of $195 million gets you free cash flow of $708 million, an increase of 22%. Trade working capital balances are noted at the bottom of the slide, which does include some inventory due to Japanese supply concerns. We continue to strengthen the balance sheet as the recovery continues.</p>
          <p>Next slide, business segment P&amp;L; business segment EBIT of $1.097 billion or 16.9% of sales, up 13%. Margin declined 40 basis points. We saw benefits from volume leverage, price increases, and cost reductions, which were more than offset by material and wage inflation, increased amortization from acquisitions, and growth investments. Difference in accounting methods of $60 million, corporate and other of $109 million; we had higher stock compensation expense of $13 million. Interest expense of $56 million gets you to the pre-tax earnings of $992 million.</p>
          <p>We'll review the business segments next, starting with Process Management. Sales in the quarter of $1.789 billion, up 18%; underlying sales were up 13% and currency added five points. By region, the U.S. was up 16%, Asia up 17%, Europe down 1%, and Latin American up 6%. We continue to see broad strength across the segment; EBIT of $366 million or 20.4% of sales, up 18% with cost reduction benefits and volume leverage offset by cost inflation, business development investments, and unfavorable foreign currency impact of $7 million. Backlog for process was $3.4 billion, up 27% from the prior-year quarter.</p>
          <p>Slide nine, Industrial Automation; sales in the quarter of $1.391 billion, up 24%; underlying sales were up 18%. Currency added five points and acquisitions added a point. By region, the U.S. was up 11%. Europe was up 21%, and Asia was up 20%. Continued broad strength across the portfolio and very strong growth continued in the power generating alternators business; EBIT dollars of $230 million or 16.6% of sales, an increase of 43%, driven by volume leverage and cost reduction benefits. Material inflation was offset by price increases. Revenue growth will continue to moderate from these very high levels as comparisons get more difficult.</p>
          <p>Slide 10, Network Power; sales in the quarter of $1.683 billion, up 19%; underlying sales were up 7%. Acquisitions added nine points, and currency added three points. By region, the U.S. was up 5%. Asia was up 7%, and Europe was up 4%. Network Power Asia resumed double-digit growth. And the global Network Power systems business was strong, including strong growth in our global UPS and precision cooling businesses, which were up over 15%.</p>
          <p>EBIT of $176 million or 10.4% of sales, a decrease of 3%; we had increased chloride amortization of $16 million; also unfavorable price, China labor related inflation, embedded computing volume decrease ;and technology investment spending; which was partially offset by volume leverage. Our EBIT margin did improve sequentially 110 basis points from second quarter. EBIT margins are expected to continue to strengthen sequentially from third quarter to fourth quarter as our aggressive actions start taking hold.</p>
          <p>Slide 11, Climate Technologies; sales in the quarter of $1.171 billion, an increase of 6%; underlying sales were up 3%. Currency added two points, and acquisitions added one point. By region, the U.S. was down 3%. Europe was up 7%, and Asia was up 9%. We saw a weaker North American resi market due to a cooler and wet May and June and inventory in the channel. Our China business was up 10%, but is expected to weaken in Q4 due to government fiscal tightening.</p>
          <p>EBIT of $229 million or 19.6% of sales, an increase of 3%, driven by benefits from cost reduction actions; we saw significant material inflation, which was substantially offset by price. The U.S. market is expected to remain weak for the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>Slide 12, Tools and Storage; sales in the quarter up $472 million, an increase of 4%; underlying sales were up 3% and currency added a point. By region, the U.S. was up 2%. Europe was up 8%, and Asia was up 4%. We saw growth in the non-res construction related businesses and a decrease in the consumer and residential related businesses.</p>
          <p>EBIT of $96 million or 20.2% of sales, up 1%, driven by benefits from cost containment actions; consumer confidence remains low and recovery in consumer and residential end markets continues to be pushed out.</p>
          <p>Next slide, the summary and outlook; we had a strong third quarter performance, with underlying sales growth of 10%, operating profit margin of 18.1%, and strong cash flow performance. We are entering a period of more macroeconomic uncertainty in the second half of calendar year 2011. However, Emerson is well positioned for the uncertain climate with a strong global footprint, a good mix of businesses and end markets, and financial strength.</p>
          <p>For fiscal 2011, guidance remains unchanged as follows: earnings per share of $3.20 to $3.30; underlying sales up 10% to 13%, and we are tracking to the lower end of that range; net sales up 15% to 18%; operating profit margin 17.4% to 17.6%; operating cash flow in the range of $3.3 billion to $3.5 billion; and free cash flow in the range of $2.7 billion to $2.9 billion.</p>
          <p>So with that, I'll turn it over to David Farr.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Lynne. I want to welcome everybody for joining us today on our third quarter conference call and our results.</p>
          <p>The quarter came in what I would say strong, not as good as we had expected just 60 days ago; however, still very strong results, with sales up 16%, earnings up 18%, strong cash flow, and high levels of operating margins, in excess of 18%. And after nine months, our sales at $17.8 billion are up over 16%; our operating profit of $3 billion up over 20%; and a record OP level of 16.8% Our net income at $1.8 billion, plus 21%; and a 9.9% margin; and EPS at $2.26 at 22% growth for the first nine months. Those are outstanding results and based on investments we've been making the last couple of years and based on performance of a strong operating team.</p>
          <p>I want to thank the global team for getting the job done. These are extremely uncertain and challenging times with the Japanese earthquake and tsunami, global material inflation, dysfunctional governments in the U.S. and Europeans not able to deal with the tough issues of debt and excess spending. I want to thank the business leaders and the operating leaders for getting the job done in very difficult and challenging times.</p>
          <p>Now why did we call out last week in our orders that things are getting weaker? Because they are, they are weaker. We have always been very open in our communication to our shareholders and to our investors. And when we see fundamental change, we call it out. There's no reason to hide it. It's the facts and we did it. Our underlying orders grew only 6.5% for the last three months. That is outside the range that I have been talking about for several months, in the 7% to 10% range. And yes, it's against tough comps, but I saw fundamental weakness happening over the last 60 days. And then a couple days later, they announced GDP. GDP in the U.S. grew in the first half less than 1%. Let's get that said, less than 1%. You look at all the facts that have been coming out the last couple of weeks and the economics have been weakening. It's not new news. We have to deal with it. We have to position the company to deal with those things.</p>
          <p>Then we have a government situation, their inability to deal with the real gut issues of excess spending and debt. All we hear out of government is we're going to raise taxes. We don't like corporate planes. We're going to sue Boeing, one of the most strategic companies we have in this country, for building a new plant in South Carolina. We have no desire to really go after corporate tax reform, which would fundamentally change this country and encourage people to invest and reinvest and create jobs in this country, but rather demagogue and go after people that actually create those jobs, be it corporations and people that are successful.</p>
          <p>We have a difficult issue right now to deal with in this country, and the same is going on in Europe. They are in no better condition. So as I look at what's coming at us in the second half this year, I do not see the catalysts that would say that the economy will be fundamentally different in the second half than we saw in the first half. Maybe the gross GDP will grow a little bit more in the second half, but fundamentally there's nothing going on in the U.S. right now that would encourage corporations to ignore the excessive regulations coming at us, not to mention the new Dodd-Frank bill relative to whistleblowers or producing or mentioning what we have to do with minerals. We have to publish now what minerals we use. You look at the new healthcare bill, you look at last week we decided in Washington to raise the CAFE standards for the second time within three years on the day that we announced less than 1% first half GDP growth in the U.S. economy. I would say Washington is arranging the chairs on the Titanic, the way I look at it.</p>
          <p>So we're dealing with realism here in this company. We're looking at slower growth. We don't know exactly what that growth is. We will manage accordingly. Our orders in industrial work will stay up. I can't tell you right now what the second half will be. I can't tell you what 2012 is going to be. So don't bother to ask me because I will not tell you. If you ask me what 2012 is, the first thing I'm going to ask you is what is your forecast for the second half of GDP and what is your forecast for GDP in the first half of 2012? Let me know and I'll tell you what my forecast will be.</p>
          <p>As a company, we have strong operating cash flow. Our balance sheet is in great shape. We've made strategic acquisitions. We are integrating those acquisitions. We don't have a lot of acquisitions underway right now. I do not see a lot of acquisitions underway in the near term. We're using our cash to pay back a dividend. We just announced a record 55 years of increasing dividends. We've increased our share repurchase. We're now on track to do over $900 million of share repurchase, returning cash back to our shareholders. And we will continue to generate the earnings and the best growth we can in a very difficult market on a global basis and reinvest for future growth and creating shareholder value.</p>
          <p>The company will perform in a very difficult environment as we have. We'll set record levels of cash. We'll set record levels of earnings &#x2013; of margins, and we will continue to drive forward. That's where we are right now. We are dealing with very uncertain times, and we will manage those accordingly.</p>
          <p>I feel good about where the company sits right now. We are performing at very high levels. All companies have issues we have to deal with, but we're dealing with them. Our price/cost is close to being in equilibrium, and we will be there in the fourth quarter. Our margins right now are running at very high levels, and we will set a record this year. And our earnings growth is good, as is our cash.</p>
          <p>So I want to commend the operating executives and the corporate executives for what they're doing in this very difficult time period. And we will play with the hand we're dealt with and we'll play the best hand we can, and that's where we sit.</p>
          <p>So now we can open it up for questions, but I will not talk about 2012 because I have no visibility into 2012 at this point in time given what's going on around this world, both in Japan, in the U.S., and in Western Europe. And that's where I sit. Thank you very much. The floor is yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. We will now begin a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Julian Mitchell with Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Julian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, how are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. I guess the first question was on your own business as you see the order growth decelerate, I noticed that your SG&amp;A growth accelerated year on year from March to June, even though your revenue growth went from 18% year on year down to 16%. So can you talk a little bit about how you guys are managing your own hiring and your own plans on investments? Obviously, your investments have been going up. But if you're seeing orders decelerate, why are you pushing up investments so much? And at what point do you start to scale back those investments because the order flow is deteriorating?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very good reasoning. We had an OCE business leader meeting about 10 days ago, a private meeting on this very issue. We will modulate our spending right now. We already started it. I think that our underlying growth rate will modulate downward a little bit. And I would have thought for the whole, for the second half we would have been double digit. We're basically around 10% right now. We could be anywhere between 9% and 12% in the fourth quarter. So right now we're already modulating and putting things on hold relative to our spending as I look at the weakening global economies, and we will keep it that way for the time being.</p>
          <p>On the industrial side, the process side, we're not doing that yet because the growth rate is still there, and we still feel our backlogs are at record levels. Just more I would say what I saw on the near-term, mid-term cycle type businesses, I'm starting to modulate spending back. Here at corporate, I'm actually modulating back, as Frank Dellaquila knows. I've asked Sly to take a relook at the last couple months of the budget. And as we move into 2012, I want to have a more conservative budget plan. So Julian, to your point, we are starting to modulate that back. You just look at the facts around the world and the growth rates are slowing, and you need to get ready for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, thanks, and then just a follow-up just on the current order intake rates. Is it the case that the standalone month July will be materially a lot worse than what you had in May? Or is it more a gentle decline, but you're seeing more later on, the decline will intensify? Or it is actually the case that the July itself growth rate will be a lot lower than what you had in May?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't see that at all, Julian. I don't see it accelerating down further. I just don't see it. I would have thought we would have been right in the 7% to 10% range, and I think right now you're going to see a general weakening. I don't think it's going to go &#x2013; it's not going to drop dramatically. Based on what we saw in July, we had a call around the Board meeting today, talking to the business leaders. It's pretty much trending in this probably now 5% to 8% range from an underlying order standpoint. I think that's where it's going to go. I think we shifted down let's say one or two percentage points in growth sooner than I thought, and I think that's where we are right now. I just don't see where the reacceleration happens in the economies around the world in the second half of the year. There's no motivation for that, as I see it right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Julian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from the line of Steven Winoker with Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, just a quick follow-up first on the last question. The growth investments you had talked about for Accelerate 2012 I think were in the $40 million range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They're still protected. They are still protected. I think right now we're on a pace just finding the right people, it probably will be closer to the low $30 million. And we will carry it over into the first quarter and I may add to that next year. These are very strategic relative to technology and emerging markets and some of our growth areas, so we will not curtail those. I'm being more selective in other areas, what I would call non-strategic growth investment areas that we really can cut back on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So these are &#x2013; just because you guys already are known to run lean elsewhere, are you talking &#x2013; is this additional G&amp;A that's volume based?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We just won't spend &#x2013; rather than spending a 5% increase, I try and cut people back to 3% or 4% type increases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not talking about draconian cuts because we're still growing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then secondly on the point around order rate starting to decelerate, on the pricing impact of that inside your markets, are you yet seeing any lack of pricing discipline as things start to decelerate? If you remember, this last cycle we didn't see as much pricing deceleration as I thought we might. And if we're heading into a slower environment again, I'm just wondering would that hold up again. Are you seeing any weakness here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I really haven't seen any weakness yet at all relative to price and our ability to get price. As you know, we went out after the last quarter and raised prices in a couple areas, and we're already seeing the impact of that relative to our order pace. We're walking away from business, so that hurts our orders. So we're able to get the price we need. And if we don't get it, we walk away from the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on Network Power, maybe you could just go a little bit into these aggressive actions that you talk about, particularly on the DC power, outside plant, China, India, and mobile chargers; any change in dynamics over the last couple of months there, competition too?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no change. I don't think the competition event has changed at all. The business is moving forward. We are actually taking the necessary price actions that we need. We're making sure we win where we want to win, and we're going to walk away from the business we don't want. Basically, what we laid out at EPG and during the conversations at the last conference call, we're executing right now. It's going to be over the next, as I said, three to four quarters. We're already seeing the initial work impact relative to our order pace in some sales in some of the early cycle what I call the Embedded Power area but nothing unusual. Moving forward, our margins were better in the third quarter and they'll be better in the fourth quarter. The volume will drop off a little bit, and so we expect that. But we'll get our profitability back in line where it should be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, and last thing is to put myself out there for you, you said you're not going to give anything on 2012, but just what multiple of GDP since you were just saying we should pick the GDP number, so that means you're picking a multiple? What multiple...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm not picking a multiple. I don't know where it's going to go. Right now, the reason we don't know, it's really hard to pick 2012 because where is the underlying growth going to be for the U.S. economy and the European economy? They are definitely decelerating right now, and the question is where does that go. You're in what I would call a transition mode right now in the two biggest economies in the world, the European economy and the U.S. economy.</p>
          <p>So it's extremely difficult to say where 2012 is going to be. I think it's a mistake for us to sit here and say okay, I think the growth is going to be 2% or 3% in the underlying GDP. And based on that, I know our GFI will be this, this, and this. I think what I want to see is where this economy goes this quarter and in the fourth quarter, and then I'll have obviously a much better view of what things are going to transpire as we go into 2012. I'm just basically grabbing stars right now and I don't think that's appropriate for me to do it. I'm running a business based on what I see right now, and I don't want to sit here and try to forecast 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome. Take Care, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from the line of Christopher Glynn with Oppenheimer. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Hi, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>How are you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thanks. Just on the Network Power with the customer selection, I wondered if you could talk first about what the impact on sales and orders was. And then also it was mentioned as having an impact on the operating margin with the lower volume. But it's a strategic move, so I'm thinking there's a pathway that by eliminating this business, it's ultimately positive to margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct. I'm not going to sit here and quantify the dollar level and how much it is. But from the standpoint of we will see a margin improvement, part of our margin improvement as we go into our fourth fiscal quarter will be an elimination of customers of low-margin business. And the customers that do take the appropriate pricing for the cost structure of what this product should be, that obviously will help us too. That's where we are right now. It will have a minor impact in sales. The short term, obviously, always has an impact on your cost structure. But over time, we will adjust. And by the fourth quarter, we'll start getting that back in line and the margins will start coming back up. It's part of our improvement that we're expecting sequentially as we go from third to fourth quarter. But I'm not going to sit here and tell you how much it is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just an update on the Chloride integration. It looks like the sales were a little lighter than last quarter, so just wondering how that's all trending.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Within the Chloride/Liebert related businesses, our orders and sales were up very nicely versus prior year. They were up over 15%. So that business was not worse off from that standpoint. If you look at the Chloride/Liebert business, we had a very strong orders and sales quarter, and that business continues to trend pretty well on a global basis. So the integration is going well there. The businesses that we're modulating back that would cause the lower growth would be in the telecom space and some of the mobile space and Embedded Power and computing space, where as we realign our portfolio of businesses, we find unacceptable margin. That's where the drop-off on sales is, not on the Reliable Power and the Liebert and ASCO Switch or the Chloride business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, you're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from the line of Eli Lustgarten with Longbow Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Eli.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of quick &#x2013; really one quick clarification. The $60 million Chloride amortization step-up &#x2013; that's permanent, I assume, for a few years? Or is it...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That will be over...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct. That was quarter over quarter, but there's a permanent step-up in the amortization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct, but that will step down after seven or eight years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but if you &#x2013; we have to factor that into the next couple consideration of quarters, this year and next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, for all this year, yes, exactly right, Eli. And as you go forward, I think it probably steps down in year seven or eight or something like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's one of the big benefits of this new approach is that you do step down some of your goodwill and amortization out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely. One question, I guess I'm not used to seeing Emerson with negative margin comparisons in four out of five sectors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I assume &#x2013; we know some of the steps are being taken to improve a bit the sequential. You just talked about Network Power. But can you go through what's going on across the divisions as far as stabilizing and improving profitability? Especially with next year being uncertain, I assume you want to have favorable margin comparisons...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...for next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The big issue, Eli, is the third quarter margins last year were pretty much an all-time high. The third quarter last year, we grew. That was the first &#x2013; our ROI growth rate was 7%, so we took off. And clearly, coming out of it we had not added any costs. And so what you have this year is you have a third quarter &#x2013; this is ignoring the impact of Chloride, which is a big chunk of the margins in the Network Power business. But we had a quarter this year where if you look at the third quarter last year, they were down a tad. But if you look at the first half this year, our third quarter margins are running substantially ahead of the first half of this year. So you've got to be careful as you look quarter over quarter because last year was a very unusual quarter.</p>
          <p>You're exactly right. We talked about it with the full Board today about where we see this going and we want to get ourselves back in line as we go into the fourth quarter. But it's not because there's a cost issue here. Clearly, we have a little bit of price/cost from material that's still negative around $15 million, Frank, from the price/cost in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct, in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>$15 million. As I said, we will get that back. We start getting positive as we go in the fourth quarter, not for the whole year. But for the quarter, we'll get it back positive. And so there are a lot of things going on. We were running at very high levels of operating profit in that third quarter. Operating profit was still 18.1% absorbing a very large acquisition, which we made about six or seven months ago.</p>
          <p>So would I be happy if they were all up? Yes, but they're up over the first half and we will end up this year at very high levels of profitability. And we will drive forward to make even more records next year. So one quarter I wouldn't get too nervous about, Eli, but we do watch it very carefully.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And to follow up, nobody wants to talk about for a forecast for 2012. But parts of your business should have some visibility into 2012, like particularly process?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Where you can look ahead &#x2013; forget GDP. Process should have a better year. The question is are we still looking at a double-digit gain in Process next year and even further strengthening profitability? And that's the kind of thing that I think is important that we find out about it at this point in time without worrying about the things that time will take care of.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you take a look at the big backlog businesses, between Process and Industrial Automation, we should have another good year going into 2012. Our Backlog in Process is at record levels. The order pace remains &#x2013; even in the last month and this month remains solid in the 12% to 15% &#x2013; 16% range on an underlying basis. We will go into next year looking at a very good growth rate, in my opinion, in Process, assuming you don't have a sudden surge of cancellations, which I see no reason for that. So from a Process standpoint, you are exactly right. I would expect us to have very strong underlying growth next year in Process. The order pace is still there. And I would expect our profitability will continue to improve. Though as you know, when I get to a certain level, I want to make sure we're not jeopardizing our long-term investment growth because we do run a very profitable Process business, the most profitable in the industry.</p>
          <p>And then Industrial Automation, based on their order pace, its comparisons are getting tougher. I would expect that Industrial Automation sales and orders do reasonably well as we go into 2012, so I would say those two segments will do pretty well. I would expect our Reliable Power business to also have another very good year as we've got the integration underway and we see that going forward. The big issue for me is, though, the difference between a very good year and what I would say above-average year right now is really based on what happens to the underlying economy more than anything else. But there are some <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:45) parts of Emerson that will have a very good next year. But I just don't want to get into are we going to grow this company next year at 7%, 8%, 9%, or 10%. I'm not in that mode right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's fine, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Take care, Eli.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from the line of Terry Darling with Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks and good afternoon, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Terry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So Dave, can you talk a little bit about China across your businesses from a top line perspective? A lot of concerns about slowing growth there; there was a comment on the Climate slide about expectation for weaker growth in Q4 on fiscal tightening. Maybe take us through some of the other businesses as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From our perspective, China is still performing very well in total. We had a very good quarter. We were up 11%, which was higher than we were in the second quarter. And we're expecting a very strong, solid double-digit growth in the fourth quarter and again for the whole year. The Climate issue you have to understand. The Climate issue had a huge surge of growth last year. They were growing 30% &#x2013; 40% in China last year because the government had picked on changing the standards &#x2013; energy standards, and we got a big growth surge last year. So from my perspective right now, as I look across the businesses, our businesses will still do reasonably well.</p>
          <p>If you look at what they're trying to slow down and where we are impacted, I would expect us to grow this year somewhere between 13% and 14% totally. And I would expect us to have 12%-plus &#x2013; let's pick a number, 12% to 15% in China next year. A lot of our strategic A12 investments are very much focused on that. A lot of new products are coming out. The economy in China &#x2013; yes, it will be slower, but maybe it's going to grow between 8% and 9%. I'll tell you what. I'd take that in the United States in a heartbeat right now.</p>
          <p>So the China marketplace has clearly slowed. There are pockets of slowing and the governments are slowing. Right now where we're sitting right now in our new product program and our investments, we're still doing okay, and I would expect us to have another good year in 2012 relative to China.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just a little more color there in, Dave, in terms of your expectations on 2012 through the segments. Presumably, you've got some easy comps in Network Power. Process remains strong, as you've talked about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The backlog is there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What do you see in some of the other businesses in China, Industrial Automation and Climate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Industrial Automation is running the best it's ever had because of the productivity investments going on in China right now. So I would expect Industrial, Network Power. Process, I would say the Climate one would be a little bit uncertain about where that goes because &#x2013; but I would say that has the most uncertainty right now. But Industrial, Network Power, and Process should be pretty good in China next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then when you look at your CapEx plans for next year at this point, have you got any additional color there? And then on the other side, how are you thinking about restructuring at this point, just overall levels of restructuring in 2012 relative to 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Relative to capital, our capital will be &#x2013; let's just stop this year. Our capital is going to up a little bit this year as we've made some strategic investments. The Middle East has held up and continued to expand. If you've noticed, we had a very strong quarter. I'm expecting another good year. So we've had to add two facilities and we're building them ourselves. We're expanding in Brazil. And I just built &#x2013; we're building &#x2013; or buying and retrofitting a new building down in Austin. So capital this year will be up in the mid-$600 million range, maybe a tad higher based on where things stand.</p>
          <p>Right now, I would expect our capital will be up. If we finish this year around $640 million, I would add $100 million for next year. I think that's where we're going to be. We're probably around &#x2013; the number you want to use, if you think of our sales, I would use somewhere around 2.8% of our sales. We are in that cycle right now where we're going to grow next year. I don't know exactly what rate we're going to grow, but our capital spending is going to be around that 2.8% level. When we start growing where we are right now, we'll have two or three years in that 2.8%. This year, Frank, are we at 2.8% or 2.7%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just right around 2.7%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>2.7%, so I think if you look at that, Terry, look and think around 2.8%, which will probably put us about $100 million. That's where I'm thinking next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just lastly on restructuring and I'll get off the call here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think restructuring this year is going to probably be at the low end of the range we've given. And then next year, as I told people, we have the Chloride, so I would say we go up a little bit from this year. But it's not going to be &#x2013; we're not going to go from &#x2013; let's say it's $85 million to $150 million. We're going to go from $85 million to $110 million, okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That gives you a ballpark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from the line of Shannon O'Callaghan with Nomura Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Shannon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Dave, on the comment about growth getting cut in half from the budget discourse and European debt, it sounds like this was the last 60 days for you in terms of deciding we're going to throttle back the spending; we've seen enough. What particularly triggered you, and what have you heard from customers to support seeing others do the same thing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I just look at the order pace. I think the biggest issue that I'm watching right now is they're not really, either in the U.S. or Europe, really addressing the gut issues. The U.S. has enormous regulations coming at us right now. The incentive to invest in the United States is negative. And from my perspective, people talk about we want clarity. I've got all the clarity I need. They're spending. They're regulating us. The tax rates, they're talking about raising the tax rates. Our tax rate this year in the U.S. will be around 36%. We'll pay in U.S. taxes this year over $500 million, actually pay the U.S. government over $500 million, and they say they want to raise it even more. And so I'm looking at that as a &#x2013; I run a company. I have a lot of money to invest. And I look at that and I say I'm not going to invest it here. And I think customers &#x2013; I think a lot of customers have the same concern.</p>
          <p>And then when you have a company like Boeing, you're talking about one of the iconic U.S. companies, gets sued by the federal government. If that doesn't get your attention, nothing will. They get sued for investing $2 billion in South Carolina. Last time I saw, South Carolina was a part of the United States of America; and you get sued for that? I tell you what, as a CEO, you get my attention. And so from my perspective, I think people are very nervous about all the regulations. We have no idea how much more healthcare costs we're going to get thrown at us. And all I see every day, things come at me. Just take the new whistleblower rule or you take the new commodity rules or you take a look at everything that's coming at us, and it's just, you're sitting there going, how much can you burden companies that do invest and try and create jobs? And the answer is I guess it's never-ending because they think that we're going to take it all and we're going to sit around.</p>
          <p>So I think the environment right now is not very good, and I think Washington doesn't understand how to create jobs. They're talking about basically raising taxes or get getting rid of corporate planes, or it's amazing. Or doubling the CAFE standards, that's going to create a lot of jobs. That's my opinion. I can control a lot of money to invest in this country, and we employ 140,000 people worldwide, including 35,000 people in United States.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks for that, and just a little more on Network Power. I know it still sounds, obviously, UPS and cooling still looking good. Network Power did okay in the quarter. But when you try to foot that all with organically 1% order growth, it seems like it's more than just you're pricing yourself out of some of this business. Are there other parts where you're seeing pauses in spending?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think right now there's &#x2013; what I would say, the Reliable Power side of the business is very good and very strong and improving. You have parts of the Embedded Power side that we're backing down because of aggressive pricing. And also the other issue there is the material, time &#x2013; material availability is back in line, so the lead times are dropping off, so people are more careful about how fast they order things. And you just have pockets of the telecom industry that one quarter will be very strong, the next quarter will be very weak.</p>
          <p>I would say generally we're trying to back things down in certain businesses right now that we find strategically are acceptable for us in margins and returns, and that has an impact. As I told you in June or May, it would have a very quick impact and we're starting to impact that already, and that will flesh out over six to nine months. So it will happen and we'll have a more profitable and healthier segment which to will grow off of as we go into 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just factoring that in, I know it takes time to play out, but do you expect Network Power to improve from the organic rate you saw in June even accounting for that, or no?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say that's a tough call. I would say it's going to be &#x2013; it's possible that in the three-month roll, as you look at the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (42:55) because we bring them out every month, it's possible that we'd have a positive underlying growth rate in the three-month roll. But I would say it's going to stay around zero until we flesh it out over the next couple of months. That's where my gut tells me right now. I don't know that, but just my gut.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from the line of Rick Kwas with Wells Fargo Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, how are you doing, Rich?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. On Process, how are you thinking about incremental margins as we move forward? You did about 20% this quarter with project picking up, MRO toning it down. How should we think about that as we move through the next few quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My feeling is where we are in the cycle right now in Process, we should run anywhere between 20% and 25%. Depending on the mix of projects, you could go as low as 18%, but it should be running let's say 18% to 25% incremental margins.</p>
          <p>The big issue for me is our Process business is going to probably hit $7 billion this year in sales. The key thing for me is we're now getting to a critical mass. So if you look at some of the facilities we've having to expand globally right now, I'm having to build expansion in my European operations. I'm doing a big expansion in Brazil. I'm doing an expansion in Texas. And so I'm having to put some infrastructure back into it as we as we set ourselves up to make a run for $8 billion. So we're in that phase right now that I'm going to have to make some investment both in people and infrastructure as we go from the $7 billion to $8 billion. So we're still going to be very profitable, but I wouldn't be surprised if you see us having to put more money into that as we go to the next level of the size of the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's about where I think we are right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then I assume something similar for Industrial Automation as we think about that business moving forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One of the things about Industrial, we are going to probably have to put some capacity in, in particular in Asia, and we have been doing that. But you also understand that we actually had added some capacity right before the downturn came. And so I think that we had fleshed out some of the capacity there, so I would say that we're going to have to continue to add capacity in some of the emerging markets. But we are in better shape relative to the infrastructure I think in IA than we were in the Process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on pricing, how do you feel about the businesses? In Climate, you've had to put another one through. What are you seeing in the other businesses with material inflation toning down a little bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Material inflation has definitely toned down, but the issue really boils on. As you look at it, we're going to still have a situation as we go into 2012 where pricing is going to have to be somewhere around 1% positive as a total corporation. So net pricing is still going to have to be positive as we go into 2012 at the current levels of commodities. If you look at global commodities, they are toning down from where they were three or four months ago, but they're still running at pretty high levels. And I would say based on what I see right now, net material inflation is going to be there, and we're going to have to have somewhere around 1% pricing as I go into 2012 looking at it today. Now that could change in three or four months depending on how much the economies slow down around the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is Network Power dominating that, or is that pretty much spread across the segments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's spread across the company and it's pretty well spread. Some are going to be higher than others. But in total, if you think about Emerson, we're going to have around 1% this year. I would think we're going to be pretty close to 1%, maybe a tad less next year, but not huge less.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, you're welcome. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from the line of Deane Dray with Citi Investment Research. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Deane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Dave. Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>How you doing? How's your new job doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>They're treating me very nicely, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>How long have you been there now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just over a year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Over a year? Gosh, time flies. That means I'm a year older.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No fooling. So Climate, update us on the issues in temperature controls. You called that out I think back in May as an issue. Just take us through the dynamics there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have some customers that when we start moving out of let's say our appliance components business, we have some situations where some of our customers, let's say they're not strategic to us anymore. So we look at that and say hey, we're going to move on to a different location, and that's basically what's going on there. We anticipated that, but it's not something &#x2013; we have to manage that over time, so that's what's going on from that standpoint as that customer shifts supply away from us. That's something that happens in this industry from time to time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And we just have to wait until that anniversaries?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pretty much it's almost done now. It will be done by the end of this fiscal year. Isn't that right, Frank, the shifting? Yes, it will be done by the end of this fiscal year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then you called out in Japan the effects of your carrying a bit more inventory.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Has that run its course? Can you size the inventory?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's around $50 million, Deane, and we'll have to work that off over time. Clearly, one of the things that based on my communications so far I would say are &#x2013; if I look at our sales right now and as we said in our press release, at one time I thought we'd be closer to $24.8 billion in sales. Now I think it's going to be closer to $24.4 billion. So we have two things working against us at this point in time: sales, the economies are a little bit weaker, and in particular in the mature countries. And we had actually to protect our customer base, we had brought inventory on. So now we're going to have to eat some of that off. And that will take us probably the rest of this calendar year to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Deane; all the best to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from the line of Jeffrey Sprague with Vertical Research. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, David. It's actually Nicole, and I'm sitting in a conference room with a large number of investors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll try to be very careful then. I'm holding up my sign. Remember, do not swear. Do not swear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm glad you're listening. First question, how would you rate your organization's execution at Network Power this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll give them a seven out of ten. It's better than last quarter, but seven out of ten.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Where did they fall short relative to your expectations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that from the standpoint of getting some of the efforts done relative to just sorting through let's say the consolidation between our acquisitions recently; also sorting through some of the issues relative to getting product done and out the door. I just think we've had slow execution relative to operations both in the product standpoint and the consolidation standpoint at this point in time. It should be &#x2013; I don't grade people at tens very often, so I would say seven. And my feeling is right now we're running higher than that. I think the team is really getting their act together. We've had several one-on-one sessions. And I think the team now is running better. As I move into the fourth quarter, they're running better. And we need that to happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then think about the challenges in that business over the next six months. Is the biggest challenge extricating yourself from the Embedded Power business successfully? Is it the consolidation of the acquisitions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The most value creation for our shareholders is the execution of the integration of Chloride and Liebert and the Knurr and the whole Avocent. That is the number one issue for creating value for my shareholders, and it's the number one priority for the business leaders in that area there. Both Scott Barbour, who has taken over, and for obviously Ed Feeney and all those guys, Stephen Liang, everyone around the world, that is the number one issue, number two issue, number three issue. That's how we'll create value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I think we have another question in the room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Martin Sankey, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Martin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I know you wish to give any real indication for 2012, but it's clear that as we've gone through the course of conversation during this conference call that there are some businesses that you have a few more worries about than others. But most importantly, where do you see the pressure points in terms of businesses or geographies as we go into 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's a good question, Martin. The pressure points, first of all, I think the longer lead time businesses as we right now sit with the backlog and the order pace holding up, those businesses I have less pressure points given where we sit right now. The pressure points I see right now are fundamentally in the U.S. and fundamentally in Western Europe. I think those marketplaces are still uncertain. The governments are having to struggle with this question of the debt and struggling with the spending. And there are huge ramifications on investment profile relative to how long will business continue to invest with that type of uncertainty and concerns going around in those two key marketplaces.</p>
          <p>So I would say the number one issue for me is what happens relative to the investment profile in Western Europe, what happens to the investment profile in the U.S. My global emerging market business I think will have a very good year next year. It will be impacted by the U.S. and Western Europe. But I think overall, I believe quite strongly the emerging markets will continue to do well and that will drive a lot of our growth. And as you know, emerging markets right now are quickly approaching 40% of our sales.</p>
          <p>So my pressure points are what happens in the U.S. and how do people get scared and do they start curtailing spending and investment in this country, and the same thing in Western Europe. Those are the pressure points that we must watch both from my standpoint and you as an investor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As a follow-on to that, so would it be fair to say you are more concerned about the consumer facing businesses still within the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The consumer businesses are pretty well dead. There has not been much recovery there. I don't know how much lower the consumer can go. I'm more concerned about just the overall investment profile. Will businesses continue to invest in expansion which has an impact? Will businesses still invest in energy assets? And those are my concerns in the short term, so that's where I am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We need to cut it off here, folks. And I'm looking forward to seeing people in the coming weeks. I want to thank everybody for joining the call today. One thing to say about Emerson; Emerson is in a very good position right now. We're extremely strong. We had a great nine months. I believe the company is operating well. We have some issues, but we'll deal with those issues. And I feel very good about where we're going here the next three to six months. And we'll deal with the uncertainty in the economies and we'll continue to grow and invest appropriately, and we'll continue to keep our cost structure. And we will set record levels of earnings and we will set record levels of profitability this year. And I want to thank everybody for joining us today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, that concludes the Emerson third quarter fiscal 2011 results conference call. If you would like to listen to a replay of today's call, please dial 303-590-3030 or 1-800-406-7325, and enter the access code of 4457238 followed by the pound sign.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>