<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1219936" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>186</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Lynne Maxeiner, Director, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">David N. Farr, Chief Executive Officer and President</participant>
      <participant id="3">John Inch</participant>
      <participant id="4">David Farr</participant>
      <participant id="5">Walter Galvin</participant>
      <participant id="6">Jeff Sprague</participant>
      <participant id="7">Eli Lustgarten</participant>
      <participant id="8">Stephen Tusa</participant>
      <participant id="9">Lynne Maxeiner</participant>
      <participant id="10">Michael Schneider</participant>
      <participant id="11">Terry Darling</participant>
      <participant id="12">Nigel Coe</participant>
      <participant id="13">Robert Cornell</participant>
      <participant id="14">Christopher Glynn</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by, and welcome to the Emerson Second Quarter Fiscal 2009 Results Conference Call.</p>
          <p>During today's presentation, all parties will be in a listen-only mode. Following the presentation, the conference will be open for questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And as a reminder, this conference is being recorded today, Tuesday, May 5, 2009.</p>
          <p>And Emerson's commentary and responses to your questions may contain forward-looking statements, including the Company's outlook for the remainder of the year. Information on factors that could cause actual results to vary materially from those discussed today is available in Emerson's most recent Annual Report on Form 10-K, as filed with the SEC.</p>
          <p>In this call, Emerson management will discuss some non-GAAP measures in talking about the Company's performance, and a reconciliation of those measures to the most comparable GAAP measures is contained within a presentation that is posted in the Investor Relations area of Emerson's website at www.emerson.com.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to our host, Ms. Lynn Maxeiner, Director of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mitch. I am joined today by David Farr, Chairman, Chief Executive Officer, and President of Emerson; and Walter Galvin, Senior Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer.</p>
          <p>Today's call will summarize Emerson's second quarter 2009 results. A conference call slide presentation will accompany my comments and is available in the Investor Relation section of Emerson's corporate website. A replay of this conference call and slide presentation will be available on the website after the call for the next three months. I will start with the highlights of the quarter as shown on page two of the conference call slide presentation.</p>
          <p>Second quarter sales were down 16% to 5.1 billion and underlying sales declined 11%. Underlying sales and process management remain positive, up 3%. Operating profit margin was 14.1% and pre-tax earnings margin was 10.8%, impacted by restructuring expense of 64 million in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share from continuing operations was $0.49, down 35% compared to the prior year quarter. Operating cash flow was 499 million and free cash flow was 359 million. Capital spending was down 22% versus prior year quarter. Our balance sheet remains strong and we made progress on trade working capital.</p>
          <p>Inventory dollar levels were reduced by over 200 million from the first quarter of fiscal year '09. We saw a dramatic weakening of the global economy in our second quarter.</p>
          <p>Next slide, the P&amp;L. Again, sales down 16% to 5.087 billion. Underlying sales were down 11% and currency subtracted five points. Operating profit was 718 million in the quarter or 14.1% of sales, the decline driven primarily by deleverage on lower sales volume, unfavorable product mix and our aggressive inventory reduction. Net earnings from continuing ops for the quarter were 373 million, a decline of 38%. Diluted average shares in the quarter were 756.9 million and we repurchased 8.2 million shares for 263 million in the quarter, which leaves you with an EPS of $0.49.</p>
          <p>There was higher restructuring in FY09, which negatively impacted EPS by $0.04. The next slide, underlying sales by geography. In the United States, sales declined 19%. Total international was down 3% with Europe down 10%. Asia, up 1%, Latin America, down 1% and Middle East/Africa, up 3%. This gets you to a total underlying sales number of negative 11%. Currency subtracts five points for consolidated sales decline of 16%. Emerging markets are holding up better than mature markets, declining only 1% in Q2.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, some income statement detail. Gross profit of 1.837 billion or 36.1% of sales. The decline was driven by volume deleverage, unfavorable mix and our lower production level to drive inventory reduction, which was partially offset by cost reduction. We also had lower mark-to-market benefit in Q2 '09 relating to commodity hedging, which decreased gross profit by $20 million quarter-over-quarter by comparison.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A was 22%, which gets you to operating profit of 718 million or 14.1% of sales. Other deductions net were 121 million, up 54 million in total. The increase was driven by a 48 million increase in restructuring. We also had a favorable $25 million impact in other deductions from increased gains, which was offset by various other deductions. Interest expense of 50 million, this gets you to the pre-tax line of 547 million or 10.8% of sales. Taxes in the quarter were 174 million for a tax rate of 32%. The tax rate is expected to be approximately 32% for the fiscal year.</p>
          <p>Next slide, the cash flow and balance sheet. Operating cash flow in the quarter, down 33% driven by lower earnings and net pension funding. Capital expenditures of a 140 million gets you to the free cash flow of 359 million. Free cash flow was 96% of net earnings in the quarter. Trade working capital balances are at the bottom of the slide. We continue to aggressively pursue our working capital initiative and we reduced our inventory balance 275 million from the prior year quarter and more than 200 million from December 31, '08. Since the beginning of the calendar year, we issued 1.25 billion in long-term debt at very good rates and repaid 250 million on mature debt.</p>
          <p>Slide seven, the business segment P&amp;L. Business segment EBIT of 587 million or 11.2% of sales, down 37% impacted by volume deleverage, negative mix and increased restructuring. Difference of accounting methods of 47 million, corporate and other of 37 million, which is down 22 million in the quarter with lower incentive compensation subtracting 23 million, a gain from an asset sale subtracting 25 million and a lower benefit in the quarter from commodity mark-to-market adding 20 million. Again, interest expense of 50 million getting you to the pre-tax line of 547 million.</p>
          <p>On slide eight, we'll review the individual business segments starting with Process Management. Sales in the quarter down 4% to 1.53 billion, underlying sales remained positive, up 3% and currency subtracted seven points. By region, the U.S. was down 7%, Asia was up 21%, Europe was up 1% and Middle East/Africa was up 5%. International sales on an underlying basis were up over 9% in the quarter. EBIT dollars of 258 million or 16.9% of sales. Unfavorable mix in the quarter was partially offset by cost reduction. Our investments continue in new products and globalization. EBIT margin excluding restructuring was 17.3%. We continue to see the power market showing strength for Process Management.</p>
          <p>The acquisition of Roxar was completed in April. Roxar is a great adjacent expansion in oil and gas exploration and production. On slides nine and 10, a little more information on the Roxar acquisition. Roxar is a leading global supplier of measurement solutions and software for reservoir production optimization, enhance the oil and gas recovery, and flow assurance. They are headquartered in Norway with 821 employees and operations in nine countries. Their business consists of flow measurement products, which are 77% of the business and software solutions, which are 23% of the business.</p>
          <p>Next slide, Roxar has annual revenues of approximately 200 million and 11.5% operating profit margin and will be reported in the Process Management segment. The acquisition provides significant market position in oilfield equipment and services portion of the exploration and production markets. The market dynamics of exploration and production favor strong growth.</p>
          <p>Roxar is a market and technology leader in this space and this acquisition broadens our oil and gas presence and provides early visibility to projects. Really a great acquisition for Emerson and we are excited about the opportunities that Roxar brings.</p>
          <p>Next slide, Industrial Automation. Sales in the quarter of 960 million, down 18%. Underlying sales were down 15% with currency subtracting five points and acquisitions adding two points. Geographically, the U.S. was down 18%, Europe was down 14% and Asia was down 16%. We expect global GFI to be down sharply in 2009 and also 2010.</p>
          <p>EBIT dollars of 97 million or 10.1% of sales, negatively impacted by volume deleverage and negative product mix, which was partially offset by cost reduction. EBIT margin was 11% excluding the restructuring impact. In Q2, we completed the acquisition of Trident Power, a power-generating alternator manufacturer based in India. Trident Power strengthens our global leadership position in alternator business.</p>
          <p>Slide 12, Network Power. Sales in the quarter of 1.28 billion, down 16%. Underlying sales, down 10%, currency subtracting four points and acquisitions subtracting two points. By region, the U.S. was down 22%, Asia was up 6% and Europe was down 15%. We saw broad weakness in the uninterruptible power supply, precision cooling and embedded computing and power businesses.</p>
          <p>EBIT dollars of 105 million or 8.2% of sales, the deterioration primarily driven by increased restructuring of 25 million and volume deleverage and the dilutive impact from an acquisition. The margin excluding restructuring was 10.5%. Our China Power Systems business has remained strong, driven by telcomm infrastructure and wind power demand and we continue to make penetration gains in those markets. We continue with aggressive restructuring to further strengthen our competitive position.</p>
          <p>Next slide, Climate Technologies. Sales in the quarter of 733 million, down 23%. Underlying sales were down 21% and currency subtracted two points. By geography, we had the U.S. down 21%, Europe was down 6% and Asia was down 31%. EBIT of 66 million or 9% of sales, the decrease driven by lower sales volume and price cost pressures.</p>
          <p>EBIT margin excluding the restructuring was 10.2%. We recently completed the acquisition of Dixell, a European manufacturer of electronic control solutions for AC, industrial and refrigeration markets.</p>
          <p>Slide 14, Appliance and Tools. Sales in the quarter of 727 million, down 24%. Underlying sales were down 23% and currency subtracted one point. By region, we had the U.S. down 24%, Europe down 23% and Asia down 6%. EBIT of 61 million or 8.4% of sales, the decline driven by volume deleverage and increased restructuring of 10 million, partially offset by cost reduction. EBIT margin was 9.9% excluding the restructuring impact. Recent order patterns indicate some stabilization of the consumer related businesses in this segment.</p>
          <p>Slide 15 with Summary and Outlook. Market conditions deteriorated sharply in the second quarter. Our underlying sales declined 11%, our operating profit margin was impacted by our decision to reduce our production levels more than the sales decline in order to reduce our inventory level, which we did. And we had seen underlying order trends improving from February to March.</p>
          <p>As the inventory corrections, backlog liquidation and reduced lead times appear to be getting through the system, we believe orders are becoming more reflective of end-market demand. Today, we reaffirmed our fiscal year 2009 guidance of underlying sales growth of negative 9 to negative 11% and reported sales, down 13 to 15% to 21 to 21.7 billion. Restructuring expense in FY09 of 200 to 250 million, full-year earnings per share of $2.40 to $2.60 and full-year operating cash flow of 3.1 to 3.3 billion, capital expenditures of approximately 0.6 billion and free cash flow of 2.5 to 2.7 billion.</p>
          <p>So with that, I'll turn it over to David Farr.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Lynne. I want to wish everyone good afternoon and thanks for joining us today. We had a very interesting Board meeting today as we reviewed all the actions we're taking across this Company. As you can see from the numbers we reported today in the commentary, we are now entered the heart of this global recession with approximately 11% underlying sales decline this quarter and as we look at the second half of this year, down 12 to 15% on average, somewhere in that range for underlying sales and most likely, down 10% in the first half of next year.</p>
          <p>The management team is taking the actions necessary to position this Company for some extremely tough waters ahead, some tough quarters and a tough business environment. As I look at it today and we'll be facing some very challenging times for most, if not all of 2010.</p>
          <p>But as I discussed with the Board today, and the OCE discussed with the Board today, we feel very comfortable we're taking the actions necessary to strengthen this Company from the standpoint of our global positioning, our new products, our technology, the businesses that we have, both through acquisitions and through divestitures. The management team is taking -- are taking the necessary actions to strengthen this Company. It's not easy taking some of these actions when you have somewhere between 200 and $250 million of restructuring. We've already impacted 20,000 people across this Company, around the world, to be a benefit for us in the second half as we move to that second half. I would expect to be another 10,000 people around the world over the next nine months are impacted by this global downturn.</p>
          <p>We have actions underway at 46 locations around the world as we position the Company. We're making tough calls, fixing the cost structure of this Company and position this Company for what I consider a very strong recovery to be able to set record levels of sales, profit margins, cash flow and returns when that upturn comes sometimes in 2011 and 2012, just like we did in the last -- after the last downturn. Our focus is to make the Company stronger and position the Company stronger, both from an underlying sales growth rate and profitability standpoint. The management team around the world are taking extremely tough actions, it's not easy.</p>
          <p>It would be really easy not to take inventory out. It would be really easy not to take shutdown facilities but that's not what we get paid to do. This quarter we took out over $200 million of inventory from the end of the first quarter, down to the second quarter. That causes enormous deleverage and under-absorption in the facilities, but it's the right thing to do because we're looking at a very difficult environment out in front of us. We will be doing the same thing the next six months. I would expect our inventory dollars by year-end to be close to $2 billion and maybe a little bit under $2 billion when we finish this.</p>
          <p>But by taking these actions now, as we move into the second half of this year, our underlying sales volume will be up a little bit, underlying production volume will be up a little bit from the seasonality and we have less people on our facilities, therefore we'll get the natural benefit of better volumes and better profitability. As we estimated today, it's worth about $100 million to us in the second half of this year from a profitability standpoint based on the actions we're taking and based on a little bit more output through our facilities as we look at those ratios. We will continue to work on those ratios as we talked about. If the business continues to weaken, we will continue to take the necessary restructuring and job actions and inventory reductions to position this Company for a stronger company going forward.</p>
          <p>Protecting the cash flow and the balance sheet is very important to this Company and we're working that very hard. But as I look at the second half of this year, I look at the benefits from the restructuring that we started in late fiscal 2008 and very aggressively in the first half of 2009, we will get the benefits to drive a little bit higher profit margin in the second half and I still feel very comfortable looking at what I see today delivering a 15.6 to 15.8% operating margin for the Corporation.</p>
          <p>Some people say the free cash flow was not very good in the second quarter. It still was 96% coverage. We had a dramatic drop-off in our net earnings. We funded more of our pension plan, we will fund more in the third quarter, but we still had 96% coverage on our free cash flow and net earnings. Based on what I see right now in our restructuring base and the inventory reduction, I still believe that we will deliver somewhere between 2.5 and $2.6 billion of free cash flow for the whole year. We still feel good about that.</p>
          <p>The third quarter will be key for us as we drive our improvement in our operating -- improvement from an operating leverage and also the asset management.</p>
          <p>Acquisitions, we are now targeting somewhere between 1 and $1.2 billion of acquisitions for the year. The opportunities are still out there. We are closing on what I call small, medium-size acquisitions, very strategic acquisitions for the businesses that we've been going after for years, strengthen this Company and we will continue to do that in the second half of this year.</p>
          <p>As we talked about in early April, I anticipated our order pace would be less negative. It's still negative, I do anticipate that will continue. We did have in the month of March, our underlying orders were less than negative 20%. I would anticipate that will happen again in April and we will continue to see that as comparisons get easier and as also we see some of the early-cycle businesses starting to cycle back into some normal production. They will still be negative, but a lot less negative as I look forward to it.</p>
          <p>In discussion with the Board today, I feel that things are trending around the world as we expected. The non-rev, the gross fixed investment around the world is going to be very difficult for the second half of this year and will be negative again next year. Both North America and in Europe are two very, very challenging marketplaces right now and therefore our focus is very much on those areas for restructuring. In this cycle, we are trying to go after some of our European facilities in our European cost-structure more than we did last cycle because I believe that Europe is going stay down much longer than they did last time.</p>
          <p>So as we look at it today, the Company has continued to move forward relative to a very aggressive restructuring to strengthen the Company going long term, we feel good about the trends in orders in what we are seeing around the world, a stability in the economic forecast that doesn't mean they're getting better, I think they are locked into a forecast now for the last couple of months which gives us a pretty good indication of where things are going to trend here as we go forward the next six to 12 months.</p>
          <p>As always, a lot of challenges around the Company. The Company is extremely strong right now. We are making money, we are generating cash, we are able to raise almost $0.75 billion a couple of weeks ago at very favorable rates. Our balance sheet is strong, and I feel that we will have a very good momentum as we go into the second half of the year. Yes, the numbers will be down but  they're going to be very good comparisons from the standpoint of what we saw in the first half.</p>
          <p>So, as I look at it, we feel very good right now. We are dealing at a very difficult environment but we're positioned to win in a very difficult environment. You go take a look at a lot of companies that we compete against in this most recent quarter and I think we did pretty well with only 11% negative underlying growth rate. And we delivered pretty good margins and we delivered pretty good cash flow. And that is because of the hard work that the management team around the world, the operating management team did around the world, and I want to thank them for doing that as they are taking the actions necessary.</p>
          <p>Now, with that I want to open the phone to answer people's calls because I'm sure they will have some questions because I'm sure they will have some questions relative to the quarter. And with that operator, please let's field some of the questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Ladies and gentlemen, we will now begin the question-and-answer session <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question comes from the line of John Inch with Merrill Lynch. Go ahead please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Afternoon, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with Process. The underlying sales up 3% but the margin's eroded little bit more than perhaps I was thinking -- you guys called out mix. Could you flesh that out a little bit? What exactly do you mean by mix, is it project specific? Is it &#x2013; is it systems, what exactly does that mean and what is the outlook there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We had, a couple of things going on. First of all we did also go after the inventories in those <mark type="inaudible" /> facilities, so we have a situation there where some of their facilities will deleverage as they take their inventories down. You also will see that I think we mentioned in the April call that the chemical industry in particular has taken a very dramatic downturn in purchases and therefore some of our instrumentation businesses have been hit early on as this cutback in capital spending in some of these chemical industries. They will also come back as those industries start stabilizing and start seeing their improvement from a sales and a profitability standpoint, they'll start spending money again. So we saw a mix relative to certain industries, in particular, the chemical industry which really dropped off, we saw an area where we cut back our own inventory and production and we also saw some completion on some very large projects around the world, which are lower margin relative to the systems and solutions side. But you're going to see this fairly rough patch here as we go forward here is mixed around these businesses and a mix within the instrumentation and systems business. But still we'll have very good profitability for the whole year as I look forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Dave, does the fact that margins are coming down with revenues still going up though imply because of mix that proportionally more of the kind of profit degradation, if you will, happens up front and then as you roll into sort of down revenues, you don't get as much of a degradation just because the higher ends already been skinned off the top, so to speak?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's hard to say that's the case, John. I think that after running the Process business, you see some of the early-cycle guides within the process -- early cycle guide that work -- our heavy instrumentation &#x2013; in particular the flow, the measurement side, flow side that they go after it first, they will come back but I don't think you're going to see you could make that statement, you're saying, okay, we're going to have more profit degradation now and then it will stabilize later. I still think you're going to see this business cycle down as I believe I said in April and the profitability will cycle down but it will stay at higher levels than it did in the last cycle. And we hit 20% operating margins here, our EBIT margins here and I would expect us to go back down, take 2-300 basis points off that as we cycle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Does the rising price of oil change the outlook in '010 or is sort of '010 already in the cards and then maybe it becomes more of an '011 issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think the '010 is more in the cards for projects but if you go to capital spending and MRO type of spending and maybe some chemical industry spending that could help us. Rising oil will help us and from the standpoint of spending in the companies, the customer base also is quickly taking action relative to their inventories and their capital spending. But as soon as they start delivering higher levels of profitability, you'll start seeing them spend money and I think that will happen later this year going into early year but we're still forecasting a down Process business for 2010. That will be the issue in my opinion. It will go down because of the -- it's coming of off very high levels both from a sales and profit standpoint.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just lastly, what was the 25 million in gains?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We actually had a long time ago -- in our leasing business, we actually owned part of a Mazda/Ford plant and we sold it back to Mazda/Ford.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For 25 million in gains? Congratulations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We wanted to get out when we could.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's been there for how long Walter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At least 19 years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Long time, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This was when we had a active finance company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Jeff Sprague with Citi Investment Research. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Dave, could we get a little bit further into kind of these cost delta issues, you mentioned kind of the 100 million I believe that's second half versus first half. But taking a little bit different cut at that, when you look at the restructuring that you did in '08 and what you have underway in '09, what kind of savings do you expect from those actions in '09, separate and apart from the seasonality issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not going to give it to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the 100 million you gave us was a combination of seasonality and restructuring benefits?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Primarily restructuring. In total &#x2013; the reason I'm not going to tell you -- I mean it's not something that you can nail down by quarter, it's not that easy to do. But in total -- let me give you some numbers. In February, we talked about restructuring around 175 to 200 million. It's now up to say 200 to 250 million, let's pick 225 as the mid point. We gave you average annual savings of 125 to 140 million in February. Now the number is more like 135 to 190 million, let's say a 160 mid point. The issue that Walter and I -- why we're struggling relative to giving this out is we are going after what I would call longer term projects from a saving standpoint. So the average return is going to be longer for us this time. Because I'm going after projects that I have, it's cost us more money upfront and the payback is going to be slower, but it will fundamentally change the cost structure of the Company two years from now. I can tell you what we've been doing since say July, August, September time period all the way up to this period and I look at the savings, I look at our 20,000 less people and I could see that we are going to get a benefit of around $100 million in the second half of this year. It's very difficult for me to sit here and give you forecasts because of the other things and it's not something that I want to get tied down to. But I can tell you we will get the savings because we're going after the projects and we see the head count coming down and we see the facilities coming offline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And could you help us actually frame the margin impact of the inventory reduction in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not really. I mean it's a function of where that inventory is coming out, it's $200 million. We know, if you look at the operating margins, the Company came down significantly from the standpoint of the sales and the production. And we know that we deleverage Walter for the quarter what was the number, 35?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>35%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>35%. So we know that as we come off of that, we will deleverage less. So let's say we'll move down towards the 25 to 30% level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that means the inventory just to reduce -- reduction of the inventory would be more like 20% deleverage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's about the average right there, exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's very helpful. And just to hit good old Appliance and Tools, which gets ignored a lot, if you break that apart was the performance in Appliance and Tools similar or is there some divergence in the performance of those businesses now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't say there's divergence, I would say that those businesses are what I would say stabilizing because of the massive inventory reduction that's happened in those businesses over the last 18 months. And so you're going to still see negative sales comps in the second half of the year, but they will be less negative. And I think that we will see pleasantly some upside potential as they move forward.</p>
          <p>And so if you look at the numbers they are not that much different apart as Lynne is showing me between Tools and Appliance, I mean they are about identical from a negative standpoint. So you're going to see them get easier comps and I think you'll start seeing some positives as some of the inventories are sort of replenished back out there in the second half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Eli Lustgarten with Longbow Securities. Go ahead please</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Eli.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I have a probably a -- rather tough question to ask you. With the way the second quarter's come in, in order to meet your guidance, you've got to get basically $0.65 a quarter in the second half. Right now you have a consensus that doesn't believe the 239 -- the 240 plus and you had actually bigger declines scheduled next year as you look at the consensus. How do I bridge the gap from where the $0.49 in the quarter with restructuring equal or greater in the second half of the year and maybe you'll have another $0.25 gain and lower volume. How do I bridge the gap to get that biggest step up from $0.49 to $0.65 a quarter? What's driving that, can you help me bridge that gap to get those kind of numbers, which is -- it seems difficult on the surface with the volumes continuing to be soft?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The issue really boils down to is -- maybe what we're forecasting internally the improvement in operating profit in the second half based on the restructuring and the slightly higher volume and the fact that we, our plants, would have less people producing a little bit higher level volume because we've got the actions taken. We believe that we'll be able to improve the operating profit in the second half of the year versus the first half, and I would say most of the people out there do not believe that. And so most people do not believe that we'll be a run of 15.6 to 15.8% operating profit for the whole year based on what we just perform in the first half. So that is the difference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that 100 million number that you quoted sort of just the tip of the iceberg of what you're expecting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Eli, one way to look at it might help you. If you look at the absolute level of sales volume, first half to second half, even though it's still down versus the prior year, the actual run rate using your estimate would probably be sales would be higher by about $300 million. On that $300 million higher sales volume, you would probably leverage, say, at around a third or about $100 million. As you look at what Dave told you with regard to the head count being down, already the actions completed as well as additional actions, you will have a reduction on the average head count, both hourly and salary between the first half of the year and the second half of the year, where the average will be down in round numbers, at least 10,000 people.</p>
          <p>If you say that, just pick a number, say the average because it's hourly and salary around the world is $20,000. That means you have a difference of about $10,000 because it's a half the year that gives you $100 million. We've also commented on in different segments that we were behind in price cost in the first half versus the prior year, we will get that back in the second half versus the first half, which will be a favorable impact of about $100 million.</p>
          <p>Another way to look at it would be, if you look at normally, over the last couple of years second half profitability versus first half profitability, for a number of seasonal reasons -- seasonal pattern reasons, is generally higher by about 150 basis points. Now it's not -- it's more than that this time, but the other contributing factors on catching up on the price cost issues in certain segments and the reduction in the head count because clearly the drop between the first quarter run-rate of being flat to the second quarter run-rate, I'm thinking organically underlying to being down 11%. You deleverage more when you get the shock in the first 90 days as you get those cost out. I hope that answers your question on the margin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, it's very helpful because it sort of explain some of the gap we're going. And is there any part of the business at this point that you think didn't see probably relatively trough margins in this second quarter versus the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Industrial Automation. I would say Industrial Automation is going to have, I think, a very difficult second half because of Europe. And our number one customer in that marketplace in that segment is Caterpillar and they're continuing to cut back. So I would say that they are going to -- they are going to struggle the hardest in the second half of the year and in addition they are -- they have more inventory reduction than the other businesses because of where they are in the power curve right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you expect this 11% to get down to what, the mid-to-high-single digits as sort of the target for them?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They will definitely go under 10.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, with the cutbacks Caterpillar's going we could have a lot more than that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We were a little bit quicker.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Steve Tusa, J.P. Morgan. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Steve</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Or good afternoon. I'm not quite sure what day or what time it is, it's been a long nine months. On Process -- .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are just starting, partner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're just starting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On Process, so you made a comment about down two to 300 basis points, what are you -- what's the base you're talking about, do you think the trough is 200 -- 300 basis points from here or from the peak, I'm just curious as to what you're -- .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say from what we saw the peak last year, which was around, let's say, 20.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So you're there, so you're there this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One quarter. I mean, do you think a quarter is the whole year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, got you. Got you. So on a --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You got to watch -- we might have a couple of tough quarters here with these guys, but these guys are still going to do pretty well this year from a positive standpoint. They're going after the action right now, I think you're going to -- over the next couple of years, you're going to see a more challenging process marketplace, but if we saw some stability in the energy market, we saw a recovery in the economy, you're going to start seeing that process guides come back pretty quickly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then you keep, I'm not sure if this is just -- maybe I'm missing something you're talking about, but you keep saying 15.6 to 15.8 operating margin, is that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I said, 15.6 to 15.8.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, I know you said 15.6 to 15.8, but --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So is that the same as 15.7 to 16 or is that a different metric we're referring to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The guidance provided is 15.7 -- 16% for operating profit margin for '09.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just one more, you keep talking about these comps getting better in the back half, but if you look at --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Easier, easier, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Easier in the back half, I mean when you look at the order rates are clearly running ahead of where you were, the revenue comps you had in the second quarter at least from a downside perspective and you basically had pretty consistent organic growth throughout 2008, I think organic was 7% throughout 2008. So I mean when -- what -- how do these comps get easier, I know -- are you just talking about for Appliance and Tools, or are you talking about for the whole business? I just want a little clarity on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you're going to start seeing some of the earlier cycle businesses, Appliance and Tools, you're going to see the Climate Technologies comps because of how far -- how much they went down before this cycle started back last year, they will get easier to compare against, it'll be less negative. From the capital side, I don't think you're going to see any easier comps going forward here until we get well into 2010. So I'm just saying as we look at the various businesses and where they are coming from, the comps from a standpoint of how far they're going to go down and how negative they are going to be just gets easier after awhile all this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, it's just sort of having it's generally housing related?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Housing and some spending, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then one more thing just on pension, is there any update on where we stand for 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we talked about in February, I thought it'd be a little bit over 100 million. A little bit over 100 million right now, I'd say it's going to be somewhere between 50 and 75 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Down from year to year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Worse, worse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, one thing when you talk about comps you have to keep in mind that orders in 2008 exceeded sales by quite a bit. So when you look at the delta, you're looking at orders you can have a higher percentage than when you're looking at the sales impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So it's -- the book-to-bill was high, so you're just basically coming off an elevated book-to-bill?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Michael Schneider with Robert W. Baird. Go ahead please. Mr. Schneider, please make sure your phone is not on mute.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Here we go. Good afternoon, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Michael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe we can start on Climate we haven't touched on it, I'm curious about what you're seeing at least heading out of April and into early May now because clearly the season hasn't been strong? But I'm curious if there is a potential at least for the orders in the seasonal period to be concentrated now in the months of May and June rather than starting back in March, just given the distribution fears out there and the distribution destocking that is going on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Michael, I think that the inventory in the channel and everywhere are extremely tight and it appears everyone has because of the lower volumes, everyone has the manufacturing capacity flexibility right now to react very quickly. So I think you are going to see a very -- a quick bang, so if you get a little heat and any improvement they are going to have to replenish some of those channel and it's going to happen pretty quickly. So we are getting ready for that. We don't know what's going to happen. But we're ready, we have the flex and we can go. But my gut tells me this could be a very quick season and where you could have come May, June, July, boom, boom, boom, boom, three months and it's going to be, they need the product and you got to ship it tomorrow. That is what is going to happen I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And are the OEMs telling you guys that, that they understand that you guys have excess inventory, so they are basically relying upon you to take that risk?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think they are pushing it back to the channel, the answer is yes. I mean but I wouldn't say we don't have excess inventory, what we have is flex and we are going to have to flex very, very quickly, up and down our channel and we're making sure that's the case because well, I think the season is going to be quick, quick this year. And we got to be ready, so we don't miss it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And from what I understand, pricing has remained fairly firm in that channel, is that one of the reasons because you do have that leverage at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The pricing seems to -- remain fairly firm because the commodities like copper have already started -- seeing the bottom and come back up again already. So I think you're seeing, people are worried about the inflation, so they are being very careful here. And so it's not going to -- people are being prudent relative to what they're trying to do from a price-cost situation because we're all worried about the fact that commodities could come roaring back as we're being very careful and disciplined as I would say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I'm just curious, in Asia, it remains extremely strong for Process. I guess what are the backlogs looks like there and do you expect that or I guess what have you seen most recently out of China with the stimulus money already hitting, have you booked new orders just any update on Asia Process?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say Asia Process is still very strong and has continued to do well from a book-to-bill. In Asia, our Network Power business has been very strong, the stimulus is very aimed at those two businesses. When you go in to our Industrial Automation or Climate or the other businesses, it's been weak. So what we're been seeing is our Network Power China and Asia business and Process has held in there quite nicely, and our China business was up for the quarter. And I would expect our China business to be up somewhere around five or 6% for the whole year. Down from what I said originally Mike, but I think that we're going to see our China business hold up and I'm still believing that they're going to maybe actually put some additional stimulus in there, which will help us significantly as we move into 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the energy efficiency rebates, the Act, everything centered around that domestically, can you just look across your businesses now and give us an update as to whether you've seen any benefit from these initiatives, whether the stimulus bill or the energy act et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I've seen nothing. I mean the only place I've seen any effect of stimulus is in China. Europe has no flexibility from stimulus, U.S. stimulus is very much based on what I would call transfer of payments, paving &#x2013; or runways and airports and things like that doesn't do much for us, and I've not seen any stimulus from a standpoint of telecom or power or anything in the United States that would say has helped us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You haven't seen any benefit though as some of the appliance rebates at least prompt people to trade up in SEER ratings, has that helped your mix?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not seeing that. The mix is fine because the movement to 13 SEERs already happened. But I haven't seen anyone out there trying to go out and buy new air conditioners or new appliances for higher efficiency. I mean if you don't have money to spend you're not going to go out and trade up to a higher efficiency; the payback will be 20 years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks again, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Terry Darling with Goldman Sachs. Go ahead please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Walter, I'm wondering if you could call out the FX headwind in the quarter at the EPS line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you mean just the --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sales, we use 16, 16%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let me just -- do you have another question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was just trying to think about the translation in the second half versus first half presumably that gets a little less of a headwind and I'm wondering what's your expectations are there as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now at the point of sales because this is how we track it -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Give us a second, looking on the board chart right now, looking at the second quarter but the full year.  You have the second quarter there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Dave, maybe I'll ask you one while he's looking on that, you had mentioned expectations for a pick up in 3Q, 4Q kind of sequentially from 2Q in the Appliance and Tools business as the inventories have kind of work their way to tighter levels, can you talk a little bit about how significant a pickup sequentially you're thinking there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Historically, we would pick up a couple of hundred million, as Walter said, two to $300 million of sales. I'm looking at a little bit of pickup we're seeing some replacement from the standpoint of inventories and some programs in some of the channels as these guys are going to replenish and start selling. So we'll see in the second half of this year somewhere between 200 and $300 million higher level of sales just from a seasonality but I also believe they'll be close to $300 million because we'll see some replenishment of inventory both on the appliance side and also on what I would call the tool side; we're already seeing a little bit of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Plus 200 to 300 just in the Appliance and Tool side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm talking about the total comp we normally see there, and I think it's going to be closer to 300, normally it would be around 200, and I think it might be closer to 300 just because some of the pick back up that we're going to see in some of the businesses in the second half of the year. That's all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, wondering if you could talk a little bit about expectations for Roxar in terms of growth rates and your goals for getting those margins up? And it does look like a little bit of a move upstream for you in that business into the realm of the Schlumbergers and the Halliburtons, can you talk about your longer-term strategy there too?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From our standpoint, the underlying growth of this business is high single-digit. It will have I think the next 12 months should be okay because we look at their backlog and I think that late 2010 &#x2013; early 2011, because we have more of a challenge for them and then it'll come back on. The profitability of that business, there is no reason why that profitability of that business can't be in the 16 to 20% range within five to six years as we look at our own instrumentation business within from a technology base within that industry today I think that we can deal with that.</p>
          <p>What we're looking at right now is be able to serve from an instrumentation and software capability to help the big oil companies deal with finding -- in improving their oil productivity in the deepwater area and Roxar brings that to us, we didn't have that. So, I mean the profitability is going to move up towards our average in that 16, 18, 19, 20% range over five to six years and I think the underlying growth rate of that business will be throughout two cycles in the high-single digits.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Should we look for you to try to continue to move upstream or is this about as far as you think you go?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think this is about as far as we're going to go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just finalizing on the FX question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>He's calculating it right now, he's got his little calculator going, his little green shade on and everything like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The average impact is about -- in the first quarter is about four points of growth, second, third and fourth, each five points of growth. So the impact for the year is about five points of growth, which is about $1.2 billion year-to-year. That at our normal foreign margin impact is about $180 million or about $0.16.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And it's got to be pretty consistent second half versus first half. So that's not a major factor in terms of the improvement in EPS, second half versus first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And our next question comes from the line of Nigel Coe with Deutsche Bank. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Nigel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just want to dig into the seasonality question a little bit deeper, particularly with Process management, we typically see a fairly pronounced pickup in the second half versus first half. Given that that business is slacking down, do you think that that will be essentially flat through the quarters this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It will be a little bit, but I think it'll be flatter. We won't see as much pick up there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the seasonality second half versus first half comes from a little bit in Appliances and Tools and Climate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Climate, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. Secondly -- .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The other one Walter and I will point out is Network Power will be up in the second half too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then secondly, temporary cost savings has been a pretty big driver of margin upsides say for other industrials and we've heard about spouts &#x2013; furloughs, and pay cuts for executives, et cetera. We haven't heard so much of that from you, seeing much more head count reductions, structural cost savings, I mean, are you doing these temporary cost savings and is that a factor in the second half of -- ?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We did them in the fourth calendar quarter of last year, we already did them. And I don't typically put out PR relations and things like that. But we have across this Company, I mean my compensation's been taken back and my base value's been taken back to 2007 level. The OCE went back one year, we have freezes around the Company, delays six months to 12 months. We are doing everything everyone else is doing, but I don't think we need to go out and put press releases out and tell what we're doing. The Company is very aggressive in doing the right things for the shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. And then finally, just wanted to touch on tax, obviously there has been a little bit of few headlines but the White House plans to --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Going after tax cheaters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes, love that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But, your tax <mark type="inaudible" /> it doesn't feel like you've pressed all the buttons in terms of minimizing your tax rate so have you thought about the implications of maybe if these changes are made what that might do to your taxes because it doesn't sound like it is going to be a big change for you guys?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It will impact us. Now, we will have to see what happens I'm not going to give you a number yet but it will impact us because we are a company that has a very strong global reach. We have global manufacturing and we manufacture to go after marketplaces like China or India and we manufacture in those marketplaces and they have lower tax rates than we do in the United States.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You can see in our footnote for the 2008 annual report how much money we make in the U.S. and how much money we make on a pre-tax basis outside the United States and we are still a large U.S. taxpayer with the normal effective U.S. manufacturing tax rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We pay our fair share of taxes. I get a little bit pissed off when I'm called a tax cheat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I agree, I'm not saying that but the U.S. tax is 35%, your effective tax rate is 32% this year, other industrials with a similar mix of international sales of 25% and below. It doesn't feel like -- it doesn't feel like you are as exposed as maybe some other industrials?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Depends, it depends on how they structure it -- the answer is we have always paid our fair share of taxes and we will be impacted by it though, Nigel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You have to look at the relative profitability of the U.S. business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I will do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A lot of headwinds coming both from the economy and Washington.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I don't want to get too much into that. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I just said it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Bob Cornell with Barclays</p>
          <p>Capital. Go ahead please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, let's clear up a couple of things on Process, way back when John asked his first question you mentioned as part of the answer that part of the margin issue was a function of project completions, does that mean you had some adverse variances when you closed some contracts that were meaningful and depressed the margins below the normal rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the answer is no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then the other question is in terms of the -- 2010 outlook for Process, you're looking for down 10 to 20 and we should assume margins come down a bit for Process in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say our -- from a sales standpoint, I'm looking down more in the 10 to 12% and the 20 might be from an order standpoint. I think that's was what confused them last time, I would say that we're going to be down say 10 to 12% right now in sales as I see the Process marketplace in 2010. I think the orders will be down more than that because of just the way this things works but we're working off the backlog and we're starting to have a mix changes. But right now if I'm going to put a forecast down, stake in the ground you're probably looking at 10 to 12% down sales next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And margins for Process?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Will be down. I don't know how far you have based on the mix but they will start cycling down, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Also I think everyone would like to know, I mean do you guys think about a cycle time between orders and sales, your orders were running down 20, now down less than 20 and maybe April better than that. I mean when typically would the orders I mean obviously backlog is an important part. I mean is there a way you think on the average cycle time between orders and sales?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we do. But each business is different. If you take Appliance and Tools the cycle time is extremely fast. If you take a look at Climate it's pretty fast, I mean typically a month to two months, if you take a process that can be anywhere. It gotten its way out to say nine to 12 months now, it's going to work its way back, Bob, I think that it's -- until you get some stability in our order pace in that backlog, we haven't seen a lot of massive cancellations, but we're seeing push outs. So it's going to take us some time to get it to dial that in, it's going to be hard for you. We're not trying to be stubborn here. It's hard for us right now to get a feel for it. It appears to us in talking to Ed Feeney and the Network Power, on the system side, there seems to be right now some stability in the orders. So that tells me we're starting to cycle into maybe a six-month cycle there right now, which is pretty good, so that's a good sign in starting to see some stability there. So we'll see -- I think as we close out this year, we'll have a better view of how things are stabilizing in that regard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just another question is -- another question you mentioned Europe you felt would stay down. I mean in this quarter U.S. was down 19, Europe down 10. I mean where do you see Europe troughing in terms of declines? Is there -- are they just lagging us by six -- three to six months? That type of thing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you're going to see Europe go down 10 to 15%. I think you're going to see the European economy as we look at our own internal forecast and we look at what's going on in Europe right now, you're going to see second half as we go into the next, you're going to start seeing these numbers go down just like we saw in that second quarter for the U.S. 15, 20%.</p>
          <p>Europe does not have -- I'll say it again does not have the financial flexibility that they had before, you have Eastern Europe that is struggling right now because of all the investments and the bad investments in the banks, and you have the Western European economy that don't have the financial flexibility to do short-term things in the economy. It's going to be tough in Europe for a while.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was confused by a question &#x2013; answer you gave earlier, Dave on the Climate --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I get confused too, myself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am confused all the time, man, especially about this market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; to get up there in age so it happens.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It does happen. The in Climate Tech, you said in the official part of the presentation that you had pricing pressure, when you answered a prior question, it seemed like you weren't having price pressure? What's the story?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, in the first half this year, we had some situations we were out of sync between price costs, we are now back in the sync in the second half this year in the price cost situation. And so that will help us in the second half of the year. In the first half of the year, we got hurt by it, and the second half of the year, we will be helped by it. I mean that industry is typically six, nine, 12 month type of pricing and it takes us a lot to get everything back into sync and right now we're going to be back in the sync.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it changes January/February.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. In Feb -- as Walter says our pricing changes more in January and February. And so that's what's going on right now. That's why you heard Lynne say one thing, see you accused me of saying it, Lynne said it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then I said something different which is true, you did catch that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Aren't you surprised at this point in the cycle you don't have more people talking about price-cutting, I mean, we've gone through the earning season, why is that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because as I told the Board, people saw that it did no good in the last down cycle to cut prices. The volumes around the world are bad, the demand is bad. So trying to get an extra two widgets sold right now when your widgets are down 20% is bad to try to cut prices. It doesn't do you any good. So people are being very smart in all parts of this channel and that's a smart way to go and I'm glad to see that because -- and then also as Walter keep pointing out to me every point in the Board meeting is also inflation is coming. And so people are looking out the right eye and seeing inflation is coming, so they're going to be very, very careful here. <mark type="inaudible" /> last time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Final question from me. Why are payables down so much? What's going on there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because our inventory is reducing and our capital is going down. And so you buy less and you pay people less.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are not changing our payment terms, what we're doing is just we're buying a lot less raw material to bring down our inventory, because the dollars of inventory went down plus the output of our materials because of course the sales are down also went down. So you have a double impact on accounts payable. You also have the reduction in capital spending in the quarter that you reduce capital spending that also reduces your payables.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we're getting ready to reduce another $200 million of capital between now and the year end as I said earlier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's all for me. Thanks guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Take care, Bob. I hope to see you soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely, man.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Christopher Glynn with Oppenheimer. Go ahead, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Nice inventory turns there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to clarify on that point. Did, Walter, did you just suggest that the decrementals excluding that impact, it would be running around 20%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, because you can't say one-to-one for that. You have entirely different dollars amount on the numerator than when you multiply it by. What I'm saying is -- are you saying the inventory reduction, I said it was 20% that's on a much smaller dollar than the overall sales volumes was down is much bigger number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You can't average those two, they are different calculations. The impact on absorption on the inventory decline is less than the significant decline in sales volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. And on the process, Dave, it sounds like you're talking about a tough couple of quarters here but decent for the year forecasting -- I'm reading it a pretty strong margin in the fourth quarter, is that kind of the fluctuations in the instrumentation side of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and, then, just lastly --.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Instrumentation and also some restructuring kicking in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And what kind of a read will we get on the Climate Tech from the April orders given the kind of cycle times, the lag there? It almost sound like you could have a pretty vastly looking year-over-year comp in the third quarter with the inventories in the channel pretty cleaned up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you're not going to see much happen here until May. I mean I just look -- I know what the weather was like in April. And so April is done and so I just looking at the weather, I would say that May, June would be the time &#x2013; we're going to have a May, June, July season I think this year and depending on how hot August gets. But there is not a lot of inventory out there, so we have to move very quickly. So I do not expect to see anything happening in August though I do see the U.S. getting their position, the inventories are lean and we're moving with them right now very quickly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As in the retail, you have to keep in mind that the holidays and this year April was different than last year's April, therefore, if you have one less workday, that is 5% in the month. So you have to also look at those things as well. But April heat was not high.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, put that way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I noticed. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Good. Again I want to thank everybody for joining us today. And we're looking forward to seeing people down in Florida at APG. And I appreciate everyone's patience. Right now we're, as I said, we're in a period -- we just entered the storm, not easy reading on what's going to happen relative to the various pieces but the Company is taking the necessary actions. We're trying to keep the balance sheet strong as possible and we're trying to position the Company to truly have a strong recovery when that happens in 2011 and 2012. So, with that I thank everybody and I hope you all have a great rest of the week. Thanks. Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the Emerson second quarter fiscal 2009 results conference call. You may now disconnect. And thank you for using ATT Conferencing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>