<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1321534" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-11-02</date>
    <companies>
      <company>186</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Lynne Maxeiner, Director, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">David N. Farr, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Jeff Sprague</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Steven Winoker</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Terry Darling</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Scott Davis</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Frank Dellaquila</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Deane Dray</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Shannon O'Callaghan</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Julian Mitchell</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Nigel Coe</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Richard Kwas</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">C. Stephen Tusa</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you for standing by. Welcome to the Emerson's Fourth Quarter Fiscal 2010 Results Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>Emerson's commentary and response to your questions may contain forward-looking statements, including the company's outlook for the remainder of the year. Information on factors that could cause actual results to vary materially from those discussed today is available in the Emerson's most recent annual report on Form 10-K as filed with the SEC.</p>
          <p>I'll turn it to our host, Lynne Maxeiner, Director of Investor Relations. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I'm joined today by David Farr, Chairman, Chief Executive Officer and President of Emerson -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Nope. I'm no longer President.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry; have to update my slide &#x2013; Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of Emerson; and Frank Dellaquila, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer.</p>
          <p>Today's call will summarize Emerson's fourth quarter 2010 results. A conference call slide presentation will accompany my comments and it's available in the Investor Relations section of Emerson's corporate website at emerson.com. A replay of this conference call and slide presentation will be available on the website after the call for the next three months.</p>
          <p>I will start with the highlights of the quarter as shown on Page 2 of the conference call slide presentation. Fourth quarter sales were up 14% to 5.8 billion with increases in all five segments, underlying sales growth of 12% in the quarter with all geographic regions resuming growth, gross profit margin of 39.9%, which was up 100 basis points from the prior year quarter, strong operating profit margin of 17.4%, earnings per share of $0.98, up 46% compared to $0.67 in the prior year quarter. This includes the positive impact of $0.23 from divested businesses. Operating cash flow was $1.27 billion and free cash flow was 1.046 billion.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet remains strong and operational efficiency initiatives continue. Our trade working capital as a percent of sales improved to 15.5% from 16.6% in the prior year quarter. Actions taken over the past few years are paying off and we are well positioned for accelerated growth globally.</p>
          <p>Slide 3, the P&amp;L, Again, sales up 14% to $5.841 billion, underlying sales were up 12%, acquisitions added three points and currency subtracted a point. Operating profit of $1.019 billion up 14%, the increase driven by cost reduction benefits and volume leverage. Earnings from continuing operations up 14% to $572 million. Diluted average shares of 757.4 million with 0.6 million shares repurchased for 28 million in the quarter, which leaves you with an EPS from continuing ops of $0.75 cents, up 12%. This includes a $0.04 negative impact from the Chloride acquisition and $0.02 negative impact from Motors being reclassified to discontinued operations, $0.23 cents from the impact from Motors and LANDesk gets you to the EPS of $0.98.</p>
          <p>Slide 4, this is a summary table we had in our press release today that provides additional detail of the impact from the Chloride acquisition and Motors and LANDesk divestitures.</p>
          <p>The next slide, slide 5, underlines sales by geography. In the fourth quarter, the U.S. was up 9%; total international was up 13% with Europe up 15%, Asia up 14%, Latin America up 11%, Canada up 21% and Middle East/Africa up 2%. Again, total underlying sales up 12%, currency subtracting one point and acquisitions adding three points, bringing you to the consolidated sales up 14%.</p>
          <p>For fiscal 2010, the U.S. was up 1% and Europe declined 7%. Asia was up 7%, Latin America down 2%, Canada down 9%, Middle East/Africa down 10%. Total international declined 2% for the year. Total underlying sales were down 1% for the year. Currency added two points and acquisitions added four points, getting you to consolidated sales up 5% for the year. Emerging markets now represents 34% of total sales in 2010.</p>
          <p>Slide 6, some income statement detail, gross profit dollars of 2.331 billion or 39.9% of sales, up 100 basis points from the prior-year quarter, the improvement coming from aggressive cost reduction programs, volume leverage, restructuring benefits and acquisitions. SG&amp;A of 22.5% of sales gets you to operating profit of 1.019 billion or 17.4% of sales. Other deductions net of 160 million which includes lower restructuring of 78 million and higher amortization of 22 million and deal costs of 14 million, gets you to a pre-tax line of 838 million or 14.3% of sales. Taxes in the fourth quarter of 254 million for a tax rate of 30.2%.</p>
          <p>Next slide, the cash flow and balance sheet, operating cash flow of 1.27 billion, down 6% versus a strong Q4 in 2009, our working capital is still positive cash. Capital expenditures of 224 million gets you to a free cash flow of 1.046 billion. Free cash flow conversion in Q4 was 140%. Trade working capital balances at the bottom of the slide show solid improvement in trade working capital to sales ratio, improving to 15.5% of sales in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Slide 8, the business segment P&amp;L. Business segment EBIT of 1.056 billion or 17.6% of sales, up 31% or 230 basis points with benefits from volume leverage, cost containment programs and lower restructuring costs, difference in accounting methods of 53 million, corporate and other up 91 million. We have a negative impact from the increase in stock price and overlap for retention purposes of two stock compensation programs of $50 million and Chloride one-time costs of about $30 million.</p>
          <p>We expect Chloride one-time charges to be at a similar level, 30 million in the first quarter of fiscal 2011. Earnings from continuing ops before interest and taxes of 903 million, interest expense of 65 million gets you to a pre-tax earnings of 838 million.</p>
          <p>Next we'll review individual business segments starting with Process Management. Sales in the quarter up 5% to 1.701 billion, underlying sales were up 5%, acquisitions added a point and currency subtracted a point. By region, the U.S. was up 8%, Asia down 3%, Europe was up 4% and Middle East/Africa down 4%.</p>
          <p>Order rates are strong globally, up over 20% in the trailing three-month average. EBIT dollars of 325 million or 19.1% of sales, up 14%, driven by significant cost containment actions and restructuring benefits, which were partially offset by wage inflation and lower restructuring expense. Backlog at the end of September 2010 was 2.9 billion, an increase of 10% from the prior year. Also, Emerson Process Management Wireless Solutions are successfully operating in more than 1,400 sites globally. We had 76 million in orders booked in fiscal 2010.</p>
          <p>Slide 10, Industrial Automation, sales in the quarter of 1.169 billion, up 23%, underlying sales were up 26%, currency subtracted four points and acquisitions added a point. By region, the U.S. was up 24%, Europe was up 30%, and Asia was up 25%. We've seen broad based growth across businesses and geographies. Capital end markets are recovering and businesses are beginning to spend again. Results for 2009 and 2010 include the hermetic motor business. EBIT dollars of 196 million or 16.3% of sales, up 96% driven by volume leverage, cost reduction benefits and lower restructuring.</p>
          <p>The September 30, 2010, backlog of 691 million increased 80% from the prior year and order trends in the quarter continued to be strong, up more than 20%.</p>
          <p>Next slide, Network Power, sales in the quarter of 1.678 billion, up 23%, underlying sales were up 12%, acquisitions added 11 points. By geography, the U.S. was up 6%, Asia was up 20% and Europe was up 14%.</p>
          <p>Avocent and Chloride contributed 153 million in sales in the quarter. We saw strength in the uninterruptible power supply, precision cooling, embedded computing and power and inbound power businesses. EBIT dollars of 255 million or 15.2% of sales, up 41% with positive impact from leverage, cost reduction benefits, lower restructuring, partially offset by unfavorable price and mix.</p>
          <p>The September 30, 2010, backlog was 1.4 billion, an increase of 33% from the prior year. The Chloride acquisition was completed in the quarter. This acquisition enhances our global reach, product and service technologies and integrated data center management solutions.</p>
          <p>Slide 12, Climate Technologies, sales in the quarter of 1.003 billion, up 10%. Underlying sales were up 11% and currency subtracted a point. By region, the U.S. was up 5%, Europe was up 13% and Asia was up 28%. Strength in our Refrigeration and Commercial businesses was partially offset by a decline in the U.S. residential business. EBIT dollars of 193 million or 19.2% of sales, up 26%. The margin improvement was driven by volume leverage, increased electronics and value-add solutions, benefits from cost containment actions and lower restructuring expense. Geographic balance for Climate Technologies continues to shift internationally. We had 46% of fiscal 2010 sales outside the U.S.</p>
          <p>Slide 13, Tools and Storage, this was formerly called Appliance and Tools. Sales in the quarter of 447 million, up 2%, underlying sales were flat and acquisitions added two points. By region, the U.S. was down 1%, Europe was up 3% and Asia was up 15%. EBIT dollars of 93 million or 20.7% of sales, up 1%, material and wage inflation was offset by cost containment, volume leverage and mix. U.S. consumer demand is still tepid and consumers are still stressed.  We've completed the divestiture of our appliance motors and U.S. commercial and industrial motors businesses, and it creates a leaner and more profitable segment.</p>
          <p>Slide 14, overview of the full year results. 2010 was a very good year for Emerson. Sales for the year of 21.039 billion, up 5%, underlying sales were down 1%, emerging markets were 34% of sales, and international sales were 57%. Nice operating profit margin expansion. We had operating profit of 3.509 billion, or 16.7% of sales. EPS from continuing ops for the full year of 2.60, up 15%. This includes a $0.04 negative impact from Chloride and $0.05 negative impact from the Motors re-class to discontinued operations. Net EPS of 2.84.</p>
          <p>Fiscal 2010 was our 54th consecutive year of increased dividends, and the board of directors voted today to increase the quarterly dividend to $0.345 per share. Strong operating cash flow of 3.292 billion, and record free cash flow of 2.768 billion. We have very good momentum entering fiscal 2010. Orders continue to be strong, and capital goods end markets are improving.</p>
          <p>The next slide. In summary, Emerson executed and delivered solid results in a challenging fiscal 2010 economic environment. We generated high levels of operating cash flow and free cash flow. Our operating profit margin was strong, at 16.7%. Gross profit margin increased 200 basis points to 39.6%. Our restructuring efforts have fundamentally changed the cost structure of the business. We've remixed the business portfolio for higher growth and higher margins, and continued investment in new technologies and next-generation products. Emerson is well positioned as we move to fiscal 2011.</p>
          <p>The current business momentum and global economics are favorable. And we will continue to make key investments in new products and technologies and in emerging markets. We're increasing incremental investments by 40 million in emerging markets in people, technology, new products and research.</p>
          <p>For fiscal 2011, we expect underlying sales up 7% to 10%; operating profit margins, 17.2% to 17.5%; operating cash flow in the range of 3.4 to 3.5 billion; and restructuring cost of 90 to 100 million.</p>
          <p>I know many of you have asked me about the business segment restatements for the quarters in fiscal 2011. We're working on those, and will work to get those out sometime this week for you.</p>
          <p>So with that, I'll turn it over to David Farr.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Lynne. I welcome everybody on the phone call today. I appreciate everyone joining us. I also want to thank all the people across Emerson, the board, especially the OCE, the business leaders and the operation presidents, for what I call a great job in 2010, a tremendous performance relative to operations, relative to the restructuring that's been undertaken the last couple years. We have continued to invest. At the same time, we've restructured, both internally and in our growth programs. We've done acquisitions, and now we're executing along all the things that we've been working on for the last couple years.</p>
          <p>As you know, our underlying order pace has been strong as we continue to expand in key emerging markets and key technologies, and our underlying sales have improved the last couple quarters, from 7% in the third quarter, to 12% in this fourth quarter, and our total year was basically flat. So, from my perspective, we have momentum &#x2013; pretty good momentum as we leave this year going into 2011.</p>
          <p>Our operating profit margins, our GP margins, are all set at record levels right now. And we are set to go to 40% plus GP, and we are set to go to 17-plus percent operating margin, through all the tremendous work as we restructure the company, as we made investments, and as we discontinued businesses and divested businesses.</p>
          <p>As I look at our free cash flow, we set a record level this year at $2.8 billion. And over the last two years, we had set a target to exceed over $5 billion, which we did meet, at 5.4 billion, over the last two years, which allowed us to do close to $4 billion of acquisitions.</p>
          <p>We paid back close to $2 billion of dividends. We did share repurchase over the last two years, around 800 million. We divested companies around $800 million. We have strengthened the balance sheet, both from the standpoint of liquidity and capability, and we have the ability to do what we need to do in the next several years. And I feel very good about where we sit at this point in time.</p>
          <p>The restructuring programs which we initiated as the downturn happened in the middle of 2008 are basically done. We still have a few left we have to get done, but we will be dialing these back to our normal level, based on what we've been undertaking the last couple years.</p>
          <p>We started to invest. As you know, we started investing incrementally at higher levels in February of 2010. The OCEs made the decision, in addition to our normal investment profile, that we have increased our investment in strategic areas, and we put $40 million on top of what we normally do at the $15 million level at the corporate strategic programs. They've been identified. They've already been started. The business leaders worked with Craig Ashmore and the OCE to identify these programs, and they are being funded. And they will &#x2013; they're all about making investments in emerging markets, in technology and new products, and investments that would eventually been done, but now, we're going to pull them forward and get them done this year, in early 2012, to make sure that we have a stronger underlying growth profile as we come out of this recovery and continue to grow.</p>
          <p>I think this is a strong indication that we feel very good about where we sit today, and we feel that with our increased profitability, our record levels of margins and GP and the cash flow, that the time has come to step up our investments and to accelerate our growth rate.</p>
          <p>You'll remember that in February, of this year, we talked about the five-year profile would be slower because the economies will be slower. I still believe that. But with the incremental investments and the restructuring that we've done at this company, I now believe that we have a chance to slightly exceed 7% for the next five years. And this investment we're doing right now and improved profitability and the globalization of the company is allowing us to do this.</p>
          <p>As I look at where we're driving the company, we're going to be somewhere in the 40%, 45% emerging markets. Our international exceeds 65% in the next five years. We have a very strong foundation. And in talking to the board today, we're talking about accelerating our investments because I think the visibility is there. I believe that we can see what's going on in this world today and we know that we need to take the initiative to grow and to invest. And we're doing that where we believe the growth opportunities are in the markets around the world and the technologies. And we're making those investments. It's very clear to me. There's not uncertainty, I know what's going. And we're making those investments. And we're going to put that investment out there to grow this company and improve the profitability.</p>
          <p>If you look at what's going on inside the company right now, we're sitting at record levels of cash and margins. Our free cash flow per share this year has set a record level at $3.65 per share &#x2013; 3.65. That is a value driver of this company. How we generate cash and returns. And it will set records, again, I think, as we look at 2011.</p>
          <p>Right now we're in the mode of execution. Restructuring's done. The big acquisitions we've undertaken the last couple years, we're now in the mode of executing. The divestitures, we've got some big ones done. We're now in the mode of settling the company down. We have one small acquisition &#x2013; divestiture, we'll do this year, one divestiture around $100 million. And I would look at our acquisition profile right now, somewhere probably around the $500 million, $600 million, $700 million. Not a big number. We're about executing what we have accomplished already. We have restructured. We have positioned the company.</p>
          <p>We are now focusing on investments in strategic areas for growth because we know the GDP and around the world is going to be slow. We know that it's not going to accelerate fast. The U.S. government, the European governments need their own restructuring. They have wasted money. They've overspent. They need to restructure not only their cost structure but their balance sheet before growth will return in these mature markets.</p>
          <p>Companies like Emerson have already done it. We're positioned and so we need to invest for pockets of growth around the world. Visibility is very clear to us where we need to put our money and we're making those bets right now. So as I look at where we sit today, I want to thank the board. I want to thank all the business leaders, the OCE, the operating executives. They have executed over the last two years. The company's foundation is strong. We have the growth potential. We are all about accelerating growth in 2011 and trying to control our own destiny and drive value for our shareholders and for the people that have invested in this company over the years.</p>
          <p>I feel very good about where we sit today. I feel very good about what we're going to see in 2011. Clearly there's always issues that can surface at any point in time, but I believe that Emerson is well positioned to have extraordinary growth over the next 12 to 18 months, set record levels of profitability, set record levels of cash flow, set record levels of returns for our shareholders and deliver for what we've invested in. And that's what it's all about. It's execution. It's execution. It's execution. And there's nothing else that we have to do at this point in time.</p>
          <p>So with that I want to turn it over to answer questions and I'm sure there's plenty of questions out there. But, again, I want to thank everybody around the company that had an extraordinary year. Thank you very much for what you've done. You've positioned this company to really be able to perform and have a great 2011. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And our first question comes from Jeff Sprague with Vertical Research Partners. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Jeff. What can I do for you today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm wondering if you got out and had a chance to vote, also?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I voted twice already. I'm flying my dad here to vote here, too. Of course I voted, I believe we're going to have a change in direction relative to what makes this country great and stop wasting money and spending money in the wrong places.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Amen to that. So my question is really on the balance now between profitability and growth. Clearly you have done a lot to get the portfolio into great shape. Profitability and cash flows obviously always central to what Emerson's about. But do we think about trading a little bit of profitability for growth as we move forward in the slower growth environment? And I'm thinking about it kind of implicitly, looking at the guidance construct, that maybe suggests incremental margins are in the 20s next year. Some of that's kind of the noise from Chloride and the like on the top line. But just give us some color on how to kind of put that in perspective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think that's a very good question, Jeff. What's going through our mind right now at the OCE level and the board level, is that we clearly are looking at a lower growth environment, particularly 2011, as there's a global stimulus that's pulled back and people have to seek underlying growth. We have made the decision to increase our, what I would call incremental investments both in &#x2013; for people and technology.</p>
          <p>As I look at the company today, and we drove the company, we could drive &#x2013; we probably could get to an 18% operating margin pretty quickly. I feel that would be a mistake. I fundamentally believe I would like to see us make investments right now in particular in some of the emerging markets where the growth opportunities are there for us and if we get ahead of this game plan, given the strength of our financials, I would look &#x2013; expect our flow through profitability this year to be more in the 25% to 30% range. We've been running ahead of that. I think it's important right now that we invest at this point in time to try to figure out how to &#x2013; not have a 5% or 5.5% underlying growth rate going forward for the next five years, but to make it more like 7% or a 7.5%. And I believe we have identified through our programs this year, strategy assessments, unique opportunities.</p>
          <p>And that's why the OCE decided to put the $40 million on the table and get on with it. We've already started investing the money. So I think it's &#x2013; we are well-positioned to do that. And if we get the growth, our profitability obviously will continue to grow with that. And I think we'll do pretty well. So that is exactly what's going on. You're right on the mark there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how do you feel about price/cost in 2011? Did you finish up here in the green? Are you getting some price -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We finished up green, slightly green this year. We see material inflation as a negative right now. It's pulling back. I think right now what we see the year, it's going to be plus or minus 0.25%. We've had a couple of very good years relative to price/cost relationship. There's a lot of commodities moving around. It's sort of extraneous right now, we have some component shortages still. I feel that we'll be very close to being zero. But if I was going to put a mark down right now, I'd say it could be plus 0.25 to minus 0.25, sort of in that range right there. But pretty close to that zero level.</p>
          <p>But clearly something that we're working on very carefully right now, because there is definitely inflation coming at us. And as the U.S. government continues to do its quantitative easing, that will create even more inflation, in particular around the emerging markets, which is really our key growth area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I could just sneak one more in -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>IA looks great obviously on a year-over-year basis, but sequentially, it was off the charts, too. And just wondering if something in particular really kicked into gear there in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple things happened there. Jean-Paul and his operation guys really got hit hard, as you well know. And they took a lot of restructuring head-on, early on in 2008 and 2009. The volume has started coming back for them, Jeff, and they are really leveraging. And I give a lot of credit to Jean-Paul and his team, because this is a very European-based company, are under that. And they took these cost structures right on, and that's what you're seeing.</p>
          <p>So I mean, there's nothing fun or games going on. There's nothing unique. It's just pure solid execution. And I'm &#x2013; and Jean-Paul came to me for some growth investments. And we are giving him the people he wants to invest in for his emerging markets and &#x2013; because of pure execution. They did a great job.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks a lot, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It looks like a couple people got cut off. So you may have to call back in on the questions, folks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our next question comes from the line of Steven Winoker with Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, or good afternoon, actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Steve. Thank you. It's great to hear &#x2013; depends where you are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it does depend. I know I hit some part of the world that way. Anyway, listen, just trying to get a little better handle on the whole price/cost thing that you talked about with Jeff just now, particularly in Industrial Automation, where you actually saw it go the other way. And given where margins already are, where do you see the biggest risk across the business units there? And what are you doing on price specifically? I know Charlie and company have done a lot &#x2013; have put a lot of effort into that. Are you seeing continued traction in your ability to get price, regardless of the material side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer is yes. We are continuing to have positive traction relative to price, and the biggest issue we see right now, we have some underlying commodities that are taking off. Steel is back down, which is good news, but copper is now running close to $4. We have an electronic component issue going on from our perspective. So I think there's a lot of moving parts going on.</p>
          <p>And as I look at it right now, I think we're going to end up with slightly positive price this year, and a slightly negative net material inflation, and we're going to end up probably pretty close to zero. But the commodities are the biggest issue right now for us.</p>
          <p>From our standpoint, the labor, and those cost structures, we are in very good shape, and the productivity programs are there. Hence, we're investing in capital right now to offset that type of cost. But my issue right now is we're starting to see some price/cost issues, or cost issues on commodities and certain electronic components, and certain other components which are a little bit short in supply.</p>
          <p>So we are able to get price. Charlie's programs have really helped us, but in this tactical mode right now, we're going to have to get a little bit of positive price. But we have not seen an accelerator get out of control. But I'm very nervous about that issue, because of all the quantitative easing that's going on in the United States and other parts of the world. But I think it's under control right now. I feel pretty good about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And what are your comments around investment for next year, which are mostly it sounds like expense R&amp;D based, labor-based? How about on the capital side? How are you thinking about that? I know those have already been in place for awhile.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Our capital spending is going to be &#x2013; it'll be close to $600 million. You notice that our capital spending did accelerate in the fourth quarter. And the reason for that is we were able to accelerate some of the new product initiatives, and we clearly wanted to start getting ahead of some of our emerging market investments. So we had to make some investments there.</p>
          <p>I would expect us to spend $600 million, plus or minus $20 million, next year again. And it's already underway. And it's going to be primarily in what I would say capital investments for productivity. So it will be equipment, to drive up productivity. And also, we are making some capacity investments in emerging markets, and we'll be making those investments, and just basically around our new product areas and in particular, around our emerging markets at this point in time. And that's where the investments are going.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Any particular business units there that you'd highlight?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think &#x2013; I think you're, I mean, there's nothing in particular. There's nothing out of whack from that standpoint. I don't have any &#x2013; there's not a big compressor of expansion. There's not a big process expansion. You're going to see pretty normal capital by each of the businesses. And just like the restructuring, the restructuring has gone through its way, and there's nothing extraordinary going on there either. So it's going to be pretty normal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>May I sneak in one last one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As long as it's quick go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, just Q1 color. Any thoughts around Q1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not really. I mean, at this point in time, it'll be the easiest comparisons relative to our growth. It will &#x2013; we do have, as Lynne mentioned, Chloride. We still have some underlying costs we have to amortize. I think you said around $30 million?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>30 million in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the first quarter. And from that perspective, that's going to come through. We have the close-out of our performance share base this quarter. We're paying that off. And so I think it's going to be a good quarter, but it will be a toughest quarter for us, I think, to deliver from the standpoint of a lot of moving parts still going on. But still good momentum, as I go in the quarter. But nothing really other than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't manage quarter-to-quarter. We sort of manage as a year now, as you know that, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we get that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Terry Darling with Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Dave. Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Terry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm wondering, first on a bigger picture item, if you might comment on what you're seeing in the U.S. shorter-cycle businesses? I think a lot of folks were surprised by the strength in the ISM. And I guess I'm wondering your views on U.S. in general, but specifically, on your shorter-cycle businesses, do you think that some folks are trying to get ahead of price increases that might be coming because of this raw material dynamic? And did you see the kind of acceleration through October that the ISM suggested others saw?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we did not. From my perspective, the short-cycle business in the U.S. is going to be very challenging.</p>
          <p>Where we're seeing the investments going on are the capital-related, where people like us had really backed off capital spending. We're seeing that type of investment coming in from a standpoint of productivity or capacity, issues where people had scaled it back. They don't want to bring &#x2013; hire people at this point in time, because they're a little bit uncertain what type of growth they're going to be looking at in 2011. So I am very cautious and nervous about the short-cycle businesses in the U.S.</p>
          <p>From my perspective, our divestiture of the appliance motors and controls was pretty good timing-wise, because I think that business had a nice little pick-up and I think it's going to struggle next year.</p>
          <p>From my perspective right now, I don't see much growth in the U.S. in the short-cycle stuff. I see a pretty good growth next year in our industrial capital-related businesses, and I believe we'll have a good year, both in the U.S. and in Europe, as those companies invest again coming out of this recovery &#x2013; coming out of &#x2013; the recovery takes hold.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I'm wondering just kind of a guidance question. The interest expense and other deduction item of 670 to 700, can you take us through the changes and the pieces within that number that you're thinking about for '11 versus '10? Interest expense?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we come back to you? We'll talk to you on the phone. Let Frank look at that for a second and talk about it, and then we'll come back on you &#x2013; stay on the phone, we'll answer that question. Let's give Frank a second to dig through that, okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, maybe then just quickly. The 40 million of incremental emerging market investment real quick. Should we think of that as a one-timer in 2011? Or should we think of that as ongoing? And any color in terms of where you may be over-weighting that investment by division?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For instance, I think the $40 million will hit us this year. I think we'll probably continue part of that next year. My fundamental belief is, we'll see the growth, so they'll be able to cover this as we move into 2012. I believe the OCE will say, let's keep part of it going and help them as they get into 2012, but I expect that the divisions will get the growth, or the businesses will get the growth, and they'll be able to cover this incrementally as they go into 2012. But I most likely wouldn't be surprised, if I invest 40 million this year, if I don't invest another 15 or 20 million next year on top of that. We'll have room to do that.</p>
          <p>Primarily the big dollars, or the biggest areas, you could imagine where they're going to be. They're obviously in Process, Industrial Automation, and Network Power are the three big areas. Every business is getting it, but this will run through the corporate P&amp;L, the corporate line. But it's primarily what I see in the strategic areas, where we have unique technologies and we want to get ahead of the power curve, and we want to really push forward right now as the market &#x2013; I think the window's open, and the people that take aggressive actions right now will succeed in the next 12 to 18 months, and I want to be one of them.</p>
          <p>We'll answer the question. Frank will work that up and he'll come back to you before you go off the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes in from Scott Davis with Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So a couple things, first on Process, a couple great quarters in a row and in many ways that business has come back a lot faster than probably most of us thought it would.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Faster than I did. I was wrong on that. Yes, you're exactly right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's certainly different than past cycles for sure. When you look out to 2011 a little bit I would assume that there's some mix shift to more project-related business. Or do you still think it's going to be more the day-by-day higher margin business that you've had the last couple quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we're seeing right now is the orders have expanded. We are starting to see medium, large and larger projects booking, Scott. And so it has actually started to shift. What we're going to see early on in the first half of this year I think will be more the productivity, the MRO as people are investing and improving the plants at this point in time. The smaller projects, the incremental capacity, which are smaller projects, they're starting to hit right now.</p>
          <p>As we leave and move to the second half of 2011 and move out towards 2011 you're going to start seeing the larger projects start hitting us at the sales line. The orders should accelerate this year because of the larger projects which are now being bid on and I think will continue to go forward, but they won't really hit our sales level until late 2011, early 2012. Right now it's going to be medium, small, small capacities and MRO-type stuff. So our profitability &#x2013; what we're focusing on right now is &#x2013; I would expect us &#x2013; our underlying profitability in the Process business to improve next year. And we are going to have accelerated investments in Process both internally and then the money I put on the table here because I'm setting up for the growth in 2012 and 2013 in that business. As you know, it's a very profitable business for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Did that help you? Did it help?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, it helps a lot. A lot of it is just timing, right? Just trying to figure out when the big stuff comes in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And none of us &#x2013; we're not that smart, Scott. I can't &#x2013; I was wrong in this cycle and these guys have done a very good job here. And I thought the MRO investment would have come earlier, now it came later. So I &#x2013; it's a tough call, it's timing. But we're back, we're strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I totally understand. Now I want to come back to the earlier question on Industrial Automation because the incremental margins this quarter were just so phenomenal. And I can see this being kind of difficult for those of us on this side of the world to model out in 2011 as it relates to incrementals. Plus you've got hermetic motors. How &#x2013; I'm kind of begging for modeling help here, how do we -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Begging. Scott is begging?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm groveling for modeling help. How do we &#x2013; how do we even think about incremental margins in 2011 in this business? Or how do we at least think about modeling a &#x2013; with hermetic or without hermetic? What's the new normal, I guess is the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hermetic is not going to have a huge impact relative to the &#x2013; you think about the size of the whole IA area, the hermetic will have a little impact. But in reality what you're seeing right now is this business and I'm trying &#x2013; do you know what it peaked at? Can you help me what it peaked in say 2008? What'd that margin peak at in IA? Lynne or &#x2013; can you guys tell me? I think we're going to go back and we are going to go by the peak of 2008 and -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The peak was 15.6 in '07.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're going to see this business come up &#x2013; going to be coming up to that 17%, 18% range. Again, I want to give credit to Jean-Paul. Jean-Paul and his operation team really &#x2013; some very significant cost restructuring went underway. And so I &#x2013; they peaked at say 16%, I really believe these guys are going to be going into the 17%, 18% range here as we move into 2011. I don't know what the &#x2013; 16? Okay, but it's not going to get that high next year. So I think you're going see continuing to go towards that, but the model number you should be thinking about for this business is 17%, 18%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which is two or three years to get there, but that's &#x2013; mentally I think Jean-Paul has made some fundamental changes to the cost structure. Hermetic motors does help a little bit. But that's not going to drive the 17%, 18%. It's what Jean-Paul and the operational team did. A little volume and significant restructuring and these guys hit it and boy, they hit it well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, clearly that's structural shift there for sure. Okay. Well, look, I'll pass it on to the next guys. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, and any time you want to beg, just send me an e-mail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Deane Dray with Citi Investment Research. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Deane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One of the pleasant surprises this quarter was Europe. And it wasn't that long ago there was a lot of hand wringing going on whether Greece was going to create a domino effect. And here you put up 15% core revenue growth. So just take us through the mix, geographically and then the outlook for 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think &#x2013; we've talked about this, Deane, and you've &#x2013; I think you've been here when we were talking about Europe. Europe went through a period here where they &#x2013; from the standpoint of under-invested and then when the euro got weak and you saw Germany take off and you see some of the investment profiles, both coming out of Europe into Africa and the Middle East we're starting to see that benefit right now. We knew it was coming and I believe we're going to have a very good year. I wouldn't be surprised if Europe doesn't outgrow the U.S. next year. I make crazy calls like this all the time in my business. And Emerson's business, I wouldn't be surprised if Europe does not outgrow the U.S. next year. It's because Europe is working very hard in the industrial side to restructure. They are actually ahead of the U.S. from that perspective.</p>
          <p>You think about the government standpoint and therefore you're going to start &#x2013; I think you're going to see some of the growth coming out of Europe into the emerging market. And we benefit from that, from the Process world, the Industrial Automation World and the Network Power world. So I feel that we're going to have pretty good underlying growth for Europe next year because of what the countries have done and then what our business has done. And the unique businesses we're in. So that's what's going to happen. I think it was a pleasant surprise and I feel pretty good that I &#x2013; like I said, I think Europe could actually outperform the U.S. next year in underlying growth or be close to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful. And then just over in Network Power, one of the numbers that jumps out is the 33% increase in backlog. How much of that is organic? Was there a contribution from Avocent and Chloride?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The &#x2013; so I'm assuming some of the backlog is Chloride in there -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe it is. We report full backlog.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We report back &#x2013; so some of it would be, I couldn't tell you some of it, but the business is starting to pick back up. I would expect the Network Power business in particular to start picking back up in the Liebert Chloride side in early 2011. Just bringing up the calendar years, 2011, the early stages of backlog right now, are more in the embedded power and computing area where the growth has been strong, The component shortages has been a big issue for us. That backlog is built there. But overall, the momentum has shifted in Network Power both in Jay Geldmacher's side and then obviously at Ed Feeney's side and Chloride coming in helps us. But that's not a huge backlog business. But it's definitely, we see momentum shifting there which is very good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from the line of Shannon O'Callaghan with Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Hey, just a question on Network Power first of all. I mean, good margins there in the quarter. Can you give us an update on the Chloride integration and how we should think about Network Power profitability kind of through the quarters of '11, as you bring that in on a full-term basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The integration of Chloride is going extremely well. And from my perspective, there's not going to be a whole lot of restructuring in that business this year because we're right now working from the standpoint of trying to understand what we can do and not do. And I think from our standpoint we're looking at a period that restructuring would be more in 2012, 2013. I would expect the profitability of this segment would start to improve quarter by quarter by quarter by quarter as the underlying business improves.</p>
          <p>So I would expect this business to continue to improve profitability-wise. I think as I've talked about it, I think that in total the Network Power business is moving towards that 15%, 16% level. And I think that these guys are going to make progress each quarter this year as we go forward here. And I look at the Network Power business, I think they're going to have a very good 2011 as they move into that 15+% which we've never hit. And so we're not going to quite get there. But it's still going to be a nice improvement as we go forward here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sequentially into 1Q as you bring it in full term, I mean do you expect them to decline a little bit sequentially from where you were in 4Q?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Sequential they're going to decline and then we should start seeing improvements as we go forward through the year. The Chloride impact obviously is going be there for the year. And Chloride is a &#x2013; typically is a lower margin. And we have a good &#x2013; we have obviously the amortization going on there, I forgot about that. So it's going to take us a while to get back up to that 15. But I think this segment is going to be a 15% segment again. And we'll probably be more like in the &#x2013; we're going to be approaching that by the time we &#x2013; end of the fiscal year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we should be approaching 15%. And we go down and we start working our way back up. But these guys are doing the right things. And then we're going to do restructuring, more in Chloride and Network Power in 2012. So that's where I sit right now for that business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just on some of the Resi businesses, the inventory correction in HVAC and then the Storage business kind of weak. How do you see those playing out as we move through the fiscal year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said earlier, the consumer businesses right now are really going to struggle in 2011. The consumer is still stressed. They're going through deleveraging. The job market's still going to be very challenging for them right now. And so I think that the residential consumer business, for our AC business is not going to be all that strong next year. We had the issue that there were some incentives put in place to help. But I think that will be a challenge for them. I do not think the Tools and Storage business will see much growth next year.</p>
          <p>Discretionary spending is not all that exciting, relative to the consumer at this point in time. So I'm looking at moderate growth, low single-digit-type of growth out of that space. Our capital guys are going see us &#x2013; are going to be the improvement. And what we're investing there is in the Tool and Storage area is basically some of the emerging market growth that we need to start investing in for them. But that's not going to be a big driver of growth. It's not going to hurt us or not going to help us. And I would expect that profitability to be up a little bit next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Julian Mitchell with Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Julian, can we hold off? Frank is now ready to answer that question that I &#x2013; can't remember who's asked that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Terry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was Terry who asked that question. So Julian, just stay put for one second. Frank, why don't you go ahead and answer that question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hello. I believe the question was on the last chart, the interest expense and other deductions was 630 this year and the range we gave of 670 to 700. Basically we expect a modest decline in interest expense as we work off some of the acquisition debt, a decline as well in restructuring on the order of 15 or 20 million, and then we've got about 80 to 100 million going the other way, which is essentially the result of the acquisitions, namely Fluoride, higher amortization and then some of the one-time items like the valuation of backlog and things of that nature. So that gets us to the range of about 670 to 700.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. And if you have any other questions on that, you can follow up with Lynne. Okay, Julian. Your point, Julian. It's your floor. Julian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello? Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, Julian. It's your floor. Thanks for holding off. We wanted to get back on that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, of course. In terms of the organic growth outlook for a 7 to 10% range for the year ahead, just when I look at your 12% that you did in the quarter just finished, it sounds like you're quite positive on Europe for the year ahead. The growth rates that Asia and Latin America put up in the low teens don't seem crazy versus the GDP growth expectations there. So I just wondered which region, is it really all in the U.S. where you think you're going to see a slowdown over the next sort of nine months versus the 9% underlying growth you had in Q4?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think Middle East is not going to come back very &#x2013; it's going to be kind of slow. I think U.S. will still grow, but I'm concerned about what level we're going to see in growth. I think a lot of our customers right now are looking to invest outside of the United States. Clearly, if we have continued momentum in orders, Julian, I mean it would be clear that maybe we have more upside in our underlying sales growth. But from my perspective right now, we've had strong orders, I am also very concerned about what's going to happen in the U.S. and I could be wrong relative to Europe, but I feel that it behooves us right now to obviously push internally, but also be very cautious in what we think we can do underlying growth.</p>
          <p>I mean statistically if you look at it right now, and look where we're coming out of it, it should be a strong double-digit &#x2013; I mean a double-digit number. It should be more than 10% as you're pointing out, but I want to see us get some months and a quarter or two behind us before we say okay, let's make that 10 or 12%. I mean it just &#x2013; there are things that could go wrong. There are people, as you well know, said that 2011 is going to be a lot stronger than 2010. Well, there's a lot of people right now saying 2011 is going to be weaker than 2010. So I want to be very cautious. We have positioned ourselves and things looking good, and we could be stronger, but I also want to be very cautious. It behooves me to be cautious from that standpoint just so people don't get ahead of me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And in terms of the cost growth, you mentioned obviously some CapEx moving up, in terms of things like head count or R&amp;D or specific, say, sales force expansion programs in different regions, can you give any more color on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, our investment, for instance, in the $40 million, part &#x2013; we will be hiring 1,000 people. And these will be high-end salespeople, marketing people, technology people. And they'll be going around the world from that perspective. That's just focusing on technology and sales and marketing. And from my perspective, our hiring &#x2013; we are increasing our head count at this point in time, in particular outside the United States, in particular outside Western Europe. And so the investments you're going to see from a capital standpoint and a technology investment are all increasing. As a ratio, if you look at our capital spending, I think we'll be somewhere between 2.5% and 2.6% next year, so we're going to be very tight.</p>
          <p>There's nothing that I need to make a major investment. If I look at our technology investment, we're probably a tenth, within a tenth of what we did this year. A lot of this is emerging markets. It's a lower-cost type of structure. So there's nothing crazy, but it's going to be a tenth higher here, a tenth higher here, two-tenths higher here. It's all about investing. And we have the margin room because we actually did a lot of aggressive restructuring and it gives us the capability of doing that. And so that's where we are right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. And good call on the capital, Julian. Congratulations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Nigel Coe with Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>David, good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Nigel. How you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm good, thanks. Just what &#x2013; obviously you're going to provide a lot more color on the segment forecasts in February next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But I wonder would you &#x2013; are you prepared to give us a bit more color in terms of how you expect the five segments to play out versus that 7% to 10% range next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you say that question again, Nigel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, any color on in terms of how the five segments will play out versus the 7 to 10% range?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, I'll give you &#x2013; I'm not going to give you specific numbers right now, but clearly if you look at Industrial Automation, you look at Process, you look at Network Power. Those three segments right there will be the strong growers. Climate Technology will have the issue relative to the North America business, which was a huge grower this year. And now they have to overcome that. And so, from my perspective Climate Technologies growth is going to be Europe, Latin America and Asia-Pacific; and that'll be, that one will be down, I believe, this year versus last year. And the drivers are definitely going to be Industrial, Network Power and Process. I think they'll all end up being, in my opinion, double, 10% plus at Process, Network Power and Industrial Automation before the year's out. And the Climate and Tools will be low to medium single-digit type of growth rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And clearly, the order rates, the process implied double-digit growth pretty soon, do you think that happens as soon as 1Q?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think it goes back to the conversation that I had, I can't remember if it was Deane Dray or Scott Davis asked on the Process, I think it was Scott. What we're starting to book right now, Nigel, are some of the medium and medium-sized projects which will not start executing until later this year or early next year. So I think you're going to see the underlying improvement maybe high single digits, maybe it sneaks over to 10%. But you're going to see this build as the year goes on, but still, given the restructuring and what the mix of business, it should be a very good business segment for us this year, as you can imagine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then one more for me; you've given the pre-tax margin range but not a post-tax margin range. Is there any variability in the tax line this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the tax rate is going to be around 30%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have nothing extraordinary. Obviously the pressure is upward based on what's going on around the world right now, and hopefully with the right election and the right focus on restructuring corporate tax rates, we pay a lot of taxes as you well know. I hope we'll get a more balanced tax rate for us going forward. But we're going to be paying around 30%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the number to use.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from the line of Rich Kwas with Wells Fargo Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Rich. How are you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Two quick ones; electronics components, you talked about that as a problem earlier in the year, it's still there, other companies have talked about it. Do you see relief in sight here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not yet. We still have some issues with IGBTs, we have some issues in some of the components coming out of Japan. The capacity's taking longer to come on board. And I don't think the yields have gone well. So we are still seeing some shortages, and that's not a good sign. That will obviously create a cost issue for me as we try, I have to pay premiums to get those things. I thought this would be really stabilizing by now and actually seeing an improvement. My gut now tells me, based on what I'm hearing from my people, it'll probably be early 2011, the calendar of 2011, before we see some stability there, Rich. And that's not &#x2013; I don't &#x2013; that is not a good thing. I think our suppliers did not do a good job getting ready for this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. That's helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I treated my customers this way, my global top ten customers, they'd be on my door in about two nanoseconds. They'd be camped out, I guarantee it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay, great. Thanks. And then on, second on Process, just a housekeeping question. Fourth quarter margins declined from third quarter, you usually see a sequential uptick. Anything going on there? I know Q3 was very strong so was it just a comp and Q3 was very strong? Or was there a mix issue in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we had a big pick-up in currency mix in the third quarter and there was a currency transaction that helped us close to $19, $20 million. That helped us. We knew this was going to come. And so it has flowed through, the dollar, the European currencies moved around. That helped is in the third quarter. So that really helped that margin. The 20%, I think we had 20% in the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the fourth quarter it was like 19.1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>19.1, okay, there is nothing extraordinary. You're right, sequentially they would normally improve, but because of that currency impact in the third quarter, there's nothing funny or weird going on there, just sometimes these currency things hit you or something like that, nothing unusual.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our final question comes from the line of Steve Tusa with JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you hear me okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I can. Where are you calling from?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm calling from Chicago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chicago, okay. In a car or taxi? What're you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm huddled in the corner of this kind of like phone booth thing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I apologize -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you want to, I'm going to get my GPS on you. We'll send a SCUD missile up there or something, okay? If you're close to my backyard, I can get you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just trying to snoop around, figure out what's going on. But I guess I'll take your word &#x2013; I guess I'll take your word for it today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. What's up, Steve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, a question on Climate from me. Your fiscal year has had a lot of stuff going on, given you would have seen the benefit from the R22 channel loading at the end of last year. So I'm just curious, what was your Resi business &#x2013; for the year, what was your U.S. Resi business? Where did that finish from a growth perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our U.S. Resi business for the year because we have a very strong replacement market. I would say we're up 10%, 12% in the U.S. The first thing about what's going on there, was a good year for us. And obviously, I think we're going to be facing a much more challenging U.S. business as we go into 2011.</p>
          <p>There's a lot of things going on. As you well know, you know this industry extremely well, there's been a shift going on. Obviously the incentives have disappeared, from the government standpoint. And I think you're going to see this fourth quarter here, this calendar quarter is going to be tough as our customers look at maybe doing some inventory reduction, which will hurt us. I think as we get into the calendar, or the calendar year 2011, we could see some growth return. But I think it's going to be very challenging for us on the residential side, after a very good year this year. And -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So you did see those replacement compressors grow pretty fast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So people are actually not just letting their system sit there or buying window units or fans, or going without air conditioning?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. No. We have good &#x2013; and I think we're going to have some pretty good replacement business again in the first part of the year. But I think the underlying &#x2013; the housing market's not good. The upgrades in the housing's not good right now. I think there was some build-ups. So I'm expecting some, what I would say, some pretty tough comps for us as we move into the first part of 2011 for the Climate guys.</p>
          <p>But on the positive side, we're seeing the Refrigeration business, the Non-Res business, the Container business, and the Global businesses doing much better. So the residential side struggled, but we're seeing the other side improve. So it'll be an interesting year. I think the Climate guys could be surprising to me. I'd say they'd be low, medium, underlying growth rates for the year. They could surprise me, because of the other businesses coming back. But the residential's tough.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do your guys tell you anything about the demand destruction from the R-410A high-priced systems? I mean, if those systems came down dramatically in cost, do you think that would help drive people to go back to replacing more of the systems, as opposed to just buying a compressor? Is it really &#x2013; obviously, since they're replacing a compressor, there is a cost issue, versus what they used to do, which is just replace. Am I looking at that the right way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there's no doubt about it. Yeah, we do talk about it. It's not something I'm going to publicly talk about, but there's no doubt about it. I think the biggest issue to me, and I've been involved in this business quite long &#x2013; is the size. I think the astronomical size of the new units is a big problem. The technology they used, is they made them bigger. And I can tell you right now, many people cannot fit them into the house or outside. They just don't have the space. They need to figure out how to get the efficiency without making them bigger. Our compressor is not bigger, as we move to efficiency. But for some reason, as they made &#x2013; as the air conditioning guys and the heating guys made these things so much larger. You've seen them, Steve, they're massive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I mean -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So two more quick ones. First, if we went back to R22, would that be an impact? And then second of all, how are you thinking about price increases to your compressor customers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, for many people on the phone, they probably don't understand what you're talking about, going back to R22. I personally don't think it'll have an impact on us per se, the units will be sold. But I hope the government does not go back to R22. We made the decision to go forward with relative to energy efficiency and a change in the refrigerant, and I think going back is a big mistake at this point in time. That's my opinion as a person.</p>
          <p>I don't think that, on the pricing standpoint it's all commodity-driven. Right now, is if the price of copper, the price of aluminum, the prices of those components continue to increase, we're going to have to pass some increases on. We're working with our customers. We know we have this issue relative to the &#x2013; already the costs going higher because of efficiencies. I mean, the government's passed these efficiency standards. As you know, we have one coming again in 2015, which we really don't need. But they're going to pass another one. And the OEMs right now are struggling with this issue from our standpoint. And that's why we're investing in the electronics area, to try to figure out how to get the efficiencies without making these units larger and more costly. It's a big issue for the industry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, and then one more. Has the consensus look about right for the first quarter? You usually give us some color on the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I haven't really looked at it. I really have not looked at consensus, Steve, to be honest. Typically, who knows what's going on in there? I think it will be an interesting quarter, from the standpoint, it should be an easier comp at the top line. But as I say, we have other things flowing through there. So we'll try to give some more color, and then what we might do is look at our next order release, and I'll try to look at that, Steve, and put some input in that, okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Why did you guys release orders last month? Earlier this month?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's two reasons. First of all, I asked Lynne &#x2013; I mean, I've been doing this, why do we release them at the same time when we have them? So it's two. And two, I did want to get them away from all the changes that we had going on relative to the divestitures and the acquisitions. So I wanted to get it clean and get that information out ahead of that because I knew there'd be a lot of discussion relative to the restatements and I wanted to get it separated. And there's no reason why I can't put the orders out before I put the P&amp;L out. And so we'll go back and do that from now on. There's no reason. I don't know why I did it historically, other than that it's always done that way; and that's not a good reason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for all the color. Way to go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to make you guys work twice, that's all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And I will now turn the call back to management for any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Again, I want to thank all of the people across Emerson for working so hard the last 18 months. The work &#x2013; your effort has really paid off. We had a great finish to 2010. I feel very strong about where we sit relative to 2011. I feel very good about the investments we're making, the position of the company as we globalize the business. And I look at what we've accomplished and, from my perspective, we are extremely strong and the foundation's strong, and look forward to an exciting 2011.</p>
          <p>Also want to thank everyone for being on the call today, and I look forward to seeing everybody as the year progresses. And we'll see people here in St. Louis in February. And I promise there will be no snow. And that one you can &#x2013; I wouldn't bet on it, but I promise. Take care, everybody. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude the Emerson Fourth Quarter Fiscal 2010 Results Conference Call. If you'd like to listen to a replay of today's conference, please dial 1-800-406-7325 or 303-590-3030 and enter in the access code 4370601. AT&amp;T would like to thank you for your participation, and you may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>