<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1305212" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-05-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>186</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Lynne Maxeiner, Director, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">David N. Farr, Chairman, Chief Executive Officer and President</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Steven Winoker</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Terry Darling</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Nigel Coe</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Robert Cornell</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Jeffrey Sprague</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Scott Davis</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">John Inch</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Eli Lustgarten</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Richard Kwas</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you for standing by. Welcome to the Emerson Second Quarter Fiscal 2010 Results Conference Call. During today's presentation, all parties will be in a listen-only mode. Following the presentation, the conference will be opened for questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> This conference is being recorded today, Tuesday, May 4, 2010.</p>
          <p>Emerson's commentary and responses to your questions may contain forward-looking statements, including the company's outlook for the remainder of the year. Information on factors that could cause actual results to vary materially from those discussed today is available at Emerson's most recent Annual Report on Form 10-K, as filed with the SEC.</p>
          <p>At this time, Emerson's management will discuss non-GAAP measures about the company's performance and the reconciliation of those to the most direct comparable GAAP measures. Content within this presentation is posted in the Investor Relations of Emerson's website at www.emerson.com/financial.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to our host, Lynne Maxeiner, Director of Investor Relations. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Luke. I am joined today by David Farr, Chairman, Chief Executive Officer and President of Emerson; and Frank Dellaquila, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer.</p>
          <p>Today's call will summarize Emerson's second quarter 2010 results. A conference call slide presentation will accompany my comments and is available in the Investor Relations section of Emerson's corporate website. A replay of this conference call and slide presentation will be available on the website after the call for the next three months.</p>
          <p>I will start with the highlights of the quarter, as shown on page 2 of the conference call slide presentation. Second quarter sales were up 1% to 5.1 billion. Underlying sales declined 6%, and underlying sales in the quarter were positive in Climate Technologies and Appliance and Tools. Operating profit margin was 15%, up 90 basis points. We saw a nice increase in business segment EBIT margin, which was up 340 basis points to 14.8%. Earnings per share from continuing operations attributable to Emerson of $0.54, up 10% compared to $0.49 in the prior-year quarter. Another quarter of strong operating cash flow, 632 million, and free cash flow of 543 million. Our free cash flow to net earnings conversion was 134%. Solid trade working capital performance, with trade working capital as a percent to sales improving to 17.5%.</p>
          <p>Slide 3, the P&amp;L. Again, sales up 1% to 5.144 billion. Underlying sales declined 6%. Acquisitions added 4 points, and currency added 3 points. Operating profit in the quarter of 770 million or 15% of sales, the increase primarily driven by cost-reduction benefits. We had a negative impact from the strong increase in stock price and one-year overlap for retention purposes of two stock compensation programs. Net earnings up 11% to 414 million. Diluted average shares in the quarter of 757.4 million. We repurchased 0.6 million shares for 27 million in the quarter, which leaves you with an EPS from continuing ops of $0.54, up 10%. A negative $0.01 impact from discontinued operations related to the LANDesk business leaves you with the reported EPS of $0.53.</p>
          <p>Next slide, underlying sales by geography. First, in the United States, sales declined 3%. Europe was down 18%, Latin America down 12%, and Middle East/Africa was down 13%. Asia continued to grow and was up 5%. Total international was down 9%, which gets you to a total underlying sales decrease of 6%. Again, currency added 3 points and acquisitions added 4 points, getting you to the consolidated sales growth of 1%.</p>
          <p>Slide 5, some income statement detail. Gross profit dollars of 2 billion were 38.9% of sales, up 280 basis points, the improvement driven by cost containment programs, restructuring benefits, acquisitions, and favorable new product and innovation mix. SG&amp;A of 23.9% of sales, which brings you to operating profit of 770 million or 15% of sales. As previously indicated, we had a negative impact from the stock price change, as well as the overlap of two stock compensation programs. Other deductions net of 92 million, which includes lower restructuring, lower currency transaction losses, and lower bad debt expense, which was partially offset by increased acquisition amortization and lower one-time gains. Interest expense of 67 million in the quarter gets you to the pre-tax of 611 million or 11.9%. Taxes in the quarter of 184 million for a tax rate of 30.1%. The tax rate is estimated at approximately 30% for the fiscal year.</p>
          <p>Next slide, cash flow and balance sheet. Operating cash flow continues to be strong and was up 27% in the quarter to 632 million, driven by working capital benefits and higher earnings. Capital expenditures of 89 million; we're keeping the capital tight until the recovery absorbs excess global capacity. Free cash flow of 543 million, up 52%. The trade working capital balances at the bottom of the slide show our strong improvement in our trade working capital to sales ratio at 17.5% in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Next slide, the business segment P&amp;L. Business segment EBIT of 788 million or 14.8% of sales, a strong increase of 32% or 340 basis points, the improvement driven by cost-reduction benefits and lower restructuring cost. Difference in accounting methods of 49 million, corporate and other of 159 million. This includes the negative impact from the strong increase in stock price and one-year overlap for retention purposes of two stock compensation programs, in total, 72 million. And lower one-time gains, 25 million, gets you to the earnings before interest and taxes from continuing ops of 678 million. Interest expense of 67 million, up 18 million, the increase driven by the change in debt mix. We issued 1.35 billion in long-term debt in the last 12 months, which gets you to the pre-tax line of 611 million.</p>
          <p>Next we'll go through the individual business segments, starting with Process Management. Sales in the quarter of 1.428 billion, down 5%. Underlying sales were down 13%. Acquisitions added 4 points, and currency added 4 points. By region, the U.S. was down 5%. Asia was down 13%. Europe was down 19% and Middle East/Africa was down 6%. The underlying order trends turned positive in the quarter. We saw improvement in MRO, mainly in power and chemical end markets, as well as oil and gas and nuclear end markets. EBIT dollars were 241 million or 16.9% of sales. While the margin was negatively impacted by volume deleverage, we realized the benefits from our significant cost reduction and restructuring efforts. Recently, IEC unanimously voted to certify WirelessHART technology as the first global wireless standard. Emerson customers are currently using WirelessHART in over 1,200 global installations.</p>
          <p>Next slide, Industrial Automation. Sales in the quarter down 10% to 867 million. Underlying sales were down 16%. Currency and acquisitions each added 3 points. By geography, the U.S. was down 18%, Europe was down 19%, and Asia was up 8%. We saw growth in the electrical drives, fluid automation, and electrical distribution businesses. And while still negative year-over-year, the alternator business is starting to turn. EBIT in the quarter of 94 million or 10.7% of sales. We were able to deliver flat EBIT margin despite significant volume decline and increased restructuring. The volume deleverage and higher restructuring was offset by cost reduction benefits. Order trends turned positive in the quarter and were up 10 to 15%. Restructuring efforts are ongoing to continue to strengthen the competitive position.</p>
          <p>Slide 10, Network Power. Sales in the quarter, up 4% to 1.351 billion. Underlying sales were down 6%. The Avocent acquisition added 7 points, and currency added 3 points. By geography, the U.S. was down 3%, Asia was up 2%, and Europe was down 20%. We saw growth in the embedded power business and moderate declines in the uninterruptible power supply, precision cooling, and telecom energy systems businesses. EBIT margin up 47% to 157 million, the margin improvement driven by benefits from cost-reduction actions. Also, restructuring decreased 21 million versus the prior-year quarter. The restructuring actions in 2009 strengthened our global best-cost position.</p>
          <p>Next slide, Climate Technologies. Sales in the quarter of 908 million, up 24%, with underlying sales up 19%, acquisitions adding 3 points and currency adding 2 points. By region, the U.S. was up 13%, Europe was down 11%, and Asia was up 67%. The growth in Asia was driven by well-structured China stimulus programs. EBIT dollars of 163 million or 17.9% of sales, driven by volume leverage, cost reductions, benefits from prior-year restructuring, and price/cost management. The new energy efficiency regulation in China is expected to be implemented June 1 of 2010, but we're already seeing the benefits in orders and sales now. The China market has already had sizable shifts to these higher efficiency levels via the stimulus programs that have been in place.</p>
          <p>Slide 12, Appliance and Tools. Sales were up 4% to 760 million. Underlying sales grew 2%, and currency and acquisitions each added a point. By geography, the U.S. was up 3%, Europe was up 4%, and Asia was up 9%. EBIT of 133 million or 17.4% of sales. We had nice margin improvement, driven by leverage on higher sales volumes, based on our aggressive cost-reduction programs over the last three years, restructuring benefits, and lower restructuring expense. In the quarter we saw solid growth in the Tools business. While consumer demand is still tepid, the demand is improving off a very weak two-year base.</p>
          <p>Next slide, the summary and outlook. Market conditions have improved in the second quarter. Underlying sales decline moderated to 6%, and orders in sales are trending slightly better than expected since our February investor conference. Underlying order trends have turned positive for all five business segments. Cash generation remains strong, and we have significant new product innovations and introductions under way.</p>
          <p>Our operating profit margin is showing improvement from our aggressive cost repositioning efforts. And we absorbed approximately $50 million increase in stock compensation expense due to the stock price changes versus the prior-year quarter. We now expect underlying sales to be flat to down 3% and net sales up 2% to 5% to 21.3 to 21.9 billion for the fiscal year. Also, operating margin 15.7% to 16%, earnings per share in the range of 2.40 to 2.55, operating cash flow of 2.9 to 3.1 billion, and free cash flow of 2.5 to 2.6 billion.</p>
          <p>So with that, I'll turn it over to David Farr.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Lynne. I want to welcome everybody here this afternoon. Thank you for joining us. I appreciate it.</p>
          <p>First of all, I would like to thank all the business leaders, the presidents, and the global operational people for delivering and executing a very strong quarter. With underlying sales down, we were able to deliver up, up earnings, up margins, strong cash flow, and strong returns. And we have strong momentum going into second half with our global orders turning up nicely. This was a very strong operational quarter with excellent participation and contribution across all the businesses. They all had a major contribution in delivering the earnings and the cash and making this a stronger company as we move into the second half.</p>
          <p>As I look at the second half right now and I look at our profitability, the orders, the sales, and the cash flow, we are well-positioned. And I would like to remind people on the phone that Emerson does not &#x2013; and I mean does not &#x2013; give quarterly sales, profit, EBIT, EPS, cash flow forecasts. And we have not for eight or nine years. We give you our best trend line assessment. We give our global market assessment of our businesses. And we give you an expected range for our total year where we're looking at what's going on across the business.</p>
          <p>We are very much focused on investing and executing for a one-year, three-year, five-year window to create long-term value for our customers, our shareholders, our employees. So we do not manage earnings and expectations or bogeys for a quarterly target. We manage for the long term, and we invest accordingly, and we execute accordingly. And people know that of me since I've been CEO for almost 10 years.</p>
          <p>As I look at where we sit right now, I feel very positive about our order trends. I look at our new product, our innovations. I look at the introductions we have going on right now. I look at the profit improvement. I look at the restructuring and the new products. Everything is kicking in and working extremely well. The order pace is strong. And I clearly have concerns about other parts of the world, and I'll talk about that in a little bit, but right now where we sit we are slightly ahead of where I expected, both from a top line standpoint and a profitability standpoint, as the global personnel are executing extremely well on the issues and challenges we face across the world.</p>
          <p>We have increased our global personnel by a little bit over 6,000 people on a reported basis, which does include some acquisitions. We're flat or slightly up, couple hundred people, in the U.S. Western Europe we are down. And the best-cost parts of the world we're up significantly as we continue to grow and invest in our emerging markets. That's where our strong growth is as we look at it going forward.</p>
          <p>As I look at the world today, and I look at where we sit from a global economy, I see the U.S. economy improving. I personally believe the U.S. economic numbers will slow down a little bit as the second half emerges here. I think that businesses will continue to improve their spending, but at the same time I think you'll see some of the back off- &#x2013; the corporate &#x2013; the government spending, and that will unwind a little bit. So I see a reasonable second half of the economy in the U.S., but not accelerating U.S. global economic growth.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe, I remain very concerned about what's going on with the excessive debt levels, the excessive spending, bailouts, and the impact of what that's going to have on the European economy. I think the European economy will grow in 2010. But the growth will underperform what we see in the United States. So if I'm looking at 3.5% in the U.S., for growth, somewhere between 3.2 to 3.5, I'm looking at under 2% in Western Europe because of what's going on in those &#x2013; in that country at this point in time.</p>
          <p>As I look at Latin America, those markets are continuing to improve. And we will see a better economic scenario for our Latin America business in the second half.</p>
          <p>Asia has continued to grow nicely. And I expect that to improve a little bit as we go into the second half. China, I've always felt all along would be somewhere in the 12 to 14% growth for us for the whole year. You can't look at a quarter, because we have some projects that move in and out, but we've had a very good start in China. And I would expect that to continue. We are seeing the impact of some of the dial-back of the stimulus money because the economy in China has been so strong. That's not unexpected, though I still expect us to do pretty well as we move into the second half of 2010.</p>
          <p>So overall as I look at where we sit today based on the orders, our underlying sales were down around &#x2013; I think around 14% in the first quarter. We are down 6% in the second quarter, which we just reported. In my opinion right now, based on the order trend, our underlying sales will be up in the 5 to 7% level, in the 6, 7% level, in the second half of this year. And our order trends right now will support that.</p>
          <p>We are well-structured for growth. We are investing the strong profitability levels we're generating right now. We are investing in the emerging markets, we're investing in new products, and we're positioning ourself for what I would call a slow, steady recovery. As people look at it, yes, it's a V, but it is what I would call a muted V or a slower V. It is definitely recovery. But you got to keep in mind, we went down a long way, as many people did in this world, and it's going to take time to recover where we came from just in 2008.</p>
          <p>Our position's very strong right now from a profitability standpoint, a cash flow standpoint. The operating people are executing extremely strongly on our trade working capital from receivable management, from inventory management. We are setting record levels of performance here, as you saw in this quarter. And I would expect that we'll have a very strong performance in the second half, hence our improvement relative to our operating cash flow and free cash flow.</p>
          <p>As I look at our capital spending rate, we probably bottomed this quarter as I look at it. And then we'll slowly increase it. We have plenty of capacity around the world right now. Given the fact that we were a $25 billion company in 2008 and we're going be less than a $22 billion company in 2010 tells me I have capacity. But as I look forward quarter by quarter by quarter, our underlying capital spending will start to improve from this quarter. But still, we'll be most likely down versus prior year. And it'll be a very slow, gradual recovery as we move into 2010. We do not need the excess capacity to be investing right now because we have productivity, we have repositioning around the company, and the company is performing extremely well.</p>
          <p>I would like to comment one more time on the operation and corporate people around the world. This was a very strong quarter. If you look at it from top to bottom, this was very strong execution, and people did a great job. And many of these people had still down sales versus prior year, yet the restructuring and the actions they're taking to improve this corporation were significant, and the board and the CEO and the OCE truly appreciate it. And I want to thank them all for making that happen.</p>
          <p>One last comment before we open the lines is relative to Chloride. For many of you that may know "Hogan's Heroes" &#x2013; I used to watch that when I got home from school. And Sergeant Shultz would say, "I know nothing." I cannot comment on Chloride. We are controlled by the UK Takeover Panel. So don't ask because I will not tell. Don't ask, don't tell. "Hogan's Heroes."</p>
          <p>So with that, I'll open the floor to questions. But again, I want to thank everyone around the world. It was a great quarter, a strong quarter. We are well set up for a strong second half and a continued recovery, and I feel very good about where we are today. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question today comes from Steven Winoker of Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First question is around the March exit rates for underlying sales on Process management. Obviously up 10% plus in that March number means that you have a real accelerating rate there. What is going on in terms of projects? I mean, how lumpy is this? And were there any special one-time things going on right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you well know, the Process business is clearly a lumpy business. And as I look at it right now, my expectations that I laid out earlier in the year and late last year are I expected things to be much weaker in the Process business. The orders are coming back around the world. And I would expect them to continue to and the trend line to continue to improve. I still do not expect positive underlying sales growth in the Process business this year. It will start happening in the first quarter of next fiscal year.</p>
          <p>However, it won't be as negative as I originally thought. But the business &#x2013; and when I look at the MRO business, I look at the chemical industry business, I look at some of the oil and gas businesses, people are spending. The larger projects &#x2013; there are some big ones out there &#x2013; they're happening. You're winning some, you're losing some. Right now I look at a fairly steady improvement in the Process business. I like the recovery. It's happening probably six months sooner than I thought.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then could you expand a bit on China? I know it's only one quarter, as you had mentioned. But could you give us a few more numbers and a little bit more detail across the businesses in terms of, beyond Climate, also what you're seeing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think that if you look at our &#x2013; I'm going to get the little sheet here. If I look at the various businesses relative to China, our industrial businesses are starting to recover. They are obviously less positive than Climate and Technology, but they are recovering. Our Process business in China is clearly going be later cycle recovery. It's going take a while for that to get back to where it was. If I look at the Network Power business, it's still okay. They were extremely strong last year, and they were getting a lot of the Chinese stimulus money. That's coming back off, so their comps are much harder. So that will be a more challenging second half for us. But across the businesses, I would say that we're going to do okay in China.</p>
          <p>The Network Power will be the most challenging from a comp standpoint. Profits will get better as the year goes on. The industrial has definitely gone positive. And then I look at the &#x2013; Climate and Technology will drive this for the next six months. But in total I feel pretty good about China. I still think we're going to do somewhere between 12 and 14% underlying sales growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then finally before I pass it on, am I correct in looking at the backlog and assuming that a very, very small part of that backlog is exposed to projects in Southern Europe, to your earlier comments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very small.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very small.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Terry Darling of Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Dave, wondering if we could follow up a little bit on your comments on orders and organic growth. We've seen a nice acceleration in the orders, particularly in Industrial Automation and Process. I'm wondering if you could characterize for us where you see those rates going over the next couple of months. Presumably March very strong versus February and January. You had some down 25 or 30% months last year. I mean, looking out three, six months, are we going to see those numbers in that 20 to 30% range, you think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, I'm not that &#x2013; I wish I was that good. I wouldn't be in this job. I'd be a gazillionaire betting on other things. But we clearly right now are coming into the weakest part, if you look at our trend line, order trend lines. This month and next month are a bottom. So I would expect this to continue to trend up and move into &#x2013; I mean, I feel comfortable in saying it's going go in the 10 to 15 to 20% range because of the comparisons. But I don't think it's going to be as strong as you were saying. I think it's going to be more gradual, which is going to be a better situation for us to manage at this point in time from an operational, too, because it's easier to digest that type of growth. But I don't see that type of acceleration you're thinking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm thinking there will be acceleration, but I don't think it's what you're talking about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And kind of kicking that into the discussion on second half organic, you mentioned 5 to 7 or 6 to 7, in that range. Presumably you're thinking a little below that for 3Q and a little bit above that in 4Q. Is that the way to think about it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then, can you -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you look back at last year, our &#x2013; the third quarter and the fourth quarter underlying growth rates were pretty negative, or pretty close to negative 20%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I'd expect that to improve as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I missed it. Can you true us up on restructuring expense by segment here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I won't do it by segment. But I don't have those numbers the top of my head, but the restructuring number we've been saying &#x2013; Lynne, help me. We've been saying 150 -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To 175.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>150 to 175.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To 175. Right now I would say that the 175 is probably going be too high from that standpoint. I would say we'll probably be somewhere around the 145 to &#x2013; I'm giving my &#x2013; 165, 170. I think you're going be &#x2013; as improvement happens in our sales, I think we'll start trending down towards the lower number. What it will mean is that we'll have a little bit more in the first half of next year, but last year we did 300 million. So if I was going to pick a point number, I'd pick pretty close to 150.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just trying to think about that comment in context with what you're saying on what's happening with incremental guidance as implied by the change in your guidance for both operating margin and revenues. So essentially you're taking &#x2013; the margins up 50 basis points, you're taking revenues up 300 basis points. At the midpoint of those ranges, kind of 30ish percent incremental margin, but you're lowering restructuring expense for the year. Does that just create a conservative element on those incrementals? Or is there a mix effect in there? Or are you worried more about pricing deteriorating the in back half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not worried about pricing. I'm worried about &#x2013; I always keep an element of &#x2013; I'm not supposed to swear, but whatever happens. I was going to say "Oh, S," but -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Stuff happens.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But something bad happens. So I mean, as I look at the forecast right now, if everything clicks like we're seeing clicking right now, our EPS will move towards the higher end. It's clear. Based on what we just said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Nigel Coe of Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good afternoon, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Nigel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I just wanted to do just &#x2013; I guess concern on the corporate expense. The mark-to-market effort was a one-quarter impact we'll see on the corporate expense. I mean, I realize you got an overlap this year, but the spike up this quarter is &#x2013; that's a one-off impact?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The one-off impact has to do more with the change in stock price. The fact that in second quarter this year the stock rose $8 versus second quarter last year it went down about $8. So you had that divergence, which caused that $50 million swing. Now, obviously the stock price fluctuations will impact every quarter. It does. But you get into a situation once you hit third quarter where stocks were going up last year, including Emerson. So you don't have that same delta impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I mean, that's a good problem to have. But it looks like your original guidance was $100 million headwind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's now 150. So I'm not going to ask for 2011 guidance or anything else, but as we go to 2011, we go into a single plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Should we expect maybe a $100 million, maybe a $150 million tailwind since 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. It's going to be less than that. I mean right now, if I was factoring in a number right now, I'd be looking at a total &#x2013; everything I see right now &#x2013; in a range. I'm going to give you a range, a broad range, because it's kind of early, Nigel. But I would say we're going to have a tailwind of 50 to 100 million next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I mean, the margin performance is pretty impressive, Dave. I mean, 15.7 to 16 this year. You've got 80 basis points in pension corporate expenses. Underlying therefore 15.5 to 15.8 on an apples-to-apples basis. What does this mean &#x2013; you said in the Investor Day 17%-plus next cycle. I mean, what do you think at this point in time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I still think that 17-plus the next cycle is good. The issue right now is that anytime you have a recovery come at it and the restructuring we've done, we will have higher incremental margins. And the issue for me right now working with the business leaders, and Frank and Ed Monser working with the business leaders, is we need to start picking up our incremental investments or we will generate higher margins right now and then we'll have less margin improvement next year. Do you understand?</p>
          <p>So we're investing right now, and we're encouraging people to invest, particularly in the emerging markets and some of the next-generation new products, continue to aggressively invest, because right now the flow-through profitability of the company is running at peak performance, and it will continue to do that, especially as the underlying sales goes from negative to positive. And I want to make sure we invest for the future. I mean, we could clearly maximize this year and ride that profit margin way up, but then we will hurt our long-term, I think, profitability and growth prospects. So we're in a trade-off right now. We're going to continue to grow, and we're going to continue to make pretty good margins, but I want to start trying to invest some of that money as we're coming out of this early cycle for 2011 and 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And just one more quick question on Network Power. I know that some of these long type of businesses are difficult to forecast on a quarterly basis, but it looked like &#x2013; if we adjust for Avocent &#x2013; that underlying sales declined from 1Q to 2Q. Seasonally, that's quite an unusual trend. I mean, anything to call out there? Especially given the order strength that we've seen in that business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Network Power China had a phenomenally strong first fiscal quarter for us. The way our mix of business is right now, we are clearly having a different type of cycle going on across our Electronics business. We are actually having problems with electronic components. In the semiconductor capacity was taken down so hard that we're struggling right now getting components on shipments. Our sales would have been higher in the Network Power area if we had electronic components. And I think this was going to happen for the rest of this calendar quarter. I mean calendar year, I'm sorry. And so where we are right now is &#x2013; I mean, Network Power is recovering, but it's being damaged a little bit by or held back a little bit by the electronic components issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is that the only area where you're seeing supply chain constraints?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of anything of substance &#x2013; I mean, that you can measure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome. Thank you, Nigel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Bob Cornell of Barclays Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so just following with Nigel's question. I mean, it looked like Network Power margins sequentially were a little softer than I thought. You didn't break out specifically what the Avocent impact was. Was it the $0.02 we expected or a little more than that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. It's not any more than that. The issue was &#x2013; and we tried to warn people in February &#x2013; the way that Avocent came in &#x2013; because we warned everybody. I can go back and get the transcript; I know I said it &#x2013; twice &#x2013; is that we had one month of Avocent. It was the best month, December, it was very good. The cost of amortization kicked in, in the second quarter, full cost. And that alone drove that margin impact down. So I feel very good about the margin improvement that we forecasted for that segment for the year.</p>
          <p>I believe that we said EBIT margin improvements for the Network Power was going to be somewhere in the 13.6 to 14. We are going be at that high end or slightly above that by the time we finish this year. So we're trending the right way. It's just that that &#x2013; that one quarter. That's why we tried to call it out. And it's not always easy to hear everything we say, but that's &#x2013; we knew this was going to happen here. Not surprising.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Seasonally, it looks like Network Power, always a little softer the second quarter. Is there something structural or seasonal that causes the second quarter margin to be a little -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our customer base for the year-end numbers is always strong because most of our customers are calendar year number guys, so they drive to have a very strong November-December. And then obviously we always have Chinese New Year. So you have two things &#x2013; our second quarter, we have Chinese New Year and we have the drop-off because of our calendar-year customers, which are quite predominant in our Network Power base.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Moving to Climate Tech, I mean, you mentioned the China, efficiency regs in place in June. Are we starting to see scroll shipments? And are we going to get the kind of ramp in scroll in '11 that was anticipated a couple years ago when these regs were first discussed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're having &#x2013; it's happening now. The answer is yes, it's happening. We had a very strong recovery in scroll. Our scroll shipments are growing. We reported to the board today, 20% this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think at one point we were talking about a couple of million scrolls in China as a result of these regulation changes. Is that still what we're looking at?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are already capacitized around 2 million scrolls. Let's say compressors, okay? Scroll compressors in China. It will go north of that the next two or three years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I guess final question. You want to flesh out just the Shell contract and how you won that, who you competed with, and -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What do you mean? You put -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, we can't go there. "Hogan's Heroes." Go watch "Hogan's Heroes."</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That was Chloride. I'm talking Shell; I'm talking Shell.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We're talking Sergeant Shultz. "I know nothing."</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No comment. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Jeff Sprague of -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sprague, Sprague.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, thank you, Vertical Research Partners. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, my father-in-law was Italian, and he said I needed a vowel at the end of my name. So I went by "Spragoo" sometimes with him.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can call you "Spaghetti."</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Couple questions, a lot of ground covered. 2% growth in Europe. You used to say you couldn't grow anywhere with 2% growth. Can you grow in Europe with 2% growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Where we're going to see our growth, Jeff, and we're already starting to see our order pace pick up, with the euro sitting at 1.30, the strong export customers we have are now starting to export. So the European economies, the countries that have strong export capabilities, are going to have a very strong recovery in the second half if the euro stays down at 1.30. And it could even drift below 1.30. And so we're seeing those customers that we serve ordering our products. And that's helping our orders right now. And we would expect &#x2013; one, we had terrible comparisons last year, so we're going to have some growth in the second half.</p>
          <p>But if you look at the pure domestic players at less than 2%, your comment is still right on the mark. And I'm very concerned about Europe. Their debt position and &#x2013; I mean, is not very good. You got UK, whose debt position's extremely high right now. I think Europe's going to struggle here for the next couple years. And you know my opinion what that means relative to the United States over time, too, with our debt position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on MRO. A little bit surprised to hear that Power MRO has picked up given just what we've seen in some of those end markets. Where are you seeing that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's around the world. The power industry has long-term cycles of anything &#x2013; even the maintenance repair stuff is long-term, Jeff. So it's a function of what happens over an extended time period. They have long-term shutdown plans. They'll go ahead and spend the money. And so the cycle right now is good. Now, it could slow down in, say, 12 or 18 months. But right now around the world we've seen people spending money on upgrades. You've got the environmental issues, and you also have trying to get more capacity out of the current power plants right now. So they're spending money.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I guess just finally, you made a strong point about long-term investment. I think -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You heard that. You heard that. Okay. Good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It came through. So I guess the question that many investors have, though, is what cost is that long-term investment? Obviously you need to do it. The jury's out on Avocent, but a lot of people thought that was expensive, and this other deal we're not talking about looks fairly rich, too. So I'm just wondering when you put it in the context of maybe the "strategic deal" versus the more kind of normal investment, if there's a different valuation framework or ROIC framework, or how do you internally come to a conclusion on a deal like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, the comment &#x2013; I'll come back to that question. The first comment I'd make on long-term investments &#x2013; I'm talking about technology investments, internal investments, and also &#x2013; and people investments. So we're in a mode right now &#x2013; we were going through a mode but we, our peak employment was 141,000. We went below 120. Now we're back up to over 130.</p>
          <p>And so the issue for me is we're &#x2013; I want to make sure we're investing right now even though our underlying sales are still negative, we're investing in where that growth's going to come for us for the next six, 12, 18 months. So it's people investment and then also innovation and new products. That's the comments that I'm making. Because it's real easy to say, okay, let's wait until we see the really strong recovery happen and then make those investments. But right now a key issue for me is to balance that margin expansion, which we have going on right now, with flat or negative underlying sales. And that's what's key for me at this point in time.</p>
          <p>Relative to acquisitions, we have a very formal process relative to what I'd call bolt-on acquisitions, which we did one today. We approved one today. And that type of return typically is going be around a 15, 16, 17, 14-type percent return on total capital to us. And that's a return on that investment over time. A strategic acquisition is going be, as I look at it, in the realm of 9 to 11. It's a business that we know extremely well, and it will over time accrete value. Not only in the acquisition but in the core business that we're trying to expand into. And so that is how we look at the long-term strategic investment profile.</p>
          <p>When we made the Fisher acquisition, which many people thought was very expensive, it greatly increased our presence in the Process business and greatly increased the value of our total Process business. The Avocent transaction and the Chloride transaction will greatly increase the value of our business in the Network Power over &#x2013; and that will be over time. And so that's how we look at them. And then we obviously, by country, sometimes we look at countries and we look at the cost of capital by various regions of the world and the risk profiles. That's how we go at it, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very helpful. Does your financial model require you to get to the 9 to 11 on the standalone company without bringing in those larger company kind of ancillary benefits that would filter in over time, that -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; probably are really there, but hard to measure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We do not &#x2013; that's something we talk about on top. We don't &#x2013; it's not in the model per se.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome. Jeff. Take care.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Scott Davis of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think this might be the first presentation where you really call out new product innovations, introductions and &#x2013; obviously you guys have always been really well-known for your kind of engineering side of it. And maybe underrated on the innovation side. But how do you measure that? I mean, is there a way &#x2013; do you guys think about a vitality index? Or is there some sort of, maybe just a little bit of background you can give us on how you've gotten to the point where you actually think that's an important driver now, where in the last up cycle, other than a few things like DeltaV, it wasn't as much of a conversation piece.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think it's changed. I think that, as we talk about in the February session, we look at what we call &#x2013; what I would call &#x2013; core breakthrough type of technologies and innovations that will change the underlying growth profile and capabilities of the company. And we focus on those by business, and then we make sure those are properly funded at the business level and the corporate level we fund them. And it makes a big difference relative to where we take our acquisitions, where we take our internal investments, and where we put our people.</p>
          <p>And I would say that's refined over the last 10 or 12 years significantly, where now I would look at as I look at the innovation and technology breakthroughs we're looking at, we have a tracking mechanism where we look at the percentage of our money being spent and the people being spent in what I would call new innovation and breakthrough innovation. And we try to share that with people over time. But that's how we measure. We have a very disciplined process inside looking at what we'd call the game-changing innovation and how we're investing in that, the dollars and the people, and it's a process. And we do it by business. So it's something that we really drove into the culture since the last upturn. And I think it's going have a big impact on us as we come out of this, I think, a little bit of slower growth, global growth environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Right. Okay. We'll stay tuned on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you'll see it. We'll talk about it. It's something that's important. So we'll talk openly with them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Guys, I haven't really heard you comment on &#x2013; there's been a lot that's gone on in the Tools business. And I know your business is a little bit different than some of the other guys. But you've had the two big transactions, Black &amp; Decker/Stanley and then Danaher/Cooper, as kind of a response to that. I mean, what does that mean for you guys? Is there more pressure to maybe find a partner here? Or -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, nothing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Does it matter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It makes no &#x2013; we sold them. I sold those businesses already. Those businesses are gone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's wild.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The Tool business we have now &#x2013; I mean, we have in there &#x2013; is like a vac business, and we have the high-end RIGID, which are more of a technology company; it's not really a tool company anymore. So, we sold -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. No, I understand that. That's kind of why I asked the question. It's a little bit different, but is there any scale issues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I suppose you're still selling to some of the same customers, I guess, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I mean, yeah. We both sell into Home Depot. But we sell them products they don't sell.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So there's really no overlap there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, we made the decision to get out of that, and before you started following us, we got out of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We got out of those type of tools because it was a low-margin, low-growth. It was very competitive, and China was changing the game here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. No, I understand. Guys, just last night &#x2013; I hate to harp on it. We all know that Europe's a bit of a mess right now. I think our average companies come in on growth maybe negative 3 to negative 5% in Europe. You guys came in at negative 18. I mean, what do you attribute to kind of the &#x2013; is there some sort of a de-stock that maybe you guys saw that other guys didn't see, or just a little bit more timing issues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're heavy non-res. We're heavy capital related. We're heavy late cycle in Europe. And that's what it is. And a lot of our customer base is more export. So that's what function is. The Process guys are very strong. I mean, our Process business if you look at our European entities, is $2 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so it's a cycle with kind of the companies we have there. That's what you look at there. So we stay up longer, and it takes awhile for us to come back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's nothing unusual &#x2013; though I've been &#x2013; I've not been positive in Europe for quite some time now, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nothing new for me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I get it. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's all. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Take care.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Tony Both of FAF Advisors. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Just wanted to get a little bit more on the sequential operating profit bridge for Network Power from the first &#x2013; I know you mentioned to Bob that you had a good month from Avocent. But I guess I'm kind of looking for &#x2013; I don't know. If I look at this sequentially, maybe just what could happen in the second half that impacted you in the second quarter &#x2013; or that won't impact you in the second half that impacted you in the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what you're going to see &#x2013; I mean, I think the underlying business will continue to improve from a growth standpoint, so the growth will continue to improve a little bit. Most of the restructuring within the Network Power is done. The Avocent impact is not going be any different from quarter to quarter right now. So I mean I think it's pretty well done. The key issue for us was that we had a &#x2013; if you look at the Avocent &#x2013; that December was an extremely strong month when we booked it. And then you also have the issue of the way it comes in. We didn't have a whole quarter intangible amortization going on. So there was nothing unusual going on. There's nothing funny going on. I just think you're looking at it now more of a steady rate. And you'll start seeing, I think, a continued improvement in our profitability in our Network Power business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then on Appliance and Tools, I mean you've got some real easy compares -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; on an organic &#x2013; I mean, this quarter it kind of seemed like you should have done a little bit better organically than you did. Should that improve go-forward? Was there something that happened this quarter there, where you didn't quite get all you could get?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think so. I think that from the standpoint we're just &#x2013; you're not seeing a lot of returning yet into what we'd call in the big-box centers, the Home Depots, the Lowe's. The buying profile still is not moving up, up-dollar yet. So a lot of our products are more up-dollar value. So they're buying the low-end stuff. And so we're not seeing the consumer or the &#x2013; well, I said a residential marketplace yet going into the mode where they're buying our type of product. We'll see that improvement as we go along.</p>
          <p>You're also not seeing what I would call the home repair type of market. With the equity down on houses, people are not spending the money in that. And those are types of products that our businesses sell into. So the mix right now is not good. So I would look at a better second half, but it's not going to be that strong a recovery. If you look at U.S. residential, it's still improving, but it's coming off a low, low base. So it's going be a long recovery cycle for these guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then on the alternator business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you expect that to be flat for the year or slightly down for the year? And how does that compare to what your expectations were maybe a quarter ago?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would expect it still to be down. My expectations now are higher than they were before because we see investments going on around in the emerging markets. And we're seeing some of the production coming back online. And so some of the strong export markets are starting to pick back up. So I would say I'm more positive about it now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from John Inch of Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Hi, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So Asia up 5%, and I think you had sequentially significantly easier comps in Asia if you look at the underlying sales growth. And then you had Climate up 67, which was an acceleration. So for the businesses that you would call out that got sequentially weaker, I guess you did talk about Network Power in China. Was there anything else?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Network Power had to have been the biggest one out because of the strength that we had in the first quarter. It was a very strong quarter. I don't think Process, any of those guys &#x2013; from the standpoint Process is still going have a struggle this year. But I don't think &#x2013; it's just a quarter to quarter mix between Network Power and other guys. And other guys are just starting to recover. So nothing surprising there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>There wasn't a region or anything like that that was off, was there? Other than China?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, from the difference &#x2013; I'm looking at the businesses right now. I don't think so. I don't think there's anything weird going on between the regions. I mean, sometimes we have lumpy &#x2013; the Process business can have a very lumpy demand in Asia, the size of that business. And &#x2013; but I don't see anything unusual in the various markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Your CapEx expectations for the year were taken down fairly meaningfully. Is that a broad statement, or was there a couple of bigger projects you were looking to do in a &#x2013; say a given segment? Or is there any kind of color you would provide around that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think I took it down meaningful. I said that &#x2013; I think our forecast was around $550 million, wasn't it, for the year? And now &#x2013; oh, okay, it's a rounding thing, John. I would say &#x2013; what I'm saying right now, I think rather than being around 500 I think we're going to be somewhere around 450 to 500 million. That's what that says right there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, okay. I'm sorry. I thought it was a little more than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You deal with billions here and round it.  And so right now if you look at what's going to happen, I think we're going to be somewhere around the 450 to 500 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So there's nothing really material, then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Where do you stand, Dave, on inventory restocking? There seems to be this debate as to whether the stocking is well under way and about to end or depending on the industry, some people seem to think it hasn't really begun. Where do you stand on that? And really what's embedded in your organic growth in the second half? Are you assuming a degree of restocking? And if so, where?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My view of the U.S. right now is that the restocking is pretty &#x2013; is almost finished. I think they've got it geared up. I think there's some &#x2013; obviously certain segments that might be a little light. But if I look at our industry, if I look at our own inventory, which is higher right now on a dollar level, and I think we will keep it pretty close to that same dollar level, plus or minus maybe $100 million, I think there might be a little bit more upside. But I think we've got the biggest benefit already in a restocking in the U.S. marketplace. That's my assumption. That's my feeling and view of the world. And you're right, everyone has a different view. You're clearly right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Yeah. Just lastly, Dave, this isn't really a comment on Chloride, but if you think of the decline in the euro, the pickup prospectively of companies there in their export business, I don't know, I assume you have some cash in Europe today. I mean, should we be looking for more European M&amp;A activity? I mean, how are you thinking about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We definitely have money in Europe. We have a lot of cash in Europe. We buy companies in Europe. But, I mean, I look at the various pieces and &#x2013; it's probably a balance. I mean, we do some in Europe. Last year we did a couple in Europe. I think we do a couple in Europe every year. So I don't think we're going to be changing our position on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So this isn't presenting a bigger, significant incremental opportunity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I don't think so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Eli Lustgarten of Longbow Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Eli.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You might have missed your calling. The euro just hit 1.30 even.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That's interesting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Anyway, you look at volume getting better, you can understand improved profitability. But can we look at the margins; both Climate and Appliance have a big step up. Is there any upside to those margins that we saw in the second quarter, or is the goal just to hold to that level of profitability?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One second here. I think from my standpoint, it's a function of if my European business starts to kick in, in the second half, then I think my Climate margins &#x2013; we should be able to improve overall for the year. I'm going to start investing. One of the key issues for me will be starting investing. They had a very strong quarter. Now, the question will be, can they maintain that? But I think that we had a &#x2013; usually strong fourth quarter, so my gut tells me that we should be able to maintain. And I'd like to see a little bit of improvement for the whole year.</p>
          <p>And this business will clearly be above what we had said early on in the year. But there's only a certainly point of level profitability you can get out of these businesses where you have to start putting money back in. And we were talking to the board about that today, about putting some money back in investment and back in that we had delayed both from a capacity standpoint and some other &#x2013; SG&amp;A investment in the business, which will now come back in given an investment. So I would say the profitability is pretty close to where it's going be for the short term but then it'll continue to trend back up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Then same thing in the Tools?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Tools I think we should see improvements in profitability as the year goes on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it was an amazing quarter to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Lynne just corrected me. She says she doesn't think it's going to get &#x2013; I mean, this was an amazing &#x2013; she says it's &#x2013; I think we'll be pretty close to that same range. I don't see it's going to drop off what they're saying here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Material costs, the big buzzword that everybody's talking about, are you starting to feel it? Do you have any issues with that &#x2013; other than everybody has it and you got to work with it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My concern right now as I look at later this year, going into next year, there's clearly inflation coming, as I've talked about since February. And I see material inflation coming at us. So we're going to have to keep driving pricing to offset that material inflation &#x2013; steel, copper, the oil prices, which is going into our plastic parts. You're seeing it flow through the system. And that will start hitting us &#x2013; the way we have our contracts right now later this calendar year and going into the first half of next year. So that's our focus right now is on there. We're pretty good for the rest of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And one final question. I guess the new buzzword that's being floated around is called nearshoring I guess, where it's a movement of capacity back to this country to shorten supply chain, rebalance we're close to Asia what's on here. On the next one to three years are you talking to any companies here about revamping their capacity here and making more components in the United States or in North America than you've seen? Or is that sort of still wishful thinking?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say that is wishful thinking. For a global company that has our growth segment outside the United States, I would say it's wishful thinking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I mean, that's the new buzzword we're hearing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you know, that's a good thing. Buzzwords are good things. I'm never big into buzzwords. I'm never big into fads. I'm never big into Baskin Robbins 31 flavors of the month shit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess I'll have a little fun. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Rich Kwas of Wells Fargo Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A question on Industrial Automation. Given that you're still about 25 to 30% below the peak on revenues and given your mix and what you've done restructuring the business, how do you feel about margins as you look out the next 24 months? Are we thinking 15% is achievable at a lower revenue run rate, or how should we think about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Industrial Automation I think it's going to &#x2013; 15% is pretty quick for the next 12, 24 months. I think you're going to take a little longer to get back to that level. It's going come back up, but it's not going to come back up that fast. You're not going to get 4 or 500 basis point in two years. I think it's going be a very gradual recovery. Because you got to think about &#x2013; our Industrial Automation business is pretty strong in Western Europe and in the United States. And so those businesses are going have a weaker recovery. But clearly the trend line is going back to the levels we reached before. And we're obviously restructuring in the next four or five years to be at higher levels, as I said. If we're going to get to 17%, we need Industrial Automation to get back and beat levels they've gotten before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay. That's what I was kind of thinking. And then on Process. In terms of the MRO on deferral of maybe expenditures that occurred last year and the recovery in that, where are we in that? Are we kind of exhaust getting through that and that's going to fade? Or what's your view on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My view is that will continue. I think the key issue right now is, yeah, they feel comfortable about the recovery. They feel comfortable they have the cash flow. They feel comfortable they can get the money. And so I think this recovery and that type of spending will continue. And that's part of why I think we're going to have a better second half in the Process than I originally thought, and the projects are going to be more for 2011 and 2012. So I feel comfortable that the MRO is going to continue to improve and help as we go forward the rest of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome. All the best to you. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And there are no further questions at this time. Please continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>With that, I want to thank everybody for joining us today. Again, I want to say it was a very strong quarter operationally. We feel good about where we're going to the second half of this year. I want to thank all the Emerson executives and operational people around the world in delivering an outstanding second quarter in a still-challenging global environment. Thank you very much. Appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the conference call for today. Thank you for your participation, and you may now disconnect your lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>