<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1407791" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-11-09</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1562</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Controller, Enbridge Energy Co., Inc.">Jody L. Balko</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Patrick D. Daniel</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">J. Richard Bird</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="TD Securities">Linda Ezergailis</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Canaccord Genuity Corp.">Juan Plessis</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="BMO Capital Markets (United States)">Carl L. Kirst</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Scotia Capital">Matthew Akman</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Dominion Securities, Inc.">Robert Kwan</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="CIBC World Markets, Inc.">Paul Lechem</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="FirstEnergy Capital Corp.">Steven I. Paget</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Reuters">Scott Haggett</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Argus Media">Justin Amoah</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Bloomberg News">Bradley Olson</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="The Globe and Mail">Nathan Vanderklippe</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to the Enbridge Inc., Third Quarter 2011 Financial Results Conference Call. I would now like to turn the meeting over to Jody Balko. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Natasha. Well thank you and good morning, and welcome to Enbridge Inc.'s third quarter of 2011 earnings call. With me this morning are Pat Daniel, Chief Executive Officer; Richard Bird, Executive Vice President, Chief Financial Officer and Corporate Development; and John Whelen, Senior Vice President and Controller.</p>
          <p>This call is webcast, and I encourage those listening on the phone lines to view the supporting slides, which are available on our website. A replay and podcast of the call will be available later today, and a transcript will be posted to our website shortly thereafter.</p>
          <p>The Q&amp;A format will be the same as always. The initial Q&amp;A session is restricted to the analyst community, and once completed, we will invite questions from the media. I would also remind you that Jonathan Gould and I will be available after the call for any follow-up questions that you may have.</p>
          <p>But before I begin, I'd like to point out that we may refer to forward-looking information during the call. By its nature, this information applies certain assumptions and expectations about future outcomes, so we remind you it is subject to the risks and uncertainties affecting every business, including ours.</p>
          <p>This slide include a summary of the more significant factors and risks that might affect future outcomes for Enbridge, which are also discussed more fully in our public disclosure filings available on both the SEDAR and EDGAR systems.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'd like to turn the call over to Pat Daniel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks, Jody, and good morning, everyone. Thank you for joining us for a review of our third quarter results. As you know, earlier today, we were very pleased to announce that our adjusted earnings for the third quarter were $241 million or $0.32 a share. On a year-to-date basis that puts us at $385 million &#x2013; I'm sorry; $835 million of adjusted earnings or $1.11 per share, and this is an increase of roughly 10% relative to the same point last year.</p>
          <p>You will note that our GAAP earnings for the quarter of $4 million looks a little unusual. This is driven by the mark-to-market impact of several of our hedging programs. You're likely aware we actively work to remove market price volatility from our businesses and we will speak in a bit more detail on the dynamics giving rise to that accounting and outcome as we go through our morning.</p>
          <p>Based on a strong first three quarters, we are now very confident that 2011 will be yet another good year for Enbridge and we are now updating our guidance for 2011 to be near or slightly above the top end of the original guidance range of $1.38 to $1.48. The strong performance comes from all areas of the business and of course one of the main drivers during this quarter is the liquids pipeline segment where we've seen stronger than expected volumes on the mainline system. You'll recall that increasing volumes now drive higher returns from our Competitive Tolling Settlement that took effect at the start of the third quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to just review some of the more recent project announcements that we've made. And of course many of you on the line today will have been part of our annual investor conference in Toronto or New York at the beginning of October, but for any of you that weren't I would certainly encourage you to take the time to access a replay, go to the transcripts that are available on our website from that very thorough presentation. At that time, the management team spoke at length about the significant opportunities that we have ahead of us and it was right across the organization. What was at the time an $8.5 billion secured project portfolio is now even bigger as we've been successful on several fronts, even since Enbridge Day. And as a result we now have commercially secured nearly 50% of the total growth capital that we expect to have invested by 2015. We'll continue to update this perspective, of course, as we announce additional projects along the way.</p>
          <p>In our gas businesses we are very pleased to have now acquired a 71% ownership of the Cabin Gas Plant development in the Horn River Basin and that's from Encana and other area producers, and our offer to the producers holding the remaining 29% remains open. As it currently stands, this represents a $1.1 billion investment and it's a great fit for Enbridge. The Cabin Gas Plant development enables us to bring our project construction and operational expertise to bear in the Canadian midstream space, having of course been in this business for many years in Texas and Oklahoma through Enbridge Energy Partners. And then further in the long-term &#x2013; its long-term stable fee-based revenue is really complementary to the reliable business model at Enbridge that we speak so much about. And of course on top of it all there is further growth potential from this investment and &#x2013; as and when capacity beyond the initial two phases are required. So we are very pleased with that investment.</p>
          <p>Also in our renewable power business, you have seen last week that we have acquired a 50% ownership interest in the Lac Alfred Wind Farm Project from EDF Canada, and we're very pleased with this opportunity to enter the growing Qu&#xE9;bec renewable energy market, especially with a partner that has the proven development and operations track record that EDF has.</p>
          <p>The project, of course, has the same low-risk contractual framework as the rest of our renewable portfolio. And it's a turnkey project. It has a long-term PPA in place with Hydro-Quebec. And just as importantly, it further reduces Enbridge's commitment to environmental &#x2013; it reinforces our Enbridge's commitment to environmental stewardship and it really progresses us further towards this goal of achieving an environmentally neutral footprint.</p>
          <p>So in addition to those announced projects, we're continuing to make excellent progress on several other investment opportunities that we spoke to at Enbridge Days. These of course include our liquids pipeline market access initiatives, and to expand access for U.S. Bakken crude oil and for Western Canadian crude oil to additional markets in eastern PADD II and Canada, as well as to the U.S. Gulf Coast. The progress on these projects has been significant and notable, since the signing of the CTS agreement, which has provided toll certainty to our shippers.</p>
          <p>And I'll just reiterate my Enbridge Day comment that we've never before seen a broader or deeper array of attractive investment opportunities as what we have today, providing us with a very high level of confidence that we can achieve a growth rate in EPS averaging 10% through the middle of the decade. At the same time, of course, we continue to attach the highest priority to operational safety and integrity, as we mentioned at the Investor Day conference.</p>
          <p>So with that brief update on some of the more recent business development initiatives, what I'll now do is hand it over to Richard to get into the financial results for the quarter in a little more detail. Richard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good morning. So picking up on slide 10 of the visuals, I'm going to start by spending a few minutes on the difference this quarter between our raw GAAP earnings and the adjusted earnings, and the slide depicts the net adjustments to the raw GAAP earnings to arrive at adjusted earnings over the last four years just to put the current quarter in context.</p>
          <p>Some of the more significant noise factors that we've adjusted out have been the gains on asset sales, the effect on future income taxes of tax rate changes, and the market-to-market movements on the hedges we put in place in support of our reliable business model, which is playing up the effect in the current quarter. All of the hedges we put in place through financial derivatives are designed to reduce the volatility of cash flow and earnings due to movements in exchange rates or interest rates or commodity prices and we do that by locking in the rates applicable to future cash flows.</p>
          <p>Moving to the next slide as an example, the new CTS agreement means that our revenues on the Canadian Mainline are now received in U.S. dollars. And shortly before the CTS agreement was approved by the NEB, we were able to lock in the exchange rate at a better rate than the forecast that we based our agreement on and bring our U.S. dollar exposures in line with the way we've managed our other U.S. dollar exposures, generally about 80% hedged through the 2015 forecast period, a little higher in the front end.</p>
          <p>So as the future unfolds and the exchange rates fluctuates our cash flows and our adjusted earnings will be relatively unaffected and as a result our ability to achieve that 10% average growth rate that Pat referred to, will depend largely on the underlying performance of the business, and not much on exchange rates.</p>
          <p>So moving to the next slide, slide 12, and coming back to the big difference between the raw GAAP earnings and the adjusted earnings this quarter, we saw the Canadian dollar weakened abruptly and substantially at the end of the quarter closing at a spot rate of C$1.04 per US$1 versus C$0.96 per US$1 at June 30.</p>
          <p>As the future unfolds, if the exchange rates were to remain at September 30 levels, we would see in each quarter our U.S. dollar revenues coming back as a larger number of Canadian dollars than we were planning on. We would need to use part but not all of these extra Canadian dollars to settle the hedges which mature and are realized in each quarter. We'd still be ahead of what we were planning on in each and every quarter, and the slide depicts this result based on an illustrative $0.05 weakening, which ties exactly into our MD&amp;A FX sensitivity disclosure. You can see that the net impact is muted by the hedges as intended, but would still be favorable by about $64 million over the period and in fact that's just the picture that you would see for our adjusted earnings.</p>
          <p>Our foreign exchange hedges, however, are marked-to-market each quarter under GAAP, so the whole change in the mark-to-market value of the derivatives is charged to the GAAP earnings in the current quarter, and that's a $248 million number for the example on the slide. So the irony is, even though we would like to see the substantially weaker Canadian dollar of September 30 continue, it does play up that large mark-to-market noise effect you see in the third quarter GAAP earnings.</p>
          <p>Moving onto slide 13 I will next go over the adjusted earnings results, which as Pat mentioned, were once again stronger than we expected and are now trending toward top end of our full year guidance range or slightly above.</p>
          <p>You can see from the summary on the slide that all of the segments are up for the third quarter versus the prior year with the biggest increases coming from Liquids Pipelines, Gas Pipelines, Processing and Energy Services and the Corporate segment. And in fact, it is these same three areas that are contributing more than we expected resulting in the guidance bump.</p>
          <p>Within Liquids Pipelines, the strength for the quarter and expected for the full year came primarily from the Canadian Mainline now operating under the new CTS agreement. The primary factor is throughput volume, which has been a little stronger this year than we expected including through the third quarter. I'll come back to the Mainline in a few minutes. Our regional oil sands system is another source of strength in Liquids Pipelines.</p>
          <p>Gas distribution was up again this quarter, but we do expect to give back some of the year-to-date strength in the fourth quarter. In Gas Pipelines, Processing and Energy Services, offshore had another weak quarter for the same reasons as discussed last quarter and our full year guidance allows for continued weakness. Aux Sable had an okay quarter, but we are expecting a strong finish. And Energy Services continued to benefit from unusually favorable arbitrage opportunities, which we expect to continue during the fourth quarter, though not indefinitely and I'll come back to this business as well.</p>
          <p>Sponsored investments are on track with our expectations and Corporate is doing a little better primarily on lower financing costs and we also expect to start seeing stronger earnings from Noverco. So taken altogether, we are seeing a $0.03 or $0.04 upward momentum in earnings per share for the full year relative to our look at the second quarter, bearing in mind that a good part of this is from the unusually favorable marketing margins.</p>
          <p>Moving to the next slide, the one titled CTS revenue determinants. A number of you have been looking for additional information on how to roll forward our CTS earnings. So we've included a discussion of CTS revenue determinants and costs in the MD&amp;A. The revenue determinants that are discussed there can be organized into a formula as laid out on the slide. The only variable in this formula which isn't straight forward is the scale factor and it's required because although a significant component of actual revenue does consist of heavy barrels moving from Hardisty to the U.S. border at the Residual Benchmark Toll, it also consists of various other commodity types and various other receipt and delivery points to which different tolls apply, as well as non-toll revenue and Line 8 and Line 9 revenue. So the scale factor is intended to allow for these other revenues.</p>
          <p>From the third quarter data you can back-calculate the scale factor to be 1.20. It will tend to be more variable from quarter-to-quarter than it will be for a full year and we also expect it to decline over time as some of the non-IJT revenues that the scale factor is capturing decrease as a percentage of total revenue.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 15, our Energy Services business model, which I said I'd come back to given that it's been a prolific money maker this year. Because it's been so profitable I'll just go into a little more detail on this; our Energy Services business employs several distinct strategies to generate earnings. They are simplest to understand separately, though in reality many transactions include a combination of these strategies. There are parts of this business which operate on a simple fee-for-services basis.</p>
          <p>For example, barrels are aggregated in the field on behalf of producers, nominated on feeder and mainline systems and delivered to a buyer all for a fixed fee. This is the bread and butter part of the business. It's stable. It doesn't have a lot of profit, but it does provide good insight into where the best markets for crude are, and the challenges of getting it there.</p>
          <p>The big money makers are the arbitrage strategies. There are always modest arbitrage opportunities to be captured by a services business with the right assets and skill sets. And some of the time, the margins on these arbitrage plays open up quite significantly. They also tend to close back down as competitors figure out how to replicate, or as storage and pipeline facilities are expanded.</p>
          <p>So I won't spend any time on the point in time or storage arbitrage, because I think the concept is pretty well understood, other than to say that Contango, can be captured either by storing barrels in a tank or by moving barrels through a pipeline. I'll come back to the location arbitrage with an example of how it works in just a moment.</p>
          <p>So you make money in this business either on the strength of your skills in ferretting out opportunities and the logistical mechanics to capture them, or on the strength of a proprietary asset position, which is located advantageously. But you make the best money when you combine both of these, skills and assets, and that's what we do.</p>
          <p>Our Energy Services group doesn't own many assets, but it does lease storage and railcars. And most importantly it holds nomination rights on a number of key pipelines as a result of its historical use of these lines. So it holds a scarce resource in times of apportionment on these lines, which makes it difficult for others to replicate certain arbitrage plays.</p>
          <p>And moving then to the mid-continent arbitrage slide, location arbitrage opportunities do come in many places and with many different commodities. For example, moving condensate from Conway in Mont Belvieu to Edmonton for diluent has been a profitable business for us, but the one that makes the biggest difference in 2011 is a mid-continent light crude arbitrage depicted on this slide. And that depiction is a partial example of the strategy. There are actually many places that crude can be sourced from that are experiencing the mid-continent discount and may paths that it can be moved on to reach the Eastern PADD II market, but the variation depicted on the slide is the simplest.</p>
          <p>The Eastern PADD II light crude refinery market tends to price off of LLS at St. James as its default supply option. On a delivered basis at Patoka, this creates a theoretical arbitrage of up to $26 a barrel based on the recent WTI to LLS discount.</p>
          <p>It isn't possible to capture all of this theoretical arbitrage, but even a modest part of it makes very nice profit. As I said earlier, it's this business that's a good part of the reason for our latest guidance bump, coupled with the strength in liquids pipelines. But we're certainly not counting on these unusual margin opportunities to persist for long.</p>
          <p>And with that I'll turn it back to Pat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Richard. So, let me just very quickly summarize, first of all, it's shaping up to be yet another <mark type="audio gap" /> (19:36) earnings growth. So much so that we're now increasing our earnings guidance to be near or slightly above the upper end of the original guidance range of $1.38 to $1.48. Secondly, we continue to have great success in securing new projects across all of our business units and finally we're even more confident that we can achieve an annual growth rate in EPS averaging 10% through 2015 based on conservative mainline volume and the project securement assumptions.</p>
          <p>So that concludes our prepared remarks for this morning and now I'd like to ask the operator to open up the phone lines to take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> I would first like to invite all analysts first for questions and please allot one question at a time and return back in the queue for any follow-up questions. Later, we will prompt for media questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Please stand by for your first question. Your first question comes from the line of Linda Ezergailis with TD Securities. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Congratulations on a very strong quarter. I have a question with respect to your CTS details, and my understanding is that there is a provision that allows parties to renegotiate the settlement if Keystone XL is not approved. And I'm wondering if you can elaborate on that in the event that a presidential permit is not granted, or if it's delayed. At what point would a delay potentially trigger a renegotiation and are there parameters laid out for the renegotiation or do you just start from a totally new beginning?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Linda, the understanding that I have, and Richard or Jody correct me if I'm wrong on this, is that if by the end of 2012, the presidential permit has not been granted to XL, then the producers have the right to renegotiate CTS with us because it has been negotiated under the understanding that that system would ultimately be in place. The parameters around which it would be renegotiated are not defined; I think we would just have to work closely with our customers as we always have to work out a mutually agreeable <mark type="ph" /> toll (22:37) arrangement with them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; thank you. And just as a follow-up detailed question. Your regional oil sands earnings growth year-over-year is $7 million, how much of that can be attributed to a change in your depreciation rate versus higher volumes and tolls?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jody, yeah, I don't have that detail handy, and that's probably going a little more granular than we would go into in our disclosures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, maybe you can just help us understand the magnitude of the change in depreciation rate on an annualized basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I don't have either, Linda, basically we've re-synced the depreciation rates on those systems to reflect the longer tenor of some of the contracts more recently entered into like the effective 45-year term on the Woodlands Pipeline serving the Kearl project but I don't have the detailed breakdown of what the impact of that has been on earnings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe we can ask Jody and Jonathan to get back to you after the call and then provide what detail we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Juan Plessis with Canaccord Genuity. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much. Appreciate the additional information on the CTS. Given that this was the first quarter that the mainline operated under the CTS, first, could you tell us if the contribution in the quarter was one that would be, I guess for the lack of a better word, a good run rate going forward excluding the impact of throughput? Or was there something in the quarter that may have helped improve earnings like future tax benefits that may not necessarily be recurring?</p>
          <p>And secondly, with the integrity plan and the line replacement 6B, should we be looking to see the U.S. portion of the IJT increasing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, Juan, with regard to the first part of the question, I think it's fair to say that this should be a reasonable run rate recognizing that with the volume sensitivity it will depend on production and volumes out of the oil sands and out of the Bakken, but I think it's &#x2013; there is really nothing unusual outside of volume that's been &#x2013; that drove the very strong performance to date. And, sorry; the second part is with regard &#x2013; oh, the IJT. And Richard, can you comment on the split on the IJT?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. So, yeah, couple things. One is, as Pat said, there isn't anything unusual about the quarter, although I think we likely will see that scale factor that's referred to in the &#x2013; on the slide something that tends to drift downward over time. And yes, with respect to the IJT and the split of that IJT, the additional capital on 6B will be one of the factors that will play into that, but of course there are other factors that play into that as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Juan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Carl Kirst with BMO Capital Markets. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, everybody. Also great quarter and do appreciate the color here on the CTS. Actually, Richard, you had just sort of hit on the scale factor and as you sort of reiterated the expectation for it to perhaps drift down over time, I didn't know if maybe there was any additional color we could get on that in the sense that is this something that ultimately you expect to drift down to parity over the life of the 10 years of the contracts or is it something that could come a little bit of a sharper angle? I don't know if there is any more color that can be added on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, probably not a lot until we get another few quarters of experience, Carl. But I don't foresee it coming down abruptly, it's just that there is a whole pile of mix, what I call the mix factors that will change over time as we move ahead and generally our cross-border shipments will tend to be bigger as a percentage of the total and so those extra revenues that are being picked up by the scale factor will be smaller as a percentage of the <mark type="ph" /> toll. (27:16) So driving directly off of cross-border volumes and tolls will give us slightly lower impact as we move forward through time. But I don't expect it to be an abrupt change, it's probably hardly going to be noticeable over the period of a quarter; as we get out five years it might be more noticeable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's helpful. The second question really is just looking at the overall better volumes on the mainline, also trying to kind of get a sense of has that dynamic continued here into November. And I guess one of my questions is, are we seeing anything abnormal in those volume flows, or is just purely a function of production out of the oil sands, out of the Bakken. Because what I was trying to get to was is there any &#x2013; you noticed or you mentioned the mid-continent arbitrage, I didn't know if there was an arbitrage going on from Canada to PADD II such that we were seeing a correlation for instance between the great results of energy services as well as the higher volumes in the Canadian mainline, and I just wanted to be cognizant of that if that were true.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think it's fair to say, Carl, that there isn't any particular factor other than the general issue around CTS and the tolling certainty that the shippers now have that makes it even more attractive for a spot barrel to move on our system and for shippers to commit to the Enbridge system as a result of that. Just the strong production of course because of relatively strong crude oil pricing and we'll see that strengthen up further through the U.S. Midwest markets as more refining capacity moves to be able to produce &#x2013; to process Canadian heavy. But nothing unusual in that would cause that to significantly swing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's very helpful. And then as far as those current volumes lasting into November, have we continued to see that or has it been more variable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I haven't seen the October numbers yet but certainly our expectation is that we'll continue to see roughly comparable strength in the fourth quarter as what we've seen in the first three quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great; thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Carl.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Matthew Akman with Scotia Capital. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone. Couple of questions on marketing. First of all, Richard you mentioned that there is some asset lease agreements that you guys have in place and I'm just wondering approximately how long those last?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Those are typically fairly short ended railcars a matter of years tanks in some cases going out five, 10 years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thanks. And separately on marketing, given your ramp up in the overall field services business in Canada, is there interest in the organization in NGL marketing in Canada in the same way as someone like <mark type="ph" /> Kiera (30:45) does?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well not in a big way, I guess, Matt, you realize that we are now just entering into the Canadian midstream business and don't have the same position either on the gas or NGL side that we would have in Texas and Oklahoma where we do have marketing associated with some of the gas and some of the NGL that we move. Also remembering that Aux Sable and Alliance are the main points to which the NGLs get directed and marketing is done through the owners and through the Aux Sable Liquids Plant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And just one more question if I might on, this is for Richard on your tax profile, on the supplementary cash flow information, it looks like you guys haven't paid any cash tax this year and you've transferred the renewables down to ENF which I presume had some nice tax attributes. So I'm wondering if going forward in the next two, three years, you think you're going to pay much in the way of cash, is your cash tax rate going to rise?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys. Those are my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Matthew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Robert Kwan with RBC Capital Markets. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just on CTS and the scale factor and what's in there, I know you mentioned oil allowance revenues and some terminaling, I'm just wondering whether it's better to think about that number almost as an absolute dollar amount where the oil allowance is going to move with crude pricing and then terminaling should probably grow as volumes grow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the oil allowance will tend to grow as volumes grow as well, so it will be a factor not just of crude prices which by the way we tend to hedge as we do with most things, but also of volumes because with allowances as a percentage of volumes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I guess, is to better to think about it though as a more of an absolute dollar amount in the quarter and if that is the case was that absolute amount in the quarter pretty representative of where you think you would be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but it was representative of the volumes that were shipped during the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's great. Thanks. And then just last question I have you talked about Energy Services and one of the advantages being historical apportionment rights and you highlighted Ozark there and Ozark has kind of reached a point on nominations that seem to be a little bit ridiculous just given the constraints. So I'm just wondering have there been any complaints from other shippers given your position in the line as well or is it very well documented that the historical rights are definitely for the benefit of your Energy Services division?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have heard nothing to indicate any concern about our participation on the line as a shipper Robert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think that's pretty well known title which is our Energy Services business unit has been on the line in good times and bad since we first put the asset into operation. So no there has been no issue there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay that's great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Robert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from a line of Paul Lechem with CIBC. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning. I believe the open seasons for the Flanagan South and Wrangler pipelines have ended is there anything you can &#x2013; any comments you could make on how those went and the corral rate of that, is there &#x2013; given the uncertainty of the Keystone XL process, are there any thoughts about expanding the Flanagan South to a larger volume than the initial capacity you laid out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Paul we received significant commitments on both the Flanagan South and the Wrangler segments in the open seasons. And as is always the case with an open season, the commitments include conditions, sometimes on terms, sometimes the rate at which volumes ramp up or whether participants are interested in equity and we're currently in discussions with shippers now to accommodate those conditions. So it's a little early for us to give a definitive response to that, but we expect to conclude those discussions with sufficient volumes to proceed with both segments of the line, but you're going to have to wait just a little bit longer for us to be able to firm that up. And we have not really seen any move as a result of &#x2013; and to answer the second part of your question, any move to see a change in the volume metric commitments as a result of uncertainty around XL, but we are pleased with the response that we received on both those open seasons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. If I can slip one more question in. Given the volume of projects you've moved forward over the last quarter, has that put your international expansion efforts &#x2013; have they taken a little bit of a backseat here or you still looking to go forward on that front?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're still looking to go forward on that front, and as we indicated at Enbridge Days it's not that we see any urgency in a number of the new initiatives that we have at Enbridge. Whether it's international, whether it's power transmission or the potential to get into the gas-fired power generation, no dramatic urgency on those, but they are long-term growth platforms that we think will continue to put forward this tremendous growth story at Enbridge beyond the middle of the decade. So we have not changed in any way our approach on international, still are looking at prospects in South America and also some potential as we indicated to feed LNG into the Asian market from countries like Australia, Indonesia, et cetera, but certainly not slowing that down. We expect it'll be part of the long-term growth story of Enbridge.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Steven Paget. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Again, Steven Paget from FirstEnergy. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. We've been hearing about possible bottlenecks anticipated at Superior. With lots of capacity going in, of course, but maybe not so much demand pull, is this behind the 50,000 barrel a day Line 5 expansion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The Line 5 expansion is primarily to feed through to our Eastern Canadian and PADD II expansion strategy where we're seeing the demand to &#x2013; from the perspective here in Alberta, to push crude oil further east and potentially in the longer term totally reverse Line 9 to be able to have access to the East Coast. So it's really more of a demand for incremental crude oil in Eastern PADD II and in Canada, than it is a bottleneck at Superior. We also of course, as we are just discussing are looking at the same kind of the Southern access pull and push, but it's primarily to feed that eastern market, Steven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. That's it from me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from the line of Carl Kirst with BMO Capital Markets. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Sorry, just a quick follow-up on Cabin Gas and just with respect to the initial capital that's being put in for phases I and II, if we do hit phases III and beyond, will there be sort of incremental pickup on marginal returns because of the fixed asset base, or is it as phases III and beyond get done as we put in more processing trains, for instance, that we're going to kind of maintain sort of the original fee-based targeted of 12% type ROE? Just wondering how the future development potential may play out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We should have Al Monaco here to respond to that, but Richard can you address it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the &#x2013; revenue model for subsequent phases is very similar to the first phase, Carl. So, no, we don't capture scale benefits, those effectively are passed to the customer and we continue to earn roughly the same rate of return.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. That clears up. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Carl.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Scott Haggett with Reuters. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I'm wondering, given the uncertainty in Keystone, should the line not proceed &#x2013; what capacity does Enbridge have to pick up those volumes and move them to the U.S. market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Scott. You were a little bit hard to hear, but I think your question is along the line, should XL not proceed what capacities does Enbridge have. And it's very hard to give you a one number answer to that because as always the system as big and as complex as ours, the bottleneck shifts from one area to another. The &#x2013; I think it's fair to say that the current bottleneck that we have in our system would be from Superior down into the Chicago and Flanagan area and but suffice it to say that we do have sufficient capacity available and or relatively low cost expansions to be able to accommodate most of at least the early volumes of what would have moved on Keystone XL.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your next question comes from the line of Justin Amoah with Argus Media. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking my call. I just wanted to follow-up on Wrangler and Flanagan South. Do you guys see the decision or the success of Wrangler as contingent up on the delay or disapproval of Keystone XL?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And could that project still move forward if the Seaway pipeline is reversed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it could and Seaway of course would &#x2013; if reversed would bring additional capacity to the Cushing south area but as well we see the potential for, at some point in time, further capacity again beyond that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So is there room for three pipelines out of Cushing to the Gulf Coast or two in your opinion, or how do you see that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think &#x2013; well, it's a very good question, Justin. I think the question is over what term and what periods of time you are talking. I think we've made the point at Enbridge right from the outset that the best way to introduce a bigger volume of Canadian crude oil into the Gulf than what is currently moving is incrementally, so I think in a lot of ways having several horses in the race is going to gradually move further crude into that market. But the potential would be there at some point in time for all of them to proceed on the basis of the huge refining capacity in the Gulf and the very big reserves and resources available in the oil sands and in the Bakken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Bradley Olson with Bloomberg. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. My question is just about what potential you see out there for opposition &#x2013; excuse me, what potential do you see there for opposition to these two alternatives? Is there any chance that the same people who have turned against the Keystone XL line would begin to focus on these alternatives that you're proposing? That's actually something that TransCanada's CEO Russ Girling told us at some point in an interview.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wasn't aware of that comment, Bradley. But what we're talking about is expanding in existing right of way and existing systems, putting further volume through existing systems in an incremental way rather than a big new construction project. So, I would find it surprising if the opposition &#x2013; to that, it's just basically expansion of an existing service that we're referring to and I guess in pretty much all cases use of existing right of way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess the idea is the Cushing to Gulf line, as far as I know wouldn't be existing right of way, but I just wanted to ask if the same folks that are targeting Keystone XL and Northern Gateway might sort of turn their interest as it looks like there may be issues surrounding the Keystone XL pipeline. And also just so I can clarify, TransCanada's CEO did not say that particularly about Enbridge; it was just a general comment about other pipeline options.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, and by the way, I certainly agree with that point that opposition to something that is as well supported as XL is not a good precedent for the industry. We think it's very important to be able to keep this country and North America operating efficiently, to be able to deliver energy to those that need it. And so I think that's very relevant.</p>
          <p>Going back to your point about Cushing South, our intention would be to be adjacent to or very near existing right of way. It may not be actually on the right of way, but it wouldn't result in a significantly different route. So would be extension and widening of existing right of ways in most cases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Nathan Vanderklippe with The Globe and Mail. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, just I guess following on some of these recent questions. But do you have a sense of how many years of expected growth in Canadian oil production you'll be able to manage with your existing system?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nathan, that's &#x2013; so what you are saying is that with the existing system with no change at all, I'll have to get back to you and quantify a number there because we've got bottlenecks at various points in the system. I can't give you the exact number on that but it's important to note that we can accommodate significantly more capacity with very low capital. For example, the next expansion of our Alberta Clipper project is a relatively low capital incremental pumping capacity. Now we do have constraints south of Superior from Superior to the Chicago area, again incremental pumping capacity. So relatively low cost expansion from where we are, but hard to give a definitive answer to your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just a clarification with regards to your Energy Services business, did I understand correctly that you are able to move some of those volumes by rail to achieve some of these arbitrage opportunities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes we are, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question comes from the line of <mark type="ph" /> Grey Gibbard with Energy Intelligence. (48:53) Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I was just wondering if you could give a couple more details about the Line 9 reversal plan. I was just wondering if you had a timetable in mind and if you had any thoughts as to how much capacity a reversal of Line 9 could &#x2013; what that capacity of Line 9 would be? And also if you had any worries about the East Coast U.S. PADD 1 refining segments since so many of those refineries are up for sale or might be shuttered? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Line 9 reversal is in a stage of discussion with potential users and the discussions range all the way from use of Canadian crude oil in Montreal to the potential to move the crude oil to Portland, Maine and reversing the Portland pipeline and around into the Philadelphia market. And my recollection and somebody correct me if I'm wrong, but I think the capacity on Line 9 reversed in the range of 170,000 barrels a day and I'm getting nods around the table. The issue with regard to Philadelphia refineries is one that we stay in touch with very closely there is a pretty strong indication that being able to move Canadian light or synthetic crudes into that market would help with the viability of those refineries and I think that's an important consideration as they look at their future. So that's one of the drivers is really to address and improve the economics of that refining business in the Philadelphia area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd now like to turn the call over to Jody Balko for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have any further items. Thank you, very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation. You may all now disconnect. Good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>