<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1367015" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-08-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2090</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Luca Torchia</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Luigi Ferraris</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer, Director &amp; GM">Fulvio Conti</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="UniCredit Bank AG Milan Branch">Javier Suarez</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd. (Italy)">Antonella Bianchessi</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Alberto Gandolfi</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="JP Morgan">Javier Garrido</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Bank Plc (Italy)">Susanna Invernizzi</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International Ltd.">Pablo Cuadrado</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Centrobanca">Edoardo Montalbano</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening ladies and gentlemen. This is Luca Torchia speaking. Welcome to Enel's 2011 Interim Results Presentation. Today, we are here with us Mr. Luigi Ferraris, the Chief Financial Officer and then Mr. Fulvio Conti, the Chief Executive Officer will be joining us in a few minutes.</p>
          <p>I will handover to Mr. Luigi Ferraris for the presentation and then usual Q&amp;A session will follow. Thank you very much again. And please Luigi, start.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to our 2011 interim results presentation. I'd like to start the session by quickly reviewing the general macroeconomic trends across the areas in which we operate. Reflecting on the assumptions underlying our current industrial trend, the gradual upward trend observed in 2010 has continued with demand growth registered in the first half of this year in Italy, Russia, Slovakia and Latin America. As far as Spain is concerned, if we consider the demand on a like-for-like basis, the trend is about 0.4% down.</p>
          <p>Let me now run you through our main efficiency actions starting with slide number three. As far as The Enel-Endesa synergies program is concerned, we continue to deliver above our targets. In the first half of 2011, the combined actions between Enel and Endesa recorded &#x20AC;522 million synergies, of which &#x20AC;464 million regarding Endesa and &#x20AC;58 million, Enel.</p>
          <p>Adding up the above-mentioned synergies program and Endesa's own Zenith program, which has delivered &#x20AC;82 million, we recorded a total amount of &#x20AC;604 million, which means about 60% of the full year target. Therefore, we are very confident that at least we will deliver the full-year 2011 synergies target as we have always done in previous years.</p>
          <p>Moving on to Zenith program on slide number four, Enel is continuously progressing on each sections aimed at optimizing cash flows. On this chart, I would like to draw your attention to our total savings contribution during the first half of 2011, for the cumulative amount of &#x20AC;510 million versus 2008, of which &#x20AC;410 million relates to EBITDA improvements and &#x20AC;100 million to working capital optimization.</p>
          <p>At this stage, we have achieved more than 80% of our total global targets i.e., &#x20AC;3.5 billion versus 2008. On top of these initiatives, let me now introduce you a second wave of the Zenith program aimed at optimizing the costs of group, staff and services.</p>
          <p>Moving on chart number five. These new initiatives which involves all of our countries allows us to identify further saving for about &#x20AC;1 billion accumulated over the next four years in terms of cash flow. In particular, we are focusing our attention to streamlining general services processes and reducing our auxiliary activities all throughout groups support function to be become leaner, faster and less expensive. This is an important result, of course, not only in terms of optimization of our cash flows, but also as an additional step towards being a one company.</p>
          <p>And now, let me move to analyze the first half of 2011 results on chart number six. Let me provide you an overview of some of our key financial highlights. Group EBITDA increased by 0.6% as you can see in the slide during the periods we have recorded some positive and non-recurring and non-cash items relating to the re-evaluation of some assets after a change in the consolidation method and capital gains for a total amount of about &#x20AC;400 million.</p>
          <p>Net of these, EBITDA year-on-year declined by about 4%. This decline in recurring EBITDA includes the perimeter effect for assets sold last year in Spain of &#x20AC;96 million and for the disposal of our controlling stake in Hydro Dolomiti Energia of &#x20AC;26 million, a negative one-off effect in Columbia of &#x20AC;109 million, and generally unfavorable hydro conditions which worsened during the second quarter this year impacting Chile by &#x20AC;136 million and Italy by &#x20AC;66 million.</p>
          <p>On the positive side, we recorded a strong performance in the Market division in construction and networks and our Russian activities as well as the growth of Enel Green Power. Group net income stands at &#x20AC;2.5 billion or 5.2% higher than last year. This growth mainly resulted from the already mentioned effects and lower net financial charges versus first half 2010.</p>
          <p>I will be more specific on the later &#x2013; in the following charts. Let me also highlight that group net income has been positively affected by the previously mentioned revaluation of assets and capital gain. Net of these effects, group net ordinary income equals to about &#x20AC;2.3 billion. Net debt has increased during the first half of the year by about &#x20AC;1.2 billion to &#x20AC;46.1 million. I will provide more detail on this later on as well.</p>
          <p>Now, moving to chart number seven. Our net financial charges stand at &#x20AC;1.4 billion, registering a decrease of &#x20AC;356 million, mainly as a result of the following: as far as interest charges are concerned, the lower financial results recorded at the end of June, substantially offsets higher interest charges on short-term debt.</p>
          <p>The decrease of other items by &#x20AC;368 million was due to the following: &#x20AC;100 million recorded in 2010 as a one-off regularization effect of the accrual in financial revenues from previous years related to tariff deficit; the positive impact of &#x20AC;110 million of lower liabilities related to the actualization of post-employment benefits. Other items by &#x20AC;156 million mainly relating to the favorable ruling by Spanish National Court on Enel's appeal of previous year income tax.</p>
          <p>Also, let me remind you that our normalized annual average cost of gross debt stands at 4.9% versus 4.4% of the last year. Finally, the group's tax rate increased from about 29% in the first half of 2010 to about 32.5% in 2011. On a normalized basis, our annualized tax rate is about 31%, 32%, in line with full year 2010.</p>
          <p>Let's continue with an update on forward electricity sales activities on slide number eight. In Italy, we have fully hedged our 2011 production at an average base low price of about &#x20AC;71 per megawatt hour, and 60%, 65% of 2012 at an average base load price of about &#x20AC;75 per megawatt hour. Also, considering the positive effect of the most recent sales, which came in at &#x20AC;76.</p>
          <p>In Spain, we are fully hedged for 2011 and 55%, 60% for 2012 at an average price of about &#x20AC;56 per megawatt hour for both 2011 and 2012. In Latin America, we are 75%, 80% hedged for 2011 and 65% to 70% for 2012.</p>
          <p>In Slovakia, we are 100% hedged for 2011 and almost fully hedged for 2012 at an average price of about &#x20AC;52 per megawatt hour for 2011 and &#x20AC;66 for 2012. All of this will have to explain our EBITDA evolution on chart number nine, which provides an overview of all of our operations.</p>
          <p>I will now go through the EBITDA of each of our divisions in more detail, starting with Generation and Energy Management Italy on slide number 10. Overall divisional EBITDA remains stable and this is mainly the results of the following: a decrease n the generation margin of &#x20AC;112 million mainly closed by lower margin and hydro volumes; and an increase of &#x20AC;206 million in either items mainly due to the reevaluation of Hydro Dolomiti Enel assets after the change of the consolidation method in Enel Group from fully consolidated to proportional occurred on April 1, 2011 partially compensated for by the perimeter effects of the disposal.</p>
          <p>Let's move on to the EBITDA evolution analysis of the Market division on chart number 11. EBITDA totaled &#x20AC;326 million versus &#x20AC;193 million of first half 2010. This strong performance has been driven by the following effects: the increase of &#x20AC;100 million in the contribution from the free market, mainly thanks to higher electricity and gas margin partially compensated for by higher client-related costs and other minor items; an increase of &#x20AC;32 million in the regulated electricity market, mainly thanks to lower client-related costs.</p>
          <p>Moving now to chart number 12 on Domestic Infrastructure and Network division. EBITDA amounted to &#x20AC;2.25 billion, an increase of about 10% versus last year. This is the net effect of the following: the decrease of &#x20AC;40 million in the energy margin mainly due to negative price components on the tariff, partially compensated for by higher volumes distributed; higher connection fees of &#x20AC;136 million mainly related to energy producers; and &#x20AC;84 million, thanks to lower personnel costs and other minor items.</p>
          <p>Moving now to slide number 13, on the International operations, EBITDA decreased by about 5% or &#x20AC;43 million versus last year. This decrease came mainly from Centrel but was partially compensated for by increases from other countries. In particular, Slovensk&#xE9; Elektr&#xE1;rne recorded a decrease of &#x20AC;116 million totally attributable to the positive non-recurring <mark type="ph" /> neutral decommission (13:02) and provisional release in 2010. Without taking into accounts this one-off negative effects, EBITDA would have been in line with the first half of 2010. Russia increased by &#x20AC;62 million with generation activities contributing &#x20AC;43 million and supply activities contributing &#x20AC;19 million, mainly thanks to higher volumes.</p>
          <p>Before analyzing the remaining divisions, I would like to address your attention to our Russian generation activities on slide number 14. OGK-5 reported first half 2011 EBITDA of about &#x20AC;177 million or 40% up versus last year. This was mainly due to increasing power prices on the free market and higher capacity payments.</p>
          <p>Let's now move onto Endesa results on slide number 15. Well, first, let me remind you that numbers we report in this slide and in the following one are the results of the application of Enel Group's accounting principle, which might differ from Endesa's principle due to a difference in local standards.</p>
          <p>The Iberian division has recorded an EBITDA decrease of &#x20AC;299 million. This was due to the following: a decline of &#x20AC;193 million in the Generation and Supply business, which can be largely explained by the increasing energy costs related to the higher level of Spanish pool prices and a higher thermal component of the generation mix versus last year, partially compensated for by the increase of the last resolved tariff, higher volumes and better extra peninsular generation margins; an increase of &#x20AC;4 million in the Distribution business thanks to the implementation of the new regulation based on investments partially compensated for by lower connection fees versus last year; a decrease of &#x20AC;110 million in other items mainly due to the lower perimeter effects on the distribution asset sold last year and on the renewable sold to Enel Green Power.</p>
          <p>Let's turn to Latin America on chart number 16. The Latin American division has recorded an EBITDA decrease of &#x20AC;137 million. This has been mainly the result of the decrease of &#x20AC;32 million in the Generation business, mainly due to lower hydro production in Chile, which was partially compensated for by better margin Colombia and Peru, thanks to higher volumes. An increase of &#x20AC;12 million during the Distribution business mainly thanks to higher volumes distributed in Colombia and higher activity in Chile after last year earthquake, partially offset by the normalization Ampla's of regulated revenues in Brazil versus last year. And finally, a decrease of &#x20AC;107 million in other items mainly related to a one-off increase in Colombian patrimonial tax for amounts of &#x20AC;110 million recorded in the first quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>And now, let me review Enel Green Power on chart number 17. EBITDA totaled &#x20AC;876 million representing an increase of about 35% versus the first half of last year. This is mainly due to the following: a decline of &#x20AC;38 million in Italy and Europe mainly due the termination of the CIP 6 incentives; an increase of &#x20AC;84 million in Iberia, Latin America, which is mainly the result of the consolidation of the same for &#x20AC;41 million and overall higher prices in Iberia amounting to &#x20AC;34 million and higher prices in Chile and Panama as well; an increase of 24 million in North America thanks to higher volumes in wind and hydro production; and a one-off positive impact of &#x20AC;16 million indemnity on a renewal plant dispropriation; and finally an increase of &#x20AC;146 million mainly related to the fair value evaluation of net assets in Terraza, in some assets in Portugal in April as well as the capital gain on the asset sales to Gas Natural.</p>
          <p>With regards to the evolution of our net debt, you can see on chart number 18 that net of assets held for sale, overall net debt stands at about &#x20AC;46 billion. The &#x20AC;1.2 billion increase during the period is mainly due to dividend payments and tax payments partially offset by the operational cash flow.</p>
          <p>Our liquidity position is supported by the availability of committed credit lines aimed at serving the management of working capital. Also, taking into account cash and cash equivalents, liquidity at group level amounts to about &#x20AC;22 billion and allow us to cover 12 to 18 months of maturities. Please refer to the annexes for further details.</p>
          <p>Moreover, at the beginning of July, we issued on the European market, a market tranche bond targeted for institutional investors totaling &#x20AC;1.750 billion. This is in line with our plan to issue bonds in order to extend the average maturity of our medium and long-term debt. Since the beginning of the year, the total amount issued account for &#x20AC;2.2 billion at a weighted average cost of 4.6% and 8.6 years of average maturity.</p>
          <p>Finally, let me remind you, that the tariff deficit securitization started in January has allowed Endesa to cash in &#x20AC;3.6 billion further strengthening the consolidated group liquidity position.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention. And now let me hand over to Fulvio Conti for some final remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you Luigi. And good afternoon to all of you who are listening to this conference. Let me try to sum up and give you some takeaways from this presentation.</p>
          <p>I think the first and most illustrative item that I can speak of is the fact that our Italian operations, as a whole, Generation, Distribution and Sales are reporting first half of this year's margins which are slightly up versus last year. It's something that I think is worth for you to note. Italy is doing better year-on-year. I think this will continue in the second half of the year. And therefore, I think overall 2011 EBITDA numbers for Italy as a country will be at the very least in line with 2010, if not better.</p>
          <p>I also expect for the second half of the year to report additional positives. Our positive factors inching in, the new capacity and operations in Russia 420 megawatt sweat few dollars for us. I think the incremental capacity in Spain, I'm referring to the combined cycle and <mark type="ph" /> tackle (21:36) and following agreement, which 50% of which is owned by Endesa and as the repowering normalized, and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (21:43) also add to that.</p>
          <p>I think about the additional capacity that the Green Power will deliver, about 600 megawatts of incremental technologies sweating profitability for us. With the experience of July, I think the drop that we have endured over the last few months in South America is over. I do expect to have higher hydro volumes in LatAm. And I think also referring to our efficiency program to continue to enact through the Zenith 2 initiative and for lower financial expenses and much better profile of our second half income.</p>
          <p>All of this is leading me into a statement to maintain our commitments that we have delivered to you over the presentation in March of our financial targets for 2011 and I'm pretty positive about being able to deliver those numbers.</p>
          <p>Having said all of this, I think we are now open to take Q&amp;A questions. Please come in and raise your points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. We are now ready to start the Q&amp;A session. I remind you that we have people connected via Web and via phone calls, so we would be connecting from both. I understand that the first question is coming from Mr. Javier Suarez, UniCredit. So, please, Javier, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon to all of you. Three questions, if I may. The first one is on the distribution activity in Italy. I just wanted to have your first reading on the regulatory document that the regulator had issued, the first consultation document. And I just wanted to have your view on how do you read the document at first reading? How do you see &#x2013; the comment that on first of all, additional incentives apparently the regulator could include? And what is your view on the tax rate and the inflation rate that the regulator again could use in the calculation of the allowed internal tax draft for the next the regulatory period? That is the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question on the Generation business in Italy, could you please kind of quantify in absolute terms the level of margins for the generation activity year-to-date? What you are expecting for the second half of the year, also in absolute terms?</p>
          <p>And the third comment is on the markets condition in Italy. We have seen a significant expansion in the margin, if you could elaborate please the reason for that during the first half and what do you expect from the second half of the year? Many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Fulvio here. Let me give you a general comment about the draft of the regulators. As you can see from the document, this is not in any way or fashion the Armageddon that some you was thinking about. This is a plain continuation of the sweet, soft adjustment that have been instigated by previous agencies and this is confirmation that good common sense always prevail. Therefore, I'm very pleased to read the draft the way it is.</p>
          <p>Of course, this is a draft and will need a lot of work with the authority and I'm pretty sure that that will be possibly upside to it that will favor the profile that we have been showing of efficiency and the quality of our distribution network here in Italy to become a window for opportunities for even the regulators. Having said all of this, I'll leave it &#x2013; hand it over to Luigi for the individual questions. If you want to take on this detailed questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Let me start from the second question that you raised. The margin in Generation, Energy, Management division. All in all we have recorded in the first half of 2011, &#x20AC;142 per megawatt hour without taking into account the impact of the ancillary services, which means that &#x20AC;3 more or less than last year.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the Market division &#x2013; well in the first half, we had really an excellent performance from the division. The reason for that is our strategy of selecting specific segments of capital is starting to deliver also effects on our profitability. Therefore, if you look at the portion of our free markets, both electricity and gas but in particular in electricity, we can count in the first half of the year. On the unitary margin of &#x20AC;10 per megawatt hour or &#x20AC;10 per megawatt translated into megawatt tower. This is the first components.</p>
          <p>On the regulatory side that we registered any improvement mainly driven by efficiency and cost reduction, of course. And we expect to see this positive trend also to continue in the second part of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (27:42)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Antonella Bianchessi, Citi. Please, Antonella, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. A quick question, first of all if you can give a little bit to more detail on the Zenith 2 program, and from the back of it, you are able to upgrade your target for 2013, 2014? So, this is the first question. Second I just wonder if you can give a little bit of detail on the acceleration of the CapEx in Q2 and which are your estimates for the full year? And then if you can explain on the debt, I see that the taxes at the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (28:26) only &#x20AC;1.1 billion, so if you can explain how does it works? Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Antonella, good afternoon. It's Fulvio speaking here. I think answering your question, the way you are posing it will force us into next month's presentation to give you an idea about eternity because you are pushing out limits beyond reasonable borders at this point of time. Be content on the point that 2011 looks as promising as I was commenting to you in the market presentation in March and I am confirm you to that. And we have a good decent degree of up scoring positively on our commitment.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the rest of questions, Luigi, would you please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely, yes. Well, in the second quarter we had an acceleration in the CapEx, but let me also remind you that here we are talking about total CapEx in the first half lower than &#x20AC;3 billion. So, we are still by far below the original amount placed in our business trend. We foresee for the entire year a trend of CapEx which is going to be substantially in line with or slightly lower than our original target. In other words, what we are thinking of is to stay in the region as a group level of, say, &#x20AC;6.5 billion to &#x20AC;7 billion. That's what we foresee today.</p>
          <p>Of course, the projects are not being changing, so the total CapEx for filing the five years are still the same. There are no major changes in the project. There might be a positive impact of the delay in protocol, of course, which will end up with the reduction in the CapEx in the full year.</p>
          <p>When it comes to taxes, what happened in terms of cash is what normally happens every year. We have paid <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:53) in the region of &#x20AC;1.1 billion, of which is a little bit lower than last year, because last year we also had the payment of the third tranche of the famous substitute tax, which was in the region of &#x20AC;350 million at last tranche.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the tax rate, I confirm that 31%, 32%, as I said during the presentation, the difference versus last year is due to the fact that in 2010, we had to record some tax credit &#x2013; one-off tax credits at the level of energy Europe, Spain for a couple of hundred million euro. But on a full year basis, we are at 31%, 32%, so, no major changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just a quick follow-up question. So, can you give us your view on the tariff deficit securitization in Spain and also how you plan to refinance the &#x20AC;8 billion expiring over the next 12 months? It's going to be a long-term bond or do you think you can add up at the securitization procedure to cover it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Fulvio again. Definitely, we continue to see by talks that we have ongoing with the government. They are stubbornly pursuing the completion of that program to repay back the current deficit they're committed to during 2011.</p>
          <p>As you know, they've been trying even over the last few weeks only to see a moment of financial distress in the markets and therefore they decided not to take on the addition emission that was planned to be made in the month of June and July. That commitment continues to be unscathed.</p>
          <p>I think with the idea that we are meeting, as you know, we had cash, cash gain 3.6 of the peninsular deficit in about &#x20AC;400 million of the island deficit. So, we got &#x20AC;4 billion altogether. We are still confident that in September, October, possibly we're not even last week of August, depending on market conditions that they might be willing to carry on with this program. It's related to their credibility and its related to the fact that they don't want to add additional deficits vis-&#xE0;-vis their commitment to maintain the deficit at the current year at the level of &#x20AC;3 billion, no more than that.</p>
          <p>So, reasonably confident that of course we have to wait for the development of the market. And I know there is also a Web question on this subject coming from Oscar N&#xE1;jar with Santander, so I think this is answering also Mr. N&#xE1;jar's question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The question of Mr. N&#xE1;jar is related to our growth financial targets for full-year 2011. He is asking whether the full-year target that we've stated in particular EBITDA and net profit are recurrent. And then he is indicating some general questions relating to Spanish future institutional regulatory environment, as well as future forward sales in Italy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you want to take on this, about the &#x2013; I don't know...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...the recurrent?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. We have confirmed that &#x20AC;17.5 billion EBITDA and the &#x20AC;4.5 billion net profit. The &#x20AC;4.5 billion net profits are to be considered recurrent and therefore subject to dividend and to our dividend policy.</p>
          <p>Then, I think, there is another question regarding the forward sales in 2013 in Italy, at the moment the level of forward sales is I would say low. There is no liquidity and no huge demand. Of course, we have our ongoing and rolling sales activity to the final retailers of the small customer, the small office, which every 24 months as you know is renewed. But on the full markets, the liquidity is quite poor at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question will come from <mark type="ph" /> Enrico Bartoli <mark type="indiscernible" /> (35:48). Please, Enrico, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Three questions, please. Just a little clarification on your indication about EBITDA for this year, the 17.4, 17.5 does it include the <mark type="ph" /> &#x20AC;100 million (36:02) or one-off recorded in this first half or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It does.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It does, okay. Thank you very much. And, a second question is related to the net loss provision. I saw that you are having a significantly positive trend in your connection fees. If you can elaborate on that. And if you think that this trend is going to continue also in the second half of the year? And the same as related to the &#x20AC;84 million of cost cutting that you had in that division, is it something that we'll see also in the coming quarters?</p>
          <p>And the last question is related to Slovensk&#xE9;, your indication on the price of &#x20AC;56 per megawatt hour. It seems to me that the recent additions have been more closer to &#x20AC;60 per megawatt hour. If you confirm that and if you are seeing a positive trend in the average prices there probably because of the effect of the general market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to the infrastructure and network division, the positive trend in the connection of fees which, of course, regards mainly the producer, the connection regarding the Solar Photovoltaic activities. We expect that this trend &#x2013; this positive trend is going to continue in the second-half of the year as well.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the &#x20AC;84 million of &#x2013; actually, I mentioned other improvements also which there is a portion of cost optimization and there is also a portion of personnel reduction. I would say that &#x20AC;84 million cannot be considered pure cost cutting, the cost cutting here is in the region of &#x20AC;30 million to &#x20AC;34 million then we have other regulatory and minor adjustments.</p>
          <p>When it comes to Slovensk&#xE9; Elektr&#xE1;rne, what the &#x20AC;56 per megawatt power is the average of forward sales of the entire portfolio regarding 2012. Of course, we have seen also forward sales, I would not say close as &#x20AC;60, but at &#x20AC;58 for sure, yes. We have already built most of our portfolio of forward sales in 2012, so the remaining 9%,10% which is still to go, it will go very likely at &#x20AC;58, even &#x20AC;60. We see &#x20AC;60 plus in 2015. If we look at the forward sales in the Slovakian market, the expectation are higher than &#x20AC;60 per megawatt hour. For now we have sold 13% and we hope to continue in this way in the coming months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And sorry, just a follow up on that. Probably this is in line with your expectation in the previous months or it's something let's say slightly better than what could be expected in March?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I would say that after the Fukushima accident, this is in line with our expectation, so we have seen the premium because of that accident more of that because of the decision of abandoning the <mark type="ph" /> Luke (39:37) in Germany. So, for now, it's in line with the estimate debt after what happened in Fukushima.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Alberto Gandolfi, UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good evening. It's Alberto Gandolfi, UBS. First question is on Zenith program. Can I ask out of the &#x20AC;1 billion incremental figure you gave, how much of that is OpEx? How much of that will be seen EBITDA by 2015?</p>
          <p>Secondly, I think, one of the criticism that some commented about raising is about growth profile for Enel. So, for 2012, would it be possible, I know you cannot reveal anything, but would it be possible to talk about your expectations at EBITDA level macro-divisions. What do you think will be up, what do you think would be stable, what do you think could be down next year overall? So, if you can just give us your feel given you're so hedged in the unregulated part.</p>
          <p>Another question about your CapEx spend for the cash flow profile. In light of the recent worries about what's happening to the sovereign debt in the yield, both in Italy and in Spain, what is your contingency plan? Are you thinking about potentially taking CapEx down even further or I don't know, how you planning to tackle potentially an even higher interest rates on the financing?</p>
          <p>And I promise, very last one. Would it be possible to have the calculation of what's work in progress as of today? So, what is the CapEx, what is the cash already spent on development projects that do not contribute to earnings yet, because I think Mr. Fulvio Conti has been quite explicit in talking about asset developed above <mark type="indiscernible" /> (41:24) you already fully paid for but they are not contributing at all to the earnings. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alberto, Mr. Conti speaking, as you call him. Your question about the potential ups and downs of the 2012, cannot be answered, of course. I don't want to be sounding reticent. I just wanted to pinpoint the fact that we are here, discussing and commenting six months result and giving you &#x2013; looking forward statements to 2011. And you have to bear with us. We will be commenting about future long-term when will be appropriate with a plan and there is a presentation going on as scheduled as usual next March to speak about it.</p>
          <p>What I can demonstrate to you is the resilience our business, the ability for it through our generation mix in Italy and Spain, through our geographies' growing energy consumption and our ability to select category of customer to sell to. We are performing very well notwithstanding the difficulties and the vagaries of the market. So, be my guest &#x2013; be my guest, take your view about it and let us work on future plan presentation. I leave Luigi to answer to that final questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Well, Alberto, when it comes to the new Zenith program we mention &#x20AC;1 billion accumulated savings. Of course, those &#x20AC;1 billion I would say about 100% referred to OpEx and G&amp;A reduction. Therefore, they will affect the EBITDA. You will start seeing in 2012 a contribution of &#x20AC;120 million up to &#x20AC;300 million by the end of 2015.</p>
          <p>The other question was referred to how much we've already committed to in terms of new CapEx or what do we have in work in progress. Let me start for instance with renewable, as I think it was mentioned also yesterday during the conference call. The Enel Green Power division today has basically &#x20AC;1.8 billion under construction which are not delivering any EBITDA for now. So, I think this will be an upside particularly for them and of course for the Group as a whole.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the larger projects, first of all, as you know, we have not started spending for the very known reason. For Slovensk&#xE9; Elektr&#xE1;rne, we have not started spending. We are finalizing months three and four. And we are starting to &#x2013; sorry we have finalized the two gas combined cycle in Russia that are now in operation and therefore ready to deliver EBITDA and additional production. And we have capital projects, one in Latin America and one in Spain which are under construction and for now, we are talking about few hundred million euros. So, I would say that the CapEx are not fully reflecting even in this year, the full deployment into EBITDA.</p>
          <p>When it comes to your third question, do we have a contingency plan in case of worsening of the scenario regarding the cost of debt and the sovereign debts of each countries Italy, Spain, whatever it is? Well, as you might recall, I already said that we have a strong and solid liquidity position. So, we can count on &#x20AC;22 billion of liquidity position which allow us to cover the next 18 months of maturity easily. 80-plus percent of our total medium, long term debt is definitely at fixed rates and fully hedged. And when it comes to the CapEx, of course we have flexibility because the real commitment are the one that I just mentioned to you right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have another question coming from the website, <mark type="ph" /> Mr. Andrew Mulder, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (45:44) is asking whether the 2.5 times net debt on EBITDA target which we have for this year, assume further <mark type="indiscernible" /> (45:59) repayment on top of what you have already received?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, this is Luigi Ferraris speaking again. Let me clarify, the 2.5 net debt on EBITDA ratio is based on a net debt which is already netted of the Italian deficit financial receivable. So, this is not going to influence this ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Javier Garrido, JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Most of my questions have been answered. Just a very quick clarification from Mr. Conti, if I may. When you mentioned just for the Italian operations by year end to deliver at least the same gross or the same EBITDA in 2010 again here are they included in 2011 one-offs or this is just recurring EBITDA? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't get the question. They do contain the one-off for the EBITDA level. They are not when it comes to net income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I remember your response to the general company targets, but specifically on your comments regarding Italy, is it the same case then, as you are including one-offs in your comment about EBITDA in Italian operations being at least the same as last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, they do contain the one-off, both in the accounting numbers. But what I'm saying Italy is one element of the one-off. There are other geographies and other countries they have their own. What I wanted to say is that you might consider &#x2013; because of sum of your projection, Italy to be slowing down -- Italy is not slowing down. In its aggregate, Italy is delivering better results than you might expect and you are projecting, as a matter of fact, and that's what I wanted to stress with you, to correct your judgment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Susanna Invernizzi, Barclays.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good evening. Just a couple of follow up questions, please. So, first of all going back to the Zenith program, if you can again to, if you can maybe elaborate more on the geographical fleet of where these cost savings will be achieved. And also clarify if there are any risk factoring cost of &#x2013; use of the business that are maybe associated with this plan?</p>
          <p>And then, looking on the financial debt factor, I was just wondering if you're happy with the current fixed debt variable fleet or if you're going forward, then you're maybe considering a different factor? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Susanna, I must admit your last question came garbled to us, can you please repeat it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course. I was just wondering if you are happy with the approximately 80% split fixed variable debt, looking at the debt cluster always you are considering maybe dividing the structure of the debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Let me hand it over to Luigi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. The second wave of Zenith program is applied to the entire Enel works. So, to all the countries, parts of the Group. If you were just split by geography, well I can tell you that 55%, 60% of the expected saving of the one bigger you expected will come from Italy. The remaining from of debt will come mainly Iberia but also Latin America and international division. So, there will be an additional strong streamline of our support staff function and that will be where we got all the geographies of our Group. There will not be any exception.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the structure of our net debt, if I understand properly your question, well we are not changing our policy or our strategy. We are committed to maintain for the future the same ratio between fixed and variable. Of course, if you look at the end of June results, you will not see the positive impact of the new bonds in issuance that we have just finalized in the month of July for a total consideration of &#x20AC;1.75 billion, which is going of course to extend our maturity and to improve our ratio of fixed rate.</p>
          <p>80/20 would continue to be our target. If there is a slight change it's depending of course on market condition, but we confirm the commitment once the market is getting better to further issue some bonds to extend and to lock in also the rate. But for now, I think, we are in good shape. At the end of June taking into account also the positive impact of the last issuance, if we look at our ratio in terms of fixed or swapped interest rate, we are higher than 80% on the total medium and long-term debt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Pablo Cuadrado, Bank of America-Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon everyone. As well a lot of my questions has been already answered. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:09) just focus on two follow-ups, first one is basically if you can give us a sense either bit on the <mark type="ph" /> associate line (52:15), looking to Q1 results and Q2 results there is a slow down there. I guess that wasn't somehow a little bit expected, but basically you can guide us how do you split the performance going forward <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:26)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pablo. Pablo, sorry to interrupt you, but we are missing you so &#x2013; will you be so kind as to repeat the question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, basically, can you hear me good, is the first question is linked to the <mark type="ph" /> associate line (52:42) looking to the P&amp;L. At the end of Q1 the <mark type="ph" /> associate line (52:46) was close to &#x20AC;60 million. Looking to the Q2, there has been a significant slowdown. Basically, if you can guide as which is the expected performance that we should expect for the <mark type="ph" /> associate and the equity accounted (53:00) line during H2?</p>
          <p>And the second question very quickly is on Russia, very good results versus last year. Basically, if you can update us a little bit with your views. I think the Russian government in the last few weeks they have been talking with industry members about the gas price and power price increase for next year. I think overall, the news for that is coming that it seems pretty good, but basically you kind of update us which is your views for the next year pricing in Russia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me try to answer the Russian question. I continue to be very optimistic about the outcome of Russia liberalization process. You keep hearing about calls for moderation in price increases, we are well within those appeals. Because most of those refers to the area of the country like the Far East and Siberia where we have not present.</p>
          <p>Therefore, in euros in Western Russia where we want are to see less of that, the moderation is already part of our plant and a steady growth is also part of the willingness to favor additional investments and refurbishment and new capacity that are much needed to support the level of growth with their economy. So, I am pretty confident this will continue to be a good ongoing open surprise to all of you guys. Russia is good and it's a frontier of development for us.</p>
          <p>Luigi, on the first quarter to second quarter of share income from equity investments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we are talking about &#x20AC;60 million of improvement versus last year. Well there is not a specific reason for further difference. It's a matter also of timing of consolidated &#x2013; let me put it this way, the number on a step-by-step basis. The guidance for the full year, those numbers are mainly referred to our average investments in a company like <mark type="indiscernible" /> (55:24) like the investment that we have in the coal company in Indonesia and in Southern America where we also have some investments. So, in India and we expect that this positive trend is going to continue. Quarter by quarter we're going to record our portion on net profit report.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We have another question coming from the Web. He's <mark type="ph" /> Christian Schwartz, Pinco (55:55). He is asking whether we can provide clarity on the working capital developments in the first half despite interest vis-&#xE0;-vis with the tight deficit collection at Endesa.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Luigi again. Well, first of all let me remind you that we do not have in a working capital the financial receivable regarding the target deficit, because they are parts of our financial receivable cash and they're netted from the gross debts. When it comes to the working capital evolution, we had a negative evolution. In other words we have two negatives, but we have absorbed something like one bigger euro roughly speaking, cash. 50% of that is coming from an increase in the inventory and this is mainly due some increase in Spain in our gas stock. And also we have recorded in the inventory also the value equivalent for certificates for the future certificates. And this covering 50% of that.</p>
          <p>The remaining portion of that is due to a seasonality effect in particular with regard to our accounts payable because you might recall that we have pushed our CapEx program at the end of last year. And of course, we have seen in the first six months a reduction of our accounts payable and that is going to influence the working capital. When it comes to the accounts receivable, I think we are in line with last year, so there are no major exceptions to highlight.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have a time for one final question, which I understand is coming from Edoardo Montalbano, Centrobanca.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. One question on nuclear, this are the first results after the referendum in Italy on nuclear. In your last business plan you said &#x20AC;400 million for the launch of nuclear in Italy. Have you already addressed that at this morning on that project or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think in nuclear in Italy, the referendum is basically telling us no nuclear for at least the generation, it's no more. There will be no chances there will be proposing additional projects. We continue to be nuclears in countries like Slovak Republic and France and Spain.</p>
          <p>The money allocated to nuclear during the plan, which was just for the initial start up of the projects will be obviously allocated to other ongoing projects namely the coal plant of Portugal and coal will be the base load capacity that the country will need to replace the nuclear that we are going to miss. That is just and that's simple. And thank you very much for all of your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The Investor Relations office remained available for any further questions or inquires. Thank you again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>