<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1367014" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-11-09</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2090</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Luca Torchia</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Luigi Ferraris</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Pablo Cuadrado</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd. (Italy)">Antonella Bianchessi</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Fidentis">Enrico Bartoli</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Bank Plc (Italy)">Susanna Invernizzi</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Equita SIM SpA">Roberto Letizia</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley Bank International Ltd. (Italy)">Anna Maria Scaglia</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="UniCredit Bank AG Milan Branch">Javier Suarez</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Alberto Gandolfi</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="operator">Operator</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening ladies and gentlemen. This is Luca Torchia speaking, and welcome to Enel's Nine-Month 2011 Results Conference call. We will be doing the usual presentation with the Chief Financial Officer, Mr. Luigi Ferraris. Then, we will lead a Q&amp;A session.</p>
          <p>Thank you again. And please, Luigi, go head.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Luca. Good evening, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome again to our nine months 2011 results presentation. I would like to start this session by giving a brief overview of the general macroeconomic trends across the areas in which we operate on chart number two. The gradual upward trend observed in 2010 has continued, even though during the third quarter 2011, we have noticed some contraction versus the first half 2011 results in areas like Spain and Slovakia.</p>
          <p>In any case, the assumption underlying our current industrial plan continue to apply to countries like Italy, Russia and Latin America. As far as Spain is concerned, if we consider the demand on a like-for-like basis, temperature and working days, the trend is flat year-to-date.</p>
          <p>I will now give you an overview of our key financial highlights on chart number three. Group EBITDA in the first nine months 2011 was in line with the same period of last year. As you can see on the slides, during the first nine months of 2011, we have recorded some positive non-recurring and non-cash items relating to the revaluation of some assets after a change in the consolidation methodology and capital gains for a total amount of about &#x20AC;400 million.</p>
          <p>Net of these, EBITDA declined year-on-year by about 3%. This decline in recurring EBITDA includes the perimeter effect for assets sold in Spain, Italy, and Bulgaria for a total amount of &#x20AC;235 million; a negative one-off effect in Colombia of &#x20AC;109 million.</p>
          <p>On the positive side, we recorded a strong performance in the Market division, infrastructure networks, our Russian activities and Enel Green Power. Group net income stands at &#x20AC;3.5 billion or about 1% higher than last year and already takes into account the inclusion of the additional Robin Hood tax.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, net of the above mentioned effect, group net ordinary income equals to &#x20AC;3.234 billion. Net debt has increased during the first nine months of the year by about &#x20AC;2.8 billion to &#x20AC;47.8 billion. I will provide more details on this later on.</p>
          <p>Now, moving to chart number four. Our net financial charges stand at &#x20AC;2.338 billion, registering a decrease of &#x20AC;300 million, mainly as a result of the following: lower interest charges of &#x20AC;86 million has the positive impact of the lower net financial debt position, is more than offset higher interest charges paid on the variable short-term debt.</p>
          <p>The decrease of other items by &#x20AC;216 million was due to the following: &#x20AC;100 million recorded in 2010 as a one-off regularization effect of the accrual in financial revenues from previous years related to tariff deficit; the positive impact of &#x20AC;48 million lower liabilities related to the actualization of post-employment benefits; other items by &#x20AC;64 million, mainly relating to the favorable ruling by Spanish National Court on Endesa's appeal of previous year income tax.</p>
          <p>Also, let me remind you that our normalized annual average cost of gross debt stands at 4.9% versus 4.5% of the last year. Finally, the group's tax rate increased from about 30% in nine months 2010 to about 34% in nine months 2011. These higher taxes are mainly the result of the inclusion of the already mentioned Robin Hood Tax.</p>
          <p>Let's continue with an update on forward electricity sales activities on slide number five. In Italy, we have fully hedged our 2011 production at an average base load price of about &#x20AC;71 per megawatt hour, and 80% of 2012 at an average base load price of about &#x20AC;75 per megawatt hour.</p>
          <p>In Spain, we are fully hedged for 2011 and 70%-75% for 2012 at an average price of about &#x20AC;56 per megawatt hour both for 2011 and 2012. In Latin America, we are 75%-80% hedged for 2011 and the same for 2012.</p>
          <p>In Slovakia, we are 100% hedged for both 2011 and 2012 at an average price of about &#x20AC;53 per megawatt hour for 2011 and &#x20AC;56 per megawatt hour for 2012. All of this will help us to explain our EBITDA evolution on chart number six, which provides an overview of all of our operations.</p>
          <p>I will now go through the EBITDA of each of our divisions in more detail, starting with Generation and Energy Management Italy on slide number seven. Overall, divisional EBITDA declined by &#x20AC;216 million. This is mainly the result of a decrease in the generational margin of &#x20AC;255 million, caused by lower margin in prices achieved versus 2010, coupled with the ongoing lower idleicity during the first nine months of the year and an increase of &#x20AC;169 million in other items, mainly due to the revaluation of Trento Hydro Dolomiti Enel assets of about &#x20AC;200 million partially compensated for by the perimeter effect of this change in the consolidation methodology from fully to proportional.</p>
          <p>Let's move on to the EBITDA evolution analysis of the Market division on chart number eight. EBITDA totaled &#x20AC;446 million versus &#x20AC;281 million in nine months 2010. This strong performance has mainly been driven by the increase of &#x20AC;157 million in the contribution from the free market, thanks to higher electricity margins, partially compensated for by lower gas margin and higher client-related cost.</p>
          <p>Moving now to chart number nine, on domestic Infrastructure and Network division, EBITDA increased to &#x20AC;3.129 billion, 11% up versus last year. This is mainly due to higher connection fees of &#x20AC;198 million related to energy producers; 8,000 megawatts installed in 2011 versus 1,600 megawatts installed in the same period of 2010. We expect full year 2011 installed capacity to be about 9,000 megawatts; and &#x20AC;132 million, mainly thanks to lower personnel costs.</p>
          <p>Let me underline that if we consider our Italian operation as a whole, nine months 2011 EBITDA stands at &#x20AC;5.2 billion or 5% up versus nine months 2010. On the basis of this, I confirm 2011 full year EBITDA guidance at &#x20AC;6.7 billion.</p>
          <p>Moving now to slide number 10 on International operations, EBITDA is in line with nine months 2010 as the perimeter effect on Bulgarian assets has been more than offset by the positive performance of our Russian operations. In more detail, in the Centrel region, Slovensk&#xE9; Elektr&#xE1;rne recorded a decrease of &#x20AC;84 million mainly attributed to the positive non-recurring nuclear decommissioning provision released in 2010. Russia increased by &#x20AC;93 million, with generation activities contributing &#x20AC;53 million and supply activities contributing &#x20AC;40 million, thanks to higher margin and volumes.</p>
          <p>Before analyzing the remaining division, I would like to point your attention to our Russian generation activities on slide number 11. OGK-5 reported nine months '11 EBITDA of about &#x20AC;266 million or 35% up versus the same period of last year. This was mainly due to increasing power prices on the free market and higher capacity payments.</p>
          <p>Let's now move on to Endesa's results on slide number 12. First, as usual, let me remind you the numbers we report on this slide and in the following one are the results of the application of Enel Group's accounting principles, which may differ from Endesa's principle, due to local standards.</p>
          <p>The Iberian division has recorded a decrease in EBITDA of &#x20AC;347 million. This was due to the following: a decline of &#x20AC;282 million in the Generation and Supply business, which can be largely explained by the increase in energy costs related to the higher level of Spanish pool prices versus last year, partially compensated for by the increase of the last resort tariff; an increase of &#x20AC;150 million in the Distribution business, thanks to higher margin, mainly explained by the implementation of the new regulation based on investments; a decrease of &#x20AC;180 million in other items, mainly due to the lower perimeter effects on the distribution assets sold last year.</p>
          <p>Let's turn to Latin America on chart number 13. The Latin American division has recorded an EBITDA decrease of &#x20AC;121 million. This is mainly the result of an increase of &#x20AC;4 million in the Generation business, mainly thanks to improved hydro conditions in Chile during the third quarter versus the first six months for the year and, better margin recorded in Colombia and Peru.</p>
          <p>An increase of &#x20AC;39 million in the Distribution business, mainly thanks to higher volumes distributed in all the countries in which we operate, partially offset by the normalization of Ampla's regulated revenues in Brazil versus last year. And finally, a decrease of &#x20AC;102 million in other items, mainly related to a one-off increase in Colombian patrimonial tax for an amount of &#x20AC;109 million, recorded in the first quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>And now, let's have a review about Enel Green Power on chart number 14. EBITDA totaled &#x20AC;1.183 billion, representing an increase of about 22% versus nine months 2010. This is mainly due to the following: a decline of &#x20AC;34 million in Italy and Europe, mainly due to the termination of CIP 6 incentives; an increase of &#x20AC;69 million in Iberia and Latin America, which is mainly the result of the consolidation of <mark type="ph" /> Asir (13:58) for &#x20AC;41 million and overall higher prices in Iberia for &#x20AC;33 million.</p>
          <p>An increase of &#x20AC;22 million in North America, thanks to higher volumes in wind and hydro production; and a one-off positive impact of &#x20AC;16 million indemnity on a renewal plant expropriation. And finally, an increase of &#x20AC;165 million, mainly related to the fair value revaluation of net assets in <mark type="ph" /> Cerraza, Termito Portuguesa and Elfort (14:30) as well as the capital gain on the asset sales to Gas Natural.</p>
          <p>With regards to the evolution of our net debt, you can see on chart number 15 that net, overall net debt stands at about &#x20AC;47.8 billion. The &#x20AC;2.8 billion increase during the period takes into account a &#x20AC;1.7 billion increase during the third quarter, due to the negative impact of the seasonality on working capital, higher CapEx and foreign exchange differences, mainly due to accounting translation effects and valuation of foreign currency debt.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, let me also underline that our present liquidity levels enable us to cover our maturities until the end of 2012 and beyond. In fact, we can rely on available committed credit lines for a total amount of &#x20AC;15 billion; the multi-tranche bond issued in October for the total amount of &#x20AC;2.250 billion; the cash-in of the last issuance of the tariff deficit in Spain for amount of &#x20AC;800 million raised in October, and moreover, further transfer of the Italian deficit securitization in Spain will help us in improving our liquidity position.</p>
          <p>As for the full year net debt target, we expect the usual cash improvement related to seasonality of working capital and we are currently working on the following action, cash-in of regulatory items mainly in Italy and some minor assets disposal. All of these should allow us to reach 2011 full year net debt targets.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention and now, let's open the Q&amp;A session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, everybody. Let's start the session by reminding you that we have people connected from the web, but also people connecting via phone. So, we'll be connecting question from both people on the web and on the phone. The first question comes from Mr. Pablo Cuadrado, Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Please, Pablo, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, guys. Just two or three quick questions. The first one is related to the Robin Hood Tax. When I look in the nine month figures, the tax rate reported is around 54%. Here, I was wondering whether you can give us a guidance for year-end in terms of tax rate including the Robin Hood Tax? And also, you can precise or you can give more color, if the tax rate or the taxes that you have paid in Q3 include also an impact linked to the change in tax provisions for the deferral tax?</p>
          <p>Second question is on the guidance for year-end. I think it's very clear that you just mentioned that the net debt and the EBITDA looking year end is everything on track, and it might be an impact on the ordinary net income, based particularly on the extraordinary items on the Robin Hood. Here, I would like to know if you can give us an indication of where do you expect to move the ordinary net income by year end? And the third question is quickly on the distribution review, there's been a lot of press comments after the Robin Hood tax, how that is going to be treated by the regulator, et cetera and basically, if you can update us a little bit on how you see that process going forward? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Pablo. Let me start with the first question. Robin Hood Tax, at the end of the nine months, we have recorded the impact of the Robin Hood Tax on the nine months results, and the impact on the current taxes is the region of &#x20AC;250 million. We expect that on a full year basis, we will be in the region of &#x20AC;400 million, maybe something less depending on the final results, of course, of the Italian operation. This is not yet a cash item. It will be a cash item next year. Therefore, there is no impact on cash in the current year.</p>
          <p>When it comes to your &#x2013; sorry, the expected tax rate on a full year basis, it will not change a lot. It will be in the region of 34%, something like that, for the entire year. As we said in our previous press release, we expect Robin Hood Tax to impact not only this year, but also 2012 and 2013. Therefore, 34% is something that we consider or we are foreseeing for the coming years.</p>
          <p>Ordinary income, by the end of the year, you might recall that we gave a target of &#x20AC;4.5 billion net ordinary income. If we assume the impact of the Robin Hood tax in the region of &#x20AC;400 million, but of course, this is something that we will have to value properly at the end of the year, once we are going to close the books. So, I hope could be something less in terms of net impact, but for now I have to say &#x20AC;400 million, something like that. We have to consider a net ordinary income in the region of &#x20AC;4 billion, &#x20AC;4.1 billion. That's what we foresee now as expected net ordinary income by the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Third question, how it's going on with the discussion? We are talking with distribution. We do not have any major news or changes with respect to what we have already commented in the past months. The current draft document is in line with our expectation. We, of course, are working in order to see if there is a possibility of improving this document by considering, in some way, the impact of this tax increase on the expected remuneration of our incurring investment in <mark type="ph" /> our route (21:23).</p>
          <p>So, let me put it this way. We can say that we hope for at least maintaining what you see now in the draft document, which is in line with our business plan numbers, which means a theoretical impact of a couple of hundred million euro reduction, which we hope to offset or partially offset.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Ms. Antonella Bianchessi, Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes good evening. Just a very few nitty-gritty questions. First of all, if you can provide some detail on your refinancing, because I noticed that on the slide number 23, you're still at &#x20AC;11.4 billion between now and the end of 2012. They were &#x20AC;10.7 billion in the interim result. So if you can explain what has happened and which will be the number updated for the recent bonds that you issued?</p>
          <p>The second question is on the other financial cost, the &#x20AC;285 million, if you can go into the detail and explain what it is? And the last things is the CapEx. I noticed that the CapEx reported by Endesa are a different number compared to what it is in your estimate. So if you can just help and reconcile these two data?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Antonella, so if you can just repeat the last question, because there was a noise on the-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the CapEx and there is a reported &#x20AC;1.8 billion CapEx, but it's only &#x20AC;1.4 billion in your consolidated accounts related to Endesa. It's maybe reclassified somewhat else or we should expect this CapEx later and if I may ask, also, which is the CapEx level you expect by the end of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you Antonella. Let me start with the last question, maybe it's easier, and it's quick. The difference is due to the way we consider and we treat the connection fees. We net the connection fees from our CapEx, while Endesa is reporting the gross number. So the two number are perfectly aligned, the difference is in the region of &#x20AC; 400 million is due to this reclassification that we do at year end '11.</p>
          <p>When it comes to your first question, are we going to refinance the next &#x20AC;10 billion maturities, well, as I said before, if we look at our liquidity position today, we can count on &#x20AC;15 billion of committed credit lines, out of which &#x20AC;13 billion have a maturity beyond 2013. On top, we have &#x20AC;4.2 billion of cash and cash equivalents, which are all available to serve any repayment in the future. And on top of this, we also have the cash-in of the &#x20AC;2.250 billion of bonds that we just issued in October. That will go, of course, for the repayment of the future maturities and the portion of tariff deficit that we have cashed in through Endesa.</p>
          <p>And we also have about &#x20AC;1 billion, of which a portion has been already cashed in. A portion will be cashed in the coming months of funding from the European Investment Bank, which has been already committed at very, very positive condition. So altogether, &#x20AC;13 billion of credit line with a maturity beyond 2013. &#x20AC;1 billion of European Investment Bank funding. &#x20AC;2.2 billion of bond. We are in the region of &#x20AC;16 billion, &#x20AC;17 billion. And on top of this, I also would like to add the positive cash-in that we do expect to reach in the last quarter of this year and of course, also, next year. And about next year, I will be &#x2013; we will be more specific during March presentation.</p>
          <p>The other question, other financial charges, a decrease of other financial charges, which is equal to &#x20AC;116 million, is related to &#x20AC;100 million recorded in 2010 as a trust. Therefore, we do not have any more, which was recorded at the Endesa level as a one-off regulization effect of the accrual in financial revenues from previous years related to tariff deficit. In other words, that was an adjustment of the interest related to the tariff deficit done by the authority last year at the Endesa level. So, this is &#x20AC;100 million.</p>
          <p>Then, we have &#x20AC;48 million of less liabilities related to the to the actualization of post-employment benefits that we do at the Endesa level and this will change every quarter, depending on the rate of interest evolution and &#x20AC;64 million of interest related to a favorable ruling by Spanish national courts on Endesa's appeal of previous year income taxes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Luigi. My question was different. I was wondering what is the &#x20AC;285 million, what it referred to and why the refinancing have increased on the same compared to H1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The refinancing of the &#x20AC;10 billion maturity that we do have in 2012, it doesn't seem to me that has increased. We still have on the long term profile, a maturity of &#x20AC;10 billion. That's what we were talking about also in June. And, the way we are going to refinance that, is what I told you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I have not seen any major changes with &#x2013; if we compare June versus September in term of refinancing needs. If you look also the portion of short term debt, so there might be some changes in some credit lines, which fall in maturity due by the end of the year that we have already refinanced. And therefore, the forecast that I explained to you has already taken into account the short term needs on the banking loan expiry.</p>
          <p>The &#x20AC;285 million regards, in real value, the size of the so-called accrual for liabilities related to the actualization of post-employment benefits regards the change in the equity investment that we do have in our portfolio at the Enel Green Power level. So this depends on the evolution of the net income. We have, for instance, the joint venture in Russia with Eni and Gazprom, called SeverEnergia, which is showing in these days a negative result because it is in the start-up phases, so all those type of elements. They are not pure financial. The pure financial line is the one that I mentioned to you called infrastructure. This is the real cost of my debt altogether.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, the next question is comes from Enrico Bartoli, Fidentiis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. Three questions, if I may. One is related to your forward sales. I wonder if you have some volumes already sold for 2013 and if you can give us some hint on the possible selling price?</p>
          <p>The second question is related to the effect of the IFRIC 18 on the difference between the EBITDA from Endesa and the one you reported. If I calculated well, this year, the difference should be around &#x20AC;100 million, last year, it was &#x20AC;200 million and for the full year 2010, it was around &#x20AC;400 million. Should we expect more or less the same level for the full year 2011 as you reported last year? And the third one is related to the cost of debt, if you can give us any indication of the full year cost of debt that you expect? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Let me start with the forward sales activities in 2013. If we, I mean, as you know, we have the three, I would say the three different markets, Spain, Italy and Slovakia. In Italy and Spain, we have the usual growing activities and therefore, I would say that we are in the region of 15%, 20%. What are the prices that we foresee today are not different than the 2012 one.</p>
          <p>Of course, the market is not very liquid, because there is still a question mark about the CO2 impact in 2013 in particular. Therefore, we don't push and the market is not asking us to push. When it comes to the retail segment, of course, this is the warning activities. Therefore, you will see that going as according to schedule.</p>
          <p>And I think this is really for Slovakia, for Italy and for Spain. Very likely, I am assuming that we should see something more stable or we should have better visibility when it comes to the CO2 impact starting from next year. It seems to be me that indeed, the European governments have different problems in their mind or different topics to take care of.</p>
          <p>On the IFRIC 18, well you are right. This is &#x2013; the number that you mentioned at the end of September are correct. On a full year basis, we do expect a decrease of this amount. So, I do not foresee &#x20AC;400 million for the full year in terms of positive income in our EBITDA because we have seen in Spain some slowdown in this connection activities and this connection fees. So, the impact could be much closer to &#x20AC;300 million rather than &#x20AC;400 million. Of course, in the guidance that I gave you, I have already considered this impact.</p>
          <p>Cost of debt on a full year basis, 4.9%, 5% will be our total cost of our gross debt. So, I do not expect any major changes. The &#x20AC;4.5 billion bonds that we have issued during the current year, altogether, show a cost, fully swapped just in the region of 5% with a maturity just below 7%. So, we are perfectly in line with this guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question coming from the web from <mark type="ph" /> Frank Batti, Credit Suisse (33:46).</p>
          <p>The question is, first, if we can confirm that Enel will provide Endesa with a &#x20AC;3.5 billion intragroup credit line and that Enel will centralize funding on the Eurobond market going forward? And second, if we can &#x2013; that our press release is stating that we are indicating a &#x20AC;5 billion potential bond differences by the end of 2012, if we think that this amount is achievable amount, considering the present market environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let's start with the first question. Yes, of course, I confirmed that we are finalizing with Endesa a bank loan facility &#x2013; a loan facility between our financial arm in the Netherlands and Endesa itself in the region of &#x20AC;3.5 billion, with a maturity of about five years at the market condition.</p>
          <p>And when it comes to the bonds issuance, I can confirm that at a European level, Enel will be the issuer. Endesa will have, of course, the possibility of tapping the market by raising a bank loan facility to serve and to fund the working capital and the short-term, medium-term CapEx needs.</p>
          <p>Today, the Enel Board of Directors approved &#x20AC;5 billion possible bonds issuance, addressed both to institutional investor and retail investor to be finalized by the end of 2012. So, we have in front of us 15 months to manage, of course, this process. The way we consider the market in these days, which is very volatile, requires the companies, the corporates to be ready to tap the market when the market, as we've done in October and in July, show a potential window to go ahead. So, that's the way we will manage in the future this &#x20AC;5 billion potential issuance, in order to diversify our sources of funds and in order to be in a condition to catch the opportunity when the market is getting better. Of course, in these days, it will not be the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Susanna Invernizzi, Barclays.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good evening. First of all, I'd like to have a little bit more comment on your working capital, particularly in terms of expectations for year-end? And second, looking at our credit facility, just considering the facility that you obtained in 2010, the &#x20AC;10 billion facility, can you tell me a little bit more if you have used it already, if it has covenants and what is that the cost of this facility? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's start with the working capital first. We have seen in the third quarter a decrease of our net working capital, and the decrease, because it was negative at the end of December and it's still negative now. So, it's funding our cash needs, because we have seen an increase in our receivables and in our stock of, in particular, CO2 certificates that we have acquired and both are built to the usual process.</p>
          <p>The &#x20AC;1.4 billion receivable increase is due to on one hand, seasonal effect, as I said, and this is happening every, let's say, first and third quarter as usual. It's due to the fact that we have increased our turnover at the group level and therefore, we have an increase of the size and it is also due to the fact that our customer are paying with less punctuality than in the past. In other words, if we look at days of sales outstanding, the number has increased, in particular in Italy, in the region of five, six days and one or two days in Spain.</p>
          <p>When I said before that we have put in place some action and order to recover, of course, we are expecting to cash-in, in the fourth quarter, the overdue receivable. We are expecting to have the benefit of the different seasonality of our working capital, and we also expect to cash in some regulatory receivable, which accounts for about &#x20AC;1 billion. That should be cashed in by the end of the year and also, we expect to have less payments because of our CapEx profile.</p>
          <p>The third quarter has been impacted by payments regarding CapEx that we have performed during the first and the second quarter. This happened in Enel Green Power, happened in our Utilization division and in Endesa as well. So, in the fourth quarter, we expect to be able to recover this gap by readdressing the working capital in the way that I explained to you right now, by cashing in our regulatory receivable, by finalizing some minor disposal that we still have in the portfolio for about &#x20AC;400 million. So, altogether, we are confident that you will see our net working capital at the end of the year in line with what we have seen last year and therefore, by serving our net debt reduction.</p>
          <p>&#x20AC;10 billion facility, we have already drawn &#x20AC;1 billion. The cost of this facility is 90 basis points, on top, of course, of the Euribor. The maturity is five years. Therefore, it's going to expire in 2015. We do not have any covenants or something like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Roberto Letizia, Equita.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good evening. I would like to go back to one previous question, because the numbers showed in page 23 actually confuses me a little bit. Because you have the same numbers of maturities within the short-term, but you put on in the market &#x20AC;2.2 billion of volumes recently. So, unless the &#x20AC;2.2 billion does not cover the 12-month maturity, that number should be lower. So, can &#x2013; if you can confirm that the number does not include the cash from the &#x20AC;2.2 billion bond emission? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And again on the net income, because there has been a bit of confusion on the press in the past month, but can you just confirm that the payout remains 60% for the dividend on this year? That means applied to a possible &#x20AC;4.1 billion, &#x20AC;4.2 billion recurring net income?</p>
          <p>And the third question on the distribution review, you commented already. But actually, there is a new element from the government in recent law which entitles the regulators to check if the incentive mechanisms for the regulated company and, I mean, also distribution are coherent with the European averages. So, we're not experts in international level, but do you see any risk that this could end up with lower recognition maybe on the CapEx side that with lower incentive, or not?</p>
          <p>And I have a final question, sorry for that. But, I'm happy about you confirming the good trend in the Italian market, but October has actually been a terrible number, a terrible month, with the gas at minus 13% year-over-year and the electricity demand at 1%. So if you can spend a few words about the picture of the coming months for the Italian market? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Let me start first by commenting chart number 23 and its long-term debt maturity profile. The number you see reported over here, the maturity profile you see reported over here does not include the impact of the amounts issued in October, because this number is &#x2013; this maturity are referred in the position of the group at the end of September 2011. So, they do not show the impact of &#x20AC;2.2 billion of bonds issued in October. They do not reflect the impact of the European Investment Banking funding that I mentioned to you of &#x20AC;1 billion. And, they do not consider the impact of the tariff deficit cash held in October.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the net ordinary profit, or better, the dividend policy, let me confirm that for the current year, the dividend policy is based on a 60% payout ratio to be applied to our net ordinary income, that as of now, we estimate, as I said, in the region of &#x20AC;4 billion, &#x20AC;4.1 billion, which is basically the result of the original target, netting the impact of the Robin Hood tax.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the problem that you raised regarding the distribution in particular, if in Italy, we are benefiting of a special treatment or a special remuneration of our asset base by comparing this remuneration with the rest of Europe, I can tell you that it might be the other way around. The fundamental point is that our distribution business in Italy is probably the best performer at European level, because we are most efficient. If you look at our cash cost per customer, we are by far, I would say today, the number one, thanks to the investment that we have done in our digital meters, thanks to our streamlining of the organization that we have done in the last years.</p>
          <p>Therefore, the fundamental point is that &#x2013; and that will happen, that the regulator allow us to retain 50% of this saving, which in our case, are definitely quite huge. And if you look at the total size so therefore the components of the transportation and distribution cost in the final bills of the customer, I think the Italian one is one of the lowest at the European level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, if I can ask just quickly, but the measure refers just not overall remuneration, for just on the incentive. So it means for me that they are referring only to the extra returns allowed on the capital expenditures, which should not be lower in Italy versus Europe. So I don't know if I'm wrong or if you have further thought on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if we refer to the medium and low voltage distribution business, to be honest with you, this is something that I have not seen. I read something about the high-voltage portion of the business, but as you know, we are not anymore managing high-voltage grid. We are definitely on the medium and low-voltage. And to be honest, again, I can't see this excess of incentive. We have remuneration based on the graph and on the knowledge of our cost structure.</p>
          <p>And our cost structure is decreasing year-by-year because of our efficiency program and therefore, the major discussion with the authority regards the profit sharing of this benefit that we have been able to achieve. And for now, if we look at the draft documents, the 50% is confirmed. The feeling that I have that what you are talking about is mainly impacting the transmission business, which is not any more in our hands.</p>
          <p>Fourth question, the Italian generation market and the October results, the October consumption. But let me remind you again our policy. When it comes to 2011, as I sold &#x2013; we have substantially sold forward 100% of our expected outlook and therefore, we have locked in our margin. And that's also, this also happens in 2008, 2009 when we passed through the peak of the crisis or the peak of reduction in the electricity demand. Of course, if we look at our September results, we have seen a reduction in our auxiliary services, which means that the impact of the new solar photovoltaic capacity is reduced in the peak prices and also is affecting the way the market works. But this is not going to impact our 2011 results, because they have been already locked in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question has been posted in the web by Andrew Moulder, CreditSights. He is asking actually a couple of questions. First, he is asking about maturities. So, he is indicating that out of the &#x20AC;10.7 billion of maturities that we have over the next 12 months, about &#x20AC;8 billion relates to bank loans and others. And about this, he is asking whether we expect to roll these over, or if we'll look to replace the bank loans with capital market debt?</p>
          <p>Second question, also from Andrew Moulder, is related to commercial paper. We have &#x20AC;4.8 billion of commercial paper outstanding, as indicated in slide number 24. He is asking whether this is included in the &#x20AC;10.8 billion of 12-month maturities and also, how easy for Enel to access the commercial paper market at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Luca. Let's start with the first question. Correct, we have &#x20AC;8 billion expiring out of the &#x20AC;10.8 billion maturity. A portion of that will be rolled over, so we are, of course, negotiating or we are going to negotiate with the banks, but let me remind you that we already have &#x20AC;10 billion or five years credit line of &#x20AC;13 billion of credit line facility, which are already in our hands and that are not used today. So those are there already to refinance this eventually &#x20AC;8 billion to bridge in case of worsening of the market scenario. But of course, we are thinking to negotiate the portion of this line with the banking system and we're already working on that.</p>
          <p>Commercial paper, correct. By the end of September we have used &#x20AC;4.8 billion of commercial paper. We've have seen a reduction in this source of funding in the last months. That was expected. That's the reason we have worked in August to increase our credit line facility, as a back-up for potential decrease of this instrument. The &#x20AC;4.8 billion are not included in these &#x20AC;10 billion maturity, but I can tell you that if we look the month of November or the last couple of months, we are rebuilding our position of commercial paper and therefore, we have seen an inversion now versus the months of July and August, because we are starting to see an increase of availability on the market and we are using it. Enel is one of the few corporate player in Italy which can tap this market and we do not have any sign, at least up to yesterday, with regards to this specific market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The next question comes from Mr. <mark type="ph" /> Sabi Strategy, Morgan Stanley (51:22).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, just, most of my questions have been answered. I just have two queries at this point of time. One is, first question is on Spanish tariff deficit. I know you are pretty confident that Spain will go in to tap bonds in the market and repeat with the deposits. But in such markets, when you consider that the sovereign volatility is so much and it's difficult for a sovereign entity to tap the market at this point of time. So what is your backup plan regarding if things really go worse from here out, because you have quite a pretty hefty portion of the deficit pending to you? So any guidance you can give us whether you are planning to do some more asset sales or dividend cuts to offset this tariff deficit problem?</p>
          <p>Or, I mean, if I look at the example of commercial paper, I mean, clearly, this is a declining trend, like you had &#x20AC;7 billion outstanding in H1. Today, if I see, you have &#x20AC;4.8 billion. This is also a bit of stress. So if I add &#x20AC;4.8 billion to your existing maturity schedule, plus the tariff deficit of around &#x20AC;4.5 billion to &#x20AC;5 billion, so how do you plan to mitigate these through like a more asset sales or some dividend cuts? And second question, like can you give us some EBITDA guidance for 2012 maybe, because if I look at your presentation most of your production has been hedged, if I'm right? So, any guidance on the 2012 EBITDA? That's it. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. So, I will try to answer your question and I hope to have understood everything you said. But let me start with by commenting the tariff deficit. Let me recap where we stand now at the Endesa level. We have already cashed in &#x20AC;4.4 billion by considering also what we have cashed in, in October. We still have to cash in something in the region of &#x20AC;6.8 billion including both the peninsula, the extra peninsula and the new tariff deficit, which of course has arisen during the course of the current year.</p>
          <p>What are the expectations? Well, of course, we are all perfectly aware of what's going on in the financial markets, so I'm not going to repeat what you can easily read that and watch everywhere in these hours. The market condition today does not offer the possibility, at least in the coming days, to tap the market. I am confident that there is a strong commitment from the current Italian &#x2013; the Spanish government to continue to tap the market to finalize the complete program that the FADE has in place by the end of next year. They have also issued a government guarantee to support this process, and so we believe that this commitment will continue also very likely with the new government.</p>
          <p>What is going to happen if, for any reason, we are not going to cash-in in the coming months, because this is something due and of course, it will be cashed in and Spain has demonstrated the willingness to pay this debt to the utility players. But, of course, we are ready to face any critical moments. How? First, we have to continue focusing our attention in the cash flow generation, which remains a must and that's something that we are going to pursue in the fourth quarter of this year, but also and moreover next year.</p>
          <p>Second, as I mentioned before, we have &#x20AC;19 billion of liquidity which is represented by committed credit lines, cash and cash equivalents for &#x20AC;15 billion of committed credit lines and &#x20AC;4 billion of cash and cash equivalents. On top of this, we also have the &#x20AC;2.2 billion of bonds raised in the month of October. We have the &#x20AC;1 billion European Investment Bank facility and therefore we have to add another &#x20AC;3 billion, which means &#x20AC;22 billion. And in the meantime, we expect to be at least cash flow &#x2013; at the breakeven in terms of free cash flow.</p>
          <p>So, after paying dividend, taxes, everything, the operating activities this year, we'll not ask for additional cash. So, we have &#x20AC;22 billion. We have to cash in &#x20AC;6.8 billion now plus the maturity that you see over &#x20AC;10 billion. We are fully covered also in the possibility that FADE, for any reason will not raise or will not issue any additional bonds on the market. So, I feel relatively confident that we are in a position to be safe for the next, say, 15 months even in the worst worst-case scenario.</p>
          <p>Second question, EBITDA guidance, what is going to happen in 2012? I'm sorry, you have to be patient and wait for March for our business plan presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. And as a follow-up, when you say that the Spanish government has guaranteed to pay back <mark type="ph" /> the tariff deficit (57:16), I mean, is there any way that they can do it without issuing the bonds? I mean, I'm not really aware of this, but is there any way, that is without tapping the bond market, Spain can come back to you and get the money under the regulations, when they say they have guaranteed you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the way they have decided to manage the tariff deficit mature up to the end of 2010 was to ask the utility to place this receivable into this FADE and this FADE, let's say is a government owned organization, with, let's say, the aim of placing on the market that the &#x20AC;17 billion &#x2013; the &#x20AC;22 billion of past tariff deficit and new tariff deficit.</p>
          <p>When I say this is guaranteed by the government, I mean that all the issuance that this FADE is going to do in the next or is already done are fully guaranteed by the Spanish government. That's the strong commitment that the Spanish government has put in place. And this guarantee does not need to be renewed. Therefore we do not have to or to receive the re-approval of the new government because this is based on the royal decree. And in Spain, when the king say that this has to done, they are fulfilled.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thank you. The next question comes from Anna Maria Scaglia, Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good evening. Just one quick question, can you give us an indication in terms of your expectations for the full year CapEx? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes Anna Maria. What do we expect for 2011 full year CapEx? We are projecting something in the region of &#x20AC;7 billion for the entire group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Javier Suarez, Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good evening. Two questions remaining. The first one is on the revision for the distribution activity. The question is if you see any risk that this revision could suffer a significant delay even beyond the year end, as a consequence of the significant deceleration of the macro and political environment?</p>
          <p>And, the second question is on the cost of debt. You have given an indication for the cost of debt by the year 2011. Could you extend that visibility into the years 2012 and '13? And just a very final question on the dividend. Just for the sake of being 100% crystal clear, have you clarify that the 60% dividend policy on recurrent dividends is only valid for the year 2011 and that beyond 2012 could be revised downward or upward? My thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, let me start with the first question. If there is a possibility that because of the current economic condition, the Italian authority, which is supposed to be independent, is going to change the regulation to take in to account the negative outlook or the negative macroeconomic condition.</p>
          <p>But, to be honest with you, I do not expect such behavior. I believe that the authority will continue to work as it is doing in order to finalize the package of the regulation by the end of the year. It is very important not only for the utilities, but for the system, because let me remind you that this is valid for Italy and it is valid also for Spain, the distribution business is one of the key player or the key investor in the territory in Italy and also in the other European countries. So this is very important also for the economy and for the employment.</p>
          <p>We do not have any sign in such a direction. We see the authority fully committed and in Italy, let me remind you, we do not have this issue of the tariff deficit, because this system is well balanced. All the additional costs are charged to the final customer. So everything will have to be managed by an increase, eventually, in the final tariff to the customer.</p>
          <p>Cost of debt 2011, I gave before a guidance of 4.9%, 5% for the current year. When it comes to the next year, I have to say that again, we should talk about that in March. But I do not expect, at least as I foresee now &#x2013; or better, I expect in the worst case, something in the region of 5%, 5.5%. But it is too early to say. I think this is something that we should consider and include &#x2013; incorporate in our business plan. And therefore, I will be more specific during March presentation.</p>
          <p>When I said 60% payout dividend policy, so far, this is the dividend policy that the company has.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have time for one final question, coming from Alberto Gandolfi, UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. I have a couple of questions and it's regarding, particularly, the possibility of government intervention. So, can you give us an update on what Italian government is up to, provided there is an Italian government for another entire week? But recently, the industry minister or the secretary for energy talked about starting negotiation to reform the power market. Typically, when we hear the word reform in economic environment like this one, it is just to try and lower power business. So, are you involved at all? Can you give us some color on that?</p>
          <p>Secondly, on Spain, we have elections in just over 10 days and we have heard that the think tank of the opposition party talk about likely extension of nuclear. But most likely, that will not come for free. So, what do you think could be the outcome over there and why is them talking about, again, about taxation, given it's been happened in several countries in Central Europe? Can you give us an update on what you &#x2013; what is the political climate as far as other taxation is concerned in Slovakia? Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let's start with Italy first. I read this idea of re-discussing the structure of the Italian energy markets. There are no technical table in place. There are no structural discussion in place. I think this is just an idea of the ministers of the current government. And for now, to me, to it remains an idea. We have been talking many times in Italy about the possible change in the structure of the market. To be honest with you, for now, I can't see any concrete action in that direction.</p>
          <p>When it comes to, more in general, to what could be the outcome or the possible maneuver of the Italian government, well, let me remind you that the utilities sector has been already affected by the Robin Hood tax on a very dramatic basis. I can't see how there might be some additional intervention in that direction, because that would jeopardize the investment program as it has been already done of the utilities company.</p>
          <p>So, the discussion at least on the basis of what we read and we hear, would be more on the key topics that the European Union has already highlighted to mention, which is more impacting the pension scheme and all these kinds of things that we will be impacting the citizens rather than more than the corporation, which are supposed to support the growth and the reduction of the unemployment.</p>
          <p>Spain. Well, they expect the new government, as I would say, that the representative of the center-right party has not yet touched in great detail what they have in mind when it comes to the energy sector. This is something that remains still a little bit vague. So they have not taken a position. I think what we've said for months with regards to the Zapatero government that will continue to be valid also for the new government, which means that the tariff deficit has to be addressed. Otherwise, Spain is going to lose huge investment program and this is going to be deteriorate the unemployment rate which is already at 20%, 21% in Spain, which I think is definitely quite high.</p>
          <p>The extension on nuclear, this is something that we heard. It could be an option, could be that coupled with a possible introduction of a new tax. I mean, this is something that we have to see in detail when and if it's going to happen. The extension, for sure, will be positive for Endesa. The tax would be immediate. So, this is something that we still have to value. But for now, there are no serious discussion. As I told you, as always happens, we have to see the government when it will be in place.</p>
          <p>Slovakia, it seems to me, under this perspective, very committed to finalize the CapEx program. Therefore, <mark type="ph" /> Malta 3 and 4 (1:07:53) is definitely one of the key priority of the country. There are no changes already with regards to nuclear and this is very important to us, because Malta 3 and 4 1,000 megawatts of new capacity in that part of the world, will be definitely very competitive and will support us in serving to reach German market, which has decided to abandon the nuclear sector and the Central Europe more in general. So, I see in Slovakia opportunity under this perspective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Luigi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you, Alberto. I think we are over with the Q&amp;A session. Thank you very much again for staying with us and as always, the Investor Relations department will be available for any further enquiry. Thank you again and have a good evening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for joining. The conference is now over and you may disconnect your telephones.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>