<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1289167" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-12</date>
    <companies>
      <company>827</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Paolo Scaroni, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Alessandro Bernini, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Iain Reid</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Domenico Dispenza</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Jason Kenney</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Claudio Descalzi</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Jon Rigby</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Michele Della Vigna</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Alastair Syme</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">James Hubbard</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Colin Smith</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Alejandro Demichelis</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Aymeric de Villaret</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Neill Morton</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker>
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to our Q4 and Full Year 2009 Conference Call. Unfortunately, Rome has been hit by a snowstorm, which means that that Paolo Scaroni is connected to this call remotely. The call will go ahead as planned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to our 2009 preliminary results conference call. As you may remember at our start of the presentation in February 2009, we said that we expected difficult market conditions to continue for at least a year. And that aiming was ideally placed to cope with the challenge because of the resilience of its business portfolio.</p>
          <p>This has proved to be the case and we performed well relative to our industry. Our E&amp;P division's focus on core areas has enabled us to deliver the promise 27 start-ups which will add 180,000 boe per day to our production at plateau and to achieve record production of 1.886 million unit a day in the forth quarter.</p>
          <p>Our Gas and Power division has proved to be particularly resilient to the downturn with stable volumes and an excellent operating performance. In R&amp;M we have seen depressed refining margins throughout the year and margins in the fourth quarter at the lowest level for decades.</p>
          <p>Our relatively small exposure and the good performance in marketing has allowed us to limit the losses. We had continued to focus on improving efficiency in all our businesses. The cost reduction program we launched in 2006 has delivered 1.3 billion of savings to date. Overall, we have achieved solid financial results with over &#x20AC;13 billion of operating profit and over &#x20AC;5 billion of net profit in a challenging environment.</p>
          <p>In 2009, we have also delivered several key achievements which will drive growth in the future. In ENP, as you all well recall we are strategically focusing on giant projects in the world's fastest growing oil producing areas.</p>
          <p>During 2009, we entered Iraq's Zubair, one of the world's largest oil fields. We then have agreed to develop two more giants in Venezuela, Junin 5 heavy oil and Perla wet gas that have resources in excess of 1.4 billion barrels. These two countries would be immediately accretive to production and reserves.</p>
          <p>We've also added 1 billion boe new resources with discoveries in Angola, Ghana and Gulf of Mexico, and made a 30% reduction in exploration expenses year-on-year. We have also strengthened our exploration portfolio in several high potential areas by adding acreage in West Africa, Gulf Of Mexico, China and Norway.</p>
          <p>Turning to gas, we completed the restructuring of the regulated business, unlocking value through integration. In the months, we have delivered on two further strategic agreements. One, our long-standing relationship with Gazprom, which acquired our Gazprom Neft stake earlier in the year, has enabled us to complete a deal on our long-term take-or-pay contract. Meanwhile, we have reached an agreement with the EU on the disposal of three international pipelines, which resolved a long running and <mark type="inaudible" /> investigation without affecting our transportation rights. These two key agreements will enable us to continue to build on our leading position in the European gas market.</p>
          <p>Alessandro will now comment on the fourth quarter results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Paolo and good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. The market environment in the fourth quarter was mixed. On the positive side, oil prices increased by 36% compared with the fourth quarter 2008. While, on the negative, gas prices, particularly those prevailing on the European market, were more than 40% lower, and refining margins, which averaged $1.24 per barrel, were down 84% as a result of the significant overhang of industry refining capacity. Finally, the euro showed an appreciation of 12% versus the U.S. dollar, averaging 1.48 during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning to the financials, fourth quarter adjusted operating profit has been &#x20AC;3.7 billion, down 6% year-on-year. This result reflected the anticipated weak performance of the refining and marketing division, almost entirely compensated by the better operating performance of exploration and production and the gas and power divisions.</p>
          <p>Adjusted net profit in the fourth quarter declined by 29% to &#x20AC;1.4 billion, as a result of the decrease in the operating profit, lower results reported by equity-accounted entities and an adjusted tax rate 7.8 percentage points higher than the last quarter of 2008. This came as a result of the higher amount of corporate income tax due in Italy. As a consequence of this surcharge provided by the law, which enacted the Treaty of Friendship between Italy and Libya and the tax charges paid by the E&amp;P division in Libya following the conclusion of last year discussion with local top authorities.</p>
          <p>Hydrocarbon production in the fourth quarter reached the record level of 1,886,000 boe per day, increasing by 1.7% compared to the same period of last year. This increase is due to production ramp-up and new field startups, mainly in the Gulf of Mexico, Congo, Egypt and Nigeria, as well as the reimbursement of royalties in kind in the USA and other contractual revisions totaling approximately 40,000 boe per day.</p>
          <p>These positives were partially offset by the OPEC cuts, mature field declines, as well as the negative impact of the PSAs. Fourth quarter adjusted operating profit of &#x20AC;2.8 billion was up 3% compared to the corresponding quarter of 2008, mainly as a result of higher hydrocarbon realization in dollars and increase production sold which was offset by the appreciation of the euro versus the U.S. dollar.</p>
          <p>In terms of reserve, we replaced 96% of our production but at a constant price, we delivered 109% reserve replacement ratio maintaining the life index above 10 years. These results compare well with last year's performance of 83% at constant price and confirm the solidity of our upstream portfolio.</p>
          <p>The overall gas volumes sold in the fourth quarter of 2009 including both consolidated and associated companies decreased by approximately 11% year-on-year, totaling 26.6 billion cubic meters.</p>
          <p>The decline in volumes is mainly due to the economic downturn and the increased competitive pressure in Italy. Despite the lower volumes, adjusted operating profit increased by 65%, compared to the same period of 2008 as a result of the favorable trends in the quarter of the euro/dollar exchange rate, while it had negatively affected the previous year quarter results and the good performance registered by these figures.</p>
          <p>The fourth quarter results also benefited from gains on the settlement of non-hedging commodity derivatives associated with the future sales of gas and electricity at fixed prices, compared to our last posted &#x2013; in the last quarter of 2008, the positive difference was approximately &#x20AC;190 million.</p>
          <p>Adjusted pro-forma EBITDA during 2009 amounted to &#x20AC;4.4 billion, exceeding our performance in 2008, whilst in the fourth quarter was &#x20AC;1.1 billion more than 23% after compared to last year.</p>
          <p>As you recall we breakdown our EBITDA into marketing of gas in Europe and infrastructure-based activities, namely Snam Rete Gas and the international transportation pipelines both of which have a stable returns. The split between these two business segments is approximately 50-50.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter results of the marketing segment increased by 73% as a result of the previously mentioned euro/dollar exchange rate and the excellent performance of Distrigas, but were adversely affected by lower volumes sold in Italy.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, Snam Rete Gas along with Italgas and Stoccaggi confirm that their resilience to the economical downturn, posting in the quarter an EBITDA of &#x20AC;363 million in line with the preceding quarters.</p>
          <p>Finally, the EBITDA generated by the international transportation declined versus the fourth quarter of 2008 because of the reduced tax charge paid in Tunisia and recovered through revenues preserving the margins at net income level.</p>
          <p>In refining and marketing, utilization rates declined to 73% in response to the negative scenario due to a weak industrial demand of gasoil and narrow price differential between light and heavy crudes.</p>
          <p>The fourth quarter recorded an adjusted operating loss of &#x20AC;196 million, compared to an operating profit of &#x20AC;243 million in the same period of 2008, reflecting the steep decline of refining margins and to a lesser extent the higher commercial margins registered in 2008 as a result of the downward trend of oil prices. Retail volumes slightly decreased, but we were able to maintain our market share in Italy above 31%.</p>
          <p>Finally, a quick overview of the other businesses: in the fourth quarter of 2009 the petrochemical business posted an adjusted operating loss of &#x20AC;104 million, mainly due to high feedstock costs. Engineering and construction mainly siten has delivered an operating profit of &#x20AC;204 million, in line with last year, but confirming to be resilient to the economic downturn, thanks to our diversified and strong backlog. The other activities in corporate showed an aggregate loss of &#x20AC;151 million versus a loss of &#x20AC;195 million in the fourth quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Moving to the financial results, in 2009 operating activities generated a cash flow of &#x20AC;11.3 billion. On top of this, a disposal of the Gazprom Neft 20% stake in the marginal E&amp;P assets, as well as the Snam Rete Gas minority shareholder capital increase contributed around &#x20AC;5.1 billion bringing the overall cash generated to &#x20AC;16.4 billion.</p>
          <p>The cash flow generated financed a total CapEx of &#x20AC;13.7 billion, acquisition of &#x20AC;2.7 billion mainly related to these figures minorities and dividends paid in May and September which totaled &#x20AC;4.5 billion. Other disbursements absorbed approximately &#x20AC;100 million and brought the overall cash outflow to &#x20AC;21 billion.</p>
          <p>As a consequence, net financial debt at the end of December of &#x20AC;23 billion related to a debt-to-equity ratio of 46% compared to 38% of at the end of 2008.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention and now I will hand you over to Paolo for his final remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I will now take you through our outlook for 2010. We expect the challenging market condition we've seen in 2009 to continue this year. In this context, Eni would continue to deliver solid results. Our 2010 upstream production will be in line with 2009 in a $65 a barrel brand scenario, assuming OPEC cuts at the same level of 2009.</p>
          <p>We expect growth to resume in the subsequent years reinforced by access to major new fields and our successes in installation. In Gas &amp; Power, we expect resilient results in our marketing business despite increasing competitive pressure and the slow recovery in European gas demand. The recent agreement with Gazprom will also help to reach this target.</p>
          <p>The regulated business will continue to improve delivering synergies from the integration of Snam Rete Gas, Italgas and Stogit. 2010 results will not be impacted by the disposal of TENP, Transitgas and TAG, which would be finalized between the end of this year and the beginning of 2011.</p>
          <p>In Refining, we see continuing tough conditions ahead. Refining margins are not showing signs of recovery, but we will benefit from a good performance in marketing and continued efficiency improvements. As you know, our exposure to R&amp;M [Refining &amp; Marketing] is small compared to our peer group. Consolidated CapEx for the group is expected to remain broadly in line with 2009 to support the development of our pipelines of projects. These projects will continue to drive Eni's growth in the future, a theme which we will discuss further in our strategy presentation next month.</p>
          <p>We will now be pleased to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. The first question from Mr. Iain Reid from Macquarie. Mr. Reid, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there gentlemen. Can I ask two questions please on the gas business? First of all, can you say whether you've had a take-or-pay liability for your imported gas in 2009? And if so how much that was, and what you expect for 2010? And secondly, you talked about the renegotiation of your Gazprom import contracts? Can you say exactly what you've done there, what you managed to achieve there in terms of either the take-or-pay level or the &#x2013; or how you've changed the oil indexation on which you buy the gas? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will hand it over to Domenico to explain to you even if I am not sure, it will reply as completely as he would like. Domenico?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we'll try to reply. We are still in the process of analyzing our agreements with our suppliers. What we wish to make today that the pick-or-pay counter to liabilities for 2009 will be around &#x20AC;280 million. Also it's important to remember that when we speak of take-or-pay liability, we are speaking in fact of curtailments of gas that we will take at a later stage paying the difference between what was paid already and what we will pay. It is difficult to give an estimate for what will happen in the year 2010 because they are mainly elements that are not yet clear.</p>
          <p> First for instance is the duration of the crisis then of course there is the difference between the spot prices they also for the oil linked to price is also is important to see how much will be the recovery of the gas demand and what will be the balance between the supply and demand in Europe, <mark type="inaudible" /> Europe is in state to make an example. So, it's difficult yet to predict what would be the exposure . <mark type="inaudible" /> that some exposure will stay but it's really very difficult today to predict how much it will be.</p>
          <p>The second question was our deal with Gazprom. I should say that after a long discussion we reached an agreement that we can consider satisfactory &#x2013; satisfactory for both parties, we have additional flexibility and this help us reduce our risks. Of course, you understand that I will not go in additional details because these are commercial sensitive issues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Can I just follow-up on that? I understand that in terms of commercial sensitivity but can you say whether you've achieved something on the price or the volume side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say that we touched some part of indexation that is still linked to oil products but revised to date in what is happening in the market today. I would not comment specially on the results, I could repeat, but overall I could say that is satisfactory for us and for Gazprom, in the sense of both price condition and flexibility of contracts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you Domenico.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Mr. Jason Kenney from ING. Mr. Kenney, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi guys, it's Jason from ING. I was interested in your guidance for essentially flat production this year versus 2009 and I was hoping to get a bit of breakdown on oil versus gas. I am assuming that you see some growth in oil production and some decline in gas output and if that is the case what kind of oil uplift would you envisage. Secondly on Karachaganak, gas volumes there, would you expect them to be lower in 2009 &#x2013; sorry in 2010 or higher than last year's volumes from Karachaganak? And then finally where would you see your gearing at the end of 2010 assuming a fixed $5 oil price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Claudio will answer the first two questions. Let me start on the third one, about the gearing. We would speak about these kind of issues in our strategy presentation in March. Claudio, on the first two questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Production, production in 2010, we said that we're not &#x2013; we will produce at the same level and not less what we have produced in 2009 as a reported value and we considered &#x2013; we consider in our assumption that we are at the same OPEC level, so we considered we include OPEC level. And also the impact of the gas market, or the gas market that impacted our Italian and Libyan production. So that is more or less the main reasons. Next year, we're going to produce more oil than gas. And we're going to increase 1% our oil production in respect to gas production. So in 2010, we start inversion, promoting more oil projects than gas projects, that's because of the price situation and price scenario. Karachaganak, the expectation for the next year in &#x2013; are to produce at the same level of 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Jon Rigby from UBS. Mr. Rigby, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, yes, thank you. I've got two questions, I take on board your remarks about waiting till March, but I just &#x2013; on gearing and cash flows, et cetera, but can we just go back to that a second? Looking at your cash flows for 2009 and then looking forward to 2010, which you said you generated operating cash flow of 11.3 billion. That doesn't cover your indicated CapEx and dividend for 2010. I mean, the way you did it in 2009, was by some &#x2013; quite a lot of portfolio management. And clearly, you were in the running for Uganda as well. So can we work on the basis that more portfolio management in 2010 and 2011 is going to be the order of the day, as you sort of shuffle the pack, and balance the books?</p>
          <p>Second question is just on TAG and the supply into Italy. When you sell the interest or the ownership of the lines, will there be any issues about your ownership of the capacity rights as well? And how would you see those capacity rights evolving over time? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer to your second question, then we will move, we move to Sandro for the first one. On the TAG, we do not own the pipeline, we own 89% of the capacity of the pipeline. This is what we would be selling, but we will keep for us all our transportation rights, that is, we'd be able to continue to transport through the target the same quantity of gas we're transporting today, roughly in the region of 22 billion cubic liter of gas every year. Sandro, would you like to answer the first question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Of course, we will be more precise about the future when we will release details relating to our strategy for the next year. But for sure, what we can state immediately is that our present level of leverage is not a matter of concern for us, because it is and remain within the parameters of what we defined a solid financial position. We wanted to maintain an efficient access to the debit capital markets and we are maintaining so far this easy access.</p>
          <p>And please remember that a significant portion of our net financial position, almost 40%, belongs to the regulated business, namely Snam Rete Gas, Italgas, and the Stogit. And accordingly, there is a significant difference in terms of risk with this type of &#x2013; this type of debt. And also the rating agencies consider the utility component when they assess their credit rating and because of this important portion linked to the regulated business, we have been and we are capable to maintain a strong credit rating.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But in principle, would you expect to balance cash in and cash out over 2010, 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, for sure we will be more precise at the strategy presentation. But also for 2010, we don't foresee any particular problem in financing our growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Michele Della Vigna from Goldman Sachs. Mr. Della Vigna, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I would ask three questions, if I may. First of all, your deferred tax liabilities has come down from about &#x20AC;5 billion at the end of last year and 4 billion at the end of Q3 to only 2 billion at the end of '09. So I was wondering if there was any large one-off tax payment that you had in the last few months of the year?</p>
          <p>Secondly, I wondered if you could give us an idea of the order of magnitude of the operating working capital outflow that you expect from the Gas and Power division in 2010 as a consequence of prepayment, especially to Gazprom? And then finally, I was wondering if you could give us some guidance on the tax rate that you expect for 2010? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will ask to Sandro to answer the question number one, number three, but as far as the question number two, I am afraid we cannot give you the details. We might be willing to give some more information around take-or-pay at our strategy presentation, but certainty not today. Alessandro?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Starting from the last question, I can confirm you that, presently, the adjusted tax rate that we expect in the current year will be broadly in line with what we have achieved in 2009. So we do not expect any major difference.</p>
          <p>As far as the tax liability is concerned, for sure the most significant portion relates to the taxable income. Of course, we have &#x2013; you know that our results are 50% lower compared to last year. Accordingly, the taxable income decreases accordingly. So the liability follow, of course, mainly the taxable income.</p>
          <p>So the reason of the decrease in the tax liability is only due to the recurring guidance. There are no major extraordinary items affecting our balance sheet position, our liability position vis-&#xE0;-vis the tax authorities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Alastair Syme from Nomura. Mr. Syme, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon. I wonder, just on guidance, if you could talk a little bit about where you see upstream cost this year, based on a cash and non-cash basis? And also maybe, Paulo could you just maybe update us with your current thoughts regarding Rete gas, as it's fairly been in news a lot?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So let me answer first, the second question and then I will let Claudio to answer the first one. Now let me try to clarify what is my thought around, generally speaking, the gas business we have, because there has been lot of discussions and a lot of debate.</p>
          <p>Now, first of all, I think that there is a general agreement now that the marketing part of our gas business is very synergic with our E&amp;P business. It wouldn't make a lot of sense to even think about a divestment from this traditional position we have, very synergic in what we do in upstream. So that would be the first one.</p>
          <p>Now moving to our regulated part of business, Snam Rete Gas first, but of course also our international pipeline, essentially Snam Rete Gas. We consider that any potential divestment from this business, on which we do not have a dogmatic approach, is very much in the hands of the Italian government and parliament, which they have to apply to the Italian legislature, the third directive of the European Union on Gas.</p>
          <p>We don't know what the Italian parliament will decide, it will take some time. When the parliament will take its own position, then we might review what we want to do. More on the specific, what is our specific position, I would like to point out, first of all, that if we had divested our stake in Snam Rete Gas in 2005, we would have been making a big mistake because since then, the total shareholder return of our stake in Snam Rete Gas has given us a 50% return, which has been quite exceptional, particularly considering how stable normally is this kind of investment.</p>
          <p>And then second, that we expect that in the next 18, 24 months Snam Rete Gas will generate a considerable amount of synergies, on cost reduction, as a result of the integration of Stogit and Italgas. This is to say that we have not, even in our terms, any urgency to look for alternative position in this business.</p>
          <p>Claudio, do you want to answer to the first question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Operating costs 2009 amount to $5.8 a barrel, so it's a slight increase with respect to 2008, and that's if we talk about recalculated considering the equity production. If we look at the efficiency of our operations, so looking at working interest, our operating costs are about $4.5 per barrel, that is in line with the cost of 2008. Considering the DD&amp;A for 2009, the amount is $10.3 per barrel and we expect for the next year to having a slight increase, up to $11 per barrel and that's because the new projects that come on-stream in the next year and the other years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Paolo, can I just come back to the Rete Gas question, because obviously one of the alternatives for shareholders is a de-merger, give it to the benefit from the synergies from the storage and the regulated part-time business? Is that something you will consider?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure I understood your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Rather than a divestment &#x2013; you're saying you think there's further share price appreciation to come, surely shareholders can benefit from that through a de-merger of the shares?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The merger of our shares...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A de-merger, so you give shareholders the shares in Rete Gas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, let me clarify this. Even if I had to sell one share of Snam Rete Gas, I need government approval, because the government has a golden share on Eni, due to our shareholders in Snam Rete Gas, and any movement in my shares has to have a decree from the government. So &#x2013; since I'm not expecting the government and the parliament to take any action before the introduction of the third directive in the Italian law, all this is really a very premature question.</p>
          <p>On top of that, any divestment today is to be a very bad deal, because I'm expecting Snam Rete Gas to do well in the next 18 or 24 months, due to the integration of Stogit and of Snam Rete Gas &#x2013; and of Italgas. I must have been clear?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no okay. No that makes sense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. James Hubbard from Morgan Stanley. Mr. Hubbard, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. Three questions, if that's okay. The first is your CapEx guidance for this year, although flat on last year &#x2013; maybe I am wrong, but it was a bit higher than I was expecting, and seems inconsistent with the four year guidance you gave last year, this time last year. Is there a Zubair and Venezuela impacting there that's hitting 2010? And if so, could you quantify that?</p>
          <p>Secondly, on Livorno, could you just update this &#x2013; update us on the plans to sell that refinery? And thirdly, I know you don't want to go into great detail on gearing. But you do put in today's press release that your management's considering measures to support credit ratings. My question is, if you're comfortable with your access to the market for debt, and comfortable with your level of gearings, especially if you just consider your economic interest in Snam Rete Gas rather than fully consolidated, then why do you feel the need to consider measures to support your credit rating? And then, can you give us some color on what those measures are that you're considering?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me just say a word about Livorno, Livorno is not anymore for sale for several reasons, including the fact that there is no buyer around for refineries in Europe. As for the CapEx guidance, and more specifically Zubair and Venezuela, maybe Sandro would like to say a word and thinking around what we plan to do about gearing. Sandro?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. So, Zubair and Venezuela will not affect significantly the CapEx of 2010. For sure, Zubair, a little bit, because it seems is a faster track project. We have to start with our development already in 2010. And particularly their CapEx of 2010 will be interested by an amount which is around 200, &#x20AC;300 million. But as far as the difference compared to what we stated during our strategy presentation of last year, you have to remember that when we release our announcement we were in a complete different cost environment.</p>
          <p>At a better time the price of the barrel was in the region of $40 per barrel, and accordingly we estimated in our long-term plan to take a significant benefit of the cost reduction of raw materials and services. As you know, the price of the barrel resumed very quickly and accordingly the cost profile of services and materials didn't take any &#x2013; we were not able to benefit off the revision of the oil prices. Accordingly, since today the cost profile of materials and services are more or less in line with those existing before the crisis. So mainly the difference compared to what we've stated last year is due to the increase in the cost profile of our already existing project plus something, but not so important relating to Zubair.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the gearing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on the gearing side, we stated in our press release that we have already identified some measures. But, first of all, we have already stated over the &#x2013; all over 2009 that we have identified some upstream assets marginal which are located in areas in which we expect not to extract major synergies or our declining assets to be sold. So we have received some offers. We are analyzing them. And we expect to be able to finalize such disposal quite soon. Then as anticipated and disclosed by Paolo, we will sell probably by the end of this year or early next year the three companies TENP, Transitgas and TAG. And we expect to cash &#x2013; to cash a significant amount of money. So accordingly this will reinforce our financial structure. But I repeat even without this extraordinary transaction, we are confident to be able to maintain any risks to the debt capital market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And could I just ask one follow-up on that point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Which is I guess, simply &#x2013; you seem to be repeatedly on this conference calls giving impression that you think your credit rating is under threat and then make the statement that you're not really concerned, you have access to the market. So, are you really bothered if S&amp;P downgrade you one notch, is that a big deal for you or not because I kind of get mixed messages on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me &#x2013; of course nobody likes to be downgraded. This is something that nobody likes to happen. Having said that we never said that this rating we have today was untouchable and we think that even if we are downgraded we would be moved between eight regions. This is a very solid credit rating in any case. And thirdly, we point out that the quality of our debt is completely different than the quality of the debt of most of the other oil companies. Simply, just to give you a few numbers, I might give you rough numbers and not precise numbers, but if you take our &#x20AC;23 billion of debt we have more than 10 billion which is linked to the Snam Rete Gas, another four billion which is linked to the ships to Saipem. In total it makes something close to 15. Then we have Kashagan which alone &#x2013; which alone accounts for roughly &#x20AC;4 billion of debt, which is a huge field which will start production in a couple of years, but so far has only created huge investment. In total just to say that when an agency looks at our balance sheets, looks at our gearing in a different way which will look a gearing of another oil company which doesn't have the same characteristics that we have. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I can. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So basic kind of approach we take. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Colin Smith from ICAP. Mr. Smith, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Afternoon, gentlemen. Two questions. Firstly, when you talk about resilient's earnings in gas marketing, can you just give us some feel for whether that means sort of resilient 2009 levels or resilient 2008 levels or quite what that actually means?</p>
          <p>And the second things is; in the last few weeks, we've seen quite a lot of what look like fairly hostile comments coming from senior politicians in Kazakhstan over Karachaganak and I wonder if you could just tell us a little bit about how things stand with regard to what the government is trying to do either with our the ownership positioning in Karachaganak or over the fiscal terms are they going to apply to it? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well on the resilient gas and power business of ours I would probably leave it to Sandro to comment on our results in 2009 as compared to 2008 and on Karachaganak maybe Claudio would like to say something?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will take the first question, I'm Domenico Dispenza. The first question, in 2008 we told you in fact that we were expecting for 2009 slightly the same result in fact we had as you can see in the numbers a slight higher results than 2008. When we say what we foresee for 2010, of course it's stated clearly from before that we don't have clear picture what is going to happen. But when we say resilient, we say that we expect margin in line or slightly lower than what we got in 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, just to decorate what Domenico has just reported, but as repeated during the presentation please that &#x2013; remember that when we talk about Gas &amp; Power division results we are talking about marketing activities, marketing business and regulated business and international transportation. So, these last two businesses are for sure extremely resilient, because they are almost not affected by any economical cycle. So we expect also in 2010 a result very in line with 2009. Then as far as the marketing business Domenico has already given guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Karachaganak; so, as know we are discussing with the Republic of Kazakhstan, we are discussing with the Minister about the Phase III development. As you know the development of the Phase III was originally considered before the recent market prices. So for that reason we are starting together again the <mark type="inaudible" /> and the feasibility study in order to get the same result in term of production, but reduce the costs. So that is what we're doing with the Republic and we have the next month in 2010 to get these results and things are going quite well. So that is the main issue under discussion in &#x2013; as far as concerned Karachaganak.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. But there has also been talk about KazMunayGas gas taking a stake and about fiscal terms being reopened again. And I think you still got an ongoing dispute over the export tax that you have paid under protest in 2008?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are two different issues. One is the stake. So the participation of KazMunayGas in Karachaganak, that was a known option that had already been discussed in the past. And that is possibly maybe after the discussion on the Phase 3, something that we can discuss. But it's not on the table now, just on the newspaper, but not on the table between <mark type="inaudible" />. And I'm talking about the joint venture and the KazMunayGas.</p>
          <p>Talking about tax, that is a statement that we read on the newspaper; but until now we didn't get any notice or any formal communication. We never discussed with Minister of Finance or with the Minister of Oil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Alejandro Demichelis from Bank of America. Mr. Demichelis, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon, gentlemen; two questions, if I may. The first one is you give us the guidance of production at $65 per barrel. Maybe you can give us a reminder of what's the sensitivity to the oil price as you go along changing your production mix? And the second question is, you touched on Livorno and your refining of the petrochemicals business. Maybe you can tell us what are your plans there if you're not going to be selling Livorno?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer first the second question, then I will let Claudio to speak about the sensitivity to the oil price. On the refining business, we feel that it's not the right time to plan any sale. The market is quite dramatic for refining across Europe and in many areas of the world. We had <mark type="inaudible" /> market a few months ago for Livorno, but we didn't find really a real buyer for the refinery; and I think it would be even less today.</p>
          <p>As far as our chemical business, for which we forecast in 2010 somewhat better results than in 2009; we think that the market is finally showing signs of improvement. All our efforts are directed to reduce the areas of losses of this business, and we continue to close down factories or part of factories which are making losses. We continue to be the same during 2010, being very careful to the cash that we pour into this business.</p>
          <p>Claudio, do you want to speak about sensitivity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, very quickly &#x2013; an answer. Broadly, when we talk about sensitivity we can confirm, we still confirm 1,000 barrels for each dollar. So that is still the sensitivity and that is the same sensitivity that we run also in 2009 that will be at the moment &#x2013; at the moment maintained also in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's clear. Thank you. So just to come back on the chemicals business, Paolo. So can we see the chemical business breaking even this year? Or you think that's going to take a longer time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's very early days to say that, because the improvement took place as recently as January. I normally measure the temperature of the economy looking at our chemical business, because our polymers go into different factors such as automotive or white goods or transportation or packaging, et cetera. And for the first time in many months, we have seen January and February orders improving quite sharply. So we feel that the situation is improving. I'm not sure that this year we will breakeven in economic terms. We might be looking for improvement in terms of our cash flow. But certainly this is a recent good news for us and for the economy in general.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Aymeric de Villaret, Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Mr. De Villaret, Please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. On the three pipes you want to sell before the end of the year, I would like to concentrate my question on the two <mark type="inaudible" /> and Transitgas pipes. First of all, could you please <mark type="inaudible" /> that your partners E.On and Swissgas have preemptive rights in those two pipes? Secondly, do you think those preemptive rights are acceptable by the EU Commission, i.e. will it make sense for E.On that has been signed on pipes already mismanaged to get a stake or a higher stake in TENP? Secondly if this is of the case, who do you think might buy those pipes? And final question, why did you get the price and how did you achieve the price you gave to the price? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alessandro, would you like to the answer these questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So after having submitted to the European Commission our proposed remedies and after having received the early approval, we have started to have contact with our partners. Since contractually, based on the existing shareholders agreement they have apprehensive rights. They have not yet decided to exercise it, because as you know, we have some months in order then to execute what we have agreed with the European Commission.</p>
          <p>So presently they are aware what we have we must do in the next few months and that we are waiting for their reaction. Then as far as the prices, which appears on the newspaper recently this is just an estimate is our internal evaluation of such assets. Even though I wanted to emphasize the fact that the business carried out by these companies is in a certain way quite simple because &#x2013; and accordingly also the economic and their financial flow are quite predictable and accordingly, also, the economical evaluation is not very complicated. There are not many variables which can influence the evaluation of these companies, and we can &#x2013; we are quite confident that the amount which has been published on the newspaper could be the appropriate value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good take. And I have a follow-up. I mean do you think it will acceptable from the European Commission point of view to get E.On to get this &#x2013; your stake in the trend? I mean, normally it should be something else &#x2013; somebody else, so is those contracts &#x2013; is contract &#x2013; that an old contract still acceptable at the EU level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, of course, you should ask the question to European Union. I tend to agree with you that may be they would not get permission to buy, but frankly I don't know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if E.On doesn't buy it, who could be interested?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there are several buyers who'd like to invest in this kind of regulated business because in fact these pipelines are very much similar to regulated business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Mr. Neill Morton from MF Global. Mr. Morton, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. A couple of quarters ago we were discussing the Nigerian bribery case and I noticed this morning that one of the other partners in the consortium technique has announced a charge for their Q4 results. I <mark type="inaudible" /> earlier this week and there was nothing on Nigeria on that particular call. Could you perhaps comment there?</p>
          <p>And then just secondly on the refining, I'm not sure if this is a question, more of a statement. You talked about low exposure to refining. Perhaps in terms of absolute capacity, yes, but in terms of absolute losses a &#x20AC;200 million loss in Q4 versus the likes of <mark type="inaudible" /> BP generating profits is still quite sizable? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on refining, you're quite right, the demands &#x2013; the last quarter has been catastrophic &#x2013; has been catastrophic for, I think for everybody in the industry. And it's been particularly difficult for us because we suffered, not only from the lowest refined margins in the last two decades. But we also suffer from the fact that &#x2013; the difference of price between heavy crude and light crude has been shrinking to almost nothing during the quarter, and since our refining system has been built to refine heavy oil, we could not benefit from the differential of price. So it has been quite an exceptionally bad quarter, which we do not expect to repeat in the future. As far as Nigeria, I think Alessandro would like to answer this question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you are right the <mark type="inaudible" /> has been &#x2013; why they disclose the &#x2013; by our report throughout to 2009 . We as Eni and Saipem, we are presently cooperating with the investigation that's carried out by both Italian and U.S. authorities. The Italian investigation, in particular, has shown positive developments in the last few days, which enable us to say that on this front we are approaching a favorable outcome.</p>
          <p>Then as far as the U.S. front is concerned, we are continuing to provide our cooperation to the U.S. authorities. We understand that we went through the press release which Teknik has issued this morning and we have understood that they are making a provision for the settlement with the U.S. authorities. We are not currently making any provision for this, as the outcome of the investigation on the U.S. front is still very uncertain and the possible losses cannot be still quantified. Teknik probably is in an advanced stage and probably they are closed to finalizing something with the U.S. authorities. We are still in the cooperation phase and presently we have not the element which create for us any particular worries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And just back on refining, you mentioned resilience of marketing, could I just ask the usual question, a split between refining and marketing in Q4?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have the number by-heart, but maybe &#x2013; but for the full year, for the full year, I can give you because this I remember, we made around 400 million in the market and we lost roughly 550 refining. Am I correct Alessandro? Alessandro.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the -- I am sorry there was a problem with the line. So in refining all over the year we have realized an operating loss around &#x20AC;700 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And we made in marketing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In marketing, we succeeded in realizing a profit, operating profit of almost &#x20AC;350 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no further questions for the moment. I confirmed there are no more questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the conference call is over. Thank you very much for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>