<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1444348" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>827</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Alessandro Bernini</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Theepan Jothilingam</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Operating Officer, Gas &amp; Power">Umberto Vergine</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies International Ltd.">Iain S. Reid</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Jon Rigby</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Plc">Nitin Sharma</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Michele della Vigna</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Operating Officer, Exploration &amp; Production">Claudio Descalzi</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Hootan Yazhari</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep" affiliation="Managing Director, Versalis">Daniele Ferrari</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Oswald C. Clint</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA (UK)">Irene Himona</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Mediobanca Banca di Credit Finanziario SpA (Broker)">Andrea Scauri</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Rahim N. Karim</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="corprep">Unverified Speaker</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to Eni's 2012 Third Quarter Results Conference Call hosted by Alessandro Bernini, Chief Financial Officer. For the duration of the call, you will be in listen-only mode. However, at the end of the call, you have opportunity to ask questions. I'm now handing you over to your host to begin today's conference. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to our Third Quarter Results Conference Call.</p>
          <p>Let's start off with the highlights. With the sale of Snam and Galp progressing, the new Eni is starting to emerge. Our balance sheet at the end of Q3 is stronger benefiting from cash inflows from the disposals of 5% of Snam reported as is an equity transaction and 5% of Galp and the consolidation for a total of around &#x20AC;11.1 billion.</p>
          <p>You should also bear in mind that this figure doesn't include the &#x20AC;3.5 billion consideration from the completion of the sale of 30% of Snam to CDP and, further, that big consolidation from Snam in the region of &#x20AC;1 billion. Our business is increasingly focused on our E&amp;P division which, in the third quarter, continued to show strong performance is driven by the ramp-up of Libyan production and exceptional exploration success.</p>
          <p>Looking at the Gas &amp; Power, Refining &amp; Marketing and Chemicals, we are making good progress on our plans to tackle challenging market conditions. In Gas &amp; Power, we are working on the renegotiation of our supply cost and have opened negotiations with counterparties including Statoil and GasTerra.</p>
          <p>On the commercial front, we continued to grow in our target markets with sales in France, Germany and Austria up by 43% year on year and to focus on higher margin segments such as retail and international LNG.</p>
          <p>In Refining &amp; Marketing, while benefiting from the current spike in refining margins, we continue to work on reducing overall capacity with an agreement to reconvert our Venice plant into a green refinery and on cost-cutting which we expect to total almost &#x20AC;100 million by year end 2012.</p>
          <p>Lastly, we are working to improve our Chemical footprint in the context of a very weak market. In particular, in the quarter we have signed joint ventures agreements leveraging on our elastomer expertise to grow our presence in the favorable Asian market.</p>
          <p>And now I will take you through our Q3 results in more detail.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter of 2012, the market environment was broadly positive, the brand price averaging $109.6 a barrel in the quarter up 1% versus last quarter and down over 3% year on year. The appreciation of the dollar versus the euro continued, also, in this quarter up over 2% versus last quarter and over 11% compared to one year ago. The European refining scenario was also supported with an average Brent-Ural margin of $7.35 a barrel, almost a three-fold increase from the third quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>Turning now to our results, you should remember that following the divestment of Snam, their regulated businesses in Italy have been deconsolidated from Gas &amp; Power results and represented as discontinued operations in accordance with the applicable reporting standards. Consequently, margins generated by transactions between Snam and Eni Group companies are considered as a part of the EBIT adjusted and net income adjusted from continued operations, while the margins generated by transaction between Snam and third parties had been classified as discontinued operation.</p>
          <p>The same reporting standard has been applied, also, to Q3 2011 results in order to facilitate the year-on-year comparison. In the third quarter of 2012, adjusted operating profit from continuing operation was &#x20AC;4.36 billion, up 2.2% from the third quarter 2011. The result reflected a better operating performance reported by the Exploration &amp; Production division up 10.8% due to an ongoing production recovery in Libya.</p>
          <p>The Refining and Marketing Division improved its results supported by a positive trading environment and efficiency and optimization gains. These increases were partially offset by a large operating loss incurred in Gas &amp; Power, down by <mark type="ph" /> 63% (5:55).</p>
          <p>In the third quarter 2012, adjusted net profit from continuing operations was &#x20AC;1.78 billion increasing by 3.1% from the corresponding period of the previous year. In the third quarter 2012, Eni's reported liquid and gas production of 1,718,000 barrel of oil equivalent per day was calculated assuming a new conversion rate of gas to barrels equivalent which added 9,000 of barrel of oil equivalent per day to Q3 production.</p>
          <p>On a comparable basis, i.e., when excluding the effect of the new gas conversion rate, production increased by 16% in the quarter. The performance was driven by an ongoing recovery in Libyan production as well as the start-up and ramp-up of new fields in Australia and Russia. These positives were partially offset by the shutdown of the Elgin-Franklin field in the U.K. and the impact of unexpected production standstills, in particular, in the Gulf of Mexico due to hurricanes in addition to mature field declines.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter of 2012, the Exploration &amp; Production Division reported an adjusted operating profit of &#x20AC;4.3 billion representing an increase of &#x20AC;422 million from the third quarter of 2011, up by 10.8%.</p>
          <p>Turning now to Gas &amp; Power, despite sluggish gas demand and the rising competitive pressure, sales of natural gas from the third quarter of 2012 were 18.8 bcm, an increase of 8.7% from the third quarter of 2011. The better performance was due to increased volumes sold in European and international markets.</p>
          <p>This was partially offset by lower sales of the Italian market, in particular, in the Power Generation segment. Despite the increasing volumes, adjusted operating losses in the Marketing segment increased by 18% to &#x20AC;354 million owing to deteriorating competitive environment partially offset by the cost benefits of supply renegotiation and the increase in Libyan volumes.</p>
          <p>This number doesn't include the negative effects of price revisions with certain long-term gas suppliers pertaining to previous reporting periods as these have been presented as special items. EBITDA's are well-reflected temporarily inflated supply cost for these contracts, an issue which we are already addressing through further renegotiations.</p>
          <p>Gas &amp; Power results also reflected sharply lower contribution from international transport, down from &#x20AC;104 million to &#x20AC;50 million due to the divestment of the company's interest in TENP and Transitgas executed at the end of 2011.</p>
          <p>Let's now take a look at Gas &amp; Power adjusted pro forma EBITDA. Compared to EBIT, this metric shows deterioration versus Q3 2011 mainly caused by the lower contribution from associates. You should note that the marketing segment is impacted by the reclassification of Galp, an asset available for sale, while international transport results reflect the divestment of the company's interest in TAG as well as those in TENP and Transitgas.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter of 2012, the refining market individual reported improved operating results amounted to &#x20AC;51 million up by &#x20AC;49 million from the year-earlier quarter. This increase reflects the recovery in refining margins and gains achieved on the efficiency and optimization measures. These positives were partially offset by shrinking price differentials between light and semi-crudes that impacted the profitability at complex refineries and lower demand of products due to the current economic downturn.</p>
          <p>Lower product demand also impacted result in the Marketing business where we reacted to the difficult scenario with a high-profile promotion during summer weekends.</p>
          <p>In the quarter, the Chemical division reported an adjusted operating loss of &#x20AC;173 million increasing by &#x20AC;96 million from the third quarter of 2011. The escalating cost of oil-based feedstock against a backdrop of a weak product demand led to a negative benchmark margin of cracking.</p>
          <p>Saipem reported a solid operating performance up by 15.9% in the third quarter to &#x20AC;386 million. Other activities and Corporate showed an aggregate loss of &#x20AC;106 million versus &#x20AC;146 million in the previous year. Net cash generated by operating activities was &#x20AC;1.9 billion in the quarter. Cash out-flows in the quarter include dividend payments of &#x20AC;2 billion which reflected the payment of the interim 2012 dividend.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditure amounted to &#x20AC;3.2 billion and mainly relates to the continuing development of oil and gas reserves and the upgrading of the Saipem offshore vessels and drilling units. Disposals of assets mainly regarded a divestment of a 5% interest in Galp for an amount close to &#x20AC;590 million, the sale of 5% of Snam for &#x20AC;612 million and other minor non-strategic assets.</p>
          <p>The change in net debt was impacted by other items including the refinancing of the intercompany loan by Snam for around &#x20AC;9.9 billion in the quarter. As a result, net financial debt during September 2012 was down by &#x20AC;7.3 billion from June 30, 2012.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention and, now with Claudio Descalzi and Umberto Vergine, we are ready to answer <mark type="indiscernible" /> (13:41).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the Q&amp;A session is now open. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> First question comes from Mr. Theepan Jothilingam from Nomura International. Mr. Jothilingam, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon. A few questions, please. Alessandro, you talk about in the press release a debt equity ratio in line with other majors. I was just wondering if you could provide a little bit more color, what the appropriate level you think for Eni is given your credit rating.</p>
          <p>Secondly, just in that context, I was wondering where you thought your debt equity ratio would be at the end of this year, and then moving on to gas marketing, clearly still very difficult market. Could you just talk about your thoughts on if or how and when you may go about potentially renegotiating contracts over the next 12 months? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will answer to the first two questions you have raised and then I pass to my friend, Umberto Vergine, for the appropriate answer to the question relating to Gas business.</p>
          <p>So as far as what we deem appropriate in terms of leverage after having disposed Snam and when we will have realized the disposal of the residual stake, we believe that an appropriate debt to equity ratio could be in the range of between 20% and 25% which, more or less, is the average of debt to equity ratio of most of the companies in our peers group. So this is what we deem appropriate but, for sure, we have the possibility to achieve a better ratio thanks, also, to the disposal of the other investment that we have to realize. I'm referring to Galp. in particular.</p>
          <p>Then as you know, as you have realized from our third quarter report, we have a debt to equity ratio of 0.32 by the end of September and, thanks to the monetization of the 30% stake that we have sold to CDP as well as some other minor disposals in the last part of the year. but predominantly because of the strong cash flow generated by the recurring operation, which we expect to achieve in the last part of the year, we expect that debt to equity ratio will be much lower compared to the level existing by the end of September.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If how and when we are going to renegotiate, Eni is currently involved in several discussion with the supplier in order to guarantee cost entry that the cost of gas is competitive. In 2012, these were related to a significant portion of our portfolio, and it is equivalent to 30% in volume and we expect that some of this renegotiation will be closed by the end of the year. In 2013, our contract will allow us to renegotiate another 40% of our portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. And just coming back then, if gearing does go below those levels, your preference would be to use the buyback to return cash to shareholders rather any further rebasing of the dividend? Is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Buyback is one of the elements which the board has already proposed to the shareholders, to the shareholders' meeting. But as far as the buyback policy is concerned, this will be announced in more detail when we will present our next four-year plan at the next strategy presentation in early March of 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Mr. Iain Reid from Jefferies. Mr. Reid, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, morning, sorry, afternoon, gentlemen. Can I ask another question about the marketing supply contracts? I think Mr. Scaroni was talking a few weeks ago, perhaps, a more radical solution to the gas supply contracts potentially of signing them to some other company or maybe even the government itself. Is this something which you are discussing internally and, perhaps, with the government?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The statement of Mr. Scaroni that was made in front of the Italian Parliament reflected the need of recognizing the value of the security of supply and, therefore, the cost associated with this value particularly at the time when the marketing is moving very rapidly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and just one other point on this. Given your expectation for the renegotiations which are currently taking place, what's your view on the recovery of the business into profit going into 2013? Do you think that's reasonable given your expectation of where prices might end up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This year, we are extremely busy on the continuity of renegotiation. And the ability to bring back the supply cost to the market price is the key to achieve these results. Of course, as you can understand, this is a game played by two players, us and the supplier. So our intention is to use all the contractual means to achieve this result.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if you achieve that, you'll be back in profit in Marketing sometime in 2013. Is that what you're saying?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You see, our guidance is to improve in operating profit compared to 2011 and this, of course, comes a lot on the result on the renegotiation of Gazprom, the same achievement <mark type="ph" /> with the current (21:05) renegotiation with our 2013 results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question come from Mr. Jon Rigby from UBS. Mr. Rigby, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you. Just a couple of questions I see. One is just go back, sorry to labor the point on these gas contracts. Isn't the issue that you have structural is that you're selling on a part an indexation partly to spot. You're buying on an indexation to oil. But, ultimately, wouldn't the best solution and, is this the way you're going, be to rebase everything so that you're buying and selling on the same basis and to remove that basis risk? Is that ultimately where you would like to go on this and would remove this kind of volatility?</p>
          <p>I mean, I guess following up on Iain's question is are we to understood that, at some point or other, there will be adjustments made in terms of catch up that will restore, on average, the level of profitability for the Gas &amp; Power business, although it will be lumpy. So let's say 2013, late 2013 or 2014, some sort of catch up that will make the average for 2012, 2013 something more recognizable for us to look at?</p>
          <p>The second question is just on CapEx. I think Mr. Descalzi said at the EMP Seminar recently that his expectation was that there will be a slowly rising CapEx figure, but nothing outstanding based on this years but rising a little. How should we understand this, as you see it right now, that the CapEx a burden for the rest of the business is, I guess with the removal of Snam, optically it will be lower. But what are we seeing around the rest of the business, and is there more CapEx to come in the downstream businesses, Refining &amp; Marketing, Petchem, to try and realize some of the benefits you talk about to finally bring these businesses back to profit? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on the gas contract, you are right. We have two ways to achieve market reflectivity in our contract; one is to introduce more elements to link directly to price to the spot market prices. The other one is to work on the formula on <mark type="indiscernible" /> (23:47), namely the P0 that qualifies as the sixth element of the formula.</p>
          <p>Depending on the type of concept and the structure of the contract, we are applying either one or the other strategy or both at the same time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as far as CapEx, the question relating to CapEx, of course, we can provide a guidance as we have, we already did in our press release with reference to 2012, Jon. As far as 2013 is concerned, now we are preparing our new estimates for both 2013 and subsequent year. So I believe that it is too early to provide a specific guidance on what we are targeting for next year.</p>
          <p>But, however, since most of the spending relates to the upstream, we can already anticipate that we don't see any specific reason why the number, the amount of the spending for next year, should be significantly different compared to what we are forecasting for 2012.</p>
          <p>As far as any particular transaction, sale transaction affecting other businesses, presently we are not targeting any major transaction in this respect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Can I just follow-up on &#x2013; I tried to hint at it, but if I take a quick glance back through my model, I might be wrong, but it looks to me that the Petrochemicals earnings were just about the worst quarterly earnings figure you've recorded in that business and, yet, there is an ongoing restructuring. I mean, when should we expect to see, taking into account obviously the prevailing market, but when should we expect to see something that we, as outsiders, can judge as being progress towards at least starting to stem some of these losses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are right. We have already announced at our strategy presentation but, more specifically, over the last few months with the specific price release, it is, I believe that what we have already announced confirm the intention of any to perform in complete downturn in our Petrochemical business.</p>
          <p>For sure, these moves can be divided into two big groups; one which affect predominantly the cost optimization and the other one we are addressing the business into the production of those products which are capable to provide in higher return compared to what we are producing so far and as well as expanding the activity outside the Italian territory. And this has been confirmed through the signature of joint venture, in particular, with other operators in the Far East market. The effect of those actions partially has been already realized, and I am referring to those actions which has already delivered some reduction, some cost reduction and efficiency.</p>
          <p>Unfortunately, this positive effect had been destroyed by the negative market environment. But the most significant effects are expected starting probably something in 2013 but, more significantly, from 2014 onwards because from 2014 onwards some of the initiatives which are presently under realization I am referring to, for example, to the new biochemical plants we are realizing in Sardinia, these will be capable to provide significant return only as from 2014 onwards.</p>
          <p>So still let me say one year of <mark type="ph" /> Sabbath (28:31) after that, we expect a significant downturn in the earning generation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Alessandro.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Mr. Nitin Sharma from JPMorgan. Mr. Sharma, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Afternoon, gentlemen. Two questions if I may. First one on upstream. Could you please explain the decline in liquid realizations in this quarter despite the increase in benchmark? So why is it going that away? And second one, you mentioned likely divestment of Galp stake by end 2013. Could you provide some more details on your plans, and is offloading the stake in the market an option? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question, the lower realization in Q3 versus Q2 are mainly due to two factors; one, the weakness of some condensate prices include with high natural content and so mainly caused by low demand in the Petchem; and secondly, some light sweet in <mark type="ph" /> different (29:33) crude.. So as far as Eni, in particular, we have lower realization price in Libya with Zueitina condensate in NC 41, in Egypt in Abu Madi and el Qar'a. So that are the main reason of the lower realization for our crude.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, with respect to Galp, you have mentioned &#x2013; you had remember that in one of our previous statement, we have committed ourselves, based on your statement, that we will sell our residual stake in Galp within the end of 2013. Well, is, for sure, we are committed to monetize our stake in Galp as soon as possible but only to the extent we will be in a position to realize a consideration which satisfy our minimum expectation. And this depends, of course, on the market value of Galp shares.</p>
          <p>But let me emphasize one issue. Since today, our financial situation has been improved dramatically as a consequence of the disposal of Snam shares and, thanks to their reimbursement of the loans that we have previously granted to Snam, now we are not in hurry to monetize nor Snam stake and Galp as well. And only to the extent, I repeat, it will be possible to realize consideration capable to satisfy at least our minimal expectation, then we will proceed.</p>
          <p>Otherwise, seems the investment is granting a quite remarkable return, we will keep it. However, just to give you an update, we have received quite recently a lot of interest from many financial institutions, so potentially our financial investors, and a market transaction based on these demonstrations of interest, a market transaction could be easily realized very soon. But since the benchmark is the prevailing market price today, this doesn't satisfy our minimal expectation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question come from Mr. Michele della Vigna from Goldman Sachs. Mr. della Vigna, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you for the presentation. I had two quick questions. For the first one, sorry to go back to Gas &amp; Power but, what we've seen in the last couple of months is strengthening in the spot gas price in Northern Europe and I was wondering if that would help the business with reducing the spread to the cost in your long-term contracts or if to see a recovery marketing you really need to see a recovery in European and, in particular, in Italian demand? And then the second question was on E&amp;P. You clearly had high margins value upstream this quarter, the Gulf of Mexico, also, Elgin-Franklin, I was wondering how quickly you thought you could resume these volumes. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Gas &amp; Power, the increasing spot in the Northern Europe is one of the phenomenon that, as we said before, we'll try to reflect in our contract re-negotiation particularly and those that are directly supplying gas in Northern Europe. The issue of the demand that is the criticality of the science as well, of course, in Europe and in Italy the impact of the lower demand, of course, has a peculiar impact on the creation of spread between the long-term contract and the market prices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So talking about Elgin-Franklin, as you know the operation has been successful. The well, G-4, has been killed and now completely under control and, in November, there is anything also on other wells you find. So while I assume that in our expectation is to resume production on this field in the first quarter. But you know that we are not the operator and we are always in contact with <mark type="ph" /> Total (34:32) that is manning all the operation and is also the interface with the authority in U.K. That is our expectation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And for the Gulf of Mexico field?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, for the Gulf of Mexico field, I think that we are present completely about 95% and, by the end of the year, we can reach 20%, but we resume completely our production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Mr. Hootan Yazhari from Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Mr. Yazhari, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there, gentlemen. Just a couple of questions. Let's start with Kashagan; maybe a quick update in terms of where you are there, how comfortable you are about a March start-up as you recently guided, how much cash contribution we can expect from this in 2013. And then also just to go back to the Petchem's business, you have some pretty ambitious plans there in terms of cutting cost and the like. However, if we start to look towards the United States, the increase in Petrochemical's capacity and the ability to export there within Eni cost advantage on the natural gas side. That has to be expected in the longer term. How do you feel about this and at what stage would you consider stepping down your Petrochemical operations, or is that just unfeasible given political practice? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Kashagan, there is no major news with respect to what I presented just 10 days ago during the upstream seminar. I can say that we continue the mechanical completion as planned and we focus to finish completely all the mechanical completion of the first train by the end and so our end of commissioning as well is continued and the weekly progress is in line with the budget.</p>
          <p>So we are still confident that we can reach this target at the end of March and in absolute we assure that we can reach the target, the contractual target, that is by production by the end of June. So, so far so good in term of respecting our budget targets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With reference to your question relating to the Petrochemical business, since there is with us, Daniele Ferrari the Managing Director of Versalis, he will provide you with the detailed answer to your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It's Daniele Ferrari. Let me come back to the Petrochemical description of the strategy that Alessandro read before. What we are trying to do is essentially to deemphasize our business on the olefin, polyolefin side and try to maximize the output of our cracker more on the heavier fraction, I'll call it, it co-products, which are the most valuable for us and which are the one that will not be available when you crack gas molecule like the United States market.</p>
          <p>So we do realize that the shale play in the United States is going to create a lot of capacity that is generating capacity on products that we are not going to compete with because we couldn't do it. So we just target our strategy towards reducing our exposure on the products we cannot compete like polyethylene coming from Middle East or United States in the future and maximize the revenue that will come from international expansion of new products biorefinery system that we use to convert all the necessary Petrochemicals unit and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (38:31) which are the products we feel more strongly about and which are the products we have based our technology for the joint venture that Alessandro was mentioning before. I hope I answer this for your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Mr. Oswald Clint from Sanford Bernstein. Mr. Clint, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you very much. Can I ask just on the Gas &amp;  Power business, is there a limit in terms of how far you can push something like Gazprom on the long-term contracts versus your ambitions to be ever-present in the Russian upstream and part of projects like South Stream, et cetera, or is it two separate divisions separately having these discussions? And then the second question just on Iraq, if you could just let us know what the volumes were in the third quarter and, also, have you started recovering some of the early CapEx from that development? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we treat the matter of the renegotiation independently from other business. With Gazprom, we don't have upstream activity anyway. Of course, the general partnership is always behind the company relationship but, on the commercial side, the matters are very separate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Iraq?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So for Iraq, respecting last year, Iraq is doing quite well because with respect to 2011, we add about 11,000, 12,000 barrels per day. So the budget for Iraq this year is of about 18,000 barrels per day. And the project, the rehabilitation project, is progressing now. They are producing about 260,000 barrels per day, and we hope that in 2013 we can increase this figure at about 350,000 barrels per day in line with our budget.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Ms. Irene Himona from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;neral&#xE9;. Ms. Himona, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. I had three short questions. So first of all Libya, if you can please update us on what we should expect for full year production from Libya. And then secondly, the tax rate in Q3 was below expectations, again, if you can remind us of your guidance for the full year on tax. And also on depreciation, I note the nine-month depreciation charge was up about 22%. Is that the actual level for the full year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first Libya. This quarter, we have oil production is about 250,000 barrel per day, a little bit more. We think we can confirm our outlook for 2012 of 240,000 barrel per day because we push through the year and some maintenance program. So that is the update on Libya. And as I already said a few days ago, we are working on <mark type="indiscernible" /> (42:14) very positive and constructive way on six big projects, and six big projects that's related mainly to gas and condensates and oil that we hope that we can perform in the next four- year plan. For tax rate, Alessandro.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tax rate, you are right, Ms. Himona. Our tax rate in the first quarter was, tax rate adjusted, was 54% significantly lower compared either to the second quarter or to the corresponding quarter of last year. The main reason why the tax rate was so low in the third quarter that we've made the most important reason are predominately true. The first relates to the income from associates, the amount of which the amount dividends distributed by associates in the third quarter was significantly higher compared to both the third quarter of last year and the second quarter, and you know that dividends are under the participation exemption rules. So they are almost without any taxation effect.</p>
          <p>And then in the third quarter, there was also a contribution of the fair value evaluation of some currency derivatives which, by the way, supported, also, the lower financial charge in the third quarter, which are taxed normally at a lower tax rate. And these are the two most important reasons why the tax rate in the third quarter was significantly lower compared to the normal adjusted tax rate.</p>
          <p>As far as what we expect for the full year, I believe that that it is useful to remember that the tax rate can flip the weight over the quarter because of some, let me say, extraordinary effect like the dividends, which I had mentioned before.</p>
          <p>But for the full year, our guidance remains in the region of 60% as we already announced previously, and these 60% will be a little bit higher compared to 2011 since, of course, we expect a higher contribution from the earnings generated in Libya where the tax rate, local tax rate, is significantly higher than the average tax rate of the, in particular, the upstream business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. As far as depreciation, depreciation is concerned, yes, you are right. We have already accounted for a quite important increase both in the third quarter compared to last year and in the nine-month period and this, of course, relates to the start-up of new projects, projects which have been realized in the recent year so which carry normally in the higher depreciation compared to the previous project.</p>
          <p>So it was expected. It was in line, absolutely, in line with our expectation, and what we have registered so far is expected to be almost in line, also, for the rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question come from Mr. Andrea Scauri from Mediobanca. Mr. Scauri, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. A question on Mozambique, if I may. I was wondering if you could provide an update on the exploration activity on the back of the latest upstream seminar when you said that you are in your plans, three or four additional wells. When do you expect the exploration is going to be finished? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We just finished today, the well that we are drilling on Mamba South East 2, and we tested. That is the first test that we are performing there and that has been very successful. We have not yet issued the press release, but it's really more than confirming the quality of the reservoir. And now we're going to move the rig to drill Coral 2 reservoir entirely in the area four. So that is the second well and I think that we can drill. There is still space to drill an additional appraisal before the end of the year. That is the update on the Mozambique.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And if I may, are there chances to see a further increase in the 73 million cubic feet of resources in place that you announced recently?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is our hope that 73 million cubic feet is really a big figure so that is our hope. And now we are testing because we did, at the last well, we increased not with the risk of other research <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:02) of 72 million cubic feet, 73 million cubic feet.</p>
          <p>But at the moment, our action is to really to be sure about the 73 million cubic feet. Now we are more or less at 65 million cubic feet, and we are to derisk the other at 73 million cubic feet. So we have this hope especially with the future steps. As you know, by March or April, we finish the Mamba campaign in Coral and then we start new campaign in the South without a prospect new, new fresh prospects, and that really offset can increase the amount of resources on the canal..</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>No more questions at the moment. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Next question comes from Mr. Rahim Karim from Barclays. Mr. Karim, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. Two questions, if I may. The first is just around the cash flow statement for the quarter. It seems to have been quite a weak cash conversion during the 3Q. Just wondering if there was anything in specific that you would draw to our attention, perhaps, around working capital and how that might evolve over the course of 4Q. And the second question was just around take or pay liabilities, if there was any guidance that you could give around that at this stage? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you are right. The third quarter, the cash flow generated by, say, a recurring operation was a little bit disappointing. But at the same time, we are extremely confident that this situation will be improved and my sense is is already supported on what is already happened during the month of October. In particular, above, in the third quarter, I believe that is useful to remember that the third quarter is traditionally lower in terms of cash generation, in particular because of the lower cash generated by our Gas &amp; Power division.</p>
          <p>Since, during the summer season, a portion, quite important portion, of the gas purchase is addressed to the gas storage in view of the new thermal season. So we incur a liability. We have to pay our supplier. But in the meantime, we have no proceeds generated by the disposal. Then of course, this situation is due to change in the last quarter because traditionally the last quarter of the year is quite important in terms of sales volume and, say, in the cash flow generated by the normal sales of the Gas &amp; Power division.</p>
          <p>Then, as already announced, also, Saipem, which we consolidate with the integral criterion, Saipem has already announced that has experienced a quite significant increase in the working capital in the third quarter. But also for, also, Saipem is expecting to reverse significantly this situation in the last quarter of the year.</p>
          <p>So all-in-all, the third quarter had been disappointing but because affected by all seasonal or extraordinary elements which are due to be reversed completely in the last part of the year. So we are confident, as I already mentioned in another previous answer to another question that the last quarter will be extremely important in terms of cash flow generated by the recovering operations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On gas, despite having reduced 2012 minimum contractual quantity by our renegotiation, we still expect to incur some take or pay prepayments in 2012 mainly due to the significant amount of reduction, particularly in Italy. This extra take or pay volume are anyway the same direction that we will be able to recover within the full life of the contract.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to complete the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (53:15), just to come back for a while to my previous sentence, the third quarter had been also negatively affected by a payment to one of our suppliers, Gastar, as a consequence of the arbitration proceeding which has been published within the end of September and, as a consequence of this arbitration proceeding, we had to pay within the end of September the relevant amount which was quite a remarkable amount of money.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. If I could just press you, is there a number that you could provide in terms of the take or pay liability that we can expect for the end of the year? I understand you'll be able to recoup that in future years but, just help us whittle the cash flow, is there a number that you're able to give?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I would integrate the amounts which has provided by Umberto. I am not so confident to provide a specific figure because it will depend a lot on the volumes of the sales that will be realized in the last quarter of the year and that sales volume are also can be significantly affected by, for example, the weather conditions during the last part of the year and could be also affected by the already ongoing renegotiation which normally affect both prices but, also, as well as the minimum quantity that we have to pay to our supplier.</p>
          <p>So I repeat, we expect to face a payment within the end of the year in terms of take or pay but it is too early to provide a number, which could be significantly modified thanks to the elements which I mentioned before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Perfect. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>No more questions at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. If there are no more questions, perhaps we can bring the conference to a close and, if you have any questions at a later date, feel free to call us on the Investor Relations number. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the conference call is over. Thank you for calling Eni.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>