<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1330733" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-08-11</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2864</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Sascha Bibert, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Dr. Johannes Teyssen, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Marcus Schenck, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Patrick Hummel</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Martin Young</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Benjamin Leyre</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Lueder Schumacher</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Bobby Chada</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Andreas Thielen</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Bernhard Jeggle</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Deborah Wilkens</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Tanja Markloff</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Andrew Simms</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Vincent De Blic</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Alexander Karnick</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Christopher Kuplent</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Dear ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the E.ON Interim Report Call. At our customers' request, this conference will be recorded. As a reminder, all participants will be in a listen-only mode. After the presentation, there will an opportunity to ask questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>May I now hand over to Sascha Bibert, Head of Investor Relations who will take you through this conference. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good afternoon everyone. Welcome to the conference call on the first half 2010 results. Johannes Teyssen, our CEO will summarize the main Group financials, comment on the nuclear tax discussion in Germany, update you on the operating environment in our power and gas business, take a special look at our supply and sales business within Pan-European Gas, discuss the status quo of our portfolio streamlining initiatives. And finally announce changes to the E.ON management team. Thereafter Marcus Schenck, our CFO will go into more details regarding our financial results. With that I hand over to you Johannes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, everybody, the analysts and investors. Welcome to our conference call on the first half-year results of 2010. The developments of the first six-months show that our company is operationally very well on track. The E.ON Group EBITDA amounted to 7.9 billion, up 9% year-on-year, and adjusted EBIT reached 6.1 billion, an 11% improvement. In the analysis of the headline profit figures you should keep in mind that we have lost some 500 million of EBIT due to asset disposals across the Group. Meanwhile, our operational, our performance improvement program Perform-to-Win is progressing well. We reached more than 600 million of EBIT improvements in the first half. For example 25% of that is due to reduction in service and overhead spend, another 10 to 15% each for the optimization of our procurement and measures directed to improve our operations in the UK Retail business, under the title Clean Utility Project. Those are just examples. And we are therefore well on track to deliver 1 billion for the full year. This also makes us very confident to reach our target of 1.5 billion of sustainable improvements to adjusted EBIT by 2011.</p>
          <p>The operating performance in the first half was supported in a broad front. Pan-European Gas benefited from the inclusion of our new upstream participation Yushno Russkoje. This field will contribute some 6 bcm to our equity gas production. In addition, the supply and sales business benefited from positive price and significant volume effects. To some extent this is a result of the recent first round of renegotiations of our LTCs, which hedged us well for the current gas year running on to the 30th of September.</p>
          <p>In the UK, Retail margins recovered from an unsustainable low last year driven by a favorable price environment as well as substantial operational improvements within our operations. Those include the reduction of bad debt and the consolidation of call centers. The market remains very competitive however and E.ON UK decreased gas prices for residential customers by 6% at the end of March.</p>
          <p>Nordic gained from higher revenue in power distribution and somewhat improved availability of our nuclear fleet. For much of last year Oskarshamn 3 had been maintenanced to upgrade its capacity from 1,150 megawatt to 1,400 megawatt and to modernize it in preparation of a lifetime extension to 60-year lifetime. However the upgrade of Oskarshamn 3 has not yet been fully effective and takes longer than scheduled. We expect it to operate at full capacity as of October. Successful hedging support our trading operation. I would like to remind you all that this year's hedges were mostly placed in the high-priced environment of 2007 and 2008. In our new markets, earnings in Russia were driven by expanding margins due to the ongoing liberalization process and very strict cost management. Continuous capacity additions delivered higher profits for climate and renewables.</p>
          <p>On the negative side, earnings in Central Europe declined, however, mainly due to the disposal of generation capacity and the sale of our TSO business. One-off effects in the carve-out of A2A depressed our Italian operation on a year-on-year comparison.</p>
          <p>Now moving forward down the P&amp;L, adjusted net income was down 1%, are pretty much year-on-year levels, as a consequence of higher net interest, especially higher tax expenses. Overall, we are confirming the outlook for the full year. We expect adjusted EBIT to grow by 0 to 3% and adjusted net income to be in line with previous year. We expect the second half to be more challenging with supply and sales margins at Pan-European Gas to suffer substantially in the first quarter. Furthermore, Retail margins in the UK are expected to deteriorate in the latter part of this year.</p>
          <p>I'm planning to talk about the developments beyond 2010 during our Capital Market Day in London scheduled for September the 28. However, should we run into a situation where there is insufficient information on the nuclear debate in Germany and we would consider postponing the event in order not to waste anyone's time. But I sincerely today hope that this scenario will not materialize.</p>
          <p>During today's presentation, as Sascha indicated, I'd like to discus four topics in more detail. The nuclear energy in Germany, the operating environment for our power and gas business, the development of our supply and sales business with Pan-European Gas, and an update regarding the portfolio streamlining activities.</p>
          <p>If you turn to chart number two before describing the status quo of the nuclear debate, let me make one personal comment. Over the last month, we all have been faced with a vast array of news flow, not a single day goes by without someone making claims on how the energy world is suppose to look like, or how perceived profits from the utility should be used. This has resulted in significant share price volatility and valuations have suffered alongside.</p>
          <p>In spite of this E.ON has been relatively quiet. I have not been pounding the drum in this or that direction. Let me be absolutely clear, this is a very serious situation for our company. However, so far, I have decided that not being too vocal to public debate is ultimately beneficial for all stakeholders. Nevertheless, rest assured, that we're doing our at most to contribute to solutions that are acceptable for all sides. We are fully aware that we are part of society, but we are not a stated-owned company. E.ON is fully owned by investors, by you, and we will act accordingly.</p>
          <p>Now back to my script. In its coalition agreement the German government had announced that it would pursue an ideology-free technology-neutral and market-oriented energy policy. 10 months later, what we're seeing as a new start there are still no clarity about the clear direction of Germany energy policy and thus there is also no clarity about the future of nuclear power in Germany either. Germany wants to continue to play a leading role in the fight against climate change. Similarly, Germany also wants to strengthen its economy. There is absolutely no doubt in my mind, but it cannot achieve these two goals without CO2 free and low cost nuclear power. Last year's economic and financial crisis have clearly shown how much the economic success of Germany relies on the competitiveness of its industry based on the backbone of its energy industry. Access to secure and competitive power is a decisive element in this respect. Nuclear energy contributes significantly to those goals today and could continue to do that tomorrow, if our highly secured reliable nuclear power plants were allowed to operate as long as what is usually the case in many other countries.</p>
          <p>In this regard we are prepared to share the benefit of a lifetime extension. But any benefit sharing must be balanced. I explicitly warn of charges of such a magnitude that the operation of nuclear power plants could become uneconomic and that the much-needed resources of investments in the green transformation of the energy system would disappear. Germany's proposed nuclear tax would be such a negative unacceptable charge. The charge would come far above the so-called windfall profits, which it claims to capture from the introduction of the European Emission Trading Scheme. Leaving aside the fact that emission trading is designed to favor CO2 free power generation such as nuclear at the expense of CO2 intense alternatives, we estimate that the real benefit of Emission Trading amounts roughly to &#x20AC;7 megawatt hour post tax at the current CO2 price of &#x20AC;15 per ton and compare that please to a proposed charge of up to &#x20AC;25 megawatt hour pre-tax for the nuclear proposal here in Germany.</p>
          <p>In total we currently estimate that the tax could burn our adjusted EBIT by 1.3 to &#x20AC;1.5 billion if the figures mentioned in the draft law would become reality. The subsequent charge would not only weaken the results but also the investment capacity of a company such as E.ON goes without saying. I would also like to point out that we doubt whether such tax complies with European law and with the German constitution. Furthermore it would damage to a significant extent the competitiveness of German nuclear and power production compared to foreign plants and compared to other technologies.</p>
          <p>More specifically, smaller nuclear plants would come under substantial pressure as they're position in the merit order would shift behind lignite and base load. And this is ridiculous result of the so claimed new energy policy. We are therefore making every effort together with the other operators of nuclear power plants in Germany to work on an alternative and legally more secure solution with the German government. They would have to be based on new production rights and a fair sharing of burden to take nuclear energy &#x2013; to tax nuclear energy to such an extent that it becomes uneconomic. Well, in my opinion, would produce an outcome that is a reverse of what the government really wants both economically and ecologically.</p>
          <p>I turn to chart three, let me now review the latest developments of power and gas demand, the commodity and power price environment, as well as E.ON sales volumes. In power, demand for the first half of the year was up 3.4% in all three major markets, which are Germany, the UK and Sweden. Demand in Germany was even up 4.6% in the first half mainly driven by the recovery of industrial production. In Sweden, where electricity is widely also used for private heating, demand benefited from the cold winter and grew even by 6.6%. By contrast, in the United Kingdom, demand had remained rather flattish so far this year. In Italy, on a low-base power demand, rose by 1.9% and Spain by a 3.6%; and both cases adjusted for weather and number of working days.</p>
          <p>With the exception of crude oil, prices for commodities and power rebounded in the second quarter. The macroeconomic data, including early indicators, remained volatile, especially with respect to the further economic development in the United States. German power forwards for 2011 base load follow the coal and gas price developments with the first half and ended on the same level as at the beginning of this year, roughly at &#x20AC;53 per megawatt hour.</p>
          <p>The Nordic market was particularly influenced by the cold and dry weather in the first quarter, leading to significantly lower than average hydro reservoir levels. The corresponding Nordic power price reached &#x20AC;45 per megawatt hour at the end of this period. In this environment, our own power production increased by 3% to around 137 terawatt hours. This was mainly driven by new gas-fired units in Central Europe, Irsching in Bavaria, Datteln also located in Bavaria, Emile Huchet in France as well as our new CHP station in Sweden and also one station in Scandale, Italy went on line.</p>
          <p>E.ON sales volumes broadly mirror the demand trends I've outlined for our major markets. Our sales to residential customers up 6%, but particularly stronger Nordic and new markets, while our sales to industrial and business customers progressed most in UK and Central Europe.</p>
          <p>On the gas side the amount was supported by the long and cold winter, mainly in the first quarter, by the recovery of industrial production and by switching towards gas-fired power generation. In the so-called Big Six European gas countries, gas demand was up 12.5% year-on-year over the period January to May. In Germany demand even improved by 14% in the first half.</p>
          <p>E.ON Ruhrgas performed well in this environment. Its sales volumes in Germany grew by 19%, outside Germany sales volumes improved even by 33%, but the latter figure includes some sales for trading. We have not yet fully recovered the volumes lost due to the economic crisis of 2009 and admittedly some of the good news on power and gas demand is due to an unusually long and cold winter, which is unlikely to repeat itself. Nevertheless, the general underlying trends on the demand side are reasonably positive.</p>
          <p>I turn to chart four, this graph shows how TTF gas forwards have heavy roles compared to Brent oil forwards, an illustration of the gap between oil-indexed LTCs and spot prices. The difference between the two reached a maximum around March and April this year, but has narrowed significantly since then and keeps being volatile in the last space.</p>
          <p>In this the oil forward did not change so much but the TTF forwards increased substantially and we see three key reasons for this development. First, the effect of the harsh winter on demand and storage, secondly, the recovery of industrial production, especially in the second quarter. As a result demand in Asia and Europe proved more robust than anticipated, and thirdly, finally, heavy maintenance of gas field and LNG facilities restricted supplies during the summer months and beyond the late spring months. It will be interesting to see how TTF prices will behave in the coming weeks once these facilities come back online.</p>
          <p>In general this development should serve as a reminder how volatile the situation is and how quick these spreads can open or narrow with subsequent impacts on our results. As most of the sales contracts for the 2011 gas year running from 1st of October to 30th of September 2011 have already been signed these movements will only have a limited influence on the earnings of the supply and sales business next year.</p>
          <p>For the majority of the contracts, the price level was negotiated at a time when difficult market conditions prevailed. Starting in the last quarter of 2010, we expect therefore margins in supply and sales to decrease substantially and possibly even turn negative. We have therefore already started to once more discuss the situation with major gas producers and plan to formerly open another round of renegotiations with most of them this autumn.</p>
          <p>Besides the revision of pricing of the long-term contracts, we intend to have general discussions with the producers regarding some fundamental elements within long-term contracts. We are convinced that the changes to the market environment that we're now seeing are here to stay. We therefore believe it is vital to adapt the long-term contracts to these market conditions in order to have a sustainable business model for all parties involved and to keep Russian, Norwegian and Dutch gas marketable.</p>
          <p>While the changes in the gas market are substantial most notably the development of separate markets for oil and gas and the increasing relevance of hub price signals our long-term positive view on the gas market stays unchanged. Economic growth and the role of gas and flexible power generation both fuel demand for the clean fossil fuel gas. Indigenous production in Europe will decline. Accordingly the imports will increase and long-term contracts will continue to be relevant for diversified supply portfolios, especially as liquidity on the gas hubs remain limited.</p>
          <p>On chart five, you will find an overview of our portfolio streamlining program. With the sale of E.ON US earlier this year, we have posted our two short-term objectives, namely, first, to deliver on our commitment to the EU Commission to divest 5 gigawatts of generating capacity in Germany as well as our power transmission network. And secondly, we raised disposal proceeds of at least 10 billion to reduce our leverage. I am pleased to report that the E.ON US transaction is proceeding as planned. A few days ago I met with politicians, regulators and Jim Miller of PPL. All the necessary filings have been done and the approval processes are progressing very well.</p>
          <p>The transaction got first approval Hart-Scott-Rodino in July. As a result, we remained very confident to close the deal by the end of this year. Meanwhile, our further portfolio streamlining program is continuing. The main objective now is on focusing the Group on those activities that we can add most value while keeping our balance sheet in order. With the sale of our 21% stake in the Swiss <mark type="inaudible" /> BKW for more than 0.5 billion in early July was another good step in that direction. We decided to exit this business as we saw no potential to generate further value.</p>
          <p>In the first step of the transaction, we sold 14% for roughly 350 million. BKW itself has an option to purchase a remaining 7% stake until September 2011 for another 180 million. Due to various preemptive rights at low price levels, we are very satisfied with the achieved price. I would also like to take the opportunity to highlight 14 smaller transactions that has been carried out since the start of the portfolio streamlining program. The sale of these assets when generated altogether some 700 million of disposal proceeds while they contributed only 20 million to adjusted EBIT, truly beneficial for our balance sheet and also favorable from a P&amp;L perspective. Those transactions demonstrate that we investigate all areas within the E.ON Group. One example is the sale of the former Thuga headquarter building, another the sale of two minorities stakes in Sweden electricity distributors. We sold 10% stake in the UK interconnector and furthermore disposals of smaller wind parks in several countries that did not fit within the E.ON climate and renewable portfolio.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, with chart six, let me conclude my presentation. The nuclear tax as proposed in the finance ministry draft would have a substantial impact on our results. It is likely to endanger the economic viability of nuclear power plants and would lead us to reduce investments. However, we are making every effort to work on an alternative solution within the German government. We expect the government to clarify its policy on lifetime extension and related charges by early September, all the cause of September obviously depending on the political process.</p>
          <p>After the deep fall of 2009, power and gas demand is recovering rather faster than we had anticipated. This was one of the factors that helped us to achieve strong operating results in the first half. Nevertheless, demand remains below the record levels achieved in 2008. We continue to be confront with some serious business challenges most clearly saw in our supply and sales business at Pan-European Gas. That is why we consciously keep our full year targets unchanged even though they might appear conservative at first sight. We are also delivering on our present strategic objectives. The BKW transaction announced in early July was such another step forward in the portfolio streamlining program. We are screening the whole portfolio at a very detailed level to bring more focus for the Group.</p>
          <p>Another element is the finalization of our new leadership structure. In this respect, I'm pleased to announce today that Bernhard Reutersberg, so far Chief Executive of E.ON Ruhrgas, that lot of you know for meetings will join my Board of Management at E.ON AG as of today. As a Manager in charge of the country subsidiaries, he will steer all the distribution and supply businesses of the Group with more than 30 million customers and lead all the related, political and regulatory processes. Bernhard Reutersberg has built a deep management experience in sales and marketing at Henkel and at Vaillant, and not least, more than 10 years in E.ON's power and gas businesses.</p>
          <p>In addition, he has developed excellent relations in Russia, for example, during the successful acquisition of Yuzhno Russkoye. In his new functioning, he will also be in-charge of coordinating our growing activities in the Russian markets. I am personally very convinced that his enrollment will further support the development of such Russian activities. Klaus Sch&#xE4;fer, who also, lot of you know, from with his former job will succeed Bernhard Reutersberg as CEO of E.ON Ruhrgas. Klaus Sch&#xE4;fer successfully carried out the integration of the assets acquired from Endesa as CEO of E.ON Italy. His Board experience in strategy, sales, trading and local gas utilities will certainly prove useful for steering E.ON Ruhrgas to a difficult phase. Ingo Luge will become Chief Executive of E.ON Energie succeeding Klaus-Dieter Maubach who will also join my Board in May. Ingo Luge has led E.ON Kraftwerke, the fossil power production of the Group since 2006. Prior to that, he has various management positions in German distribution and supply. Luca Dal Fabbro will take the operational leadership of our Italian subsidiary where he was Head of Sales until today.</p>
          <p>Miguel Anto&#xF1;anzas will take in addition to his other job, the task of, President of E.ON Italy in addition to his job as CEO of the Spanish subsidiary. He will more specifically steer the relations with politicians and regulators. Finally since a few days Jonas Abrahamsson the former CFO of our trading business succeeded H&#xE5;kan Buskhe, CEO of our Nordic business.</p>
          <p>With all of these decisions, all the responsibilities of the Board of Management of E.ON have been filled and the leadership of our most important operating subsidiaries has been clarified. I would like to highlight that we feel particularly comfortable handing over some of these responsibilities to in-house managers. This demonstrates the high quality of our management development programs and secures a seamless transition to concerned subsidiaries. Furthermore, these management changes will support the broader changes happening with the Group, which we will discuss on the 28th of September.</p>
          <p>Thank you for all of your attention. Marcus will now present to you the first half-year figures in more detail. Marcus, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, dear investors and analysts. I'm pleased to comment on what we consider to be very strong results for the first half of this year. Johannes already gave you the headline numbers with adjusted EBITDA up 9% to now at 7.9 billion and adjusted EBIT up 11% to &#x20AC;6.1 billion. Both benefits from a particularly strong first quarter this year with 3.3 billion, adjusted net income is almost at prior year level, and operating cash flow is up 30% to now &#x20AC;5.6 billion.</p>
          <p>Let me walk you through the main drivers for the increase in adjusted EBIT on a Group level. The biggest positive items, UK Retail is up &#x20AC;0.4 billion. This is a reflection of both our ongoing performance improvement measures, and in particular, driven by higher volumes and margins. The extremely cold winter led to high volumes in times when wholesale prices were depressed. This naturally increased our margin. Q2 did not see the same uplift given more normal volumes and a price reduction in gas, which became effective as of April.</p>
          <p>In our German DSO businesses, we see an 0.3 billion improvement over last year, of which 100 million is a one-off recovery of cost incurred in the first half of 2009. In our gas upstream activities we see a significant increase in profitability in the second quarter. We benefit from successful renegotiation of our long-term contracts during last autumn and winter. As Johannes outlined this improved gross margin will come under significant pressure due to new sales contracts coming into effect beginning in October when the next gas year starts.</p>
          <p>As expected we see a better asset optimization results in energy trading related to our power portfolio. Additional contributions from Perform-to-Win amounts to &#x20AC;0.2 billion. There are two main negative items. We lost earnings due to disposals made last year and we have the one-off effect from the termination of unfavorable power contracts in Italy that we spoke about in Q2 in 2009. This allows me to highlight a few aspects that may help you to assess the underlying operational performance of our business. Those two main negative effects should not be a sign to real business performance. Furthermore, you should take out 50 million of profit, which we consolidated last year and which now is carved out to A2A in Italy. Hence like-for-like, the first half of 2009 would have been 800 million lower. Conversely with the one-off recovery of 0.1 billion network cost from last year, 74 million from the first time inclusion of Yushno Russkoje and 100 million provision release in our gas and supply sales business which I'll comment on later. The first half of 2010 includes almost 300 million of profit that is not related to this year's operational performance. I could, if you want further deduct around 100 million positive translation effect, which we recorded in the first six months of this year. When you then do the math i.e., you knock off the 400 million from this year, this half year's figure, and the 800 million from last year's half year figure, you can easily see that the underlying operations improve by around 20%.</p>
          <p>Let me now go straight into the segments starting as usual with Central Europe on chart 11. Adjusted EBIT is down 300 million to &#x20AC;2.5 billion. However, this delta includes almost 420 million of earnings in the first half of 2009 that were related to assets sold in 2009, in particular generation capacity in Germany and the German TSO. Central Europe West non-regulated experiences a drop by &#x20AC;755 million, the main negatives are the following. The aforementioned 0.3 billion earnings from generation capacity sold around 100 million weaker results in the nuclear business due to higher maintenance cost, higher expenses for revision and slightly increased depreciation and a reduced equity results. Our gas retail business was 70 million weaker and we also have some profit transfer from Central Europe into energy trading based on the transfer price mechanism.</p>
          <p>And finally, last year we had a 74 million gain from the reevaluation of our purchase agreements in our French business net. Whilst our newly commissioned power plant added only 35 million given the unfavorable commodity price environment, Central Europe's generation fleet does not show the positive effect from higher achieved wholesale prices from 2010. These consequences of our hedging activities in particular those executed during 2008 for delivery year 2010 are as we explained last time recorded within energy trading and not within Central Europe.</p>
          <p>Central Europe West Regulated is up 4.2 billion. The minus 130 million effect from deconsolidating the TSO is overcompensated by higher earnings in the DSO businesses. These include 190 million higher network charges in power, around 50 million higher network charges in gas and of which 100 million is a recovery of one-off cost in 2009 at the DSO level for higher TSO charges, never positive came from lower cost for network losses. For the remainder of the year, we expect a further improvement from these effects over last year's results of up to 200 million. On the downside, we will have the loss result from the sold TSO of roughly similar size.</p>
          <p>Central Europe East improvement is driven by higher gross margins in power and lower network losses in Hungary and the first time consolidation of Prager Gas with 25 million and there is also some smaller translation effects that contribute positively.</p>
          <p>Let me move over to Pan-European Gas, adjusted EBIT increased by 17% to &#x20AC;1.3 billion. In Q2, we reversed the negative trend of the first quarter partially driven by one-off effect of around 100 million. Let us do the easier part. In the regulated business, we continue to see a decline of 160 million driven by last year's introduction of cost-based regulation in gas transports. Furthermore, last year we had a one-off positive effect of 97 million from the conversion of German GAAP into IFRS for two subsidiary transportation companies. We spoke about that in Q2 of 2009. The drop in other represents the effect from the sale of more stuff to the last year of around 170 million.</p>
          <p>Now move over to non-regulated, where we record an improved results. Upstream improves based on 73 million contribution from Yushno Russkoje and 63 million positive price effects mainly in oil, overcompensating around 50 million negative volume effect. But our storage business remains basically stable. We benefit from higher volumes around 150 million in the first half of 2010. With 365 terawatt hours, we record an increase by 65 terawatt hours mainly with industrial clients and in exports. The big swing and with the price effect, it's the price effect of in total 206 million. Here we benefit from the higher usage of spot portion of the long-term contracts, which were negotiated during winter and we recoursed roughly 80 million provision release, that's the point I commented about earlier related to the long-term contracts that we booked in Q4 of last year. It is critical for you to not misinterpret those results. We will most likely continue to see some recovery in tax results in Q3, before the situation then changes with the beginning of the next gas year. Johannes has explained to you that in Q4 contracts start to kick in where we have to expect very low and partially negative gross margins, hence our outlook for Pan-European Gas for the full year remains unchanged.</p>
          <p>The earnings momentum in UK slowed down as expected. Still we see a further improvement in the second quarter over last year and now stand at 663 million for the first half year, which is an increase of 180%. Whilst the regulated part is only slightly up, we see a 430 million increase in non-regulated. The retail margin has come down slightly compared to the first quarter this year also because we reduced gas prices to consumers by 6%. I do not want to repeat the reasons for the unusually strong Q1 performance, I trust you recall our statements around cold temperatures, higher than normal volumes and unusually lower wholesale prices allowing cheap spot purchase. These effects are not sustainable and have kicked in already in Q4 of last year, so the second half of 2010 will actually be weaker than the second half of last year.</p>
          <p>Let me now move on to Nordic on chart 14. We had a strong second quarter and up 39% in euro terms and 25% in local currency. The regulated business is up 45 million mainly based on higher network charges and higher volumes resulting from the very cold winter. Don't forget here the heat market in Nordic is very much a power market. In the non-regulated part we finally start to see positive volume effects primarily in nuclear. You'll recall the outages in Ringhals and Oskarshamn, which led to a decline of 0.5 terawatt hours in Q1 compared to prior year, now after six months we are up 1.3 terawatt hours. And we do not expect further improvements given Oskarshamn is still only running at 1,050 megawatt capacity and will be at 1,400 megawatt capacity in October. Overall volumes were up in total 3.1 terawatt hours, again 1.3 in nuclear, 0.4 in hydro, and another 1.3 in our CHP in Malm&#xF6;.</p>
          <p>Over to Energy Trading, Energy Trading's adjusted EBIT improved to 826 million, the increased results solely from our asset optimization activities, main effects are the following. In the power portfolio we see a higher locked in wholesale price that finally comes through, around 200 million effect, a further improvement of around 150 million stands from our gas portfolio, these are long-term gas purchase contracts in UK and partially in Continental Europe, which we either sell into the gas market or we use the gas to produce electricity in our power plants. This is the short-term optimization that a flexible generation portfolio allows for; in our core portfolio we have a similar effect.</p>
          <p>Looking in to future years, please note, the progress in our 2012 hedging, you can see that in the appendix. In Central Europe, we now have 60 to 70% sourced at an average price of &#x20AC;56 per megawatt hour, this compares to 40 to 50% and &#x20AC;55 per megawatt hour as reported after our first quarter. In Nordic, we have a similar development. Hedge level is 50 to 60% at &#x20AC;41 per megawatt hour compared to 40 to 50% at &#x20AC;40 per megawatt hour as per the last reporting date. Our Prop Trading business continues to be disappointing, there's not a single reason or a specific sizable risk positions though that we took.</p>
          <p>Over to new markets, new markets are down 20% to 429 million, adjusted for the one-off effect of 210 million in Q2 of 2009 in Italy spent for the 59 million of profit carved out to A2A, new markets are actually up almost 60%. In detail, climate and renewables benefits from higher installed capacity where we are up 1 gigawatt in capacity and up 50% in production, which now stands at 3.8 terawatt hours.</p>
          <p>Negative, still are the low wholesale prices for power in the U.S. and lower prices in Spain. Russia is performing well ahead of plan. Spreads and volumes improved from the back of a recovering economy. Liberalization during the first half of this year allowed for 60% of the industrial volume to be sold into the free markets compared to 30% last year. As of July this year, the liberalization level is at 80%. It is also noteworthy to highlight the continuing performance measures that our team on the ground is implementing, this includes, for example, the procurement side for fuel as well as OpEx on the plant level.</p>
          <p>In Italy adjusted for the power contracts and the A2A carve outs, the adjusted EBIT is still down 3%. The power price environment continues to be depressed at non-sustainable levels. Also we still lack access to cheaper gas. This can only be addressed over time as our current gas purchase contracts run out. Spain continues to hoard up against a tough market environment. Our flexible gas fleet allows us to capture higher gross margins in a highly volatile market with a huge share of renewable energy.</p>
          <p>Moving on to chart 17, adjusted net interest expense has increased by 146 million, around 120 million are linked to interest expenses due to tax provisions. Here we had a release in 2009 based on closed tax audits for prior years. This effect was not repeated this year. In addition, we have a minus 80 million effect from lower interest rates being applied to various long-term provisions other than nuclear and pensions. The change in NPV of those is booked as a cost in the interest results. The main positive item is a 50 million lower net interest charge on our net financial position. Net book gains add up to 0.7 billion, this year 130 million relates to the TSO sale and 400 million to the sale and swap of generation capacity. Other non-operating earnings are up 400 million, here the two main effects are 200 million higher mark-to-market of derivatives valuation and lower impairment of securities where we charged 200 million in the first half of 2009.</p>
          <p>I've only two comments to slide 18, the income tax rate is now at a normal level of 27%, up from 25% for last year, which is also our expectation now for the full year, 27 is the expectation for the full year. As explained last year we had a number of positive effects on the tax side in 2009, which will not be repeated this year. Results from the discontinued operations now includes as we've explained on our last call E.ON U.S. Last year's results were burdens by the settlement cost for WKE, whilst this year we recorded a 900 million impairment charge for E.ON US, obviously you see the post-tax figures in the line here.</p>
          <p>Chart 19 explains the usual reconciliation of adjusted net income, which is down 1% despite the increase in adjusted EBIT. As you will have concluded already this is caused by a weaker net interest results and the higher tax rates.</p>
          <p>Let me now explain the main drivers for the development of operating cash flow. First we have the increase in adjusted EBITDA of 700 million. In addition, last year's adjusted EBITDA included a number of non-cash effective items, including the 210 million for the Italian contract that has been re-negotiated that was purely a valuation effect, 50 million for the re-evaluation of SNET contracts, the French business, around 90 million, 97 actually, for the GAAP conversion for two Ruhrgas subsidiaries and a few smaller items. Altogether, 500 million higher cash conversion is included in the EBITDA development, which now needs to be added here when you look at operating cash flow.</p>
          <p>Pan-European Gas has now significantly higher storage volumes, in total, an addition of 44 terawatt hours compared to last year. This translated into a negative working capital effect. There is a positive working capital effect related to the disposals of Th&#xFC;ga and Transpower of around 300 million. Central Europe and Energy Trading improved their working capital as part of our ongoing improvement programs to more effectively managed net working capital.</p>
          <p>Interest payments are up 0.1 billion. The other effects add up to half a billion; these include many items such as lower tax payments, lower usage of provisions and others. On the investment side, cash-effective investments are down 0.4 billion compared to last year. Here we can just continue to execute our organic investment program. The big drop in Nordic relates to last year's cash payment made to Statkraft as part of our E.ON Sverige buyout.</p>
          <p>Chart 22 reconciles economic net debt development. Investments and dividends, I believe, are clear. Divestments is basically the sale of the German TSO. I explained operating cash flow. So let me comment quickly on the two remaining items. Pension obligations increased due to lower interest rates applied in Germany. We now use 5% compared to previously 5.5%. In the UK we now use 5.4% versus 5.7% as of end of last year.</p>
          <p>There is a big item other. This includes 400 million for the purchase of shares in SNET, which under IFRS must not be shown as investments since we already fully consolidated SNET, a French business. There are 1.6 billion of negative translation effects in the valuation of debts in non-euro currencies. Be aware that we have on the other side positive effects in our earnings results came from translation effects and also be aware that here the lion's share is U.S. dollar where we expect the proceeds from our disposal in December as Johannes pointed out.</p>
          <p>Last page, we reiterate our outlook for the full year. Adjusted EBIT we continue to expect to be between 0 and 3% above prior year. As highlighted in Q1 we see the major downside in our gas supply and sales business and in UK Retail in the second half. These were the main drivers for the positive development in the first half of the year and now we think that will reverse during the remainder of the year. Also, unchanged is the outlook for adjusted net income. That concludes my comments on the financials and we will now move to your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Patrick Hummel from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon gentlemen and thanks for taking my questions. Three if I may, two on the nuclear regulation complex. First you mentioned that the tax will have, if it comes, a significant earnings impact, you did not comment though on the impact on dividends. Can you just share your view how you would look at your dividend policy going forward? Would you stay committed to the payout ratio i.e. would we have to expect your dividends or would you consider increasing the payout ratio?</p>
          <p>And the second question is relating to your comments in the report about a potential alternative clawback instrument and this alternative would potentially have a less pronounced negative impact on the debt metrics or the gearing metrics. And I'm just wondering what's behind that. Do you think the Finance Minister would accept a regulation that would lead to later payments or do you think the government is highly committed whatever the instrument is that the money flows as proposed in the nuclear tax?</p>
          <p>And the third question is on your CapEx schedule for 2011 and '12, can you just give us an idea, you are guiding for 8 billion next year and 6 billion '12, what percentage is still flexible in your CapEx schedule? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Patrick, as far as the nuclear possible solutions are concerned, as long as we don't announce otherwise our payout ratio stays unchanged. And therefore it is obviously also too early to foresee what is coming out because we don't know if the tax will take effect and what the consequences of an alternative solution would be. We are hesitant to discuss the precise details of an alternative discussion. I would only point out that obviously the proposed tax burden wouldn't take EBITDA in a full way, while alternative solutions while still allowing some cash flows could be organized perceived in a way that it predominately would be perceived as an investment and therefore have a different impact on all the &#x2013; on cash flow, on EBITDA and others.</p>
          <p>But we believe it is not advantageous at this point to go in detailed discussion upon possible alternative solutions and those in the end would be tabled by the government again because in every case, I expect there would be a government solution predominantly. But there are better solutions and we lobby for that. And last question Marcus?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On flexibility we have in our CapEx program, here, I would say there is little flexibility as it relates to not starting projects because actually most of the things where we have communicated numbers to are related to projects that are started or are related in particular on the grid sides to investments that we are quasi committed to undertake. There is obviously always flexibility in a sense that you do not necessarily have to continue to own all those assets of select projects you're working on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much. If I may follow-up on your comment about the treatment of the alternative instrument, did I get that right that you could potentially get to a solution where you can account for that as an investment i.e. the cash outflow would still be the same but you would not have an immediate earnings burden and therefore your gearing or net ratios would just look better, is that sort of the key point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I would not like to go in more details and not necessary the cash flow would be exactly the same. Obviously, in any case there could be more upfront loaded solution, let's say, for compensating new production rights.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One thing is clear. I would say, any solution will next year imply some burden whether that is on earnings or on cash flow and they are what cash flow that is yet unclear, but there will be some burdens; certainly some burden relating from any solution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And the next question comes from Martin Young from Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, good afternoon to everybody. I think I should respect the two questions per person rule. The first one relates to your comments around the gas business, obviously you've been pretty clear about the impact, the fourth quarter of 2010, given the gas year ends October to end September, could you shed a little light on what you think that might mean for 2011 as far as the Pan-Euro Gas business is concerned?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, looking at the disposals that you've made, obviously you've made it perfectly clear that you have been disposing of stakes that don't contribute much by way of adjusted EBIT particularly in relation to their magnitude, I am sure you have many more of those including the Gazprom stake, maybe you could shed some light on your intentions for the future as far as disposals are concerned? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take the easy one first, which is your second question. As it relates to disposals, here, I would say we are pleased that certainly by now we think we assuming closing of E.ON U.S. sale in December we have more than delivered on our promise that we made in March of last year, first observation. Second observation, we've always been very clear and I think Johannes has stressed this on the last two calls that we will continue to screen our entire portfolio of activities for those, I would say, smaller activities where -- that don't really make a difference for our long-term future development.</p>
          <p>And in particular those where we feel we cannot really expand our own influence now there &#x2013; yes, there are still a number of those and I can tell you we're working on some of those, none of those are of a size where any of you would now immediately get excited, but the theme we will continue to work on. Don't ask me for how much that is going to be, I'm really talking about the next 50, 100 or 150 million disposal that I'm sure in two months we will report to you there is another one or two that we finished. So that will continue. On the gas...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In major disposals we will continue not to &#x2013; and pre-announce, but if any would occur, we will announce the delivery. And so there is nothing to announce in that respect today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On your first question, the gas business indeed Q4 of this year will be in sales and supply heavily burdened by the margins that we have locked in. So assuming an unchanged situation with our producers, this indeed Q4 isolated can actually produce negative margins.</p>
          <p>Now what that will mean for 2011, I think is unclear at this stage, because we have just begun to talk to all the producers about the situation that we see in the gas markets. Admitted, we've seen the gas oil spreads come down a bit, but it was higher a few months ago. So it's a volatile situation and we think we need to revisit, as Johannes has pointed out, sort of the entire pricing regime of those contracts; that is something that we will continue to have discussion in the coming months. This can take us until the end of the year and once we have clarity there we can also comment more explicitly on what it will mean for 2011. Situation unchanged, 2011, I mean, you can conclude that from my comment on Q4 obviously would be a very, very difficult situation for the gas sale and supply business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And the next question comes from Benjamin Leyre from Exane BNP Paribas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much and good afternoon. First question still on gas please, do you expect the new renegotiation to be more difficult this time around or actually easier because you have some recent precedent. And second point, can you also tell us your level of happiness about the draft electricity load proposal in France where you're, of course, actively involved? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the first question, hard to say what is difficult or more -- from the perspective do they understand that the market has changed and have they realized that fundamentally something needs to be done. I think it won't be easier because even when talking to the Russian leadership, which I did a little while ago, they have realized that if they want to secure a marketable regime for Russia and Norwegian gas they need to move.</p>
          <p>From size perspective, this will be most likely bigger than the first round and therefore, obviously, when it gets to money, it usually doesn't get so much easier. So a mixed picture, but it doesn't say that we clearly have initiated new talks. We legally will claim our rights in the time as of September and then the processes will begin. We're prepared, let's say, even better than last time. We've secured all management needs, we've secured all legal support that we foresee and we are prepared to progress that in a speedy way because we don't intend to realize losses if preventable at any means. And secondly, what was the second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What's your question, what we think about the norm law?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh yeah, the norm law. I think we obviously hardly impacted with our present position yet. I don't think we have formed the final opinion on our lobbying position; we are in consultations with the political parties.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We interpret it as aiming for more competition in that market, which obviously, we think will be a good thing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your question. And next question comes from Lueder Schumacher from UniCredit London.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Two questions. One is on some headlines that are just popping up on Bloomberg, which are talking about yet another tax that the government is thinking of levying on generation activities in Germany, this time coal.</p>
          <p>But a few questions have come from that. A, is this something that is part of the overall discussion, maybe something that could replace the current year nuclear fuel tax? Or is this a new tax? Is this something you're aware of? Could this maybe be a pass-through item, if it's a general cost and could actually be passed through to the electricity parts? Any comment on that would be quite appreciated.</p>
          <p>And the second question is on the regulated gas business, where of course earnings were down quite significantly. Are you looking for recovery there or are these basically new regulated returns where the return has been eroded away and we have to adjust to this new level of profitability?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well for the first question we also got some early news from some contemplations, but only one minister yet in Berlin. It appears still try to tackle another form of raising tax revenues from our industry starts to be more, more troubling. It has nothing to do with this information. We see it has nothing to do with nuclear item. There is no connect whatsoever to that. It's therefore since they have not indicated in anyway how they would pursue that, I would imagine that it could be a pass through item because coal usually since that the price in the merit order and it changes and obviously production costs in merit order, so it has a different impact, but it would make obviously German coal less competitive to foreign production. And I would &#x2013; my initial reaction would be very negative as putting another levy on the energy industry and the customers are making Germany less efficient and that's competitive. But we have to wait for more information. I think it's very premature and very early thinking those that people get room then others get we've not seen a drop. We have not seen an announcement from the Minister itself. So I hesitate to yet believe that it will be pursued, but we prepare ourselves obviously, as of today we prepare ourselves to react to any proposal in that direction. And the second question Marcus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on the regulate &#x2013; on gas transports, I think we highlighted already when it was a full year outlook that we expect a decline in profitability here given the sort of incentive regulation space that we are now in. We said that for the full year we have &#x2013; we think there is going to be negative impact over last year's result of around 150 to 200 million and that's at least for now it puts us at the level where tariffs will then be set.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's no recovery.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question comes from Bobby Chada from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, good afternoon. Two questions, the first, again, I'm</p>
          <p>sorry, was on the gas business. My understanding of contract renegotiations, I'm talking to some of your suppliers, they seem to concur is that a renegotiation is normally based on a change in circumstances. And since your last round of contract renegotiations TTF prices have gone up quite a lot. So what exactly is the basis for the change in circumstance, because couldn't they argue that contracts agreed with your customers when prices were very low is a very temporary effect? And isn't it indicative of the entire market?</p>
          <p>And then the second question is really about the trading business. Obviously, optimizations had a really strong result. I wondered if optimization is doing better, partly because of some of the financial players leaving the market and therefore giving you a sort of bigger share of the trading business overall. Or is it simply the benefit of those transfer prices, which are very helpful? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Bobby, the first question, no we don't have any serious doubts. We have a good case to argue. Our contracts are very clear that there should never be on any circumstance a negative margin to be realized. The contracts are clearly made in a way that we are in a way that we're prepared to profitably market our gas. And you have to realize and obviously this is not public. What price level and what sales price level were subject of the last three negotiating round. So it's not just probably TTF prices are going to the arguments with our producers also realized sales prices going to the argument in a ways, those are lower than last time we have a case. And as we said they are lower. Therefore, we see a very clear case and we have no doubt that we are legally well based in going through the negotiations, so trading business predominantly it's an effect of higher prices when the hedges were placed that is the main effect that drives the income up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The 2010 volumes were transferred at 2007 forward. In 2007 at forwards from 49% to Europe to Energy Trading and Energy Trading predominately sold that volume in 2008, you know we're priced, were over for 2010 were in '07 and where they were in 8 and then you can see why profit has moved sort of from the Genco into energy trading, but it has nothing to do financial players leaving the market. We actually also do not actually see so many financial players leave the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is an effect in rather small markets. Nordic market has lost some liquidity, also some players have moved away from there, but if you look in Central Europe, and I'd say liquidity and participation of players is still very high.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Andreas Thielen from MainFirst.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Firstly, on the regulation in Central Europe, you</p>
          <p>mentioned the positive effects there. And that 100 million is a recovery from last year. Could you give some more light on potential one-offs from the strong overall 240 million positive effect you had in the network, how much of that is sustainable? And secondly, again on gas, probably for us to understand the starting point, would you be prepared to, as in the past, break down the non-regulated business, at least broadly, in terms of what is storage, what is upstream, and what is sales and supply, in terms of the EBIT contribution?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can tell you E&amp;P was roughly at 200 million in the first half of the year. Storage, as we highlighted, for full year, is always around 400, 450 million and half of that roughly is in the first half of the year and the remainder is sales and supply. As far as the effect in Central Europe, our concerns on the regulated side, here we have, we basically have an effect of around 100 million that is a recovery of cost that we incurred last year that we can only charge to customers this year. And that cost were not resurfaced, but it's, the recovery will also not then resurface. So in that sense, it's a one-off effect that we have this year, which is why I highlighted, when you want to do a fair comparison of underlying operational performance, this is maybe something that you may want to knock-off figures, it's related to something that happened last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I just may, is that then a pure H1 effect, the 100 million? So is it done for this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The effects now there is going to be a smaller portion of that also in the second half of the year but that's a bit &#x2013; this was more around 40 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Bernhard Jeggle from LBBW.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon to everybody. My first question is on Perform-to-Win. You've stated that you have achieved efficiency improvements in the first half, in the magnitude of &#x20AC;600 million. I'm wondering the breakdown for the divisions, respectively. And the second question is on Russia, which developed obviously better than expected. And this was driven by the deregulation. Would you provide some hints regarding the third, on market outlook and especially regarding those, in terms of the adjusted EBIT? So, can I expect the growth rate we saw in the first half to continue in the second?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. As far as Perform-to-Win is concerned, it looks with today's divisions, roughly, let's say 250 million will come from Central Europe or have come from Central Europe, 200 million from Pan-European Gas, our gas division in Ruhrgas, 60 million from the UK, predominantly Retail, 30 million from Nordic, predominantly overheads, and the 100 million within the category of others procurement and so on so forth. It could also be broken down according to functions, but I think that should be sufficient and as far as Russia is concerned, Marcus?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the situation in Russia is, you can obviously expect further improvement when you compare second half of this year with second half of last year, but you should bear in mind that the winter also in Russia was very cold. So from a pure volume point of view this was particularly favorable to us. And yeah, I think it would not be appropriate to assume that that will continue to be the case. So there will be an improvement, I think when you do the math for the first half, what was it around 80 million is the improvement in EBIT terms. We expect the second half of the year also an improvement, but less so than in the first half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But the market I would say develops well, volumes as well as margins are developing somewhat better than planned and expected from our perspective. And in some of the regions of Russia significantly, further out east, we see volumes already going beyond 2008 levels. So the recovery of the Russian economy is somewhat progressing and not everywhere and maybe last word, we're not directly impacted yet by the big fires. We have only one plant that is close to the fire, but it's surrounded by lakes. Obviously our employees in Moscow and in Tatura are somewhat impacted by the bad conditions, but materially we don't see yet significant damage in any way and we're watching the development carefully.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Deborah Wilkens from Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon. My question, first of all, is just a clarification on</p>
          <p>your initial comment on the dividend, in the context of the potential nuclear tax. Are you ruling out considering a higher short-term payout ratio to maintain the divvy or the tax to be levied as currently planned? And my second question is linked in some way, in that, in your second slide you talked about your expectation that there will be clarification also on nuclear life extensions by early September. What underpins that expectation and does it also reflect an involvement of the Bundestag?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is you know the second question goes to the timeline of the political process. The government has indicated that late in August or late in this month they will contemplate on the first review of the new energy scenarios. And as of September they will put all the forces together to decide on the whole nuclear story being lifetime, being questions on different treatment of power stations, being on new investments with life time extension all of that together with the financing questions should be brought to the same table and brought to a decision.</p>
          <p>Obviously, political process is always subject to some unclarity, but presently the announcement indicate that within first half of September there could be the needed clarity. And we need to wait and see if there are changes to the process. That's what I indicated when I said there, based on risk, but in the end the political process drags longer than expected and that would have impact on our timeplan.</p>
          <p>And the first question I don't think I'd go beyond what I said as long as we don't change our payout ratio policy we don't change it. If we would change it we would indicate that obviously we hear all the questions and we will contemplate on payout ratios and dividend policies in our strategic review, but there is nothing to indicate today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question from Tanja Markloff from Commerzbank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon I have one more question on the gas operation. It's whether you could give us an indication of the volume of new sales contracts that become effective in Q4? And the second one is on the Datteln Power Plant in Northern Australia now after the regional &#x2013; after the unfavorable outcome of the regional elections, what the situation is here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, this second question concerns the new big power plant on a construction called Datteln in the state where we are located. It is in a broad way it is almost completed. And we have invested more than 800 million in that and the leading party of the new minority coalition, the Social Democrats here have clearly indicated their party program as well as the coalition program that they intend to continue and finish all investments under construction.</p>
          <p>They question whether new plants would be started, and how the future energy investment should look like, but they have told us that they intend to finish all such constructions. So we believe we have the general support. Obviously the minority party in that government, the smaller party in that government, the Green Party is throwing balls in the air questioning the project. We will continue a straight dialog with the new Prime Minister of the state to see whether we, how to secure the completion of the project. And we still strongly believe that we have a good legal and a good administrative case to proceed and there is no reason to believe that the new government will not in the end support. The question of the sales volumes in the first quarter, Marcus?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, typically a quarter to one-third of the contracts sort of are then being based on low terms, so that's also then what you should assume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Andrew Simms from Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Just a quick question on Perform-to-Win, could you please clarify the implementation costs for the 600 million for the first half? And also please can you provide so the phasing for this year and next year and the implementation costs for both of those years? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew, its Sascha. You're probably too close to your mike, so maybe you can just reiterate the question, apart from Perform-to-Win, we couldn't really follow it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Apologies, please can you provide the implementation costs for the 600 million Perform-to-Win for the first half, and then also for 2010 and 2011, so the phasing for the cost savings and the implementation costs related to that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't have the specific numbers now, reiterated, we will deliver this to you. I mean my gut feeling tells me firmly in the first half of the year, it's maybe around 100, 150 million, but we'll give you the specifics, but it will be for the full year around 150 plus that's a full year effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Vincent De Blic from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, two questions please. The first one on your hedging, you hedged a lot in Q2 for your 2012 output around 20%. Is that basically reflecting your view on power prices or is it also linked to your desire to secure cash flows in view of the tax risk, which emerged at the beginning of June? This is first question.</p>
          <p>And the second one on your indication of 1.3 to 1.5 potential impacts from the windfall tax on EBIT, am I right to infer from this number that you will be paying further tax on the EnBW and Electrabel drawing rights or do you use more than the &#x20AC;22 per megawatt hour average in the draft because of your specific power plant portfolio? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Marcus will go to the numbers, but let me be very precise and clear. Besides the name of windfall tax this has nothing to do with the windfall tax.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, nuclear fuel tax.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I know, what you're talking about. I'll try to give a straight answer. The Finance Ministry claims that it has a background of the windfall tax. There is a windfall tax for nuclear being present in Sweden, which amounts to roughly 6 to &#x20AC;7 megawatt hour. And if you look at the present certificates of the last months are on &#x20AC;50 and the translation factor into power prices is 0.6 to 0.7. The effect before tax is about &#x20AC;10 a megawatt hour and after tax is &#x20AC;7 a megawatt hour. And therefore if someone comes up with the tax claiming &#x20AC;25, it makes pretty clear that on reality there is nothing to do with windfall tax. The main windfall tax is about as helpful as the Robin Hood tax in Italy that had nothing to do with Robin Hood or Nottingham. It is just let's say a fiscal excuse for raising income and now to the numbers, Marcus?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First on your hedging question, I mean I can make life easy for me and say, you know obviously when you look at the development between where we started in Q1 and where we stand now, and you look at what price have we apparently secured during that time period and you take a look at where the forward prices are today, it was not so bad. Now does that mean we have sort of now a fundamental view on the price? No, I think we just took advantage of times when we thought prices were decent, we think, we continue to believe that prices will predominantly move sideways, which always makes life a bit more difficult, but at least during Q2. It looks like in hindsight we managed to pick those days when it was smarter to forward sell pricing gas. That is from my perspective good news.</p>
          <p>On your question with regard to the drawing rights, the situation is different. For Electrabel on the one hand and EnBW and EDF on the other hand. With regard to Electrabel the risk there is on them, not on us. With regard to EnBW it's the other way around.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Alex Karnick from Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes good afternoon. Thank you for taking my question. It's a little bit of a brave question, maybe. But considering your strong statements on the possibility that <mark type="inaudible" /> power plant become uneconomic under certain conditions, if they would become uneconomic, would you be prepared to shut them off? And obviously that would &#x2013; it influence the supply and demand balance for electricity in the longer run. And it was obviously putting some pressure on politics, on coming up with alternative solutions. Otherwise it would probably &#x2013; we'd get a supply shortage and then a massive squeeze in electricity price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer ought to be somewhat mixed, your background is very loud by the way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You mute yourself, it will be much easier for the &#x2013; yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you very much. The answer needs to be somewhat mixed. Yes, some power stations could even turn uneconomic to run or be out of the money with this assumed tax. However, keep in mind, bear in mind that we've very clear belief that this tax would be unconstitutional and against European law, therefore closing it doesn't give so much sense because we would obviously, if the tax would occur, we would fight it, try to displace it and then continue run a healthy plant. But would we produce power that is out of money now. Therefore obviously we would find a solution that allows us not to burn money, but keep in mind, an option that is deeply in the money available for the right available time. But I would say it's too early because I still cannot believe that the government clearly won the last election that claim that a competitive power production as nuclear should be available will in the end place a law that makes it uneconomic and even pursue a lifetime shortage instead of lifetime extension. But the discussion although being moving since a while is not yet over and we have to wait and see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much for that answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Christopher Kuplent from Bank of America/Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, thanks. Just two quick questions. First, I just wanted to see whether you could give us an outlook on your effective tax rate. It's obviously gone up from Q1 to Q2, not just for the rest of this year, but maybe also your longer-term view of this? And secondly, on your comment about nuclear power plants becoming uneconomical, I guess that's a very powerful argument vis-&#xE0;-vis the government. But doesn't that also invite just a revision of the taxes, but are you effectively saying you're in principle in favor of some form of tax? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously, I cannot be in favor of unconstitutional tax that is prevented by my being a good citizen. But to find clear solution to distribute additional value of new lifetime that is something that we always have indicated with the ear open. Because if this government creates new production rights and therefore new opportunities create value that can be then divided in a fair way by whatever means, decent way to do that. But that is all we can say at this point about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chris, on the tax rate, we continue to see our normal tax rates in the range between 27 and 28%. So that's also, you know that's the forecast for the full year, that's the forecast for the second half of the year, I can, I dare to say it's likely going to be the forecast for 2011. But as you could tell from the effects we saw in 2009, we can never rule out that there is going to be a one-off item in one or the other direction that you can actually not really plan for. But for, I mean for your question the answer is 27 to 28%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, everyone now we have to close the call. Thanks very much for your participation. Thank you to Johannes and Marcus for the comments and we look forward to speaking to you. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Bye, bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your attendance. This call has been concluded. You may disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>