<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1458498" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-03-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2864</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior Vice President-Investor Relations">Sascha Bibert</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman-Management Board &amp; CEO">Johannes Teyssen</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Marcus Schenck</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Vincent P. Gilles</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Westlb AG (Broker)">Peter Wirtz</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS AG (Broker)">Patrick Hummel</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane BNP Paribas SA">Benjamin Leyre</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Peter A. Bisztyga</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Bobby Chada</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Deborah B. Wilkens</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Martin C. Young</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Vincent De Blic</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (Europe) Ltd. Germany">Matthias Heck</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="MainFirst Bank AG (Broker)">Andreas Thielen</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Baader Bank">Karin Brinkmann</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Christopher Kuplent</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Kepler Capital Markets SA (Germany)">Ingo Becker</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Dear ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the E.ON's 2011 Annual Results. At our customer's request, this conference will be recorded. As a reminder, all participants will be in a listen-only mode. After the presentation, there will be an opportunity to ask questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>May I now hand you over to Mr. Bibert who will lead you through this conference. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you and good afternoon, everyone. Welcome to our 2011 results and the outlook presentation, despite the known challenges, we do have some positive messages for you today and, accordingly, I quickly hand over to our CEO, Johannes Teyssen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you, Sascha. Good afternoon, everybody. I'm on our first chart on number 2, is a presentation of our new strategy at the end of 2010. We already then have prepared E.ON as well as our external share stakeholders for challenging times ahead. Reduced market economic growth rates and <mark type="ph" /> both (1:17) supplied European power markets, coupled with a very capital intensive transformation of the energy system will require energy companies to fundamentally rethink their positions. However, next to those challenges, we saw and there are plenty of opportunities.</p>
          <p>Energy demand over time is growing substantially in many parts of the world. The increased use of electricity is a global phenomena at new business models, for example, in the area of distributed energy, will rise. What becomes even more important is that companies are willing and capable to adapt faster to change circumstances than in the past. In this context, the year 2011 surely presented challenges on a scale that we had not foreseen in late 2010 and that were substantial. Therefore, EBITDA dropped by 30% and underlying net income by almost 50% in the last year. You're all fully aware that the sudden change in German nuclear policy in the aftermath of Fukushima led to a &#x20AC;2 billion &#x2013; &#x20AC;2.5 billion EBITDA reduction alone.</p>
          <p>Furthermore in the year 2011, we continued to suffer substantially from too high purchase costs in our gas supply and sales business. In that respect, let me emphasize that I am glad and happy to report to you today that we have found a commercially acceptable and a structural solution, our renegotiations with our major supplier Statoil, and here we've resolved the ongoing price review. The solution found implies that the parties adjust the contract terms towards prevailing market conditions, however, this deal is subject to certain conditions.</p>
          <p>In addition to a de-risking of our gas procurement portfolio, we also see increasingly the benefit of the new earning drivers: renewables, Russia and upstream oil and gas. Accordingly, as announced earlier, we will propose to pay a dividend of &#x20AC;1 per share for the fiscal year financial year 2011. While some challenges remain, we are nevertheless confident that 2011 has marked the earnings trough for E.ON. For the next years, we targeted a growth of earnings per share of more than 10% per annum.</p>
          <p>For 2012 especially, we expect an EBITDA in the range of &#x20AC;9.6 billion to &#x20AC;10.2 billion and target to propose a dividend of &#x20AC;1.10 per share. For 2013, we keep our targets for EBITDA and underlying net income as well as the dividend that was communicated last August unchanged.</p>
          <p>I move to the next slide, slide number 3. Today I will talk about five key drivers that are paramount in order to make the E.ON transformation success. First, disposal of assets that are non-core for the group, second, use part of these disposals' proceeds to safeguard the financial strength and stability, third, ensure future earnings growth by investing into our targeted growth areas, fourth, reduce cost, enhance efficiency and turn E.ON into a more agile organization and, fifth and finally, make better use of our capital in the future.</p>
          <p>I'll move to chart number 4, divest non-core assets. Especially in Europe, we are focusing our asset portfolio on those assets that can create the most value in the long term and that strategically fit together. Back in November 2010, we have therefore set ourselves a target of divesting &#x20AC;15 billion of assets until the end of 2013. So far, we have disposed of &#x20AC;9.5 billion worth of assets. The two largest transactions you're well aware of have been the sale of our stake in Gazprom for &#x20AC;3.4 billion and the financially quite attractive disposal of Central Networks, our U.K. net business, for &#x20AC;4.8 billion. Furthermore, we have divested our Italian distribution network for around &#x20AC;300 million and are in the process of selling our 40% stake in the central German municipal utility HSE for a similar sum.</p>
          <p>The remaining disposals total &#x20AC;0.7 billion and are made up of a long list of small operations, such as the disposal of a stake in Stadtwerke Duisburg and Karlsruhe, the sale of Robin Rigg OFTO and of E.ON Bulgaria. I'm just mentioning those past transactions to illustrate that we are really scanning the group according to strategic and financial criteria we have communicated to you. The result is, for example, not obtained in simple disposal of our regulated assets but rather driven by the individual positions and characteristics of the respective business.</p>
          <p>We have succeeded to carry out those disposals at attractive prices. For Central Networks, for example, I'd like to remind you that we achieved a premium to regulatory asset base of close to 40%, one of the highest ever among U.K. regulated assets. We are currently working on a number of additional potential transactions. All those assets do not fall just into one category.</p>
          <p>We have initiated the process to sell OGE, our German gas transmission network, as well as E.ON Energy-from-Waste, the leading German electricity generator from waste incineration. We have also been approached by a number of municipalities, who would like to purchase our stake in the regional distributor E.ON Westfalen Weser. As usual, there is no guarantee that any of these transactions will come to a successful conclusion. However, we are well advanced in our disposal program and we are therefore under no pressure to pursue unattractive offers. If the economics of a transaction were not right, we can always think about alternative options, but we stay very confident that we will conclude our program in due time.</p>
          <p>I'll turn to chart 5. We remain convinced that financial flexibility is a prerequisite for any successful strategy execution. We have worked past the peak in our financial debt and reduced it by around &#x20AC;10 billion in the last 24 months. At the <mark type="ph" /> open (8:01) number of 3.9x, the economic net debt to EBITDA was, as expected, higher in 2011 than our midterm target of less than 3x. However, 2011 was obviously an extraordinary year. Without the &#x20AC;1.5 billion one-off hits to EBITDA due to the nuclear exit, for example, it would have been just 3.4x. Our credit ratings remain in line with our strategy to keep a solid single A rating. S&amp;P has us on a single A flat rating with negative outlook. However, Moody's has set our rating at A3 with a stable outlook.</p>
          <p>Next to the development of debt, we have a very comfortable liquidity position. We have almost &#x20AC;12 billion of liquid funds in non-current securities. In addition, we have access to revolving credit facility of &#x20AC;6 billion. And, finally, our &#x20AC;10 billion commercial paper programs can be used as needed. All bonds have a long-term and well-balanced maturity profile with an effective duration of 6.6 years. In light of our liquidity position, we will have no need for any funding activity in 2012.</p>
          <p>I'll turn to chart number 6. We will continue to keep the balance sheet in order, but will nevertheless also ensure that our earnings will grow over the coming years. In the execution, we will rotate capital in our described growth areas, mostly outside Europe as well as in renewables. In renewables, these expansions reflect in our CapEx. Since 2007, we have invested &#x20AC;7 billion and we plan to invest a similar sum again in the next five years. But today I want to focus on our expansion outside Europe.</p>
          <p>At our <mark type="ph" /> third Q (9:40) presentation of November 2010, we had announced that we wanted to enter two new regions outside Europe besides the two where we are already quite active and successful, namely Russia and U.S. renewables. In January of the current year, we made our first major step and we announced a strategic partnership with the MPX Group in Brazil. Why the Brazilian market in the first place? Well, be defined several criteria that any new region outside Europe has to fulfill. First, there must be a clear potential for long-term growth. Over the last few years, the Brazilian economy has done quite well.</p>
          <p>In particular, strengths in the industrial sector and agriculture and primary raw materials have contributed to Brazilian's development. The economic growth is underpinned by strong demographics. The population has grown by 20 million people over the last 10 years and moreover, the share of the active population is increasing. We should also note that between 2005 and 2010, 30 million people moved from poverty into the middle class. Finally, Brazil has a stable political system leading to reliable regulation in the power sector. These trends are clearly supported for power demand. We therefore expect power demand to move broadly in lined with GDP. This growth will be driven mainly by the industrial sector, followed by growth of the residential consumption.</p>
          <p>Our second criteria is that the region must offer an adequate and stable risk return balance. As most of you will be aware, Brazil has a sophisticated regulatory framework, which aims to ensure that demand is met and that the generation mix evolves in the direction chosen by the government. The corresponding long-term planning for generation allows for attractive margins to attract new capacity. Today, the Brazilian generation mix is heavily dominated by hydropower. This is an important sector of conventional technologies which functions as kind of backup facilities for those hydro plants and cover their lack of stability. This introduces a certain volatility, for example, in the volume side.</p>
          <p>However, the Brazilian PPA framework adequately takes a specific feature of the power system into account. Not only is the commodity price risk carried by the system, but the same is true for the volume risks. Generators only carry those risks which they can really manage themselves such as licensing and construction risks. Our third criteria is whether our skills and competencies are in demand, and thus we can expect those to be adequately rewarded. This is indeed the case in Brazil, especially in conventional generation renewables such as wind.</p>
          <p>Let me now move to chart number 7. This brings me to some of the details of our agreement with MPX. Let me briefly describe key elements. First, we participate in a capital increase of MPX and will ultimately get a stake of 10% for about BRL 850 million, roughly &#x20AC;350 million.</p>
          <p>Next and more importantly, we will form a 50-50 joint venture with MPX. MPX will bring into this joint venture half of its stake, the 11 gigawatt of projects currently in development. Site selection, licensing and general preparation of those 11 gigawatts is well advanced but these projects have not yet received PPAs, however, they will participate in the forthcoming PPA auctions.</p>
          <p>In addition, the joint venture will develop at 100% of all projects coming after this 11-gigawatt pipeline. We also have the longer term ambition for the joint venture to develop 20 gigawatts of capacity and to expand into renewables. MPX will keep the 3-giggawatts of projects which are already in execution, as well as the stake in the Seival coal mine and the Parna&#xED;ba basin gas fields for itself. Nevertheless, the joint venture will also benefit from MPX access to these fuel resources.</p>
          <p>This uniquely advantageous fuel supply will undoubtfully provide our projects with a competitive edge in the forthcoming PPA auctions. In sum, our agreement with MPX marks a first major step of our strategy to expand in new regions outside Europe. All in all, E.ON will get an economic interest in the development of 3.7 gigawatts, 3.4 gigawatts, directly and indirectly via the joint venture, and 0.3 gigawatts via MPX.</p>
          <p>Turn to chart number 8 with me, this agreement is also perfectly aligned with our general entry strategy into those growth markets. First, we prefer to concentrate on conventional and renewable generation as these are the areas which are best matched with the skills and competences that we can bring to the table. The essence of the joint venture will consist entirely of conventional power general projects, half gas, half coal. Further projects, however, are likely to include renewable generation as well.</p>
          <p>Second, we want to have a highly disciplined approach to investments and therefore prefer to focus on organic growth with a limited use of equity capital rather than entering into a large existing asset base via possibly expensive acquisitions. Clearly our agreement with MPX is mainly about bringing a pipeline of projects to fruition, the related upfront investment is very limited.</p>
          <p>Third, our entry strategy rests on cooperating with a blue chip local partner. With MPX, we couldn't have found a better partner in Brazil. MPX is part of the EBX Group built by Eike Batista, one of the most successful businessmen in Brazil. Both partners bring substantial and complementary competencies to the table.</p>
          <p>Fourth, we do not want to make too much &#x2013; we do not want to take much commodity risks unless we can manage them. As already explained on the Brazilian PPA framework, commodity price risks are managed at the system level, the same holds true for volume risks. Our advantageous access to competitive fuels will substantially increase our chances for winning PPA auctions. I'm very confident that our partnership with MPX will become a major contributor to value creation over time. The implementation of the agreement is running its course as planned. We aim to sign the definitive agreement during the second quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>We'll turn to chart number 9. Last summer, we shared with you the next major step in the overall E.ON performance initiative with the target to reduce controllable costs to &#x20AC;9.5 billion by 2015 at the latest. Our key objectives are reduce costs to ensure competitiveness in our operations and investments, and simplify structures to speed up decision-making. As part of the necessary steps, this program is expected to reduce our almost 80,000 strong workforce by around 11,000 jobs. In January this year, we signed a key framework agreement with the German labor unions to support the execution and to handle the personnel reduction in a socially responsible manner.</p>
          <p>We have now backed up our overall target with more than 50 specific related projects. All together, these projects would leave a more than &#x20AC;2 billion of cost savings. This will ensure that we reach our &#x20AC;9.5 billion controllable cost target, even when taking the normal degree of cost inflation into account. As the chart illustrates, most saving can be grouped into three broad categories. Operations, obviously, the biggest total part of the cost, will provide about 40% of the savings. Around 30% of the savings will come from simplifying structures and reducing administrative costs. One example is the merger of Trading and E.ON Ruhrgas, another example is the closure of the Munich subsidiary. Savings in procurement will provide the remaining 30%.</p>
          <p>Let me illustrate, what we do on a procurement side with a small example. Many people tend to believe that procurement savings are mostly a matter of getting better prices from your suppliers. Well of course, that is indeed one lever that we plan to use. But another lever is to change the way things are done. The small example I choose is our Spanish distribution business. But we notice that we are laying our underground electric cables at a depth of 80 centimeters while, according to regulation, 60 centimeters are considered sufficient. In addition in Spain, the cables are encased in two side-by-side pipes themselves protected by a layer of concrete. Elsewhere, the cables are put directly in a layer of compacted sand. Just by aligning Spanish practices with what we do in all other countries, we need substantially less material and labor.</p>
          <p>Just to summarize, we know how to target, we know how to labor on the target, not just on a high level, but also very specially at the point of cost origination and we've already established important agreements with unions. I'm therefore very confident what we will deliver on our ambitions.</p>
          <p>Moving to chart number 10, besides increasing efficiency, another pillar is to improve capital management. Well, how would we do this in our everyday operations? First, we have raised the returns that investment projects have to meet. Infrastructure investments must now meet hurdle rates which are 1.5 point above the cost of capital instead of 1% earlier. Most non-infrastructure investments have to achieve additional returns of at least 2.5% above cost of capital instead of the earlier number of 1.5%. And the most risky investment such as E&amp;P and wind offshore have to beat their cost of capital by at least 3% instead of, previously, 2%. These higher hurdle rates will make approval of investment projects more selective and thus naturally direct investment toward those projects that create most value.</p>
          <p>Second, we also want to improve our capital management by changing our business approach. In renewables, for example, we are trying to implement a build, operate, and share approach. Once a project is commissioned, for example, in offshore wind power, we will seek whether outside investors might be interested to take a stake in it. We will then not necessarily fully own the wind park anymore, however, would continue to operate it and get a corresponding remuneration. This approach would allow us to rotate capital more rapidly and focus on those parts of the renewable value chain so we can create the most value, namely, project development and construction. Outside Europe, we will make more use of partnering. We can, for example, expand scope and quality of potential investment opportunities by sharing CapEx.</p>
          <p>Finally, paying out attractive dividends is also a way to ensure capital discipline. We are proposing to pay out a dividend at a lever which is consistent with the earnings potential of the group in the midterm. We continue to see a payout ratio of 50% to 60% of underlying net income as an appropriate balance between the need of reinvestment and the demand of cash returns to shareholders. 2011 and 2012, however, have been described previously as two difficult transition years. That is why we accept a temporarily higher payout ratio on those years.</p>
          <p>In a capital intensive business such as ours, I am fully convinced that a disciplined capital management is absolutely key to long-term performance. I'm also well aware that some of our investments of the past are not meeting the grade in that respect. Some of the related challenges are due to the economic crisis of 2008 and 2009, which put many investments on a wrong foot and in only our sector by the way. But as in other aspects of our strategy, we do our utmost to address the issues that we can control and influence. Over the last few years, there is no doubt in my mind that we have become much more disciplined in our investment approach. I'm confident that the investment projects that we initiate today will make the test of time.</p>
          <p>I turn to my last slide, the executive summary. Let me summarize, 2011 was impacted by extraordinary events. 2012 will have challenges as well, but recent events, as that Statoil deal, increased our confidence that we are now past the trough. And for 2013, we have kept our EBITDA and underlying net income targets unchanged. This implies an earnings growth of 13% per year on average under 2013, and of more than 10% per year under 2015.</p>
          <p>Well, now over to you, Marcus, for further details of our financials.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Welcome also from my side. As Johannes has already provided you with a summary of our key financial highlights at the beginning, let me go directly to the EBITDA bridge for the year 2011. Although before doing so, just a point &#x2013; let me just point out that there is some changes in our terminology. As you may have recognized, we have renamed adjusted EBITDA and adjusted EBIT by just deleting the word adjusted. Hence, we will, going forward, only call it EBITDA and EBIT. Adjusted net income has been renamed into underlying net income. Again, the definition is the same, it is just new names.</p>
          <p>So now first to the key drivers of group EBITDA in accordance with the half year as well as the nine months reporting, the single biggest negative is the EBITDA decline in German nuclear. The &#x20AC;2.5 billion effect was caused by the exit decision and the fuel tax which is also included here. In our power portfolio, we lost &#x20AC;1 billion compared to 2010, the biggest income &#x2013; the biggest impact comes from our Central European outright portfolio. But we also earned less in our spread portfolio and suffered from reduced volatility in the <mark type="ph" /> front desk (24:10).</p>
          <p>In our supply and sales activity on the gas side, we lost around &#x20AC;700 million driven by loss-making oil linked gas procurement contracts. Portfolio effects mainly from the disposal of Central Networks, but also from the E.ON Rete, i.e., our Italian distribution business &#x2013; gas distribution business sale, contributed a negative &#x20AC;0.5 billion. The absence of last year's positive one-off effect in our German regulated DSOs drove down EBITDA in the German grips by &#x20AC;0.3 billion compared to 2010. A series of minor, smaller effects as well as 2011 factor cost inflation add up to a remaining other position of minus 0.1. Now it will be positive. Performance measures resulting from our PerformtoWin program contributed a gross &#x20AC;0.4 billion improvement, about 50% is cost related and 50% efficiency measures. Our gas upstream operation benefits from rising gas and oil prices while Russia as well as our renewable activities predominantly benefit from newly added capacities.</p>
          <p>Let me skip page 14 and go straight to the divisional level starting, as usual, with generation. As you will know, here we have pooled all our European nuclear coal and gas-fired generation activities. As you know, the earnings dynamics of the segment generation are mainly driven by availability and internal transfer prices to our trading division rather than our reported average achieved prices. Hence the earnings movement may differ from what one expects when looking at our published hedging reporting from a group perspective.</p>
          <p>From our reported average achieved price, which is down this year for the Central European outright portfolio by &#x20AC;9, roughly, per megawatt hour, you would expect the nuclear generation to show a negative year-on-year price effect. However, in this reporting segment, we're actually showing a &#x20AC;0.5 billion positive price effect for nuclear. The transfer price that drives this effect dates back to the year 2008, when forward power prices for 2011 where, on average, quite high. Hence the generation segment benefits from these higher transfer prices, whilst Energy Trading, where the actual hedging on the traded market happens, takes the full price hedge from the lower achieved prices.</p>
          <p>A further effect to nuclear is a positive &#x20AC;0.1 billion volume effect related to Nordic nuclear volumes, where outages of the plants, Oskarshamn and Ringhals, had reduced volumes in 2010. Remember that also this effect is positively distorted by the high 2011 transfer prices. These actually quite substantial positives look small when put next to the big negatives resulting from the political nuclear policy turnaround in Germany. In total, the moratorium, the subsequent shutdown of 3.2 gigawatts of our German nuclear capacity and the fuel tax have cost us &#x20AC;2.5 billion in EBITDA compared to 2010.</p>
          <p>Our steam fleet benefits primarily from higher transfer prices, predominantly in the U.K. In the CCGT fleet, falling spreads in both Italy and Spain were offset by additional earnings contribution from our CCGTs, Grain and Irsching, which, as you know, have been renamed into Ulrich Hartmann.</p>
          <p>Over to chart number 16, in the segment renewables, we report the results of our European hydro fleet as well as our wind, solar and other renewable activities. Hydro benefited from a positive impact of &#x20AC;0.2 billion, driven by the transfer price. Just like in the case of the nuclear generation, the expected hydro generation volumes are transferred three years ahead of delivery to each, which then takes care of the hedging in the traded markets. Hence also in the hydro segment the transfer prices for 2011 are based on the high prices that we saw in 2008.</p>
          <p>On the negative side, higher volumes in Sweden were not sufficient to offset the reduction in Germany, Spain and Italy. Wind, solar and other renewables is mainly driven by higher volumes from increased capacity compared to 2010. Year-on-year, we added some 600 megawatts of new capacity to end up at 4.2 gigawatts of total capacity at the year end. We currently have some 1.5-gigwatt of capacity under construction. The two biggest constituents of this under construction portfolio are U.S. onshore with about 500 megawatts, which are all contracted out, and European offshore with about 750 megawatts.</p>
          <p>Then let me come to the gas division. Our gas segments ended the year with a decline of 22% at a level of &#x20AC;1.5 billion. In our upstream business, earnings were just marginally up. The big positive was our participation in the Russian gas field Yuzhno-Russkoye, where EBIDTA came in &#x20AC;0.2 billion higher than in 2010, driven by higher prices. Our North Sea activities were weak in volume terms due to problems in our fields Njord, which was down more than 35% and Rita down more than 70%. The positive price effect from higher oil prices was not enough to offset this.</p>
          <p>Our midstream business is down &#x20AC;0.6 billion and also, overall, loss-making for the fiscal year 2011. In 2011, EBIDTA from supply and sales was about &#x20AC;700 million lower compared to the prior year. And again to remind you, 2010 was basically breakeven in this subsegment. Compared to our initial outlook of a loss of about &#x20AC;1 billion, supply and sales came in better than expected, thanks to a higher level of renegotiation success in 2011 than what we initially anticipated, as well as optimization gains mainly from making use of storage flexibility in our gas portfolio, which we spoke about in the context of our Q3 results. For 2011, we have renegotiated around 40% of our oil index supply volumes, up from 37% at the Q3 results. For that year, practically just the Gazprom and Statoil contracts were burdening the earnings.</p>
          <p>In the other/consolidation position, which has shown a positive development during 2011, several effects materialized, two of which are rather one-off in nature. Firstly, we had a positive deconsolidation contribution from the disposal of Stadtwerke Duisburg of around &#x20AC;60 million. Secondly, we have a gas internal consolidation effect from settlements of liabilities and receivables between Ruhrgas, the wholesale business there, and Open Grid Europe, concerning balancing and settlement energy, leading to approximate &#x20AC;150 million year-on-year gain. Again, both these effects will not reoccur next year.</p>
          <p>Over to the Trading side, which here we do see a negative delta of &#x20AC;1.8 billion compare to 2010, mainly driven by the strong swing in the optimization results. As mentioned before, for 2011, Trading procured its outright power at prices set in 2008 for delivery year 2011. As 2008 was the year with record high base load power prices all across Europe, its cost position in 2011 was quite high. Conversely, the achieved prices for 2011, which represent Trading's revenue line, dated back only in part to the strong period, but to a larger extent were hedged in the weaker years, 2009 and 2010. This explains why we record a loss in optimization. The even stronger year-on-year delta in earnings is due to the fact that in 2010, the situation was actually just the other way around. Back then, Trading's top line profited from record achieved prices, while the transfer prices, which dated back to the year 2007, were comparatively low.</p>
          <p>We have continued hedging our outright position for 2012 and 2013 but are also now progressing on hedging 2014. The Central European outright portfolio as per December is as follows: for 2012, 90% to 100% are hedged at &#x20AC;54 per megawatt hour; for the following year 2013, we &#x2013; the level is at 80% to 90% hedged at &#x20AC;55 per megawatt hour; and for 2014, we already have hedged 20% to 30% of the volume at an average price of &#x20AC;55 per megawatt hour.</p>
          <p>The Nordic outright position, same data here, 2012, 80% to 90% at a level of &#x20AC;43; 2013, 60% to 70% at &#x20AC;44; and 2014, already 30% to 40% at a level of &#x20AC;45, all, of course, per megawatt hour. For Nordic, please always be aware of the fact that not all the final volume is going to be hedged, as always, some &#x2013; around 10% that we hold back, given the uncertainty about the hydrological levels. What these numbers show you is that the level of distortion which we have seen at Energy Trading and the generation units will be less pronounced in the coming years as prices on the achieved price side but also in terms of transfer prices are less volatile year-on-year.</p>
          <p>On page 19, you see the commentary regarding our regional unit Germany. The regulated DSO business suffered from lower network revenues. In 2010, we were positively impacted by one-off recovery of costs which we incurred in 2009. This effect was already discussed in previous results calls. In the unregulated activities, we improved substantially compared to 2010 by &#x20AC;300 million. Biggest driver are higher earnings in distributor generation, and in the retail business, partially with a one-off character. EBITDA also benefited from improvements stemming from cost cutting measures.</p>
          <p>The segment of other EU countries is next on slide 20. Whilst we show the breakdown along countries in the annual report, we here show you the functional split. You can find the other data in the backup of this presentation. The segment earnings were down by 13% to &#x20AC;2.3 billion. On a like-for-like basis, however, i.e., adjusting for the mentioned disposal of Central Networks and Rete, the segment's EBITDA would have increased 6%. This deconsolidation effect was the sole driver behind the negative trends in the earnings of our EU distribution businesses, which were down &#x20AC;0.2 billion over the period. Biggest positive here is the Czech DSO where we passed on increased renewable energy costs, mainly photovoltaics, to the end consumer.</p>
          <p>Over to the sales businesses where we do see an overall &#x20AC;0.2 billion reduction. U.K. is down a &#x20AC;100 million, the situation here improved in the fourth quarter due to lower margins in Q4 2010 and two price rises during 2011. Further effects were deteriorating debt situation in Italy, where we have, I would say, a one-off negative charge, an increased gas purchase cost without pass-through in our Romanian business.</p>
          <p>Over to chart 21. Our regional unit Russia added a strong fourth quarter to the already positive trend, which we have seen throughout the year. Our new units contributed a total of &#x20AC;0.2 billion to this growth, while the existing units just about compensated for the general growth in cost.</p>
          <p>On the following slides 22 and 23, we reconcile net income starting with the EBITDA line. Economic net interest expense dropped, driven by the improved net financial position and the reversal of a liability, which we have billed late 2010 related to the expected prepayments into the renewable energy fund. Net book gains came down strongly compared to last year due to the large book gains which we realized on the disposal of the Gazprom shares in Q4 of 2010. In 2011, next to remaining Gazprom disposals, we recorded a book gain from our sale of Central Networks.</p>
          <p>In the restructuring position, this year we booked an &#x20AC;800 million one-off charge in the fourth quarter, mainly for severance payments related to the new E.ON performance program. This figure might still increase, but it is probably probable that this one-off chart reflects the bulk of what we will need for the program.</p>
          <p>In December 2011, we had to announce a sizeable impairment for our Spanish and Italian power generation assets, but also for some assets from the Central European power generation portfolio, overall, a &#x20AC;3 billion charge. Our reported tax rate is 36% compared to 22% in 2010. As the pre-tax income in 2011 is negative, the tax rate reflects an overall tax benefit. Nothing to comment on for 2011 in terms of disc ops, the loss in 2010 relates to the sale of U.S. Midwest.</p>
          <p>Over to chart 24, the &#x20AC;2.4 billion or 49% drop in underlying net income was the result of a &#x20AC;4 billion drop in EBITDA, which was partially offset by a &#x20AC;1.1 billion lower tax and the &#x20AC;0.5 billion lower interest cost.</p>
          <p>So let me now move to operating cash flow. On chart 25, we reconcile the steep drop in 2011 operating cash flow. Remember that our operating cash flow definition is post interest expense and post tax. Indeed, strongly reduced 2011 EBITDA, there was a substantial non-cash portion of around &#x20AC;1.1 billion. Please note that this includes the full &#x20AC;1.5 billion from the accelerated nuclear phase out. In the U.K. and Germany, we book the one-off funding of the pension deficit in the amount of &#x20AC;0.2 billion. In global gas, Trading and other EU, we have several working capital movements all in the wrong direction. At EC&amp;R, we received &#x20AC;0.2 billion less cash grants in the U.S. compared to prior year and at group level, there's one big positive, resulting from &#x20AC;0.7 billion lower tax payments.</p>
          <p>Now to our debt position in chart 26. Year-on-year, we are recording an improvement of &#x20AC;1.3 billion. Basically all of this improvement results from the net financial position, which was &#x20AC;2.3 billion lower than at the end of 2010. Overall, we saw more investment activity in the fourth quarter than in the previous quarters. Dividends paid during the year amount to &#x20AC;3.1 billion. CapEx is down 21% compared to last year's levels, now we stand at &#x20AC;6.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Divestments including the deconsolidation of debts amounted to a positive &#x20AC;6.5 billion in operating cash flow as described at &#x20AC;6.6 billion. Asset retirement obligations increased by &#x20AC;1.2 billion with the main drivers here being the impact of the early retirements but also a change of discount rates in Q4. In the other position, several effects took their toll. Next to the net increase of margin and payments at <mark type="ph" /> each (41:10), we also recorded an &#x20AC;0.4 billion currency related increase in economic net debt.</p>
          <p>Today, I would like to highlight again that the cornerstone of the E.ON finance strategy is our strong commitment to a solid single A rating, which is again emphasized on chart 27. We believe that this rating level enables us to combine our objective of an efficient capital structure with access to a variety of financing sources even under difficult market circumstances. E.ON is and remains committed to the solid single A rating and will also in the future continue to support this. We are therefore taking considerable efforts to stick to this objective and introduced a number of measures to reduce debt and to improve underlying earnings and cash flows.</p>
          <p>In addition, we introduced an additional way to look at our EBITDA. We have developed the pie chart you can see on the slide in order to demonstrate and prove the underlying stability of our earnings base. As you can see, 40% of our 2011 EBITDA is fully regulated and a further 10% is either quasi-regulated by, for example, a supportive incentive mechanism for German renewables or is long-term contracted.</p>
          <p>We expect the quasi-regulated and long-term contracted portion to grow significantly over time, while we execute our strategy of providing cleaner and better energy. As a result, 50% of our 2011 earnings base is very stable and immune to earnings volatility. Although the overall share of stable business was obviously supported by last year's weak performance in merchant activities, it also proves that the stable businesses provide a supportive basis to our group. During its ongoing transformation, E.ON will maintain a healthy balance between stable and merchant operations to support this credit profile.</p>
          <p>Now on CapEx on chart 28. First, I would like to point out that the &#x20AC;6.5 billion recorded investments for 2011 compared to an original budget of &#x20AC;7.5 billion to &#x20AC;8 billion as communicated last August. We've managed to reduce CapEx partially &#x2013; have shifted into future years and, of course, we no longer have CapEx related to the sold Central Networks business.</p>
          <p>For the coming years, you see that a large and growing share of our investments per annum will continue to be invested into stable business areas, such as our regional segments, which includes Russia, as well as the renewable business. The chart also shows you that our annual CapEx continues its general downwards trend in 2013 and 2014. These two years are planned at &#x20AC;6 billion per annum compared to the &#x20AC;6.5 billion level for last year. The short uplift in 2012 is due to some postponements of CapEx compared to plan from 2011 into 2012, in particular in our renewable segment.</p>
          <p>So then finally to the outlook. As Johannes has already briefly taken you through the headline numbers for our full year outlook for 2012 as well as the target for 2013, I will just touch on some technical aspects of these numbers. As you will remember, we had adjusted our 2013 guidance from &#x20AC;900 million of disposal effects in August last year. To remind you, this disposal impact was based on the &#x20AC;9.1 billion of achieved disposals as per August 2011. This parameter is also the one we have chosen for the full year outlook and the 2013 target. We expect further disposals to materialize in the course of the year. Should they be significant in terms of EBITDA to be lost, we would adequately reflect this in the targets. On the other hand, you have to understand that we want to keep the number of target revisions as low as possible, so it will clearly not be each &#x20AC;100 million EBITDA dilution which would trigger the next adjustment. What I would also highlight is that the maximum further dilution potential, which we are estimating on this chart, is pure EBITDA, i.e., lost without corresponding savings on interest expense and connected lower depreciation. Most notably, it does not contain any impact from future reinvestments.</p>
          <p>So now over to chart 30. On this chart, we are showing you the most important drivers behind the expected increase of EBITDA from &#x20AC;9.3 billion in 2011, at least to &#x20AC;9.6 billion to &#x20AC;10.2 billion in 2012. The, by far, biggest positive year-on-year is the absence of the &#x20AC;1.5 billion nuclear one-off effect. Furthermore, we are expecting an improvement in our gas upstream results. This will however, be far less pronounced in what we have been expecting when we presented our financial update in August 2011. Main reasons for this are a delay of the start of operation of the Skarv/Idun fields into summer this year and problems in our North Sea fields Njord and Rita.</p>
          <p>Don't forget, the Skarv field is operated by our partner BP, and there's clearly always some risk related to that field. Nonetheless, we expect our E&amp;P business to contribute some additional &#x20AC;100 million positively. Also, Russia will, again, help full year earnings in 2012 with the uplift mainly driven by full year contributions from the power plant commissions in the course of 2011. This positive effect should also be around &#x20AC;100 million.</p>
          <p>The biggest negative factor will be a lower power result, half of this around &#x20AC;400 million effect will be coming from outright and the other half from spread generation. The spread effect is a mix mainly between Central Europe, but also our Southern European portfolio. At this point, I would like to highlight that the achieved dark spreads before short-term optimization were very good in 2011 due to strong hedging dated back to 2009, when dark spreads were still quite satisfactory and expected economic generation also quite high.</p>
          <p>Also power related is the following effect. We are also expecting higher nuclear fuel tax of around &#x20AC;150 million. The deconsolidation effect is straightforward, it's mainly due to the mentioned Central Networks business, which still contributed about &#x20AC;200 million to our 2011 earnings during the first quarter of the year. Last but not least, lower retail margins in U.K. and the absence of positive one-off effects in global gas adds a further &#x20AC;200 million, &#x20AC;300 million negative.</p>
          <p>Now a few words on supply and sales. We assume that business to make a loss in 2012, similar to the year 2011, so, say, around &#x20AC;700 million to &#x20AC;800 million. Given the current status of renegotiation that Johannes has commented, this assumption only exhibits upside from further renegotiations with the outstanding counterparties. We actually do not see any more downside in this segment.</p>
          <p>Over to the segmental outlook, which is presented on chart 31. As you can see by the title of this chart, we are planning to modify the group structure during the course of the year, actually with Q1. The segmental outlook along with this new reporting structure as well as the changes in segmentation we are conducting, you can find explained in the backup of this presentation on charts 36 and 37. In essence, we are breaking up the global gas business into two pieces following the measures introduced by our EON 2.0 program. The E&amp;P business will become a separate reporting unit while the remaining gas businesses are being merged into Energy Trading to form the new segment trading and optimization. Generation is expected to be above 2011. Renewables is expected to be below the 2011 levels mainly because of lower transfer prices for the hydro generation transfer to each.</p>
          <p>Gas is expected below last year's level mainly due to the absence of several one-off effects which lifted this position in 2011. Please keep in mind, as I said before and from our perspective, conservative assumption related to the supply and sales business, trading is expected above last year mainly due to a recovery in the optimization result. Germany is in line and other EU is expected below 2011 levels mainly due to the deconsolidation of Central Networks. Russia, as I said before, will again be above last year's level due to the full contribution of the capacities added in 2011.</p>
          <p>So over to my last chart, where we briefly outlined the major effects that take us from 2012 to 2013, where we confirmed, as Johannes said, the ranges that we quoted in August last year. On the positives, cost cutting will have a &#x20AC;600 million to &#x20AC;700 million positive impact; E&amp;P will profit from the postponement of startups of some fields in 2012 and grow strongly by around &#x20AC;1.1 billion compared to 2012. For supply and sales, we remain confident that it will return to a normal level of profitability. For renewables, we expect &#x20AC;0.2 billion earnings upside from a higher installed wind capacity. Also Russia will contribute positively again another &#x20AC;100 million in addition.</p>
          <p>On the negative sides, the biggest position and it's almost the only one is the CO2 effect, which we have spoken about very often. Basically here, what folds away are the about 55 million tonnes of freely allocated CO2, for which we have sold in the year 2012 and where we now expect, in that sense, a loss &#x2013; or a year-on-year negative effect of around &#x20AC;800 million.</p>
          <p>In power, we expect to lose some further margin in the spread position, while the outright positions are expected to stay basically unchanged. In total, the effect, which reflects an updated view on power prices as per early 2012, is not much more that &#x20AC;0.1 billion down on 2012.</p>
          <p>So that concludes my part, and we will now go straight into your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Mr. Vincent Gilles from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, everyone. Inevitably, my two questions will focus on the gas business and I will have one question to Marcus, one question to Johannes most probably. Marcus just a point of precision, you just said that based upon the guidance you gave us for 2012, any further upside would come from further renegotiation in the gas supply business, which I understand as what you renegotiated with Statoil is part of the guidance you gave us. I guess it attracts a very simple yes or no answer.</p>
          <p>And the second question is very inevitable I'm afraid. When I hear you say that you've reached a commercially acceptable solution trending towards market conditions, I'm afraid I have to ask you, can you just be a bit more precise? there are so many solutions you can reach and that would all be perfectly acceptable to both sides, so if you can put a bit of flesh on the statement, I'm sure everyone would be very grateful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take the technical one. The outlook that we are putting forward includes the solution now found with Statoil and I think as I was indicating, any further renegotiation with another player would add upside to the segment outlook.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the other question I think, I know that you and probably 10 others will ask for details of the commercial terms of the deal. And let me therefore be very open, we will not give much flesh to it, We will not disclose how it's been done because then it would be transparent to our competitors, and we and Statoil could be read and that is not in our interest nor in the interest of Statoil. But we have pronounced <mark type="ph" /> two pacts (55:25), the commercially acceptable conditions, meaning that we obviously can live with this in our sales side. And secondly &#x2013; and we refer to prevailing market conditions, I think that should be clear enough.</p>
          <p>And the second thing that I would rather even more pronounce is that it is a structural solution. So while in some other instances, we just did, let's say, deals for one or two years and then we have to meet again and see has anything changed or could we fall back to something, this solution that we have entered into will offer answers longer term that are acceptable to us and I think that are not subject to something but that can be secured by us. And I think that is extremely important looking on the broader portfolio. Gives you some insight, definitely not what you would love to hear, but I'm afraid however the next questions around it will be phrased, the answer will be very much like the one I've just provided.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (56:42).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You seem happy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm delighted. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Peter Wirtz from WestLB. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good afternoon. So I'll give it a try on gas supply. In terms of your 2013 outlook, what are the underlying metrics here? Do you assume that all disputes are solved and you are back on track, which means you will achieve a positive gas supply margin? Ad in terms of the upside or downside risk, is there no upside chance anymore from company to repayments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the first one is, obviously, you have to make a distinction between 2012 and 2013. 2013, we always said we expect that all major disputes will be settled. And we are back, let's say, to an acceptable position, meaning a small margin on the gas and supply and sales business. Nobody can expect an enormous margin and we never said so, but an acceptable low margin on that.</p>
          <p>2012, we always have been, obviously, much more conservative. And our guidance that we gave out today also, <mark type="ph" /> as usual (57:59), as the guidance had come down, so it's a upside potential. I think Marcus has been quite open that due to the late hour events of last night, we see the downside being gone, meaning upside being left but not with a certainty above 50%, therefore, nothing we can say more about it.</p>
          <p>So 2012, if something happens in the later course of the year, might be better 2013. Therefore, you should not expect such a huge upside because 2013 was foreseen as being more settled. It could rather even have some effect saying if something significantly would happen in 2012 that we'll also see in 2013, you could see a timing difference of some effect, but probably nothing to be built in any model. I think the main thing is 2012 is more certain that we thought and 2013 is in line with what we said, a small profitability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just &#x2013; if I can just add maybe two sentences to that. When you look at the sum of 2012 and 2013, our guidance now basically still assumes a substantial loss for 2012, and it assumes that in 2013 we are back to normal. For these 24 months, we are not presuming any recovery of past losses for the years or for the five quarters that we had. So in total, there is, when you look at the sum of those two years, a substantial upside.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. This clarifies it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Patrick Hummel from UBS. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, everybody. Two questions on your 2013 guidance and I won't follow up on the gas contract because I don't want <mark type="ph" /> raise (59:54) the question here. So 2013 EPS, you confirmed the &#x20AC;1.70 to &#x20AC;2. At the same time, you gave an update to the underlying assumptions and the situation for the outright part of your generation fleet has deteriorated. So I was wondering what the other positive effects are compared with the situation in August last year which would make up for the lower profits you should see now in your outright generation, or is it just fair to lean towards the lower end of that range?</p>
          <p>And the second question is regarding your big incremental swing in the E&amp;P business that you see in 2013 by &#x20AC;1.1 billion. Could you just give us a spilt here what the incremental volume growth is year-over-year that you assumed for 2013 and what might be price related? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let me first talk about 2013. Quite frankly, I have stopped speculating where within the range we end up because if we were to do an update every four weeks, we're always at a different point in that range. So what I felt &#x2013; what we can tell you today is we will be, given what we know today, in this range, again, assuming constant portfolio. Yes, there has been a certain minor negative development on the commodity pricing side. There are other things in the group that have, on the other hand, moved in a slightly positive direction. So all in all, we are still comfortable to confirm here the range.</p>
          <p>And then, when you &#x2013; on your second question related to E&amp;P for 2012, the main effects that we expect from on the volume side is essentially resulting from the Skarv field, where we assumed that with the beginning of July, and there's a certain risk that this may get delayed a bit, that field will be producing. So that is an upside of I think it's around 7 boe or 8 boe, whilst we have some downside, in particular, from the Rita field, which will not be producing during the entire year 2012, as well as a four-month maintenance period for Njord. Both these, I think, will cost us I think around 3 boe to 4 boe. So that's in total, we expect to be up by some 3 boe to 4 boe. That's broadly what the numbers are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Just to follow-up, my question was rather related to the 2013 swing over 2012. So the incremental volume in 2013 which drives basically the big &#x20AC;1.1 billion uplift in earnings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So then, Skarv will be available for the full year, which is around 16 boe. We will also have the Njord and Rita be then fully available, and we have two new fields, Huntington and <mark type="ph" /> Hume or Hume (1:03:35) or whatever this is pronounced. Those together will also add around 15 boes so that in total we should be up by some 31 boes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>31 boe year-over-year. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. A part of that, you also have, as I mentioned before, in the year 2012 because of the ramp-up of Skarv. Yeah, I think, it's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So basically, it's 31 boe minus the 7 boe to 8 boe that might already come in 2012. Is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Benjamin Leyre from Paribas. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you and good afternoon. Two questions, please. First on the debt factor, without any further disposal, can you please tell us where you think your debt factor should be at the end of 2013? So, again, without any further disposal? And second point, on Gazprom, I actually wonder why you do not include any recovery of the <mark type="ph" /> previous zloty (1:04:50). Is it something that you just give up on and why is that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, for the first one, obviously, you know that we are targeting to move on or below 3. When that precisely happens, we cannot prognose in detail. So we don't have a precise <mark type="ph" /> soft target (1:05:09) for 2013.</p>
          <p>For Gazprom and past losses, obviously, we believe we are entitled to recover such losses, and it doesn't mean that we don't have some optimism. Still obviously, when putting out outlooks we also remain somewhat cautious on things and it's the combination of various effects. And, therefore, there might be some upside behind that fact. There is no indication that we have <mark type="ph" /> latter trust (1:05:20) for recovery there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The question on debt factor, I understood you were asking about 2012...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>2013. Well, of course, if we don't realize any of the disposals, which is your underlying assumption, there is a risk that we will not yet get back to the target that we have, namely, debt factor below 3 times. Of course, the things that will work in our favor is us working on improving the operating cash flow. At the same time, as you did see, we're taking down CapEx. But, clearly, and that we've always pointed to our part of the delevering &#x2013; that deleveraging is also being done in order to improve the healthiness of the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>So, the answer to your question, absent the disposals, there is a risk that we would exceed the level of 3 times, which is not our target. And I think, as Johannes has pointed out, when talking about the disposal program, we are quite optimistic that your question is a theoretically, maybe, interesting one, but practically will be of no relevance for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Peter Bisztyga from Barclays Capital. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. Two questions, please. First of all, Dr. Teyssen mentioned that the Statoil contract renegotiation had some conditions attached to it. I was wondering if you could elaborate at all on what you meant by that?</p>
          <p>And then, secondly, could you elaborate whether the quick-fix contract renegotiations that you've made so far, are those contracts going to be out of the money at the current gas-to-oil spread and is there a risk that they could lose money in 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The conditions precedent or subject to are of no substantial relevance for the analyst community, I would just say. So they are more normal conditions that are of no major commercial importance. We still agreed with Statoil to mention those in all our communication jointly. But, really, you should not worry about them.</p>
          <p>The other question is with the quick fixes or the interim solutions, could there be a reopening of a gas-to-oil spread exposure? Well, theoretically, yes. That is in the content of a quick-fix traditional agreement. Is there a substantial likelihood of that? I would say no because if the counter party has agreed for one, two or three years to a settlement that accepts the prevailing market circumstances, I would believe that it's extremely difficult to be willing to enter arbitration afterwards, saying now suddenly the world is very different. If the world were very different at that time, well then, obviously, we have an issue. But if the world were the same, I would be more than surprised if suddenly we are back to square one or something. So I would say, theoretically, yes, practically, limited.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Bobby Chada from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. My first question is simply on the CapEx. Can you share with us how much of the CapEx over the next few years is committed year-by-year?  And then, secondly, sorry to labor the whole gas point, maybe you can simplify it slightly. Whenever you talk about a structural solution, am I right in understanding that that means regardless of whether the oil-gas spread moves positively or negatively from where we are today and regardless of changes in TTF or NCG gas prices you would expect not to be in a loss-making position?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Structural solution, I would translate into the order that the exposure to risk or that part of the portfolio has been de-risked by whatever measure so that, yes, market developments would not expose us in the same manner as today to, let's say, losses or anything. But, again, I'm afraid I will not go further than that. But structural is meant as structural, as something that is cost in a way, that does not contain elements of surprise in a manner that management cannot address.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bobby, on your CapEx question, I don't have the precise number there. Basically, I would say that it would be difficult for us to take CapEx in a year below a level of, say, &#x20AC;4 billion because there's maintenance CapEx, there is certain CapEx in the grid businesses which is mandatory, and there are always certain projects that have already been started. So, that's an average number.</p>
          <p>Of course, when you look at the year 2012, by now the number is higher because of certain major projects, for example, in renewables, have been started. But as you could see, quite frankly, also from all &#x2013; I would say, actually, all the previous years, we in every year somehow managed to take down CapEx a bit compare to what we originally thought would be the overall outcome. And I think this is partially a function of the fact that there is always a certain, rightfully so, that there is a certain buffer built into at least the major projects. And then, secondly, in the last three years we have been trying to fight the declining markets. And one end that we have been working on was trying to take down CapEx, which I think the last three years would show you every year we successfully managed to get that done. This is how I would frame it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Ms. Deborah Wilkens from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Two questions. Now I think we have a better picture in terms of the worst-case scenario for the gas supplies business in 2012. Can you help us understand what the best case could be? And my second question, you mentioned this morning that you will evaluate older plants for potential closures. Just for clarification, is that for Germany as well as the U.K.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think maybe I'll take the first and Johannes the second question. I think the issue that you are asking about in terms of further renegotiation outcome, I would frame as follows: we do have still losses related to the five quarters prior to the year 2012 which we think we are entitled to recover under certain contracts, in particular, when you look at the discussions with Gazprom. Of course, by now we are also assuming that we will continue to be in a loss-making situation on those contracts for the year 2012 as part of our outlook. I think when you add all this up, and I'm not going to give you the precise number, but it will not take a rocket scientist to figure out that the sum of all of that clearly &#x2013; will definitely exceed &#x20AC;1 billion. So that is a number that at some stage we would expect to surface. We can't tell you whether this is going to be this year or next year, but it should at some stage be there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And you referred, Deborah, I believe, to the possible plant closures of all the inefficient plants or plants that are subject to end of licensing. All what we announced here is not looking at a specific country. It contains, for example, our present outlook contains things in the U.K. We announced the closure of Kingsnorth, a hard coal plant, but there was also German plants included, there are French plants included. So, whenever we look at our fleet, we don't look at it from a nationalistic perspective, but <mark type="ph" /> to the wholeness (1:14:51) of the fleet, and we have I believe a more set a significant number of stations and we have them all in a merit order and we work them down when necessary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Alex Karnick from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead. The next question comes from Mr. Martin Young from Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon to everybody. Hopefully two very quick and simple questions. The first is about the diluted impact that you've indicated for the disposals you still intend to make. What impact would we be seeing at the EBIT line and what impact should we be looking for at the underlying net income line assuming no reinvestment? And then, you've alluded to a normal profitability in the gas supply business. Are your expectations around that still of the magnitude of about &#x20AC;400 million? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, we earlier &#x2013; I'd take the second question regarding the EBITDA one. We had said, we're seeing the magnitude of between &#x20AC;200 million and &#x20AC;400 million. So obviously, that depends on the size of the portfolio we are marketing, the level of risk we take, and if they were the upper or lower end, depends on development of markets. So it's &#x2013; the expectation would be somewhere in that range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the &#x2013; on your question with regard to dilution, I think as I said on my remarks, the dilution from the disposals on an EBITDA level, we would see at around &#x20AC;800 million, give or take. At an EBIT level, of course, that number has been, in total, a bit lower. But at this stage, I would actually prefer to not go into the details, because then we will soon end up discussing each and every disposal before we've done it. I think the guidance that we've put forward should allow you to model it.</p>
          <p>The &#x20AC;800 million at an EBIDTA level is a good proxy. It can be &#x20AC;100 million more, &#x20AC;100 million less, depending on what we sell. And depreciation should &#x2013; you probably have to deduct depending on what assets it will, some additional &#x20AC;200 million or &#x20AC;300 million. That's roughly how you can then frame it. We are, at this stage, not assuming reinvestments proceeds or contributions until 2013 in our guidance here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And with the proceeds of any disposal, would you just hold then on your balance sheet as cash or would you pay down debt, because obviously that makes quite a bit of difference in terms of the interest cost?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That we will decide when the disposals process come. Of course, our preference always is to pay back debt when it's maturing, because as you know it can be quite costly to buy it back earlier. This is something that we have to optimize. Then, in the given situation, clearly, our intention is to really take down the gross debt number. We already carry, as you can see in the balance sheet, quite a substantial cash potion in &#x2013; on our balance sheet. Of course, post dividend payment, it will be reduced. But the way we want to manage our balance sheet is not that we just pile up more and more cash and leave the gross debt unchanged. We, overtime, will reduce the gross debt amount.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Vincent De Blic from JPMorgan. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Two questions, please. The first one is on the CapEx. You talk about &#x20AC;6.2 billion for 2014. I wanted to know if it was a good guide for the long-term CapEx <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:19:09) to the group? I think you mentioned on slide 28 that it's before portfolio and E.ON 2.0 measures, maybe you just could quantify this.</p>
          <p>And secondly, you also reiterate in the slide that 2015 guidance of &#x20AC;2 to &#x20AC;2.3 EPS. Could you give us roughly what <mark type="ph" /> committed (1:19:29) assumptions you used, whether it's close to mark-to-market or whether it's the same assumption as in August 2011? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the last one, we still use the same assumptions that we put forward in August last year. And with regard to the &#x20AC;6.2 billion, that number in terms of CapEx, this is a number that steady states is still higher than what we think is a realistic number for the long-term. And here, again, you always need to be careful whether you talk about a trajectory where you just plan to substantially expand the business or not.</p>
          <p>I would say, in our base case, where we still assume that certain businesses are being continued to be build out, and is always, that Johannes pointed out, as our main strategic growth area, such as renewables, such as stepping into new markets, such as distributed generation. When we add it all up, we think the level that we will be looking at is more in the, say, &#x20AC;5 billion to &#x20AC;5.5 billion range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Super. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Matthias Heck from Macquarie. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi, good afternoon. My two questions are firstly on the gas-to-oil spread. After the renegotiation of the Statoil deal, could you just run us with the mechanics of your current gas-to-oil spread, by how much it has come down and where do you stand for 2012 on a bcm or terawatt hour basis?</p>
          <p>And secondly, just a quick clarification on your 2012 outlook and the implied assumption on the Statoil deal, do I understand you correct that you set up the guidance prior to the agreement with Statoil? And then, you made a rough check and came to the conclusion that the impact is not significant enough to move the overall target upwards?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on your first question, exposure to changes in the gas-to-oil spread for the fiscal year 2012, it's de minimis. I don't want to say it's nil, there's probably some minor volume there but nothing that will have &#x2013; I mean, it's maybe a low two-digit terawatt hour number but it's really the de minimis and it's actually only in the fourth quarter of this year. So, that won't basically impact our numbers.</p>
          <p>And with regards to the guidance, look, we &#x2013; what we're doing here is we are making no assumption as to the outcome, in particular with Gazprom. It may be that this slips into the next year, and we fully reflect the results of the negotiation with Statoil in our guidance. So, basically, as I said, there is only upside from that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. No, it's just because I heard you guys saying that you sign that deal with Gazprom yesterday night, and the outlook...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With Statoil?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With Statoil, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the outlook was basically decided already prior to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, look, we had assumed a certain recovery. And more or less by coincidence, I would say, that recovery is the same that we have, and we never knew where it would come from but now we see it come from the discussions with Statoil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's very clear now. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Andreas Thielen from MainFirst. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Firstly, with your medium and longer-term guidance, it seems to imply that tax rate is going to be 30%. Is that what you see after the full effect from higher taxes you will have to pay on the upstream gas business once everything invested in there is fully up and running? And secondly, are you yet in the position to give any kind of indication what you expect from MPX as earnings contribution within that timeframe, i.e., within your 2015 guidance, is there anything meaningful from that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We cannot &#x2013; we announced that there will be now PPA auctioning and project development, so we are not capable at this point to break the portion or any end results <mark type="ph" /> where MPX is down (1:25:02) too early. I think we'll do that when we have deeper insight. And the tax rate, Marcus?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on the tax rate, first as you rightful point out, increased earnings contributions for E&amp;P has a &#x2013; an uplift impact on the tax rates, that is correct. Second, always bear in mind that at the same time, we continued to also invest into the segment, which has a dampening effect on the tax rate. All in all &#x2013; and I'm pretty sure this will vary during the years, and as you &#x2013; I'm sure, some of you were surprised in the end by the tax rate that we finally booked for the year 2011, which came out lower than with what we had originally anticipated.</p>
          <p>Steady state, we would see tax rate somewhere between 30%, maybe up to 33%, so somewhat in that range given the share of the E&amp;P business. But it will always somehow fluctuate, yeah, so, please never nail us on, oh, but you told us it's 31%, and now suddenly it's 29%. I can promise you this will happen in the future, but somewhere in that range we expect &#x2013; we would expect it to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Karin Brinkmann from Baader Bank, M&#xFC;nchen. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. Just two questions, the first one on the implementation costs for your cost cutting program, will we see implementation costs in 2012 again? And then, second question would be, if we look at the disposals, the divestment program, are we more expecting it to see it in 2013 or are you currently working on disposal that you can say we will already see it very soon? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say, you are aware, Marcus told you that we have booked roughly &#x20AC;800 million in 2011. We don't see any very substantial things being added to that in 2012. Some minor things due to local arrangements or whatever, he hasn't prognosed, but we don't expect something major there in 2012. And the &#x2013; how we do the further disposals, is it in 2012 or 2013, we cannot lay out a date. It depends on development markets circumstances and others. I think, we undertook the obligation to commit the program, we completed that until the end of 2013, and more we can't say. So, I know that leaves you with some issues in doing the modeling, but we cannot go further than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the discount disposals...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:28:10)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Does this answer your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Christopher Kuplent from Bank of America. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon. I noticed you've changed a little bit, or maybe you can update us on your original target when we talked about &#x20AC;15 billion of firm asset disposals. I think at the start, you said about half of that you wanted to re-employ. You are well beyond half of that and we're still talking about reducing debt. So I was wondering whether you could give us an update on how much you have earmarked for investing in new markets and maybe be a bit more specific about Brazil. Hopefully you have a bit more visibility there about how much CapEx commitments you'll be taking part in or whether that's a self-financed <mark type="ph" /> LICO (1:28:52) there?</p>
          <p>And the second question, just a quick one, is does the <mark type="ph" /> Benelux (1:29:03) financials decision today, does that change your treatment of nuclear taxation as rather than just a P&amp;L item, also as a cash out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's just a cash question &#x2013; cash out question. On the P&amp;L, we have always took provisions. And be aware, the decision doesn't say nothing at all about the constitutionality of the tax. It just takes the size of the fiscal and says as long as a possible tax payer <mark type="ph" /> in bankruptcy rather stood up from this (1:29:28). But on the other hand, we have lots of calls now saying that they believe the taxes aren't constitutional. And if that legal insight would prevail, the Finance Ministry has to pay back any payments with 6% interest to us. So we would have a AAA counterparty paying us 6% interest, so it doesn't change the world for us. And we still believe that fundamentally we are on the right calls there. And the other question goes to Marcus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on the reinvestments, I think we've always said that reinvestment is something that can happen until 2015, so not necessarily within the period until 2013. We have &#x2013; we are at this stage still predominantly using the disposal proceeds to strengthen the balance sheet, because we short term want to improve our rating credit &#x2013; rating statistics and we will continue to do that. We expect the situation to look a lot better in the years 2014 and 2015. So that is then also the period where we would then also see the certain additional reinvestments. That's point one.</p>
          <p>Point two, to some extent, we are reinvesting. I mean, part of the increase in CapEx that we have is, for example, related to the offshore projects that we have started. Some of that exceeds actually the original budgets that we have set ourselves.</p>
          <p>And then, as well, your question on MPX, I mean, that is also CapEx, that in a way not part of our original plan. And we expect a higher amount to be paid at some &#x20AC;354 million this year, and then a run rate of, say, &#x20AC;100 million to &#x20AC;200 million per year. Please always remember that we &#x2013; what we are really financing from here is our 50% portion of the equity that will go into new projects. And given these projects are highly levered, on a project basis, actually, the equity amount required is not that high.</p>
          <p>And I would like to make an &#x2013; another point, that actually Sascha pointed out to me while Johannes was talking, and it's related to the 2015 guidance, because I think there was a previous question on the impacts that the development in the commodity markets have had. Let me try to be clear here; with the prices that we see or assume for 2013, we actually don't really need an uplift or any material uplift in power prices to basically bridge the gap between 2013 and 2015. There will be other factors such as cost cutting and the impact from growth investments that then will to start to be productive, that already will take us to that range. So, just to make that a bit more precise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Sorry, may I come back with one question just to check how many years you're planning to invest in that 6% <mark type="ph" /> LICO (1:32:36) until you have a chance of getting &#x2013; paid back the principle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, in that 6%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, you mean the tax rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is in the hand of the Constitutional Court of the Federal Republic of Germany, and I cannot tell you. They have full discretion when they hear a case and when they decide a case, and after the constitutional call. They may have decided in the fiscal quarter puts it into place, and then the Finance Minister pays it back. And this is beyond my prognosis, I don't have a glass ball. You want to <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:33:34), Chris?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Chris. We will now take the final question in the interest of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The final question comes from Mr. Ingo Becker from Kepler Capital Markets. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you. Good afternoon. I have two questions, one on your guidance. I just want to double check if I understood that. I think, Marcus, you said that you only see upside for the 2012 guidance in case there's a early solution with Gazprom. If you would agree with Gazprom on similar terms as with Statoil or in line with your expectations tomorrow night, I understand that would drive up your 2012 guidance, but it would not at all affect your 2013 guidance. Is that correct?</p>
          <p>And my second question would be on Statoil. I know you won't talk about the conditions, so I try -maybe it's a valid question, is it &#x2013; regarding the compensation for part losses, do it have any effect that rather than these being paid back in a year like this year or next year, it might be embedded in the terms affecting the coming years on a temporary basis, i.e., is there an element of, say, temporary structural improvement that will reverse in a few years from here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, first of all, Statoil has no reverse element whatsoever. With Statoil in 2010, we've put a deal in place that sealed everything to the end of 2011. So there is no revisiting of part losses from our side. And whatever we did with Statoil, we are not entitled to that, we didn't try that, period. So there is no &#x2013; therefore, no element that it could be challenged in the future, could be changed in the future due to that.</p>
          <p>Now, in a possible settlement with Gazprom, how that would be structured and what would be placed in where is nothing I can tell you today because we have no insight in any of that yet and we have to wait for that.</p>
          <p>And, as you clearly said yes, there would be an upside in 2012. And as Marcus said, overall, there could be some upside over the two years and probably the lion share would be the settlement happen more in 2012 than 2013. But all of that now is speculation because we don't have any insight yet. How and if the Gazprom case would be settled is not yet in our prognosis and our outlook.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But your 2013 outlook includes a solution with Gazprom?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It assumes that we are then in a normal stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In a normal stage, no compensations for past losses. As we indicated before, those would come on top, probably in a one-off payment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks, everyone, for participating. And thanks for your questions, I'm sure there are more. We are asking to please <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:36:32) and we look forward to those. So have a good day. Thank you and bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Dear, ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your attendance. This call is being concluded. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>