<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1135639" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2007 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-03-06</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2864</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Kiran Bhojani, Executive Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Dr. Wulf H. Bernotat, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Dr. Marcus Schenck, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4">Christopher Rogers</participant>
      <participant id="5">Marcus Schenck</participant>
      <participant id="6">Johannes Teyssen</participant>
      <participant id="7">Martin Young</participant>
      <participant id="8">Wulf Bernotat</participant>
      <participant id="9">Christopher Kuplent</participant>
      <participant id="10">Andreas Thielen</participant>
      <participant id="11">Lutz Feldmann</participant>
      <participant id="12">Kiran Bhojani</participant>
      <participant id="13">Marcus Schneck</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, <mark type="inaudible" />. Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to our Analysts and Investors Conference on our Annual Results 2007. We would also like to welcome all analysts and investors on Internet, as well as our colleagues on intranet throughout the E.ON Group.</p>
          <p>Our special welcome to our colleagues from Investor Relations on Internet from OGK-4 in Moscow. And here in the room, Sergey who's sitting at the back, he is the Deputy Director General of OGK-4 and he is trying to follow what we do at investors and analyst conference here.</p>
          <p>As you can see that the integration process in Investor Relations between OGK-4 and Corporate Center is progressing extremely well. Lastly, how can I not forget, as every year, my warm greetings to the big fan of E.ON, it's my family in Bombay and Bangalore, they are watching me right now.</p>
          <p>Today, we have Wulf Bernotat, our CEO; Johannes Teyssen, Chief Operating Officer; Lutz Feldmann, he has a big title. He's a member of the Board responsible for Corporate Development and New Markets. I rather call him Mr. M&amp;M, Madrid and Moscow, that's his home all the time. And finally, Marcus Schenck, CFO, a finance genie.</p>
          <p>Before I handover to Wulf for his presentation, I'd like to make a few comments. Wulf and Marcus will make presentation based on charts sent out to you this morning. There are no written speeches available afterwards. In this respect, I would like to thank both of them, Wulf and Marcus, for taking the lead in communication in Germany without making a big, great-English speech and making presentation on based on charts. Reality is that, I should admit, investors don't have to work and write those long speeches. That's reality.</p>
          <p>Anyway, second thing, power generation charts we sent to you this morning. We thought that since this is a hot and mostly discussed topic in the capital market, we decided to update you on the power generation in Europe and what's E.ON views are. Thanks to all of you for your feedback and comments and they decided to give it to you back.</p>
          <p>And finally, I also like to thank colleagues in the room and behind the door. We call it vision trade, people with knowledge helping us behind the scene. And last but not the least point, we will have a presentation on renewals in the second quarter of this year. The exact timing and location, we will let you know as soon as possible.</p>
          <p>And finally, I request you to turn off your mobile phones, and the card you received with your name, would you be so kind to put it in the front of your microphone so I can exactly watch everybody who are there, who is sitting.</p>
          <p>And with this, my remarks, I hand it over to Wulf.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon ladies and gentlemen and welcome to our conference this year in D&#xFC;sseldorf. I'm going to present you a few slides only on results and the rest will be done by Marcus as usual. And I will try to sum up the E.ON story, which all of you know.</p>
          <p>Well, anyway let me start by just showing you the key figures for 2007. And it shows the development of our adjusted EBIT going up by about 10% and also the net income going up by 9%, and at the same time &#x2013; I'm sorry, I've got a cold today &#x2013; and also there are. And also the ROCE went up to &#x2013; I'm losing my voice at the wrong time, actually. I must say that the results are very positive if you look at the full set of all the figures and in particular that we are delivering on our promises. If I continue with the return to shareholders, which I'm showing on the next slide, you can see that also in terms of our dividend policy, we are on track. We are delivering against our promises and you can see a continuous improvement of that line with a proposal of 4.10 euro for the year 2007, which is a payout ratio of 51%.</p>
          <p>So, you see on this chart, on the left hand side, promises and on the right hand side, delivery against promises. And that shows that we also have the interest of our shareholders in mind when it comes to dividend policy and also the share buyback program.</p>
          <p>Just a few words on the understanding we reached with European Commission last year. I'm afraid that I cannot give you specific details on that agreement today, but this chart shows the basic components of our understanding. And that is that we are prepared to divest from our TSO and that we are also prepared to divest from generation capacity to the tune of 4,800 megawatt of installed capacity, and that those transactions have to be done within two years for the TSO and in six to maximum 12 months for the generation capacity.</p>
          <p>The whole process behind that is a very complicated legal process, which will take us another six to nine months potentially, and we are just at the beginning of it. So we have to agree on specific details with the commission still in the weeks to come. So I ask for your understanding that there is not much more we can say about this agreement today although I'm sure that you all are very interested and curious to hear more about it in more detail, but that we'll have to do at a later stage.</p>
          <p>Moving on, talking about our investment program for the new mid-term planning periods. You will remember last year we announced a 60 billion investment program in May, covering the years '07, '08, '09. And 6 billion of that 60 billion were projects initiated in that period, but not expected to be completed in that period. Now in the last mid-term plan, we have reviewed our investment program and the total number has gone up to 63 now, including 2007, to have a comparison through the previous one.</p>
          <p>So all in all, a slight increase of another 3 billion.  Where is it mainly coming from? It's shown on the chart here. It is 4.4 billion for the asset swap with Statkraft and additional investments into renewables and also additional investment in Russia for the project of OGK-4 mainly. So these are contributing to the change of our investment program as compared to the announcements we made last May.</p>
          <p>If you look at it in more detail, you can, sorry, that is one too fast. In more detail you can see, and I don't want to go through all the individual components of this chart, but you can see that 72% is for growth and 28% is for maintenance CapEx, or stay-in-business CapEx so to speak, and of the 72%, 85% will go into the unregulated business. So more and &#x2013; more or less inline with what we announced last year, slight revision, slight update, same direction. So organic growth, small acquisitions, unregulated business as a preference and growth, predominantly growth of 72% of total investment.</p>
          <p>If I look now at our development program for our generation fleet, you can see on this chart that we will become progressively more a company with less CO2 in their emissions in the portfolio of our generation fleet. And you see the target number on the right hand side of this chart for the year 2030 where we target for a 50% reduction on a specific base compared to 1990 as far as carbon emissions is concerned. And that of course, will come from carbon-free generation capacity like renewables, or coal with CCS technology. So, also in this area, the direction of the company has not changed. You have seen similar charts before.</p>
          <p>What has changed though, is the cost to build power stations and that has gone up significantly as you can see on this chart on the left hand side where you see the development of a typical coal-fired power station that has gone up from about just under 1 billion to 1.6 billion, and all this is coming from higher costs for components and also for the civil engineering part of new constructions of power plants. So a significant increase, which makes investments of new entrants more difficult as you can see on the right hand side of this chart where you see current prices roughly and the costs to invest into coal-fired generation including CO2 emission or carbon cost, you can see that is already exceeding the current price levels. That means, basically, no incentive for new builds, no incentive for new entrants who come into the market.</p>
          <p>What we have done to counter that development, we have secured the vital components for our new projects. For 14 projects in total, we have secured most of the components there, so that we are still living in a sense in the world which is shown on the left hand side of this graph with costs which are roughly still in the order of 1 billion or slightly above. But we can still afford to invest in new project units and we maintain our target of a full percentage above capital costs for those projects. Otherwise, we will not do them. So that is still possible, but for others who are new entrants, it's going to be increasingly difficult.</p>
          <p>Taking a closer look at the projects we are involved in, that's shown in this chart, the ones in red color are under construction, the one in black are planned. We have taken one out of our program that is Czech Coal, a lignite project in the Czech Republic. The rest is still ongoing.</p>
          <p>We have some question marks behind one project in Germany, Staudinger 6, where we have political and public opposition. You may have followed the development in Germany over the recent months that there is a growing opposition also against coal-fired units here and in this particular case, we just had local election or recent election there and knew that the incoming government is likely to be against this project. So, more and more opposition. But we have alternatives to use the components, which we have secured for that plant for other projects. So, if that project will be finally hold up by political decisions, we have alternatives.</p>
          <p>We are also planning to build four conventional projects in Russia and one in the U.S. Midwest. In Russia, that's part of our acquisition commitment in the case of OGK-4. In U.S. Midwest, it is part of the &#x2013; to fulfill the regulatory requirements in Kentucky to have a reserve capacity or reserve margin of about 14%, we are just building a coal-fired unit there.</p>
          <p>If you add it all up, you can &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; we are still confident that we can continue with those projects which we have announced perhaps with the exception of Staudinger. We believe that those projects are economically viable despite the fact that we now have to expect a full auctioning after 2012 for carbon certificates, because we have secured the important parts for those projects which we are either implementing or are about to implement in the near future. So, there is still the organic growth story intact in our company.</p>
          <p>The conventional part of our business will be complemented by an increased focus on renewables. And in that respect, we have taken significant steps, acquisitions last year, one in Spain and one in the United States, and that is a very good platform now for us to develop our business in addition to what we had before.</p>
          <p>And if you look at the next chart, I'll come back to this one in a minute, we have a position that is spread around Europe. We have strong positions in U.K. We have positions in the Nordic market. We have now a good platform in Spain as I said. We have an excellent platform in the United States where we've just recently completed new projects with a total capacity of 330 megawatts just in the last weeks.</p>
          <p>So, the pipeline, which we have acquired together with the acquisition of Airtricity, is now being implemented. So, we are rolling out those projects and we're bringing them on stream. So, all in all, a very ambitious program on renewables. We have doubled our capacities since May last year. We will double our capacity until the end of this year and then reach those targets as you can see on this chart.</p>
          <p>And one point to mention, that's on the previous chart, I'm going back now, is that this industry is going through a fundamental change. It used to be, as we call it, a boutique approach, small manufacturers building the windmills and smaller operators operating them &#x2013; smaller companies or financial investments, and this is now moving up to a bigger scale on an industrial scale which means we are in the future cooperating with manufacturers of a different size and dimension on a similar level like General Electric or others in Europe, and we will also operate those wind parks in a different way when it comes to preventive maintenance and other aspects.</p>
          <p>So, I think this industry is in a process of changing itself fundamentally to upturn industrial level and industrial scale. And we are part of that. We are now number seven in the wind business in the world and that is a significant step forward. But we are not only concentrating on wind power, we are also looking at other renewables that includes solar where we have got a joint venture with another German company, developing the thin-film technology.</p>
          <p>We are also looking at biomass. We have the largest biomass plant in Lockerbie in Scotland. And we're also very much involved in biogas or biomethane where we have just opened the largest plant of that kind in Germany feeding the biogas directly into our grid, blending it with natural gas because it has got exactly the same specs and therefore it can be blended into our existing business volumes. And also, we look at wave and tidal energies where we've pilot plants, which we are developing and geothermic projects. So, we are looking at those potential future aspects of renewables business whilst concentrating on the development of let's say more developed projects in the wind power industry.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we are investing in infrastructure for the gas business that includes gas pipelines, the most prominent here shown in this chart is the Nord Stream or former Baltic pipeline as it was called through the Baltic Sea from Russia to Germany and then across Germany into Holland and to the U.K. And that has some spare lines as well. We are also investing in storage capacity for gas and in potentially in LNG terminals, always depending on LNG availability, why you have a sort of chicken and egg situation. You need LNG to justify the construction of a terminal and you need to have a terminal in order to be a credible partner for the LNG suppliers. We have now secured the first agreement with Equatorial Guinea for a small volume of LNG and as you all know, we are looking into possibilities in the Persian Gulf, in Qatar and also in Iran, knowing pretty well that Iran is a very difficult issue politically at the moment.</p>
          <p>As far as receiving terminals are concerned we are looking at a number of projects, one in Wilhelmshaven in Germany, one in Krk in Croatia, Le Havre, we have secured some capacity in the U.K. in the terminal of Grain. So, we have options and we are working on the supply of LNG which is, I have to admit, difficult because it is a sellers market and the Qatari government is still continuing with its moratorium on new projects.</p>
          <p>We have the unique situation in our business that we have power and gas in a strong way in our business portfolio like nobody as yet, in the same way maybe Suez and Gaz de France after their merger will come close to our situation but at the moment we are leading in that respect. And there are some benefits to be gained from the convergence of power and gas; we have got &#x2013; you see here the development of the dual fuel customers in the U.K. and our own numbers are showing in the same direction and you can see on this chart also the success of our new daughter company in Germany E wie Einfach which has seen a tremendous increase in customer numbers over the last year and again both for electricity and for gas and of course there are optimization opportunities between power and gas when it comes to the procurement issue of gas for power generation or in the trading area on European basis where we are in the process in finalizing our new trading outfits E.ON Energie trading. So, also there we will benefit from being involved in those two markets.</p>
          <p>As for as our focus for this year is concerned, it is unchanged from previous presentations. Obviously, we will concentrate on the integration aspects of our business, and integration means integrating those assets which we have already acquired like OGK-4, which is a mammoth task actually to do, but also the renewables activities Energi E2 and Airtricity, and finally, once the deal is completed the assets which we get out of our deal with Enel and Acciona in Spain, in France and in Italy. We are also finalizing our organizational changes when it comes to energy trading and our new market unit, climate and renewables, which we've set up as a separate unit to have a sort of broad portfolio &#x2013; global portfolio to look at and also our new build units which will concentrate on all our new build projects on the generation side.</p>
          <p>We have also committed ourselves last May as you remember and I think Marcus will talk more about that potentially, to review our total portfolio up to the year 2010. We will look at all our assets, all our companies in our portfolio to see whether they actually fit strategically and whether there is a financial performance we can expect from those activities that meets our expectations. And you can see on this chart here, first results to be expected in the year 2008. So, you would hear more news from us in the course of this year in that context.</p>
          <p>To sum it up, we are committed to create value in the short and long-term. We have, so far, delivered on our promises from May 31st last year. We have the best European footprint in our industry and that will remain so even if some moves like Suez, Gaz de France will be implemented. We have a significant investment program in plan confirmed to our mid-term planning. So, we will continue on a very high level to grow organically. Our adjusted EBIT will increase by 10% on average between '07 and 2010 and the target of 12.4 billion adjusted EBIT remains intact.</p>
          <p>We will continue with our current dividend policy of dividend growth between 10 and 20%, remember for last year, we have increased it by 22%, and we will maintain our target payout ratio of between 50 and 60% of adjusted net income. And we will also maintain our financial discipline and then our financial targets, as explained last May, there is no change in that respect. So, focus is on integration, consolidation whilst at the same time, we will grow our business to achieve our financial targets, and of course our vision remains intact. I thought it should come now, but it is not there any longer. The world's leading power and gas company. So that is still the same, unchanged, ladies and gentlemen, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.  Okay, I will now give you the details on another strong financial year 2007 as well as guidance on the year 2008, a year of organizational change for E.ON.  Almost all figures have improved; earnings related ones, the cash related ones, and also the ones related to the capital structure.  Let me begin with EBIT first.  We are pleased to report a 10% increase to 9.2 billion euros.  That is better than budget; quite frankly, it also exceeded our own expectations that we had at the beginning of 2007, and it is fully in line with our 10 out of 10 target that Wulf has referred to.  Let me go straight into the market units.  Central Europe is up by 10% to a level of 4.7 billion euros now.  The main contributor is our Central Europe's West Power business, which is up 500 million.</p>
          <p>And let me comment on some of the key effects.  The single biggest one is an increase of 1.4 billion euros that stems from rising gross margins; included there, is in particular, an increase of our wholesale power position where we've seen an average increase in wholesale power price of 10 euros per megawatt hour, and that applied to a 112 terawatt hour production last year gives you already a 1.1 billion improvement.  That is partially offset by about 365 million euros of higher procurement cost.  We have a special effect and I will come to that also back again later of 570 million increase in EBIT which resulted from a reduction in our nuclear provision due to the harmonization with our finance strategy.  What we have done there is, we looked at the external financing cost included in the valuation of the financing of the construction of the final storage.</p>
          <p>We've taken the assumed leverage down to the level that we apply to all of the E.ON Group, i.e. down to 35% in line with our capital structure, and we've also adjusted the interest rate that is assumed for such external financing from 7 to 5.5%.  The overall impact of that is a reduction in the provision by 570 million.  We have about 170 million cost related to higher feed-in of renewable energy.  We lost 144 million euros due to the outage of the nuclear power plants in Kr&#xFC;mmel and Brunsb&#xFC;ttel.  And we've built a 223 million provision for covering deficiencies detected in our German network during regular inspections, that is a one-time effect.  There is also included here, a 200 million euro charge that basically you will find the equivalent of that as a plus in our Corporate Center number. There is a reallocation of costs resulting from our <mark type="inaudible" /> project.</p>
          <p>Coming to Central Europe's gas business that is down by 70 million, basically as a consequence of milder weather last year.  Our Eastern European business is up by almost 100 million, mainly because of higher gross margins, in particular in Hungary and Romania.  Now, before I come to the other market units, I would like to offer some support for those trying to reconcile whether we in fact improved in Central Europe or whether we didn't, because I wouldn't be surprised if most of you now just simply took the 570 million of reduction in nuclear provision and then wrongly concluded, boy, they are actually down.</p>
          <p>Let me try to prove the opposite.  What is the right 2006 number for comparison?  There is a lot of minor effects; there is one that is bigger in nature, and that is what is mentioned here on that page, and that is, we effectively had a 129 million extraordinary capital gain on divestments of smaller participations, that is a number that one probably would need to adjust in the 2006 results.  More important, however, are the effects for 2007.  As mentioned, there is the 570 million effect of the reduction in our nuclear provisions.  There are some offsetting effects. There is the 223 million provision that we have built for legal obligations in our network operations.  The cash out is going to take place this year, but it's a provision that we already built last year.  This is a one-time effect. There is the technical effect that I already mentioned of 200 million, which is effectively a cost reallocation from Central Europe into sort of the Corporate Center/Consolidation.</p>
          <p>If I only take those three effects, the 570, the 223 million as well as the 200 million and compare the resulting corrected EBIT with the EBIT 2006, that already would give me a 10% increase.  There is two other effects where you can debate as to whether they are operational and usual in nature or not.  One is the outage of the Kr&#xFC;mmel and Brunsb&#xFC;ttel power plants with an impact on EBIT of minus 144 million, and then there is the first time inclusion of E wie Einfach, the business which is in a ramp-up phase, trying to &#x2013; or actually successfully acquiring customers in Germany, and the negative effect of that start-up company are about 80 million in this year.  Taking those two effects on top of the ones that I had mentioned before would actually result in a 16% increase in the operations of our Central European business.  You can pick sort of which line you take.  The point we want to make here is, it is a bit more complicated than just looking at the 570 number.</p>
          <p>Pan-European Gas is also up 10%.  The upstream business has come down a bit mainly due to lower prices.  In the midstream business, gross margin is also down basically due to increased price competition in the German market.  Nonetheless, we've seen an overall increase in Pan-European Gas mainly because of the downstream business.  The core effects in that area are the following; the full year consolidation of F&#xF6;ldgaz, our Hungarian gas business, has in total improved EBIT by 166 million.  That is a significant improvement over the 2006 number, and we have in addition seen basically the absence of impairment charges we had in the year 2006 at the level of Th&#xFC;ga.  You may remember we had a 188 million charge due to impairments in the group business of Th&#xFC;ga, which obviously we no longer had again in 2007.  2007, just to make that clear, has been an exceptionally good year for Pan-European Gas business, and it's going to be tough to beat that number going forward.</p>
          <p>U.K. was a bit of a rollercoaster in the year 2007.  At year-end, it's down 1% over the 2006 number.  Whereas the regulated business is slightly up, we lost money in retail despite a strong first quarter of 2007.  Why was that?  Well, prices were down.  We actually lost customers.  We lost in the U.K. 400,000 customers in 2007, and it was again warmer than normal.  However, we no longer had the higher gas input cost of 2006 that we could avoid, and also we didn't again have the outage of the <mark type="inaudible" /> power plant which caused EBIT losses in 2006.  U.K. remains a tough market in retail, where we expect further operational improvements, and I will come to that when I talk about the outlook.</p>
          <p>Nordic is up 31% to a level of 670 million euros.  Main effects in the non-regulated business are about 110 million on the pricing side due to successful hedging, and then volume is up on the generation side as well.  However, we have seen a 150 million charge as far as the nuclear provisions are concerned, that is a function of new cost estimates that we have been provided by the Swedish Nuclear Authority, hence we have to build an additional provision.  Nordic has improved a lot and we expect that to continue.</p>
          <p>Our U.S. Midwest business is basically flat in dollar terms, and the only reason why it's down on that chart here is the further dollar/euro effect that has caused a 1% decline in the EBIT contribution of our U.S. Midwest business.</p>
          <p>Let me now walk you through the rest of the P&amp;L.  Net interest is flat compared to last year.  Net book gains are up.  This includes, as a big item, the capital gain we had on the sale of our telecoms business in Austria, ONE Austria that we sold mid last year.</p>
          <p>Non-operating expenses, we have a major swing.  That swing has two main components.  There is a 2.5 billion euro swing, which is just a consequence of the mark-to-market valuation of the derivatives.  And then there is about 400 million of network impairments which we had the year before and didn't incur again in 2007.  The tax rate is back to, I would say, a normal level.  In 2006, we had a very special situation, two effects had caused basically a zero percent tax rate.</p>
          <p>There was a 1.3 billion effect for the first time recognition of the corporate tax credits.  We were reporting about that a year back.  And then secondly, we had a positive deferred tax income on the losses on the negative mark-to-market of the derivatives.  Again, we didn't have that in 2007.</p>
          <p>Discontinued operations in 2006 basically included Degussa, both earnings and capital gains; and in 2007, we realized the deferred book gain on part of the Degussa transaction when we sold &#x2013; when he finally sold them our stake in RAG.  Remember we had sold Degussa to RAG still maintaining a certain shareholding in RAG.  We didn't realize the full profit on the sale of Degussa.  We only did that when we then finally sold our shareholding in RAG, which took place in 2007.</p>
          <p>Overall reported net income is up 27%.  Now you all know reported net income due to in particular the swing in a mark-to-market of derivatives is of less relevance to us.  The relevant metric is our adjusted net income, which is also the basis for the determination of our dividend payments.  It's up 9% to now a level of 5.1 billion euros.</p>
          <p>Let me come to cash flow.  Operating cash flow is up by 1.6 billion euros or more than 20%.  Main contributors to this increase are basically Pan-European Gas and the U.K.  In Pan-European Gas, the biggest effect results again from F&#xF6;ldgaz, 1.3 billion euros.  There are three effects that add to this big number.  For the first time we were including the first quarter, don't forget in 2006 we only consolidated F&#xF6;ldgaz from April onwards.</p>
          <p>In particular, Q2 and Q3 in 2007 were massively up compared to the year before.  And then when we had acquired the E.ON F&#xF6;ldgaz business, it basically came with an empty storage, and that led to a big cash outflow in 2006.  We didn't have the same effect in 2007.</p>
          <p>A further driver of the big increase in cash flow at Pan-European Gas is the better usage of storage at the E.ON Ruhrgas, that's about 800 million euros, and then about 300 million higher dividends resulting from our international businesses.</p>
          <p>In the U.K., basically the main impact there is an improvement in working capital, some of that is a function of us actually improving the situation with operations, some of it admittedly is price related, or changed &#x2013; basically due to the change in prices.</p>
          <p>In corporate center the negative number you see there in terms of the change is entirely tax related.  There are higher external tax payments on the one hand, which is about half that change, and then there is lower tax refunds in 2007 compared to 2006.  We now also show a different breakdown in terms of our capital expenditures. We will going forward always show you separately the maintenance CapEx, I think that hopefully helps people here to get a better understanding of what is really required to keep the machine running.  And then we will separately show you investments for replacements, acquisitions, and other.</p>
          <p>On the investments by market units, I actually will not comment a lot on that.  Wulf has basically walked you through the main issues as it relates to our investment program.  The only point I would like to stress is that whilst the cash effective amount was 11.3 billion euros, obviously given the nature of acquisitions, in order to really come up with a right investment or economic investment number one has to add the indebtedness we acquired in the context of the acquisitions we have done.  And if you add up those numbers to the 11.3 billion, you get to an economic investment of a total 12.7 billion euros that includes about 200 million for leasing obligations.</p>
          <p>How has all that impacted our capital structure?  Economic net debt increased by about 6 billion to a level of 24 billion euros at the end of 2007.  Most of those numbers I've explained by now.  The only item I would like to highlight is the decrease of 1.1 billion euros in our pension provision, which is entirely a function of a change in discount rates, which we have taken up from 4.5 to 5.5% at the year-end 2007.</p>
          <p>This gets us closer to our target capital structure, the debt factor increases from 1.6 to 1.9.  Our target remains to 3 times, and as Wulf said, we will reach that level in 2008.</p>
          <p>Just a quick update on the share buyback.  In 2007, we bought back shares for an amount of 3.5 billion euros, 25 million shares have been cancelled as promised at the year-end.  During the course of 2008, we have acquired further shares for a total about 400 million euros.</p>
          <p>You can follow this almost daily on the Internet.  So in total, we have by now spent 3.9 billion euros for acquiring 31 million shares.  We have also sold 13.5 million put options to capitalize on the high volatility in the markets.  Again, we remain fully committed to the implementation of our share buyback program.</p>
          <p>Before I come to the outlook, let me give an update on the progress with our funding program.  Basically, I think we have seen a very successful start in 2007 with the largest euro offering of a corporate since the beginning of the credit crunch.  We have the second largest sterling bonds, the second largest Swiss franc deal last year.  We have successfully increased our syndicated credit facility from 10 to 15 billion, which gives us more flexibility and the required backup for our CP program.</p>
          <p>Let me now come to 2008.  Now, before I come to the outlook, let me make some technical remarks.  From January 1st, 2008 on, we have reorganized our businesses.  Trading renewables as well as Italian assets have been carved out from our 2007 market units.  As a consequence, we are not in a position to offer a like-for-like comparison and outlook for our previously reported market units.</p>
          <p>From Q1 2008 on, we will account following our new segments.  A segmental outlook can only be provided in 12 months from now when we will report about 2008 and then give you the outlook for 2009.</p>
          <p>Now, I am aware that people would have preferred us to give an outlook on a market unit basis, but we ask for your understanding that technically this is simply not possible at this stage. But you have our commitments that that will change when we have implemented the new market units and then have a basis from which we can come up with a relative comparison.</p>
          <p>So let me now comment on 2008.  We expect adjusted EBIT to be up 5 to 10%.  Where we come out will also depend a lot on the Endesa/Viesgo situation.  In other words, if we close early in the year, say April, we would expect to be more at the upper end of that range.  If we close sort of at the back end of the year, for example as late as Q4, we might come out more closer to the lower end of the range.</p>
          <p>We expect a short position in CO2 emissions for the whole group of around 20 plus million tons, and that is fully factored into our forecast.  We are continuing our restructuring efforts for our German distribution and retail business and that also is factored into our forecast.  We do not assume any material contribution from proprietary trading business, which I believe is very important in today's markets.  By the way, proprietary trading also hasn't added a lot of profitability in the year 2007.</p>
          <p>Net income &#x2013; adjusted net income, we expect to be slightly up over last &#x2013; compared to last year.  Now, before you ask me what does that mean, with slightly up &#x2013; basically we're implying a 3 to 5% increase.</p>
          <p>Net income, we expect to be trailing to EBIT a bit since interest expense ramp-up will be a bit quicker than the EBIT ramp-up given the nature or the organic nature of our investment program. Tax benefits resulting from the German tax reform have been considered as part of our forecast.  We don't assume any special tax effects at this stage.</p>
          <p>Now to give you at least some understanding of what we expect to be the major things that might drive the development in our businesses, let me just comment a bit, I'm going through the different market units, just to highlight what we think are going to be some key drivers.</p>
          <p>As far as our Central European business is concerned, clearly we expect the power margins to continue to positively contribute to the developments.  We expect first results from our internal restructuring and the consolidation of SNET, the French business, which will be included in Central Europe, should also add to the development of the new Central European business.</p>
          <p>On the downside, there is a higher cost, as far as CO2 emissions is concerned.  Grid regulation will have a negative impact. And also, we will carve out trading renewables and the Italian business from Central Europe.</p>
          <p>Pan-European Gas, as I said, 2007 was a really a very, very strong year and it's going to be tough to beat that number in 2007.  Regulatory effects might have some negative impact and we also believe that the profitability we are seeing of <mark type="inaudible" /> was very high in 2007.</p>
          <p>In the U.K., we expect the retail business to continue to be a tough business.  Margin pressure will continue to be in place.  Having said that, we are working on a number of improvements &#x2013; improvement measures as far as our retail program is concerned.  In the U.K., like as the case for Central Europe, we will carve out the trading business and some of the renewable activities.</p>
          <p>Our Nordic business, we expect positive contributions from wholesale price movements.  Clearly, we no longer expect another charge as far as the nuclear provision is concerned, that hopefully will not reoccur in 2007.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, EBIT may or will come down once we close the transaction with Statkraft.  Don't forget we are basically giving up about the third of our hydro capacity in Sweden.  Again, like as the case for U.K. and Central Europe, trading and renewable activities will be carved out there.</p>
          <p>The U.S. business, we expect to be stable and corporate center cost might go up a bit given we will charge some of the integration costs and this will be a year of integration from the new market units.</p>
          <p>Our Russian business as well as the renewables activities, we still expect to only contribute to a very small degree to our overall profitability.  So these are really going to be at this stage more de minimis amounts.</p>
          <p>As for your understanding that at this stage, I'm not in a position &#x2013; we all are not in a position to comment on the profitability of Endesa/Viesgo given that we are right in the midst of discussions with our partners on the other side.  That basically concludes my remarks; hence, we are obviously now more than happy to take your questions.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Marcus. Thank you, Wulf. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. I think the first question comes from Mart, Martin, Christopher Rogers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay, Chris Rogers from JPMorgan. First question, you've increased your CapEx program by 3 billion euros. Given that you've said previously your long-term EBIT target includes contribution from CapEx, you haven't moved the EBIT target; does that mean the CapEx comes in after 2010 or is there some sort of offsetting effect? Secondly, looking at the trading business, can you just give us some guidelines as to what the baseline trading profit is going to be for that separated business unit? And can we presume that the 400 million euros of trading profit improvement that's in your 10-by-10 program will go solely into that business unit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on the first question, what has really caused the increase in CapEx? It's the acquisition of OGK-4. Yes, we expect that to positively contribute to the 2010 EBIT number. Then there is the 4.4 billion deal with Statkraft, which is an acquisition, but will actually lead, given that we always fully consolidated EBIT, to a decline in EBIT in 2010. And then, we also today clearly see, you know, a further downside as far as the German grid regulation is concerned. And if you just take those three effects and I agree there are a number of other items, but they basically almost offset each other and that gives you sort of the increase in CapEx.</p>
          <p>What we also then had adding to the increase in investment was the investment into Airtricity, which is in a massive ramp up phase. And there, basically, the EBIT contribution in a strict sense, is probably a, is not yet a three-digit million number, it's clearly below that. Which is by the way, in particular, a function of the fact that not all of the profitability of Airtricity actually shows up above the EBIT line. Some of that, as most of you will know, actually is below the EBIT line. I think going forward, we have to see how we deal with that. We have also not changed our assumptions as it relates to power prices. So whilst I agree with you there is more investment and it's more in growth, actually when you take all those effects, there is no reason to alter the 2010 number. Also please always bear in mind, the 2010 number is assuming current portfolio and the investment plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, could I just clarify...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You said that you've assumed further downside in grid regulation, i.e. does that mean that your assumption now is quote "worse" than it was back on May 31?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is slightly worse, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then as far the trading business is concerned, honestly speaking, I can't give you the answer. The reason being that, for some of the markets units, we are still working on the precise definition of the transfer prices, and only when that is fixed, we have clear visibility on, you know, what sort of the baseline trading figure is going to look like. Personally, I would expect, and then Johannes should probably also comment on that, that not all of the improvement would actually show up in the trading business. Some of that, I think, may be visible on the site of the generation assets. But we will actually try going forward to show you a full result for generation, which will include sort of the generation site and sort of the trading around those assets in one number going forward. Johannes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think like, what Marcus said, you know, we have trends consolidate the business after it's already quite live in all our areas. Therefore, we have to obey international tax treaties and tax situations, and therefore a substantial amount of, let's say the asset optimization trading result needs to show up on the asset side. And obviously, the significant part of the prop trading results will show up here in the trading unit, and there is still conversations with the tax authorities across Europe to see upon exact ways and move forward. But I can confirm that there's no doubt that the announced 400 million additional profit that we saw from that line of responsibility will come and it will be there. Where it exactly shows up needs to be seen over the course of the year, but it is included and there is no moving backwards from that outlook.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Martin Young.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi there, it's Martin Young at Lehman. Two questions: Firstly, in relation to the announcement that you made a couple of weeks ago about the disposals of the transmission grid and the generation capacity here in Germany. Taken at face value, looks like an excellent move, obviously very much in keeping with your strategy to manage the business on a portfolio basis, but you of course laced it with references to wanting to put an end to the EC anti-trust investigations. Could you sort of shed some light on what exactly you were worried that the EC could do to your business and if possible, put a financial quantum on that? And then secondly, following on from Chris's question, could you just shed some light on what you are now thinking about the development of regulation back here in Germany, particularly with reference to the magnitude of network fee reductions that you expect for 2008 and possibly, again into the future? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the first one. I am afraid I can't really give you any more detail on background and our internal considerations when it came to the decision, because we are still in the process with the European Commission to put a more concrete frame around our joint understanding, but we had to sort of weigh all the arguments for and against and we decided that this is the right move in the interest of the company and our shareholders. And therefore, I can't really comment on those details at this stage.  I ask for your understanding there. As far as regulation is concerned, Marcus?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, don't over-interpret what I said.   There is a further decline we expect for 2008 and that's, given this will form the basis for the incentive regulation, will thus feed through into the following years. I mean, we don't know the sort of what the final result is going to be, but this is probably somewhere in the order of magnitude of, you know, a high two-digit million number or maybe a bit more, but I mean, don't misinterpret this as a humongous impact, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" />. Peter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I had one question regarding regulation, in terms of incentive regulation. So far we've nothing seen regarding gas midstream, what can we expect here from the regulator for 2009 on that business, especially for Ruhrgas.  And the second question is regarding your success in the E wie Einfach business.  You have gained 700,000 new clients; how many clients have you attracted from your own franchise and from rivals? And is this success coupled with the discussion about potentially selling your interests in Th&#xFC;ga, to be much more aggressive regarding this strategy to attract German clients here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This was actually more than one question. But on the Th&#xFC;ga side, I can tell you that we have seen market speculations in the last couple of weeks. We have not taken a decision concerning Th&#xFC;ga, but I can confirm that we went through a very intensive strategic review with the Th&#xFC;ga management last summer. And we have to see what that means for the development of the business.</p>
          <p>One thing appears to be clear &#x2013; that Th&#xFC;ga will find it very difficult to grow in the German market. And since we have taken away the Italian market to combine with our market unit Italy, the former Th&#xFC;ga business in Italy, the growth prospects for Th&#xFC;ga in the German market are somewhat limited and that has to be taken into account. As far as gas regulation is concerned and into E wie Einfach, Johannes, you comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think for the gas midstream business, there's first to be a decision on the national regulator how the regulations shall be performed. The law left it open whether it should be on a competitive market view or on a cost base. That decision is not yet finally  <mark type="inaudible" />. So the rules for the regulation of midstream are not yet settled. That decision appears to move forward but it's not in yet. So, it's hard to say yet what the outcome is, and therefore it's even harder to prognose how it will look 2009. So, at this present stage, since the regulator is still moving let's say slowly along, it's impossible to give you a clearer indication on the consequences. But obviously, we are in good negotiations and good talks with the regulator and I would not be surprised, and we foresee that in our plans, that there will be probably some downward moves as in all/any kind of first-time regulation. But we don't foresee let's say something beyond our expectations at this given time.</p>
          <p>For E wie Einfach, we have announced that we have gained 700,000 customers. You should compare it with our original plan to acquire just 100,000 in the first year.  Let's say we were positively surprised by the sudden faster movements, faster churn rates in this market and I guess we were more than optimal positioned time-wise and product-wise last February. And therefore, we could profit from this change development very positively. We also announced that we lost about 400,000 customers in our traditional sales entities. So, if you compare these numbers with total customers, I think it's fair to say that we... the traditional segments we lose according to market development, not more significantly than others, maybe a little less, but that is not very significant. So, we gain the main, let's say the total surplus is mainly coming from other people and in our internal sales channels we lose and gain according to market developments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just perhaps one additional comment. My colleague just reminded me that as far as Th&#xFC;ga is concerned, we should add that, with us as being the owners of Th&#xFC;ga they can't go, with a different owner obviously they can participate in the further consolidation of those municipality participations. Or let's say upcoming merger activities between municipalities that definitely is possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is <mark type="inaudible" />. I will give this a try and first question relates again to the grid and the capacity disposals. Can we get any data with regards to regulated asset bases and profitability numbers? I said I'll give this a try. Second question on this, I'd be quite curious to know if you could shed a little bit more light on the timing, why it has cropped up now? It appears that there has been some lead discussions up to this. If you could shed some more light on this timing at this particular point in time. And also, you are selling capacity within Germany, now clearly, have you already have had thoughts of where you would wish to redeploy that growth within the generation business and within other regions? Is that it? Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, as you said, it was a good try. And unfortunately, we can't really give you more details on this. Now, we can say a little bit on the timing of the process, not on the timing leading to the result, which we achieved only a week ago with the commission. We will have two years for the disposal of the TSO, and we will have six to nine months for the, let's say, arrangements to give up capacity on the generation side that can be extended by another six months. So, we talk about nine to 12, no, even more, months, which we'll have in order to find arrangements for those assets, and we will definitely target for swap deals rather than straight sales because we've no interest principally to give up our European market position. We have he intention to do the contrary, that means to increase our European position by arranging appropriate swaps. So, that I'm afraid, is all I can say at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't comment on regulated asset base, but we obviously understand and appreciate the notion that people want to have some indication on what is it that might be going out there. So, the 2007 EBIT number, I can indicate to you is basically a high two digit million number for the TSO, that is before the 2008 tariff. So that's a historical number; the high two digit million number. Regulated asset base, it's not only that I actually don't have that number because it's not so easy to actually quantify it, but we also don't want to comment on it at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I want just a clarification on the cap program. Just wanted to clarify that that doesn't take into account any proceeds from the transmission, generation disposals. And secondly, if you could just outline that your funding needs for 2008, and whether you're expecting anything to come in from these disposals? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The investment program does not assume any divestments. It is an investment program. So, no, the sort of any portfolio measures are not included in those numbers. As far as funding is concerned, I think the only messages I'd like to give there is that we've always made it clear what our overall funding need until the end of the decade is, which is around 30 billion number. Clearly sort of the peak funding year, you just have to look at our investment plan profile, is going to be 2008. I don't want to comment on what the specific funding needs in 2008 are, but quite frankly given the flexibility we have it's also not such a relevant point to me. Because we have, just looking at our CP program, there is little usage where we have there right now, we could easily ramp up that figure to pretty high levels because in contrast to many banks, we seem to be a very trustworthy counterparty. And so we see ample opportunities to find money in the markets. But given, there will be transactions this year, I ask for your understanding that I don't want to comment on the specific program we have for 2008. I hope that answers the questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hello. It's, maybe one question if you could give us update on <mark type="inaudible" /> about the discussions there, and secondly, sorry for that, but coming back to the grid and what you said about reviewing your portfolio. Given the value creation requirements you have, wouldn't the TSO don't fall out anyway in '09 or '10 given the attractiveness or low attractiveness of the grid regulation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, starting with the second point, we have looked at all of our assets in our portfolio in the course of last year. We reviewed it again this spring in our strategy workshop. And, as I said in my statement, we will come up with first implementation steps in the course of this year. And, of course, that included also all of our gird business in on the power side and also on the gas side and the differences indeed. So, as far as <mark type="inaudible" /> is concerned, no news unfortunately. Our Russian partners, Gazprom, were unable in the last few weeks to take any decisions because of the changes to be expected in the total leadership structure in Russia. And Gazprom is very much a political company in a sense. And therefore, we have to see how it all settles first and then resume the talks and see whether we can finally find you mutually acceptable agreement. It's still about asset valuation and those aspects. The assets we talk about as swap assets are identified but it is still a valuation issue. So, unfortunately, I must say, no real progress on that score.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Christopher Kuplent, Christopher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, Chris Kuplent at Credit Suisse. Two questions, rather long-winded I'm afraid. Getting back to the EU, there have been calls for unbundling, you've now, I guess, strengthened the EU's case. Hypothetically speaking, if we believe that the EU took high-voltage as a first step, waiting for cracks to appear, do you expect more effort being spent in the medium term on further unbundling downstream also in gas, and to what degree would you also be willing to talk about compromises with the EU, why, why not?  And as a second question, coming back to the EBIT target for 2010, you've shown a 50 billion and quite a detailed breakdown of that CapEx program.  Can you give us a number of how much CapEx actually contributes to that EBIT number, given that you have power plants, you've shown that starting well beyond 2010, you've got Nord Stream in your CapEx that I don't think will start delivering EBIT by 2010.  A feel would be very helpful.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the first one.  What the commission has pursued for quite some time under the name of unbundling was covering both the power and the gas sector.  So they are looking at the TSO level, not going further.  So the TSO, the transmission business, not the distribution business so far, and I don't think they have that in mind at this stage.  And on the gas side also the high-pressure pipeline grid.  We maintain the position that those two businesses are not comparable, that there are indeed significant differences between the gas and the power grids, and we see no reason to talk about anything on the gas side at this stage.  So, Marcus, give it a try.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not so easy.  Thanks for that.  I mean I'm doing this basically sort of from the top of my head here.  If I include sort of the main effects which is acquisitions, in that time period, because most of the organic investments save for the ones that come on stream earlier such as Livorno Ferraris, most of them will only contribute post 2010.  Also our gas upstream investments will basically contribute after 2010, storage the same.  That could give me a number, and also taking into consideration that we are losing some EBIT as a consequence of the Statkraft transaction, I get to maybe a level of around sort of 1.5 billion compared to the 2006 figure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now that number is out Marcus.  I am in trouble, now they will ask me all kinds of questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I said that's roughly.  I might be wrong by maybe 200 up or down.  I think.  Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a big disclaimer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's actually on with me. Sorry.  Would it too much to ask for on what CapEx number that's based on, because obviously that's the EBIT, the 50 billion is CapEx.  So can you tell us how much CapEx, two-thirds, 20%, is actually not delivering any earnings before 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.  I mean I can work all this out, but not within sort of one minute here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.  The next one is <mark type="inaudible" /> I know you've been waiting for a while.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. <mark type="inaudible" />, Morgan Stanley.  I have two questions on the gas market.  And the first one is on the German gas market and what the Cartel Office is doing right now with your regional units.  I would like to be interested what you expect in a worst case scenario could happen to your regional units and <mark type="inaudible" /> group where you see your gas prices compared to competitors.  And the second question is we remember that the EU is also working on a case in the gas business against E.ON and I would be interested if you're working on a compromise to make the EU dropping that case as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with your second question with the gas case.  That's a pending case which refers to a day old agreement which was I think signed at the end of the 70s and never implemented and later on cancelled.  The main content of that agreement was, if I remember right, capacity arrangements on the transit pipelines in Germany.  That case will take its course.  So we'll see whether the Commission will pursue it or drop it later on.  It has dropped a similar case, that's what we know.  And it is not affected by our talks with the Commission of the last few weeks.  And other than that we are not aware of any concrete proceedings in the gas sector.  So that's as far as the Commission is concerned.  Now to the German Cartel Office.  Johannes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What is new now is much too premature to call anything because what they do, I would rather call a small sector enquiry on the gas market.  There is no orders towards any of our companies to lower gas prices yet.  What they have asked for is getting information.  And it seems to be going in line between the Bundeskartellamt and the state authorities in various German states because the Bundeskartellamt is only, can only act on companies that supply more customers beyond one national state.  What they're investigating is an interesting new concept.  They first time compare let's say pure commodity prices, subtracting the grid price, subtracting tax and other tar tax and similar charges, and then coming down to let's say an obvious commodity price and comparing those between market participants and say, let's assume it would be full effective market, can there be such differences?</p>
          <p>The surprising use is, and I think the whole market is, I don't want to take it lightly, but a little bit amused.  The offices here is supposed to be market leader in East Germany is the city utility of <mark type="inaudible" />, you might have to look very hard on your map to find that.  And in West Germany the new price leader supposedly is the <mark type="inaudible" />, which also never showed up in the past as something very spectacular.  So I think it is necessary and meaningful exercise for us to see what is right or wrong there, who communicated what, and what is the reality behind <mark type="inaudible" />.  I don't think it will be done in a week or two, and I wouldn't be totally amazed if there is also significant misunderstandings in communication there. But I also won't rule out that there are some meaningful differences that the Bundeskartellamt wants them to talk about and find out where they come from.  But my main view is that I told the President of the Bundeskartellamt when I saw him two days ago is you know we are the only ones that act competitively across Germany in gas.  We earn almost 250,000 gas customers because we are the only one that offer competitive gas product across our nation.  So maybe it's more interesting to look in a more active market than trying to analyze costs or other kind of regional pricing, but it will take time.  I don't foresee anything fast, and therefore if you would ask me, if you already have a horror scenario, obviously far away from that yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question comes from Andreas Thielen [MainFirst]. Andreas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, first a simple question, you were giving some indications on the profitability of E wie Einfach given the customer gains there, what is the outlook for the current year? And secondly with respect to the investments, you were talking about shifting CapEx from Turkey to Russia, obviously Russia require, there is more chance for investments, but has anything changed in your idea about Turkey, about the prospects of that market, the profitability there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Last point, no, not really, I mean what we have done when we drew up our plans last year. And announcing in May, we could not clearly foresee that we would be successful just a few weeks, almost or months afterwards in our acquisition with OGK-4 in Russia.  So, we had to -- in the absence of any better knowledge, we had to set aside a certain amount for Turkey and Russia.  We spent more in Russia than we were anticipating, therefore we now have to see how much we can afford to spend in the Turkish market and what the opportunities are or the strategic options are in the Turkish market.  We have not given up Turkey as a potential market to enter.  And we have a company and a small team sitting in Turkey looking at market opportunities and we are just at this point in time looking at options and weighing our options whether we should now move or not move into Turkey, E wie Einfach --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I don't think E wie Einfach is obviously a market unit and will not regularly be reported towards the market.  I think the first year was obviously something worth to mention because we built up first time a national brand.  We had to install significantly all the processes and the whole organization and high advertisements and a significant ramp-up phase.  And that was so significant  in that year.  And the second most significant thing was that we were so incredible successful.  But from now on, it will be just a normal part of <mark type="inaudible" /> in the market unit -- central unit -- Central Europe market unit. And I don't foresee that we will as has competitors communicate individual numbers for that, which would be also a little surprising because then other people can calculate where we position ourselves. How we calculate and that would not be too wise in a competitive market to be so open and frank on a single entity on that level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Sorry, I should have probably been more precise.  I just wanted to understand if you expect that business to be profitable as of 2008, I mean obviously given heavy upfront spending last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we don't expect it to be profitable in 2008.  It will continue to be in a growth phase and just the nature of the business, I mean it's a thin margin business and then you obviously have an acquisition cost per customer as a function of marketing expenses and the first time inclusion into your back-end systems the stuff that costs money when you do it for the first time, and the share of sort of newly acquired customers will still be big compared to the overall number of customers.  It's the same basically in any ramp-up business where you are, in the customers which you are acquiring.  It takes two-three years until you have a chance to become profitable.  We could become profitable but then we would have to stop going for new customers and that's not the strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe for your model, just compare how much it costs in Holland or U.K. or other liquid markets to acquire 700,000 customers and what is being paid for acquisition of customers.  If you just look from that perspective, you could also argue it's a very cheap and very effective way of growing a market share and I would argue that way, but otherwise, the market is obviously right.  It is also part of an investment in the ramp-up phase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Christopher Rogers [JPMorgan].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I have a couple of follow-up questions.  I can't see Luede here, so I'll have to ask these questions for him.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, he is on Internet, he is going to ask questions for him.  Luede, don't worry about it, your questions -- all the Internet questions are coming to me, we'll be taking them once we finish in the hall here, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent.  Okay, apologies Luede. I will ask my own ones. How precisely are you going to improve the U.K. retail business?  Clearly, the main lever you have is pricing and then you have kind of cost controls beyond that.  I'd just be interested there.  And secondly, just to be clear on the nomenclature, you're talking about selling the TSO, the operator, but not the assets, because clearly there is a difference between the two, I just want to be clear on what we're talking about here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, on the second one, I mean we are selling -- when we say we would dispose off the TSO, its assets and operatorship, not just one.  As far as the U.K. retail business is concerned, just to give you some indications, and you will understand this is a fiercely competitive market and I don't want sort of go too much into details, but there is obviously certain cost measures one can take when you look at the call center support, you can -- when we look at our own activities, we can further consolidate that.  We think we can improve on our customer number by actually putting more emphases into sort of the field troops that basically walk from door to door to try to acquire customers in U.K., that's actually a quite successful way to gain market share.  This is something which we will explore more aggressively going forward.  And then, there is a high portion of costs included in our 2007 numbers that stems from sort of writing off unpaid amounts -- unpaid bills.  There is still quite a significant weakness in the U.K.'s grid system that, in a sense, that doesn't give you timely enough the volumes that actually you should charge to the customer, we think there are certain things we can improve there.  So, these are just some of the examples.  But obviously, the single highest impact you've already mentioned and that is the increase in price.  But that is something that has taken place already or has been announced already.  We think we took a very good position there, positioning us well compared to where the competition is.  But again, it's a whole stuff of measures that are on the way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, Christopher?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, just to follow-up, you are saying then given that you've got to get your door-to-door army out there and all these things, is it that the recovery in supply is not going to come in '08, it's going to be more an '09 kind of issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we hope that we will see some improvement already in 2008, but indeed, the biggest impact might come a year later, that is correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From Martin Young [Lehman Brothers], Martin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, just a couple of quick follow-up questions.  Endesa have announced that they will hold a presentation next week on the asset disposal process.  Obviously, you will of a side of that particular equation.  I wonder if you could just shed some light on what the process is going to be from here and potentially give us some indication around timing.  And then secondly, regarding the capital expenditure plan, in the plan communicated last May, &#x20AC; 6 billion was actually declared as being outside the period 2007 to 2010.  It now all appears to be within the period 2008 to 2010.  Is that correct or is that actually an element of that expenditure that is still sitting outside that timeframe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lutz, you want to answer the first one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have been made aware of that fact that Endesa has called for this IR conference call on I think Monday, the 11th or probably Tuesday, the 11th.  Today, we struggle to understand what they are intending to do.  We actually believe that as per the agreement that we have reached and signed back in April last year, this is something that if it is supposed to deal with anything, any transaction as per the contract should have been agreed with us upfront and we're testing that legal thinking with them whilst we speak.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the other question, no, the 6 billion has not been folded into the period until 2010.  It is still out there.  It is likely no longer 6 billion.  The reason why we are not reporting it is because, when you then go into the details you actually see that -- just to give an example, part of the investment plan until 2010 is the acquisition of a site and there we are in sort of a single digit million range for a potential nuclear power plant in Finland. Now, if it gets built there is a big number that comes after 2010, and in a way this is a bit of -- that's not a terribly meaningful number to report as part of our investment plan. That's the -- given that we had a number of those items, we haven't -- we've basically decided to not report what will come after 2010. The number you see there is probably roughly what would be required to work on those or to finalize those power plants that are part of the program that Wulf has shown in his part of the presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Basically just take a view on how much of that power plant expansion program you think will be invested post 2010; take that out and you're going to come up with a number for the next couple of years that is actually lower than the 63 billion that you see on there in terms of spend from 2007 to 2010 inclusive?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't get the question, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would also like -- we only communicate differently. It has been only once in our life, let's say, last May that for the purpose of understanding the story, we communicated not just the investment spending for three years, but we also communicated, let's say the finalization of projects that were started in the period, but the final phase happened a little later. The only thing we do is, we go back to the original way we always communicated, we communicate three years investment spend, and next year, the next three years, and then these finalization of projects will still occur out there in the later years, and these numbers -- some numbers will be in the next year's communication. There is no change whatsoever around the story, it's just a different format of communication on investment spend or investment projects. So I don't think there is anything big to speculate around the number. It's just the format how we communicate; we are back to how we always communicated, and therefore we don't talk about the 6 billion any more, but don't worry, they come back, there's nothing spectacular about it, it's just in later year's plans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so basically it's not 63 billion to 2010 versus the 54 billion that you communicated last year; it's a number that we can decide upon ourselves versus 54?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. For the period -- to be precise, for the period 2007 until year-end 2010, the number 63 billion is the correct number for our -- for the investment plan we have announced today. You can see it actually on this chart which is the 13 last year plus the 50 to come. And then you should compare that with assumed 54 billion last year and the 9 billion difference -- I mean as we always said is mainly OGK-4 <mark type="inaudible" /> which is not cash effective, and Airtricity. And then, a lower assumed investment in Turkey. That's how you -- basically that allows you to reconcile this by 95%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> all clear. Okay, I think I'm going to take three questions from the hall before the questions coming on the Internet, they are going to kill me and they are saying, Kiran doesn't even listen to -- or doesn't look at any questions. So <mark type="inaudible" /> Ingo and Andreas, I will take those questions. <mark type="inaudible" /> you start with first please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's only one this time. Can we come back to your view on CO2 and the component cost for new plant constructions? How &#x2013; can you give us some idea -- I mean, you put up this new engine and basically, it looks like the issue here is the CapEx cost. This is the first element, there's the 2006 level of CapEx cost and the current level of CapEx cost. You're saying you're having secured, basically, the bulk of your components, but presumably not the engineering costs. So where about between those levels would your CapEx cost is situated at this very stage? How much impact has your component sourcing had on this CapEx cost compared to the level where we are at the moment?</p>
          <p>The other question relates a little bit to your view on CO2 and the newer allocations, but it also plays together with the CapEx cost issue. When I look at your slide where you, I guess, all of your power plants are in, that are in planning and construction stage, it looks like that most of your coal plants are in planning stage whereas the ones that are being constructed are apparently in the majority basically CCGTs. So, can you tell us how safe are your plants for those coal plants upon which have some decisions have been taken, and where are things that could change?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Apparently I need to take a crack at this. First of all, I'm pretty sure I'm not going to answer all what you asked, but let me sort of go through the main points. There is this page that shows the new, the entire new-build program of 13 advanced projects and two major upgrades &#x2013; may be we can, yeah this one.</p>
          <p>Following messages, first, we are not saying that necessarily all of these plants will get built. Second, some of those may get built, but a bit later than what you see here because we may well decide that we push them out from a timing perspective because we actually do not like today's component prices. And in particular, for those where we haven't secured any equipment, there is a high chance that those might get pushed out and that's in fact also assumed, at least to some extent, in our investment plan.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, for those where we have secured the equipment &#x2013; to my knowledge actually, in most cases is also engineering, this third-party engineering, that is included in sort of the securing of the cost that is related to 10 plants.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have significant engineering capacities ourselves. We have a huge fleet of engineering sitting in Germany and England that we employ in these projects, I don't think that engineering is the main cost driver in our case, but civil work and other works are also not getting cheaper in these days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have seen an increase for one or the other plants on that page compared to what we had assumed in May. That's already included in the investment plan that we have presented today. Yes, I think that's basically...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me add one comment. We have seen increases which are still within our economic parameters in Datteln and Maasvlakte, which we have approved, and those projects are still or will still earn one full percentage point of our cost of capital, that's Datteln and Maasvlakte. We have just a few days ago approved Ratcliffe, the life extension, which is also a coal-fired plant and we have &#x2013; this is in this the planning commission for Kingsnorth because you said this is only guess, that's of course true as far as Italy is concerned and Bovaria, Irsching 4 and 5. And also the CHP plant in Sweden, in <mark type="inaudible" />, the only one way we are currently as I said in my presentation not so sure about starting a 6, but not so much for economic reasons, but probably more for political reasons. For that one we have also secured the major components, we have now to take a decision relatively soon where to use them because we don't want to lose them. So, that is something which is bit up in the year but that's the only one as far as I can see on this list.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ingo, your question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I had another question on your E wie Einfach business, your supply business. Given the way it is operated in Germany that you're under cutting local supplies by &#x20AC;0.01. Could you say, if the business is profitable, if you adjust for the fact that you're still growing it, I mean do you have to make any concessions to wholesale price levels to have a profit there? And my second question is on your remarkably low maintenance level of just below 2 billion. Do you expect that to remain there over the next foreseeable future like, e.g., until '10?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the E wie Einfach, I would communicate obviously we'll not communicate on the profitability of individual products. I don't know that is beyond expectation, we have new products in line some that we are out. And to communicate how we calculate individual product would mean that we disclose our cost base, our sales costs, and everything. And then would be rather smart to end competition don't you think? So we will not communicate on that one such an individual line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On maintenance, the level we have last year 2 to 2.5 billion is a good proxy for the year going forward, for the entire period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Last question from Andreas [MainFirst] and then I'll take the questions from the Internet, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I do understand that you don't give guidance for the individual units for the current year just to understand with respect to your caution on the outlook for Pan-European gas. I know there has -- you have detailed all the individual sectors behind the improvement in 2007. But, would it be correct to assume that, given more upstream gas coming into 2008, given that average gas prices should be nicely higher, that there is still room for an improvement in the current year? Or is it...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you &#x2013; well, I think that the main item people should pay attention to, we are, we basically live in a margin business there. Yes, we are gradually growing our upstream position but actually the major increase on the upstream side will come a few years from now.  I mean, <mark type="inaudible" /> will take another -- I think 2011 is the first year of production.  So conceptually we are in the margin business there.</p>
          <p>In addition, people should bear in mind that there is more third-party volume being put through the German system. That is causing, has already caused more competition; that was what I was referring to when I was talking about our midstream business. We expect that to continue. And also as far as the regulatory side is concerned and we see some potential components that could suggest downsize for the business. And that's why I was trying to point out that 2008 is not necessarily going to be better than 2007.</p>
          <p>Again, we always have this issue that there is some of the Ruhrgas business that is being carved out and being put into ET, some of the short-term trading. But other than that, I mean the main effect basically suggests that Ruhrgas or Pan-European Gas in 2008, is not necessarily going to beat '07.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Now the big task for me starts now and the first question comes from <mark type="inaudible" />, from Santander [Banco Santander] in Spain about the sale of generation assets in Germany. If you do an asset swap, what countries are you most interested in Spain, France, Italy or others? Wulf you want to answer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we can comment on that, there are interesting assets in all those countries that were mentioned, but we are not in a position yet to have a clear view on whether they have the opportunities, first of all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We like them all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Second question those guy is asking on Russia, when will be the beginning of the expected good performance of the Russian assets? I remember you expecting 1 billion in 2011, isn't it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What currency?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>He is saying dollar, yeah, $1 million, yeah. I guess he meant 1 billion, not 1million, it says here $1 billion, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>1 million we may make a bit earlier. There is no change in what we assume for the EBITD and EBITDA development for our Russian business. The indication we gave for 2011 still is valid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>He is now supposed to ask the third one but will apologize because we get nice drinking Spanish wine with him maybe in Russia, he is saying. If you finally sell the assets in Germany, are you thinking of employing even more the shareholder remuneration as you did with Degussa?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The shareholder remuneration will strictly follow -- I think he is referring to special dividends.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will stick to what we said. If we are at the target leverage level three times and we will -- what you will see is as paying dividends in the 50 to 60% payout range, full stop. Only if we deviate southwards from that three times number and don't have attractive, sufficiently attractive, investment opportunities then we will consider ways to redistribute cash to the shareholders whether that is done by way of dividends or another share buyback. This is too early to say, we will decide if and when that is relevant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Simon Flowers from Merrill Lynch. First question, will EON be content to operate unbundled in the German market if others remain bundled? Are you also pro gas unbundling?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry I couldn't --.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you -- will EON be content operate unbundled in the German market when others are bundled still?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no problems to operating in unbundled situation. Like Sweden and the U.K.. So, we have got sufficient business experience that we can operate in different systems, whether it's fully integrated business as we have in some markets or where we are only involved in some parts of the business. So that is not really an issue for us. As far as gas is concerned, the are no talks on the gas grid. So, there we expect that we will continue in the integrated business model.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In German, the second question in from Simon is, in German generation plus the plant 4.8 gigawatts cell, from this transmitter, does EON put itself at a competitive disadvantage by reducing its market share to around half that of the largest player? Johannes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are not at half of the market, the biggest market player to begin with. Let's assume we are around 24%. It will always varies if you look on capacity or output or what number you take, but let's take for granted it's around 24% and we move around 20. And RWE as the biggest market participant is, in the same way of calculation probably around 30. The next one behind us is significantly smaller than us. So, doesn't make a hell of a difference strategically if you are 24 or 20, especially if you built new capacity.  While we talk, I don't think so and we understand the way we act any how has not abusing market power in any way. And if you don't do that and if you follow integrated market views and run your business according to market signals, it shouldn't make any difference and we don't foresee that it makes any difference. Obviously, we have less investment in that market and we will redistribute some of that. But from a strategic point of view I don't foresee any significant strategic change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Vincent De Blic from Cazenove.  First question, what was your average achieved generation price in 2007 from Central Europe West power, for 2006, you had said 42 megawatt hour. Is it therefore &#x20AC;52 per megawatt hour?</p>
          <p>The answer is clear. Yes, I can answer that question, 52 euro is okay.</p>
          <p>"How do you explain the difference with RWE's reported 47 megawatt hour for 2007?"</p>
          <p>I'm not going to answer that question, ask my friends at RWE.</p>
          <p>"Second, can you elaborate on the increasing competition in Pan-European Gas midstream. What is it driven by?" The answer is increased throughput volume by the third parties they're putting in in the gas business.</p>
          <p>And last, the third question. "Just a clarification on slide number four of Mr. Bernotat's presentation, is your new investment plans, 63 billion total, or 63 billion in 2008-2010 plus 6 billion post-2010?" To answer first, I think we've already answered that. 63 in total <mark type="inaudible" /> Marcus do you want to comment? No, I think we already talked about that.</p>
          <p>The next one is our friend Lueder Schumacher from Dresdner. "You stated that you have not changed your power price assumption in your 2010 target. Given that, power prices were about 55 euros per megawatt hour. When you first mention that target" in May 31 he means, "and that you see tight reserve margins and new entry cost at 70 euros per megawatt hour. Isn't that the outlook based on your assumption that you are too conservative?" Marcus?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean -- look we've -- I don't think -- I mean, I don't want to comment on whether it's too conservative or not. To me what is relevant is, when I look at the forward rates, currently for the different markets in 2010, Central Europe that's around 62 and Nordic is around 51. Then basically I would say, yes we continue to be south of those of numbers. Luede has mentioned the number as high as 70 euros there, we don't exactly see that for baseload. We still feel comfortable with our projection, mathematically given we have not yet sold all of the 2010 volume, all things being equal, yes then there is some upsides. But I mean, what do I know what the power prices in 2010 are going to look like going forward? We will manage that position and then we will have to see in the end where we come out.</p>
          <p>I think what is relevant to people here is that we feel comfortable that the 12.4 number we put forward, we just didn't create that number by making some ludicrously high assumptions as it relates to prices at which we might sell our generation volume. We are -- as it stands today probably a bit conservative on that end, but I mean the situations may change, we've seen very drastic movements in power prices in the U.K. wholesale market, so I think we all don't know what exactly the prices will look like in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that is a good point, we've obviously also seen in particular coal be very expensive, so in fact, just looking at the spreads, we don't see that big upside in the different markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" /> "Regarding German market, how much of the 2008 production have you sold already? What kind of price changes are you experiencing?" And I think it was shown on the backup page from Schenck's presentation on page 21, how much we have sold in Germany and U.K. but we can answer, 90% sold in Germany. Regarding the price is concerned I think Marcus already mentioned just lately. Second question, "when you said 10 million investments in Nissan, does this include minorities?" I think we are -- in the current -- in the middle of the negotiation, and will not comment on the details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The third is, "how do the new transmission revenues compared to those of 2007 as opposed to those proposed by new regulation?" Marcus? New transmission revenues compared to those of 2007 as opposed to those proposed by you regulation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The revenues might be slightly up even, because we have higher volumes, their relative price for the transmission services are slightly down. But if you compare our numbers to the numbers of some competitors, we think we got out -- we came out somewhat more positively, I would say. If you compare that to our expectations and to what we think should be the right result came out somewhat, as Marcus said, a little more negative than we thought should be the results. But much more we can't say at this given time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Johannes. Next question come from Peter Bisztyga from Citi. "How much of the 1 billion euro target operational improvement can we expect to contribute to 2008 adjusted EBIT. And what will be the level of restructuring costs impact on, impacting on 2008 adjusted EBIT, first question?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't give an answer to that question. Part of the 1 billion that we communicated back in May last year was also an improvement in gross margin. So there is too many detailed effects that will some how also find its ways through to some extent into the 2008 number. But we don't have the details there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question from him is, "will all of the one time effects in Central Europe in 2007, page 5 of the Schenck's presentation reverse out in 2008 or will some item for example cost allocation consolidate effects will be ongoing." Marcus?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, the -- costs, the reallocation of costs of 200 million that I was referring to in terms of a charge to Central Europe and a sort of an income at the consolidation slash corporate center level. That will continue to be in place. We obviously do not expect another change in the nuclear power provision resulting from an adjustment to our financing structure. I mean, we have adjusted it and we don't expect &#x2013; we will not change our financing structure in the course of 2008. The <mark type="inaudible" /> know that some of that may reoccur -- or will reoccur in 2008. What the overall amount is going to be will depend on when the plants come back on stream and the 223 million provision that we've built. Yes, we do not expect that to reoccur in 2008. And as far as the, what is called consolidation effects mainly <mark type="inaudible" /> as concerned we clearly expect that number to come down in 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Marcus. Next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" /> from EXANE BNP Paribas. Question, "could you please elaborate on the discussions you're already having with the U.K. government regarding potential funding of fuel poverty scheme? Are you threatened as first suggest to be imposed a claw back?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, <mark type="inaudible" /> those discussions have just started; it's a big political issue in the U.K., probably driven by the desire of the politicians to react to do something about the increases the market has seen in the recent months. And as far as I learned it was triggered by a rather, let's say unprofessional presentation by Centrica that sparked off the whole discussion, unfortunately -- but it's too early to have any assessment what it might end up with. But it sort of sounds to me like a typical reaction of politicians trying to jump on the political issue, showing some action, and whether there will be a result of the debate remains to be seen, but certainly there is no clarity at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Wulf. The next question, the last one from Internet is, if I don't say correctly, <mark type="inaudible" />. Could you please tell me what is going to happen with current OGK-4 management, are you satisfied with it? Second, when OGK-4 strategy will be disclosed? What are the perspectives of gas business development in Russia for E.ON? Lutz?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So question number one, we are extremely happy with the performance of the current management. No reason to change anything in that regard. Strategy of not OGK-4 but of E.ON in the Russian power market is worked out whilst we speak and we will probably have a chance to disclose more of that, if we want to &#x2013; towards the end of this year. And the third question, Kiran, to be honest I didn't really get it. Was that about us entering the gas business in Russia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What are the perspectives of gas business development in Russia for E.ON?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think nothing has been considered in that regard and I am not sure whether we want to compete with the state monopolist Gazprom in the Russian gas market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Lutz. The next question here in the hall is Christopher Rogers [JPMorgan]. Chris?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  A further couple of follow-ups. Firstly, could you just tell us what your achieved price in the Nordic region was in '07, if that's possible please? And secondly I noticed from your usual EVA analysis that you've increased your weighted average cost of capital. Could you just explain why you've done that, for where you have done that? And also whether there is any impact on the remuneration of management as a consequence, I know that's been a measure &#x2013; that EVA has been a measure in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Christopher, do you mind to repeat that WACC increase for overall general you're saying?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. No, I was just looking at the table that you put into the annual report with the EVA analysis, the cost of capital has been put up for a number of the divisions at the grid level. I'm just wondering why that is and whether that has an impact on remuneration in any way given that EVA I know has been a benchmark measure for you in the past?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Nordic for 2007 average price realized is 34 euros and I think the way I understand your question is we &#x2013; is it just on the remuneration of people or was that a question on the WACC?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It was kind of both. Why have you moved the WACC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We have changed the weighted &#x2013; the WACC, but we did that quite frankly already back mid last year, because we wanted to adjust it to what is really our target capital structure. And bear in mind in the past we had always worked from a I believe 55% assumed debt portion of the capital structure, which was not exactly reflecting where E.ON was back then. And we have also furthermore adjusted the cost of capital to reflect a higher beta compared to what we have in the years before, what we had in 2006. So all these changes were introduced, again they were introduced back in May. Clearly quite frankly this is something we will have to take another look at I would say sort of in the second half of this year in light of the fact that we have obviously, since May last year seen another shift in the capital markets, and we will have to see what that means for how we should think about our cost of capital, but it's too early to speculate on what that is going to imply, we will have to do the analysis. As far as the remuneration is concerned, you may want to comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I mean there is no direct link of the WACC to the individual remuneration or bonus schemes of our managers. So that is a total unrelated issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the remuneration continues to be based principally on EBIT...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the EBIT targets, which we are agreeing with our market and business units, and therefore also it's being further broken down to intermediate level of our senior management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is some ROCE impact, but it is not influenced in any way by this change. So, let's say not a single dime to anybody on this table or any other table due to this change, not a single one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I have questions from <mark type="inaudible" /> from Goldman Sachs on Internet. Question, "has the level internal competition for the growth CapEx led you to see upside to the returns spread and/or the medium-term earnings from the growth. Do you see upside for the &#x2013; to the 100 billion &#x2013; 100 basis points spread?" Marcus?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all the 100% bps spread that we were referring to back in May was related to the organic investment plan on the generation side. We &#x2013; I mean &#x2013; I don't have visibility now here on all the projects included in the investment plan. What is clear is that we in fact do have by now a much higher competition in fact whenever someone comes up with a new investment proposal, she or he has to at the same time come up with a suggestion on which other projects we should just strike out from the existing investment plan. So that inevitably will lead to the fact that any new thing being proposed almost by definition has to bring a higher spread compared to the average of the existing projects. And, so in that sense &#x2013; but I can't point to, this or that specific project, we clearly see a greater discipline in us taking investment decisions and quite frankly, already in the way people put forward investment proposals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question from <mark type="inaudible" /> is a long one, I had to take a breath in to read it. "In your chart, you showed the upside to power of prices based on new build economics. Around what level of power prices is your medium-term earnings target based and what will trigger you to increase the power price assumptions you use in your internal guidance to align them with increases you're signaling in your generation presentation?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean where I think I've commented on that when answering Lueder's question on power price assumptions for 2010. We are reviewing our own assumptions on an annual basis. Quite frankly, we are right now in the midst of doing that again, but at this stage, there is no reason to change it. And as far as our generation presentation is concerned, what it is trying to work out is that in fact for the short-term, new entrance cost has come up. There is not always a short-term link between what is new entrance cost and what are the wholesale prices in the market. There can be a time delay, I mean over time, theoretically, they obviously have to somehow converge, but we're talking here about the time period until 2010. And today, as I said before, we don't see a need to adjust our numbers. We will review them on an annual basis and if we feel or if we see that there is a major change that should be introduced, we will do that and then communicate it to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Lueder Schumacher [Dresdner Kleinwort]. Question, "the components you have secured for new power plants, how long are the prices you secure valid for, and does it matter where the project is completed?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It doesn't matter where the project is completed. I think we have quite good context on that, that for most of the significant components we are not depending on the location. The first part, location is not important. What was the other one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For how long?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For how long?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>How long?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That varies between components, and obviously, also not very smart to announce everywhere, where they might be an opening coming up at some point. I don't think it's wise to discuss that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" /> from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. "Regarding the funding of the <mark type="inaudible" /> investment plan, would you consider using some of the large amounts of E.ON's liquid funds on balance sheet? What would be the optimal level of liquid funds on balance sheet? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is still some liquidity we can use. People shouldn't forget that some of what we show as liquidity is in fact assets under management on balance sheet that are backing both pension provisions that you see and also some of the nuclear decommissioning provisions. I don't have and would not want to give the specific breakdown in terms of how much liquidity we believe we can still use of the &#x2013; whatever the specific number now is, 1 billion that you can see on the balance sheet. But again, it's &#x2013; quite a significant portion of that is assets that are backing pension obligations and nuclear decommissioning obligations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the last and the final question from <mark type="inaudible" />. Question, "what was the reason for the change in the discount rate from 4.5% to 5% and therefore the decrease in the pension liabilities?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is something we have to do every year. There is a certain method by which the interest rate that should be used when calculating the pension obligation, that then has to be applied. It effectively looks at a quasi risk-free rate and then adds to that a certain spread to reflect, I believe it's a AA corporate rated bond. And we have seen compared to December 2006, an increase in both in sort of the quasi risk-free rate on the one hand and then &#x2013; I mean that is obvious also in the spreads that are being charged for corporate rated bonds and those two effects together just technically translate into a 100 basis point increase on the interest rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And I hit my deadline 4:20 exactly, I was expecting. On behalf of analysts and investors, I like &#x2013; we like to thank Wulf and Marcus, Johannes and Lutz for helping us and talking to you directly. Second thing, we like to thank you for coming to Dusseldorf despite the strikes and problems in transportation. Third, thanks for joining all on Internet and don't forget to thanks all our colleagues sitting here in the back, the <mark type="inaudible" /> people's knowledge of helping us. And we see you again, and as I said, we will have a presentation on the numbers and we will let you know as soon as possible. Thank you all for coming on behalf of the management. Wulf, would you like to say something?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to join in thanking you for coming and showing an ongoing interest in our company and being so patient to stay with us during this conference and all the questions coming via the Internet. See you again in individual meetings or group presentations or whatever and take care. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Last one thing I forgot to say, we will have drinks and to eat outside a little bit so you can chat with the management and this is a time, use it. And see you again. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>