<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1413045" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-08-10</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2864</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior Vice President, Investor Relations">Sascha Bibert</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman and Chief Executive Officer">Johannes Teyssen</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Member, Management Board and Chief Financial Officer">Marcus Schenck</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Vincent P. Gilles</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank GmbH (Broker)">Alexander Karnick</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (Europe) Ltd. Germany">Matthias Heck</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Kepler Capital Markets SA (Germany)">Ingo Becker</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS AG (Broker)">Patrick Hummel</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="MF Global UK Ltd.">Ashley M. Thomas</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Landesbank Baden-W&#xFC;rttemberg (Broker)">Bernhard Jeggle</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>So good afternoon, everyone. Welcome to the E.ON's Strategic and Financial updates. It's good to having you here in Frankfurt. Disruptive political events and challenging markets require clear answers. So our CEO, Johannes Teyssen and our CFO, Marcus Schenck will outline today how we execute our strategy putting an even greater focus on the value levers that we can control.</p>
          <p>The formal presentation will last a bit more than one hour; thereafter we take your questions. Given that some of you could not come to Frankfurt today due to the extraordinary market circumstances, we tried to organize a solution so that we can also take some questions from the Web site.</p>
          <p>With that, I hand over to our CEO, Johannes Teyssen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone.</p>
          <p>Obviously, circumstances are extraordinary and for that it's already amazing how many of you made it possible instead of watching the boards. Less than a year ago, Marcus and I had presented our revised new strategy to you based on the conviction that our company will continue to face a very challenging environment in its traditional market, but also quite strong belief, that the sector, overall, will continue to present opportunities in the decades ahead. That overall assessment has not changed. On the contrary, we see it rather even reinforced by recent events.</p>
          <p>Despite some minor improvements in prices and spreads in the last month, the overall environment for conventional generation in Europe, however, remains very challenging as the economic difficulties in many of our countries are more pronounced than expected. From the political front, decisions to reverse the lifetime extension of nuclear energy, within weeks, in Germany only illustrates a broader trend towards increased government decision and intervention. This is an environment that we have to face and work with.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, we don't simply accept an even lower profitability in the short term and stagnation in the longer term. Quite the reverse. It is especially in those times where strategy and especially stringent execution makes difference. This is why we have announced today the most far-reaching performance target in the history of E.ON and I believe outstanding to <mark type="ph" /> unheard (2:52) the entire utility industry at least.</p>
          <p>We are now determined to reduce our controllable costs to defined amount of &#x20AC;9.5 billion in 2015 at the latest. This corresponds to a reduction of &#x20AC;1.5 additional billion relative to the level of 2011 or nominal terms even more if inflation is taken into account. The resulting cost reduction could affect 9,000 to 11,000 jobs and will most likely affect those.</p>
          <p>Cost and performance measures are the necessary self-helping mechanism in the market environment. They are, however, not an end in themselves. We are building a better and faster company to control our own destiny in future and to be able to position ourselves in the most attractive segments to generate future earnings growth.</p>
          <p>Since the last Capital Market Day, we have made significant progress in transforming our European portfolio and to focus on our best assets. We have to dispose of assets worth more than &#x20AC;9 billion and have, therefore, regained our balance sheet flexibility by reducing financial net debt by around &#x20AC;14 billion in the last 12 months. And I like to reinforce that we almost have half of financial net debt in just a year.</p>
          <p>Despite the significant headwinds, I remain absolutely convinced about the entire industry. Energy will stay the core element of economic development, which makes it one of the few sustainable long-term growth businesses. At the same time, hardly any other industry needs now to change more rapidly in order to adapt to the new political realities, the new technologies, the changing competition and different customer demands.</p>
          <p>Traditional value pools will decline and possibly not return but, at the same time, new opportunities will arise. Europe is still heading for a very capital-intensive transformation of its entire energy system while showing limited underlying demand growth alongside ample supplier. Therefore, we redirected even greater share of our resources towards new value pools such as renewables and decentralized energy around customer demands.</p>
          <p>Outside Europe, demand continues to grow strongly and the regulatory environment is more welcoming. Expanding our presence outside Europe to capture these new opportunities is a natural, is almost necessary to easy development for E.ON. All this fits well with the strategy that we presented to you last November. We, therefore, despite the tough times today, see no need to change direction but we do need to run our businesses even harder, much harder.</p>
          <p>Marcus will go in detail to the financials of this year and later years later on. From our perspective, to make it very clear, 2011 earnings are absolutely unacceptable. Our loss in the second quarter has significantly reduced profits for the full year is not what E.ON stands for. However, given that in the first half, we suffer from around &#x20AC;1.9 billion of nuclear effects with an adjusted <mark type="ph" /> EBITDAR (6:30) that are beyond our control. There's a limit to we can do in the short term.</p>
          <p>In the midterm, next to a challenging marketplace, we are furthermore faced with an ongoing reduction of our German nuclear fleet resulting in a foreseeable loss of earnings that we have originally anticipated in the last year.</p>
          <p>Accordingly, we see an even greater need now to work out self-help mechanisms, but also had to reduce our dividend commitment once more. This has surely not been done lightly. The payout ratios in 2010 and, even more so for the fiscal year 2011, however,  are clear signals that even in such tough times as nuclear faces in Germany, we pay utmost attention to our owners. 2011 will mark the earnings trough for E.ON. Thereafter, EBITDA shows steady increase, opening room for the dividend to follow later.</p>
          <p>Let me now discuss the operating environment for E.ON as we see it. We observed numerous political interventions in all European markets. In Germany, however, we now at least have clear visibility from the government on the future of nuclear power. Around 8 gigawatts were shut down immediately. 12 gigawatts will follow according to a set time line until 2022.</p>
          <p>While disruptive for nuclear operators, it does not yet fundamentally alter the supply/demand balance. Compared to 96 gigawatts of reliable capacity available in Germany, 8 gigawatts looks a lot. However, compared to the 250 gigawatts of reliable available capacity in Germany, France and the Benelux, that figure looks much less significant and actually is.</p>
          <p>But what about the 38 gigawatts of old conventional capacity that might be shut down in Europe in the coming years, you might say? They will have an influence. But in Germany, France and the Benelux, for example, we see 18 gigawatts of new conventional capacity and 27 gigawatts of unpredictable renewable capacity coming to the markets over the next four years.</p>
          <p>So there is a reduction of reliable capacity, but not as much as one would like to see. This will more than compensate for the 12 gigawatts of old capacity that we expect to exit those markets over the same period.</p>
          <p>Accordingly, the price and spread reaction was limited so far, and currently, no new build signals are visible in the Central European or any other main market. In such a challenging environment, E.ON will behave in an economically rational way and will evaluate all investments on a case-by-case basis within the portfolio context.</p>
          <p>In France, we have concluded now that roughly 1,100 megahertz of our 2,300 megahertz of old coal capacity will have to be shut down, starting from 2013, as they have become uneconomic due to the difficult regulatory and market environment.</p>
          <p>By contrast, however, renewable continued to benefit from a lot of tailwind. While we have seen cuts and claw-backs to renewable subsidies, the underlying rationale is not a reduction in general political support, but a rapid fall of costs. Both reduced costs alongside overly favorable subsidies led to temporary investment excesses, and authorities were right to weed them out.</p>
          <p>E.ON is wholeheartedly participating in the transformation of our power system towards renewable generation. We are already one of the largest renewable players worldwide and have become an <mark type="indiscernible" /> (10:28) leader in offshore wind. We maintain our preference for developing and investing in cost-effective, industrial-scale renewables whether wind, solar or biomass.</p>
          <p>The system transformation that Europe and, especially Germany, has embarked upon is capital intensive and generally unproven, but we see new value pools emerging. For example, around decentralized energy solutions.</p>
          <p>In Germany, decentralized renewable generations such as solar, photovoltaic and small-scale wind has grown from less than 2% of total power generation in 2000 to almost 12% last year. In the U.K., we expect the share of decentralized power capacity to grow from 4% in 2010 to about 1/5 in 2035, with Micro-CHP taking the lion's share of growth for its account.</p>
          <p>However, currently, each of the new products is marketed on their own merits, without a comprehensive view of the needs of the customers. It only makes limited sense, for example, to invest in superefficient heating if you're building a highly insulated house. Therefore, we see a growing demand for providing integrated solutions in the area of decentralized energy.</p>
          <p>This includes services such as advising energy efficiency, offering smart home solutions, which would bring together home automations, smart metering, decentralized generation and storage services. Services around immobility, which would be a big power consumer for a household, also fits into the picture.</p>
          <p>The challenge for us is to find the right business model in this area. We're not going to transform ourselves into big installer of solar panels, for example. But across all our regional units, we are working on ways to leverage our 26 million European customer base to generate additional new value from decentralized energy and transfer some of the learning to markets even outside Europe.</p>
          <p>Moving to the global picture, it looks quite different. There, also, renewable generation is on the rise, but there is still a very significant demand for conventional <mark type="ph" /> power (12:50) generation capacity.</p>
          <p>Power markets in the most emerging countries are still immature; therefore, significant growth of power demand is expected and large investments in power generation will be needed. Clearly, these investments will only come to those countries which allow investors to see an adequate return on their capital. While there's also downside potential to the growth dynamics expected for those countries in case the global economy falters, even a reduced GDP profile would still result in power demand significantly exceeding the growth in advanced economies.</p>
          <p>With this environment in mind, we have asked ourselves whether the strategy announced back in November is still adequate. I can confirm that we have no doubt that we're on the right track. First, we do not see ourselves anymore as a fully integrated utility in any market. Instead, we only focus on those parts of the value chain where we can create the most value.</p>
          <p>We believe that this are those parts of the value chain where we can make a difference through our own skills and efforts and harvest capabilities. These are all the businesses open to competition and scale and those stable business where we are not forced to invest, such as renewables.</p>
          <p>To be clear, this does not mean that we will sell every infrastructure network or regulated activity. Instead, we will carefully balance the stabilizing contribution of individual assets to the overall portfolio on the one side with a cash flow consumption and overall value contribution on the other side.</p>
          <p>Second, due to fundamentally different long-term outlooks, we will continue to expand on non-European operations. We will do this based on our successful entries into the Russian power market and our U.S. renewable business. And we will execute with utmost care under no time pressure. We will rather accept earnings dilution than value destruction.</p>
          <p>Third, we have a fundamental belief that an outstanding performance culture is vital key to beat the competition and to secure a profitable future and also to count on the ongoing support of our owners.</p>
          <p>Fourth, capital is a scarce and valuable resource and, therefore, we need to apply it in an even smarter and more diligent way than we have done in the past. So what have we done since the Capital Market Day? Is it just words or action? We have exited, noncore business worth more than &#x20AC;9 billion. We have, thereby, reduced debt, and from now on further disposal proceeds are available for profitable redeployment in our focus areas.</p>
          <p>The expansion outside Europe is underway, priority regions are defined and our teams are working in the respective countries. Contributions from our U.S. renewable business and from Russia, including Yuzhno Russkoye, will help to expand the share of the non-EU EBITDA, to &#x20AC;1.7 billion to &#x20AC;2 billion in 2015. Value contribution comes first and, accordingly, we have consciously softened the previous targets to a vision of 25% contribution to total EBITDA by 2015, plus.</p>
          <p>We're also working on specific transactions illustrating our less capital, more value approach. Put differently: moving from a pure design build owned model to a designed build partially monetized and reinvest model. Portfolios with existing wind assets have been created, and we are currently testing the environment to see whether there is an opportunity to bring in external investors at effective terms while continuing to operate and maintain the assets. Resulting proceeds would then be reinvested thus increasing capital velocity and allowing us to participate in those stages of the life cycle where we can add most value with our capabilities while allowing other inventors to benefit from stable returns once commissioned.</p>
          <p>With respect to performance, we have to create targets to increase efficiency, transparency and control and to become top quartile in all businesses and processes. Since January, we have put in place a new functional setup and reporting of the group. During the course of the year, the improvement program, Perform-to-win, will come to a successful conclusion.</p>
          <p>We targeted for Perform-to-win to improve adjusted EBITDA by &#x20AC;1.5 billion over three years, and we are fully on track to deliver this as planned. Nevertheless, Perform-to-win, as well as the additional &#x20AC;600 million communicated back in November, are not expected yet to lead to a sustainable cost base.</p>
          <p>Since expected profitability has changed, a performance culture means that we now need to reduce costs even further. Based upon a series of benchmarking initiatives and stringent KPI-based steering. We have now set ourselves a goal to achieve the control of the cost base for these businesses we entertain not exceeding &#x20AC;9.5 billion by 2015 at the latest.</p>
          <p>This comes on top of all previously announced measures, such as Perform-to-win and the additional &#x20AC;600 million, with <mark type="ph" /> a letter factually (18:38) only offsetting inflation. It is also a reflection of our new performance culture. Rather than implementing fixed programs with well-sounding titles, we were flexible to changing market circumstances and to changes in the expected profitability.</p>
          <p>We will now investigate and implement swiftly a significant simplification of our legal and governance structures, especially in our German home market, an optimization of gas trading and support functions in Germany generation and a group-wide streamlining of administration functions. Overall, all those changes could affect 9,000 to 11,000 jobs. To make it clear, this is not business as we are disposing of. This is 9,000 to 11,000 less people in the same businesses. This is drastic, but we are convinced that we need to reengineer the way we operate.</p>
          <p>Disruptive political interference, challenging market environments and expectations by the capital markets make this unprecedented target unavoidable and necessary. The benefits of the described preliminary results do, however, go beyond the pure lowering of cost by avoiding duplication by focusing on pure necessities in the businesses.</p>
          <p>We hope also to become more agile allowing us to position ourselves at the forefront of this changing environment. We want to be transparent in the execution and will, therefore, update you every year where our control with cost base stands. If there are changes in scope, we will adjust for those but we're not losing our ambition level. Before I hand over to Marcus for the financial part, let me summarize where we stand today.</p>
          <p>Ten months have passed since we presented the strategy. We have already made very good progress in delivering the corresponding objectives. We executed &#x20AC;9 billion of disposals. We regained balance sheet flexibility and restored our balance sheet. So other than other parties, we don't see any need to <mark type="ph" /> for rights (20:53) issue anything.</p>
          <p>The expansion outside Europe is underway and today we have announced preliminary results for significant further efficiency improvements and these thoughts will be implemented, which should enable us to return to more healthy levels of profitability and position our portfolio for new growth opportunities.</p>
          <p>So first now, Marcus, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon also from my side.</p>
          <p>Johannes has basically just outlined that our strategy remains valid. However, the changes that we have seen in the markets, as well as on the political front, are surely affecting our half-year numbers and also the medium-term targets. 2011 is going to be a truly awful year, and this is predominately due to a &#x20AC;2.5 billion burden on adjusted EBITDA related to the nuclear exit decision in Germany. They're up around &#x20AC;1.5 billion of one-off charges, &#x20AC;0.6 billion of nuclear tax and &#x20AC;0.4 billion of foregone margin.</p>
          <p>In the medium-term, we need the additional described efficiency measures to return to an acceptable profitability path.</p>
          <p>In evaluating our revised targets, please keep in mind that both 2011 and 2013 are on an achieved disposal basis. That means we exclude, in particular, central networks and the Italian gas distribution grids. While the <mark type="ph" /> new (22:32) number we are giving you for 2015 is on what you could call on a fully diluted basis, i.e., excluding the entire loss also from the outstanding disposals of around &#x20AC;6 billion; &#x20AC;6 billion obviously not being the EBITDA loss but the expected disposal proceeds that will allow us then to complete the &#x20AC;15 billion program. We expect the additional EBITDA loss to be at around &#x20AC;0.8 billion.</p>
          <p>The implied debt factor in 2015 however, will then allow us to reinvest, as Johannes already said, the coming disposal proceeds into our described focus segments and regions which should also add earnings to that 2015 target that we're giving you.</p>
          <p>Let me now summarize the 2011 first-half results. There's an additional presentation that we've made available to you which goes through all those numbers in greater detail as you are used to from our normal quarterly reporting.</p>
          <p>Adjusted EBITDA is down &#x20AC;3.5 billion or 45% to &#x20AC;4.3 billion compared to the first half of 2010. A good part of this strong decline can be explained by the nuclear phase out; &#x20AC;0.2 billion due to the introduction of the nuclear tax, in addition &#x20AC;0.2 billion of foregone margin due to the moratorium and then plus an enormous &#x20AC;1.5 billion charge related to the disorderly shutdown, much higher than we had originally anticipated. That is a total burden of &#x20AC;1.9 million in the first half year due to these nuclear effects alone.</p>
          <p>In addition, we have two negative developments that we discussed before;  fall of around &#x20AC;1 billion in gas supply and sales and about &#x20AC;0.3 billion due the decline of achieved power prices. The strong decline of adjusted EBITDA feeds almost one for one into adjusted EBIT, which is down 61% and further down into adjusted net income, which is now down 71%. On the positive side, we have made further progress in reducing our economic net debt. Between June 2010 and June 2011, we have reduced our net financial debt from slightly more than &#x20AC;30 billion to &#x20AC;16.5 billion. In the second quarter, divestments, especially Central Networks, reduced net debt by another &#x20AC;5.2 billion. Provisions remained constant, at a level of around &#x20AC;17 billion.</p>
          <p>I would now like to explain in more detail how Germany's decision to exit nuclear energy impacts our financials starting with the first-half effect and then I'll come to the full year.</p>
          <p>The one-off effect included in adjusted EBITDA amounting to &#x20AC;1.5 billion are equivalent in the first half and in the full year 2011, and there are essentially four elements. &#x20AC;0.2 billion of write-down of nuclear fuel and spare parts at the two power plants operated by us, namely Isar 1 and Unterweser, &#x20AC;0.3 billion for additions to the nuclear provisions at those two power plants, &#x20AC;0.4 billion for additions to other provisions at Isar 1 and Unterweser. Those actually refer mainly to penalty payments with subcontractors started but not yet finished, investment projects and certain CapEx that was still underway.</p>
          <p>And then there is &#x20AC;0.6 billion for additions to other provisions with regards to the two power plants operated by Vattenfall, Brunsb&#xFC;ttel and Kr&#xFC;mmel. Both of those we consolidate at equity. In addition, we have &#x20AC;0.2 billion of one-off effect below EBITDA. The change in depreciation due to the write-down of fixed assets in use, which is about &#x20AC;100 million, is offset by the reversal of the interest charge related to the renewable energy fund which, you may recall, we had to book in Q4 of last year.</p>
          <p>In addition, there are &#x20AC;0.2 billion of non-operating earnings driven by impairments; about half for our two owned plants, and then about the other half for the equity value that we have in our books for Brunsb&#xFC;ttel and Kr&#xFC;mmel As I have just outlined, the one-off effects, I can now focus on the recurring elements in the years 2011 through to 2013.</p>
          <p>We lose 3.2 gigawatt of nuclear capacity, although out of a total of 8.6 gigawatts, roughly 1.3 gigawatt for Unterweser, 0.9 Isar 1, 0.7 for our stake in Kr&#xFC;mmel and 250 megawatts for our third stake in Brunsb&#xFC;ttel. However, Kr&#xFC;mmel and Brunsb&#xFC;ttel were expected to operate during the course of 2011. Therefore the loss of output is proportionally lower than the loss of capacity. We lose 12 terawatt hours in 2011 and about 23 terawatt hours in the years 12 and 13.</p>
          <p>You can see in the package we gave you for the first half year results that our hedge ratios for outright power has gone up strongly. This is not because we have hedged more. It's simply that by now we have excluded the nuclear output from Isar 1, Unterweser and Kr&#xFC;mmel from the denominator; either 100% has declined.</p>
          <p>For the loss volume, we lose revenues. We save, obviously, the variable cost. We also do not charge the fixed cost because that is now provisioned for and we avoid the fuel tax related to those power plants. In the short term, we had already sold forward almost all the outright power for 2011 and '12. As a result, we either have to produce from other plants or buy power on the market at a higher cost to fulfill our delivery obligations. Hence, the effect on adjusted EBITDA is slightly more negative than if we had not sold forward and only lost the production.</p>
          <p>In total, this results in a net recurring effect; net in the sense that we include the fact that we don't have to pay the nuclear tax of &#x20AC;0.4 billion in 2011 and then, for the coming two years, it's &#x20AC;200  million to &#x20AC;300 million negative.</p>
          <p>Let me now discuss the outlook for the full year 2011 adjusted EBITDA.</p>
          <p>Compared to the outlook we communicated in May, we have two negative effects related to the nuclear phase-out. As of the first quarter, the 2011 outlook already included &#x20AC;0.2 billion of foregone margin due to the nuclear moratorium, which you will remember.</p>
          <p>As discussed, the full year effect is expected to be &#x20AC;0.4 billion, i.e., &#x20AC;0.2 billion higher. This includes the avoided nuclear tax at Unterweser. And of course we have to take the 1.5 of the nuclear one-off effect into accounts. Note that these one-off costs are EBITDA effective but do not have an immediate cash impact.</p>
          <p>The other changes to the outlook are relatively limited, first regarding gas midstream. We have started arbitration proceedings with Gazprom, the possibility foreseen in the long-term contracts, when a commercial agreement is not reached in due time. However, we expect to continue commercial discussion in parallel to the arbitration proceedings.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, we have made further progress in our negotiations with other producers. So far, we have renegotiated more than 1/3 of the supply volumes and improvement relative to the 25% that we have previously communicated. Therefore, we now expect supply and sales to post a slightly lower loss than the &#x20AC;1 billion that we have communicated so far. However, this will be compensated by gas upstream and start of production for the Skarv field will be delayed by a couple of months.</p>
          <p>All in all, we are lowering our outlook for 2011 adjusted EBITDA by about &#x20AC;1.6 billion from a range of &#x20AC;10.7 billion to &#x20AC;11.4 billion to now a range of &#x20AC;9.1 billion to &#x20AC;9.8 billion. We also lower our outlook for 2011 adjusted net income from previously &#x20AC;3 billion to &#x20AC;3.7 billion, to now &#x20AC;2.1 billion to &#x20AC;2.6 billion, and then translated into adjusted EPS from &#x20AC;1.6 billion to &#x20AC;1.9 billion, now down to &#x20AC;1.1 billion to &#x20AC;1.4 billion per share.</p>
          <p>Let me now move over to the 2013 adjusted EBITDA targets. First, we need to adjust the more than &#x20AC;13 billion starting points for the more than &#x20AC;9 billion of disposals that we have realized since the Capital Market Day in November of last year. With about &#x20AC;900 million, this is the single biggest change to the 2013 adjusted EBITDA targets.</p>
          <p>Next, we have the impacts of the nuclear exit. Net of nuclear tax and considering slightly increased wholesale prices, this is about the aforementioned minus &#x20AC;0.2 billion to minus &#x20AC;0.3 billion in 2013. Still on the negative side, we have a series of effects which generally reflect the worsening conditions of our sector and the slower-than-expected economic recovery.</p>
          <p>While each single effect is not material, the total sum of those is almost &#x20AC;1 billion. Just a few examples, and you will see some of them or maybe more, a timing effect. We have delays due to the startup of the coal-fired new build <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:09) plants, partially due to permitting issues.</p>
          <p>We also have delays to the Livorno LNG terminal. There's a clear deterioration of the overall outlook for our generation activities in both Italy and Spain, given the economies there are not recovering. There are several negative regulatory developments in Eastern Europe and, most recently, we've also seen one in Russia.</p>
          <p>On the positive side, we observed slightly increased commodity prices relative to our assumptions that we communicated at the Capital Market Day in November last year. With respect to the additional performance measures outlined by Johannes, our preliminary targets are for about 50% of the targeted improvements of around &#x20AC;1.5 million to contribute already in 2013 to the EBITDA number. Overall, we are conscious of the fact that was a new headline target range of &#x20AC;11.6 billion to &#x20AC;12.3 billion, should be in line with your expectations, the earnings contributed underneath that are different.</p>
          <p>Lower results in our operations due to poorer market circumstances will be offset by the increased performance measures. Note, also, that there have been no change to our expectations for global gas supply and sales. Here, we continue to assume a return to a normal level of earnings by the year 2013.</p>
          <p>Let me now briefly talk about CapEx. Our previous CapEx plan still included some amounts related to Central Networks and to some other businesses that we have divested now. Over the period 2011 to 2013, this has reduced CapEx by &#x20AC;1.4 billion. Against this, we have increased CapEx in other segments where we see attractive opportunities especially in renewables, that's the lion's share, and then, to some extent, in upstream oil and gas. Please remember that there is roughly an additional &#x20AC;6 billion of growth CapEx to come as further disposal proceeds will be reinvested.</p>
          <p>Let me now move to the mid-term outlook. Starting with the 2013 adjusted EBITDA, I will move down further in the P&amp;L to the bottom line. Compared to the Capital Market Day, the changes to our assumptions for depreciation net interest income reflect the &#x20AC;9 billion of disposals already carried out and the increase of CapEx.</p>
          <p>The assumed tax rate on adjusted pre-tax profit is between 26% and 30%. Please note that the effective tax rate in that year can be very different. This is a number which is very difficult to predict, but it should normally be in that range. Minorities are assumed to be at around &#x20AC;500 million. Adjusted net income would thus come out at between &#x20AC;3.2 billion and &#x20AC;3.7 billion, which would translate into adjusted EPS between &#x20AC;1.7 and &#x20AC;2 per share.</p>
          <p>We also want to give you an even longer term perspective by giving out a glance of some 2015 figures. Compared to 2013, the main drivers would be as follows. On the negative side, as I said earlier, further dilution to the full &#x20AC;15 billion of disposals instead of &#x20AC;9 billion achieve so far. In the numbers on the chart, we do not include any reinvestment returns out of those additional disposals.</p>
          <p>On the positive side, higher commodity prices is, unlike 2013, we have not sold forward volumes so far. More productive CapEx, for example, from those delays <mark type="indiscernible" /> (37:10) and Livorno, are coming online. And of course, the full impact of our new performance measures, as presented by Johannes, should support earnings in 2015.</p>
          <p>As a result, we are expecting an adjusted EBITDA between &#x20AC;12.5 billion and &#x20AC;13 billion in 2015. That translates into an adjusted EPS of &#x20AC;2 to &#x20AC;2.3 per share, once again including the total dilution effect, but not considering any additional reinvestments. The implied debt factor in that year will be below 2.5, which will give us the necessary strategic flexibility and room to invest around &#x20AC;6 billion, i.e. those additional proceeds that we expect from the additional disposals to be done.</p>
          <p>Finally now on dividends and dividend policy. We generally continue to see a payout ratio of 50% to 60% of adjusted net income as providing an appropriate balance between, on the one hand, shareholder remuneration and capital discipline on the other side and financial means to provide further growth on the other side. It is clear, however, that adjusted net income will be abnormally low in 2011, in particular, given the one-off effect. Therefore, we have taken 2013 as a more appropriate reference point in our thinking about dividends.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, we do not want to set dividends for 2011 or 2012 at levels which might not be sustainable afterwards. Given the deterioration E.ON's economic environment, the minimum dividend of &#x20AC;1.30 per share that we had previously announced for 2011 and 2012, does not satisfy these criteria. Even in 2013, the payout ratio would have been between 65% and 75%. As we always want to provide an attractive financial profile in the long run, we considered that range to be too high.</p>
          <p>We have concluded that a dividend of minimum &#x20AC;1.1 is appropriate for 2013. This would correspond to a payout ratio 55% to 65%, which would still be on the high end of our target range but adequate due to the balance the aforementioned elements. For the two years before, we suggest or we would propose following &#x20AC;1.00 per share for 2011 and &#x20AC;1.10 for the fiscal year 2012.</p>
          <p>That completes my part on the financial update and the outlook, and I will hand over now once again to Johannes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Marcus.</p>
          <p>He has shown you the expected financial development. I would now like to explain where those numbers come from and, more generally, how you should think about the E.ON equity story in the years to come.</p>
          <p>Our ambition is far reaching and stays far reaching. We want to transform E.ON from a portfolio of European national utilities into a global energy solutions provider. While every one of you might be convinced at first sight, for some the vision is too abstract; for some it sounds like a risky venture.</p>
          <p>Please remember, that only a little more than 10 years ago, E.ON or its predecessor companies used to be predominantly a national utility or collection of conglomerates. In a relatively short time span, we have then developed into a European energy utility. We are now growing the next steps, focusing on only selected energy solutions and focusing on promising growth markets. This will result in full benefits.</p>
          <p>First, a more balanced geographic business mix. Already by 2013, Germany will account for less than 50% of our EBITDA. In the years thereafter, the share will decline further as our existing businesses like Russia will grow faster, and a higher share of additional growth CapEx will be invested into our focus areas. This overall reduces the dependency on any single jurisdiction, while still offering synergies if operations are run from single platforms and not from multiple independent national solutions.</p>
          <p>The second benefit, a reduction in carbon emissions giving proof to our cleaner and better energy heading. In Europe, the sale of renewables in our power generation fuel mix will more than double to above 20% by 2020. The carbon intensity, however, will slightly increase from today's levels as the share of nuclear production declines. We are, however, still financially long CO2. Every euro increase in the CO2 price results in a net benefits to E.ON.</p>
          <p>Third benefit, a change in the risk and return composition to what businesses that we can influence, while paying attention to a balanced risk contribution. Traditional regulatory activities will be declining; however, stable, non-regulated activities are increasing. Here, I'm referring to non-merchant renewable businesses for earning streams dominated by capacity payments, like in Russia.</p>
          <p>Overall, we want to increase the contribution of those businesses. But we can make a difference through our own efforts and our own capabilities without significantly altering the group's risk exposure. Finally, new earnings growth drivers, other than German nuclear or gas midstream, will increasing the shape of E.ON story, and I will quickly discuss a sample of those on the remaining slides.</p>
          <p>Renewables are a key examples of such an earnings contributor. From less than 4.4 gigawatts in 2007, E.ON's renewables, capacity has grown our operational investments to 3.6 gigawatts at the end of last year. On the basis of our current investment plan, capacity will surpass the 5 gigawatt mark by 2013.</p>
          <p>This figure could be further topped by reinvestments on the remaining &#x20AC;6 billion of disposable proceeds. In 2013, renewables are expected to contribute &#x20AC;1.2 to &#x20AC;1.6 billion of adjusted EBITDA. We have superior expertise in all key technologies. Next to long-standing hydro experience, we are especially proud of our onshore and offshore wind know-how.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., which forms part of our <mark type="indiscernible" /> (44:03) emissions, we are progressing towards achieving our goal of an availability of more than 98%. The load factor remains at high levels; almost 30% last year and even 37% in the first half of 2011.</p>
          <p>Russia is another existing operation that forms part of our non-EU business. It has delivered a strong result in 2010, and we expect this development to continue. The capacity framework, together with the free energy market, is clearly a system which is supportive for our investments.</p>
          <p>For older plants, the capacity fees cover the fixed cost, a significant improvement on the prior situation for efficient capacities. But for the plants built since 2007, the capacity fees do not only cover fixed costs, but also the full capital costs, including an adequate return on investment. In this attractive environment, we continue to increase our power generation capacity.</p>
          <p>In November last year, we had commissioned the 400 megawatt Surgutskaya CCGT. In July, Prime Minister Putin officially commissioned <mark type="indiscernible" /> (45:12) to get a 800 CCGT at Surgutskaya in Western Siberia. Furthermore, we are about to commission the last CCGT of our current Russian new built program, the 400 megawatt Yajviskaya. That leaves an only the 800 megawatt the Surgutskaya coal-fired plant to be built, a project that we have started and plan to complete by the end of 2014.</p>
          <p>All these new units will benefit from the favorable capacity fees granted to new builds which, as I said, not only cover fixed costs but provide a remuneration of the invested capital based on an assumed ROC of 13% over 15 years. We have also kept both fuel and non-fuel costs strongly in check. Together with continuous optimization efforts, this has further improved our already strong position in the merit order.</p>
          <p>Finally, wholesale power prices on the energy market are expected to increase due to economic growth. As our fleet is one of the best positioned in the Russian merit order, we should benefit from this development disproportionately. As a result, we expect a further strong increase of adjusted EBITDA from &#x20AC;377 million in 2010 to between &#x20AC;500 million and &#x20AC;700 in 2011. For 2013, the target range of &#x20AC;800 million to &#x20AC;1 billion is unchanged.</p>
          <p>Finally, a few remarks on global gas. This business has been in the focus of the analyst community in the last 24 months. However, 90% of the time of all our discussions has been spent on the sub-segment supply and sales. This is understandable in light of the significant earning swings that we have to report due to the ongoing renegotiations. But if you give us the benefit of doubt and look at the earnings contribution on a normalized basis, then supply and sales is actually insignificant relative to the earnings we expect in our E&amp;P business.</p>
          <p>Upstream oil and gas is not without risk. Quite the contrary. Therefore, we apply adequate hurdle rates when taking investment decisions. Based upon a solid improvement track record, we follow the strategy of an intelligent niche player. This means that we do not compete with the oil majors but rather pursue selective opportunities in the limited number of defined regions.</p>
          <p>Today, we operate 14 out of our 53 exploration licensees, three of our six ongoing developments and four out of our 12 producing fields. Our upstream production would have multiplied by six between 2007 and 2013, an impressive development I think. It has already reached levels comparable to other utility players which have been active for much longer in this business. The contribution of the gas upstream business to adjusted EBITDA is also set to rise strongly. From &#x20AC;700 million last year, it should reach &#x20AC;1.7 billion to &#x20AC;2.1 billion in 2013.</p>
          <p>Let me summarize before going to Q&amp;A. In our journey on the E.ON ship, we cannot influence the seas. We have no control of the weather. But what we can control is the course that we take and, most important, building the best possible ship. The degree of headwinds in the current economic and political climate does mean that we need to significantly increase the pace of transformation, especially on the cost side.</p>
          <p>With respect to our disposal program, we have already done very well securing a robust balance sheet. We at E.ON have no need for rescue rights issues. But instead, we want to continue to shape the future of our own means and skills.</p>
          <p>At the end of this transformation, we will have a better and faster ship, higher quality earnings, i.e. earnings driven by factors that we control, and an attractive risk return profile that balances growth opportunities with shareholder remuneration requirements.</p>
          <p>And now, let us take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Johannes. We're indeed going to the Q&amp;A session now. As described at the beginning, what we'll do is we take the first round of questions in the room and we take a quick short breath and I will take a few questions that we have received via the web and then we go back to the room.</p>
          <p>And we start with the two good-looking gentleman in the front, Vincent Gilles and Patrick. So, Vincent, you start, and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you said good looking, I had to do it before Patrick, obviously. I'm sorry, I'm trying to keep it a bit light as I look at your share price in the last 20 minutes and I'm very surprised to see what's happening.</p>
          <p>Can I ask three questions, please? And I'm sure the questions would go around the same things this afternoon. Could we come back to the cost-cutting program, and I'm trying to understand, I do understand you can't give us full details, but a bit where you are going to cut? Is it at the head of the divisions? Are you going to bring all the divisions back under your supervision in an effort to implement all your cost cutting? How much of the cost cutting do you think you're going able to keep in the future and how much of that is actually in the earnings estimates you gave us? I think that's my first question, so I can call that one question.</p>
          <p>The second one is on all the nuclear numbers you kindly gave us, how much of that do you think you could get as compensation from the government at some stage? And I'm not asking you for when you get a compensation because it's obviously an open question.</p>
          <p>And question number three is on the dividend. Given you sold very large amounts of numbers of pretty good multiples, why did you decide to go down so much on the dividend given your balance sheet is not at risk as you rightly said you don't need the right issue? Why didn't you try to keep it slightly higher? What I'm trying to get to here is the thinking behind it in terms of short term versus long term. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Try to remember all the questions. Usually it's always two, so I can pick one to leave it out.</p>
          <p>Now the dividend increase, I think, please keep in mind, that we had to strike a quite delicate balance between interest of all stakeholders. I don't recall any program, definitely not from a German, but I don't recall a program from a European utility, where one has proactively decided to, in a short time, take more than 10,000 jobs possibly out. And I think doing that one needs to strike a balance so we can communicate, we can implement it, with support of our people that shareholders' interest and employees' interest are sort of balanced and not one overweighed over the others.</p>
          <p>We know that our owners pay a high price already on the share price. But you also are aware that in the German environment, if you want to be successful and fast, this balance is delicate and necessarily. So that was definitely involved in our decision. But we also believe that, looking on the significant one-offs of the nuclear side and on the significant ongoing burden of the nuclear side, the balance we found is fundamentally fair.</p>
          <p>From the cost-cutting, first of all, our deep belief is that everything we achieve here should be available for the benefit of the group and our owners. So it will focus, not on regulated as is where it just <mark type="ph" /> springs through (53:28). It doesn't say that there might not be also an efficiency effort on the regulated side. But we will focus on those that we can harvest the returns. There will be definitely a very, very higher focus on overhead admin, supposed to also be supported by structural changes.</p>
          <p>I think it has been discussed by you and in the media, but specifically in Germany, we are the result of always increasing empire, where we have the quiet former independent groups with their own headquarters, and a lot of those have never been really redefined or questioned. And, for example, we believe it to be possible to bring all gas and power and all commodity trading finally under one roof. It has been still divided between E. ON Ruhrgas and E. ON Energy Trading. That should now go.</p>
          <p>Or I think we are, by tradition, the only of the major utilities that has a German national subsidiary for operating its German businesses. I don't recall that Enel has a subsidiary for Italy, or Ilya for France, but by definition, because we came into existence as a financial conglomerate and had a subsidiary, we still we had it. We will now bring those together because, in the end, the German stakeholders need to be approached once and not twice.</p>
          <p>And then we also have quite a significant administration burden around and above our generation businesses that just needs to be minimized and brought together so that <mark type="indiscernible" /> (55:18) can operate all costs around it, and minimize all costs around it, <mark type="ph" /> not finally (55:22) from one control spot. And those are examples for the issues we take there.</p>
          <p>There was one question on nuclear. What was that? How much we get back from the government? Whatever we can. [laughter] But there's two portions, I would say.</p>
          <p>One, as Marcus pointed out, there's a nuclear tax. We have filed legal complaints against each and every tax payment. So if we are successful on that, we should get every penny back with interest.</p>
          <p>And I would assume that all the one-off effects that amounted to &#x20AC;1.5 billion roughly, they are all subject to the, I would say, unnecessary, expediated and unconstitutional way the phase-out was done. And we will reclaim, to the best that I can see today, pretty much all and everything of that. Again, if we win it then in court is the second thing. But we will fight for every dime there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But the situation on the cost-cutting, it is included the &#x20AC;1.5 billion in the earnings estimated there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the 2015, it's fully included. In the 2013, half of that is roughly included. In the 2015, all of it is included. And all of that is effective, meaning that it's not flowing out to other things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I would have questions on two topics, please. First one, the gas business that we just touched marginally upon so far. Can you give us your latest take on where you stand in terms of the renegotiations? I've seen earlier today you said that you have now renegotiated roughly 1/3 of your contracts. To which extent that is fixed structurally or to which extent it's just fixed for a year through a price reduction.</p>
          <p>And would you be in a position to say that 2012 won't be worse than '11 in the gas wholesale business, i.e., would you feel confident to say that losses will not go up further from the current &#x20AC;1 billion level or slightly below &#x20AC;1 billion?</p>
          <p>And in the 2013 guidance, I understand that basically you still assume that you're going to be back to slight profit in 2013. What makes you so confident? I mean, you've, so far, yeah, probably not reached what you wanted to have by now. Arbitration is still ongoing and could take another two years or even longer. So why have you kept the gas guidance for 2013 unchanged?</p>
          <p>That's the first complex, and the second one is shorter, I promise. It's on the cost-cutting. Can you give us an idea about the restructuring effort that is behind? The &#x20AC;&#x20AC;1.5 billion sounds nice as a new run rate, but what is the one-off burden we should expect there and when will it be booked?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to the second one, I think more important than the &#x20AC;1.5 billion is that we target &#x20AC;9.5 billion of <mark type="ph" /> control the spend (58:38). Because in most industries, and admittedly with ourselves as well, all other programs will be accounted against otherwise-incurred spend. So it's always very difficult to follow what has really been saved.</p>
          <p>And therefore, we clearly decided at this time we target a clear cost base. And it could well be that it's more than &#x20AC;1.5 billion that we ought to save then, and the commitment is to undertake that effort.</p>
          <p>We don't have yet any calculation for one-off spent on that because, obviously, management has decided on the direction in a swift but rather direct way, without involving in a democratic manner the whole group. And, therefore, now we need to detail and then we need to consult, in some instances, with responsible workers' groups and whatever. And only then, after we have found a solution or decided unilaterally, then you can calculate what it really costs, and then we will take a one-time charge.</p>
          <p>But that is too premature. Just take it as a clear decision of this management that we will implement that. And we will not allow it to be voted down. And it will be done in the defined timeline.</p>
          <p>And Marcus, will you answer the gas questions as good you can?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, what gives us the comfort that 2013, we sort of stick to a normalized level?</p>
          <p>The main reason behind that is that, from a timing point of view, normally actually the arbitration proceedings should be done by then. That's what the contracts foresee. That's the key driver.</p>
          <p>That, quite frankly, also is the reason why at this stage, we're shying away from talking about 2012 because there's a lot that should then happen in 2012. And I think against that background, we prefer to talk about 2012 in the context of when we give the full year guidance. But the timing actually is such that, in a way, 2012 is the decisive year.</p>
          <p>Which would also imply that anything that is not yet settled will always look back into things that happens since 1 of October last year, which can &#x2013; I mean, it's very likely that there will be one year which will look a little bit peculiar. Because in our expectations, will mean that there will be some recovery from the past, which on the other hand, may make things look abnormally great. But I think, with regard to 2013, it's more prudent to target a normalized level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and in terms of the renegotiations that you have achieved so far, the 1/3 level, how does that split up into structural and quick fix?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You have all three components there. There are a few that really have already provided us a structural fix. The lion's share is actually two-year deals. And then I think there's also a smaller portion which, so far, only addresses the current year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But then have an element what would happen if there is no further compromise already implemented in that.</p>
          <p>And why do we keep to be fairly optimistic? First of all, some of these contracts provide for a very expediated arbitration process, literally drafted in the contract. It defines a very expediated fast track.</p>
          <p>Secondly, a quite significant number of those counterparties that have agreed with us have compromised very significantly, and none of them is, let's say, small counterparties. And we still believe it gives us very strong ammunition against the outstanding parties if we can show to the arbitration court who has agreed, in what proportion they have agreed, and why they have agreed.</p>
          <p>And lastly, one element that we don't underweigh is we have never lost in arbitration. All the clauses that we are testing now have been tested and have been used by arbitration courts in our favor. Therefore, we interpret, still, is the open game says more as timing games than content games. And we continue to work on those. And we also see an element of strong political support on our back in these renegotiations. That has been clearly emphasized.</p>
          <p>Other than that, obviously the timing effect, the timing, precise timing, one needs to have a crystal ball and precision there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And then I would propose that I'd take a couple of questions that we have received from the web, and then I'll go back to the room. What I'll do is I'll read out the questions that I have received. So Marcus and Johannes, don't hit me.</p>
          <p>But I'll start with a question that I have received from Benjamin Leyre from Exane BNP. He says that you are very advanced in the year. So what are the key elements of uncertainty that leads you to keep such a wide range of guidance for 2011 EPS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the second question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's the question. <mark type="ph" /> I'll repeat (1:04:53). So why such a wide range for 2011 EPS given that we are in August today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. What we experienced again this year is that in particular when you look at the tax rate, that is a difficult one to predict. We have a situation where we will see most likely delays in our production from the Skarv fields. That comes with a high tax burden, and actually that can have quite an impact on what the overall tax rate will be for the full year. And now it looks, quite frankly, like it will come out a little bit higher than what we &#x2013; sorry, a little bit lower than what we had thought at the beginning of the year. But given these things can change and given we do not yet know when the fleet will come back, we prefer to leave the range a little bit broader.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Benjamin has the second question, which I'm taking because I think it is &#x2013; it's a sensible question this market turmoil. He says, do you expect to be downgraded to A minus? Can you confirm that you have no financial covenants on existing debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On part B, yes, confirmed. And do I expect a downgrade? I would not want to speculate on that. I believe with regard to the credit watch, clearly this is something that would then be determined in the very near future. I don't want to speculate there. I think this is something that we will discuss in the coming two, three weeks of the agencies, and I prefer first have that debate and then come a view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously, rating agencies do what they deem necessary and right, but I would also point once again, if you compare our absolute level of financial net debt to other players in the industries, I think it's rather to the very low side. But rating agencies also take longer term provisions into account, which is financially right. But they don't need to be refinanced in the same manner as others.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I'm taking a question from Vincent De Blic from JPMorgan, a question that is surely interesting for the equity investors. He says, should we also assume 50% to 60% dividend payout from 2014 onwards?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer is yes. And then slightly bigger picture question, which I get from various people from Martin Young, Nomura, but also from Chris Kuplent, Bank of America. They ask can you provide a bit more detail on the international expansion? And then they go further. For example, can you discuss the hurdle rates for investments in those three priority regions India, Brazil, Turkey? So more details, international expansion, possibly hurdle rates?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Let me answer those. We got a question today in the press how we actually got to the markets, and actually when we presented this in our supervisory boards I think I started with a statement, this is in a way answering the question what other markets we'll be looking at. This is a no win answer that you give because either you come with something that looks quite obvious, and then people will say, well, why the heck did it take you so long? Or you come an answer that people will find intuitively surprising and wrong, and then they will just question whether you're insane or not. What we did is starting with the beginning of the year, we went initially through a very long list of about 200 countries/regions, which was purely a desktop exercise and very short time reduced that to 35.</p>
          <p>We had discussions on each of those 35 markets with local country experts, external people. We reduced it then to 10. For each of those 10 we had a one-day workshop to go through the markets, their growth prospects, the way our industry functions in those markets, opportunities where there's growth that you can really capture because some markets look great in terms of growth prospect. But then when you dig deeper, you find that it's very hard for anyone to excise it because it would just simply be handed out to local players. And then we ended up with a list of I would three plus two. And for those we then really sent teams for a period of four to six weeks into the region to have discussions with people on the ground to dig deeper. And that was then the basis for us taking a decision.</p>
          <p>Where do we stand now? We now have basically small teams. When I say small, this is a handful, setup for each of those markets. We are in discussions with people in those regions. I think we've explained in the past what the situations are that we are looking for, namely local partners that have a significant emphasis on pipeline, on new development, partners where we feel they have strong local ties, are financially sound. But like someone that can contribute on the technology side, on the operations side, which is what we bring to the party. And also have the situations which we are now currently exploring with regard to hurdle rates. That obviously differs a little bit by market, but we are looking at rates which are in the mid-teens that we want to achieve in those regions.</p>
          <p>We often then also because they don't have the chance to ask that question, get the question when can we see the first deal will be signed? We can't tell you. It may take some time. That is one of the reasons why Johannes has that we sort of &#x2013; we've not moved the target of 25% share in terms of contribution to EBITDA, but we've moved the goal post from a timing perspective, and made it a little bit flexible. Because we definitely think it is more prudent to take some time, and we've already turned down a few things that were very, very advanced because we think it is better to make sure that in particular the first transaction we do does make sense, fits the criteria that I have just communicated rather than say to ourselves, we now definitely have to show some success and then just run for the first opportunity. So I can't tell you when that will be case. It may take us well into next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I would actually go back for another round of questions in the room. So we'll just take it from here. First you and then Alex.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Alex Karnick, Deutsche Bank. Two questions around the capacity. Number one, what kind of a risk, and sort of what kind of execution do you see for something like a capacity payment or capacity incentive that's being discussed at the government level, the 15% of CapEx, I suppose? When is that coming through? Could that be potentially more? Any light you can share on that would be highly appreciated. And then secondly, you discussed your view of the reserve margin in Central Europe. You made some excurse to what you intend to close in France. But beside from that, when do you expect closures maybe to come soon and actually starting to materialize? And also what is your role in case of E.ON sort of aside from the French closures of that 18 gigawatts that you expect to leave the market until 2013? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the question, if I understood it right is, when will we see further capacity markets with capacity payments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The question is very, very detailed on Germany where the government is possibly discussing some capacity incentive or a CapEx incentive rather for smaller players?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. They are rather discussing at this point an investment scheme where they would provide for 15% of investment costs for smaller players. That has been notified, to my best understanding now in Brussels, and meets some objection there. And actually we are involved and also object because we don't see a legal basis for that. But to be honest and fair, if we would that get investment granted tomorrow morning, would we immediately buy the next shovel and start to work? Not really. At this point, the market is sufficiently supplied and even with a 15% investment scheme, I don't see big investments starting.</p>
          <p>That is also visible if you listen to some of the complaints of other market participants already saying nice to have, but what else there? We also see a capacity remuneration or something. The best of what I can hear in government circles and Berlin, they are far from agreeing to that. And therefore, I believe all these discussions are also quite virtual at this point. And I would not over emphasis the importance of those. Second was?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Basically when do you expect closure, since...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Closure...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And your role...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think one needs to understand that the question of closures is quite different from, let's say, the last phase of over capacity ten years ago. Because 10 years ago, it was just centralized production just retiring 10 gigawatts, 15 gigawatts  made the total distance to the markets. Today with these huge stake of renewables in the play, just the pure retirement of capacity doesn't change so much. We have a more energy play than a capacity play for quite some time, I believe. It is upon the efficiency of your plant and how much you can create value from the flexibility of the asset, cost position of the individual plant and flexibility of the plant that makes the difference. As I said, those rather old animals in France have for legal reasons would have had to be retired by 2015, don't make any sense to run as long. They are also very inflexible, and badly positioned in the curve. They'll be retired.</p>
          <p>Otherwise, we still decide on a case-by-case way, and we have not disclosure on early retirements of individual plants. But we continue to look through those, and we just announced individual retirements because we don't want to educate our competitors to prognose their way of running it.</p>
          <p>The capacity shortage that you have is predominant here in Frankfurt. Frankfurt is not probably a dangerous area if you need a lot of energy. The good regulator of Germany has now several times announced that the Greater Frankfurt area causes him the biggest trouble, and the most headaches. And then we have quite a shortage in Southern Germany.</p>
          <p>Therefore, I would probably not prognose too much thinking on retirement, if you're in the greater Frankfurt or Southern area where we have some, while the more Northern plants will earlier be visited.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Matthias Heck from Macquarie. Also on that chart on Page 5, where you expect an increase in the Germany, France, Benelux reserve margin. Could you run us through your assumptions on renewable load factors, and also on the timing of the existing plant projects which are coming up?</p>
          <p>Because we had a lot of news in the recent press about problems with the commissioning of new thermal generation plants, related to the T20 for steel and all that stuff. So do you assume all projects to come online well on time? And what renewable load factor do you anticipate? That's the first part.</p>
          <p>And second part of the question is should we interpret this chart as in the sense that you are very bearish on clean dark and spark spreads? And what else you included in your 2013, and '15 earnings expectations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On your second question, are we very bearish? Look, I think what we do is review what we've done in the past. We work on the basis of sort of where the markets sees prices.</p>
          <p>You have in the back half &#x2013; I think it's actually the very first chart &#x2013; you have the assumptions underlying our thinking. Some might argue that, and at some point in time, you in a way need to sort of cut when fixing those numbers. Some of those may even look a little bit outdated by now. For example, when you look at the CO2 price that we show there for 2013, what our assumption is. Obviously that number came down quite substantially in the past days.</p>
          <p>I think our message is that at least &#x2013; and probably there's the one exception that Johannes spoke about, which is the UK. For all the other markets, we think it is not prudent to assume that in a way markets will fix the problem, and prices will simply develop in a nice way, and here we go. That may or may not happen.</p>
          <p>I think what we are doing is we are just assuming where the market currently sees the prices. You have our assumptions. And our focus is then really to do those things that we can influence. We cannot influence where the spread is and the assumptions you have here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm still listening to the discussions in Brussels. There's still some likelihood, whatever percentage, that there will be change in the CO2 system, more a &#x2013; rather tighter CO2 target. That would then influence.</p>
          <p>But what we said, we are not gambling on external help. Our cost position needs to be adaptable even to the downturn, even to such rather low spreads on historical levels. So that's the game we take.</p>
          <p>On precise numbers that you ask for in Germany, for example, I would have a hard time. We now have, Eckhart, 18 gigawatts of solar panels. What is their load factor? They are running 800 to 1,000 hours a year. So if you calculate that level, I don't even know if it tells you anything, because it's more important to understand when those hours will be, and how they influence the peak and off-peak, and actually the amount of technology issues arising while we speak.</p>
          <p>Presently all these nice panels have the technical equipment that turns them off if you have &#x2013; if the hertz moves out to 50.2. So you could see a day when 10,000, 15,000 immediately shut themselves off in a second and then restart five minutes later. The system would not cope with it. So everybody gets now very nervous, understanding that the implied technology issues are significant.</p>
          <p>The load factors for German onshore wind 2,000, 2,500 hours. And offshore obviously higher, but the offshore is only starting to grow now, and it's not yet significant. So the load factors on those things are, on international levels, on the rather lower side. And that's why we picked and focused not on German onshore, because we still don't see a competitive situation for those animals compared to better investment situations.</p>
          <p>Steel question. Others &#x2013; obviously some of our competitors are earlier and more exposed to the steel issue, and we see significant progress on coping with the steel issue. I think our competitors in RWE have proven that if you do the commissioning of those plants in a very specific, technical manner, you can cope with the corrosion question. If you do it wrongly, then it's an issue.</p>
          <p>We have some time left, due to our other issues, where we can decide how to handle that. So we don't see any timing constraints for E.ON on this steel issue. Others are more exposed to that than we at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question <mark type="ph" /> Bertol (1:22:56), then Ingo, then Patrick and then I'll go back to the web.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you allow me to have two follow-up questions, please. The first one is on the further disposal of the sort of &#x20AC;6 billion &#x2013; let's round it up. You seem to imply a multiple of 7 times in a market where valuations seem to be getting lower and lower by the minute. I wouldn't say by the day.</p>
          <p>And so not being obsessed with the stock market, it's more for me trying to understand what type of visibility/certainty you may have on this disposal? And why &#x2013; maybe it's a bit difficult, but why are you committing so strongly to reinvestment when there is a very clear concern in the market in general about investment in the sector? So that's my first question or two questions disguised into one.</p>
          <p>And the second one is on the maintenance CapEx, I noticed from the chart that you have a slight decline in the maintenance CapEx, and I was wondering why &#x2013; unless I'm color blind &#x2013; I was wondering why? Is it because you have less gross CapEx in the next few years and therefore maintenance CapEx further down goes down? Are you getting more efficient in maintenance CapEx? I was just wondering why that was?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I take those questions. First of all, on your question with regard to further disposals, is the multiple high or low?</p>
          <p>There I would say this. Obviously, we have specific things in mind when we talk about this. It's not this is an abstract number. There are specific projects and this is simply our best estimate at this time. And I think in the past we &#x2013; so far, at least &#x2013; have seen that we weren't so wrong with our assumptions.</p>
          <p>When you say we are committing to reinvest, I don't think that's exactly what we're saying. We are showing you actually the numbers for 2015. The expression is probably incorrect, but as we called it, on a fully diluted basis, i.e. assuming there's no reinvestment, okay? That's the assumption behind that number.</p>
          <p>And all that we're saying is if we find attractive opportunities to invest &#x2013; and we gave you the areas where we think those will be or could be &#x2013; then there could be a bit upside to those numbers. Because we will obviously invest into something that then should produce earnings.</p>
          <p>So it's not that we're saying we're dead certain the &#x20AC;6 billion will get reinvested come hell or high water. And so maybe we weren't clear enough with the communication.</p>
          <p>With regard to maintenance, you're probably eyeballing that chart. I think the delta you are referring to is actually just the exclusion of those assets that have been disposed, which had a very high maintenance portion with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then I think next question was Ingo, and then Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. It's actually not a question, the first one, but on the chart Page 18, you were giving a 2015 EPS guidance, but no net income guidance. But you have ruled out the capital increase, so we just can multiply that figure by your current number of shares.</p>
          <p>Can you give us an update on the EU safety test? Where we are? What you expect to be the outcome? And also how confident you are that the current provision level for all kinds of decommissioning are appropriate? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I comment on the provision levels.</p>
          <p>Look, we are &#x2013; if we were not confident, I think we should have changed the number. So almost by definition, we are &#x2013; we feel comfortable with those numbers.</p>
          <p>And you've seen we took actually quite a severe hit in the first half of the year in terms of additional provisions. Not all of them, I think that's important to note, actually flow into the nuclear decommissioning provisions. There's only &#x20AC;300 million. But there's another &#x20AC;1 billion of other provisions that we book for &#x2013; &#x20AC;600 million for equipment in Brunsb&#xFC;ttel and &#x20AC;400 million for the two others.</p>
          <p>We &#x2013; I think the way to answer your question is that I would say we certainly, from our perspective, are the most prudent accounter of nuclear provisions that we found so far in Europe. You have more details on how we do it and what the underlying assumptions, broadly speaking, are on a plant level. Admittedly, we do that in the backup for a generic plan. But I think that hopefully gives you some transparency into what's happening there. So from our perspective, we feel very comfortable with the provision levels on the decommissioning side that we have.</p>
          <p>With regard to safety tests, you're probably referring to the outcome of the Reaktor-Sicherheitskommission?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All of those stations have passed all tests. That's why we also sue the government because the government found no reason whatsoever by technical problems to retire any of our plants. They are up to state. There are minor equipments that should be invested to raise level beyond that of today. That will be done and handled, but honestly, if it's European or global or a German test, I would not see one of our plants ever fail it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe just for the benefit of people on the phone because I believe we just &#x2013; we're sort of moving our heads on your question with regard to can EPS be translated into adjusted net income. Yes, it can, and you can apply the same number of shares that you apply today, just for the benefit of people just listening in. Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You have one more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just on the cost for operating a plant, given that you say that you do not expect any adverse outcome. For modeling the remaining life span of the remaining plants, do you think you can run them at the same economics with regard to CapEx expenditure as in the plants &#x2013; as in the past? Or do you &#x2013; should we assume a gradual increase in safety requirements or greater shutdown periods, things like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, you should not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question with respect to Patrick, and then we move into the middle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you hear me? Yeah. Okay. Thanks very much. Just one follow-up question. It's actually one for Marcus. Just in terms of the 2013 guidance, I still struggle in detail to understand what's going on there? If I look at the EBITDA guidance, your previous guidance was more than &#x20AC;13 billion. That's basically on Slide 16.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So let's say a bit more than &#x20AC;13 billion as a starting point, may be &#x20AC;13.2 million or whatsoever, then you reduce that by &#x20AC;900 million for the deconsolidation that has happened so far. Then you get to say around &#x20AC;12.3 million. Your new guidance, the range is &#x20AC;11.6 million to &#x20AC;12.3 million with the current group structure, so if I take the midpoint, this is down another &#x20AC;400 million net. But it already includes &#x20AC;750 million of cost savings, so that the other part is more than &#x20AC;1.1 billion. And the effects that you just gave us don't match up to those &#x20AC;1.1 billion, or maybe I'm too conservative with my numbers. That's what I'm trying to reconcile.</p>
          <p>You just said on the other slide that the lost nuke output is only between &#x20AC;200 million and &#x20AC;300 million a year. So there must be some &#x20AC;700 million to &#x20AC;800 million of others, and the effects that you were mentioning, well, maybe you can just help me to reconcile if there's something missing or numbers are just higher on the other effects that we eventually could arrive at that number that you gave? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I believe what I said was that when you look at the negative effect which is a series of six or seven items, they all add up to something which is almost &#x20AC;1 billion negative. Clearly, there are also some positive developments on the pricing side where we see some upside relative to the assumptions that we had provided a year ago, which is somewhere between &#x20AC;300 million and &#x20AC;400 million of positive effect, in particular most of that actually related to our E&amp;P position.</p>
          <p>And then as you rightfully point out, there is &#x2013; there are the cost measures with &#x2013; now, obviously, I believe your question is where &#x2013; how on earth do you get to this about &#x20AC;1 billion number? As we &#x2013; as I said, there is quite a substantial number in there that relates to the delay of three major projects, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:33:01) and the LNG terminal Livorno, which we had so far assumed would actually be productive in 2013. That's no longer the case. That's a substantial amount that we're losing there in that year.</p>
          <p>We also have experienced in I would say almost all Eastern European markets additional pressure on our ability to pass through prices to the consumers to increase tariffs. And when you go through all the markets, it actually adds up. So we really lose a couple of hundred there relative to the situation that we anticipated a year ago. Then we have, and I think you are aware of that, a slightly more conservative assumption now with regard to the remuneration of our Russian generation assets where they've just taken down the sort of the returns to be awarded by a percentage point.</p>
          <p>Now that may change again. There's election year next year. Who knows? But so far we've now basically marked down our expectation there. That has a negative impact, and then in particular when you look at Spain and Italy, we had some recovery of those markets. Given what's happening, we are more conservative there now in terms of our assumptions on recovery. That is a big step that we lose, and then there's a smaller item which relates to the sort of the margins that we think we can achieve in our sales businesses, and all those add up to roughly &#x20AC;1 billion. We really &#x2013; I think there's one effect that sits in there where you could argue it's kind of a timing point. Mentally to me that is a different category, but it still is in 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Question Indiscernible] (1:35:38)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Those three projects. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Have some questions. Firstly, I'm trying to understand on the gas side. Again, for this year, you've said that the margin lost in the first half is &#x20AC;970 million, so that would probably mean that second half is then positive in supply and sales. 2012, you're obviously hesitant to release any indication, giving the negotiations ongoing. But from the direction there were some suggestions that there could be a loss of &#x20AC;1.5 billion in supply and sales next year. But do I understand it correctly that you're rather at the other end? So that compensation payments are made, the number would rather would look high than low? And in terms of the cost savings program, the &#x20AC;1.5 billion, can you give any indication how that will split between Germany and the rest of the world, i.e., thinking in terms of the personnel effect that you just mentioned? And then lastly in terms of what you've outlined on strategy, you said you're quite happy with operating capacity markets outside of the Europe. Would that imply if the German government decides on implementing a capacity market rather than just payment that would be something which would be of interest to companies like you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, starting with the latter. Capacity markets are not that simple always. If it's new capacity, and if it's well integrated in an overall market design, it can be a very attractive environment. If it's just a partial market design and not well put in order, then it can destroy value for the overall fleet. Therefore, we are quite careful to support capacity regimes in the European market, which is predominantly an energy market.</p>
          <p>And I would not yet see how to cope with it, that <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:37:54) and Paris and others trade energy, and then you would have capacity elements. How do you cope with it? So I think it's premature to immediately call for the next regime with all the different market design, and therefore we say be careful on that, and don't easily call for it without understanding what it means.</p>
          <p>The second to last question upon splits of HR. That question was posed to me from every union leader where we expected it more. And since I didn't answer the union leaders, I don't expect to answer you. It will be defined in due time, and it's premature to speculate and it's also two full locations. And the last question, Marcus, it's your favorite topic, so I don't &#x2013; shouldn't take it away.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, your analysis on 2011 is correct, i.e., that we report a loss of &#x20AC;970 million compared to previously as you compare to prior year. And then for the full year we said that we do not expect that loss to increase, but actually it could be slightly lower. The reason beyond that is that we will now see the sort of the benefits from those contracts that have been renegotiated. But in particular, the 2010 second half year was very bad or there specifically the fourth quarter was very bad, but we had a substantial loss in that business.</p>
          <p>And that's the reason why in the second half, indeed we expect to come out slightly higher than we just take the isolated months seven to 12 and compare those with the months seven to 12 of 2010. With regard to 2012, the only source that we have for this &#x20AC;1.5 billion of loss that you mentioned is the same source that you have. We read it on some, I believe Reuters screen, and that's all I know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So fast, Reuters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So maybe &#x2013; yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Ashley Thomas from MF Global. Just to return to the 2013 guidance, but on a post-disposal basis. So if we had the &#x20AC;800 million to &#x20AC;900 million disposable dilution occurring in 2013, but didn't have any benefit from the growth CapEx. In terms of the dividend, would it be set principally on the absolute dividend floor level? Or on the 55% to 65% payout level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we mentioned there is we have the 50% to 60% as a fundamental guidance. But we also give today the guidance that the minimum level for 2013 should be the &#x20AC;110 million. So both is true, but the guidance stays 50% to 60%, but we undertake everything to pay the &#x20AC;110 million at least.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. And I'm sorry, follow-up question. Just on the tax rate, the 26% to 36% range sort of in line with your sort of historical range. I would have thought it would perhaps trend towards the higher level because of the E&amp;P contribution is a greater percentage of the group. So if you did have to narrow the range, would it be towards that high level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your analysis is correct. When we just do the pure math, we also typically come out at the higher end of the range. But then there's always certain special effects that pop up and then suddenly the tax rates look a little bit lower. You will see that this year. You've seen it already in the first half numbers. That's why we provide now the range rather than the point value. But in principle you're right. If there are no special effects we would tend to be at the higher end of that range. That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take another question from Vincent, then here and then I'll take another question from the web, and then we round it up and have a couple drinks and then discuss it further. That's all. Don't shout. Take a mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much for taking yet another question from me. And when I was reading the interim reports, I spotted that you referred twice to the loss of customers both in the power business and in the gas business if my memory serves me well. And I was wondering whether you could actually develop a bit on this, whether you, first, the sort of quantum of loss of customer, whether it's one-off or not? And if it's not a one-off, is it a trend you expect to develop? What is behind this? I think it's the first time I sit in any of your interim reports to be frank with you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, overall we don't have a fundamental change in our customer numbers. We have gained some customers, for example, in the UK. I believe we are 100,000 up or so.</p>
          <p>It is a specific issue in Germany at this point, and I would probably interpret it also in the context of these difficult discussions around Fukushima. I think we have lost less than others there, but there was &#x2013; Germany is a romantic country, and then everybody was discussing nuclear. For a limited amount of time people were rushing to green products and then stopped again.</p>
          <p>But that period also impacted us somewhat, and we lost some customers there, but that process has declined again now. I guess other issues are of higher importance than Fukushima lately in Germany, and it starts to be forgotten. But we lost some customers in that initial process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bernhard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Bernhard Jeggle from LBBW. We currently see increasing concerns regarding a flattening of the economic development, and what might that mean regarding your guidance for 2013 and '15, i.e., if the lower end already anticipates some charges from that side? Or could you provide an indication what this might mean for your guidance? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No I don't think that is possible today. I don't know if you can do it for any market. Obviously, all our slides and all our calculations were done before the world decided to play doomsday, and if that materialized in anyway, and if it really impacts commodity prices on the longer term, it's pure speculation at the point.</p>
          <p>And we have not done any calculation on that doomsday scenario, and we don't intend to do that, because we think it's a little premature. And let's wait and see when everybody gets back on the <mark type="ph" /> next three (1:45:27), and then we need to see what it means. But obviously, we watch it carefully and try to protect ourselves from immediate impact, but other than, that we need all to wait and see. And we try to stay in control and keep our cool.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then I actually take the last question from the web. I still have quite a few of those. But I think some of those can be answered in next days. That keeps us employed at least at Investor Relations. So there's still some confusion...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:46:00).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, maybe we should tell. No, there's still some confusion on the efficiency initiative, i.e. how does it relates to former programs, i.e. Perform-to-Win, how does it relate to the additional &#x20AC;6 million that was given at the capital market day? How is it going to be impacted by disposals? And finally, what are the restructuring expenses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We said restructuring expenses we cannot yet calculate before final definition of programs and elements to implement. Obviously, we also promised that the Perform-to-Win will be implemented already this year and it will so. And this already fed into all our numbers for these years. Don't forget that Perform-to-Win had also effects on the revenue side. It was not a pure cost program. So we had generated new revenues, for example, from a significant amount of new sales of products around gas storage. We increased some margins in some of our retail businesses.</p>
          <p>All of that is fully included also on the cost side, so there's no doubt that that program is being recorded and fulfilled. Obviously, following the &#x20AC;600 million now, if we announce a clear cost target, it doesn't give &#x2013; so much sense. All of that now flows into a clear cost target, &#x20AC;9.5 million, and to record separately all the other issues then probably doesn't give so much sense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Johannes. And I would also hand over to you for some closing remarks, and then I do the &#x2013; a finalization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe three short remarks that I would hope would be takeaways. We believe that we have brought our balance sheet fundamentally in a much better shape and a better position in that aspect than a lot of our sector competitors. And we don't need any external help to keep our ship floating there.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we control our own destiny, and we meant it when we said that we change E.ON to a performance culture, and we immediately act on that. If our operations go under stress indicated by Marcus because all the effects going from business to business, we squeeze ourselves harder immediately.</p>
          <p>We not just record the downturn; we immediately offsetting it. So if times get tougher, we get harder on it. And thirdly, we will swiftly implemental strategy, the refocus on Europe and very specific businesses we have defined and we will secure our growth platforms, the renewables, decentralized generation and new markets out of Europe.</p>
          <p>And also there I send a clear signal to the employees and to the media and also to you. I will not under no circumstances sacrifice our growth platforms and our ability to implement our strategy just for the benefit of keeping old structures or old costs of today. We will rather then take all necessary actions so we are capable to implement our growth strategy, and to transform the company to what we have defined last year.</p>
          <p>So those are the three clear messages that will be the ones that control ourselves, and should also be understood for anybody following our company. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Johannes. Thank you, Marcus. Thanks to all the colleagues in the room. I would also like to say a thank you to our host today, Deutsche Bank, whose facilities and services we have used. I'd like to thank all the helping hands that have contributed to the presentation, and controlling and from corporate development and from my team, and I look forward to further discussions with those people in the room and a nice cool beer.</p>
          <p>And that ends the formal part of the transmission. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>