<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1249798" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-08-12</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2864</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Sascha Bibert, Senior Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Wulf H. Bernotat, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Marcus Schenck, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Martin Young</participant>
      <participant id="5">Bobby Chada</participant>
      <participant id="6">Deborah Wilkens</participant>
      <participant id="7">Simon Flowers</participant>
      <participant id="8">Peter Bisztyga</participant>
      <participant id="9">Lueder Schumacher</participant>
      <participant id="10">Andreas Thielen</participant>
      <participant id="11">Christopher Kuplent</participant>
      <participant id="12">Alberto Ponti</participant>
      <participant id="13">Vincent De Blic</participant>
      <participant id="14">Benjamin Leyre</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Dear ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the E.ON Conference Call. As a reminder, all participants will be in listen-only mode. After the presentation, there will be an opportunity to ask questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>I now hand over to Herr Sascha Bibert. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. Welcome to the first half 2009 results of the E.ON Group. Wulf Bernotat, our CEO, will summarize the main financials before highlighting some strategic aspects. Then Marcus Schenck, our CFO, will review the half year figures in more detail.</p>
          <p>Before handing over to Wulf, I would just like to send my warm regards to my predecessor Kiran Bhojani, who has been hosting this call for 17 years. Kiran, I'm sure you are listening right now, so I wish you all the best.</p>
          <p>Importantly, Wulf will use updated slides that we have sent out after the Th&#xFC;ga announcement to make sure that you've got the right slides in front of you.</p>
          <p>With that, I hand over to our CEO, Wulf Bernotat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you very much. And good afternoon ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the presentation of E.ON's 2009 first half results. Today, I can present to you a robust set of figures with adjusted EBIT down 1% and adjusted net income up 4%. Better performance of the new markets largely compensate for the earnings pressure seen in our market unit Pan-European gas. Furthermore, our Nordic and UK operations delivered good results if adjusted for scope and other effects like currency. In the UK retail business for example, our cost initiatives are starting to deliver tangible results.</p>
          <p>For the full year, we continue to expect adjusted EBIT to stay around the same level as last year. We previously expected adjusted net income to fall by 10%. However, we now anticipate adjusted net income to decline between five and 10%, thanks to lower than expected interest and tax expenses.</p>
          <p>Today, I will talk about the latest developments with respect to the economic crisis and the performance of our new markets. I will then speak about the three-part strategy that we outlined on March 10, focusing our investments to drive future growth, improving operational performance with the PerformtoWin initiative, and streamlining the portfolio.</p>
          <p>As regards streamlining, I will come back to the details later. But let me say that the commercial agreement we reached to dispose of significant parts of Th&#xFC;ga confirms that we are able to execute complex transactions in challenging times. This step further enhances the strategic flexibility and financial solidity of the E.ON Group.</p>
          <p>Let me start with the latest developments regarding the economic crisis. Over the last three months, various business indicators have started to point to a lessening of the downturn. This is also the case in the utility sector. Looking at Germany for example, power demand rapidly declined right after the bankruptcy of Lehman Brothers in September 2008. The year-on-year comparisons deteriorated further until April when power demand contracted by 14%. In May and June however, the reduction of demand slowed to between five and 6%.</p>
          <p>In general, we are seeing first signs of a tentative recovery in the German, British and Nordic power markets. However, the situation remains difficult in the Italian and Spanish power markets, as well as in the gas business.</p>
          <p>In the first half of the year, the economic crisis had a direct effect on adjusted EBIT of around &#x20AC;260 million. For the full year, we expect this figure to reach approximately &#x20AC;400 million. While our bad debt estimates have not changed much, the estimated impact of volume losses has widened further as demand has fallen more strongly than expected. Looking forward, we prefer to keep a conservative stance as there are still many economic uncertainties.</p>
          <p>We continue to work hard on various risk mitigation measures. We are also trying to identify issues as early as possible via risk profiling and continuous risk monitoring. In addition, our extensive forward hedging will protect us from the sharper end of the recession. For the years 2009 and 2010, we are economically sold out, and for 2011 we have hedged 60 to 70% for Central Europe and Nordic.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to the performance of our new markets. With an adjusted EBIT of 538 million, operations in the new markets contributed substantially to the performance of the Group in the first half. Climate and Renewables increased its installed base from around two gigawatts at the start of the year to roughly 2.4 gigawatts. Political support for rapid development of renewables remains strong. In the UK, the intention of the government to increase the ROCs allocated to offshore wind has allowed E.ON and its partners to give the green light to the development of the 1,000 megawatt London Array project.</p>
          <p>In the US, the new system of investment tax credits introduced by the Obama administration will provide additional flexibility to develop our projects.</p>
          <p>While our investments currently remain concentrated in wind and biomass, we believe that the solar energy has the potential for an industrial scale deployment similar to wind. Therefore, we are starting to position ourselves accordingly. We are involved in thin-film technology through our Malibu joint venture. And furthermore, we have recently inaugurated our first solar farm in Le Lauzet in southern France, and we are also participating in the visionary Desertec consortium to develop solar power in North Africa to supply Europe. Overall, our ambitious targets for Climate and Renewables remains unchanged. We aim to double capacity between 2008 and 2010 to around four gigawatt.</p>
          <p>In Russia, the reform of the power market is proceeding as scheduled. On July 1, the degree of liberalization was increased from 30 to 50%. OGK-4 is amongst the best performing wholesale generation companies. While power demand in Russia was down 7% in the first half, the production of OGK-4 was down only 3%. Majority of our Russian capacity is located in regions dominated by the oil and gas industry where demand is holding up better. In addition, our plants are well positioned in the merit order, thanks to their higher efficiency.</p>
          <p>Italy is currently our most challenging market. Power and gas demand remain weak and margins are under pressure. Nevertheless, we are doing everything we can to extract additional value. In the preceding periods, we successfully negotiated unfavorable power supply contracts leading to a one-off benefit in the first half year adjusted EBIT.</p>
          <p>France and Spain are performing according to our expectations. In Spain, we improved the gas sourcing of our CCGTs by executing our first trades in LNG spot cargos. In France, our operations are benefiting from long-term capacity contracts. Operations in new markets have become meaningful earning contributors. Through active management we are succeeding to improve performance and extract additional value. In the coming years, the new markets will provide an increasing share of E.ON's growth.</p>
          <p>Let me now update you in the progress of the three strategic priorities we set on March 10, beginning with the PerformtoWin initiative. This is not a one-off cost cutting initiative, but a holistic change management program to enhance performance and efficiency. Detailed roadmaps have been defined for almost all projects. And I'm glad to say that in the last days we have reached a basic agreement with E.ON's employee representatives and unions, allowing us to move quickly into the implementation phase. We can confirm that the PerformtoWin initiative will add &#x20AC;1.5 billion to adjusted EBIT by 2011. Furthermore, this figure will be delivered faster than previously communicated. We now expect a contribution to adjusted EBIT of 200 to 400 million in 2009, 800 million to one billion in 2010, and 1.5 billion in 2011.</p>
          <p>As the breakdowns by functions and market units illustrates, PerformtoWin will enhance efficiency and improve productivity across the whole value chain and in all regions. Our first estimate for the restructuring cost is around &#x20AC;500 million. To summarize on PerformtoWin, this is the program to make E.ON leaner and faster in every respect.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn to our &#x2013; to the progress on our portfolio streamlining program. This morning we announced a decisive step forward regarding Th&#xFC;ga. We have reached a commercial agreement regarding a disposal of the largest part of Th&#xFC;ga to a consortium of municipal utilities, consisting of Stadtwerke Hannover, Mainova and N-Ergie, plus some 45 Stadtwerke from the Th&#xFC;ga portfolio. Consortium will acquire Th&#xFC;ga except for some selected assets, which will be transferred back to E.ON. These are the 37% stake in GASAG, 40% participation in HSE and 20% in Stadtwerke Duisburg and the 10% position in Stadtwerke Karlsruhe. We will proceed immediately with the resale of these four participations separate to the main Th&#xFC;ga transaction.</p>
          <p>The acquiring consortium has agreed to pay a cash consideration of &#x20AC;2.875 billion for the purchase of Th&#xFC;ga without the assets taken out. In addition, further payments will be determined at closing, such as amounts relating to intercompany debt or cash pooling with E.ON.</p>
          <p>Th&#xFC;ga as a whole generated an adjusted net income of around &#x20AC;270 million in 2008. The selected assets taken out of the main Th&#xFC;ga transaction contributed around &#x20AC;55 million to that figure, thus about 20%.</p>
          <p>The commercial agreement is now being submitted for final approval by all the parties involved. The plan is to sign the purchase and sale contract in September and close the transaction in the fourth quarter. This transaction is another milestone to increase strategic flexibility and financial solidity for E.ON.</p>
          <p>Following our commitment to the EU Commission, we have also made substantial steps forward regarding the disposal of the five gigawatt of generation capacity in Germany. We have concluded an agreement to sell the 312 megawatts on &#x2013; of run-of-river capacity on the River Inn to Verbund in Austria. In return, E.ON will receive a cash compensation plus the right to procure the equivalent of 318 megawatt over 20 years from Verbund's pump storage plants in the Ziller River Valley. The transaction value amounts to more than &#x20AC;1 billion, of which the cash compensation makes up the largest part.</p>
          <p>At the end of May, we also closed the sale of our stakes in the Lippendorf lignite-fired power plant and in the Bexbach coal-fired power plant to EnBW. And at the end of July, we signed the definitive purchase and sale contract with GDF Suez to swap 1.7 gigawatt of capacity in Germany for an equivalent volume in Belgium where we have become the number three in the market.</p>
          <p>Together with the Statkraft asset swap, we thus have agreed so far to sell 3.2 gigawatt of the five gigawatt mandated by the commitment to the EU Commission. Our priority was to swap as much of the five gigawatt as we could. So far, the transactions have helped us to increase our stake in E.ON Sweden to 100% and to add two gigawatt of capacity in Belgium and Austria. We also aim to swap the majority of the remaining 1.8 gigawatt to be divested as part of the EU commitment. Nevertheless, we expect cash proceeds from the whole five gigawatt divestment program to surpass &#x20AC;2 billion. These transactions result in a more diversified portfolio from a geographic perspective, opening new growth opportunities at reduced risk.</p>
          <p>After seven years of patient negotiations, we have also finally unwound the WKE lease and supply contracts in the US. WKE has been created in 1998 to lease 1.8 gigawatt of mostly coal-fired generation capacity from Big Rivers and the City of Henderson in Kentucky for 25 years. In parallel, WKE entered into long-term power supply contracts with Big Rivers and two aluminum smelters, in some cases also for 25 years. As the price in the long-term power supply contract was more or less fixed while the fuel prices were not, this combination of contracts thus presented a substantial economic risk.</p>
          <p>The unwind agreement provides that E.ON will pay US$575 million to Big Rivers, the City of Henderson and the aluminum smelters at closing. E.ON will also assume limited coverage of certain risks until 2011. The unwind of the WKE contracts removes a substantial economic risk for E.ON US and increases the strategic and financial flexibility for the Group.</p>
          <p>To conclude on portfolio streamlining, let me summarize where we stand. Main objectives of the portfolio streamlining program are to simplify the Group and unlock value by focusing on those businesses which we do best. In addition, the portfolio streamlining program contributes to the overall financial balance of the Group. In this respect, we had set ourselves the target of generating more than &#x20AC;10 million of cash proceeds by the end of 2010. Together, the EnBW, Verbund and Th&#xFC;ga transactions should already deliver close to five billion of cash proceeds. We are thus already halfway to our target and ahead of schedule.</p>
          <p>The third cornerstone of the March 10 strategy is our 30 billion investment plan for the period 2009 to 2011. We invested &#x20AC;4.4 billion in the first half of 2009. The majority of these investments are concentrated on our pipeline of power plant new-builds, renewables and the gas business. For the whole of 2009, we plan to spend 13 billion, including the Gazprom, Yuzhno Russkoye asset swap.</p>
          <p>In power generation, we are only building those projects which were already under construction and which were contracted when component prices were still at attractive levels. We are keeping all the other projects on hold as clean dark and spark spreads have come under pressure and component prices stay at high levels. As a result, E.ON's run rate of investments is likely to be reduced after 2011. Nevertheless, the growth investments are taking the lion's share of our current CapEx and will help to drive future earnings growth.</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, let me now conclude my presentation. After the strong contraction of demand in the first half, economic crisis is showing the first tentative signs of recovery.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, we nevertheless remain conservative in our demand assumptions. In the first half the new markets helped offset weaknesses in other market units and contributed significantly to results. Active management of our new assets is allowing us to improve performance and extract additional value, and also delivering on our three strategic priorities. We'll now start with the implementation of our operational performance initiative PerformtoWin and will deliver faster than previously anticipated.</p>
          <p>The portfolio streamlining program has taken a decisive step forward with the disposal of Th&#xFC;ga with this transaction we are very well under way with respect to our target of generating more than &#x20AC;10 billion of cash proceeds. Meanwhile our investment focus &#x2013; is focusing on organic growth and is progressing well and we will drive future earnings growth.</p>
          <p>To summarize, we wanted to make E.ON simpler, leaner, and faster to foster sustainable growth and value creation. This concludes my presentation, but before handing over to Marcus for a detailed review of our financials, I would like to say a few words on management succession at E.ON.</p>
          <p>Monday evening the Supervisory Board has pointed Johannes Teyssen as future CEO from May 1, 2010. And I wish Johannes all the best in his coming role. Until then the entire Management Board of E.ON will continue as before its current roles and positions to further develop E.ON under our current motto, performance, and streamlining.</p>
          <p>With that said, I will now hand over to Marcus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. And before, I walk you through the numbers in detail and I will just go through the pages. The big picture first on page one as we've mentioned adjusted EBIT is down minus 1%. EBITDA up 2%, both adjusted net income and operating cash flow up 4%. Investment down due &#x2013; basically due to last year's investments into the Endesa assets and Viesgo economic net debt up by &#x20AC;2 billion.</p>
          <p>All in all I would say robust results despite the economic crisis, which have had the bigger effect in the first half of the year than we had originally anticipated. Overall we estimate that effects to be at around &#x20AC;260 million, breaks down into reselling volumes, loss margin, and bad debt roughly a third of the 260 million for each of those three components.</p>
          <p>Page two shows you the development of both EBIT and EBITDA by market units, but I will now go through them on the following pages one by one.</p>
          <p>First Central Europe, the non-regulated business of Central Europe West is essentially impacted positively by three main effects. The first-time consolidation of the French SNET business roughly &#x20AC;140 million, higher generation margin of &#x20AC;47 million and largely weather driven higher retail gas margin of &#x20AC;118 million.</p>
          <p>On the negative side, we see a lower margin in power in our retail business with a minus 174 million effect. Here essentially the rising procurement costs of last year had not timely been passed through. And then as mentioned before, we estimate the impact of the economic crisis on the non-regulated business of Central Europe of around &#x20AC;83 million.</p>
          <p>As it relates to the regulated business, there's essentially just one point I would like to highlight. In our power networks, we see an upward change of &#x20AC;67 million which is essentially driven by the following. There is a higher allowed return on equity that has been approved by the regulator. And that's in conjunction with our comparatively high efficiency scores in our DSOs to remember <mark type="inaudible" /> our side roughly 100% compared to industry average of 93%, that's higher allowance tariffs.</p>
          <p>We also as mentioned before have a positive outcome of the so called hardship filings for non-controllable costs, which gives us some relief. And for the full year, we expect the positive impact of &#x20AC;67 million compared to last half year, the full year effect of that, we expect to go up to &#x20AC;200 million.</p>
          <p>Let me now come to Pan-European Gas, which is as expected the most difficult business this year. Let's first look at the regulated business. Gas transport is flat year-on-year due to lower tariffs in gas transport, which is offset by a higher participation income. In our international business in particular in Hungary, E.ON F&#xF6;ldg&#xE1;z is down minus &#x20AC;150 million. This is essentially driven by both currency effects, but in particular by a major volume drop in the country, which has partially also forced us into mintake positions.</p>
          <p>Let's look at the non-regulated business. Exploration and production has dropped from roughly 200 million in the first half of last year down to 100 million almost exclusively driven by the development of oil and gas prices. The storage result remains at the Q1 level and the main in the Ruhrgas business is the price/volume situation in what we call the supply and sales business where results dropped quite significantly by roughly &#x20AC;430 million.</p>
          <p>And here are the three effects that matter. First effect is price. We've seen a &#x2013; mainly driven by competition, a negative price effect of roughly &#x20AC;370 million in the first half and we have seen a volume effect of roughly &#x20AC;185 million. This is &#x2013; and the third effect partially being offset by a positive effect of roughly &#x20AC;120 million where Ruhrgas is benefiting from spot purchases given the flexibility that exists in our long-term supply agreements.</p>
          <p>Obviously you will ask the question what does that mean for the full year, and the one thing I would like to highlight is that as far as the development on the price side is concerned here also looking in particular at the last eight weeks, we think we have reached the bottom there. So in a way we would at this stage not expect a significant &#x2013; further negative development. And as far as volumes are concerned, we think -- we had roughly, caused by the crisis, a drop of 15 terawatt hours in the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>We think compared to last year that number could come back also in the second half of the year. But as it relates to the other volume drop, we expect the second half to be clearly better than the first half in particular because we have seen many of the Ruhrgas customers use the flexibility they have in their contracts to basically push forward purchases from the first half of the year into the second half of the year. So some recovery, actually quite some material recovery is expected on our side in relation to that effect.</p>
          <p>Let's move over to the UK, on page five, which requires also a bit of an explanation. The regulated business is down exclusively based on currency translation effects otherwise it is up. The non-regulated business, we have two main effects. One is that the generation business is down &#x20AC;74 million due to lower spreads and the unplanned outage of <mark type="inaudible" /> and the retail business is up &#x20AC;11 million. The remainder is essentially just group internal transfer to E.ON Energy Trading, which is illustrated on the next page.</p>
          <p>Chart six adjusts the first half of 2009 for changes in scope, transfer price and currency. First item are certain long-term supply contracts that are now being marketed by E.ON Energy Trading. So the result has not disappeared, it simply now shows up within EET. Secondly, the UK sells its freely allocated CO2 certificates to E.ON Energy Trading now at a lower transfer price than what's originally set. Both the 2008 and 2009 transfer price were originally set at the &#x2013; in 2007 at the same level. With the redelivery of the 2009 certificates in Q1 of this year, a repricing was necessary, although externally the position was already hedged. And then, the third effect, are the currency translation effects. So that you can see that on a like-for-like basis looking at the operational results, the remaining data is much smaller than one would conclude from page five.</p>
          <p>Let me move to Nordic. Nordic's EBIT is down 34% mainly due to currency effects and lower volumes, which is explained a bit on Page eight. Starting with the &#x20AC;341 million of EBIT reported for the first half of 2009, we need to mention three effects to get to the underlying operational performance. The first effect are the hydro volumes that have been swapped with Statkraft. To remind you, we have given up roughly a third of the hydro generation capacity in the context of assets swapped with Statkraft.</p>
          <p>Second effect is the planned shutdown of Oskarshamn III, where we are upgrading the power plant. And then, the third effect, are again currency translation effects. So you can see that actually the underlying performance, operational performance of the Nordic business is actually better than the year before.</p>
          <p>Page nine, the US numbers actually I think they speak for themselves including the comments mentioned on the page, and I will give a few more details on WKE later in the context of discontinued operations.</p>
          <p>So, let us move over to the business of E.ON Energy Trading. At Energy Trading, the Proprietary Trading business has developed favorably due to the high volatility in particular in Q1 of this year. However, we do not expect to repeat the full year 2008 results to remind you particularly second half of 2008 was actually very good. As it relates to asset optimization, we show a steep increase of roughly &#x20AC;400 million. Before explaining, I'd like to make one comment because we always get passed on the results of trading. Our asset optimization is simply marketing our assets as we did during all the prior years within the traditional market units. We actually do not take anymore risk than we did before, we just show that part of the business separately.</p>
          <p>As explained in the contest of the UK, we have Group internal effects of around 200 million towards the UK and a smaller number around 40 million with regard to Central Europe, which are just internal transfer price effects.</p>
          <p>The &#x2013; however there is additional value that was created by Energy Trading in particular in the UK spot market driven by overall market shortage in particular during the first months of this year, similar to what we have seen in Q4 of 2008. We also benefited in the oil and gas position that the Group has where 2008 we had a particularly weak results.</p>
          <p>As far as the outlook for Energy Trading is concerned, I'd like to remind you that 2008 was a particularly strong second half. So we do expect to repeat that, so please do not just simply double the half-year figure that we are showing here.</p>
          <p>On page 11, as usual we are showing you our hedge positions and the items I would like to highlight is that on this page we show that the outright power i.e. power being produced from nuclear and hydro, volumes and prices here we show for both Central Europe and Nordic. I think the numbers almost speak for themselves, it gives us good visibility for the years 2009 and now also through to 2011. We had, as mentioned before, accelerated the 2011 hedging earlier in the year, and are now moving forward I would say at normal pace. Our overall generation hedge ratios are reported in the appendix where we now also include Spain and Italy.</p>
          <p>Moving to page 12, new markets have contributed more than 0.5 billion in the first half of this year, but let's look at the different businesses. Climate and Renewables; it is up due to the doubling of the generation volume. The increase &#x2013; in a way I think you should ask why isn't it up more than what we are showing here on this page. The increase in generation volume resulted almost exclusively from roughly doubling our generation capacity in the US. But in the US, we see &#x2013; we feel in particular the drop in the wholesale price, which is part of the compensation we get for the power we are selling from <mark type="inaudible" /> in this market, and this drop in wholesale price almost offsets the benefit from the higher outputs that we see in that markets. Also the wind conditions in Europe were less, a bit less favorable than in normal years.</p>
          <p>Russia. Russia is actually performing quite well, given the very challenging market circumstances. Just to remind you, Russia is clearly suffering much more from the economic crisis than many other markets we are operating in. However, gross margins are up by &#x20AC;33 million given good availability of our plants and the good position in the merit order of our power plants. It is also up given that we have been able to sell more volume now into the free markets where the Russian government has so far fully followed their liberalization plan. Also just a point to highlight, in Russia we have a, I would say particularly strong cost management, which has also improved the performance by roughly &#x20AC;31 million.</p>
          <p>Spain. Here the increase is simply the first time consolidation of our business where we see 35 million results in generation and 23 million in distribution.</p>
          <p>In Italy there is two main effects driving the increase. The first, obviously is the consolidation of the previous &#x2013; the Endesa Italia business and then as Wulf mentioned before there is a one-off gain from the renegotiation of fairly unfavorable long-term power supply contracts. Total impact of that is 210 million. This is a real economic benefit to the Group over the coming years accounting wise it shows us in this quarter.</p>
          <p>Let's move down further in the P&amp;L on page 13, as expected, net interest result is down in line with our increased financial indebtedness. Just one comment, obviously for the full year, the interest result will be more than twice the number we show for half the year because we have been building up the indebtedness during half the year end. We had in particular been pre-funding some of our maturities and hence we were essentially also incurring some interest income during the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>Net book gains reflects in particular part of the generation capacity that has been sold in the first half of the year. Restructuring charges are essentially at the same level as last year, similar projects behind that. The other non-operating results have two main positions. There is a two billion increase from that result from the mark-to-market valuation of derivatives which is up from minus 800 million to now plus 1.2 billion. And then the second effect, negative effect is the provision that we have now built for the payment of 553 million fine that we received from the EU Commission in the context of the MEGAL case.</p>
          <p>The reported tax rate is up mainly caused by essentially the two effects that I've mentioned, the MEGAL fine is not tax deductible, and the positive derivative results is charged with a 30% deferred tax rate. As was the case last year, WKE was the sole contributor to discontinued operations. The unwind charge of &#x20AC;575 million has led to cash out in July, but we expect no further P&amp;L effects beyond our Q2 results. I would also like to highlight that the additional limited protection we are providing under the agreement is kept by an amount of $340 million and time wise ends in 2011. So that is the maximum additional exposure we would have there subject to the further developments.</p>
          <p>Overall, the reported net income is up 45%. Adjusted net income as mentioned before is up 4%. So I'm now on page 14. As you know we just reported net income for our neutral results. The slight increase is a little better than we had originally expected. Let me explain some of the tax effects that are particularly driving this development. Whilst reported tax rate we see an increase from 22% in 2008 to 25% in 2009. The implied tax rate in our adjusted net income has dropped from 25% to 21%. Where does that difference come from? It is actually the fact that &#x2013; it is caused by the fact that the implied tax rate in our neutral results is north of 30% given we tax the derivative result with 30% and the MEGAL fine not being tax deductible. So from that you can &#x2013; it's actually recalculate that the effective tax rate in our adjusted net income is actually lower than last year. For the full year, we expect the effective tax rates to be somewhere between 22 and 25%.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the operating cash flow, Group operating cash flow is up &#x20AC;160 million. As before market units specific movements are actually very difficult to interpret given there is &#x2013; there are large Group internal effects, so let me basically comment on the overall picture. The main positive cash developments, I would like to mention three, first, the increase in EBITDA of 130 million. Second, a working capital improvement of roughly 500 million in particular in the UK and Energy Trading; and then thirdly, an improvement resulting from lower storage volume, here the total effect of &#x20AC;900 million roughly is &#x2013; the equivalent is 40 terawatt hour reduction in gas storage.</p>
          <p>The main negative drivers is with 460 million higher interest cash payments, 200 million higher tax payments, then you need to correct for the 210 million negotiated power contracts in Italy. We have a 230 million lower cash effective neutral result and then there is roughly 100 million currency effects, and the rest is others. Maintenance CapEx is stable at roughly &#x20AC;600 million.</p>
          <p>Chart 16 details our investments in the first half of the year. Here I would &#x2013; I don't have so many comments, obviously last year's number is heavily impacted by the Endesa Viesgo transaction. This year we show exclusively organic investments. And as Wulf mentioned before what we are doing is executing our projects, not adding new ones.</p>
          <p>The economic net debts has increased by two billion and before I walk you through how we get there, let me just make one comment to page 17. The drop in fair value of currency derivatives results simply from the settlement of cost currency swaps that have an equivalent positive effect on the net financial position.</p>
          <p>Page 18 is in a way I would say self explanatory and it shows you why we see an increase in economic net debt. The one item I'd like to highlight is that the main item included under divestments is the sale of our share in the Lippendorf plant to EnBW and a number of smaller disposals which as you can see here, we are successfully executing.</p>
          <p>Before concluding with the outlook, a few words on funding, year-to-date we have raised &#x20AC;7.9 billion. The largest maturity was fully redeemed in May of this year and we continue to have good full access to bonds, loans and the commercial paper markets. Moody's has just confirmed our A2 rating with stable outlook, S&amp;P did so in May of this year. The successful delivery of our disposal program will support this and we will &#x2013; and we'll continue to drive down our debt factor over the coming 18 months.</p>
          <p>So, let me conclude then with a few words on the outlook for 2009. Adjusted EBIT unchanged. We're still targeting last year's strong results and I would like to highlight unchanged although the impact from the crisis is more severe than we had originally anticipated.</p>
          <p>As far as net income is concerned, we think we can be a bit more precise now regarding adjusted net income, previously we targeted minus 10% compared to last year, now we believe we will fall into the range of minus five to minus 10%, basically this precision is based on our view that both interest result and tax rate will come out slightly more favorably than we had anticipated at the beginning of this year.</p>
          <p>As far as 2010 is concerned we have no news. That concludes my remarks and we are all now open for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So, operator, we are ready for the Q&amp;A. As usual please everyone limit your questions to two and also please speak slowly and clearly as it makes our lives here easier. Operator, the questions please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Ladies and gentlemen we are now starting question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. The first question is from Martin Young from Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon to everybody. First question relates to your comments on the Pan-European Gas business, just a bit of clarification around what you were saying about price and volume. In terms of price, are you saying that you expect no further declines from the levels that you have been achieving in the first half of 2009? But obviously that would then suggest that there is an ongoing price &#x2013; negative price impact that will be retained going forward in the, I guess in the amounts of about &#x20AC;370 million.</p>
          <p>And the second part of that question, on the volume, you suggested that you were 15 terawatt hours down during the first half of the year, but you might see some recovery in the second half of the year. What sort of year-on-year movements in terawatt hours would you expect?</p>
          <p>And then just a bit of clarification on the Energy Trading business, I totally appreciated that we shouldn't look at doubling this number, but in terms of optimization given that you benefited by about 240 million in the first half of the year, can we look at doubling that level of optimization year-on-year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. First on Pan-European Gas, just maybe to try to be more precise with regard to my comments. As mentioned before, the negative price effect is roughly &#x20AC;370 million in the first six months compared to last year. What I was trying to say was that we think in a way we've reached the bottom and there are not material additional negative developments we would expect in the second half of the year. Meaning, when we comment, then, in 12 months, I hope to be able to say that the negative effect will not be materially worse than the 370 mentioned so far. As it relates to the volume, I said that we see roughly 15 terawatt hours lost first half of this year due to effects we would attribute to the economic crisis. That number we think is likely to be repeated in the second half of the year i.e. year-on-year, the total impact could be roughly 30 terawatt hours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As it relates to Energy Trading, I mean I don't expect &#x2013; I mean, I'm obviously not going to give you a full year forecast for that business, I guess what we were trying to highlight was that prop trading, I think one should never really plan for significant numbers there. We are happy to take whatever we get there in a way, so in particular do not use last year's strong results.</p>
          <p>As far as the asset optimization business is concerned the effect of the businesses that have been transferred cannot be completely doubled for the year in particular because the Gazprom contract that I mentioned were actually already transferred in Q4 of last year. So that will be a positive transfer effect just in three quarters and not in four quarters when you will at the end of the year do a year on year comparison and that's sort of the main item one would need to correct for, otherwise probably the first half of the year is a good proxy for the second half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but if you look at something like the CO2, I appreciate that you could double that in the second half of the year of 2009 to get the full year impact, but presumably when we think about this business over the longer-term you've got a lot of discretion as to where the profit sits whether it sits in, say the UK because you set one CO2 transfer price or wherever it sits in Energy Trading because you set the different CO2 transfer price, which suggest to me that this business doesn't have a great deal of predictability going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great deal of what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Predictability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Predictability. I &#x2013; it is a fair comment. This is a fair comment. I mean what we are showing in Energy Trading is essentially the commodity price swings that exists. There is a transfer pricing mechanism in place which in the first &#x2013; which now is a little bit impacted by the fact that we have created Regis one-and-a-half years ago. This change in transfer price will go away, but overall we accept the point that it is difficult over many years to predict the Energy Trading business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Martin. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Bobby Chada from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. It's Bobby Chada. I had two questions, the first on Pan-European Gas again, you highlighted the negative move at Ruhrgas International, which I think was 115 million in the first half. I think last year Ruhrgas International contributed something in the order of 270 million, so does this imply that it's only just breaking even in the first half? And would you expect it to materially improve than the second half?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, you said that you lost 15 terawatt hours in the Gas business, you think due to the economic crisis which you expect to be repeated in H2. I wondered how this tallied with your slide on page 28 of the financial presentation, where, obviously the volumes lost seems to be significantly bigger, particularly in the reseller segment, are you implying that the delta between the 15 terawatt hours and what we can see on this page has been lost to effectively to competitors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let the &#x2013; the answer to the second one, yes. And as far as E.ON Ruhrgas International is concerned, the minus 150 I mentioned was F&#xF6;ldg&#xE1;z. Overall, Ruhrgas International is down compared to prior year &#x20AC;116 million. For the full year, we actually do expect quite some recovery in particular with regard to E.ON F&#xF6;ldg&#xE1;z because here we have reached agreements with the governments under which we will recover some of the losses, actually a lion's share of the losses we had incurred in particular in the last 12 months, but again that positive effect will only show up in the second half of 2009 and also to some extent in 2010. So indeed we do expect a recovery in Ruhrgas International in the second half of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And &#x2013; but you would expect that recovery to sort of be phased then over the second half of '09 and the first half of 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In &#x2013; yes, but you will already see a significant recovery in the second half of 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And in the Sales and Trading business then given the significant volume declines due to competition, I mean is this a rebased level of volumes that we should expect to work off going forward? It feels like a big step down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Let me &#x2013; maybe my answer is too short. We clearly have lost volume to competitors. There is another effect and that is that many of the Ruhrgas customers have flexibility in their contracts, so they have a certain volume that they need to purchase, but they can decide as to when they purchase it during the course of the year.</p>
          <p>Given the quite significant difference between spot prices and the prices under the long-term supply agreements with the gas purchasing countries, the &#x2013; it is &#x2013; it has actually been favorable for many of the Ruhrgas customers to purchase volumes that they need spot or to actually use volumes that they have stored in their own storage with the expectation to then buy volume or fill up their storage capacity later in the year. So the volume drop in the second half of 2009 should clearly be much lower than the volume drop we have seen in the first half of this year. So you have the effect of the crisis, you have higher competition and you have this intra year movements. And those three effects essentially make up the drop we have seen in the first half of 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Deborah Wilkens from Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Two questions, first of all, the run rate of the CapEx in the first half was 4.4 billion, but in your slide you are showing a 13 billion target for the year. Could you help us just understand where the nine billion demand comes from and whether or not that's still a realistic level? That was my first question. The second question, if you could possibly just help us, the positive power price impact for example, in Central Europe should be over &#x20AC;200 million based on the higher prices in your nuclear and hydro; where might I find that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The first question, Deborah, the &#x2013; you would need to correct the number for the second half of the year by the asset swap issue with Gazprom that's included there. We show it as economic investments, although it is cash wise not a &#x2013; it's not a cash outflow, but similar to the Statkraft transaction we show it as an economic investment. Here the amount is roughly three billion, so mentally you would have to take that out for the sort of &#x2013; of the full year number. And then you see that, essentially the second half of this year is slightly higher than the first half of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the price effect is concerned, they will show up &#x2013; it comes back to Martin's point, actually, partially inside Central Europe and partially inside Energy Trading.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but &#x2013; my difficulty is that you said I think that Energy Trading has about 40 million from Central Europe and then you are showing a price impact in Central Europe of also around 50 or so if remember correctly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I just don't know how to get to that 200, 250 level which it should be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. 50 million is the generation impact in energy &#x2013; sorry, in Central Europe, 47 actually, that amount. This is both a price effect and the volume effect, there is a slightly lower volume in the first half of 2009. The 40 million I mentioned when I spoke about transfer price effect is similar to the UK repricing of CO2 certificates, so that's not the price effect that you are referring to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So there is an additional impact from Central Europe in trading?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You can call it, yes, it's essentially the &#x2013; marketing the Central European assets and clearly some of that extra value is now shown inside Energy Trading, correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the past that was part of Central Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Simon Flowers from Bank of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks very much. Just a question on disposals. You're retaining for the time being some of the Th&#xFC;ga assets, but you sound quite self-assured in the statement that these are for resale. Are you fairly confident that that sale can take place in a timely fashion?</p>
          <p>And the second question I've got is another one on Pan-European Gas and I just wondered we are only three &#x2013; I beg your pardon, six months on from when you talked about your 2010 targets and I wondered if the way that gas markets are panning out both in terms of the supply and trading profits that you've announced today and also where gas prices are in an upstream level, if you'd factored these &#x2013; this background into your guidance of 2010 please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Shall I will start with the disposal programs first, perhaps on the remaining Th&#xFC;ga assets which we are not including in the transaction as we said today. Basically in the process of selling the whole of Th&#xFC;ga of course, we got a clear idea of what the potential buyer community is for the other assets. In some cases it's just the companies themselves that are interested to buy the outstanding shares which we are then prepared to sell. So the process will start immediately now to dispose of the other Th&#xFC;ga assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as your second question is concerned if &#x2013; I would answer with two aspects. We have clearly anticipated a significant drop in the profitability of Ruhrgas compared to the 2008 numbers. I hope everyone heard that loud and clear when we present this on the 10th of March. And as we were highlighting today or as we are highlighting today, not all can be attributed to the economic crisis. It is also competition that has caused a drop here, point one. Point two, so in that sense yes, we had anticipated a significant drop in the profitability of Ruhrgas for both 2009 and 2010.</p>
          <p>Second comment, clearly I would say that the impact from the crisis that we have seen in the first six months of this year is higher than we had originally thought both in gas and in power. Goes back to my comments on my very first page, it is higher. Now having said that, I think Wulf mentioned, we have seen some improvement in June and also July over the months before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regulation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Peter Bisztyga from Liberum Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. Got two questions if I may. First of all, sorry to sort of belabor this Ruhrgas issue, but it looks like the decline in volumes year-on-year was about sort of 73, 74 terawatt hours, which suggests that there's sort of 60 terawatt hours from the impact of competition and also these deferrals from customers that you spoke about. Can you actually split that and tell us how much of that 60 terawatt hours was actually lost due to competition so it's kind of gone permanently? So that's my first question.</p>
          <p>And then my second question regards the cost savings, could you sort of clarify exactly how much cost savings you brought forward into 2010 versus your original expectations? Can you sort of give an indication of what this means for your guidance for 2010? Do these worse economic effects and these sort of significant competition effects in Ruhrgas gas offset that benefit for 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. 2010, we're not updating our forecast neither up nor down. Right now, it's the same number we expect. Granted, certain things have &#x2013; seem to develop better, I would say on the regulatory side, we would by now be slightly more optimistic. On the other hand, we've seen the crisis have a bigger impact, maybe there will be some recovery. It's too early to now come up again with a new number. We will not every three &#x2013; every quarter update the target there. That's just on your last point.</p>
          <p>As it relates to the volume, we &#x2013; it's difficult to breakdown how much is volume lost due to competition and how much is volume that we think will reoccur in the second half of the year. By the way just one comment, when we've lost volume to a customer I would not say this is volume lost permanently, we can obviously also fight back here which Ruhrgas will do.</p>
          <p>And let me go through the numbers, first half of the year.15 terawatt hours as I mentioned is what we would say is caused by the crisis. And we think there are volumes that can be attributed to competitive losses that are around 20 to 30 terawatt hours, then there is roughly 10 terawatt hours quite frankly that have been transferred for marketing purposes to Energy Trading, and the remainder roughly should be volumes that we expect to see again in the second half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Lueder Schumacher from UniCredit London.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. And, I've got two &#x2013; two and half questions actually but as the half one is referring to one that was already asked before, I hope that's all right. It's just on the much discussed gas business, you did mention that, you see as far as prices are concerned and the 370 million that we reached a bottom in H1, can you just remind us why that is the case, I must have missed the reason, do you expect competition to ease off? Do you just think the forward curve is now high enough that you don't expect any further downturn there? Why do you think we've reached the bottom H1? That's my first question.</p>
          <p>The second one refers to your hedging, you did mention earlier that you obviously accelerated your hedging policy, certainly as far as the 2011 contract is concerned. I just wonder why that is the case. Did you see the price level for 2011 contract as particularly interesting at the moment?</p>
          <p>And the last question is on the UK business, you did mention that there has been some slight improvement on the retail side. I just wonder where &#x2013; if you can tell us where this leads the overall supply margin in the UK? And if you can't be too detail there, maybe just indicate whether it's actually in positive or negative territory at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay in the first half &#x2013; let me take the last one first because that's the easiest one. In the first half of the year the retail margin is actually still negative. We expect further recovery during the course of the year and our target is to actually have at the end a slightly better than break even in retail. That's on your 2.5 question or third question.</p>
          <p>As far as the hedging 2011 is concerned, I think you are essentially asking whether the thesis that there will be further downward pressure on power prices in the outer years given that oil and gas markets could continue to be decoupled in the outer years. In a way I would not exactly like to comment because I would not like to completely share Energy Trading's view on the development of the power prices in the future. But I think I was indicating with my statements that we are now proceeding at normal pace that we take a fairly neutral view here.</p>
          <p>As far as the first question or first half question, the -- why may we have reached a bottom, I think the issue here is that we clearly see first signs of at least some mild recovery in the overall demand, that's one aspect. Secondly, we also see the delta between spot prices and purchase price under the long-term purchase agreements that delta to become more narrow. And three, just simply looking at the results of competitive bids that we had to hand-in during the last eight weeks, we have the feeling that the situation is much more back to normal than it was before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Perfect. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. And next question is from Andreas Thielen from MainFirst.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. Firstly on the investments you pointed already out that part is non-cash, would it be fair to assume that roughly speaking 24, would be 25 billion of the 30 billion program is cash flow, the three years to 11? And secondly, with respect to the PerformtoWin and the agreements with the unions, are you prepared to say how much of the -basically the number of employees which are going to be either reduced or externalized under the program?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me start with the second one. We have not disclosed any figures there and we have not actually &#x2013; no trust that we have not disclosed and we don't know them exactly yet. Therefore it would be premature to release figures. You may have seen some numbers in the press and if you compare those numbers with numbers which were published a few weeks ago, you see there is a significant drop. And that's what we expect. So it is &#x2013; and secondly, we have agreed with the unions that there is no forced dismissal.</p>
          <p>So we will try everything to retain people via retraining and redeploy them in the organization. So it's not a big issue and it is also not a big issue as concerned our overall savings targets, which we have just confirmed again with the 1.5 billion and we were able in the process of the validation to see some more potential in some other areas therefore we were able to compensate for some of the potential which we had to give up in the process of our negotiation. So the overall target is intact and we can confirm it today. The second is on investments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on investments the &#x2013; of that 30 billion roughly 27 should be cash. And just when &#x2013; PerformtoWin was mentioned, I think &#x2013; I don't know who asked the question, but I think we didn't answer what the changes are on a year-on-year basis compared to our prior guidance. I think originally we had sourced that in 2009 the effect would be roughly 200 million positive and now we think it's &#x2013; on average I would say roughly 300 &#x2013; roughly 100 million more and for 2010, I recall we had over six to 700 million effect and that we see as 800 to roughly 1 billion obviously still a range, but we are still in the process of getting into the implementation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Is the question answered?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Christopher Kuplent from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One follow-up to the cost cutting, you were mentioning 500 million of restructuring costs, would you be able to tell us whether you've already started i.e., whether you have already incurred restructuring costs in the first half, how much you expect to incur for the full year 2009 and whether there'll still be restructuring costs regarding this program in 2010 and '11? And whether your numbers that you have now increased are net of this restructuring cost or not, that would be my first question.</p>
          <p>And second, and I just wanted to ask for an update regarding Yuzhno Russkoye. I appreciate you don't want to give us an update on 2010, but as far as I remember, the full consolidation of Yuzhno Russkoye was still part of your 2009 EBIT guidance and now the EBIT guidance hasn't changed Yuzhno Russkoye seems to be delayed. Can you shed some more light on that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We have not taken restructuring charges of that 500 million in the first half of this year. What will now happen is that we will get specific agreements negotiated with the unions and only when they exist you can book a provision, which will then be in a way eaten up or consumed, sounds better, in the outer years. Also, to highlight, Chris, that restructuring charge I expect to be also shown in what we call restructuring cost i.e., underneath adjusted EBIT. So in that sense the numbers we are showing for savings to 1.5, in particular that was mentioned is a gross number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, any timing that you can give us on that 500 million? Will there be a provision of 500 in the second half and then you'll eat into that or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That answer is, I don't know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the closing of Yuzhno Russkoye is concerned, we think that it is likely to going to happen during the month of October, whether that's beginning or end I do not dare to say. But all material approvals have now been granted and it's essentially technical aspects such as setting up the trading company and things like that that are now being executed that takes some time. And again, we think the month of October is the most &#x2013; is kind of there's a 90% chance it will be in that month. What does that mean for the full-year contribution of Yuzhno Russkoye. We are still hopeful to get almost the full 12 months somehow included into EBIT.</p>
          <p>But just to remind everyone, in case &#x2013; essentially what we will do is we will try to then push all the volume that is equivalent to a full year volume into the time period where we own a stake in that field. Whatever volume cannot be reflected in that remaining time period, we will get &#x2013; we will be compensated in cash, which will then technically not show up as EBIT, but will however still be money to the company. But so far, let's say an October 1 closing, we are optimistic that this can give us a full-year effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's what we are assuming here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Who is next?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Alberto Ponti from Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I had &#x2013; have been answered, but just to go back on 2010, adjusted EBIT guidance, I appreciate you don't want to change it. But if I go back then, what has happened since then is that you have accelerated your Performance-to-Win program, so you have more cost cutting. The hedges you have reported in the first half of this year obviously were good and with good -- achieved prices and forward par prices have since then increased and you also have had some positive developments on the regulatory front. So obviously you've not changed your guidance, but in terms of just for the sake of the discussion, don't you think your 2010 numbers are now somewhat conservative? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, they are as conservative or &#x2013; and as optimistic as before. Again, I really don't want to get into speculation here, otherwise we can almost have a monthly update on what we believe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Vincent De Blic from Cazenove.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Questions please on disposals, the first one on Th&#xFC;ga, do you expect any impact of the disposal on your commercial relationships with utilities which are part of Th&#xFC;ga? I guess you are probably their main supplier of electricity and gas. Could that change with the transaction? And secondly on the U.S. you mentioned on the slide on the WKE unwind that it increases the strategic and financial flexibility for E.ON. I just wondered whether you could be a bit more specific about what you mean by strategic and financial flexibility, is it potential disposals or are there more scenarios you could consider? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually starting with the second one, we are considering our options and we'll certainly as always come out with results when we are there. So there is no more we can do at the moment, but certainly WKE had been a rather stumbling &#x2013; a significant stumbling block in considering and executing any options, so therefore it gives us more flexibility, that's what we can say. On the Th&#xFC;ga side, the commercial impact is not there because there is no rights to supply those minority positions in the Th&#xFC;ga portfolio.</p>
          <p>Traditionally, I mean Ruhrgas has built a position in Th&#xFC;ga in their participations even before Th&#xFC;ga was part of Ruhrgas, when it was still part of the E.ON Group. And therefore those &#x2013; let's say commercial relationships will continue on a purely commercial basis and there was no legal opportunity or right to supply those municipalities before and that will be the case also after the transaction. So Ruhrgas has to try hard in a more increasingly competitive market to sell to those participations as before, so no direct impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Benjamin Leyre from Exane.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions please, the first one is on Kr&#xFC;mmel. Are there any discussions ongoing with Vattenfall that could lead you to take over the ownership of the operations of Kr&#xFC;mmel? And the second one is on the tax rate. Can you help us on the sort of non-effective tax rate beyond 2009? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the first one on Kr&#xFC;mmel. I mean there are no such discussions underway. What we are doing at the moment on a sort of working level, an expert level we are discussing all the technical aspects and the root causes for the incident that happened some weeks ago and what could have been done potentially to prevent this, but we are not the operator of this plant. And therefore we have only limited possibilities to influence the operations. So it's more a technical exchange on various aspects, but we are not considering at the moment seriously to take over operations, which is not easy anyway because <mark type="inaudible" /> is licensed to operate this plant. So as long as they keep that, there is not even a legal possibility for us to move in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the tax rate is concerned, it's actually always very difficult to predict the tax rate in a given year because as some of the effects for example we see this year go back to things that had happened in the past, but impact this year's tax rate. Overall we would typically see the tax rate for the group somewhere in the range between 25 and 27%. Again, this year we expect to be slightly better for some specific reasons, some go back actually many years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll take two more questions and then we'll close the call. Operator, please another question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We have a second question from Bobby Chada from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Thanks very much. My follow-up was again on the gas business. You mentioned that participations in the regulated piece had increased markedly. I think the figure was up about 400. Sorry I forget the number, but it was up a lot. Could you explain why and what you expect that to do in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>400 is what you said?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, no, I'm sorry I forgot the figure, but you just gave a number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there is a 90 million higher income from participations there and it is related to two businesses. Give me one second. I need to look that up. It is two companies, one is called Nitra and the other is called NETG and here we have higher income from those participations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But again it's not 400 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, it's 92, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our last question is from Deborah Wilkens from Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have two follow-up questions. One was as you are obviously making such good progress on the disposal program I was hoping you could provide us either today or the next time you're communicating with, an overview of the earnings impact of all the disposals. I mean so far you say you're midway there. And it would be great to also have a bit more transparency in terms of exactly how that's going to affect the earnings going forward. And then the second question was just, who are you actually seeing as your tougher &#x2013; toughest competitors in the German gas market, to whom do you think you've lost the customers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the disposals, the two major impacts this year would really be Th&#xFC;ga, where I think closing is rather at the back end of the year. I think we mentioned that the earnings contribution from that business that we are giving away in 2008 was &#x20AC;215 million. So essentially I mean it's the number of months if you assume it's roughly spread evenly across the three quarters what will go out this year. And as far as the asset swap is concerned, I think on that one we will be more explicit when we talk about 2010 next year.</p>
          <p>This year, the impact will not be so significant because the closing is rather at the back end of the year. It will all in all have a slightly negative impact this year, which is somewhere between 100 and &#x20AC;140 million, depending a bit when exactly the closing is going to be. And again as far as 2010 is concerned, we will come back also quite frankly when the overall package is completed, which will happen this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then what are the competitors, to whom we've lost business in the German market, it's not a single one. We see everyone be pretty active there, the likes of Gaz De France, Shell, Wingas and others that are there. It's not that there is one player that stands out that is sort of going into this market more aggressively. It's really many.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks everyone. I think we should conclude the call. If there are more questions, we are more than happy to answer them on the IR level. Thanks everyone for participating and see you next time. Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you very much for joining our conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>