<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1343412" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-11-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>188</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Mark G. Papa, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Timothy K. Driggers, Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Joe Allman</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Scott Wilmoth</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Biju Perincheril</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">David Tameron</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Leo Mariani</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Brian Singer</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Brian Lively</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen and welcome to today's EOG Resources 2010 Third Quarter Earnings Results Conference Call.</p>
          <p>And at this time, I would like to introduce Mr. Mark Papa. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, and thanks for joining us. We hope everyone has seen the press release announcing third quarter 2010 earnings and operational results.</p>
          <p>This conference call includes forward-looking statements. The risks associated with forward-looking statements have been outlined in the earnings release and EOG's SEC filings, and we incorporate those by reference for this call.</p>
          <p>This conference call contains certain non-GAAP financial measures. The reconciliation schedules for these non-GAAP measures to comparable GAAP measures can be found on our website at www.eogresources.com.</p>
          <p>Effective January 1, 2010, the SEC now permits oil and gas companies, in their filings with the SEC, to disclose not only proved reserves, but also probable reserves as well as possible reserves. Some of the reserve disclosures on this conference call and webcast, including those for the South Texas Eagle Ford, Barnett Combo and New Mexico Leonard plays may include potential reserves or estimated reserves not necessarily calculated in accordance with or contemplated by the SEC's latest reserve reporting guidelines. We incorporate by reference the cautionary note to U.S. investors that appears at the bottom of our press release and Investor Relations page of our website.</p>
          <p>With me this morning are Loren Leiker, Senior EVP, Exploration; Gary Thomas, Senior EVP, Operations; Tim Driggers, Vice President and CFO; and Maire Baldwin, Vice President of Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>And updated investor relations presentation was posted to our website last night and we included 2010 and revised preliminary volume estimates for 2011 and 2012. We've reduced our full year 2010 growth guidance from 13% to 9%, about 70% of this reduction relates to North American natural gas volumes where we're now projecting minus 2% growth versus the previous estimate of plus 2%. Obviously in this price environment we're not incented to grow gas volumes. Our conversion from a natural gas to an oil company is still on track and we expect total crude, condensate and natural gas liquids to comprise approximately 67% of our 2011 North American revenues.</p>
          <p>However, because of lower cash flows from weak gas prices, higher frac cost, delays in frac equipment availability and the pattern drilling used to maximize resource plays, we've also reduced our 2011 and 2012 liquids growth targets to better reflect real world conditions. Even with these reductions we expect to grow crude and condensate 36%, 53% and 30% in 2010, '11 and '12. We've also made progress regarding asset sales and I'll report on that later in the call.</p>
          <p>I'll now review our third quarter net income and discretionary cash flow. Then provide some operational highlights and discuss our capital structure. Tim Driggers will provide some financial details and I'll close with comments regarding our macro hydrocarbon view and concluding remarks. As outlined in our press release, for the third quarter EOG reported a net loss of 70.9 million or $0.28 per share.</p>
          <p>For investors who follow the practice of industry analysts who focus on non-GAAP net income to eliminate mark-to-market impacts and certain one-time adjustments as outlined in the press release, EOG's third quarter adjusted net income was $46.6 million or $0.18 per share. For investors who follow the practice of industry analysts who focus on non-GAAP discretionary cash flow, EOG's DCF for the third quarter was $755.4 million.</p>
          <p>I'll now address operational results and I'll start with the South Texas Eagle Ford. The bottom line here is that our confidence in individual well results and total a 900 million barrels of oil equivalent net after royalty reserve estimate has increased since our April analyst conference. Because this is such a huge net oil accumulation and I believe investors have undervalued this asset, I'm going to take several minutes and provide an update based on our results from the last six months. Our press release provided details from a number of good wells, most of which have only commenced sales in the last month.</p>
          <p>Here's what we know right now about our asset after drilling 77 wells, 59 of which are either producing or shut-in for offset fracs or waiting on fracs. First, the Eagle Ford formation is not a typical shale but instead it's a borderline conventional carbonate reservoir. Pressure and flow data from our wells indicate we're seeing a lot of matrix flow, i.e. a significant amount of flow from the rock fabric itself, which is a very good sign.</p>
          <p>Second, the Eagle Ford is a predictable play. We have now drilled a large enough population of wells and we're getting very repeatable results across the 120-mile extent of our acreage block.</p>
          <p>Third, we've had a 100% well success rate within the acreage and the horizon as we defined to contain our estimated 0.9 billion barrels. For a start-up play this is outstanding.</p>
          <p>Fourth, for our 0.9 billion barrels of estimated reserves, the mix is 77% black oil. The oil in our portion of the reservoir has some unique characteristics that enhance the recovery factor. We've kept this information proprietary until now, but with our acreage tied up, we can now talk without losing a competitive advantage. I will apologize in advance for getting too technical, but this is a very important point because some analysts expressed concern regarding recovery factors from a pure oil reservoir.</p>
          <p>Specifically, there is an extraordinarily high differential between the initial reservoir pressure and the pressure at which solution gas breaks out of the oil, technically called the bubble point pressure. Across our acreage, the original reservoir pressure averages 7,200 PSI and the bubble point pressure averages 2,500 psi. This unusually high spread provides for a larger than normal fluid expansion recovery factor. That's why we're so confident with our 0.9 billion barrel reserve estimate.</p>
          <p>Fifth, the reservoir can be broken into two zones, east and west. In the east, we have two targets, the upper and lower Eagle Ford. These zones are relatively thick and high quality. A typical well here is the Harper #10H well which IP'd at 1,070 barrels of oil per day and 980 Mcf per day. In this same area the Cusack Clampit wells which were highlighted in the press release IP'd at rates ranging from 860 to 1,800 barrels of oil per day with 1 to 1.8 million cubic feet a day of rich gas each. We have 100% working interest in all these eastern wells. In this eastern area, we'll typically drill 4,000 foot laterals and expect average reserves per well of 460 MBOE net after royalty.</p>
          <p>The western area has only one target, the lower Eagle Ford and the rock is a bit thinner. Typical wells here are the Haynes #1H and Hoff #6H wells which IP'd at 979 and 629 barrels of oil per day respectively. We have 100% working interest in these wells also. To maximize our economics in the west, we'll drill 6,000 foot long laterals and expect 430 MBOE per well net after royalty. These per well recoveries are considerably higher than we noted in April.</p>
          <p>Sixth, the typical decline curve for both areas indicates we'll produce 40% of a well's reserves in the first five years. We originally thought we'd need roughly 2,800 wells to capture the 0.9 billion barrels of oil equivalent, but now it will take us a lot fewer wells to monetize this asset. Overall, we believe we can achieve a $12 to $15 per BOE direct finding cost across the entire play. We plan to run 14 rigs, drill 231 net Eagle Ford wells in 2011.</p>
          <p>And seventh, the direct rates of return that we expect to achieve from both the east and western wings of our sweet spot will return to the same rate of return goals as we gave at our April analyst conference. As we exit the science stage and enter the program drilling phase in 2011 and '12, we expect to achieve between 66% and 95% direct after-tax rates of return.</p>
          <p>In order to decrease our average completed well cost back to the original range by the end of next year on a normalized lateral length basis, we are implementing drilling enhancements and completion design modifications, as well as contractual and self-sourced frac solutions.</p>
          <p>Let me take a minute here to discuss our volume growth projections. This applies not only to the Eagle Ford, but also to our other oil resource plays. EOG is a company that has rarely missed its volume targets over the past 11 years, yet now we're revising our 2010-'12 numbers downward. Part of this is very simple, at current and projected gas prices we have no interest in growing gas volumes.</p>
          <p>Regarding oil, our individual wells are performing as expected, but we underestimated the downtime for pattern drilling the delays for frac equipment. As we previously stated, optimizing shale oil or gas recovery requires drilling five or six side by side wells, fracing them simultaneously and only then turning all wells to production. Therefore, if frac equipment is delayed, it doesn't affect only one well, but cascades to five or six wells and the associated production. We believe our updated volume estimates now properly account for this methodology.</p>
          <p>To give you a little more color on these frac equipment delays, we're currently experiencing delays in almost every one of our divisions and have about 100 wells experiencing delays. Since of our most budget is oil wells, this disproportionately affects oil volumes. These delays won't go away anytime soon and our new 2011 and 2012 growth forecasts assume the frac delays continue until at least mid-2011.</p>
          <p>Moving to an emerging oil play, we're pleased to report success on additional acreage in our New Mexico Leonard shale. Last quarter we told you we had proven up 31,000 of our 120,000 net acres and we can now report we've proven up an additional 18,000 acres. Our Elk Wallow 11 #1H and 2H wells are producing at 337 and 505 barrels of oil per day with 3.1 and 4.8 million cubic feet of rich natural gas respectively from an upper and lower Leonard interval, indicating we have two separate targets in this area. We have 100% working interest in these wells. We expect our Leonard reserves will likely increase from the original 65 million barrels of oil equivalent NAR estimate. Because acreage explorations aren't as critical here, we'll develop this asset at a relatively slow pace in 2011.</p>
          <p>Our Barnett Combo results continue to be consistent and we're in a steady manufacturing mode. For the second quarter in a row we've expanded the core area, this time from 150,000 to 160,000 acres. This play keeps getting bigger. Earlier this year we highlighted our first very good horizontal well in the eastern portion of our acreage where we previously targeted only verticals. Since then we've completed many successful eastern area wells, both horizontals and verticals.</p>
          <p>Recent successful horizontals are the Strickland A 2H, Settle C 3H and the Christian C 3H with IP rates of 1,118, 731 and 954 barrels of oil per day, with 1.6 and 2.1 million cubic feet a day of rich gas. EOG has working interest varying from 90 to 98% in these wells. Two successful verticals wells in the east are the Strickland 1 and Slagle 1 which IP'd at 865 and 539 barrels of oil per day. We have 96 and 100% working interest in these wells respectively.</p>
          <p>We've also achieved good results in the western portion of Montague County with the Posey C 3H testing at 536 barrels of oil per day. We're currently operating 16 rigs in the combo and plan to run 16 rigs here in 2011. One other interesting feature here, although the combo produces about one-third oil, one-third NGLs and one-third residue gas, the current revenue split is over 90% liquids and less than 10% gas, consistent with our liquid shift.</p>
          <p>We plan to drill 258 Barnett combo wells in 2011. On our Barnett gas activity, essentially all of our Johnson County acreage is now held by production so we plan to drill zero Barnett gas wells in 2011.</p>
          <p>Moving to the Bakken, per well results continue to be as expected and we continue to prove up acreage outside our core area. The newest area is southwest of the core, where we've drilled several 640 acre spaced wells with good IPs. The Mandaree 4-15, 2-9, 10-5 and 6-20 wells IP'd at maximum gross rates of 1,490, 1,358, 840 and 1,175 barrels of oil per day respectively. We have 63% to 90% working interest in these wells.</p>
          <p>Our drilling within the Parshall core area has also yielded the expected results and we've seen no unusual declines here. Overall, we're happy with our North Dakota results and this asset is currently our single largest oil contributor, although that will change within a year or two as the Eagle Ford ramps up. We plan to drill 10 &#x2013; to run excuse me, 10 Bakken and Three Forks rigs in 2011. Also, about 25% of our 2010 wells were 1,280 acre spaced laterals and that 25% will grow to about 70% next year.</p>
          <p>Our Manitoba, Waskada oil volumes are finally growing after one of the wettest summers in 60 years which inhibited our activities. Net production has increased from 4,600 barrels of oil a day in January and we expect a year-end exit rate of 7,700 barrels per day.</p>
          <p>The last oil play I'll mention is the Niobrara, in southeastern Colorado &#x2013; excuse me, that's northeastern Colorado. We're currently running three rigs here. Two recent wells, the Critter Creek 5-10H and 9-15H at IP rates of 690 and 748 barrels of oil per day on restricted chokes and we have 100% working interest in both of these wells.</p>
          <p>Even though natural gas isn't currently in vogue, we have some upbeat news from the Marcellus and continued good news from Haynesville/Bossier where we are drilling to hold acreage. In the Marcellus, we've modified our frac program and our first four wells on the EOG/NFG joint venture acreage with these new style completions are very strong. The Clearfield County pump C 34H, 35H, 37H and 38H wells IP'd at 9.2, 8.5, 7.1 and 8 million cubic a day respectively. EOG has 50% working interest in these wells.</p>
          <p>In our Haynesville/Bossier area we continue to make good wells, such as ACLCO #1, Blackstone 4 #5 and Freeman Farms #1 wells, which IP'd 34, 23 and 26 million cubic feet a day respectively. We have 48%, 75% and 75% working interest in these wells. We've refined our mapping of play's sweet spots, and although we're not known as major Haynesville player, we believe EOG has a Haynesville/Bossier sweet spot acreage position that's as good or better than any other operator in the play.</p>
          <p>Current investor relations presentation has a chart showing EOG with 67% of our total acreage position in the sweet spots of this play. During 2011, we plan to drill the minimum number of wells here that is necessary to maintain our acreage position.</p>
          <p>In the Horn River Basin we're in the process of completing several wells and early results from three wells completed in the easy section show IPs between 16 and 22 million cubic feet a day. We won't be as active here in 2011 as we've been in 2010.</p>
          <p>Outside North America, our Trinidad asset is currently in a production mode and we will begin development drilling on Toucan discovery in the fourth quarter. This will provide deliverability to meet our 2011-'13 gas contracts. In China we expect to frac another well, the third by year end.</p>
          <p>Outside of operations, part of business plan involves selling some assets to partially cover our expected 2010 and 2011 operating cash flow shortfall. At our April analyst meeting our goal was to sell assets this year and maintain a maximum 25% net debt to cap total ratio. Since April, gas prices have obviously collapsed, so we've come up with a new capital plan. We expect to sell between 600 million and 1 billion of acreage and/or producing assets this year with almost all of that expected to close in the fourth quarter. I want to stress most of these deals are not yet closed.</p>
          <p>For 2011, we plan to sell at least $1 billion of primarily gas acreage or producing properties and we've raised the conceptual upper limit on our net debt to total cap ratio from 25%, to between 30% and 35%. Unlike others, we don't intend to sell or JV any of our horizontal oil plays. We intend to emerge from this transformation retaining 100% of the oil and combo assets that we've captured and we're willing to liquidate gas acreage or assets to achieve that goal.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn it over to Tim Driggers to discuss financial and capital structure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>For the quarter capitalized interest was $19.5 million. For the third quarter 2010, total exploration and development expenditures were $1.5 billion excluding asset retirement obligations. Total acquisitions for the quarter were $3 million. In addition, expenditures for gathering systems, processing plants and other property, plant and equipment were $107 million.</p>
          <p>During the third quarter we accepted bids to sell a portion of our Canadian shallow natural gas assets for net proceeds of $320 million. Additionally, these assets were considered to be held for sale and we recorded pre-tax impairment of $280 million to write down these assets to fair value.</p>
          <p>At quarter end total long term debt was $3.8 billion and the debt to total cap ratio was 27%. At September 30th, we had $28 million of cash giving us non-GAAP net debt of $3.7 billion and a net debt to total cap ratio of 27%.</p>
          <p>Yesterday with the earnings press release, we included a guidance table for the fourth quarter and the updated full year 2010. For the full year 2010, the effective tax range is 40% to 50%. Note that this is on a GAAP basis. We have also provided an estimated range of the dollar amount of current taxes that we expect to record during the fourth quarter and for the full year.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn it back to Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll now provide a few macro comments. Regarding oil, we're still rationally bullish based on the fact that global oil demand is currently 86 million barrels a day, the same as in 2008. And the demand has rebounded very nicely from last year. It's worth noting that 2010 global oil demand growth is the second greatest in the past 30 years. We've increased our 2011 hedge position slightly and currently have 10,000 barrels of oil a day hedged at $90.39.</p>
          <p>Regarding North American Natural Gas, the question is can it get much lower? And I guess time will tell. I expect the gas rig count to fall by about 200 rigs by mid-2011. We currently have 150 million cubic feet hedged in 2011 at 5.44 price and 200 million a day hedged for 2012 at a 5.57 price.</p>
          <p>Now let me summarize, in my opinion, there are three points to take away from this call: First, beginning in 2011, we are now predominantly an oil company based on our anticipated revenue mix and there is no other company our size that's growing oil and NGL volumes similar to EOG's rate.</p>
          <p>Second, our oil assets are generating consistent and repeatable results. I'm particularly pleased with the results this quarter from the Eagle Ford, Barnett combo, Leonard and Bakken. Regarding the Eagle Ford, two recent industry transactions for acreage in the oil window have ratified our asset value, particularly when noting that we were the first mover and have a premier oil window acreage.</p>
          <p>And third, although our capital plan has changed a bit since April, we're on track to sell significant natural gas properties in 2010 and have additional sales planned for 2011. Additionally we've paired our 2011 dry gas CapEx to the absolute minimum level to hold our Haynesville, Marcellus and Horn River acreage positions. Our goal is to retain and develop 100% of our oil assets without incurring excessive debt and if we lighten up on some natural gas assets in the process, so be it.</p>
          <p>Thanks for listening and now we'll go to Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And we'll go to our first question from Joe Allman from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Joe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, just a question on a gas asset, on &#x2013; you mentioned the Horn River Basin activity will be less next year than this year. Could you just talk about the development that you plan at the Horn River and do you have obligations at this point related to LNG facility?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The status of the Kitimat LNG facility is we're still teaming up with Apache and working on that and we're making, I'd say consistent progress, but I believe it's going to be year-end 2011 before we truly know if we have a firm project or not. So over the last three months we've clearly made some headway. But it's just going to be a slow progress.</p>
          <p>I believe the project's got a pretty strong chance of actually happening. I think all the elements are in place for it but we've still got a ways to go. And so what we've adopted in light of these very dismal North American gas conditions is we've done enough science wells now in the Horn River to have a pretty good feel for the reserves, potential per well deliverability and so on. And we're just going to &#x2013; for 2011 just take a minimalist approach in terms of our CapEx related to Horn River drilling in that particular area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's Helpful. And then, regarding the asset sales, in the second quarter conference call you mentioned acreage amount that you were going to sell in various places like Marcellus, Eagle Ford and Haynesville. Have there been changes to those plans?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And we don't want to really talk about anything specifically until we get some firmer situations, but generally I'd say in either 2010 or 2011, it's likely that we'll be divesting ourselves of a portion of the Marcellus acreage and a portion of what we'd call kind of our non-core Eagle Ford acreage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And what about the Haynesville? You were also going to sell some Niobrara?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The Haynesville, we've got a small amount of acreage there we'll probably liquidate, that's not going to be a substantial amount. And the Niobrara, we have divested of a little bit of the 400,000 acres, but we'll definitely be keeping the majority of that 400,000 acres.</p>
          <p>The best way to explain all this, Joe, is our &#x2013; on the natural gas front, we've got a huge gas inventory clearly in the Haynesville/Bossier in the sweet spot. We think probably between 9 and 10 Tcf. We're quite encouraged now with the Marcellus, our combined EOG/NFG acreage. We know we've got a ton of gas in the Horn River and certainly a bunch in the Uinta Basin and some in Johnson County in the Barnett. And what we'll be looking at selling over the next 18 months are properties that perhaps are long life existing gas properties that may be time to pass down to another operator.</p>
          <p>We're a company that over the last decade, we haven't sold much. We've been in accumulating mode that whole time, so we've got a pretty good inventory of existing properties to liquidate. And there are buyers out there even at these kind of gas price conditions and so we'll be liquidating some of those. And also, on some acreage that either we'd have to invest in drilling wise before it expires or something along those lines. So what we want to do is we want to emerge from this with the horsepower for gas of all those core plays I just mentioned to you.</p>
          <p>So if it turns out that gas turns out to be a bullish commodity over the next five or eight years that we've got a ton of horsepower there and we want to emerge from this with essentially 100% of all of our oil and combo plays. We believe we can do that during the next year or two even while we're liquidating some gas producing assets and some portions of some acreage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, very helpful, Mark. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our next question from Richard Dearnley from Longport Partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Could you talk about your Permian activity in the southeastern region in Erie and related counties, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean, what we can say about that particularly in those areas and it's no secret that the &#x2013; there is a play that's active called the Wolfcamp play, a horizontal play. We're aware that at least two public companies have made press releases recently and their press releases are basically predicated on an EOG well or wells in that area. And what they're saying is based on EOG's well results, we company A and B, have a new oil play.</p>
          <p>And we're, as typically our case, we'll talk about any new potential plays whenever we have sufficient data to provide an intelligent assessment to our -e Wall Street and at this point, it's just too early for us to comment, but we do have to recognize that our name is out there in the public relating to this play. So that's kind of a circuitous answer, but it's consistent with what we've given on previous plays in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is the 40-14 well as good as the rumors have it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I really can't comment on that at this time, Richard. Except to say that at some point down the road when we really feel that we've got our acreage position locked in and we have sufficient data from sufficient wells, then we can provide you a comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Scott Wilmoth from Simmons &amp; Co.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. You alluded to some &#x2013; increasing your self-source frac solutions and I know you guys have sourced sand in the Barnett. Are you thinking of continuing to do that in other basins or are you actually considering buying into pressure pumping equipment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Kind of our current situation, Scott, is that we are indeed self sourcing our fracs, if you will, in the Barnett, particularly in the combo play. We are not going into business of buying pressure pumping equipment, but we are &#x2013; we very much recognize that the cost and the availability of the equipment from major suppliers is just flat unacceptable to us really. And we're pursuing other avenues and the other avenues we'll just say we that expect to have those in place approximately mid-2011 and at that time we'll discuss exactly what those other avenues are.</p>
          <p>But it's &#x2013; if I give you one primary reason why we've had to lower our volume estimates here, it's been lack of availability of frac equipment. And as I mentioned earlier, we are literally just in essentially every division, we're literally waiting months, not weeks, not days, months for availability of frac equipment and the cost of those, that equipment when it does show up is I'd say has increased dramatically from our April analyst conference and that's just a situation that we have to come up with a plan to ameliorate that and we have a plan and we'll articulate it more clearly as we get to mid-year next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just jumping over to the Eagle Ford, you guys have had success with increasing the EURs, has your down spacing assumptions changed at all since your analyst day, that you guys are at 125 to 140 acre spacing? Can you kind of talk through how that's progressed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Scott, at the conference we were talking about I think 125 acre spacing for the eastern or northeastern portion of Eagle Ford and I think it's 140 acres from southwestern portion. We're still experimenting with that, we have lengthened our laterals because we now have really excellent quality 3D shot in both those areas, northeast and southwest. And we now know how long we can drill a lateral before we get in trouble with faulting that sort of thing. So we have extended our lateral lengths, probably from an average of say, 3,500 feet in both areas in the past to maybe 4,000 feet in the northeast and as Mark said earlier, about 6,000 feet on the southwest and the uplift we're showing on our EURs is really &#x2013; you can tie almost all of that uplift to just to these longer laterals at this point. So the bottom line is we're not yet calling on increased recovery efficiency or down spacing or anything like that to improve our EURs per well. We think that's still in the future for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then lastly, just on the rig count in general heading into 2011, it seems like you're going to stay flat in the combo in the Bakken and picking up in the Eagle Ford. Are there any other moving pieces up or down on the rig count that I'm missing there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we're going to, we're running 75 rigs and it looks like 2011 we'll be in the 75 to 80 rigs, as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Biju Perincheril from Jefferies &amp; Co.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Biju.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning. A couple of questions, first on the Canadian sale, if I read what was in the Q correctly, I think what you sold is about half of what I thought you were producing up there. So is there more Canadian solid gas production to be sold? And number two, from what you said earlier, are you now leaning towards monetizing more of your producing properties as opposed to raw acreage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, relating to the Canadian sale, yeah, the answer is it's likely that over the next 12 months that there will be additional Canadian shallow gas sold. We only sold a portion of it or basically what's announced in the press release is only a portion of that gas. And in terms of monetizing some gas assets, yeah, I would say that relative to our April analyst conference, we are now more likely, particularly in 2011 to monetize some producing gas assets, more than we were previously.</p>
          <p>If you look at our projected volume growth in North American gas for 2010, 2011 and 2012, it's negative '10, '11 and I think it's plus 1% for 2012, and those projected sales are reflected in those volumes. So those volumes we provided are not pro forma, we're assuming that we sell property X say first quarter next year, property Y by mid-year and so that's one of the reasons why you're seeing negative North American volume growth.</p>
          <p>Our feeling is, just on macro view, I'd love to be more optimistic on gas, I hope I'm wrong, but we are so long on gas assets in this company that we can liquidate some of these gas assets and still retain tremendous horsepower if we decide to grow gas assets in 2013, '14 or '15.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's fair. And then in the Eagle Ford, you talked about the lower and upper zones. Are you accessing, can you access both zones with one lateral or are you looking at two separate wells down the road?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's not a case where we're talking about a lateral that has one branch that goes to the upper and one to the lower, that is not what we're doing. Those Cusack Clampit wells that we highlighted in the press release, those wells have alternating, one well is in the lower then the next well beside it is in the upper, then the next well beside it is in the lower and the next well is in the upper. That's kind of similar to what we've done in the Barnett. So the way to look at it is the upper requires a separate well from the lower.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And then if you look at that trend, some of your best wells there, towards the northeastern part of your acreage, any thoughts on the acreage extending, what happens as you go further northeast?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we &#x2013; on last quarter's call we mentioned that we'd gotten the 3D shot over that northeast and 3D imaged a fault block that could extend the 160 mile length of this play another 20 miles to the northeast. So we have not yet drilled that fault block, but certainly we'll do so in the next multiple months and if that fault block works, then we do have a 20 mile extension potentially of the 160 miles.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Got it. Thanks, that's all I had.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from David Tameron from Wells Fargo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. A couple questions, if I think about 2011 CapEx, you said a little bit of an outspend. I mean, should we assume that the outspend is equivalent to the projected asset sales? Is that the right way to think about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we will furnish, David, a CapEx number on our next earnings call for 2011. But the way I'd suggest you think about it is we'll be targeting this 30% to 35% debt range and to us the 35% is kind of a red zone, that's kind of a zone we don't want to go north of. So we'll be managing the asset sales, we'll be looking at what are the product prices for next year and trying to sort all that out. But the predominant determinant there is going to be the debt level. And if we have to, we'll sell more assets to keep within that debt level or less assets depending on where we stand on the product prices and our capital structure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Another question, I went back and read the transcript from the second quarter last night and you guys, not you guys, but you made a number of comments about, you said infrastructure was tight, it looked like there are some delays on the frac side. How has the market changed between August and November?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That's a good point. Let me correct one thing, I misspoke a little bit earlier, I said 160 miles for Eagle Ford, that's really 120 miles with a possible 20 mile extension.</p>
          <p>In terms of the frac situation between April and today, it's really gotten worse. I mean, worse from a producer's viewpoint. It's literally at the point now where if we wanted to frac a well and we call up one of the major service companies, typically they'll say, well we can get you maybe right after the first of the year and the price, we'll tell you the first of the year, but it's going to be even higher than your worst case scenario to frac this well and if you don't like that particular price or availability, we've got a lot of other people that are needing fracs. So it's &#x2013; I would say we certainly had a peak drilling activity several years ago when gas was $9 or $10 and there was a frenzy of activity but the frac situation was not as tight then as it is today in my opinion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We said that the second quarter that the cost would &#x2013; and stimulation was up 20% to 40%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Today we would say it's 40, maybe as high as 50% more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. One more big picture question. If I think about the PV and the impact of pushing some of that drilling back out years. Obviously the value is still there, but it takes a couple more years to get it. Do you guys have internal NAV model? And I assume you do, care to share what the next two years, the slowdown in production does to that model? How should we think about value creation other than being pushed back a couple years? Because obviously the CapEx, I mean it's costing more to drill. Anyway I'll shut up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we're not going to try and give you a NAV for any of our assets or so. But I mean, the only point I'll say, there is nobody else in North America other than maybe the heavy oil guys, who have captured essentially in one play close to a billion barrels and if this discovery were made in a deepwater Gulf of Mexico, it would be highly heralded, newspaper headlines, so on and so forth. We can beat the britches off on a direct finding cost of whatever a deepwater finding cost is and we can beat the britches off a heavy oil project. And so we have a gem of a project and yeah, maybe the PV has been pushed back potentially a year or six months, but when you look at it in a bigger picture scale, that's not all that meaningful in terms of a deferred PVs as far as we look at it. That's as far as I'll go, David, with giving you an answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Worth a shot. All right. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have our next question from Leo Mariani from RBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Leo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. A couple quick questions here for you. Previously on the debt to cap side, you were at 20%, 25%. Mark, you talked about 35% being your max red zone. Does that factor in the effect of the asset sales? So I guess what I'm asking is post asset sales next year, you're still going to be at 35%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, our game plan is between now and 2012 to be no more than 35% and that does factor in, that assumes we do have asset sales in 2011, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Obviously you guys cut your oil and liquids production guidance for '11 and '12 and clearly you've articulated a lot of the reasons. Do you expect to also see a reduction on oil and liquids related CapEx as well the next couple of years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, we'll answer that when we provide CapEx guidance on the next earnings call, Leo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Jumping over to the Eagle Ford, what are you guys seeing right now in terms of well costs over there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, they're currently higher than what we forecasted in our April analyst conference and we're working to get those down. I mean the primary reason is the frac costs there are, in rough terms, maybe as much as a million bucks higher than what we would have estimated previously and we hope by mid 2011 with some of this self sourcing that we're talking about that we can get those costs more in line. But the costs have gone up, but also the reserves have gone up because we're drilling longer laterals so in term of the returns, this is likely to be an awesome project on returns unless oil prices collapse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. Okay. One comment you guys made is that it doesn't sound like you're selling much of your Niobrara acreage. I know you haven't declared victory on that, but does that indicate that you've got some optimism about the play here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's still, I mean, what we promised is at year end we'd give an update on the Niobrara, which would really translate to the next earnings call. The issues are &#x2013; we articulated the same as we did on our last call that much more heavily fractured play, so the initial production rates are going to be quite good. The question is what do those production rates look like 6 months, 12 months after the initial rates? And so we just need a bit more time to watch it before we really give you specifics on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. Okay. Jumping over to Trinidad real quick. I noticed that you guys reduced your international gas volumes for 2011. Is there some slippage there in the start up of Toucan and when you're going to be selling some of the gas there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's really due to the &#x2013; our projection of the internal markets. What happened when we had this big recession, worldwide recession in 2009, are the anticipated growth of new methanol and ammonia plants that we assumed would be built on the country of Trinidad, well those all got put on hold and so we anticipate that there may be some just some internal demand restrictions. We may not have as high a contract takes next year as we've enjoyed this year. It's &#x2013; we've got a little bit of a cautionary factor built into our numbers there for that &#x2013; Trinidad.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And it sounds like you sold a portion of the shallow Canadian gas. Could you let us know how much volumes were sold and what the reserves were associated with that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we'd just as soon not say that because we're in the process of working to sell the remainder of the gas and we don't want to set any particular parameters out there, or benchmarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But in your new production guidance for 2011, have you factored in the sale that you've already made there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that is correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Steve Emerson from Emerson Investment Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Emerson, we can't hear you. Please check your mute function. Mr. Emerson? And hearing no response, we'll move on to Brian Singer from Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As you highlighted, one of the key drivers in the change of your oil guidance is the result of the greater completion, tie-in delays in the key resource plays, can you provide more color on how long it takes to drill, complete and tie-in wells in the Eagle Ford, Barnett combo and Bakken today, what you assumed that that could get to previously in 2011 and 2012 and what you're assuming today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a pretty broad question there. As far as the time you spud a well, then you bring it on production, it could be anywhere from, depending on the play, anywhere from 60 to 90 days, probably on the higher end of that. And as far as just going forward here, Mark had mentioned that we expect maybe to have some relief on available pump services mid-year 2011. That may drop back from the 90 days to the 60 days, Brian. Does that answer your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It partially does. As so I guess, what then changed relative to where you were previously, were you assuming that that could have gone from 60 to 30 and now you're assuming it goes from 90 to 60, is that essentially the kind of key change in how you're thinking about things here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I guess one &#x2013; I'll take a crack at that, Brian. We always knew that we wanted to complete these wells in bunches, four, five or six wells together. But what we assumed back in April was if we called up a service company and said we need you to frac the well in three weeks that they'd show up in three weeks and we'd then frac five or six wells simultaneously. Now what we're finding is you have to schedule this four or five months in advance and instead of three weeks, you're really looking at four or five months to get those things done. And what it does, is it sets you back the whole &#x2013; not one well, but six wells production comes online many, many months later than what you expected.</p>
          <p>And then what it does for you is, well, we assumed we'd have an exit rate in December of this year of let's say X, back in April. Well now we know that exit rate is going to be less than that and so that's why the gross volumes that we're projecting now for next year and 2012 are going to be less. We're still going to have pretty dramatic year over year production growth, but we're compounding off a lower base than what we previously expected because we didn't achieve our goal this year. And then we built into it the fact that miraculously these frac equipment does not become instantly available on January 1st of '11. It's &#x2013; we don't see any real improvement there.</p>
          <p>The biggest improvement we're going to see, we believe in the frac equipment, short of our self sourcing if the gas rig count drops by a couple hundred rigs. And we believe by mid next year, my guess is 200 rigs, Gary Thomas is guessing 300 rigs dropping the gas rig count. But when that happens, if that happens, then all of a sudden, whatever frac equipment is tied up there becomes available for oil plays. So we're kind of hoping that happens for multiple reasons. One is the aggregate gas market and two is frac up &#x2013; free up equipment. Hopefully that gives you a little more color there, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks, that's helpful. And then when we look at change in your gas production expectations how should we think about the organic impact from a combination of reduced activity outside the Marcellus and Haynesville combined with the stronger results you've seen in the Marcellus and the Haynesville, is still kind of an organic decline or do the two offset each other?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. They don't &#x2013; we'll be selling more gas, we believe over the next 18 months than we're developing new gas. So it's &#x2013; I would say it's a sale related decline more than anything else. In other words, the impact of the total volume of gas we're likely to sell in million cubic feet a day is going to overwhelm our organic growth and the net is going to be slightly negative North American growth numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks. And then lastly, just a follow-up on one of the earlier CapEx questions, I know you don't have guidance officially for next year. But is the way we should just back into what you would be assuming today to assume the 10% growth, assume a billion in asset sales, 30% or 35% net debt to total cap assume strip commodity prices and then back into what CapEx implies. Is that essentially a good way of thinking about what you may be modeling internally?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we want to give that much clarity at this point in time because the asset sales we're looking at next year are probably a minimum of a billion dollars as we think about it today. But we'll give you more clarity by the next earnings call on that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our final question from Brian Lively from Tudor, Pickering Holt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just trying to get a little more color on the new debt to cap target. What are the primary drivers again for the increase from 25% to the 30% range and just wondering if that's a price issue, a realization versus hedges, or is it related to higher spending or some other reasons?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say that the two clear reasons are a collapse in gas prices relative to what we thought in April. And also in April, I believe if you looked at the oil price expectation or the NYMEX that existed in April versus what we've actually achieved so far this year, we've actually gotten a lower oil price than what the NYMEX would have indicated in April. So part of it is clearly the hydrocarbon prices have provided less cash flow this year than we hoped for.</p>
          <p>And then the other part of it is just I'd say cost escalation primarily in the fracs. It just cost us more to get done what we anticipated and that's not new news. I think most everybody who has reported earnings so far has indicated some cost pressure issue relating to the fracs. Those are two big components of it, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful. And then when you think about the Leonard shale and the Eagle Ford, do you think directionally, lateral links are getting longer, more stage fracs, is that Bakken concept going to be applied do you think, or being applied to some of these new oil prone shales?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very definitely, yeah. I mean it's &#x2013; if you project that two or three years, when look at the Bakken, when we started out in the Bakken, you're looking at maybe 4,000 foot laterals and now we're kind of routinely talking about 9,000 to 10,000 foot laterals and the industry is doing the same thing up there and we started out in the Eagle Ford the data we had back in April were really based on 2,900 foot laterals and today we're talking about 4,000 to 6,000 foot laterals. So if you go out a couple years for say the Eagle Ford, it wouldn't surprise me if we end up talking about routinely 8,000 to 10,000 foot laterals because the reserves, one thing we found in pretty much all these resource plays are the reserves are just a linear function of the lateral length. Drill a well with twice the lateral length, you're likely to get twice the reserves. And the same thing would hold true for any of the other plays, whether it be the Leonard shale or the combo play or some of these things.</p>
          <p>So in many cases you've got some limitations there if you've got a lot of fault patterns. So more highly faulted an area is, you can't go out and drill a 10,000 or 14,000 foot lateral, but the sense of the industry moving to longer laterals in all the plays I think will very definitely occur.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then last question is just on LOE and as you shift to a higher percentage of liquids, where do you think directionally the LOE trends for the company over 2011, 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean there's no doubt &#x2013; I mean we certainly can't deny the fact that if you take just a dry gas well versus an oil well, the LOE is going to be higher for an oil well. And so we clearly have that that we'll be working against, but of course obviously the margin &#x2013; profit margin on an oil well is higher than a gas well. So I can't give you percentage or number other than again to defer to the next earnings call. We'll give some LOE guidance for full year of 2011 relating to that.</p>
          <p>So that hopefully will give you a little bit of input anyway, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. I'd like to thank everyone for staying with the call. And once again, it's case where EOG has been one of the most accurate companies on hitting volume targets for 11 years, but had confluence of events here, but even once you get through the sticker shock of lower volume growth that we're projecting, I don't think there is a company out there who is going to match our liquid volume growth for the next several years and I'll also mention that volume growth doesn't stop in 2012. It continues in '13, '14, '15, clearly on liquid side. We just haven't forecast that far out. So thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Once again, ladies and gentlemen, that concludes today's conference. We appreciate your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>