<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1305277" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-04-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1368</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Randy Burkhalter, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Michael A. Creel, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">A.J. (Jim) Teague, Executive Vice President and Chief Commercial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">W. Randall Fowler, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Brian Zarahn</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">A.J. Teague</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Christopher Skoog</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Stephen Maresca</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Darren Horowitz</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep">Lynn Bourdon</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Theodore Durbin</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep">Mark Hurley</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Ross Payne</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Yves Siegel</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Michael Blum</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">John Edwards</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Jeremy Tonet</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Mark Easterbrook</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Enterprise Products Partners First Quarter Earnings Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> After the speaker's remarks, there will be a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, today's call is being recorded and if you have any objections, you may disconnect at this time. I would now like to introduce Mr. Randy Burkhalter, Vice President of Investor Relations. You may begin, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, [Tina] . Good morning, everyone. And welcome to the Enterprise Products Partners conference call to discuss first quarter earnings. Our speakers today will be Mike Creel, President and CEO of Enterprise's General Partner, followed by Jim Teague, Executive Vice President and Chief Commercial Officer. And then Randy Fowler, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer of the General Partner, will wrap it up. Also in attendance for the call today are other members of our senior management team to assist in Q&amp;A. Afterwards, we will open the call up for your questions.</p>
          <p>During this call, we will make forward-looking statements within in the meaning of Section 21E of the Securities and Exchange Act of 1934, based on the beliefs of the company, as well as assumptions made by, and information currently available to, Enterprise's management. Although management believes that the expectations reflected in such forward-looking statements are reasonable, it can give no assurance that such expectations will prove to be correct. Please refer to our latest filings with the SEC for a list of factors that may cause actual results to differ materially from those in the forward-looking statements made during this call.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll turn the call over to Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Randy. We got off to a great start in the first quarter of this year with record distributable cash flows supported by all-time high volumes for natural gas transportation, equity NGL production, and propylene fractionation. We also had increased NGL, crude oil and petrochemical transportation volumes and higher NGL fractionation volumes.</p>
          <p>This strong performance resulted in an 11% year-over-year increase in gross operating margin for the quarter. The advantages of our large geographical footprint and diverse portfolio of integrated businesses continues to benefit our investors.</p>
          <p>Based on our continued strong performance, we recently announced the 23rd consecutive increase in our quarterly cash distribution rate, increasing it 5.6% to $0.5675 per unit, or $2.27 per unit on an annualized basis.</p>
          <p>Enterprise generated $580 million of distributable cash flow, our third consecutive quarterly record. This provided 1.4 times coverage to the distribution declared with respect to the quarter.</p>
          <p>One of our important financial goals is to retain a portion of our distributable cash flow for reinvestment in growth capital projects, to reduce debt and to decrease the need to issue additional equity. This quarter, we retained $156 million or 27% of the distributable cash flow we generated. Since our IPO in 1998, we've retained approximately 16% or $1.3 billion of distributable cash flow.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier, gross operating margin increased 11% or $81 million to $795 million this quarter. The largest increase was from our NGL Pipelines and Services segment, with $437 million of gross operating margin, up 25% from the first quarter of last year. This segment benefited from record equity NGL production and higher gas processing margins, primarily from our Rocky Mountain processing plants.</p>
          <p>We also had increased NGL pipeline and fractionation volumes and profits from forward NGL sales transactions that settled in the quarter. Fundamentals continue to be strong for this segment. NGL inventories are low, particularly ethane, and demand continues to be high, resulting in strong natural gas processing margins. And Jim will talk about this more in a little bit.</p>
          <p>Gross operating margin from our Onshore Crude Oil Pipelines and Services segment was $27 million for the quarter, compared to $50 million for the first quarter of 2009, primarily due to lower sales margins from our crude oil marketing activities.</p>
          <p>Gross operating margin for the Onshore Natural Gas Pipelines and Services segment decreased $32 million from the first quarter of 2009, primarily due to our Natural Gas Marketing business, which reported a loss of $9 million for the quarter compared to a record profit of $34 million for the first quarter of last year. This decrease was due to lower unit margins and higher transportation and storage expenses. The delay in the completion of the Trinity River Basin lateral pipeline is resulting in the loss of approximately $3 million per month of the Gas Marketing business due to charges being incurred for transportation capacity on a downstream pipeline in anticipation of natural gas volumes originating on the Trinity River Basin lateral pipeline.</p>
          <p>Partially offsetting this decline was the San Juan Gathering System, which reported a $7 million increase in gross operating margin, attributable to higher fees from contract index to gas prices as well as increased condensate sales.</p>
          <p>We also had a higher gross operating margin from our Piceance Gathering System due to the Collbran Valley System that began service in the fourth quarter of 2009, the Exxon treating facility which began service in March of last year, and our Acadian and Texas Intrastate pipeline systems. Our Texas Intrastate System benefited from the Sherman Extension being in service for a full quarter, partially offset by lower pipeline volumes.</p>
          <p>Gross operating margin for the OffShore Pipelines and Services segment increased by $20 million or 33%. This included $9 million of insurance recoveries and a $20 million increase in gross operating margin from our crude oil pipelines. This improvement by our offshore crude oil pipelines was primarily attributable to the Shenzi Pipeline, which began operations in April of 2009, and the restoration of service by other crude oil pipelines that were either out of service or in partial service during the first quarter of last year. Total offshore crude oil pipeline volumes were 354,000 barrels per day compared to 126,000 barrels per day in the first quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Partially offsetting these increases in gross operating margin was a $9 million decrease in gross operating margin from the Independence Hub platform and pipeline. Natural gas volumes on the Independence System decreased to 717 billion BTUs per day this quarter from 922 billion BTUs per day in the first quarter of last year, primarily due to platform down time for construction of a deck extension and other maintenance work, the re-completion of the Mondo well this month and depletion of reserves. Gas flow has increased in the Mondo well due to the re-completion and producers expect an additional well will be recompleted and another well added by the end of the year. They also expect two additional wells to be connected in 2011.</p>
          <p>The Petrochemical and Refined Product Services segment reported a $30 million or 33% increase in gross operating margin for the quarter. Our Propylene Fractionation, Octane Enhancement and Refined Products Pipelines businesses were responsible for most of this improvement. Propylene Fractionation volumes increased 16% to 80,000 barrels per day, reflecting increased demand for polymer grade propylene. Our Butane Isomerization business also had a strong quarter.</p>
          <p>Now before I turn the call over to Jim, I'd like to add that we're still on track to complete our previously announced acquisition of gathering assets from M2 Midstream next week. And I would also like to emphasize the continued efforts of our employees and management team in optimizing our existing assets while also finding new opportunities for growth and value creation for our investors. And with that, I'd like to turn the call over to Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mike. Because the petrochemical industry is such an important component of the demand for our natural gas liquids, I'd like to begin with an update on the petrochemical industry as we see it. We continue to believe the change in the price relationships of natural gas and related NGLs to crude oil and crude oil derivatives such as naphtha have led to a structural change in the petrochemical industry.</p>
          <p>As we said in last quarter's call, this is due to a number of factors, which I won't repeat except to say U.S. ethylene producers are enjoying a competitive advantage over many of their international peers given the more profitable natural gas feedstocks. International ethylene crackers have also reacted to the LPG feedstock cost advantage by importing more LPG to feed their traditional naphtha crackers. Our export terminal, consequently our export terminal on the eastern ship channel continues to be full, and propane exports are expected to remain robust at least through the middle of the year.</p>
          <p>Because of the significant margins for olefins, integrated polymers producers saw very healthy margins over the first quarter while non-integrated producers' margins were lower, but were still positive. As was expected, first quarter exports of polymers were down due to competition from new production assets overseas such as the Middle East.</p>
          <p>However, exports of polymers in the first quarter still represented close to 20% of demand. We still believe that downstream derivatives will be able to compete on a global basis. We're not the only ones to think the U.S. is competitive. Just this month, Shintech, a large PVC producer, announced that it will go ahead with the project to expand its vinyls production capacity in Louisiana. That expansion is estimated to increase total vinyls capacity by about 900,000 metric tons by the end of 2011, representing an appetite for over 900 million pounds of ethylene. If that ethylene were produced from methane, that is equivalent to close to 30,000 barrels a day of incremental ethane.</p>
          <p>We're seeing U.S. ethylene producers continue to modify their furnaces to crack more NGL feedstocks and take advantage of its cost benefit versus crude oil derivatives. We've worked closely with a number of customers to provide them with incremental supplies of ethane and propane and related logistical services, and we estimate that ethylene producers are in the process of adding more capacity to crack ethane and propane in the U.S.</p>
          <p>We expect NGL consumption at U.S. crackers to continue to increase in the future as NGLs, primarily ethane, remain the most competitive feedstock. Ethylene supplies are tight due to planned and unplanned outages over the last couple of months with ethylene prices increasing to over $0.70 per pound at the end of the first quarter. U.S. ethylene operating rates were approximately 88% of capacity for the first quarter, producing an average &#x2013; an annualized average of 51 billion pounds of ethylene, which equals the average for the last 5 years.</p>
          <p>Industry consultants estimate that in April, crackers will operate at 86% of capacity, producing some annualized 50 billion pounds of ethylene. We've said in the past, and history proves, that when they're operating at this high of a level, they have to rely on inventory draws for light end feedstocks, which is good for us.</p>
          <p>During the first quarter, demand for ethane from ethylene crackers were approximately 877,000 barrels a day. That's not only higher than in the fourth quarter of 2009, it's the highest in over 10 years. During the first quarter, over 80% of total feed stocks used by U.S. crackers were light end versus the heavier crude feedstocks such as naphtha and gas oil. We estimate there is a shortfall between current NGL production capability and potential cracker demand. We did see some anomalies in cracker economics and ethylene prices during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Plant outages tightened the ethylene markets sending spot prices to over $0.70 per pound at the end of the quarter. The higher prices impacted the ethylene business with average cracker margins across the industry at $0.30 per pound. This is for CMAI. That compares to margins that averaged in the low single-digits in the fourth quarter. The strong margins provided incentive to cracker operators to run plants as hard as they could and even some delays of planned maintenance to take advantage of the margins.</p>
          <p>Moving to our Fractionation business, we're increasing our fractionation capacity, expanding our NGL, our Natural Gas Pipeline and Processing infrastructure, and growing our NGL distribution networks in anticipation of continued growth in both supply and demand for NGLs. NGL Fractionation capacity remains tight. Our Fractionators at Mont Belvieu and Hobbs continue to run at capacity and overflow volumes have gone to our Louisiana Fractionators since mid-2008.</p>
          <p>Construction of our new 75,000 barrel a day NGL Fractionator at Mont Belvieu is progressing on schedule to go into service the first of 2011, and we expect it to be full on day 1. Additional capacity may be needed and we are evaluating that to accommodate incremental volumes from expected production growth out of the Eagleford Shale play in South Texas.</p>
          <p>Total Eagleford production feeding our system today exceeds 150 million cubic feet a day. By comparison, this was relatively non-existent at this time last year. This is helping to offset declines we are experiencing from conventional production in South Texas. We've seen both the rig count and production increase by over 50% from the fourth quarter of 2009, which has also led to higher-mixed NGLs feeding into our South Texas Fractionators.</p>
          <p>Fractionation fees at Mont Belvieu have increased significantly since pre-2005 when contracts were done between $0.01 and $0.015 per gallon. Today, fees are in excess of $0.05 a gallon, and unlike in the past, they include throughput commitments in the form of minimum take clauses for new contracts and contract renewals.</p>
          <p>Moving to our NGL Pipelines and Processing. As Mike mentioned earlier, our NGL business performed well this quarter with higher NGL transportation volumes and record equity NGL production compared to the first quarter of 2009. Throughput volumes were higher on the majority of our pipelines, driven by strong demand for NGLs. As a matter of fact, capacity is so tight that we're putting shippers on allocation on some of our systems. The Mid-America pipeline, Rocky Mountain and Seminole systems continue to run at capacity, with Mid-America dedicated processing plants operating at full rates.</p>
          <p>Our Rockies business performed surprisingly well this quarter, despite the lack of a significant uptick in drilling. Greater efficiencies for current drilling rigs and a backlog of completed wells that we have connected to our pipeline system, led to an increase in inlet volumes into our Meeker complex, which for the quarter were 1.3 Bcf a day.  That's up 20% over the fourth quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Total volumes gathered on our Jonah and Pinedale systems in Wyoming remained steady and our Pioneer cryo remains full at 750 million a day. As full operating plants, Meeker and Pioneer combine to generate almost 100,000 barrels a day of mixed NGLs that feed into our value chain.</p>
          <p>We think there are still packages of gas and acreage to be captured in both Wyoming and in Colorado and we will pursue these opportunities to maintain a solid base load for these plants and to establish a firm platform for growth.</p>
          <p>The Gulf Coast Gathering and Processing business exceeded our expectations this quarter due to increasing South Texas production. This is driven by incremental volumes from the Eagleford Shale.</p>
          <p>On our Dixie pipeline, we increased our loading fees at all of our terminals effective January 1st. The increased loading fees and a cold winter versus last year drove revenue up by approximately $5 million.</p>
          <p>We also completed the expansion of our storage at Apex, North Carolina, which will allow us to supply an additional 800,000 barrels of propane annually to the Southeast market. Also the LPG terminals on the TE Products main line were removed from the regulated tariff at the end of the quarter and those terminals are now part of our unregulated NGL Pipeline and Storage business.</p>
          <p>We receive a lot of questions on our hedging program. And as I said in last quarter's call, we were patient when it came to hedging our NGL production, waiting for the right opportunities. Currently, we are 53% hedged on our equity production for the remainder, go forward, of 2010. Approximately 57% of our Rockies deep hole production in 2010 has been hedged at a gross margin of around $0.61 per gallon. We are approaching those levels that we enjoyed in mid-2008. Approximately 42% of our liquids production has been hedged at attractive prices. We continue to have patience. We're looking for opportunities to put on additional hedges. We're waiting for the market to come to us.</p>
          <p>In natural gas, as Mike mentioned earlier, we had record gas transportation volumes this quarter, supported by higher throughput on our Acadian System, our Piceance Gathering Pipeline, the White River Hub and our Encinal System in South Texas. Volumes decreased on our Texas Intrastate System due to continued declines in traditional South Texas production and lower West to East spreads. The good news is production is up over 75 million cubic foot a day since the beginning of the year due to new Eagleford production coming online. We also begin to collect demand fees from the Sherman Extension in August of last year, and we're looking forward to the Trinity River lateral coming on in late second quarter, early third quarter.</p>
          <p>Spreads from West to East Texas have come in significantly, from $0.29 in 2009 to $0.07 this year. As a result of the high spreads during 2009 and a warm winter, it led to low firm transportation volumes. Consequently we pushed a lot of secondary firm volumes across the pipe. A colder than normal winter this year led to higher utilization rates by firm shippers leaving less room for secondary firm or IT volumes to flow.</p>
          <p>Gross operating margin from our gas marketing group was down this quarter, as Mike told you, compared to first quarter 2009 due primarily to two reasons: lower basis differentials and higher transportation expenses from capacity leased on Gulf Crossing Pipeline and the Northern Border Pipeline which started after the first quarter of last year. Our Haynesville Acadian Extension Pipeline continues to gain support in the market, and we're close to having signed up the first phase, 1.8 Bcf a day of firm capacity. Our recently announced acquisition of assets from M2 Midstream in the Haynesville is expected to enhance our opportunities for future development and expansions in that shale play such that the Haynesville Extension ultimately reaches its full 2.1 Bcf a day of capacity.</p>
          <p>Turning to the Eagleford, rig count has expanded to over 50 rigs operating at the end of the first quarter from just 10 rigs in the first quarter of last year and we expect the rig count will continue to increase driven by the richness of the gas in the Eagleford. We're continuing active negotiations with every producer in the Eagleford. In 2009 and this year combined, we expect to spend more than $200 million to serve the gas gathering, processing and NGL needs of Eagleford producers and in order to fill our existing plants. Currently we have over 400,000 acres dedicated to us. This capital program in 2009 and 2010 will support a more comprehensive solution to growing Eagleford production.</p>
          <p>Before I turn the call over to Randy, I want to spend just a moment to discuss our propylene business which reported strong results this quarter, and were almost double what we reported in the first quarter of 2009. Propylene prices increased 27% in the first quarter of 2010 as a result of lower cracker source propylene and improved product demand. The increased supply of refinery grade propylene feedstock and strong propylene demand resulted in a growth in sales and processing volumes of close to 200 million pounds compared to the first quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn it over to Randy Fowler.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jim. I'd like to briefly discuss some income items that are below the operating income of --section of the income statement, liquidity and also some capitalization items. In terms of G&amp;A, G&amp;A expense for the first quarter of 2010 increased by $2.7 million, up to $37.6 million, primarily due to higher non-cash unit based compensation expenses.</p>
          <p>The provision for income taxes decreased to $8.7 million this quarter from 16 million recorded in the first quarter of 2009. The majority of this decrease was due to lower corporate income taxes, approximately 6.9 million of that from Dixie Pipeline, which had a taxable gain associated with the sale of assets in the first quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>We invested approximately $321 million in growth capital expenditures during the first quarter, and for the year we currently expect to spend an estimated $2.8 billion, which includes approximately $1.6 billion for growth capital expenditures and $1.2 billion for the acquisition of gathering assets from M2 Midstream that we announced earlier in the month.</p>
          <p>Some of the larger approved capital projects include the Haynesville Extension Pipeline, the Mont Belvieu NGL Fractionator, finishing up the Trinity River Basin lateral natural gas pipeline and other projects in the Eagleford.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter we spent $33 million in sustaining capital expenditures. We had come in, back at the time of the fourth quarter earnings announcement, we estimated maintenance CapEx for the entire year of 2010 to be approximately $250 million. Typically we do get off to a slower start in the first quarter as far as spending those maintenance capital expenditures, most of the time due to weather. January and February of this year was very wet. So again we got off to a slow start there. I think we may have to hustle to spend $250 million this year. We should be able to come in and give you a better estimate on that at the end of the second quarter.</p>
          <p>In terms of capitalization, adjusted EBITDA for the 12 months ended March 31, 2010 was approximately $2.8 billion and when we come in, adjusted EBITDA as we note in the press release, is EBITDA less equity earnings from unconsolidated affiliates plus the actual cash distributions received from those unconsolidated affiliates. Our leverage ratio of debt to adjust EBITDA for the last 12 months was 3.7 times at March 31, 2010 with debt being adjusted for 50% equity content in the hybrid debt securities that we have outstanding.</p>
          <p>Our floating interest rate exposure was approximately 10% at the end of the quarter. The average life of our debt was 9 years which incorporates the first call date for the hybrids, and our effective cost of debt was 6.1%.</p>
          <p>In terms of liquidity, at the end of March after adjusting for the net proceeds of $485 million from our equity offering in April, we had liquidity of approximately $2.4 billion which includes availability under our $1.75 billion revolver and unrestricted cash. Affiliates of Enterprise Products Company, a private company controlled by the Dan L. Duncan family and our largest unit holder, confirmed their willingness to consider to invest up to $150 million in additional partnership units during the remainder of 2010, including their commitment to reinvest 50 million through Enterprise dividend reinvestment plan here in the May 2010 distribution.</p>
          <p>With that, Randy, I think we're ready to open it up for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Tina, we're ready to take questions now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question will come from the line of Brian Zarahn with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Haynesville Extension, I think you mentioned 1.8 Bcf of capacity has been contracted. About how many shippers does that represent?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what we said is we're getting, we're moving toward 1.8, Brian. And I'll let Chris answer as to how many shippers we're talking about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're still on the same 7 shippers and we're just upsizing some of the volumes to some of these existing players.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Jim, I appreciate the color on propylene fractionation. Do you think this level of performance can continue to the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Propylene fractionation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think our demand's going to be strong, Brian, I think what we're going to see over the next couple of months is, we've been trying to &#x2013; I'm looking at Lynn Bourdon &#x2013; we've been trying to sell forward. You did have some shift recently, to heavier feedstocks driven by a strong propylene price. I think we're expecting to see that soften a little bit in the next month or so. But in the process of doing that, we expect the ethane demand to kick up fairly hard. And it's just going to be an up and down, and we're going to have good strong demand, we're going to have decent margins and then we're going to have nice margins periodically. And it's really driven by how much ethane is being used. I mean, one of the reasons we had such strong propylene prices in the first quarter is they were using so much ethane, you didn't get the propylene produced from crackers.</p>
          <p>The other thing we're finding is our term customers have figured out that they don't particularly want the unreliability of people that can switch feedstocks and watch their propylene production vary. So we're getting more folks wanting to talk to us about term contracts because ours is a lot more reliable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then turning to NGL fractionation, I know you mentioned there was a gain first quarter of last year. But you had higher volumes but margins were down. Can you talk a little about that and what do you expect to see the remainder of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ask the question again, Brian. I must be, I'm getting old.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On your NGL Fractionation business, your volumes were up year-over-year but margins, your operating margin was down. Can you give a little color as to &#x2013; I know there was a gain in there from last year, but a little more color on that would be helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Brian, this is Randy Fowler. One of it is, in last year over at our Norco facility, we had some operating gains over &#x2013; and I think it was probably in the ball park of about 4 or $5 million, were the operating gains last year in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I guess finally, on the &#x2013; I know you're evaluating another fractionator to your system. Can you give us a sense of how far along the process is in reviewing them?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I tried. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Stephen Maresca with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, question for Jim. I thought we saw some ethane and propane price dip over the past couple of months. Was that an aberration or due to some maintenance downtime? And given what you think about demand and where inventories are, what sort of upside do see in those prices for the remainder of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't predict prices. We love margins. That's what we focus on more than the absolute. And margins have stayed at our &#x2013; for instance, in the Rockies, I guess, Lynn, we're up around $0.32 plus a gallon? That's &#x2013; you can look on anybody's reports and see that. We think you did see a little dip in ethane usage. You had some plant outages, planned maintenance. And then you did have a little bit of shifting driven by pretty strong propylene, benzene and butadiene prices during the course of the quarter. We're seeing that move back to ethane as those prices weaken. And I'm not going to tell you where we think it's going to go, but we've got a -- Lynn's got a graph as to what he thinks ethane inventories are going to be doing the balance of the year. I will tell you they're going into southeast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, you guys had talked about a dip in the onshore natural gas pipeline unit margins. Is there any color behind that? Is that something, a one quarter event or can things turn around with that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Chris. Versus first quarter last year and Jim talked about it in the call, we had the warmer weather first quarter last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We were able to use our secondary firm and our IT business to go west-east across the pipe and capture the benefit of the $0.27 spreads across the pipe. This year, the colder weather in January and February, the utilization factor of our firm customers were up and the commodity rates associated with those firm demand contracts are very low. So they were single digits, so you just see the delta there. As you see here, second quarter, third quarter, we've talked about it. We see the spreads west to east across the pipe coming back to the more normal historical pattern in that, let's call it 0.08 to $0.12 range. And remember we're mostly sold out on our firm basis from west to east exposure to central Texas. So we're not so much subject to spread risk from a firm point of view, but it does hurt our upside potential using our secondary space. So to state it probably more succinctly, we like wider spreads, but we're not as sensitive to it as other people are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot for the color, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Darren Horowitz with Raymond James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. Congratulations on the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Darren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim, a couple quick questions for you trying to get a sense of incremental ethane demand from this point forward. So can you help us by quantifying the shortfall between the current NGL production capability and cracker demand? And also, as a follow up, how much of that targeted 100,000 barrels of capacity that was transitioning the cracked light ends has actually materialized?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can point to probably, Randy, 100,000 barrels a day. Of a combination of ethane and propane, that 2 years ago would not have been used. It would have been naphtha cracking. I can tell you that we continue to work with a couple of crackers that are currently using naphtha and trying to work with them to convert to be able to use more NGLs. I think the shortfall, we had it in my script and I took it out because I'm not sure it's right, but I think we were saying something like 30, 40,000 barrels a day, Darren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just a follow-up question. As you mentioned, Jim, given the tighter domestic supplies of ethylene driving the price higher, and from a domestic perspective of us moving a bit higher on the cash cost curve, do you think the domestic exportability for ethylene could be impacted at least in the short term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it was in the first quarter. I think, Lynn, what was it in the fourth quarter of last year?  Pushing 30%, 25 to 30%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it was about 30%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're saying it's around 20%. Lynn's got a slide that's kind of good. It says you don't have to outrun the bear, you just got to have to outrun Darren. You don't have to be as good as the Middle East as long as we're competing with naphtha crackers in northwest Europe and the Far East.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think they're competitive. It's still a dadgum place to produce ethylene, produce polyethylene and I think they'll get their share of exports. They're not going to compete with ethane crackers in the Middle East, but we don't think they have to. And the latest CMAI cost curve shows that they're pretty competitive with propane and natural gasoline out of the Middle East.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just a final question for you, Jim, and I apologize if I missed it, but when you were detailing the 42% of your percent of liquids that are hedged, did you mention what price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Would you mind mentioning the price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a nice price, Darren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Well, keep enjoying the nice prices, thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Ted Durbin with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. First question is just you talked about the Rockies volumes being up in NGL. I guess, how are you seeing that happening? You got low gas prices now. Kind of what's the outlook for going forward and what's really driving the volume increase given that the rig count really hasn't bumped up as much out there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what we said earlier is we just recently tied into some wells that have been completed. So that's helped. Mike mentioned that we had completed our work to tie in the Collbran Valley and that's way down in the southern part of the Piceance where we did shut down a plant down there that added probably close to 100 million a day. And frankly, we're doing some pretty creative deals out there to keep our plants full by working with people who have dew point plants to make sure that that gas flows to our corrals if we give them a piece of the action. So we're doing everything we can to keep &#x2013; we're going to keep the plants full. And we might share a little bit of the margin but it's going to be full.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So would you say you're sort of taking share from others here and you're giving price discounts to do that or how are you actually making that happen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ted, as Jim said, part of it is hooking up wells that were already drilled. So that's not taking away from anybody else. And part of it with the Collbran Valley system, we're picking up gas that we previously did not have access to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, got it. Okay. Great. And then just on Independence, the volumes were down. Kind of what are you looking at in terms of going forward in 2010 and 2011? Do you sort of see 'em flat from here or how much volume recovery do you see at Independence?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we had volume recovery at the end of the first quarter and now into April. And so we expect volumes to remain in the 725 to 750 range over the next couple of years, pretty much flat with where we are here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. And then if I could ask the last one. In terms of just the distribution increase, you've been pretty consistent in terms of the $0.0075 every quarter. Have you thought at all about ramping up rate growth on the distribution or are you kind of comfortable with where you are right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're comfortable with the increase we just announced. And clearly we've been pretty consistent over the last several years about having good distributions. We do have a relatively large CapEx budget this year. We started out the year at 1.5 billion, 1.6 billion. We got the M2 Midstream acquisition on top of that, another $1.2 billion. So we're getting close to $3 billion. It's helpful to have cash that we can reinvest in those assets that keep us from having to tap the equity markets as much as we might have and reduce our leverage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from Ross Payne with Wells Fargo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How are you doing, guys?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Ross.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First question is what is the cost of Trinity River Basin lateral? How big is that pipe, and what's the capacity looking like for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ross, probably about 250. We actually had that spiked out in our Analyst Meeting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. And can you speak to, you know, the producers that are behind that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The capacity &#x2013; the total capacity in that system is going to be close to 1 Bcf.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we've got 1 producer committed to a long-term tenure agreement, and we're continuing to develop in the area because this is an area that gets us down into the Dallas Fort Worth area. There's a lot of municipalities along the way there that have been difficult getting our pipeline approved. That's what caused this delay. But now that we're all through all that, we've released an abundance of drilling permits to pickup. So there's a likelihood of a lot of small independents starting to actively drill in the area to hold their acreage and get the gas produced out of it.  There's been a lot of drilling done, and we've seen the permitting process more than double here in the last 60 days now that we've announced that our project should be completed by July 1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And also one item that I haven't heard mentioned yet here today is, any thoughts out of the Marcellus for NGLs, any update relative to the Analyst Meeting. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me take the first stab at that then I'll hand it off to Jim. Obviously, the Marcellus is getting a lot of attention and a lot of press releases from various partnerships on solutions. We're taking a little more holistic approach, really looking at, from the producer's standpoint, where do they get the best price for their NGLs. Because at the end of the day, they're the ones that are going to bear that cost. So it's not just a matter of extracting the NGLs and shipping them to a point. You've got to have a market that really needs it, otherwise the net back price to producers is pretty underwhelming. So we're really looking for an industry-wide solution that takes care of the producers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ross, Mike just nailed it. To put it in context, I think every press release you've seen and we're not real big on press releases for hopes, we're looking at it that you really, every one of those deals are pipeline projects. What we're looking at is, how do you take this ethane and distribute it to crackers throughout the system. And if you're going to have ethane going to crackers, you better have storage. You better have a way to keep it flowing. So, we are talking to people about a project, we're not going to press release it, that gives them the reliability of flow assurance and gives them access to a broader range of customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Ross, circling back on your Trinity River lateral question. Total CapEx on Trinity River is $278 million. And to finish up the project in 2010, we're looking to spend approximately $120 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. And Randy, while I've got you, just one final question.  Your leverage metrics are obviously quite impressive at this point, around 3.7 or so. Is that the new range you kind of see your company operating in, or is it going to vacillate a little bit with acquisitions and kind of be a 3.6 to 4.1 type range?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Ross, I think historically we've said we're sort of comfortable in that 3.5 to 4 times range. We've just sort of lived in the 4 times range and actually, depending on where we were in our construction cycle, saw that kick up to about 4.2, 4.3. I believe that's an area we don't want to live in. I think, if you would, on a steady state basis, we're more comfortable in the 3.5 to 4 times range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thanks, guys, that's it for me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Yves Siegel with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Yves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you don't mind, I'd like to ask the elephant in the room question, which is, given the passing of Dan, is there any thought, and what is the thinking as it relates to the Enterprise family of companies, i.e., when you think of Duncan, DEP and you think of the Acadian expansion, can you sort of address the thought process going forward? There's 3 entities, publicly traded entities out there and is there any change at all in the way you think of those 3 entities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Yves, the easy answer is that nothing has really changed. When we set up the EP and took it public, we said that it was there to facilitate the growth of Enterprise and to invest in slower growth assets, and that we expected it to appeal to investors that were looking for higher yield and not as concerned about the growth. Certainly the Haynesville extension is a big step for DEP and I'm sure that Randy will talk about that at the next earnings call for DEP. But going forward, our plan really has not changed. Our thought process is that if we have assets that we think have a slower growth rate, that fits the profile that DEP is looking for, that we would consider a drop down and DEP might consider it as well. I mean both sides have to agree. But absent that, there really hasn't been any change in fundamental philosophy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can I ask, to beat the Marcellus horse a little bit here, any sense in terms of timing as when ethane becomes a problem and when a solution has to be affected?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yves, as we understand it, TEPPCO has a waiver that allows them to blend more ethane. That waiver, I think, expires in 2013. So that's probably as good a benchmark as any as to when there needs to be a solution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now the question is if production ramps up enough where you can't blend it down to the BTUs, you could potentially have a problem before then, but 2013 is certainly a problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then my last two-part question is, Jim, earlier in your remarks you said you were talking about supply and demand as it relates to NGLs supply increasing. Can you put that into context with where you think it is as it relates to -- I guess, you have the Eagleford, and you have the Marcellus and I'm also thinking that with gas prices being relatively low, I'm just not sure if there might be a sharper fall-off in conventional drilling. So I'm still trying to figure out the dynamics moving forward in terms of natural gas? And then the second part of the last question is, what are you folks thinking about in terms of investing more dollars in the Gulf of Mexico?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't help you to what the supply's going to be because I tend to agree with you as it relates to conventional at these price levels. I think we do expect because of the richness of the gas, we do expect more rigs to be deployed to the Eagleford. We think that's a growth area and if there's a solution to ethane in the Marcellus because of that southwest part of Pennsylvania and the richness of the liquids, assuming the value's there for the liquids that far away from its natural home, you would expect them to drill there. I mean, as far as the Gulf of Mexico, I think we're continuing to look. I'll let Mike answer that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yves, when we look at capital expenditures, we look across all of our business segments. We look at the opportunities that are available. We look at the risk adjusted returns on those projects. We look to see which of those opportunities are here today and gone tomorrow, which ones can actually wait a year or 2. And then we kind of decide which ones make the most sense for the partnership. And so we're trying to balance the needs of the partnership. And as I said before, we're already at $2.8 billion for this year with the acquisition of those midstream assets. So it's a pretty fulsome year already, particularly since we're only in the end of April right now. But we have not ruled out anything in the Gulf of Mexico. In fact, we're looking at some projects. It just depends on when we get close to making the decision on which ones to pull the trigger on and where those stack up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thanks, guys. I really appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Michael Blum with Wells Fargo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one question really, and I apologize if you reviewed this, but I didn't catch it. In your Onshore Crude Oil Pipeline segment, gross margin was down pretty significantly year-over-year. It looks like it was around the marketing business. Could you just talk about what's going on there? Was that a blip or are you running that business differently or?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Mark Hurley. A couple of things happened there in the first quarter and it was very much margin related. One is the sweet/sour differential, particularly west Texas and Oklahoma. That differential declined quite a bit just due to the competition for the sour barrels. And so while we continue to move quite a bit of volume there, the margins hurt us on the overall marketing side. And secondly, the contango in the market was much weaker than it had been in 2009. And so the marketing of barrels in the future months just didn't yield as much margin. And so, although the contango has certainly bounced back in April, and it's quite strong now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, as Chris said on the gas side, the same thing holds true on the crude side. Our marketing businesses are there to fill up our assets and to take advantages of price differentials when they occur. But we're not dependent on them. So, both those businesses had a great year in the first quarter of 2009 and we'll continue to capitalize on those opportunities as they become available.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, is a good way to think about it that the first quarter number is a good run rate in a, let's call it a less favorable environment, and the year-over-year number from '09 is in kind of a more favorable environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Seems fair.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of John Edwards with Morgan Keegan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the Onshore Crude Oil Pipes and Services, just kind of following on &#x2013; so you're saying that where we are right now, this 27 million, you expect that you're going to be running about that for the rest of the year, you think? Just to follow on Michael's question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we've said that. I think we've said that the first quarter wasn't as opportunistic, if you will. I think contango market is coming back, Mark?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, exactly. I think the first quarter was not particularly favorable in terms of either of the marketing margins that we watch, both the sweet/sour differential and the contango. The contango has bounced back and so we expect that to be a little more favorable going forward. The sweet/sour differential I think is going to continue to be under pressure just due to the demand for the sour barrels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Jim. One of the things we're doing as it relates to our marketing activity in our crude business is &#x2013; when did we buy this operation, in October, November? What we're trying to get our arms around, and in fact we're going to do it, is we're going to model everywhere we've got margin risk, just like we do in our Enterprise assets. And when we see something we like, we're going to be pretty aggressive in locking it in to the extent we can in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And another thing that we probably aren't ready to talk about in too much detail, is we're very interested in building out that system and improving connections and making it more akin to what we have on the NGL side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's absolutely right. In the process of doing that, you create more of those opportunities to get the upside, just like we do in the natural gas liquids. So, connectivity, expanding it, is a key area of growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I appreciate the detail on that. And then, obviously, petrochemicals were quite strong. You provided a lot of good commentary there. I guess clarifying, going forward, do you think this is going to continue pretty strong, kind of at these levels?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what we're seeing is because of natural gas prices and the related costs of NGLs relative to crude that petrochemicals have a very attractive price of feedstocks. And they're very competitive across the world and even in a time when the U.S. has been in a recession and is only now starting to come out, the petrochemicals have been doing very well. So you would expect as the economic recovery continues, that they'll continue to do well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just on G&amp;A, is this quarter a pretty good run rate for the year or do you expect it to tick up a bit in the next few quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, John, I'd say I wouldn't expect it to be any more than this level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. And then I think you said maintenance CapEx was a little bit light this quarter but you expect that to tick up the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not unusual for the first quarter to be kind of light. As Randy said, we had a wet first quarter, and in a lot of the areas you've got snow on the ground and you can't get in. So typically the second and third quarters are our busiest quarters in terms of maintenance CapEx. I think Randy's right, seeing how much we have left to spend in 2010, to meet that $250 million number, we may be pushing it to get there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, that's where I think when next quarter when we have our second quarter earnings call, I think we'll be able to come in and hone in on that estimate a little bit more if there's any change from the $250 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It definitely won't be over the $250 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Great quarter. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from the line of Jeremy Tonet with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My question's been answered. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our final question will come from the line of Mark Easterbrook with RBC Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning, guys. Just &#x2013; a lot of questions have been answered already but one question, have you guys considered the use of hybrid debt again and exactly how much capacity do you have there that you can potentially go out and use the hybrid debt again to finance some of the needs that you have?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think it's a question of the capacity we have so much as the cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Mark, I think a couple of things on that front. Mike's right.  As far as from a cost standpoint, and again you guys, we've sort of communicated how we look at our cash cost of capital, both on debt and equity modeling that out over 10 years. So if you would, a hybrid security is callable after 10 years, so we look at what the cash costs of a hybrid debt security is versus the cost of 50% equity, 50% debt and is there a breakeven point.</p>
          <p>I think when we issued the hybrids back in 2006, 2007, especially 2007, you had a break over point where the hybrids  were a little more expensive probably for the first couple of years and then after that, they were more attractive than a 50/50 mix of debt and equity. Lately where we've seen that break over point is out, maybe, year 5, year 6, so not quite as attractive.</p>
          <p>I think the other thing we need to wait and see also was the way Moody's is looking to come in and change the way or considering the change of how they view the hybrid securities, scratching our head a little bit on the application to industrial companies, certainly understand it with the application to financial companies. But with that, I think the security that we have outstanding could be 25% equity credit as opposed to 50% equity credit. So I think there are 2 or 3 things happening on the hybrid front, so I wouldn't look to see us issuing hybrid securities anytime soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tina is that our last...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That is our final question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Tina if you would, give our listeners the replay information real quickly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, today's conference call will be available for replay beginning at 1:00 p.m. Eastern Standard Time. The number to dial for the replay is 800-642-1687 and the conference ID number for the conference is 70292007. Again the conference ID number is 70292007. This concludes today's teleconference. You may all disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>