<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1488269" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>192</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President, Head-Industry &amp; Investor Relations">&#xC5;se Lindskog</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Hans Vestberg</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Vice President &amp; Head-Networks">Johan Wibergh</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive VP &amp; Head-Global Services Business Unit">Magnus Mandersson</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Jan Frykhammar</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Charter Equity Research">Edward Snyder</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">Mark Sue</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Sandeep S. Deshpande</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Achal Sultania</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Securities International, Inc.">Stuart Jeffrey</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Gareth Jenkins</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Francois A. Meunier</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Kai F. Korschelt</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Arete Research Services LLP">Richard A. Kramer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to the Ericsson call for the second quarter reports. To see visual aids for this call, please log on to www.ericsson.com/press or www.ericsson.com/investors. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, a replay will be available after today's conference. &#xC5;se Lindskog will now open the call. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, operator, and hello, everyone. You're all welcome to our call today, where we will run through our second quarter report. And with me here today, I have Hans Vestberg, our CEO and President; Jan Frykhammar, our Chief Financial Officer; Johan Wibergh, Head of Business Unit Networks and Magnus Mandersson, who's Head of Business Unit Global Services.</p>
          <p>To start with then, I have to make the usual reminder that during the call today, we will be making forward-looking statements. These statements are based on our current expectations and certain planning assumptions which are subject to risk and uncertainties. The actual results may differ materially due to factors mentioned in today's press release and discussed in the conference call. I encourage you to read about these risks and uncertainties in our earnings report, as well as in our annual report. And so with this said, I would like to hand over the call to Hans Vestberg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, &#xC5;se. Hello, everyone. Let me be brief on the key developments in the quarter, as many of you probably listened to the press conference and have read our material, but in the quarter, we continue to stay very close to our customers and as I mentioned earlier this morning as well, the last 45 days, we and the executive team including myself &#x2013; we have talked to 100% of our revenue base to understand where the market is going and we don't see any major changes since the first quarter. And remember in the first quarter and the fourth quarter last year, we said that in the markets where there are some macroeconomical uncertainties, that we see more cautious operators when it comes to investments, so that is the same sort of prevailing in the quarter.</p>
          <p>But we have not seen any change to what we talked about in the first quarter. But important for us is to stay close to the customers in these times, to understand how they will act in this market. When it comes to more political uncertainty, there's no change there neither. The market that has political uncertainty or for practical reasons not doing much investments and that will for a while continue and that's predominantly markets in Middle East and in Northern Africa. But there's no news on that, it's basically the same as in previous quarters.</p>
          <p>The customer dialogue has been very much around network performance and quality of the networks, as that is becoming a key differentiator. Spectrum with the expected data growth, of course, spectrum will be important point to have both more of but also doing it more efficiently in the radio technology. And then very high on the list is monetizing the mobile broadband with tiered pricing and quality of service, driving a lot of changes in their OSS and BSS.</p>
          <p>And finally, we have had it for quite a while, that's of course efficiency discussion and focus on our customers very much when it comes to both network sharing, outsourcing, and other types of efficiency gains by using our service or product portfolio.</p>
          <p>Looking at the quarter, I will be brief here, growth of 1% year over year, down 6% year over year for comparable units and adjusted for foreign exchange. That's basically the same as we had in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>We had a sequential growth of 9%, and a normal sort of seasonality which is normal seasonality is around 5%. We will come back but both Global Services and Support Solutions had a strong quarter and are now contributing to around 50% of the turnover in the quarter of Ericsson. In Networks, Johan will come back but here we have the expected impact on the equipment sales of CDMA that is declining, and then we had weaker sales in the quarter in China and Russia.</p>
          <p>If we then look at the profitability, the core Ericsson had a profit of SEK 3.3 billion, net income SEK 1.2 billion, clearly down from last year driven by Networks, with the profitability of Networks but also that we have a wider loss in ST-Ericsson year over year not sequentially but year over year, leading to earnings per share of SEK 0.78 in the quarter compared to SEK 1.60 last year. And of course, here we need to remind you that Q1 included a one-time effect of the gain from the divestment of Sony Ericsson by SEK 7.7 billion. So, by that, I hand over to you Johan to talk about Networks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Hans. So today we have two slides on Networks. So let me start by going through a little bit on the financials on the first page. So as you've seen then, we are down 20% year over year. If you do an organic FX-adjusted sales and quarter over quarter, we're up two percentage. You should remember that first half 2011 was a somewhat tough comparison after <mark type="ph" /> a cricket (06:10) went to 10 but still we're down 20% which is a lot.</p>
          <p>Year over year, it was lower GSM sales in China. We also see reduced operating investments in Russia and India, among other places. And as Hans said then, CDMA was down some 50% year over year, and we started seeing decline back in Q4 and then it has continued. Operating margin ended 5%; we were 14% in Q2 2011. And the drivers for this of course the overall lower volumes; we are quite volume-sensitive, and with the high R&amp;D spendings we have.</p>
          <p>We also may get impacted by underlying business mix with the same world coverage and capacity as before. European &#x2013; modernization projects then and then somewhat less capacity expansions in Q2 versus Q1. If we then move to next page then, I think we see as Hans was hinted, we see a very positive discussion among operators, an increased focus and discussions around competing on performance. That's important, that's really a leading indicator for us when it comes to doing future capacity expansions. So I think that is one positive thing.</p>
          <p>Second then, we see LTE is reaching outside the initial rollout countries. I mean so far it's been U.S. and Korea that already are the major LTE countries. We have right now about 2 million new LTE subscribers per month.</p>
          <p>We have Canada and Japan also going on, few countries in Europe, but now we see more expansion in Europe. We see more Latin America coming up and Mexico, Brazil, some more countries, Chile. And I think we are real encouraged here by our well proven LTE solution that is really is outperforming competition both technically and market share wise. As we wrote in the report, and I mean on <mark type="ph" /> shaped (08:24) equipment then up until end of last year, we had some 60% market share, and I have still to read an analyst report that don't put us as being the leader in this area. And we also here then have established ourself with a really strong platform product that is performing extremely well on quality and performance and now we're adding on. Now pace in development is rapid, there's a lot of new features coming on. The pace is quick and we are in the most important countries when it comes to smart phone usage. This is good for me.</p>
          <p>Key priority is then moving forward is of course to improve on profitability. We are of course not happy with the 5 percentage points that we have, and of course we are working and both as Hans and Jan said before, that we will have a &#x2013; the effects of the modernization projects will have an impact at the end of the year and beginning of next year. We're also working a lot on both on the revenue side as well as on the cost side to make sure we do what we can without jeopardizing our strong portfolio position and the technology leadership in the things we've done.</p>
          <p>Also feel encouraged about the seven contracts, the seven customers that had issues in SSR when it comes to IP. This is important to us. It's still small money revenue this year but it's real important going forward. It's real encouraging. We also then see next step when it comes to the voice business, those operators investing in LTE, they are now starting to prepare for launches on moving voice over to LTE, and there we are working really hard to capitalize on both on our strong position in LTE as well as in circuit-switched core.</p>
          <p>And then finally, we're working on supporting our customers to migrate over to LTE, and I think we had Sprint being out yesterday also then launching LTE markets and I noticed it was only Ericsson markets that they launched. And also then, we continue to be obsessed by superior performance in our project and our product development. We believe it's a key aspect for us and our customers and to focus on that. And with that, I hand over to the Head of Services, Mr. Mandersson.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Johan. Hello, everybody. We had a very good quarter. We have again demonstrated that we can deliver profitable growth. We are seeing 26% growth; in Swedish currency adjusted, we're doing 18% year over year. All our business lines is driving high growth, as you can see on slide one. I think we have over the past 12 months worked very much with capability buildup in the front line but also in our Global Service centers, and that has driven a profitable growth for us.</p>
          <p>We see continuous strong demand for transformational services delivered by the consulting and systems integration team and, of course, it's a great focus from the operators to reduce OpEx and also to technology shifts that's driving the sales. We continue to lead in Managed Services with 17 contracts over the Q2 here. Of course, the sales is very much driven of all the 70 contracts that we took last year.</p>
          <p>So all in all, I think we have a very good momentum on Professional Services. Network Rollout is then an effect of all the new contracts that we have done with Networks, and then, of course, it's very much driven by the European &#x2013; the result is very much driven by the European modernization. I think you spent time on that already in the morning. And of course, we, Johan and I, we are driving as much as we can network performance and execution in the projects we're having around in Network Rollout.</p>
          <p>I think we also demonstrated good sequential profitable growth in Professional Services. I think this, again, it's very much driven by the set-up we're having with our local and global delivery structure, which is unique in itself. We will continue to drive that throughout the year. Also I would say that a year back, we had 5% operating margin, and we have improved that with one percentage notch in Q2 this year. So all in all, I think we are quite strong in driving the operations at the moment. And with these few words, I hand over to Mr. Vestberg and Support Solutions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Magnus. So, we're looking at the Support Solutions for the quarter, up 47% year over year. Here, of course, we have the impact of the acquisition of Telcordia; excluding that, growing some 16% including adjusted for foreign exchange rate. So we're growing well in billing solutions in the Middle East, Sub-Saharan Africa, and also in the TV area in this quarter.</p>
          <p>Telcordia had roughly SEK 600 million in the quarter in the segment of Support Solutions. We are splitting this between Services and Support Solutions 50/50, the revenues from Telcordia. The operating margins, 12%, which is the highest since we started reporting the segment, at least as I can remember. This is driven very much by the favorable product mix and the increased volumes. We are volume sensitive in Support Solutions as it's a lot of software and a fixed cost in R&amp;D for that.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we're taking down the cost levels and that creates this 12% operating margin. The key priorities right now for Support Solutions besides to execute on the strategy that we outlined in the beginning of the year is of course transform this momentum to sustainable profit at this level and the second is that of course integrate Telcordia in a good way to see that we get all the benefits from that acquisition.</p>
          <p>If I then continue with the regions and of the 10 regions that we report, six of them were growing year over year, and eight of them were growing sequentially. Some highlights, North America, we talked about still growth in North America despite the decline in CDMA or the expected decline in CDMA. Latin America has been growing for quite a while right now and grew also in this quarter by 9%.</p>
          <p>Northern Europe and Central Asia, here you see the impact of Russia, down 26% year over year. Western Europe, Central Europe, down 6%, still a good momentum for Services. Here, we have a proportionately higher share of Global Services and Support Solutions which is higher than 60% in this region, indicating that the investments in equipment is lower here at the moment.</p>
          <p>Mediterranean is also growing 12%, Middle East 4%, they have been now growing for some quarters. One region that is really coming up after some tougher times is Sub-Sahara up 26%, driven about cheaper smart phones coming out in the region but also Nigeria, which is one of the most important markets. India, we have discussed; equipment sales in India is fairly low compared to last year, down 39%, the whole region India and that is, of course, a reflection of the uncertainties of regulatory environment.</p>
          <p>However, quarter on quarter, you see that they are coming up now 20%. Then we have discussed China and Northeast Asia. Of course, what is sticking out here is that China 2G is lower compared to year over year, last year when we had a strong sales of GSM but also decreased quarter on quarter sequentially. Here is a lot of LTE happening at the moment. South East Asia and Oceania up 21%. Here, of course, Indonesia a very important market growing and there is a lot of 3G. In the other area where we have our IP or our licensing, we have the favorable development of that, but we also had the Multimedia Brokering (IPX) growing in this area as well. So by that, I hand over to Jan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you, Hans. Then let me give you some brief highlights on P&amp;L and balance sheet. We start with the very important three indicators that are impacting the gross margin and the dynamics of the gross margin. The first one is the business mix, and by that we mean the share of coverage versus capacity project, and also the modernization projects in Europe, as well as the overall Services share in the company.</p>
          <p>So let me then start with saying that we had in this quarter, as far as I can remember looking back probably the strongest Services share ever in the company, in terms of revenue share. And for you then to understand a bit better on what that does to our gross margin, we have then said that if you look at the 32% gross margin we have in the quarter versus the 37.8% we had last year in the second quarter, about half of that reduction has to do with growth in Services, which I think is important for you to know.</p>
          <p>Fundamentally, of course, growing Services is good for the business and good for the bottom line, but it has an impact on the gross margin. We also had the impact of the European modernization projects, if we compare with last year, because the projects were all in full execution in Q4. So there are these impacts, and if we then look at this quarter specifically versus last quarter, I think we have already commented on the fact that the Services share has increased again. We also have the same impact of the modernization projects in Europe as we had in the first quarter. The only big difference, I would say, is that we had somewhat more of capacity sales in Q1 than what we have in HSPA than what we have in this quarter.</p>
          <p>Overall, we have also said that the current business mix, which means then that we have more coverage projects than capacity projects than if you look in historical perspective, that business mix will prevail short term. And I'm fully aware that we have said short term now for several quarters, but with the current visibility we have with the projects that we have won, this is the best assumption that we have right now.</p>
          <p>Then if we go to the operating expenses, let me then also start there by saying that we had operating expenses of SEK 15 billion versus SEK 15.8 billion a year ago. A year ago, we also had a big restructuring charge in the second quarter, but if you look at an organic operating expense excluding the structuring charges, it is down year over year.</p>
          <p>If we look at R&amp;D, we have &#x2013; we had a run rate in the second half of 2011 that was high. Our aim and our ambition was to gradually throughout the year reduce the run rate, having then in mind that technology leadership is absolutely key for us as a value driver. In this quarter now, we have increased the guidance a little bit from SEK 30 billion to SEK 32 billion, versus SEK 29 billion to SEK 31 billion. That new guidance is still a reduction compared to last year, and it has simply to do with two reasons. One is FX and the other is to secure the potential we see in the radio area and for us, whether we have a guidance increase of SEK 1 billion or not is not important here. The important thing is to capture the value of the opportunity in radio.</p>
          <p>When it comes to operating expense overall, our focus is to optimize, and to optimize, that's extremely important for us. Operating margin 5.9% as Hans mentioned, impacted by the lower profitability in Networks, and if we compare to a year ago also, we had a higher restructuring charge.</p>
          <p>If we then go to ST-Ericsson; ST-Ericsson has had a conference call earlier today, so I refer to that conference call for more specifics. The aim here is really to look at the ownership perspective of ST-Ericsson. The main focus of the company is to secure the successful execution of the company transformation and also the revised strategy that was communicated in April. Sales in the quarter improved somewhat and operating expense continued to go down. All in all, that meant that if we compare with the first quarter, the operating income improved, still a significant loss.</p>
          <p>Then what we have done this quarter is that we have highlighted the exposures we have as Ericsson towards ST-Ericsson, so we have the investment and as well the loans to ST-Ericsson has to be transparent to all investors how the exposures we have. Then if you look at the balance sheet, I think that we have due to the fact that we have more projects in the mix and we have had so for a couple quarters, the inventory working capital level is higher than in the capacity cycle. In this particular quarter, we also ended the quarter with a very strong June. That meant that we had some impact on the accounts receivables that should be timing.</p>
          <p>Then if you look at the inventory slightly up versus the first quarter, both on accounts receivables and inventory, there is some FX impact but fundamentally, it has to do with the higher project activity. So our main corrective measure here is really to continue to focus on the &#x2013; delivering these projects with as short lead time as possible.</p>
          <p>Then finally on the cash flow, minus SEK 1.4 billion in the quarter, driven mainly then by accounts receivables and this is from our point of view, we &#x2013; you can understand that we are not happy with this cash flow. Our ambition is to have cash conversion about 70%, but I think also that we understand the reasons behind it. We also paid a dividend in this quarter, so all in all, we had a net cash of SEK 25.9 billion.</p>
          <p>I will then end with some comments on the refinancing activities. We have been very active in the quarter to extend the average debt maturity profile, but in doing that, we also had an objective not to increase gross debt. We have tapped into the U.S. bond market for the first time ever in our company history, and the purpose of that is, of course, to diversify the funding sources but also to create a natural hedge. At the same time, we have repurchased some EMT and bonds and paid back some SEK bonds in order to keep the gross debt level at the same level. The final result is more diversified source of funds, and an extended maturity profile. With that said, Hans, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, to sum up, of course we have invested both in R&amp;D and market share the last five, six quarter and we are in the midst of that execution. That's the most important thing we have in front of us, but if you look beyond that, of course, it's really to take that investment to do something good of it to make a profitable growth, I think that is the whole management's focus right now. That means that cost and efficiency is very high up on the agenda in the whole management team.</p>
          <p>We are doing quite a lot cost-efficient measures at the moment and &#x2013; which we clearly believe will have an impact. And finally, what we will not compromise on is of course our technology and service leadership, which is paving the way for us to continue being number one in the industry, that long term should pay off in a greater value. So I think that's where we are, and we really are focused on continuing taking this forward in a good way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Hans. And by this time, operator, we are ready to take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Edward Snyder from Charter Equity Research now on line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. A couple, Jan. Why was there late billing in the quarter? It's one of the reasons you had the cash flow and inventory issues. I'm just curious how that shook out? And was it an anomaly? Do you expect it in the current? And Hans, in terms of the CDMA sales dropping off which I guess was expected, it sounds like you're not seeing a commensurate increase in LTE. Is that just market share loss and not spending as much, is it macro, and do you expect that to reverse?</p>
          <p>And then on profitability, I understand you've got a lot of coverage projects going on right now, and you expect things to pick up as we head into the fourth quarter. Is that mostly &#x2013; what's the profile of that first of all? Do you expect it to be evenly spaced over the next year or so, the return to profitability just on the different business mix or will the macroeconomic environment help you out in the longer term? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so this is Jan with the first question. The answer is very simple. If you have a very strong June and your average credit days is around 100 days, they end up in the balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, and also might I add that as well the high project activity, a lot of projects are finished by end of the quarter and that was part of it as well. So that's why it was late invoicing and collection was not feasible. I think I heard your second question, I'm not sure, you have to correct me. I heard it like CDMA rolling in the U.S., asking if that is offset by LTE or not and if we will see CDMA rebound. I think that was the question. Of course, we see an uptick on LTE, that's for sure in North America as well, and on few markets that are doing quite a lot of investment in LTE.</p>
          <p>The CDMA decline is expected and we're not expecting that will come back. Remember that this we talk about CDMA equipment. We have CDMA services, everything from maintenance and all of that, that will continue for a long time as it's many, many subscribers in CDMA. But from equipment, we don't envision at this moment that this investment levels will go up. They will continue to go down. Then -- was that the question then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, primarily, it's not a commensurate increase in LTE to offset your CDMA. Verizon and now Sprint, of course, are augmenting their CDMA networks with LTE but it doesn't sound like it's a one for one swap for you. Is that share loss, is that just less spending on their part or is it something that in the future you expect to pick up more LTE as they start rolling out more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, you're cracking up a little bit, I will try again. I think you asked, is there share loss because we're in North America? It's just that last year, of course, it was quite heavy investment in CDMA and very little right now. Of course, there are LTE investment but not really offsetting totally how much we're seeing on we saw in CDMA. There are, of course, other investments on HSPA, et cetera, but now we were just talking about that small in between. But of course, over time, LTE will offset CDMA, as CDMA will continue to decline. When it comes to the profitability on Networks, we just need to split those two questions and that's what we tried to do in the quarter report as well. There are two things if you isolate impacting the profitability on Networks.</p>
          <p>One is the European modernizations, and Jan talked about they started &#x2013; some started 18 months ago. Some started all in full swing Q4 2011. What we're saying about the European modernization right now, they will start to gradually decline by end of 2012. So that impact will start to gradually decline by end of the year. When it comes to the mix, worldwide mix in Networks between capacity and coverage, then we say that short term what we can see in the final ordering is that we'll prevail in short term, that mix. We're doing a lot of coverage projects, but they're two different things. The European modernization is one and then the mix between coverage and capacity, and that, we say will prevail short term. So I think that's sort of what we're exactly describing in the report.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Mark Sue from RBC is now on the line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Hans, so if we look at the network modernization winding down, can you share us what exactly happened to the gross margins in a quantifiable metric way? And then if we consider the Services share, the business mix coverage and capacity, overall when you put it all together, can gross margins get back to 35%, does it improve to 39%? How should investors kind of think about gross margins near term and then maybe longer term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we don't guide on any gross margins here. It depends as you said yourself, depending on how good we grow in Services versus Networks, in Support Solutions, that's going to be a mix issue on the gross margin. So that is really hard to say and we're not guiding on that. But everything the same, if everything goes the same, and you have a gradual decline &#x2013; starting to have a gradual decline, by the end of 2012 on modernization, that should of course have a positive impact on the gross margin. Everything else the same. So that's what we're saying.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hans, if everything is the same, what would be the impact of the network modernization then? Should it be 200 basis points, 100 basis points, or is there a range of how investors should think about when network modernization winds down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not giving range on that one, how much it is, but of course, as we talk about these two elements in the gross margin impact on Networks, those are the big ones that we have there. Meaning the capacity coverage and the modernizations, of course they are of importance for modeling their gross margin. But we are not giving out any range how much it will impact, et cetera. But everything the same, mix and all of that, and start to have a gradual decline of network modernization by year end, end of 2012, we'll, of course, see gross margin going up. But again, everything the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And subsequently, there will be no further modernization projects around the world?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now remember, this was a distinct effort we made, and we were clear to the market and maybe &#x2013; maybe we should have even been clearer on talking about it, but this we started to talk about Q4 2010 that Europe came up. We had low market share over 3G; we wanted to come back there because we believe that a footprint will create a much stronger Ericsson long term. There are normally deals around the world all the time, and that we are dealing with all the time, and that we'll continue to do, but there are no specific region, no specific thing that we need to do right now to gain market share that we need to announce. But there's going to be deals all the time, but there's nothing as distinct as the European modernization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful. Thank you, gentlemen.</p>
          <p>.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Sandeep Deshpande from JPMorgan is now on line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, thank you for taking my question. I have a question on, Hans, on the strategic view of the company. Services continues to grow as a percentage of revenues and Services margin remains sub-double digit. So, you've recently acquired Telcordia. How do you see the Services margin, even the EBIT line, growing over the next few years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if you look at the Global Services, I think the Professional Services have been in a band and a bracket on an EBITA level of 13% to 16% since we started to report it, and that is, of course, driven about how much growth you have in it as well because when you have growth, you will capture some or impact on the gross margin, but that's where we are. And of course, we have all the ambition to keep that.</p>
          <p>The big swing factor in Services, of course, Network Rollout, which is very much impacted by the European modernization that, of course, we're far from happy with the profits we have on Network Rollout, but that is also a conscious decision we made. Then, of course, expansion in Services into media and broadcasting, et cetera, OSS, BSS is very important for us. This quarter I tried to mention also system integration and consulting that we don't talk so much about <mark type="indiscernible" /> (37:04) this is an important area for us that is growing very fast coming very much from our investment in OSS, BSS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
          <p>.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Achal Sultania from Credit Suisse is on the line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Two questions if I may to Hans. On European modernization contracts, obviously, basically we expect the gross margin impact to stretch out till the end of this year, right, as of to your expectation of probably ending by the end of Q2. Now what I'm just trying to guess is, is it due to spending cautiousness from operators, or is it to do with the complexity of these kinds of projects? And also is there a risk that some of the Southern European countries may actually lead to further stretch-out &#x2013; stretching out of these modernization contracts into early 2013? And then I've got a follow-up for Jan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to the European modernization, the only change we made was initially when we thought it would start earlier, but the timeframe of 18 to 24 months has been there all the time and we kicked in all &#x2013; all of them were in full swing in Q4. So we have not changed when they will gradually start to decline, that is basically saying because they have the maturity of 18 to 24 months. We thought they would start maybe in Q1 2011, more of them and they started a little bit slow because they were complex, but since then, it has been exactly sort of the plan that we have seen. So far, we've not seen any impact on the current modernization due to the macroeconomics. We are not seeing that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks. And basically, Jan, on the OpEx side, if I look at your revenues in the first half of this year, they are slightly down a percent year on year but the clean OpEx number excluding restructuring is actually flat to slightly up, and given that you've taken over SEK 2 billion of restructuring charges in your OpEx in the last year and a half, shouldn't that OpEx run rate be much lower because I guess my question is, shouldn't we expect this OpEx run rate to actually slow down in the second half, or is it something that you think that the current level is the normal level for your business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the question, please also remember that Telcordia came into the numbers in mid Q1 and their operating expense is actually predominantly selling and G&amp;A expense, so you should know that as well. Having said all that, our plan has all the time been to work ourselves down from a run rate point of view, and all the activities that we are running both in terms of transformation in &#x2013; continued transformation in R&amp;D and work on efficiencies in administration and so forth, are ongoing activities that should start to yield here gradually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks.</p>
          <p>.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Stuart Jeffrey from Nomura is now on line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, thanks, everyone. Hans, you mentioned you'd seen most of your customer base in the last 25 (sic) [45] (40:33) days, and I was hoping you might be able to share a bit more sort of insight as to what's happening amongst operators, specifically just remembering back to last year, everyone was very surprised by what happened in the second half, and you had an exceptionally unusual Network dynamic in Q4 in terms of seasonality. I know you don't like to talk about specific quantified guidance, but could you just take us through what's similar and what's different this time around just to help us have a bit of confidence as to where the second half might be trending? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're right, we don't guide on specific quarter or half years, but the discussions, and I can relate back to the sort of &#x2013; of course we all discuss the environment around us, the fundamentals for the industry, new subscribers, usage of mobile broadband, new devices. My conclusion is that that remains, that fundamental remains. The other is, of course, in certain markets, we talk more about macroeconomics, and here you can &#x2013; you got the feeling that they are more continue the planning than before or equal as in the first quarter but they're doing a lot of continue the planning.</p>
          <p>In the discussion, we have not seen any major changes, as I said, on macroeconomics when it comes to modernization in Europe or something like that, that they are halting them. That's what we have right now, and for us, it's to stay close to the customer all the time to see what's happening, and see if there are any changes to that, but that's what we have right now, when we close the books, by the 30 of June 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of your ability -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can also add there, Stuart, a few things. I think if you look at Networks per quarter in 2011, it was a quite strange year in the sense that it was really no seasonality, but a lot of things happened within the year as we all remember. I think now in 2012, our supply chain is working excellent, and we have, as Hans said as well, in this quarter, we had &#x2013; we made a comparison to normal seasonality, so I think that this is from many respects a bit more normal year when it comes to supply chain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Gareth Jenkins from UBS is now on line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks, this is a bit of a follow up between two of the last two questions, just on seasonality in OpEx. I wonder if you could just help us understand the OpEx moving into the second half of the year, Jan. You talked about maybe being able to work it down somewhat, but I think typically OpEx splits 50/50 during the course of an average year. I just wondered whether you feel that's the case. And obviously related to that, what you see Networks' margins doing through the course of the back half of the year as a result? That's the first one. And then just second one, given, again, that you've spoken to lots of your customers, I just wondered whether there's any sense of panic among those customers given the financing position of at least one if not two of their vendors currently. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Gareth. So, I talk about my favorite topic, OpEx. I think that -- so if you look at the &#x2013; if we start with the research and development then, we ended last year on a high run rate for a couple of reasons. First and foremost, we wanted to secure the timely launch of our IP router portfolio, the SSR, Smart Services Router. We also wanted to secure that we could deliver a CDMA baseband into our RBS 6000 and finally we wanted to secure the TD-LTE part of our portfolio. So those were three priorities that we focused a lot on in the second half of this year.</p>
          <p>Now we obviously then are working ourselves down in terms of research and development, still with the important disclaimer as I said in the beginning, because I think that research and development and the ability right now to have sufficient funds to capture more markets or extend leadership is very important, but we also work with efficiencies there, it is a gradual decline. CDMA is obviously one area where we work with reductions and other areas are really areas that that's not the impact what I would call productive R&amp;D. It's more around how we perform testing and things like that.</p>
          <p>So it's normal good improvements that we're talking about. Then if we talk about selling and G&amp;A, I think on the G&amp;A side, we have good programs in place, both with finance, IS/IT and HR in order to work down the cost base, these are multi-year programs and they yield quarterly over quarter improvements, so those are now &#x2013; we have continued with those programs. Finally on the selling expense side, as I said, the Telcordia numbers are now in the picture, but having said that, the whole new go-to-market model that we launched two years ago aims at sharing sales resources and presales resources in a better way to become more effective. So short answer, run rates should gradually come down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then you had a question about Networks' gross margin coming back. I can only refer to what I said before. Everything the same, network modernization will start gradually decline by end of 2012. Short term, in the funnel and in the orders, we have still more coverage than capacity in our delivery networks. The same comments were made in the report, I think I said a couple of times. Then you asked if some operators, customers were worried for their indebtness, et cetera. I cannot go into specific customers but it's clear that some have a pretty high indebtness and of course are trying to preserve and to reduce that. That can lead to more opportunities in services and in transformation, so &#x2013; but nothing particular to point out on any particular operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Hans. Could I just follow up on the second point on that question, I was actually referring to are you seeing any panic amongst the operators regarding the financing position of their vendors, and, therefore, picking up some business as a result of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't see any new behaviors. I think we have nothing new really to say around the competitive dynamics and the relationship with the operators, that's really for our operators to comment rather than us, I would say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
          <p>.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Francois Meunier from Morgan Stanley is now on the line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you for taking my question. Actually, I wanted to follow up on Gareth's question. Given what's going on with Alcatel, NSN and also ZTE to some extent. The pricing last year was pretty bad for hardware. It is getting better now, because of what we are seeing in the competitive environment which looks like it's improving.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Was that the question or a comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's a question. Is the pricing improving?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we look at the pricing, as it's less of a distinct European modernization. Of course in general, we have not seen any change in the competitive landscape. Big deals sort of where you compete for footprint, then of course, it's competitive. However, we see change in who is competing from one quarter to another. There's definitely quite a lot of things happening in the industry at the moment. We meet different competitors in different markets that from one year ago were probably others that we met there. So, yes, they are changing, but on the pricing environment over one quarter, I wouldn't say that I have seen any major changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you feel like that you have to be as aggressive as you've been last year in terms of, you know, pricing aggression basically to take market share in general, or is market share coming to you more easily?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't feel that we need to be that aggressive because we have no such goals at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
          <p>.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Kai Korschelt from Deutsche Banc is on the line with a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you very much. Just another question on the business mix and I fully understood what you're saying about maybe the rest of the year, but I'm just wondering if we think about more on a higher level sort of going into next year and beyond, looks like in Latin America, there will be 4G contracts tendered soon, or possibly you have China, maybe at some stage Africa. So I'm just wondering as the majority of your regions that are still in 3G mode move to LTE, will those sort of deployments and rollouts also impact gross margins negatively, and I guess the question is, is there a risk that this may just sort of happen and cancel out the margin improvements that we could see in Europe, or do you think the LTE deployments in those sort of regions won't happen next year and are really more a 2014 type story? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Still we need to understand that the majority is deployment on 3G, there of course is going to be 4G, but that's clear. That type of mix we had all the time that we always have technology shift, so that we need to manage. I think the modernization was something distinct. We're going to have, of course, new 4G markets coming up in certain markets, but that means also that some 3G markets will be in capacity. So that is a mix that we're going to see how that turns out in 2013. What we say right now short term, the mix that we have right now, with capacity and coverage, that will prevail in short term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Also, Kai, one comment more from me there, also I think we refer back to the discussion we had when we met here in Sweden last year, the importance of knowing and understanding the advantages of the RBS 6000, it is hardware heavy in the beginning, and then also feature expansions and annual software upgrades and so forth is there. So I think there is also a possibility to upsell with new softwares whether traffic is coming or not, because this is still a lot of new features asked for. Secondly, as the ecosystem continues to expand, both on 4G and 3G, more and more smart phones, more and more usage is also, of course, driving the need for more software and feature upgrades.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, we have time for one final question.</p>
          <p>.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question comes from Richard Kramer from Arete. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys, a couple questions that I don't think really have been touched on exactly yet. Hans, you made the comment in your &#x2013; in the statement that the focus is now on translating market share gains into sustainable profit growth and that was something we haven't heard before. And yet it's kind of hard to see how Networks is making much money now beyond the IPR income. When you look out on 12 to 18 month view, are you expecting increased volumes to change, and if not, why wouldn't we see a much wider restructuring program than the gradual cost reductions that Jan just mentioned?</p>
          <p>And then one for Magnus as well; back at the Capital Markets Day, I think you were you suggesting that NRO in a normal world should be break even business, and that you had one-offs that had led to the SEK 1 billion of losses up through the nine months of 2011, and now the last three quarters obviously the losses are much larger. What's causing the losses in these rollout deals? Can you be a bit more specific, because it seems to be odd that you should be losing money on rollout contracts. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Networks then, again, I think that &#x2013; I think it's a natural step here when it comes to profitable growth. We're not changing the strategy. We're going for being number one in everything we're into, mobile network services, OSS, BSS, et cetera. So the strategies and the combination of the assets is still the same. However, as you yourself said, we have been in the phase of investment in R&amp;D as well as in market share. That we don't see at the same level going forward. And therefore, we also believe that we can bring down the cost over time here, and then, of course, everything equal with these projects over time should make the profitability higher in Networks. I'm not saying it's now or tomorrow, but saying that that is, of course, the management's focus right now and we are not satisfied with the profitability as such right now. But there are reasons why we're there and we will do everything to work ourselves out of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on the question you had there on Network Rollout, just to be clear on that, the Network Rollout business, the ambition is there. This should be a &#x2013; this is a business that we should make money on. It will, however, have lower margins. The reason for the losses is related to the European modernization projects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But what's gone wrong in those contracts that you have so many persistent losses? Why isn't, over time, you starting to reduce those losses as opposed to seeing them at the same level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are in the middle of the rollout of the European modernization project, so I think we have talked a lot about the dynamics of those, and we have said that all projects are in full execution &#x2013; was in full execution in Q4, and we will continue to have an impact of these projects throughout this year, gradually improvements end of this year. So there is &#x2013; I don't really understand what you're after. I think that this is very clear that this is related to the European modernization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Hans, just to be clear on your comments, you're not expecting a volume uplift, you're saying it's about bringing down cost in the Network business over time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think that we do not &#x2013; so to begin with, we do not guide on volumes. What we say is that we have an impact on gross margin both on Networks and Network Rollout when the mix of network modernization starts to be reduced, then we also have the other important impact that we discussed at the Investor Day, and that was the fact that once you have the hardware out there, for instance, for multi-standard radio, the next cycle is more software-heavy, and finally, as Johan also mentioned here, the importance of winning deals, for instance, with the smart service router. So there are opportunities to improve gross margin also in a volume scenario that is not growing. Again, we are not guiding here for future revenues. But we are rather saying that we understand what we need to do in order to improve gross margins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Richard, and thank you, everyone. This concludes our call today then, so bye-bye, and have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. This concludes today's conference call. Thank you for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>