<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1149640" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-04-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>194</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">David Myers, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jeffrey L. Hall, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">George Paz, Chairman, Chief Executive Officer and President</participant>
      <participant id="4">Glenn Garmont</participant>
      <participant id="5">George Paz</participant>
      <participant id="6">Jeffrey Hall</participant>
      <participant id="7">Glen Santangelo</participant>
      <participant id="8">Robert Willoughby</participant>
      <participant id="9">Lawrence Marsh</participant>
      <participant id="10">Tom Gallucci</participant>
      <participant id="11">Lisa Gill</participant>
      <participant id="12">Ricky Goldwasser</participant>
      <participant id="13">John Kreger</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen thank you for standing by and welcome to the First Quarter 2008 Earnings Conference Call. At this time all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later we will conduct a question and answer session; instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. As a reminder this conference is being recorded</p>
          <p>I'll now like to turn the conference over to our host Mr. Dave Myers. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, operator, and good morning, everyone. Welcome to our first quarter 2008 conference call. With me this morning are George Paz, our CEO and Jeff Hall, our new CFO.</p>
          <p>Before we begin I need to read the following statement. Statements or comments made on this conference call may be forward-looking statements and may include, but are not necessarily limited to, financial projections or other statements of the company's plans, objectives, expectations, or intentions. These matters involve certain risks and uncertainties. The company's actual results may differ significantly from those projected or suggested in any forward-looking statements due to a variety of factors, which are discussed in detail in our SEC filing.</p>
          <p>In addition, the reconciliation of EBITDA to net income and the net cash provided by operating activities can be found in our earnings release, which is posted on our web site.</p>
          <p>At this point, I'll turn the call over to Jeff Hall to discuss our first quarter results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, David. Before I talk about our first quarter results, let me just take a second to answer the three questions I've been hearing. Why did I decide to join Express Scripts, what are my initial impressions from my first months with the company, and what is my vision for the CFO role here.</p>
          <p>One of the things I do as a CFO is analyze data and look for information in order to make good decisions. So in this context, as I went through the interview and due diligence process, three patterns that are very important to me became obvious. First, the management team and Board are both very talented and driven to succeed. Second, there is a strong focus on alignment of the company's interest with that of its clients, and as a result success is defined by improving patient's health outcomes, lowering prescription drug costs and trends for clients and patients, and providing superior returns to shareholders. And third, while shareholder returns have been in the top 1% of the Fortune 500 over the last 10 years, there are still a lot of opportunities for growth in both prescription volume and profitability. It was these three factors, a talented and driven team, the focus on alignment with clients, and the potential to grow the company that made Express Scripts a compelling opportunity for me.</p>
          <p>To the second question, my impression is after one month. I have had the opportunity to spend lot of time with the management team and I have found that great talent, the culture of alignment, and the dedication to delivering outstanding returns exists at all levels in the organization. I also had the opportunity to spend three days at our Annual Outcomes Conference, meeting with many our clients. I heard directly from them how they valued our model and how we have been helping to improve patient outcomes and lower their drug trend. In addition, our strategic programs around consumer engagement resonated exceedingly well with them and you'll hear more about that from George in a minute. So while this may sound overly enthusiastic after only a month, I am proud to be a part of this team and excited about the opportunities ahead.</p>
          <p>And now to the future and my role going forward. I will continue to build on the strong franchise here by driving growth, innovation, profitability, and returns to shareholders, while maintaining the alignment with our customers. That is making sure we continue to structure our business so that we make money when our clients save money. And finally, I would be remiss in not thanking to retiring CFO for leaving me with a very strong finance team and a first quarter that both beat guidance and was significantly up from the prior year.</p>
          <p>Now let me take you through some the financial highlights for the March quarter. Total adjusted claims were 129.6 million, up slightly from both prior year and prior quarter. Network claims were 98.2 million, up both sequentially and versus prior year. Home delivery claims were 10.1 million, up slightly from the prior year, but down slightly from the December quarter. This sequential decline is the result of the loss of two mail fulfillment clients that have virtually no impact on current or future profitability. As a result of these losses, we have updated our forecast and now expect mail volumes to be flat to slightly up for the year. Our industry-leading generic fill rate set a new record in the quarter at 65.1%. This improvement in generic fill rate created savings for our clients and helped to increase our gross profit to 10.2% or 468.7 million, up 14% from the prior year.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A in the quarter was 174.1 million, and we expect to stay at approximately this level for the rest of the year. EBITDA was 319.1 million, up 19% from the prior year, and EBITDA per adjusted script was $2.46, up from $2.10 in the prior year. This was in line with our expectations and reflects the large percentage of our book of business that was renewed last year.</p>
          <p>Net interest expense for the quarter was 18 million, as a result of the decline in interest rates. Based on current market forecasts for interest rates, we expect slight reductions in net interest expense for the balance of the year. Earnings per share from continuing operations was $0.70, a 35% increase over the $0.52 in the prior year. Cash flow from continuing operations was a record for a first quarter at 248.3 million, compared to 158.9 million in the prior year.</p>
          <p>Now let me review our SAAS segment briefly. This segment continues to deliver mixed results. On the one hand, while core specialty pharmacy continues to meet our expectations, our overall specialty results were again impacted by charges in our distribution business. We have placed a specialty distribution business under Agnes, one our senior executives who many of you know. She will focus on improving the results of this business unit in the future.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, the core specialty pharmacy business continues to be an integral part of our overall success, and we believe we are well positioned in this marketplace. Many of the clients I spoke to at our Outcomes Conference told me our specialty pharmacy offering was increasingly allowing them to improve the cost and quality of specialty care for their members. In addition, our integrated offering has become a key element in winning new PBM business, and we expect that this momentum will continue throughout the selling season.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to our guidance for the year. We are increasing our 2008 guidance for EPS from continuing operations by $0.03 to $2.95 to $3.03. We are also increasing our guidance for cash flow from operations to a range of 900 million to 1 billion. Our priorities for the uses of this cash remain the same. The first priority is funding internal innovation and growth programs. The Center for Cost-Effective Consumerism, while a relatively small investment, is a great example of how we can use our resources to create better health outcomes, savings for our clients, and increase our profitability. Our next priority is strategic, accretive acquisitions to grow the business. And finally returning excess cash to the shareholders in the form of share repurchases. For 2008, we anticipate that we will use the majority our free cash flow for share repurchases.</p>
          <p>Finally, let me reiterate how strongly I feel about the future of Express Scripts. This is a great company with an outstanding track record of performance. I am looking forward to working with the team here to build on this strong franchise, and I am looking forward to meeting with many of you over the next several months.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll turn it over to George.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jeff, and good morning everyone. Jeff took you through the details of another strong quarter, which we again attribute to our success of our business model of alignment. From our beginning, we have always been focused on better clinical outcomes while driving down our clients' drug trends. We are excited about our recent launch of a new strategic platform that will take our business model of alignment to the next level, enabling better health and value, one consumer at a time. As we continue to drive better health outcomes while lowering drug trend, we increasingly understand that financial incentives, although important, are only part of the story when it comes to driving formulary compliance and lower cost.</p>
          <p>Research clearly shows that human behavior depends on many other factors. We must better understand the basis for consumer behavior and apply those insights to deliver better health outcomes and cost savings for our patients. Guided by these findings, we have established the Center for Cost-Effective Consumerism. The center will accelerate development of an advanced understanding of the consumer and what works and what doesn't work when trying to change the way consumers use healthcare. PBMs and sponsors frequently speak to employees that they are all driven by the same approach. Historically, messaging around group's patients together by condition or disease.</p>
          <p>Yet leading consumer companies have learned through extensive research and testing that there is no one size fits all. To make a real impact on consumers, we must speak to them as individuals. The Center for Cost-Effective Consumerism fuses Express Scripts' industry-leading research capabilities with insights from an advisory board of national experts in the science of human behavior and decision-making. We are creating and implementing a more precise and reliable approach in working with our patients to further improve their health outcomes while lowering drug cost.</p>
          <p>By moving to this next level of alignment, we will enable better health and value through improved therapy adherence in key therapeutic classes including diabetes, hypertension, cholesterol and asthma. In addition, we will deliver increased savings through greater use of generics and lower-cost preferred brands, as well as increasing use of our cost effective home delivery services. We believe this new focus will also better position us around emerging specialty opportunities.</p>
          <p>Express Scripts is on the forefront of managing the costs of specialty drugs today. We have formulary management, prior authorization, and therapy adherence programs. These efforts are having an impact. As reported at our Outcomes Conference earlier this month, our actions have resulted in a upward trend in specialty drugs being reduced by one-third. Our new consumer platform will further differentiate Express Scripts in the marketplace and enhance our brand of alignment and generate continued value for our clients and growth for our stockholders.</p>
          <p>In addition, we are pleased that e-prescribing is gaining momentum. With the publishing of proposed e-prescribing standards last November, CMS estimated that with only an 18% adoption rate, Medicare savings would exceed $4 billion over five years. In December, a bipartition legislation was introduced in both Houses of Congress, which would require physician adoption of e-prescribing by January 2011. The widespread adoption of e-prescribing will result in a higher generic utilization and improved formulary compliance with lower costs for preferred brands.</p>
          <p>We know that a big advantage of electronic prescribing is also improved safety. Electronic scripts mean greater legibility and fewer mistakes, but e-prescribing will also result in better healthcare. Doctors and patients will have better access to information concerning the best drugs for specific conditions. We believe that this especially true in managing the delivery channel for optimum cost effectiveness. We are excited about our position in the marketplace and our opportunities for the future. I look forward to sharing with you this success for our new consumer platform on future conference calls and investor meetings.</p>
          <p>This concludes our prepared remarks. And now we'll be happy to answer any questions. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And our first question comes from the line of Glenn Garmont with Broadpoint Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah thanks, two quick questions. Number one, you mentioned in your prepared remarks that your outlook now incorporates lower net interest. I was wondering if you sort of quantify the magnitude of that reduction. And then secondarily, George, there has been some press lately about sort of the upward surge in specialty co-pays. Now I was wondering within your specialty book, are you seeing a trend toward either Tier 4 or coinsurance for some of those specialty products? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't &#x2013; I'm going to have Jeff answer the interest question first, then I'll take the specialty question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So first of all let me say that we don't try to predict forward interest rate. What we do when we do our forecast is we go out and look at what the market implied interest rates are. And they haven't changed a lot since we gave guidance last quarter, so I'll say that the interest rate expense that we've got in our forecast today is not that materially different than what we had a quarter ago. But for interest rate overall, we were net 18 million in this quarter, and we expect to be a little bit, as I said in my prepared remarks, a little bit lower than that for the balance of the quarter, assuming we don't see a significant change in interest rates from where the market is forecasting them today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to specialty drugs, this is a very tough issue that all of our plan sponsors must deal with. On one hand, you have the ever increasing cost of the drugs that are in the marketplace, new therapies coming to market at very high prices, which of course then drives drug trends to even higher numbers. The client has to weigh the impact of co-pays and higher co-pays and percentage co-pays against that of compliance with the overall program. At the end of the day, in certain therapy class whether these drugs are very much life-sustaining having non-compliance is not necessarily a good answer for all overall healthcare trends. Clients depending on what their needs are, where they are at in their product cycles have to decide what their appetite is and how to manage these drug costs. I believe we have the best account management and the best clinical &#x2013; clinicians available to help the clients actually try to figure out what their end gain goals are, and some of our clients do put percentage co-pays in place, others try to make sure that the compliance stays strong to keeping co-pays in check. So I think there is no one size fits all answer to this question either. It's a very difficult question that plan sponsors are being confronted with today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for the comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Charles Boorady with Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Garin stepping in for Charles. Could you help us think through the EPS progression for the remainder of the year? Are there any seasonal differences compared to prior years you could highlight the difference this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will handle that off to Jeff to answer that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We give guidance only for the full year; that's been how we've done it. I certainly don't intend on changing that practice. So we're comfortable with our guidance range for the year, but we're not going to really opine on progression throughout the balance of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fair enough. And then just a follow-up to that is what are your overall thoughts regarding how health plans are currently viewing their PBM with United Health recently renewing with its external PBM and Coventry putting out an RFP for its external PBM business. Are you seeing any sort of a change in the approach health plans are taking with PBMs or is it just the same, business as usual?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's different by plan sponsor. As you know, a significant amount of our business is with managed care plans. In those situations I think the integration of our drug data with their medical data and designing programs to drive overall costs down for their patients has proven to be a successful tool and them gaining market share. As our clients have grown, our book of business grows. So it's useful. I think other companies have taken the approach to in source. I think United's move speaks &#x2013; bodes well and speaks well to the proposition that PBMs are very strong source of value to drive drug cost down and improve patient outcomes. So we are seeing some of that, but I'm not sure there is a trend that exists today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So no change essentially from . . .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well again, I think it's client-by-client. I think some are looking at it, and others are staying status quo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. All right. Very useful. Thank you much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from the line of Glen Santangelo with Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah George, just two quick questions. The first is with respect to the pricing environment. There's been some chatter in the marketplace about CVS potentially getting a little bit more aggressive on pricing. Maybe we're seeing the managed care companies pull back a little bit. Could you give us a sense for the pricing environment and what you're seeing out there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This has been an incredibly competitive market. I came to Express Scripts on January 2nd, 1998, and I think my very first investor call, everybody wanted to know about price competition and they were hearing that price pressure was intensifying. I don't think that's let up at all. I think it really requires a very focused management team to go out and try to figure out ways to drive client trends down. At the end of the day, a client is more concerned about their overall cost, and if you look at how much a PBM makes per prescription, you can only take so much out of that.</p>
          <p>At the end of the day, the best savings that are going to occur are through generic utilization, maximizing the use of home delivery where appropriate, getting better lower cost brands, in other words formulary compliance, using second tier instead of third tier products, managing utilization where appropriate, and at the end of the day that's what a PBM should get paid for. So although there is pressure, the way you answer that pressure is not necessarily to take money out of your own pocket, but instead it's to design programs to lower those trends and that fortifies our position in the marketplace, and I think that's one of the reasons you see our retention rate so high, even in a very price competitive marketplace.</p>
          <p>So I think that there's always going to be discussions around price competition, and one person's great opportunity doesn't necessarily look as good to somebody else. So there may be a situation where Caremark CVS goes deep, because they see something in a client opportunity that maybe the other two of the competitors don't or any of the managed care plans don't. Likewise, it could be something big for Medco or vice versa. So I think this is a very competitive marketplace, and we continue to increase our guidance and achieve all-time high results. So we're pretty comfortable with our position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And George, just one quick follow-up. Any sort of update on the TRICARE contract at this point or timing on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we sent in our bid to the government. I think we are extremely pleased with the services we've provided to the Department of Defense over the time we've held that contract. The decision is supposed to be made towards the end of June, so barring an extension on that decision process, we should know by the end of June the results of that process. We like our position. We think we've added a lot of value for the Department of Defense, but obviously there's no guarantees in life.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for the comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from the line of Robert Willoughby with Banc of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey George, have you encountered any difficulties with the sale of the infusion therapy business or is that proceeding on trend? And then just secondarily, I thought you'd raised on the last conference call the possibility of reviewing the traditional distribution business that Priority had brought on board, is that still core in your mind or any change in thinking there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Specialty distribution is an interesting business, because of some of the disease states we manage. Our priority just to be clear was to make sure we got specialty put together first and managed well. I feel very good about where we stand in the specialty pharmacy business. I think we have the state-of-the-art offering and we are best-in-class with respect to clinical programs and value for our clients. So we are very proud of our specialty pharmacy offering. The second piece was to look at infusion, and the third piece will be the look at distribution. We are undecided or we are still analyzing the distribution side. I think with Agnes in there we are at a much better position. She is managing the business quite well, and we'll keep you posted on that one. I am going to have Jeff speak to the infusion process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the sale of the infusion business is going along pretty much as I'd expect, moving along well. A few people in-house doing what I would call second round due diligence, so we don't want to give a whole lot more details for obvious reasons, but you know well along.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>George, wasn't part of the synergy on the Priority deal, it was to be able to influence the physician behavior though and manage some of the trend in the physician office and that's what that core distribution business might have brought you, some greater capability there? Is that just not what you found or am I just wrong in that, in my understanding?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, you're exactly right. When you look at pulmonary hypertension and several other disease states, having access to the doctor is pretty important, and that's what we've got to get our arms around. The problem is, as you unfortunately had to bear up underneath was we've had several quarters in a row with some write offs, as we're trying to right size the business. It's hard to figure out the strategic value of an operation when you're righting the organization. So just being quite honest and blunt, we've got to get the organization running smoothly first then evaluate the strategic value in the organization, and again we'll keep you posted on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is there any timeframe whatsoever, do you have a two-year patients horizon here or?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am not. At this point, I don't want to speak to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from the line of Larry Marsh with Lehman Brothers. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. And George I think Bob Willoughby and I actually remember that 1998 conference call, so you've done okay since then. Really my question is around your mail script guidance, looks like you're taking it down by about 4 million this year, suggesting the loss of two low margin customers. I think we knew that back in February, so I guess my question is what's changed since then? I know you don't like to get too specific, but and then remind us what makes a customer low margin mail customer and how do we tell what's a good one, what's a bad one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, clearly, our financials clearly point to what the margin in an account is. So yeah, I mean at the end of the day, if it's a low margin account, it's low margin. I mean it's pretty easy to calculate. So one of the problems you have when you have a mail-only client, and there's less and less of that today, quite honestly, because I think the clients are seeing the value in an integrated offering. And I think to be honest with you, PBMs are more inclined to try to get those integrated clients.</p>
          <p>When you think about the work that can be done in mail, when we control the formulary with the help of our clients, and obviously we don't control it, we consult with our clients, but we work together to put a formulary in place. Then we can ultimately drive better formulary compliance through second tier products that are specialty distribution cost effective and compliant and really maximize the value out of the channel. In certain situations, it's better to go retail. In many, many more situations it's better go to mail. But getting the right mix of those drugs is paramount to us driving overall trend. And so having the integrated offering is a better answer for us. Jeff, I don't know if you want speak to guidance component.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think we went through and did a roll up again of where we expect mail scripts to be for the year. And flat to slightly up is what it's rolling up to. I think back to the February timeframe, I think we didn't update guidance for this back on that call. And this is something we don't normally give guidance into and we don't plan on giving it going forward. What we saw was we looked at some of the models that perhaps some of the models were will a little bit off so it made sense for us to go in and make sure everybody knew what we are expecting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, because I have specific confirmation on mid-February you said you confirmed 9 to 11%; maybe that was offline. I know that's not you, but I just want to understand as you roll back up, is it just some of your customers who rolled off are bigger than you thought or some of the new wins you thought are coming in slower than you expect or just a combination of both?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I do think it is that one of the things we did when we gave that guidance of course was we are very much focused on EBITDA cash flow and EPS and &#x2013; so any way, when these clients rolled off, they didn't really have much of an impact if any on those three metrics. So I will tell you though the one thing we're not saying here is that we do put a lot of stock in our new consumer efforts, and we don't have that factored in to the extent that we can convert mail. I'm not suggesting that that's going to take us to a whole new level in this year, but that certainly going to be one of our focuses; so that's what hard about trying to give this type of guidance because it really has a lot to do with mix. 7/1 is still around the corner, and there's still clients that are making decisions for 7/1, not huge ones, but those decisions could ultimately affect the mix as well. We'd rather ultimately just try to give EPS, EBITDA and cash flow guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just a clarification on your share repurchase. I'm a little surprised you weren't a bit more active in the first quarter given the weakness. Though it seems like every year's first quarter you're either not in the market or in just modestly. Can you remind us from a timing standpoint why that might be the case from first quarter or was that just other circumstances that just happened to coincide?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think if you look back actually 2006, 2007 we did zero buyback.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the fourth quarter and it's really just a function of how we manage the blackout periods here and the timing of the filing of Ks, so we end up with only &#x2013; and this year we ended up with only a handful of days when we were actually in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I got it. Are you giving any update on how much you bought back in April or you're not commenting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No I'm not going to comment on that, but what I will say is that we still believe that we will use the majority of our free cash flow in the year to buy back shares.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay very good, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Tom Gallucci with Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning everybody. I guess just maybe following up on that last comment; you listed sort of three uses of cash that are typical things that you talked about internal growth, strategic and accretive acquisitions, and then buybacks. And this year sounds like most of the free cash will go to buybacks, so can you discuss sort of what you see strategically in terms of acquisitions and the competitive landscape or just the amount of opportunities there and internally the types of things that are on the radar screen to the extent it doesn't seems like you're going to use a lot of cash in those places this year, even though they seem to be higher priorities potentially?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well first of all one of the beauties of our business as you well know is that it's a cash producer, not a cash consumer, so as we grow our business, we actually produce more cash, so we end up with a lot of cash. I think the guidance here is 900 to $1 billion, so when we look at where we invest it internally, and again it's systems changes and technology improvements, those are relatively small in relation to the cash flow created, but that will always be our number one priority. As far as acquisitions go, we're just not at liberty to speak to that. We will continue to look at key opportunities and we'll post everybody at the same time when the time is appropriate for that conservation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you just provide us what your hurdle rates are when you're looking at deals in terms of returns?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we really don't disclose that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think last quarter &#x2013; yeah last quarter you also gave some EBITDA per equivalent script expectations for the year. Is there any update to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we're still in the same range, 2.55 to 2.65 for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay great, and then maybe one last one as sort of the selling season has been heating up for '09 starts, can you maybe offer any color on what you're seeing in terms of client interest and sort of hot topics for benefit-design etcetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, I think step therapy has been a huge home run for Express Scripts, and as Jeff talked about, we had our Outcomes Conference a couple weeks ago, and step therapy I believe is one of our sweet spots. We're seeing more and more clients use more and more of our step therapy options, and as you know what that means, is you try a generic first, then you move to a preferred lower cost brand second, and then ultimately have access to the third tier brand, and same thing can work with specialty as well where appropriate step therapies can be utilized to try to manage overall drug trends. That has gained a tremendous amount of momentum over the years.</p>
          <p>The other option that has been looked at is really mail order in a bigger way. As the economy is slowing down and some are worried about the R word, I think that there is a &#x2013; companies have to compete in a global economy, and they're looking at ways to reduce costs, and so I think that mail being priced significantly lower than retail and more convenient and safer is starting to gain some more momentum, so we're going to certainly continue to work on that, and it remains a focus of ours as we look out for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay good. Thanks for the color.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from the line of Lisa Gill with JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. I just had a couple of follow-on questions George, just in your comments around the loss of some of this mail business and it's not being very profitable. Can you just remind us as to what is your most profitable script, what is your least profitable script going from, let's call it mails, generics, retail, branded, etcetera? So first off, if you could do that. And then secondly as we look out in the pipeline that you talked about for 7/1, is there anything specifically that you can name us that's of size that would be a 7/1 start date or can you give us an idea of how big that potential pipeline is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. With respect to the profitability, again the problem as you probably know is when you talk in averages, averages doesn't work &#x2013; those do not work for any single client, but on average what happens is that our generics at mail are our most profitable prescription. It's the biggest cost savings to our clients and lowest costs to our patients, and it's our highest profit item. Second is generics at retail, then brands at mail, then brands at retail. So brands at retail are in clearly third tier where you don't get a rebate is our least profitable product; it's the highest cost item for our plans. So that model stays, works, and it works across the book of business.</p>
          <p>The problem you get into is quite frankly we had some older contracts that were signed up quite a few years ago, that although that process still worked, that alignment still was out there. We really weren't making money when you looked at the overall mix, and so even though it would be more profitable, or less of a loss maybe &#x2013; less profitable to move to a generic in those situations at mail, it was still not a profitable contract. So I think we just &#x2013; we've got a discipline here at Express Scripts, not to, to price our products to make a profit, doesn't do us any good to work all day and night just to post up zeros. So that's important to us.</p>
          <p>As far as the sale season is concerned, I think one of the things we're seeing this year, more than probably most years in the past is an incredible stickiness of clients. We've had a history of having a very high retention rate, both us and our competitors. This year, we're seeing that even stronger; clients sticking with the incumbent. So we go through the process. We bid up against all the competitors, but we're seeing a very high stick rate in the marketplace, but this is very early on. To manage the large employer group and the middle market stuff. Middle market doesn't incur until the third quarter. The large employer group is kind of going now that goes into the second quarter, so it's awfully early to have much of a meaningful conversation around 1/1/09 starts. As far as 1/1/07 starts, mostly based on the knowledge we have today, we've baked that into the guidance we've given you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You mean as far as what you expect to win for 7/1 is already in the guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I meant 7/1; I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's okay, but that's already in the guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and then just one last follow up. If you anticipate that mail claims are going to be coming down from the last time you gave guidance, but your EBITDA per script is remaining flat, should we'd be expecting that there is some impact on EBITDA even though Jeff said there would be no impact on EBITDA? I'm just trying to understand how the math would work?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Jeff. The math all works. If you think about it, the &#x2013; we've given a range for all things, and so we're certainly inside the range. And as we said with the mail scripts that we're losing are low-profit scripts, so they are not impacting the EBITDA prescript overall, just moving around inside the range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll continue to drive the generics throughout the course of the year, so that will help offset the loss of the mail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay perfect. Thanks for your help.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from the line of Ricky Goldwasser with UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. One follow-up to Lisa's question and then another question. What percent of your 7/1 or second half of the year renewals have been already renewed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For 7/1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and for second half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the large employer groups, the managed care organizations, that's pretty much done. There's a few still hanging out there, but not much to speak about. It's very little; it's smaller, the TPA and the mid-market business that needs to be finalized.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So would you say that you're kind of like 80% completed or?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't want to get into that level of detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then are you seeing any impact from shift away from Vytorin to Simva and from any increased level of rebates from Pfizer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well as you know with all of the &#x2013; with all of the press around Vytorin, the doctors have been moving many other patients from Vytorin. We've see a pretty significant decline in Vytorin utilization, and that lands, depending on the potency, at the very low end, you see that going generic; at the by higher ends, we see it going to Lipitor, which remains a very good drug, especially in the 60 and 80 milligram dosages, and some going to Crestor, which is also a very good drug, so it just really depends on what the doctor believes needs to be done for that patient to control the cholesterol levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you think that any of the declines you're seeing and what you expect for the remainder of the year, could that have a positive impact on guidance or is that factored in already?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We factor those things in and those trends as we look at our guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>How about one more question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from John Kreger with William Blair. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi thanks. Jeff, follow-up question for you, as you kind of take an updated look on your expectations for the year, has your thinking changed at all about retail claims growth and also for the SAAS segment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we're not really going to &#x2013; we try not to give guidance on those areas as we said earlier, but overall expectations haven't materially changed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then also, are you seeing any change in the generic pricing environment, your ability to buy generics and the degree to which manufacturers are driving those prices down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Working our supply chain is one of the big focus areas for us and we've got a great team here and we're always working on ways to get better pricing throughout our supply chain. And so it's a focus area for us, we've made some progress and we're going to keep making more progress.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then George, you've talked a lot about the new consumer platform. Are anything along the lines of that &#x2013; anything on track in terms of how you might better influence physician behavior?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely. I believe again, you probably have seen them. All of us that practice in the healthcare industry historically, when you're trying to discuss diabetes, for example, we send out information or we send out messaging that treats everyone the same. The message is very consistent whether it's to a physician or whether it's to the patient.</p>
          <p>The whole idea here is that as you know when you look at really strong consumer product companies, they don't do that. The advertisement in Sports Illustrated is far different than the advertisement in Ladies' Home Journal. I mean it's just, it's a different approach to the marketplace, and we've got to make sure that we address the segments appropriately and get the right messaging to the right people. Some people are driven by cost savings. A lot of people are not; clinical comes first. In some messaging we had to have clinical first, cost second. Others we had to have savings first, clinical second. Other messages just had to be all around just different types of information.</p>
          <p>And I think that when you look at the &#x2013; with 50 million people I think it's incredibly important to improve compliance rates with cholesterol, hypertension and diabetes and asthma. Those drugs states historically have had some fairly low compliance rates, even in the high-dose characteristics, and that's just not acceptable for long-term health of our population, so driving compliance in those disease states is extremely important especially in specialty programs as well. Compliance there is critically important, so again it really is about making sure that the messaging we have when an individual calls in, that we tailor our messaging and our approach to meet the needs that are going to drive the best health outcome for that person. We're putting a lot of money into our systems, our operations to make that happen, and we think that over the next couple of years you'll see some pretty remarkable results of our efforts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great thanks. And then lastly you mentioned that your cash flow from operations was a record. Anything in particular driving the strength there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Strong profitability, strong execution by the treasury team here, but the way our business model works is we have big numbers that can move in or out of the quarter, so there is a little bit of timing that broke our way as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think one of the tributes to Express Scripts is that we are first and foremost focused on profitability and shareholder value, and secondly that only matters if you get cash, so we are very, very focused on ROIC and cash collections and that will always be a hallmark of Express Scripts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Well thank you everyone. Appreciate your time and your attention. We will look forward to seeing you at some upcoming investor conferences and meeting with you in the near future. Thank you all and have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude our conference for today. Thank you for your participation and using AT&amp;T Executive Teleconference. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>