<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1365352" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call - Fixed Income</title>
    <date>2011-01-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>198</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Shawn Ryan, Fixed Income Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Robert L. Shanks, Vice President and Controller</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Michael Seneski, Chief Financial Officer, Ford Credit</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Neil M. Schloss, Vice President and Treasurer</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Douglas Karson</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Eric Selle</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Mark Altherr</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Kirk Ludtke</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Brian Jacoby</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Patrick Nolan</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Edward Okine</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Ford Motor Company fourth quarter Fixed Income conference call. My name is Katina and I'll be your coordinator for today. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. We will facilitate a question-and-answer session towards the end of the presentation. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder this conference is being recorded for replay purposes.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the presentation over to your host for today's call, Mr. Shawn Ryan, Ford Fixed Income Investor Relations Manager. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Katina, and good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to all of you who are joining us either by phone or webcast. On behalf of the entire Ford management team, I would like to thank you for spending time with us this morning.</p>
          <p>With me this morning are Bob Shanks, Ford Vice President and Controller; Michael Seneski, Ford Credit Chief Financial Officer; and Neil Schloss, Ford Vice President and Treasurer. We also have some other members of management who are joining us for the call, including K.R. Kent, Executive Director of Investor Relations; David Brandi, Assistant Treasurer; Brian Shaw, Assistant Treasurer; and Paul Andonian, Director of Global Accounting.</p>
          <p>Before we begin, I would like to review a couple of items. A copy of this morning's earnings release and the slides we will be using today have been posted on Ford Motor Company's Investor and Media websites for your reference. The financial results discussed herein are presented on a preliminary basis. Final data will be included on our Form 10-K.</p>
          <p>Additionally, the financial results presented here are on a GAAP basis and in some cases on a non-GAAP basis. Any non-GAAP financial measures discussed on this call are reconciled to the U.S. GAAP equivalent as part of the appendix to the slide deck.</p>
          <p>Finally, today's presentation includes some forward-looking statements about our expectations for Ford's future performance. Actual results could differ materially from those suggested by our comments here. The most significant factors that could affect future results are summarized at the end of this presentation. These risk factors and other key information are detailed in our SEC filings, including our annual, quarterly, and current reports to the SEC.</p>
          <p>With that, I would like to turn the call over to Ford's Vice President and Controller, Bob Shanks. Bob?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Shawn, and welcome everybody. I'm going to start on slide one and begin by reviewing our key financial summary compared with a year ago. As shown at the top of the slide, fourth quarter vehicle wholesales were 1.4 million units, up 41,000 units, excluding Volvo, from 2009. The increase was explained primarily by higher wholesales in Asia-Pacific-Africa, offset partially by lower wholesales in Europe. The improvement in the fourth quarter brings the full-year increase in vehicle wholesales to 771,000 units.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter revenue was $32.5 billion, which was an increase of $1.6 billion, excluding Volvo, from 2009. This increase was explained primarily by timing differences related to rental repurchase auction sales and favorable net pricing. This brings our full-year net revenue increase to $17 billion.</p>
          <p>Our fourth quarter pre-tax operating profit, excluding special items, was $1.3 billion or $0.30 per share, a decrease of $322 million.</p>
          <p>The Automotive sector reported a profit of $741 million, a decrease of $173 million, and the Financial Services sector also reported a profit of $552 million, a decrease of $149 million. The decrease in Automotive sector results was more than explained by higher structural and commodity costs, both of which were aligned with our guidance, as well as unfavorable volume and mix. This was offset partially by favorable net pricing. The higher structural costs, which include manufacturing, engineering, and advertising, largely supported product launches and the growth of our product plans, investments that we believe we'll provide a strong foundation as we move into 2011.</p>
          <p>In Europe, our results were lower than expected in the fourth quarter, reflecting primarily lower market share driven by our actions to maintain margins. Financial Services decrease was in line with our expectations, reflecting primarily lower volume. Fourth quarter net income attributable to Ford, including unfavorable pre-tax special items of $1 billion, was $190 million or $0.05 per share, a decrease of $696 million. The special items impact primarily reflects a previously disclosed charge for completion of debt conversion offers that reduced outstanding Automotive debt by over $1.9 billion, and we'll discuss this more in detail on upcoming slides.</p>
          <p>For the full year, pre-tax operating profit excluding special items was $8.3 billion or $1.91 per share, which represents a profit of $5.3 billion for the Automotive sector and $3 billion for the Financial Services sector. This is an increase of $8.3 billion compared with a year ago. Full-year net income attributable to Ford, including unfavorable pre-tax special items of about $1.1 billion, was $6.6 billion or $1.66 per share, an increase of $3.8 billion. In addition, we ended the quarter with $20.5 billion of Automotive gross cash, with Automotive gross cash exceeding debt by $1.4 billion, which was an improvement of $10.1 billion compared with a year ago.</p>
          <p>Now let's go on to slide two and we'll talk more about our special items. Our fourth quarter special items were an unfavorable pre-tax amount of $1 billion, which primarily reflects, as I've said, loss on debt conversion offers. As previously disclosed, the completion of conversion offers on our senior convertible debt securities resulted in special item charges associated first with the cash premium, and then secondly a non-cash loss reflecting the difference between the carrying and fair value of our debt. This action reduced outstanding Automotive debt by over $1.9 billion, and we'll discuss our debt reduction actions in total in more details on an upcoming slide.</p>
          <p>Let go now to slide 3 and we'll talk about our Automotive gross cash and operating related cash flow. As you can see here, we ended the year with $20.5 billion in Automotive gross cash, which was down $3.3 billion from the third quarter of 2010, as a result of significant debt reduction actions in the quarter. Automotive operating related cash flow was $1 billion positive in the fourth quarter, bringing the full year to $4.4 billion positive. The fourth quarter reflects the following: an Automotive pre-tax operating profit of over $700 million; capital spending greater than depreciation and amortization of $100 million; adverse working capital changes of $200 million, including the impact of lower payables due to production calendarization in North America, largely associated with our model changeovers for the all-new Explorer and the upcoming Focus; other timing differences of $700 million favorable related primarily to end-of-year collection of vehicle financing receivables; and then finally, payment of $100 million to Ford Credit, reflecting upfront payment of subvention.</p>
          <p>Other major changes in the fourth quarter Automotive gross cash included: receipts from our Financial Services sector of $1.2 billion, which included $1 billion related to a Ford Credit distribution; net debt reduction action during the quarter that included fully repaying our remaining VEBA [Voluntary Employee Beneficiary Association] debt; further payments on both our revolving credit line and our secured term loan; and cash payments associated with the conversion of our senior convertible debt securities. These reductions were offset partially by receipts of low cost government loans mainly for the development of more fuel efficient vehicles. And then finally other cash changes of $400 million, which reflected primarily the release of cash previously restricted as to its use.</p>
          <p>Let's go into slide 4 and I'll summarize the Automotive sector's cash and debt position. As you can see here, we ended the year with Automotive gross cash of $20.5 billion and Automotive debt of $19.1 billion. As a result, our year-end Automotive gross cash now exceeds our debt by $1.4 billion, which is an improvement of $10.1 billion from the year end 2009. As shown in the memo, total liquidity was $27.9 billion, including available credit lines. This liquidity includes $6.9 billion of available credit capacity under our revolving credit lines and about $0.5 billion of other affiliate Automotive credit.</p>
          <p>During the fourth quarter, we reduced our debt by an additional $7.3 billion, building upon the actions that we took in the first nine months of the year. The fourth quarter actions included: first, the full prepayment in cash of the remaining $3.6 billion of debt that we owed the VEBA Retiree Healthcare Trust. This payment now has fully retired all of our VEBA debt trust obligations. Our fourth quarter actions also included completion of conversion offers of our senior convertible debt securities, reducing debt by over $1.9 billion. And then finally, additionally newly announced payments of $2.5 billion that we took in December; these included $1.7 billion of repayment of a revolving credit line, bringing our full year payments to $6.7 billion; and an $800 million payment on our term loan. So for the full year, we reduced our Automotive debt by $14.5 billion, lowering our annualized interest expense going forward by more than $1 billion.</p>
          <p>Now onto slide 5; here, I'd like to summarize the results of our 2010 key planning assumptions and key metrics. As you can see at the top, the full-year industry volume in the U.S. was 11.8 million units; and in Europe, it was 15.3 million units, both of which were slightly above our most recent guidance which you don't actually see on the slide. On the operational metrics, all of our regions improved quality compared with 2009.</p>
          <p>Our full-year Automotive structural costs were $1.2 billion. And although not shown, commodity costs were $1 billion higher, and both of these were aligned with our most recent guidance. The higher Automotive structural cost supported higher volumes and product launches in 2010 as well as growth of our product plans going forward.</p>
          <p>U.S. total market share was 16.4%, and U.S. share of the retail market was 14.1%. Both improved compared with a year ago, reflecting the strength of our new products. Europe market share was 8.4%, which is lower than our most recent guidance of about 8.6%, explained in part by our decision to reduce participation selectively in low margin business.</p>
          <p>Automotive operating related cash flow was $4.4 billion positive, significantly better than our expectations. And our capital expenditures came to $3.9 billion, which was in line with our most recent guidance of about $4 billion, reflecting continued efficiencies from our global product development processes. I want to underscore that are product plans remain unchanged. Overall for full year 2010, we delivered solid profit, with each of our business units profitable and positive Automotive operating related cash flow.</p>
          <p>And here on slide six, what I'd like to do is turn to 2011 and talk about our outlook, including our planning assumptions and key metrics. We expect full-year industry volume next year to be in the range of 13 million to 13.5 million units in the U.S. and 14.5 million to 15.5 million units in Europe. On the operational metrics for quality, we expect to build on the gains made last year and achieve further improvements. In terms of market share for the full year in the U.S. and Europe, we expect to achieve equal to improved shares compared with 2010.</p>
          <p>On the financial metrics compared with 2010, we expect our total company pre-tax operating profit to improve. We expect full-year Automotive structural costs to be higher as we increase production to meet demand and make further investments in new products, new technology, and growth. We expect our commodity costs to be higher this year, reflecting the increased global demand. A new element of our guidance is operating margin, which we expect to be equal to or improved to our 2010 results. We expect our Automotive operating related cash flow to improve. And finally, we expect absolute capital expenditures to be in the range of $5 billion to $5.5 billion, as we continue to invest in our product and growth plans around the world.</p>
          <p>In summary, we plan to deliver even better results in 2011 than 2010, with continued improvement in pre-tax operating profit and positive Automotive operating related cash flow. We expect this improvement to be driven primarily by our growing product strength, a gradually strengthening global economy, and an unrelenting focus on improving the competitiveness of our company. For the full year, we expect each of our Automotive segments to be profitable.</p>
          <p>And with that, I think I'm going to turn it over to Mike Seneski.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bob. If you move to slide seven, it shows Ford Credit's operating results and key metrics for the fourth quarter of 2010. As shown in the left box, our fourth quarter pre-tax profit was $572 million compared with the pre-tax profit of 714 million in the fourth quarter of 2009. You can see in the right box our December 31st on-balance sheet receivables were $81 billion, about $12 billion lower than the same period last year. This decline reflected primarily the discontinuation of Jaguar, Land Rover, Mazda, and Volvo financing and lower industry volumes in recent years. Although not shown, our December 31st on-balance sheet receivables were $2 billion lower than at the end of the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Charge-offs for on-balance sheet receivables in the fourth quarter were $101 million, and the worldwide loss receivables ratio was a very low 47 basis points, down 51 basis points from the same period last year. I'll speak more on this in a few minutes.</p>
          <p>At December 31st, the allowance for credit losses or reserve for on-balance receivables was about $900 million or 102 basis points of receivables. The reserve was about $100 million lower than the end of the third quarter and $600 million lower from a year ago.</p>
          <p>We paid total distributions of $2.5 billion during 2010, including $1 billion paid in the fourth quarter, up from $1.5 billion paid in 2009. We expect to pay distributions of about $2 billion in 2011, and we'll continue to assess future distributions based on our available liquidity and managed leverage objectives.</p>
          <p>Our managed leverage was 6.7-to-1 at December 31, 2010 compared to 7.3-to-1 at December 31, 2009. At the end of the fourth quarter, our equity was about $10 billion.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide eight, we provide an explanation of the change in Ford Credit's fourth quarter results compared with 2009 by causal factor. As you can see, volume was $100 million unfavorable, reflecting declining receivables, as discussed on the prior slide. Financing margin was $100 million favorable, reflecting primarily favorable borrowing cost rates. The decline in the provision for credit losses of $100 million reflects primarily improved charge-off performance. Lease residual performance decreased by $100 million, reflecting primarily the non-recurrence of lower lease depreciation expense related to lower gains as fewer leases terminated and the vehicles were sold.</p>
          <p>As shown in the memo, the $200 million decrease compared with the third quarter of 2010 is primarily explained by higher depreciation expense for leased vehicles related to lower auction values consistent with seasonality and the non-recurrence of net gains related to market valuation adjustments to derivatives.</p>
          <p>Slide nine provides an explanation of the change in Ford Credit full-year results compared with 2009 by causal factor. Volume was $400 million unfavorable, primarily reflecting declining receivables, as previously discussed. The decline in the provision for credit losses of $1.2 billion primarily reflects improved charge-off performance and credit loss reserve reductions. Lease residual performance increased by $600 million, reflecting primarily lower lease depreciation expense for leased vehicles due to higher auction values. Other was $500 million unfavorable, primarily reflecting the non-recurrence of net gains related to unhedged currency exposure from cross-border intercompany lending.</p>
          <p>For full year 2011, we expect Ford Credit to be solidly profitable but at a lower level, reflecting primarily the non-recurrence of lower lease depreciation expense and non-reoccurrence of credit loss reserve reductions of the same magnitude as 2010, as the lease depreciation expense will have about 170,000 fewer leases terminate in 2011 compared with 2010, which includes about 80,000 fewer leases terminating that were impaired in 2008. This will result in fewer vehicles being sold at a gain.</p>
          <p>Likewise for the credit loss reserve, we expect that to begin to level off in 2011 at about 85 to 95 basis points of receivables, down from 1.02% of receivables at year-end 2010 and 1.61% of receivables at year-end 2009, resulting in less reserve release. We estimate the profit impact of these two items to reduce profits by about $1.2 billion in 2011 compared with 2010.</p>
          <p>Slide 10 shows our quarterly trends of charge-offs and loss-to-receivables ratios for our on-balance sheet portfolio. The top box shows loss-to-receivable ratios for our worldwide portfolio and the U.S. Ford and Lincoln retail and lease business. Both worldwide and U.S. Ford and Lincoln loss-to-receivable ratios in the fourth quarter are down from the same period a year ago, reflecting primarily lower repossessions and lower severity in the U.S., as well as lower losses in Europe. Both worldwide and U.S. Ford and Lincoln loss-to-receivable ratios in the fourth quarter increased from the third quarter consistent with seasonality, reflecting primarily lower recoveries and higher severity offset partially by lower repossessions. Charge-offs in the fourth quarter were $101 million, down $137 million from the same period a year ago, and up $6 million from the third quarter of 2010, reflecting the same factors I just mentioned.</p>
          <p>Slide 11 shows the primary drivers of credit losses in the U.S. Ford and Lincoln retail and lease business. Repossessions in the fourth quarter were 14,000 units, down 9,000 units from the fourth quarter of 2009 and down 2,000 units from the third quarter of 2010. Severity of $6,900 in the fourth quarter was $800 lower than the same period a year ago, reflecting improvements in auction values in the used vehicle market offset partially by a higher mix of 72-month contracts. Fourth quarter severity was $300 higher than the third quarter of 2010. Over-60-day delinquencies totaled 15 basis points in the fourth quarter, down five basis points from the same period a year ago and down one basis point from the third quarter. Bankruptcy filings totaled 10,000 in the fourth quarter, down 1,000 from the same period ago and about the same as the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Slide 12 shows longer term trends of key metrics for our on-balance sheet portfolio over the past nine years. We have mentioned several times in the past about the higher credit quality portfolio we have today. The top left box shows the average placement FICO score for the U.S. retail and lease portfolio, which is a substantial portion of the total portfolio. The average FICO in 2010 remains consistent with our efforts to maintain credit quality.</p>
          <p>The top right box shows worldwide on-balance sheet loss-to-receivables ratios. The loss-to-receivable ratio is down from 2009 and back to 2005 to 2007 levels. The improvement in loss performance compared with the early part of the decade reflects the increase in the quality of our portfolio.</p>
          <p>The bottom box shows on-balance sheet charge-offs and the reserve. Both charge-offs and the reserve are lower than a year ago. At year end 2010, the reserve was about two times the 2010 charge-offs. Charge-offs in 2010 are down from 2009, primarily reflecting lower repossessions and lower severity in North America and lower losses in Europe.</p>
          <p>Slide 13 shows the longer term trends of our Ford and Lincoln U.S. retail and lease portfolio through several key metrics for the past nine years. Full-year 2010 repossessions and repossession ratio are down from 2009. Loss severity of $6,900 was $1,400 lower than 2009. Over-60-day delinquencies totaled 15 basis points in 2010, down nine basis points from a year ago. And bankruptcy filings totaled 42,000 down 5,000 compared with 2009.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 14, this shows the lease residual performance for our Ford and Lincoln U.S. brands. Lease return volumes in the fourth quarter at 30,000 units were down 6,000 from the same period last year, reflecting primarily a lower return rate and fewer terminations. Lease returns on 24-month contracts were only 1,000 units, down substantially from prior quarters, reflecting recent lease placement trends. The fourth quarter lease return rate was 61%, down eight percentage points compared with the same period last year. This return rate was equal to the third quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>In the fourth quarter, auction values for 24-month leased vehicles at constant mix were down about $200 a unit from the same period a year ago. Auction values for 36-month vehicles were up about $450 a unit from the same period last year. Compared with the prior quarter, auction values were down for both 24 and 36 month lease vehicles, consistent with seasonality.</p>
          <p>Our worldwide net investment in operating leases was $10 billion at the end of the fourth quarter, down $4.6 billion from the same period last year. This decline reflected primarily the discontinuation of Jaguar, Land Rover, Mazda and Volvo financing and lower lease placements for Ford and Lincoln brand vehicles in recent years.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn it over to Neil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mike. And moving to slide 15, we delivered our 2010 funding plan, completing $25 billion of funding for the year, including $3 billion in the fourth quarter. We completed $17 billion of funding in the public markets and $8 billion in the private securitizations globally. We extended the tenor of our funding by completing a five-year wholesale securitization transaction and selling subordinated notes. We also issued seven and ten-year unsecured term debt. Our borrowing spreads have narrowed, reflecting improved credit profiles of Ford and Ford Credit, strong investor demand, and support of fixed income markets.</p>
          <p>Our funding strategy remains focused on diversification, and we plan on continuing to access a variety of markets and asset-backed channels. Our liquidity remain strong, and we will continue to maintain cash balances and committed capacity to ensure liquidity adequately meets our business and funding requirements.</p>
          <p>Slide 16 shows the trends in our funding of our managed receivables. At the end of the fourth quarter, managed receivables were $83 billion. Jaguar, Land Rover, Mazda, and Volvo receivables made up approximately 4% of total managed receivables. We ended the year with $15 billion in cash, including about $4 billion to support on-balance sheet securitizations. Securitized funding was 52% of managed receivables at the end of 2010.</p>
          <p>We are projecting 2011 year-end managed receivables in the range of $80 billion to $85 billion, and securitized funding to represent about 53% to 57% of total managed receivables. It is our expectation that this ratio will fall over time, reflecting our ability to source term unsecured funding on increasingly favorable terms.</p>
          <p>Slide 17 shows our 2011 term funding plan for Ford Credit, which does not include our short-term funding programs or asset sales for our on-balance sheet asset-backed commercial paper programs. As I mentioned earlier, we completed $25 billion of term funding in 2010. About $17 billion of this funding was public, including unsecured debt issuance of about $6 billion in the U.S, Canada, and Europe, and securitization funding of about $11 billion across the same regions and all asset classes. In addition, we completed about $8 billion of funding through our private securitization channels globally.</p>
          <p>For 2011, our public term funding plans are projected to be in the range of $19 billion to $24 billion, consisting of $12 billion to $16 billion of public securitizations and $6 billion to $8 billion of unsecured debt. In addition to the public issuance, we are projecting between $4 billion and $8 billion of funding from our private sources.</p>
          <p>Slide 18 details our liquidity programs and utilization. The top box shows Ford Credit's committed capacity, which includes unsecured credit facilities, FCAR asset-backed commercial paper lines, and other asset-backed bank capacity. At year end, we ended with $48.9 billion of committed capacity in cash. After excluding securitization cash and adjusting for available assets, liquidity was $38.4 billion, of which $15.8 billion was utilized, leaving about $23 billion available for use, given our present level of eligible receivables. This equates a 27% of our year-end managed receivables. Available liquidity is $2 billion lower than the third quarter, more than explained by our unsecured debt repurchases and calls.</p>
          <p>At year end, our cash not related to securitization totaled $10.4 billion. Committed capacity at year end was $34.3 billion, $1 billion lower than the third quarter. In 2011, about $22 billion or 64% of our private capacity is up for renewal. Our renewal strategy will continue to protect our global funding needs, optimize capacity utilization, and maintain sufficient liquidity. We ended the year with about $6.3 billion of excess committed capacity, providing a future funding source for assets along with flexibility to shift capacity among markets and asset classes where most needed.</p>
          <p>So in summary on slide 19, 2010 was an extraordinary year, with our results exceeding our expectations. For the full year, Ford had a pre-tax operating profit excluding special items of $8.3 billion, an $8.3 billion improvement from a year ago. Full-year net income attributable to Ford was $6.6 billion. At year end, Automotive cash was $20.5 billion, and we have liquidity of $27.9 billion.</p>
          <p>In 2010, we took significant steps to strengthen our balance sheet, reducing Automotive debt by $14.5 billion and ended the year with cash net of debt of $1.4 billion. Ford Credit's full-year pre-tax profit was $3.1 billion, a $1.1 billion improvement from a year ago. Full-year net income was $2 billion. Ford Credit paid a $2.5 billion net distribution during 2010. In 2010, Ford Credit completed $25 billion of term funding and ended the fourth quarter with liquidity available for use of about $23 billion.</p>
          <p>Importantly, the strength of our business positions us well to further improve our balance sheet as we continue to progress to strong investment grade ratings at both Ford and Ford Credit.</p>
          <p>I'll turn it back now to Shawn to begin the Q&amp;A session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Neil. Ladies and gentlemen, we are going to start the question-and-answer session now. Katina, can we please have the first question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from the line Doug Karson, representing Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Thanks for taking my question. My question actually relates to slide 15 for the Ford North America. I wasn't able to get my question in on the equity call. And I'm having trouble footing some of the numbers. It looks like wholesale sales on the slide before it were about the same. I'm wondering. Where is the revenue increase coming from? It looks like revenue is up over $1.5 billion, and I just see some modest improvements in pricing and mix. I'm missing about $1 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. Which slide you are referring to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>He's referring to 15 from the morning deck.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>From the morning deck, I apologize. Slide 14 goes over the year-over-year changes in Q4 for North America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we talked about there is &#x2013; you said you were listening in on the morning call. Is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The earlier call; do you remember the discussion around the rental repurchase units and the timing differences associated with that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So there is a good portion of that increase that is related to that timing difference, which, as Lewis explained, is a bit seasonal, and it just simply reflects the revenue that we achieved from the risk rental units that come back to us and then we sell them at auctions. The wholesales would have been picked up at the time that we sold the units some months ago. So that's probably the key difference in terms of what you're not picking up. And then in the <mark type="inaudible" />, we had favorable net pricing, which we talked about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right, good. And then just turning the Ford Credit, you talked about the balance sheet before, and the leverage looks like it's still running around eight turns. As Ford grows over time, do you guys have a target of where you want to take that leverage? And it also seems like you're helping delever the parent company through dividends up through Ford Credit. Is that going to be something like a nine or ten number down the road, or are we comfortable with it around eight?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Doug, as you guys know, we always plan our managed leverage by looking at the prevailing market condition and the risk characteristics of our business. When we look at our portfolio, we would say the inherent appropriate leverage would be in the range of 10-to-1 to 11-to-1 versus our 6.7-to-1. We expect to return to that 10-to-1 to 11-to-1 over time. Obviously, we'd never do anything quickly. We do it as market conditions, as it looks like we should do it. And we do have an agreement with the Motor Company that we wouldn't go above 11.5-to-1. The 8-to-1 that you recognize I think is probably more of an on-balance sheet. We look more to managed leverage level, which is 6.7-to-1 right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then final question, and you may have gone over this, I may have missed it. Could you just update us? Is there a target for dividends from Ford Credit up to Ford for 2011; i.e., $1 billion, $2 billion, $3 billion type of thing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, for next year it's $2 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>$2 billion, okay. Great, that's it for me. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This year is $2 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>2011 is $2 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>$2 billion, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Eric Selle, representing J.P. Morgan. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. Looking on the balance sheet &#x2013; and I know you took a lot of heat on the first call, but we appreciate this on the credit side. And I agree with Alan that what you guys have done has been phenomenal. I don't think I've seen a credit take down almost half of its debt in one year, so thank you for doing that.</p>
          <p>But looking at the balance sheet, are you guys considering &#x2013; this is a multi-question, but are you guys considering equitizing the preferreds? What are your plans for the rest of the bank debt? Do you have a minimum cash level? And then talking to rating agencies, what is the trajectory given the fact that your leverage right now is the same as the high-grade average?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Eric, this is Neil. I think from the standpoint of your questions, I don't think we will provide any guidance or necessarily any of those specifically. I think the importance of what we were able to accomplish with the $14.5 billion of debt reduction in 2010 really sets the stage for further actions that we need to continue to take. But as Lewis mentioned on this morning's call, our first priority is product. Our second is growth. Our third is the balance sheet. And we're continuing as we generate positive cash flow in the business, plus the distributions we get from the credit company, will really go to help continue the progress of reducing debt on the Automotive book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great, that's great. And then looking at slide 15, I know we've beaten this one up, but you guys gave some detail on the year-over-year cost changes between structural, commodities, and warranty. I was wondering if you could give us similar granularity of the sequential $1 billion change. What buckets are the big ones there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The majority of it is &#x2013; this is Bob. The majority of it is actually in structural costs, and it's around our product launches. We have some added material costs. We have some increased manufacturing. And we've got some increases in our advertising expense, and it's all related to our product launches. As you know, we've got the Explorer that we just literally have started shipping to our dealers. We've got the F-Series, which right across the board got brand new powertrains, and just recently started shipping that. And then, of course, we're coming very, very close to the Job One for the brand-new global Focus. And so that's not just an impact here in North America but around the world, particularly in Europe. And so we're incurring costs for that because it's very early in the first quarter in terms of the actual production launch. So that's really what's going on in terms of driving the quarterly sequential cost increase that you're looking at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then would you characterize this as a sustained issue or just a hiccup due to a massive growth in the launches? If I look at from a platform, the Focus versus the Fiesta is obviously bigger. The Explorer has got to be a big cost in Chicago. And then I think the medium-duty launch was incorporated into the F-150, which was the year before. Is this just a jump due to the massive amount of volume you guys are releasing onto the market? Is that how we should compartmentalize it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think you should &#x2013; let's step back for a second. First of all, we don't want to get confused between looking at what's happening to our costs year over year versus what's happening from the fourth quarter to the third. And if you're looking at slide 15, I think you referenced that.</p>
          <p>If you look at what's happening year over year, you can see that we're up about $0.5 billion. And if you look in the dialog box that we've provided, $1 billion (sic) [$100 million] of that is the commodities, which is going to be whatever it's going to be. About a tenth of that is warranty and other, and that's where you're going to find the field service action that we talked about, which, clearly, is the going cost. And then if you look at the structural cost, it's $310 million, and that's again in manufacturing, engineering, and advertising. And it's related to the concentration of very large launches that we've got both in the first quarter of next year &#x2013; or this year, rather, and the fourth quarter of last year. So I think if you break it down like that, you get a different point of view about what's happening to the business.</p>
          <p>If you look sequentially, which is below that bar in the memo line, you can see the $1 billion. The majority of that is seasonal. Historically, we will see an increase in the fourth quarter relative to the third. And again, if you go back and look at history, it's because we generally are recovering in terms of volume from the lower volumes we traditionally have in the third quarter, where we have lot of plant shutdowns, and so the plants are all up and running in the fourth. And again, we traditionally have a concentration of product launches in the fourth quarter and then sometimes early the following year, which gives us a lot of costs, relatively speaking, in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>So on a go-forward basis, we are guiding that our costs will continue to increase in 2011 versus 2010, and that's related again to the fact that we're in growth mode. And so we're expanding around the world in terms of our volume. We're expanding into technologies. We're expanding in terms of our lineup and new products. So this is part of us transitioning from our fixing the fundamentals, which is what we've been focusing on the past several years, to growing this business and a growing industry around the world. And then again, remember, as we're talking about the cost, we're going to absorb all of that, grow the business, and generate a bottom line operating margin that's going to be at minimum equal to what we did in 2010; and if we work really hard, improved.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I really appreciate that color. It definitely helps us look at it. And then if I could sneak one final one in, I think Lewis said on the last call that the pension will be fully funded in the next couple of years. Is there any potential they accelerate that? You are in talks this year. We've done an OPEB buyout in the past. Is there any potential for a pension buyout in exchange for 401(k) benefits for the Tier 1 hourly workers in the upcoming talks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Eric, I think we're going to stick with what we said this morning and not get into specifics around what we could do as part of the union contract on any of the features to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sounds good, I appreciate you guys' time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Eric, before you go on, my guys caught me misspeaking. When I was talking about the year-over-year increase and I mentioned commodities, the $0.5 billion in total, I said $1 billion. Apparently, I meant to say $100 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I figured as much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I was thinking about the full year, sorry about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Not a problem, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mark Altherr, representing Credit Suisse. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking the call; a couple of Ford Motor Credit questions. Expenses, it looks like absent the special items that you had this year, 2011 you're suggesting is going to look a lot like 2010. Expenses are relatively flat, so they're going up as a percentage of overall costs. Does that tend to be a sticky line, or are you keeping things in place for growth farther out? How should we look at that? Then I've got another question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, obviously we need to be extraordinarily efficient in the way we run the business. We ended the year at $83 billion of receivables. And when you look forward, we say we're going to be in the range of $80 billion to $85 billion. And so it's our intent to ensure that we have an op cost ratio that is one of the most competitive in the industry. We're going to keep working on it, and it's going to fluctuate with the size of the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and I guess another one. The rising FICO scores, which are very nice, but does that tend to drive down the percentage of your U.S. financing share? Because I noticed that if you go back to the beginning of the decade, Europe retail and wholesale was about the same as it is now. Wholesale U.S. is about the same as it is now, but retail is quite a bit under. Is that a function of interest cost competitiveness or FICO, or is that something that can grow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When we look at FICO, remember, FICO is just one component of how we look at customers. There are a number of things that go into our credit models. And truthfully, the change in FICO over the past few years is noise.</p>
          <p>As it relates to our shares, when you look at our actual retail, share of retail and lease with Ford, U.S. Ford and Lincoln, we've actually hovered around 45% to 50% for a good part of the decade. Obviously, there are things that come into play during Cash for Clunkers and others like that that influence it. But we've been very consistent. We have aligned objectives with the Motor Company in how we go to market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But your highlights say you've got &#x2013; it's 32%. I guess I'm comparing highlights 32% to beginning of the decade 39% to 51%. That would seem to be apples to apples.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's when you &#x2013; 32% is a total of all of Ford's volume. When you only look at non-commercial, so basically retail and lease, it's closer to the 45% &#x2013; 50%-ish.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. But whatever number I'm quoting, is that number going to go -let me follow up offline. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Kirk Ludtke, representing CRT Capital. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everyone. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, go ahead, Kirk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. You mentioned that the credit provisions and the lease residual gains will be a $1.2 billion headwind between 2010 and '11. And I think I heard you mention that there were 170,000 vehicles that came off lease in 2010. Another 80,000 will come off lease in 2011. Are those all vehicles that were impaired?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, let me clarify it that for you, Kirk. We're actually going from about 400,000 terminations in 2010 to about 230,000 terminations in 2011, so it's about 170,000 lower terminations. Of those 170,000, about 80,000 of them are impaired leases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's very helpful. And could you give us those numbers for prior years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure that really matters. They would be significantly higher in number. We've come from a $14.6 billion lease portfolio down to a $10 billion lease portfolio at 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So if the number will be down, let's say you're breakeven on the other 90,000. And it's really just the 80,000, the change that's driving the lease residual gains. What would you use as an average gain per vehicle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we've said before, the amount of lower profit related to the impaired vehicles, the reduction in impaired vehicle terminations is about $400 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Year over year, that will be the change year over year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Year over year, yes, that's the change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay that's very helpful. So the other, the credit provisions is the other $800 million that gets you to $1.2 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's a combination of everything going on in lease plus the combination of what's going on with the credit loss reserves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So when you look at the credit loss reserve, we've gone from $1.5 billion and 1.61% of receivables down to $0.9 billion and 1.02%. And now we're saying we're going to be 85 to 95 basis points at roughly equivalent receivable level, in the $80 billion to $85 billion range. So it's going to be a heck of a lot lower reserve releases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes, that's helpful. Do you have &#x2013; could you give us any directional color on the other things that drive your earnings like volume, and I guess volume will probably be pretty flat, right? And I think margins...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously, Kirk, there are a lot of things that go into your models, and you know we're a portfolio business. And volume is going to be based on the receivable level and borrowing costs and operating costs, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I noticed that subvention payments are pretty much down to zero in the fourth quarter. Are we done with those?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is just a little bit left of the pay-as-you-go subvention, and then everything else we get is an upfront payment from the Motor Company going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Brian Jacoby, representing Goldman Sachs. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. How are you doing? I just want to say it was a very good year, and the debt reduction side, continue it. The question I have is mainly on cap structure; it's something that has been touched earlier. But on DOE loans, can you give us an idea just a little bit about how we should think about that over the &#x2013; sequentially? Quarter to quarter, it sounds like you could do another what, $1.5 billion this year based on how the program works. And then I had one other question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think if you think about DOE in general, as you recall, we went and we had a $5.9 billion program. The balance to date is about $2.5 billion is what we've drawn, and we spend it and then we get reimbursed as part of what has turned out to be a really good partnership with the DOE to really invest in the advanced technology and the fuel efficient products that we're coming out with. That will continue through almost the end of 2012. And so you can almost &#x2013; if you straight-lined it, you'd probably be pretty close from a standpoint of what the draw rate would be. And then in the beginning and at the end of '12, we start to pay it down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then the other questions are just around how you think about pension and actual debt reduction on the balance sheet. Obviously, contributing to the pension is good too for us debt guys. But from what you said on the earnings call, your contributions are going to be similar this year versus last year. So from what you're saying about capital structure, it sounds like debt reduction on-balance sheet, whether it be bank debt presumably, would probably a key priority versus pension. Is that the way to think about it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think for 2011, that's a fair statement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then last question. You guys typically give &#x2013; or better yet, the guys on the equity call tend to ask you this and they didn't this time around. But other Automotive, you usually provide some type of guidance to that segment there. And in the past, I think you guys were targeting $350 million annually roughly. That number moves all over the place, a lot of stuff in there, I realize. Is there any type of directional number you can give us for 2011, how to think about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Bob. I think what we did mention in the earlier call is that given the debt reduction actions that we've taken, we would expect from those actions an annualized savings of about $1 billion. I think that's the only guidance that we're providing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So annualized savings of $1 billion, I mean...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From the interest expense levels associated with that level of debt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay. So you're not really guiding to a total number, like a net number for that anymore, it sounds like?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The only caution I would give is some of that savings was actually achieved in 2010 because the debt reductions were throughout the year. So the savings or the reduction is $1 billion, not necessarily the year over year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, right. Okay, again congratulations. Despite the equity move today, you paid down $14.5 billion in debt and earned over $6 billion. That's impressive, so congrats.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Rod Lache, representing Deutsche Bank. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. It's Pat Nolan on for Rod Lache. Most of my questions have been answered, but I have two follow-up questions. First on Ford Motor Credit, I know the receivables base will be relatively steady as we go into 2011. But when you look in the return on those assets and what kind of finance revenue it would generate, is there any type of changes in that percentage we should be thinking at based on the changes in the portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously, borrowing costs are going to be &#x2013; I can't really tell what's going to happen in the market as well as you can. But borrowing costs will obviously impact our margin going forward as well as how we price new placements, which is also going to be impacted by what's going on in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And there are no changes based on just some of the higher yielding stuff that came out in 2010, some more of the legacy stuff, the interest rates, and some of the other stuff in the portfolio that might be lower?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, you've got a portfolio of a lot of four, five, six-year assets. It's not going to move as greatly as that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I would almost add that the way we hedge interest rate risk is we tend to match the runoff of the assets with the runoff of the debt. So if we have high yielding assets coming off, we tend to have high yielding debt come off with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's helpful. And just the discussion about the sequential walk in the step-up in structural costs in the Motor Company was helpful. Can you just help us think about based on the launches in the Q1, I know some of them will carry over. But does that cost start to tail off in Q1, or is it something that's going to continue into the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not providing more specific guidance on our costs next year than what we did, which is we do expect our overall costs to increase. And we also expect &#x2013; and as part of that, our commodity costs to go up as well, driven by the growing global economy, so that's all that we're prepared to say at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Katina, I think we have time for one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your final question comes from the line of Edward Okine, representing Basso. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello yes, actually most of my questions have been answered. But I guess on the preferred, I was just wondering. How do you look at those? <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Edward, we're having trouble hearing you, but I think I can hear. How do we think about the preferred? Is that the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct, that's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think it's on our balance sheet. Obviously, it's debt on how we think about it as we go through our capital strategy and reduction of debt. It becomes a tool that we've got. And we'll continue to evaluate all of our debt as we go forward in recognizing that our strategy is to improve our balance sheet, and that's part of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but any intention of trying to equitize it at all, just moving it into equity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not going to talk specifics about any plans we might have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that concludes today's call. Thank you for joining us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation. You may now disconnect. Good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>