<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1207780" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-01-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>198</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Alan Mulally, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Lewis W. K. Booth, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">John Murphy</participant>
      <participant id="5">Alan Mulally</participant>
      <participant id="6">Rod Lache</participant>
      <participant id="7">Lewis Booth</participant>
      <participant id="8">Chris Ceraso</participant>
      <participant id="9">Christ Ceraso</participant>
      <participant id="10">Pat Archambault</participant>
      <participant id="11">Neil Schloss</participant>
      <participant id="12">Himanshu Patel</participant>
      <participant id="13">K.R. Kent</participant>
      <participant id="14">Itay Michaeli</participant>
      <participant id="15">Lewis  Booth</participant>
      <participant id="16">Itay Michaela</participant>
      <participant id="17">Bryce Hoffman</participant>
      <participant id="18">Jeff Bennett</participant>
      <participant id="19">Tom Krisher</participant>
      <participant id="20">Amy Wilson</participant>
      <participant id="21">Robert Schoenberger</participant>
      <participant id="22">David Bailey</participant>
      <participant id="23">David Kiley</participant>
      <participant id="24">Joann Muller</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Ford Motor Company fourth quarter earnings conference call. My name is Catena and I'll be your coordinator for today. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. We will conduct a question-and-answer session towards the end of this presentation. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. As a reminder, this conference is being recorded for replay purposes.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the presentation over to your host for today's call, <mark type="inaudible" />, Director of Investor Relations. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Catena and good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to all of you who are joining us by phone or webcast. On behalf of the entire Ford management team, I'd like to thank you for spending time with us this morning. With me this morning are Alan Mulally, President and CEO and Lewis Booth, Chief Financial Officer. Also in the room are Peter Daniel, Senior Vice President and Controller; Neil Schloss, Vice President and Treasurer; Mark Kosman, Director of Accounting and K.R. Kent, Ford Credit's CFO.</p>
          <p>Before we begin, I'd like to review a couple of quick items. Copies of this morning's earning release and slides that we will be using today have been posted on Ford's Investor and Media websites for your reference. The financial results discussed herein are presented on a preliminary basis; final data will be included in our 2008 Form 10-K report. Additionally, the financial results presented here are on a GAAP basis and in some cases on a non-GAAP basis. The non-GAAP financial measures discussed in this call are reconciled to their GAAP equivalents as part of the Appendix to the slide deck.</p>
          <p>Finally, today's presentation includes some forward-looking statements about our expectations for Ford's future performance. Actual results could differ materially from those suggested by our comments here. Additional information about the factors that could affect future results are summarized at the end of the presentation. These risk factors are also detailed in our SEC filings, including our annual, quarterly, and current reports to the SEC.</p>
          <p>With that, I'd like to turn the presentation over to Alan Mulally, Ford's President and CEO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, <mark type="inaudible" />, and good morning, everyone. As you all well know, in the fourth quarter, we faced nearly unprecedented challenges across our global markets. Demand weakened dramatically not only in North America but also in Europe and Asia. The worldwide economic slowdown driven by tight credit markets and weak consumer confidence has shaken the foundation of even the strongest companies in the automotive sector and other industries.</p>
          <p>Clearly, at Ford, the severe economic challenges had a significant impact on our fourth quarter results, both in terms of our operating losses and our cash flow. In response to these challenges, we took decisive actions and we saw many positive developments that made us confident that we're on the right plan, are taking the right actions to survive this global downturn and emerge as a lean, globally integrated company, poised for long term, profitable growth.</p>
          <p>In these challenging times, we remain completely focused on our four point plan; aggressively restructure the business; accelerate development of vehicles people want and need; finance our plan and improve our balance sheet; and work together as one team, leveraging our global assets. Customers are starting to see that Ford really is different, not only because we continue to believe we are well positioned to survive this global downturn, but also because of the growing fuel efficiency, quality, safety and smart technology we are engineering into every new vehicle.</p>
          <p>I will start off today by providing you with an overview of last quarter's results, and our recent products and business highlights. Lewis Booth will take us through the details. I will then summarize our plan going forward, including our 2009 outlook. This will include an update of the actions that we are announcing during the third quarter call to reduce our cost structure and improve cash. We are also pursuing additional actions to further restructure our business and we will be providing details of these at a later time.</p>
          <p>Before I review last quarter's results, this morning we announced that we have provided notice to our banks to fully draw the 10.1 billion of available funds under our secured credit lines. We took this action because of our growing concerns about the instability of the capital markets, with the uncertain state of the global economy.</p>
          <p>Lewis will cover this item in more detail during his portion of the call. Also today, we announced that the United Auto Workers union has agreed to end the "jobs bank" at Ford, known as the Job Security Program. The company and the union are presently working out the details of the implementation.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide three to review the key financial results of the quarter. As shown at the top of the slide, vehicle wholesales last quarter were over 1.1 million units, down 505,000 from the same period in 2007. Ford's fourth quarter revenue is 29.2 billion, a 16.3 billion decrease from a year ago. The decrease is primarily explained by lower volume, the sale of Jaguar Land Rover and exchange translation.</p>
          <p>Ford's fourth quarter pre-tax operating loss from continuing operations excluding special items is almost 3.7 billion, over a 3 billion decline from a year ago. The decline included about 2.4 billion at automotive and 653 million at Financial Services. Our fourth quarter net loss was almost 5.9 billion, including about 1.4 billion of pre-tax special charges. We ended the quarter with 13.4 billion of cash. This was down about 21 billion from year-end 2007 levels, with almost 16 billion of that decline occurring during the first nine months of the year.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide four. Results at all operations were worse than last year, because of the sharply lower industry volumes and our actions to reduce dealer stocks to keep them aligned with near-term demand expectations. Fourth quarter U.S. industry volumes were down 35% from a year ago and our other major markets were down 12% to 27%. Cost reductions provided a significant offset to these declines.</p>
          <p>We reduced our automotive costs by over 1.4 billion compared to 2007, with 1.2 billion of that improvement occurring in North America. Since 2005, Ford North America has reduced automotive costs by more than 5 billion, exceeding our targets. Ford North America incurred an operating loss of 1.9 billion, about 400 million decline from a year ago. The decline was primarily explained by lower industry volume and lower dealer stocks, partially offset by significant cost reductions.</p>
          <p>Ford South America earned an operating profit of 105 million, a 313 million decrease from a year ago. The decrease primarily reflects lower industry volume and higher material costs, partly offset by favorable net pricing. Ford Europe incurred a 330 million operating loss, a 553 million decline from a year ago. The decline was more than explained by lower industry volume and favorable exchange and lower dealer stocks, partly offset by cost reductions.</p>
          <p>Volvo incurred a 736 million operating loss compared with a breakeven a year ago. This decline primary reflects lower industry volume, unfavorable net pricing and unfavorable exchange. Ford Asia Pacific and Africa incurred an operating loss of 208 million, a 218 million decline from a year ago. The decline primarily reflects lower industry volume again, unfavorable exchange and adverse product mix.</p>
          <p>We earned 79 million from our investment in Mazda and changes in our financial reporting for Mazda will be discussed on the later slide.</p>
          <p>Financial Services incurred an operating loss of 384 million, a 653 million decline from a year ago. The decline was primarily explained by higher provision for credit losses, market valuation adjustments to derivatives and lower volumes.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide five. We are continuing our rollout of new products our customers want and value. The new 2009 Ford F-50 full-size pickup truck was launched in North America and already has earned several prestigious awards, including the North American Truck of The Year at the North American International Auto Show and Motor Trend's Truck of the Year. The new F-150 has helped Ford gain net market share in the full-size segment in the fourth quarter and Ford's F-Series pickup finished 2008 as America's best-selling truck for 32 straight years. The F-150 also was named Top Safety Pick by the U.S. Insurance Institute for Highway Safety and Ford now has the highest number of ratings, 16, Top Safety Picks in the industry. Ford brand also has more U.S. government five-star safety-rated vehicles than any other brand.</p>
          <p>Production is underway for the 2010 Ford Fusion, Mercury Milan and the Lincoln MKZ sedans, which go on sale this spring. Both the gasoline-powered and hybrid versions of the Fusion and Milan will offer the best in fuel economy when they hit showrooms this spring. The Fusion and Milan hybrids achieve 41 miles per gallon in city driving, making it America's most fuel-efficient mid-size sedan.</p>
          <p>The 2010 Ford Mustang, America's favorite muscle car debuted with an all-new look and will be in dealerships in a couple of months. We also announced an aggressive new electric vehicle plan that will bring the market new battery electric vehicles, hybrids and plug-in hybrids during the next four years.</p>
          <p>In Europe, Ford reached full production of the new Ka and is off to a strong sales start. The new Ford Fiesta named Car of the Year by What Car? magazine, Britain's leading source of new car advice. Fiesta was the best-selling model in the UK in November and December and is already the second best-selling Ford model in all of Europe. Ford Galaxy and the Ford S-MAX, both named number one for reliability among multi-activity vehicles by German vehicle testing agency DEKRA. Volvo launched the new XC60 in Europe and the highly acclaimed crossover will reach U.S. showrooms this spring.</p>
          <p>Slide six details some of our key business highlights of the fourth quarter. In November, we began the evaluation of our strategic options for Volvo Cars, including their possible sale. We expect the review to take some time and we won't have additional details to share today. In the meantime, Volvo has continued to implement an aggressive restructuring plan and substantially implemented its global personnel reduction of around 25% by the end of the quarter. We sold a portion of our ownership stake in Mazda for around 530 million, while continuing our successful 30-year strategic partnership with Mazda through our ongoing joint ventures, as well as sharing of platforms and powertrains. Our alliance is one of the most successful in the automobile industry.</p>
          <p>We ended large SUV production at the Michigan Truck Plant, which will be one of three plants we are retooling to make small, fuel-efficient cars beginning in 2010 as part of our global product transformation. In the U.S., the Ford, Lincoln and Mercury brands collectively increased market share all three months in the fourth quarter compared to the prior year. This is the first time we have achieved three consecutive months of U.S. market share gains in 12 years. And based on preliminary sales data, we are poised to make it four months in a row, when we report January sales results next Tuesday.</p>
          <p>Ford Europe improved its fourth quarter and full year market share in the 19 markets we track and became Europe's number two overall selling brand. Europe's performance was boosted by the strong sales start for our new global Fiesta car.</p>
          <p>We maintained sufficient liquidity and did not need to access government bridge loans. Ford also defined its plans with the U.S. Department of Energy to invest about 14 billion over seven years to produce advanced fuel-efficient vehicles. This could allow Ford to qualify for up to 5 billion of direct loans by 2011. Similar actions are being taken with the European Investment Bank.</p>
          <p>Now I will turn it over to Lewis, to provide more details on our fourth quarter financials. Lewis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Alan. Let's move on to slide eight, which provides more information on our results. Starting at the lower left, our net loss for the fourth quarter was about $5.9 billion. And our net loss included minority interests in affiliates. This net loss also included $874 million of tax expense, more than explained by a reversal of tax benefits, recognized earlier in the year for Accounting Standard FAS 109, related to our deferred tax valuation allowance. This is consistent with the guidance we have provided to you in last quarter's call. Adjusting for these items leaves the fourth-quarter pre-tax loss of over $5 billion. These results include pre-tax charges for special items of about $1.4 billion, which we'll cover on the next slide. Excluding these special items, we recorded a fourth quarter pre-tax operating loss of almost $3.7 billion. Most of the remaining slides will focus on these pre-tax operating results.</p>
          <p>Slide nine covers special items, which were about $1.4 billion in the fourth quarter. In North America, we recorded a charge of $229 million, largely related to hourly personnel reduction programs in the U.S. International operations incurred $280 million of charges, related to personnel reduction programs, primarily related to implementation of Volvo's and Asia-Pacific's restructuring plans.</p>
          <p>We recognized a gain of $82 million, due to the planned reductions in the number of employees in Job Security Benefits reserve, primarily due to the utilization of these employees at other plant locations. We recorded a charge of $224 million for accelerated depreciation related to a lease buyout at our AAI facility. And we recognized a $201 million loss on the sale of a portion of our investment in Mazda. In addition we incurred supplier settlement another cost of $209 million. Finally, we recorded $356 million of retiree healthcare charges related to the VEBA agreement with the UAW, primarily reflecting losses on the temporary asset account [TAA]. These losses will be reversed upon transfer of the TAA to the new independent VEBA.</p>
          <p>Now on to slide 10, which shows our pre-tax operating results by sector. The fourth quarter pre-tax operating results were a loss of almost $3.7 billion. These results included a loss of about $3 billion for the automotive sector and a loss of $384 million for Financial Services. The total company full-year operating results were a loss of $6.7 billion and these results included losses of $6.2 billion for the automotive sector and $495 million for Financial Services.</p>
          <p>Let's move on to slide 11, which shows pre-tax operating results for each of our automotive operating segments and other automotive. We'll focus here on other automotive, and then cover the operations in detail on the next slides. In the fourth quarter, other automotive was a loss of $330 million. This loss was more than explained by a net interest expense of $448 million, partly offset by a favorable fair market value adjustment of $118 million, primarily related to the impacts of changes in the exchange rates on intercompany loans.</p>
          <p>Slide 12 shows the change in fourth quarter results compared with the year ago; a decline of $2.4 billion. For comparison, the full year results are shown in the memo.  Volume and mix was about $2.8 billion unfavorable, primarily due to a decline in industry volumes and the impact of lower dealer stocks across all of the automotive operations; partly offset by market share improvements. Net pricing was about $200 million unfavorable, explained by a decline in Volvo and in North America, offset partly by improvements in Europe and South America.</p>
          <p>Cost changes were over $1.4 billion favorable in the fourth quarter, and $4.4 billion favorable in the full year, and we'll cover this on the next slide. Exchange was about $100 million unfavorable, more than explained by unfavorable exchange in Europe and Volvo, partly offset by favorable exchange in North America. Net interest and related fair market value adjustments were $200 million unfavorable, primarily due to lower cash balances and lower interest income rates; while the non-recurrence of Jaguar Land Rover profits in 2007 also adversely affected the year over year profit comparison by about $60 million. Finally, included the other decline of $400 million, are lower subsidiary and cost profits largely related to the decline in volumes.</p>
          <p>Now on to slide 13, which explains our cost reduction. Cost reductions of $4.4 billion compared to a year ago. The fourth quarter cost reductions were over $1.4 billion favorable. Full year net product costs were over $1.1 billion higher than the year ago, and fourth quarter net product costs were up about $800 million. Both increases were more than explained by higher commodity costs and unfavorable mark-to-market adjustments on commodity hedges. Warranty expense was over $100 million lower, as a result of improved quality. The manufacturing and engineering costs were over $1.5 billion lower, largely reflecting the continued benefit of our restructuring actions in North America.</p>
          <p>Spending-related costs improved by about $1.3 billion, primarily reflecting lower expense related to the North America assets impairment at the end of the second quarter, and the non-recurrence of accelerated depreciation and amortizations for facilities that we recently closed. Pension and retiree healthcare expenses were about $1.2 billion lower, primarily reflecting healthcare efficiencies and the affect of the U.S. hourly retiree healthcare VEBA agreement.</p>
          <p>Overhead costs were over $1 billion lower, primarily due to our restructuring actions. And advertising and sales promotions were about $400 million lower than the year ago.</p>
          <p>For the next section of the slides, we'll cover each of the automotive operations, starting with North America on slide 14. In the fourth quarter, wholesales of 484,000 units, down 197,000 units from the year ago; primarily reflecting the 35% decline in the U.S. Industry SAAR from 16.3 million units in fourth quarter 2007 to 10.6 million units in the fourth quarter 2008.</p>
          <p>During the fourth quarter, we also took actions to reduce U.S. dealer stocks by 36,000 units. At year-end, our dealer stocks were reduced by over 90,000 units or 17% from a year ago. As a result of our actions to keep production aligned with sales expectations, Ford was one of the few OEMs to reduce dealer inventory during the fourth quarter. We have amongst the lowest days supply in the industry.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter revenue was $11.3 billion, a $6 billion decrease from a year ago, primarily explained by lower volumes and unfavorable model mix. For the fourth quarter, Ford North America reported a pre-tax loss of about $1.9 billion, a $313 million decline from a year ago. I will cover this change on the next slide.</p>
          <p>So slide 15 provides an explanation of the change in North American results compared to the year ago. Volume and mix was about $1.6 billion unfavorable, primarily reflecting the decline in the U.S. industry volumes, lower dealer stocks and unfavorable production mix, partially offset by higher market share.  Our production mix was about $300 million worse than our mix of vehicles sold to final customers due to stock reductions on pickup trucks and large SUVs. Directionally, our losses would have been about $600 million lower if our production had been equal to our retail sales.</p>
          <p>Net pricing was about $200 million unfavorable, more than explained by higher retail incentives. And costs decreased by $1.2 billion, more than explained by lower structural costs including lower manufacturing and engineering, pensions and OPEB, spending related costs and overhead; while the structural cost reductions were partly offset by higher commodity costs and product content. Exchange was $300 million favorable consistent with the strengthening of the U.S. dollar relative to the Canadian dollar and the Mexican peso.</p>
          <p>Slide 16 provides an explanation of the improvement in North America's fourth quarter results compared to the third quarter. Volume and mix was $500 million favorable primarily reflecting an improvement in our U.S. market share from 12.4% to 15%, dealer stock reductions that were lower than third quarter reductions and favorable mix, partly offset by a decline in the U.S. Industry SAAR from 13.1 million units to 10.6 million units.</p>
          <p>Net pricing was $200 million favorable consistent with higher net pricing on 2009 models and costs increased by $100 million, more than explained by increased recognition of manufacturing costs as inventories are reduced and by higher advertising costs. Exchange was $200 million favorable consistent with the strengthening of the U.S. dollar relative to the Canadian dollar and the Mexican peso.</p>
          <p>The slide 17 shows U.S. market share for Ford and Lincoln Mercury. In the fourth quarter, our market share was 15% including 10% -- sorry, including 10.7% for retail and 4.3% for fleet.  This was the first time in 12 years that we improved our overall and retail market share in three consecutive months. Retail market share improved by 0.9% compared to &#x2013; over the last year, and this increase is more than explained by higher F-Series and Fusion shares from the introduction of the all-new Lincoln MKS and the Ford Flex. Fleet share remained flat at 4.3% compared to last year.</p>
          <p>Slide 18 provides a summary of cost reductions in North America.  In the fourth quarter, operating-related cost reductions totaled $1.2 billion compared with the year ago.  Net product costs were about $500 million unfavorable, more than explained by higher commodity costs and product content, partly offset by material cost reductions.</p>
          <p>Structural and other cost reductions, totaled $1.7 billion in the fourth quarter compared with the year-ago. This reduction includes about $250 million for reduced depreciation from the fixed asset impairment in the second quarter. We exceeded our $5 billion cost reduction target, compared to 2005 by about $100 million, excluding the favorable impacts of lower depreciation related to impairments. Hourly and salaried personnel in North America totaled 75,000 people at the end of the fourth quarter, down 5,000 personnel from the end of the third quarter. In addition, during January we further reduced our salaried employment levels by about another 1,300 people.</p>
          <p>Now on to South America on slide 19. In the fourth quarter, wholesales were 97,000 units, down 29,000 units from a year ago, primarily reflecting the 27% decline in Industry SAAR from 4.5 million units in the fourth quarter 2007 to 3.3 million units in the fourth quarter 2008. This decline is largely related to the global financial crisis that began to impact South America during the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter revenue was $1.7 billion, a $700 million decrease from a year ago, primarily reflecting lower volumes and weaker Brazilian currency partly offset by favorable net pricing. And for the fourth quarter, Ford South America earned a pre-tax profit of $105 million, a $313 million decrease from a year ago. This decrease primarily reflects lower industry volume and the higher net product costs, partly offset by favorable net marketing -- sorry, favorable net pricing.</p>
          <p>Slide 20 tells us Ford Europe. In the fourth quarter, wholesales were 378,000 units, down 109,000 units from a year ago. Fourth quarter Industry SAAR for the 19 markets that we track was 14.8 million units, down 3.5 million units or 19% from a year ago. In addition the Russian Industry SAAR was 2.7 million units, down 300,000 units or 10% from a year ago. The fourth quarter market share was $0.085, up three-tenths of a point from last year. And the full year market share was up in most of the major markets that we track; but adverse country mix limited the full year improvement to 0.1%. In the fourth quarter, revenue was $7.6 billion, a $2.8 billion decrease from a year ago, primarily due to lower volume and unfavorable currency translation, partly offset by favorable mix. For the fourth quarter, Ford of Europe reports a pre-tax loss of $330 million, a $553 million decline from the year ago. And we'll cover this change on the next slide.</p>
          <p>Slide 21 provides an explanation of the change in the Ford Europe results in compared to a year ago. Volume and mix was $500 million unfavorable, more than explained by the decline in industry volume and lower dealer stocks, partially offset by improved market share. The industry volume decline reflects a significant economic weakening in almost all European markets.</p>
          <p>Net pricing was $100 million favorable compared to a year ago. This reflects favorable vehicle pricing primarily in Britain and Germany, in part to offset unfavorable currency exchange effects. Costs decreased by $200 million, reflecting lower warranty costs driven by continued progress in quality, lower manufacturing and engineering costs to align capacity with demand, and reduction in pension costs, partly offset by higher commodity costs. Exchange was about $200 million unfavorable, mainly due to the weakening of the British pound and the Russian ruble compared to the euro. Other was $100 million unfavorable primarily explained by lower earnings on our joint ventures due to lower industry volumes.</p>
          <p>Slide 22 covers Volvo. In the fourth quarter, wholesales were 80,000 units, down 47,000 units from a year ago.  This reduction is explained by the sharply lower industry volumes primarily in the UK and Europe as described earlier, and the reduction in market share.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter revenue was $3.3 billion, a $1.8 billion decrease from a year ago, primarily explained by lower volume, unfavorable net pricing, and unfavorable currency translation. For the fourth quarter, Volvo reported a pre-tax loss of $736 million compared with breakeven a year ago. And we'll cover this decline on the next slide.</p>
          <p>Slide 23 provides an explanation of the change in Volvo's results compared to a year ago. Volume and mix was $500 million unfavorable, primarily reflecting lower industry volume and market share. Net pricing was $200 million unfavorable compared to a year ago, primarily reflecting increased incentive spending in Europe and Russia, and lower residual values in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Costs decreased by over $100 million, largely explained by actions taken to reduce structural costs, while exchange is about $100 million unfavorable. During 2008, Volvo initiated restructuring actions to reduce total personnel levels by 6,000 people or around 25%, and these actions were largely implemented by the end of the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Going now on to slide 24, which covers Asia Pacific, Africa and Mazda. Overall fourth quarter losses were $129 million and full year profits were $77 million.  For the fourth quarter, we earned $79 million from our investment in Mazda, a $4 million increase from a year ago. And this is the last quarter we'll be reporting our share of Mazda profits. As a result of reducing our ownership interest in Mazda from over 33% to about 14%, our remaining investment will be treated as a marketable security in our investment portfolio. This investment will be revalued quarterly to reflect share price changes in U.S. dollars.</p>
          <p>So slide 25 covers Asia-Pacific and Africa. In the fourth quarter, wholesales were 99,000 units, a decreased to 46,000 units compared with 2007, primarily reflecting industry weakness in both markets and lower dealer stocks. The fourth quarter Industry SAAR was 17.9 million units, down 2.4 million units or 12% from a year ago. And the fourth quarter revenue, which excludes sales at  our joint venture in China was $1.4 billion, a $300 million decrease from a year ago; more than explained by lower volume and unfavorable currency translation. For the fourth quarter, Asia-Pacific and Africa reported a pre-tax loss of $208 million, a $218 million decline from the year ago. This decline primarily reflects lower industry volumes, unfavorable exchange, adverse product mix and higher incentives; partly offset by cost reductions.</p>
          <p>Slide 26 shows automotive cash and cash flow. We ended the fourth quarter with $13.4 billion in gross cash, down $5.5 billion from the third quarter. Our operating related cash flow was $7.2 billion negative in the fourth quarter, reflecting an automotive pre-tax loss of about $3.3 billion. Capital spending during the quarter was about $600 million higher than depreciation and amortization, primarily because of spending associated with the launch of all-new F-150 and the impacts of the second quarter asset impairment on depreciation and amortization.</p>
          <p>This also reflects a change in working capital and other timing differences that were $2.7 billion negative. This is primarily explained by a reduction in trade payables of about $4 billion and other timing differences as a result of lower production at the end of the quarter.</p>
          <p>Significant reductions in inventory and receivables were offsets to the lower payables. And payments of $600 million to Ford Credit, reflecting our change to up-front payments of subvention. This outflow continues to be significantly impacted by declining global demand and the actions we have taken to reduce dealer stocks by another 50,000 units compared with the third quarter to better align with future expectations. Once volumes stabilize, payables will stop declining and generally will grow as volumes recover. In addition, in part because of the major F-150 launch -- in part because the major F-150 launch will be behind us, we expect spending to decline in 2009.</p>
          <p>Separation programs resulted in an outflow of $200 million for the quarter, while we contributed $100 million to our non-U.S. pension plans. We received a $1.3 billion tax related payment from Ford Credit. We also received about $500 million from divestitures, primarily the sale of our Mazda securities. Including all of these impacts, the total decline in gross cash during the fourth quarter was $5.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Slide 27 summarizes our automotive sector's net liquidity at December 31, 2008. Total liquidity, including the available credit lines was $24 billion. This liquidity includes $10.1 billion available under our secured credit lines, and 500 million of other automotive credit lines. As Alan mentioned earlier, we provided notice today to our banks to fully draw our secured credit lines. We took this action, because of our growing concerns about the instability of the capital markets, given the uncertain state of the global economy.</p>
          <p>We believe that it is prudent to draw the secured credit lines in this environment. The $10.1 billion will get added to our cash and included in our first quarter balance sheet. Under the terms of our credit agreements, we expect to receive funds from this borrowing next Tuesday, February 3.</p>
          <p>Our year-end, automotive debt was $25.8 billion, almost less than $3 billion of the external debt matures in the next three years. The automotive debt excludes the impacts of the secured credit line draw. Also this month, as permitted by the underlying agreement, Ford converted the temporary asset account funds into a new Ford note payable at the end of this year. This will provide the flexibility to utilize over $2 billion of funds to support operations if needed within the year. As a result, this amount will improve liquidity and be included in gross cash starting this quarter.</p>
          <p>Now, let's turn to slide 28, and Financial Services. For the fourth quarter, the Financial Services sector reported a pre-tax loss of $384 million, a $653 million decline from the year ago. For the full year, the pre-tax loss was $495 million, a $1.7 billion decline from a year ago. Other Financial Services reported a loss of $12 billion in the fourth quarter, an 18 million decline from a year ago. For the full year, pre-tax loss was $22 million, a $31 million decline from the year ago.  These declines primarily reflect non-recurrence of asset sales. We'll cover Ford Credit in more detail on the next slide.</p>
          <p>And Slide 29 explains the change in Ford Credit's pre-tax results from the fourth quarter compared to the year ago.  For the fourth quarter, the pre-tax loss was $372 million, a 635 million decline from a year ago. The decrease in earnings primarily reflected a higher provision for credit losses, higher net losses related to market valuation adjustments for derivatives, lower volume and lower financing margins. Also lower operating costs were largely offset by other expenses.</p>
          <p>The volume and financing margin were lower, primarily reflecting declining asset levels in the fourth quarter of 2008.  The increase in the provision for credit losses primarily reflects higher severities, higher repossessions, higher dealer rate and higher dealer related losses in the U.S., and higher losses in Europe.</p>
          <p>Residual losses were about the same in the fourth quarter 2008 compared with last year. While auction values have declined significantly from last year, the fourth quarter profit implication declines were mitigated by the second quarter $2.1 billion lease impairment charge, and we expect auction values to continue to be volatile.</p>
          <p>I'll turn to the number on the left-hand -- on the left of the -- the lower left of the slide, Ford Credit's December 31, 2008 managed assets were $118 billion, about $29 billion lower than a year ago. This decline primarily reflects lower North American receivables, changes in currency exchange rates, the impact of divestitures and alternative business arrangements, and the second quarter 2008 impairment charge for the North American operating leases.</p>
          <p>In addition, Ford Credit is restructuring its U.S. operations to meet these changing business conditions, including lower automotive sales and the planned reduction in Jaguar, Land Rover and Mazda receivables, and to maintain their competitive cost structure.  The restructuring will affect servicing, sales, and central operations, and will eliminate about 1,200 jobs and agency positions, or about 20%. The reductions will occur in 2009 through attrition, retirements and involuntary separations.</p>
          <p>Slide 30 covers the liquidity and funding outlook. The left box shows Ford Credit's committed liquidity programs and cash, and the utilization of liquidity sources at the end of the fourth quarter. Ford Credit's liquidity exceeded utilization by about $21 billion. Ford Credit's funding strategy remains centered on maintaining liquidity to its short term funding obligations, including holding a substantial cash balance. Excuse me.</p>
          <p>We are maintaining our funding programs and securitization structures so that we're ready to access to public markets when they return. We are planning to renew committed capacity throughout this year and we'll utilize appropriate government sponsored programs. Until market access returns, utilization of government sponsored programs in the U.S. and around the world will be an important to fund the Ford Credit's short-term funding plans. It has utilized the U.S. Commercial Paper Funding Facility and the European Central Bank's Liquidity Facility and plans to use the U.S. Term Asset Backed Securities Loan Facility, the TALF, when launched later this quarter.</p>
          <p>Gaining approval of our application for an Investment Loan Corporation, is a component of Ford Credit's funding plan, as it will provide access to lower cost, diversified funding and certificates of deposit. And Ford Credit will continue to explore and execute alternative business and funding arrangements in those locations where it lacks other funding capability. At the end of the fourth quarter, Ford Credit's managed leverage was 9.921 and Ford Credit's equity was 10.6 billion.</p>
          <p>Finally, we will continue to reduce the size of our balance sheet in 2009, reflecting our strategy to focus on Ford brands, and influence alternative business arrangements, as well as lower overall automotive sales. By the end of 2009, Ford Credit's managed receivables will be in the range of 90 to $100 billion.</p>
          <p>Slide 31 provides an update on our pension plans. Worldwide 2008 pension expense, excluding special items was $500 million, down $300 million from 2007, primarily reflecting the ongoing impact of separations and higher discount rates in 2008. At year end 2008, our U.S. funded plans were underfunded by $4.1 billion; and worldwide our pension plans were underfunded by 11.9 billion, primarily reflecting the impacts of lower asset returns in 2008. We do not have a requirement to fund our major U.S. pension plans in 2009.</p>
          <p>Slide 32 provides an update on OPEB. Worldwide OPEB expense, excluding special items was $800 million, down $900 million from 2007, primarily reflecting healthcare efficiencies and the affect of the new UAW VEBA agreement. Retiree benefit payments were $1.5 billion in 2008.</p>
          <p>At the end, at year end 2008, our OPEB plans had a funding shortfall of $16.3 billion, a $7.9 billion improvement from 2007. The change in funded status primarily reflects the lower obligation for the new UAW VEBA agreement. We have not shown cost trends this year, as we have our capped our obligation for hourly costs, as a result of the UAW VEBA agreement and previously, we had established the company contribution limits set at 2006 levels for the U.S. salaried retiree healthcare benefits.</p>
          <p>And now on to slide 33, which shows the results of our 2008 full year planning assumptions and operational metrics. Total industry volume for 2008 was 13.5 million units in the U.S. and 16.6 million units in Europe, both down substantially from our planning assumptions. On the operational metrics, the quality of our vehicles has risen consistently for four straight years and our vehicle satisfaction has reached an all-time high. Ford, Lincoln and Mercury vehicles collectively reduced things gone wrong, TGWs by 7.7% compared to last year. Our TGW level is now at the lowest levels ever, or statistically a tie with the best Japanese brands.</p>
          <p>Automotive costs were reduced by $4.4 billion, significantly better than planned; and the U.S. market costs were 14.2%, consistent with our plan but better than our recent expectations. Absolute operating cash was $19.5 billion, and this was higher than our plan. The capital expenditure was $6.5 billion.</p>
          <p>The slide 34 covers our 2009 first quarter production plans. In North America, first quarter production schedule is 400,000 units, down 292,000 units from 2008, and 30,000 units lower than our prior guidance. Most of the decline from last year is in trucks and SUVs. For Ford Europe, we expect first quarter production of 325,000 units, down 214,000 units from a year ago, in part to further reduced dealer inventories. And at Volvo, we expect first quarter production of 67,000 units, down 45,000 units from a year ago.</p>
          <p>Overall, production is not down greatly compared to the fourth quarter, because we'd already taken decisive actions to implement significant stock reductions for the last half of 2008, bringing our U.S. base supply down to a level 8% below the average industry. Importantly, we are planning much of our downtime early in the first quarter to continue to rebalance dealer stocks.</p>
          <p>In comparison, much of the fourth quarter downtime occurred late in the quarter, and this should result in our payables at the end of the first quarter being greater than our year-end levels, reducing cash -- and reducing cash burn during the quarter.</p>
          <p>And now, I would like to turn it over to Alan to summarize our plans going forward, including our 2009 outlook.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Lewis. On slide 36, we provide an overview of the business environment. We expect weak volumes this year across all markets, with worldwide sales down over 10%; a record decline according to our data. Most of the 2008 weakness outside of the U.S. occurred late in the year. Significant government policy stimulus has been implemented in most markets. This is expected to improve the environment for sales later this year. Financial markets remain under significant stress and further government and central bank actions to provide liquidity and stabilized banks are needed.</p>
          <p>Our suppliers and dealers also have been weakened by the global economic downturn and financial crisis. The decline in oil, fuel and other raw materials' prices will provide a partial offset to the weak demand conditions. Currencies are very volatile, which poses some risk. Of note, is a substantial weakness in the British pound, Russian ruble devaluations and some Asian currency weaknesses.</p>
          <p>Slide 37 summarizes the key aspects of our plan. These have not changed. We are more focused than ever on implementing our transmission plan to respond to the significant challenges presented by the continuing global economic downturn, and deliver longer term profitable growth. We are glad that we went to the capital markets at the right time to obtain liquidity to finance our plan and that we sold non-core brands to raise further capital and allow further focus of our resources on Ford. And I am especially pleased with how the team is working together to create ONE FORD and leveraging our global resources.</p>
          <p>Despite the present turbulence in the worldwide economies, I continue to believe that Ford is well positioned to take advantage of our scale and global product strengths. With a balanced portfolio of highly acclaimed, best-in-class vehicles and sharp focus on the Ford global brand across the globe, we can effectively operate through the current downturn. Going forward, this balanced portfolio will allow the flexibility to adapt more easily to changes in our environment and begin to grow profitably as the global economy rebounds.</p>
          <p>On slide 38, as we have discussed on numerous occasions, despite the financial crisis, our plan is to invest in new smaller, fuel-efficient vehicles and achieve a more balanced global product portfolio remains intact. Our pipeline is full. In combination with the business improvements being achieved, we expect our ONE FORD product development vision and process to deliver a broad range of highly acclaimed global vehicles in what we call the global segments, B, C, C/D and Commercial Vans beginning this year.</p>
          <p>As indicated before, by 2010 about 40% of our entries in North America in these segments will be shared with the Ford of Europe platform and top-hats with complete alignment of the lineup in these segments shared with Ford of Europe by 2013. This compares with almost nothing in common today. And every new product, as evidenced by the Fusion, will be the best or among the best in the segment for fuel economy as well as quality, safety and value. Our new products will be assembled in plants featuring lean manufacturing techniques. And in nearly all facilities flexible body shops will make them competitive with the best in the business. Importantly, longer term, we expect to have our vehicle assembly capacity match to the demand. As we make these changes we are also continuing to fix the fundamentals of the business as evidenced by our plan to reduce automotive structural costs by about another $4 billion this year.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide 39. Based on our current planning assumptions, Ford has sufficient liquidity to make it through this global downturn and to maintain our product plans without the need for government bridge loans. We would however, require a government bridge loan if there is a significantly deeper economic downturn or a significant industry event, such as the bankruptcy of a major competitor that causes disruption to the company's supply base, dealers or creditors.</p>
          <p>We are on our way to delivering the 14 to 17 billion of automotive cash improvement actions we defined in November.  These actions include reducing spending and inventories, and achieving other working capital improvements; further reducing salaried personnel-related costs and achieving additional efficiencies in engineering, manufacturing, advertising, and information technology; releasing capital consistent with Ford Credit's smaller balance sheet and focus on Ford brands; developing incremental sources of funding, including sale of other non-core assets.</p>
          <p>In addition, we are pursuing other restructuring opportunities in conjunction with our various stakeholders and we'll have more to discuss on this as they develop. These restructuring opportunities are being pursued on a global basis with each business unit throughout the Ford world focused on restructuring its operations. Ford remains on track for both its overall and its North American automotive pre-tax results to be breakeven or profitable in 2011, excluding special items.</p>
          <p>Slide 40 summarizes our 2009 outlook, including our key automotive planning assumptions and operating metrics.  We are expecting total industry sales to be in the range of 11.5 to 12.5 million units for the U.S., and in a range of 12.5 to 13.5 million units for Europe. These estimates include both light and heavy vehicles.</p>
          <p>On operational metrics, we will continue to improve our quality. As mentioned previously, we will continue to reduce our automotive structural costs by about another 4 billion during 2009. We have focused this metric on the structural costs as these are the costs largely within our control. While we will continue to pursue our material cost reduction initiatives, we recognize that commodity costs and related hedging gains and losses will continue to be very volatile.</p>
          <p>On market share, we expect that both our total U.S. share and our share of the U.S. retail market will stabilize and improvements are possible within our new product lineup. We have included the second share performance measurement, the U.S. share of retail market as this is the most important and traditionally the most profitable market segment in which we participate. In this context, we are defining the U.S. retail market as excluding all fleet sales, including those to daily rental companies and governments. For 2008, we estimate that we had about a 12.1% share of the U.S. retail market.</p>
          <p>We anticipate total Europe share to be about equal or improved as compared to 2008. We continue to expect operating cash outflows in 2009, but these will be significantly less than those incurred in 2008. This is based on industry volumes stabilizing early in the year and beginning to recover later in the year. This should result in improvements in both payables and in number of other factors.</p>
          <p>In addition, the outflows related to acceleration of subvention payments to Ford Credit will decrease in 2009 and we will be realizing benefits from the actions initiated under our 14 to 17 billion cash improvement plan. Further, we expect to receive funding from the Department of Energy, the European Investment Bank, and other sources in support of our investments to improve fuel efficiency and reduce CO2 emissions.</p>
          <p>Finally, as indicated in November, capital spending will be in the range of 5 to 5.5 billion, down from 6.5 billion in 2008, as we'll be completed spending on our new F-150 and realize even greater efficiencies from our ONE FORD global product development initiative. Given the volatile nature of today's market, at this time, we do not believe it would be prudent to provide any other further guidance on profitability for 2009.</p>
          <p>Now on to slide 41. Business conditions have deteriorated rapidly on a global scale, but our ONE FORD plan is more right than ever. We are focused on swift and decisive actions to stay on course with the four elements of our plan. We are working on longer term restructuring actions on a global basis and managing all elements that we control to decisively respond to the changing economic conditions.</p>
          <p>In the next year, our product offensive continues with the new Ford Mustang, the new Lincoln MKZ, <mark type="inaudible" /> and new hybrid versions of both the Ford Fusion and Mercury Milan, the new Ford Taurus with EcoBoost engine, Lincoln MKS and Ford Flex, both with EcoBoost engines, an entirely new type of small commercial van for this market called the Transit Connect, and the all-new Lincoln MKT, three-row premium crossover.</p>
          <p>In addition, Volvo is launching its XC60 crossover in Europe now, and in the U.S. market this spring. A freshened S80 comes later this year. These vehicles will build upon innovative new products that were introduced late last year such as the Ford F-150, the Ford Fiesta, Kuga and the Ka.</p>
          <p>In summary, these continue to be challenging days for the auto industry, yet I remain convinced that Ford is implementing the right plan.  I continue to believe that Ford is well positioned to take advantage of our scale and our product strengths worldwide. Now, we would like to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alan. Ladies and gentlemen, we're going to start the Q&amp;A session now. We have about 35 minutes for the Q&amp;A. We will begin with questions from the investment community and then take questions from the media, who are also on the call. To allow us many questions as possible within our timeframe, I ask that you keep your questions brief, so that we don't have to move callers along after a couple of minutes. So with that, Catena, can we please have the first call -- question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from the line of John Murphy, representing Merrill Lynch. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to ask a question about dealing with your constituency here, I mean you have two weaker competitors or competitors who are not as well positioned, that are having very significant negotiations with labor at the UAW and with creditors. And thinking that they might achieve something at some point in the future through various means, is this something that you are pursuing right now? Particularly on the debt side, you're burning the balance sheet quite a bit here, drawing down this revolver. I was just wondering if there might be an opportunity to do a -- more equity for debt swaps or debt for debt swaps? And on the UAW, would you be able to get a similar, maybe downsized contract, that GM or Chrysler might be able to achieve and are those negotiations ongoing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet. I understand completely, John. And the way I would characterize it is that, this clearly is a restructuring of the automobile industry. And even though we're in a different place and as you pointed out much further along, we thought it was so important that we support the industry for the good of the industry and the U.S. economy and our suppliers and our dealers, which is why we went with our colleagues to Washington D.C. to help.</p>
          <p>Now having said that, clearly the response we got was that this is an industry restructuring, the government wants to see a very viable automobile industry in the United States. And so, as we go forward, we -- our plan is to continue to work all elements of competitiveness, including the ones that you delineated. And I really believe from the ongoing conversations that we're having with all of the stakeholders and the U.S. government that as we go through this and we continue to take the actions that we need to take, that we will not be disadvantaged.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, okay.  So is there an intention or something or negotiations that are going, or talks going on right now with creditors specifically? Or is it more on the operating upside right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I would like to pass on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just leave it at, we're talking to all the stakeholders clearly; just like we have been over the years. And clearly the elements of competitiveness, we all know very well.  But I'm very pleased with the response of all the stakeholders to this bigger restructuring.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if I could sneak one other one in, Chrysler's cutting labor costs at dealerships or labor reimbursement for warranty work, and doing some other things that are pretty onerous for their dealers. Do you look at the dealership network as an opportunity to cut costs or do you look at them as they're an opportunity as other dealerships are coming under pressure as a real strategic advantage here? I'm just wondering how you were dealing with the dealership base right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet, John. I absolutely think of it in the latter. The Ford distribution network is a tremendous asset, as you know. The clarity of focus on the Ford, Lincoln Mercury brand is phenomenal.  The fact that we have been consolidating those over the last few years to improve the dealers' throughput and their profitability, we're tremendously strong in every small and medium-sized community across the United States, and the only issue that we have been working with the dealers on has been the overcapacity in the large metro areas.</p>
          <p>And clearly the dealers want to work that and this is the time to do it, because they're business people, they're entrepreneurs and they absolutely know that we need to straighten this out in the big metropolitan areas, and that's where we've been focusing. And I know you know the numbers of the consolidations that we have accomplished. And so, we're going to continue to work with them. This is clearly led by them. There's lots of working together we can do to help make it go easily, but I am very pleased with the progress we're making on our distribution channel. And one reason I think it makes it much easier so to speak, is the fact that we have such a laser focus on the Ford brand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Rod Lache representing Deutsche Bank. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Rod. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. Can you talk a bit about working capital going forward? I think Lewis, you mentioned the cadence of production could help you a bit in Q1 versus Q4, but there's also a lot of talk about supplier distress and the potential for fast-pay programs to help suppliers. So, just elaborate a little bit on what your expectations are, and how would you be able to increase payables from here just given the state of the union among suppliers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. In the fourth quarter, all our production cuts were basically towards the end of the quarter. And that meant our payables runoff significantly. As we look at the first quarter, our production cuts are basically as we came out of Christmas, so at the beginning of the quarter we would expect our payables to come back up to a more normal level in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>And then as we go through the year, if the recovery happens that we're projecting in the second half we'll have a higher level of production and therefore a higher level of payables. Our suppliers are under some distress. It varies by individual suppliers, it's not a Ford problem, it's an industry problem. And we'll continue to work with them to solve individual problems, but we believe the payables will come back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it your view that this still represents a systemic risk, just given the magnitude of the cuts and the distress? There's been a lot of talk, especially in the past week or two that suppliers may need some federal assistance here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think the whole industry is concerned about the low level of production, which affects all the suppliers. And with our interdependence, and it's not just the domestic brands, it's the transplant brands as well, are all dependent upon a very similar supply base and we're all very, very carefully watching the situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can you also elaborate on the $4 billion cost reduction objective? How does that break down North America, Europe, Volvo, and just also clarify, is that still a net cost reduction objective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's, we won't give you the detail by business unit, Rod, but it is a net cost reduction on structural costs. It does not include material cost changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. What's your preliminary view on material costs, is it a plus or minus, looking into '09?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably, both. We expect to see our material costs related to the commodity costs increases we see last year continue through the first half, as we see some of our contracts rolling through. And in the second half to come back down a little bit, as the prevailing commodity cost levels start feeding through into our supply contracts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just lastly, when do you expect to hear back on this ILC application, is there any guidance that you've been given and what the status of that application would be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're in --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Active negotiations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Active negotiations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Rod, I might also add on your supplier comments, which I think is really important. We're continuing to see -- I think we'll continue to see more consolidations, as they take out the overcapacity and they focus on the three big companies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rod.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Chris Ceraso representing Credit Suisse. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One thing maybe you can help to clarify. When you talk about these structural cost savings, for example the 5 billion over the past few years, you say it's on a constant volume basis. Does that mean that it was actually greater than that, but because volume was lower, you've adjusted it or --? I'm wondering if you shouldn't have saved a lot more, considering the big drop in volume and the costs that would go away naturally because of the drop in volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the volume adjustments only work on variable. And when we do the analysis, we take out the volume adjustments first, and then we do the cost reductions at constant volume. Otherwise it changes whether the volumes are going up or going down. So that's why we do it. We think that it's a much more representative way of explaining material cost changes. But a large part of the cost savings were not variable. They were true fixed costs. So the only area that may get into that is a bit of an exchange rate movement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You've outlined the change in pension funded status, yearend '08 versus '07, but you didn't give us your expectation for pension expense in '09. Can you share that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the U.S., we don't expect any expense this year. We're still up  &#x2013; sorry I'm using the wrong terms, as some of my friends pointed out, contributions. For the non-U.S. affiliates, we're still updating that and we'll have that in the 10-K.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But on a P&amp;L basis, not a cash basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll tell you in the 10-K.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The Volvo -- what's -- do you think you're going to have to fix this? How do you expect to sell it when you're generating these kinds of losses? Do you think maybe you have to pull back and fix it before you can get interested buyers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, all we've said is we're exploring our strategic alternatives. The -- our management team at Volvo is completely consumed with fixing the business and would -- and continuing to get large amount of supports from the rest of the Ford team. So whatever the results of our deliberations, the local team and the encouragement they get from Dearborn is to fix the business. That needs to be done whatever happens.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for your help.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Patrick Archambault representing Goldman Sachs. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yes. can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi Patrick, we hear you well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the supplier issue; obviously there's been a lot written in the press about Visteon.  And I just was wondering if you could comment a) -- have there been any discussions between you and them in terms of trying to get ahead of what some people have speculated to be a filing within the coming weeks? And how do you react to people who sort of look at the parallel between Delphi and how involved GM had to get in that in the attempt to turn around? Are those parallels accurate or is the situation very different having gone through several restructurings with Visteon already?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I understand Patrick. I think that Visteon and Ford are clearly in a different place, they, since we've completed those transactions and we took care of parts of the plants and they started Visteon; they have really diversified their portfolio. And so they're in a much different place. Now with respect to your first question, we along with Visteon with all of our supplies &#x2013; we are talking to all of them weekly, because the most important thing we do is continue to make progress and deal with this overcapacity and keep the supply chain going. But they are, I think clearly in a different place, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And any chance you could give us a sense of kind of the dollar amount of -- things have changed so much, the dollar amount of parts that you guys do count on them for on an annual basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, but I just would emphasize that you can probably get that, maybe more insight from Visteon but they have clearly move to dramatically diversify.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And I had one on the UAW VEBA. I guess you've replaced cash with notes, it sounds like if I'm interpreting it correctly, giving you access to that that liquidity for the year. Is that something that you negotiated with the UAW in recent weeks, or was that just part of the original contract that you just decided to exercise?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was in the terms of the agreements and we obviously in consultation with the UAW agreed to access it really to help us through the first quarter with the January slowed startups.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very cooperative discussions with the UAW there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, it was done in consultation with them?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, yes. Oh, absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a big deal for them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I guess one last one, I guess, just housekeeping. How come you didn't draw down the entire 10.6 credit facility, because I believe the number you mentioned in the press release was 10.1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Neil, you --.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The 10.6 includes letter of credit facilities that we've used, so the available -- net available for us on the facility is 10.1. So we did draw the full amount available.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Okay. Thanks a lot guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I just like to clarify my comments to Chris at Credit Suisse. In terms of what we'll give you in the 10-K, we'll give our total pension contributions, not expense. Sorry for the confusion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I might add on the drawing down our credit facility; that our plan is to not use that money to fund the ongoing operations. And we think we also have sufficient liquidity to maintain our minimum cash balance without using that facility. What we tried to say, really clearly is that, we thought it was just -- at this time very prudent with the volatility in the credit markets due to the uncertainty in the global economy that it was just a prudent time to move that asset over to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Himanshu Patel representing JPMorgan. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>There's been some, I think, actions taken outside of the U.S. by various governments to stimulate sales. I think there's been some scrapping incentives in Germany and a tax holiday in Brazil. Can you give us an update on whether any of these have had any immediate impact?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We had some impact in Brazil in the -- at the very end of the fourth quarter. And we are seeing significantly increased showroom traffic in Germany as a result of their scrapping incentive. I must admit, I'm not sure, I haven't spoken directly to Ford of Germany to find out how much of that has been translated into sales, although they look like they're having a good month. So I think we're modestly encouraged by the German action.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I don't know if Neil is there, but the on ILC, have you -- can you give us an update on -- just trying to quantify how much that could help you by in terms of providing a low cost funding, should we still think about may be 12 to $18 billion worth or so per year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Himanshu. This is K.R. To be clear on the ILC. The ILC was never expected to be a big portion of our overall funding plan. We've talked in the past at looking at a bank that would grow over time to somewhere near 10, 12 billion or so. So it has to grow up over time, it's not one time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think initially that the plan is -- was to use retail assets and so I think we still have numerous options from a standpoint of those assets and how they get funded.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, can you talk a little bit about the TALF, how meaningful do you think that would be? There's obviously a lot of excitement in the marketplace about that being something that could be effective on the ABS market but I guess in the case of Ford, you've got some conduit lines at Ford Credit that are running off. Do you view some sort of improved access to ABS as essentially offsetting that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think, from our perspective we're pretty excited about the TALF program in general, because it clearly is a broad asset program. It's term and we have gotten a lot of interest already from investors for TALF-eligible securitizations. So we're working with the New York Fed and we expect to have something up and running mid-February.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from line of Itay Michaeli, representing Citi. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning. Just a couple of questions on cash flow and liquidity. Just for clarification, on the 14 to 17 billion of cash improvement, how much might you expect to generate in '09? And is the 4 billion of structural cost savings that you're guiding embedded in the 14 to 17 as well, or is that incremental?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's roughly half and half 2009 to 2010 of the 14 to 17. And the $4 billion is embedded in the, in our 2009, they're part of the 2009. But as Alan said, we're continuing to look at restructuring, we're just not ready to talk about the details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on liquidity, if I take the comments on the revolver drawdown as merely a backup for the operations as opposed to actually being used in the operations; if I just run very simple math with 15 billion of cash, let's say you need 7 to 8 billion of minimum cash. So should we roughly assume 7 to 8 billion is what you are thinking for an '09 cash burn or am I missing something there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We won't go into the math, because we're not about to declare the minimum cash levels. But we expect 2009 cash burn to be much, much lower than 2008. There are some significant, there are some significant one-offs like VEBA payments in 2008, there's the payables impact as we go through the year with a gradually increasing volume rather than declining volume. CapEx is down 1 billion to 1.5 billion. And we are, as you've heard us say, applying for both Section 136 loans from the Energy Independence and Security Act and also applying to the European Investment Bank for CO2 related loans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I see that. That's helpful. And then just finally, just a point of clarification on the stakeholder negotiations. I know you can't really get into any detail but should we assume these are just simply Ford Motor Company stakeholders or are you also speaking with stakeholder specific to Ford Motor Credit, like specifically creditors there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, our actions are around being competitive in the auto industry. So the discussions that Alan was talking about specifically were Ford Motor Company stakeholders. We are doing a number of things about Ford Credit, not just financing actions but also we're having discussions on different business arrangements in various countries where funding is difficult to achieve.</p>
          <p>For example, we just announced that we've withdrawn from retail financing in Australia along, and we're about the last person to withdraw. And we've made different arrangements in some parts of Northern Europe, and obviously as the Jaguar Land Rover divestiture occurred, we're making different arrangements for Jaguar Land Rover financing. So, there are different actions happening with Ford Credit in this -- today that the U.S. part of Ford Credit announced a 20% personnel reduction during this first half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, at this time, we'd like to welcome questions from the media community. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from the line of Bryce Hoffman, representing The Detroit News. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bryce.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Am I understanding correctly that you've just lowered your SAAR estimate by about 1 million units for the year, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We --.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've provided a range when we are at -- in Washington on December 2, we provided a point at 12.5, we're now providing a range of 11.5 to 12.5. It's very volatile. We don't just know whereabouts in that range it'll be, but the fact that we've identified a range suggests we're within 12.5 is towards the top-end of probability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Then Lewis, just following up on that. You guys have said that you wouldn't need to go to seek federal assistance if the domestic market didn't significantly deteriorate from your planning assumptions. Isn't this a significant deterioration potentially from those assumptions? Can you explain a little bit more how you remain confident in your ability to proceed without aid from Washington given that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well it's specifically -- it's not what we would regard as significant deterioration. Obviously as volumes come down a little bit, we have to work harder on other aspects of the business. And I think you've seen in the past that we're relentless if reacting to the prevailing demand and that's what we're doing. And that is, this is not just around the U.S., it's around Europe and South America and Asia-Pacific.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. One just clarification too. Following upon the analyst's question about Visteon, I just wanted to be clear; you guys are not anticipating any sort of dramatic rescue action with regards to Visteon, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, with what we've seen of the press reports, we're not contemplating dramatic action.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to extend my response to Bryce on industry volumes. As we said in Washington, it's not just around the absolute volume, it's also around the length of the downturn and when the recovery starts. We still feel that with the amount of stimulus that's going under the U.S. market that we will see some improvement in the second half of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Jeff Bennett representing Dow Jones. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Lewis, just a quick question, I -- my line cut out. So, you are not anticipating making any kind of cash contributions into Visteon to keep it running? It's basically on its own from your standpoint.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Visteon is a stand-alone company. And like all our suppliers, we talk to them -- we talk to our suppliers when they have problems and try and work with them. But they're a stand-alone company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And do you anticipate in the structural costs that that would include more involuntary layoffs and plant idling, or where would that focus in on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it really, Jeff, is going to be determined by the market and the industry, and the volumes going forward. We're about where we need to be right now, but we're going to -- like we have, we're going to monitor it very closely and take decisive action. Because the most important thing we do is, is measure our production and real demand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Tom Krisher representing Associated Press. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello gentlemen. I --.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>-- was just wondering if -- has the restructuring, your $4 billion structural cost reductions for '09. Does that include anything you might net out of the Treasury Department's demands that you're trying to seek parity with Chrysler and GM?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, there are no demands on Ford, while we don't request our government's assistance. The demands on Ford are self-induced to remain competitive. And anything we do to improve our competitiveness will go towards achieving or overachieving on the 4 billion cost reduction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the 30,000 units of production that you plan to take out beyond your prior estimates. How would you achieve that? Would that be any plant closures or is that line rate reductions and more gradual things, since it's a relatively smaller number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is a relatively small day-to-day production adjustment. It's, it'll be a bit of downtime, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Amy Wilson, representing Automotive News. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Amy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I wanted to ask, when is the soonest that you think you can get the DOE funds and how much would you expect to get in an initial disbursement there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't know the exact timing of that, Amy. But I think it's going to be relatively soon. We -- the feedback we've gotten is that, we're in very good shape with our submittal, our enabling technology is very much lined up with the intent of the 2007 Energy Independence and Security Act. So we're continuing answering questions for clarification, but I think that'll be relatively soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And as far as the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I can't give you an estimate on the amount yet, but I just may say that I think it's really meeting the intent of the Bill that was passed in 2007, because it really is going to help develop the enabling technology that the Congress really wanted to support. It will be substantial.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But so we understand correctly, it is something that could help bolster your liquidity position during this calendar year as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I just wanted to ask, why was the CapEx higher, 0.5 billion higher than the plan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mainly, completing the launch of the F-150.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that was more expensive than you had budgeted for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not so much that it was more expensive; but we -- as we continue to develop our whole product cycle plan, we just ended up where it was about, we wanted to spend that much to further solidify the product strategy going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>CapEx spending forecasting towards the year-end is really hard. Sometimes the bills pop over to the next year. When we set the objective, I think it was actually around at $6 billion and we're pretty close.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Robert Schoenberger representing The Plain Dealer. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  I have a technical question and a more serious one. Just on the technical side, jobs bank, how many people are in that right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About 1,500 right now. We expect that to reduce significantly in the first quarter, as some of those -- some people move to different plants where we have opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, at the Detroit show, Jim Farley had mentioned that January sales were looking a bit healthier than December. Has that trend continued or is there any hope for any kind of even modest recovery in the first few months of this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's about the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>About the same for as December or --?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As December, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of David Bailey.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can't hear David if he's online.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, are you on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, we didn't hear your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The question was, do you expect the Volvo books to go out in the next few weeks in terms of the potential sale of the brand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not giving any detail of the timetable of our exploring strategic options.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, it's a further question about -- about the supply base. Certainly we've talked a little bit about Visteon. But how much do you have -- have you broken out, how much money you expect to need to put into the supply base this year to keep it running, given the stresses you've discussed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of David Kiley representing BusinessWeek Magazine.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, David, have you driven a Ford lately?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I have as a matter of fact. The -- two questions here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One, on cash burn for the year, could you give -- the first question is if you could give me a little color on that, the 9.4 billion line item and exactly what that -- what goes into that. And then secondly, if you could -- if you could do a little color on how the production mix in the first quarter is going to impact cash burn. Because I believe that you're doing lot more truck and I wondered how that's going to impact your cash burn in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The $9.4 billion -- more than $5 million or about $5 billion was accounted for by our payable declines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, what are the declines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Trade payables.. So that's the biggest element of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> we're reducing the production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It really reflects the reduced production and the fact that the last few weeks of December, we had very little production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, I didn't hear your question on mix in the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. I wondered if you could, because you've said that your cash burn will be much improved. And I wondered in the first quarter; I believe that production of the F-Series is going to be a much more pronounced part of production in the first quarter. And I wondered a) if you can give some color on how that's going to impact cash burn and also what are your dealers telling you about demand for the new F-Series?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the bigger -- the bigger impact on cash burn in the first quarter will be around total production, the mix will be a secondary impact. And in terms of response from dealers, we're hearing very encouraging things about the reception of the F-150. Very, very high series mix which is encouraging. So, we've had an encouraging start.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dave, I might add just a little bit more color. One of the positive things about taken decisive and aggressive action in the fourth quarter on production to match the production to the real demand is that we kind of got that behind us now. And as we go along here at these -- stabilize at these lower rates for the first two quarters and then start to come back in the second half of the year; that really, really help us -- helps us significantly reduce the cash burn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to just sneak a quick one in here. The -- as far as dealing with the government right now, since you're not accessing loans per se but have this application outstanding for a line of credit, are you having to meet basically all the same parameters of financial viability, as GM and Chrysler are for the actual loans by February 17 and by March 31?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not at all. We're not in that process. We stay involved &#x2013; we'll continue to update them on our continuing restructuring of Ford. And also, I might just point out, David, at the end of the year, last year, the Treasury put in place an Automotive Financing Act or vehicle that the intent was that anybody that needed to see them to keep, without hurting the automotive recovery, there was a vehicle for them to come see them. So we don't have a standing line of credit, but we have a vehicle that if we ever need to access some money that we could use. Now we're not in that process, because we're not taking any taxpayer money.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />, we have time for one more question then please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your final question will come from the line of Joann Muller representing Forbes magazine. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Joann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Alan. You said that you still believe Ford doesn't have to access any government funds unless there's a significant event. Could you be a little more specific about what you would define as a significant event?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, because it could be many things. It could be the economy itself. It could be the industry. It could be share. It could be the Credit. We haven't scoped that out. The best thing we did during the -- as you know, during the hearings is that the Congress asked us for a range of outcomes, and so we gave them a range of three different outcomes that kind of bracketed the whole thing. And we're clearly moving along on the bottom side of that -- of those scenarios.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The bottom side of it, you said?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the first half and then coming back in the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to be clear, it sounds like he door is still wide open that you might need to go and ask for some assistance with so many things that you just ticked off there that could go the wrong way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's a very volatile time for all of us, but I think that with the actions that we're taking on the fiscal policy and the monetary policy that -- we think that's going to support the economic turnaround and it's not our plan at all to access the government money. And as we shared today, we put this plan in place two years ago, including the line of credit. And so we have sufficient cash to continue to finance our product development and our restructuring. So, we have no plans at this time to, or don't anticipate using the government funds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And one last thing on Ford Credit, you talk about it as a strategic asset. General Motors of course, as a result of the aid that GMAC got will no longer have a captive finance at all, I suppose you could argue that they didn't -- when they sold controlling interest. But nonetheless they're going to wind down to almost nothing. How do you think that would put Ford at an advantage to have its own strategic or captive finance company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we have believe more than ever, Joann that Ford Motor Credit is a strategic asset of the  Ford Motor Company. The dealers just absolutely love an integrated approach with being able to finance the cars and finance the showroom and have one-stop shopping; they're completely integrated when you work with Ford. So we're more positive than ever that Ford Motor Company is, really is a strategic asset for Ford.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Your write-downs, any idea what the total write-downs have been for credit losses over the last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>K.R. thinks they're going to do a credit call pretty soon. It might be good time to -- it'd be a good place with -- you'll have all of the experts there to cover credit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Watch out for that dog.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry about that, my colleagues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Joann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That concludes today's presentation. Thank you for joining us today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes your presentation. You may now disconnect. Good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>