<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1285229" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-01-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>198</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Brian Harris, Director of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Alan Mulally, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Lewis W. K. Booth, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Joseph Amaturo</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Lewis Booth</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">John Murphy</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Rod Lache</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep">K.R. Kent</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Brian Johnson</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Chris Ceraso</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Himanshu Patel</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Patrick Archambault</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Pat Archambault</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Bryce Hoffman</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Dee-Ann Durbin</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Brent Snavely</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Chris Isidore</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Joann Muller</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Jeff Bennett</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Fourth Quarter Ford Motor Company Earnings Conference Call. My name is Katina, and I will be your coordinator for today. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. As a reminder, this conference is being recorded for replay purposes. I would now like to turn the presentation over to your host for today's call, Mr. Brian Harris, Director of Investor Relations. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Katina, and good morning ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to all of you who are joining us today either by phone or webcast. On behalf of the entire Ford Management team I'd like to thank you for spending time with us this morning. With me here today are Alan Mulally, President and CEO of Ford Motor Company, and Lewis Booth, Chief Financial Officer. Also in attendance are: Bob Shanks, Vice President and Controller; Neil Schloss, Vice President and Treasurer; Paul Andonian, Director of Accounting; and K.R. Kent, Ford Credit CFO.</p>
          <p>Before we begin, I'd like to cover a few items. Copies of the mornings' press release and presentation slides we'll be using here today have been posted on Ford's Investor and Media website for your reference. The financial results discussed herein are presented on a preliminary basis. Final data will be included in our 2009 Form 10-K. Additionally, the financial results presented here are on a GAAP basis, and in some cases on a non-GAAP basis. The non-GAAP financial measures discussed in this call are reconciled to our GAAP equivalent as part of the appendix to the slide deck.</p>
          <p>Finally, today's presentation includes some forward-looking statements about our expectations of Ford's future performance. Actual results could differ materially from those suggested by our comments made here. Additional information about the factors that could affect future results is summarized at the end of this presentation. These factors are also detailed in our SEC filings, including our annual, quarterly and current reports.</p>
          <p>With that, I would now like to turn the presentation over to Ford's President and CEO, Mr. Alan Mulally.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Brian, and good morning, everyone. We are very pleased to be able to share today our fourth quarter and full year 2009 financial results.</p>
          <p>As you all know, 2009 was an extremely challenging year for the global automobile industry. For Ford it was also a pivotal year and the strongest proof yet that our One Ford plan is working, and we are forging a path toward profitable growth by working together as one team leveraging our global scale. Despite the deep economic downturn, historically weak sales, and the government-funded bankruptcies of our domestic competitors, Ford returned to profitability in 2009. For the full year, excluding special items we posted a pre-tax operating profit of 454 million, a 7.3 billion improvement over 2008, despite the decline in business conditions and lower worldwide revenues.</p>
          <p>On an after-tax basis, including special items, Ford's full year income was $2.7 billion. In addition we returned to positive automotive operating-related cash flow in the second half of the year, increased full year market share in North America, South America and Europe while continuing to improve transaction prices and margins, reduced automotive structural costs by 5.1 billion, exceeding our 2009 goal by over one billion, and made progress in strengthening our balance sheet. We finished the year with automotive gross cash of 25.5 billion, however we still have significantly higher debt on our books than our key competitors.</p>
          <p>Our North American operation posted a fourth quarter pre-tax operating profit, excluding special items, of $707 million, its second straight profitable quarter. As a result of our 2009 U.S. financial performance, we will pay profit sharing to 43,000 eligible U.S. hourly employees, consistent with the 2007 UAW Ford Collective Bargaining Agreement. The average amount is expected to be approximately $450 per eligible employee.</p>
          <p>Ford's product resurgence continued in 2009 with the launch of more cars and trucks our customers want and value, such as the Fusion Hybrid and the Transit Connect, recently named North American Car and Truck of the Year, respectively.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, while the business environment will remain difficult for the full year 2001, we plan to be profitable on a pre-tax basis, excluding special items, for North America, total automotive and total company, with positive automotive operating-related cash flows based on our assumptions. Our full year 2011 guidance remains unchanged also. We remain on track to be solidly profitable on a pre-tax basis, excluding special items, with positive automotive operating-related cash flows based on our assumptions.</p>
          <p>I will start off by providing you with an overview of our financial results and business, product and sales highlights. Then Lewis Booth will walk us through the financial results in even greater detail. Finally I will recap our 2009 performance, and summarize our 2010 outlook and our plan going forward.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide three, I'll begin by reviewing the key financial results. As shown at the top of the slide, vehicle wholesales in the fourth quarter were 1.4 million units, up 301,000 units from a year ago. Our fourth quarter revenue was 35.4 billion, a 6.4 billion increase from a year ago. The increase was more than explained by higher volumes and favorable net pricing. Our fourth quarter pre-tax operating profit, excluding special items, was about $1.8 million, a $5.5 billion improvement from a year ago. Automotive results improved by 4.4 billion, and Financial Services improved by 1.1 billion. Our fourth quarter net income attributable to Ford was 868 million, including unfavorable pre-tax special items of 711 million, a $6.8 million improvement over a year ago.</p>
          <p>For the full year, pre-tax operating profit, excluding special items, was 454 million, and net income attributable to Ford was 2.7 billion, despite revenues that declined by about $20 billion. We ended the year with 25.5 billion of automotive gross cash, up $12.1 billion from a year ago. This will be discussed in even more detail later.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to slide four. In addition to total company pre-tax operating results improving by 5.5 billion compared with the same period last year, results improved in all of our operations. We reduced our automotive structural costs by 500 million compared with fourth quarter of 2008, bringing full year structural cost reductions to 5.1 billion, which exceeded our goal in 2009 by over $1 billion.</p>
          <p>Ford North America had an operating profit of 707 million, a 2.6 billion improvement from a year ago. Ford South America had an operating profit of 369 million, a 264 million increase from a year ago. Ford Europe had an operating profit of 305 million, a 643 million improvement from a year ago. Ford Asia Pacific and Africa had an operating profit of 19 million, a 227 million improvement from a year ago. And Volvo had an operating loss of 32 million, but a 704 million improvement from a year ago. Finally Financial Services had an operating profit of 683 million, a 1.1 billion improvement from a year ago.</p>
          <p>Slide five details some of the key business highlights since our last earnings release. We announced a 2.3 billion investment in Brazil over five years. This underscores our commitment to modernizing our plants and expanding production in our profitable South American operation. Earlier this month, we signaled our plans for vehicle electrification when we announced a 450 million investment to build a next-generation hybrid and plug-in hybrid at our Michigan assembly plant and move the development and assembly of battery packs in-house at Ford. The investment will create 1,000 new jobs for the plant.</p>
          <p>On December 31 of 2009 we completed the transfer of our UAW retiree healthcare liabilities to the UAW Retiree Medical Benefits Trust or VEBA. As part of this, we transferred assets into the VEBA Trust and made a $500 million prepayment of our obligation to the VEBA Trust to reduce our debt.</p>
          <p>Another key move related to the balance sheet was completing our plan to amend and extend our revolving credit facility. Revolving lenders agreed to extend the maturity of $7.9 billion worth of debt commitments to 2013 from 2011. We issued $2.9 billion of convertible notes to continue to strengthen our balance sheet, a key pillar of our One Ford strategy.</p>
          <p>We also announced in December that we had settled all substantive terms on the sale of Volvo to Geely. We expect to reach the definitive sale agreement in the first quarter of 2010 with the closing of the sale likely to occur in the second quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>Turning to Slide Six, we'll look at Ford's product highlights since our last earnings release. Ford unveiled the 2011 Fiesta for the U.S. market at the Los Angeles Auto Show in November. Production begins later this quarter. The Fiesta is off to a very strong start in Europe and in Asia with sales of about 600,000 vehicles since the vehicle was launched in Europe in late 2008 and in Asia in early 2009.</p>
          <p>We were honored with both the North American Car and Truck of the Year awards. Media voted the 2010 Fusion Hybrid as Car of the Year and the 2010 Transit Connect as Truck of the Year at the North American International Auto Show. The Fusion also won Motor Trend's prestigious 2010 Car of the Year award topping a field of 23 contenders.</p>
          <p>Our next-generation Ford Focus ECOnetic was launched during the quarter in Europe, delivering even lower CO2 emission.</p>
          <p>At the Brussels Motor Show, we unveiled refreshed versions of the S-MAX Crossover and the Galaxy MPV for Europe with high-efficiency engines and more distinctive designs. The vehicles go on sale in the spring of 2010.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, we launched the new Ford Focus 1.6-liter Flex, a hatchback with the new Sigma Flex Fuel engine, and the Ford Ikon sedan led its segment in a J.D. Power study of initial quality for the Indian market.</p>
          <p>On slide seven, I'll cover Ford's fourth quarter and full year sales highlights, our strong product lineup drove full year market share gains in North America, South America and Europe, while maintaining share in the rapidly growing Asia Pacific and Africa region. In addition we continue making improvements in transaction prices and in margins.</p>
          <p>In the U.S. Ford, Lincoln and Mercury fourth quarter sales were up 13% versus a year ago, leading to Ford's first full year market share gain since 1995. Fusion sales rose 22%, setting a new annual record, while the F-Series was the number one selling truck for the 33rd straight year and the number one selling vehicle for 28 consecutive years.</p>
          <p>In South America, Ford Brazil had its best ever full year sales, thanks to a 15% increase in 2009. Sales for Ford Europe increased 19% in the fourth quarter, led by the Fiesta, Focus and Ka. Ford strengthens its position in Europe to number two brand. Full year market share in the region of 9.1% increased 0.5 point, setting an 11-year high. Fiesta climbed to a number two, best-selling spot in the region in 2009. Fourth quarter sales for Ford Asia Pacific and Africa rose 53%. Full year sales were up 15% in the region, and making an annual record. Ford sales in China led the full-year increase, up 45% from year-ago levels.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to turn it over to Lewis to provide even more details on our fourth quarter financial results. Lewis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Alan. Let's move on to slide nine, which provides more detail on the financial results. Our fourth quarter pre-tax operating profit, excluding special items, was about $1.8 billion, a $5.5 billion improvement from a year ago. Most of the remaining slides will focus on these pre-tax operating results.</p>
          <p>Our pre-tax operating profit excludes unfavorable special items and $711 million, which we'll cover on the next slide, and we recognized $109 million of tax expense on 65 million of our income was related to non-controlling interests. Bottom line, fourth quarter net income attributable to Ford was $868 million, a $6.8 billion improvement from a year ago.</p>
          <p>For the full year pre-tax operating profit, excluding special items, was $454 million, a $7.3 billion improvement from a year ago. Full year net income attributable to Ford was $2.7 billion, which included about $2.6 billion of special item net gains as discussed on the next slide.</p>
          <p>As mentioned last quarter, a new accounting standard effective January 1, 2010 relating to consolidation of variable interest entities will require us to deconsolidate many of our joint ventures.  This will have no effect on net income attributable to Ford and it is expected to have minimal impact on cash flow.  This change however is estimated to reduce our full year 2010 pre-tax operating and business segment results by 350 to $400 million.  Our 2010 first quarter earnings review will provide additional information on this accounting standard change.</p>
          <p>Slide 10 covers special items which were unfavorable pre-tax amounts of $711 million in the fourth quarter.  We recorded $346 million for retiree healthcare and related charges reflecting primarily a net loss on the settlement of the UAW Retiree Healthcare VEBA Agreement, and this will be covered in more detail on the next slide.  We recorded a charge of $296 million for job security benefits explained primarily by reserve increase related to the announced closure of St. Thomas plant next year, and additional global personal reduction charges of $173 million.</p>
          <p>Also we record $134 million of held for sale accounting related adjustments for Volvo, reflecting the elimination of depreciation and related costs.  Based on our plan to sell Volvo, beginning in the first quarter of 2010 all of Volvo's financial results will be reported as special items and excluded from our operating results.</p>
          <p>For the full year, pre-tax special items were a net gain of about $2.6 billion which is more than explained by $4.7 billion of gains on debt reduction actions, offset partially by global personnel reduction actions and the UAW Retiree Healthcare VEBA settlement.</p>
          <p>Slide 11 provides an update to our UAW Retiree Healthcare and OPEB liabilities.  On December 31, 2009 we completed the transfer of our UAW Retiree Healthcare liabilities to the UAW Retiree Medical Benefits Trust or VEBA.  Assets were transferred to the trust and our obligations were irrevocably settled.  At settlement a net loss of $264 million was recognized reflecting the 2009 amended UAW VEBA Agreement and the fair value of assets transferred on December 31, 2009.</p>
          <p>Settlement of the obligation reduced our global OPEB liabilities by about $10 billion from $16 billion at year end 2008 to $6 billion at year end 2009.  The remaining amount is related primarily to U.S. salaried health care and U.S. hourly life insurance liabilities.</p>
          <p>As discussed last quarter, incremental tax of about $7 billion was reported on the balance sheet, reflecting the remaining fair value of the notes under the 2009 amended agreement after initial payments of $2 billion and a prepayment of $500 million made on December 31, 2009. 2010 interest expense related to this debt is now projected at about $600 million. This interest expense is included in our scheduled payments for the notes. 2009 global OPEB cash benefit payments were $1.6 billion including $1.1 billion for UAW retiree health care.</p>
          <p>Slide 12, excuse me, provides an update on our pension plans. Worldwide 2009 pension expense excluding special items was $600 million, up $100 million from 2008, reflecting primarily returns on lower 2008 year-end asset balances. In 2009 we made $900 million in cash contributions to our worldwide funded pension plans, down $800 million from 2008. Pension contributions made in 2008 included $600 million related to the sale of Jaguar Land Rover. At year-end 2009 our U.S. funded plans were underfunded by $4.6 billion and worldwide our pension plans were underfunded by $12 billion. We do not have a requirement to fund our major U.S. pension plans in 2010.</p>
          <p>Now on to Slide 13 which shows our pre-tax operating results by sector, our fourth quarter pre-tax operating results were a profit of about $1.8 billion. These results include a profit of $1.1 billion for the Automotive sector and a profit of $683 million for Financial Services. As Alan mentioned and as shown in the memo, total company fourth quarter pre-tax operating results improved by $5.5 billion compared with the same period last year. Our results also improved by $646 million compared to the third quarter of 2009. Our full-year pre-tax operating results were a profit of $454 million which included losses of $1.4 billion for the Automotive sector, offset by a profit of $1.9 billion for Financial Services. As shown in the memo, total company full-year pre-tax operating results improved by $7.3 billion compared with 2008.</p>
          <p>Let's move to Slide 14 which shows fourth quarter pre-tax operating results for each of our Automotive segments and Other Automotive. In the fourth quarter almost all of our business segments reported a profit for the quarter and showed significant improvement compared with a year ago, and compared with third quarter 2009 as shown in the memo. We'll cover the Automotive segment in more detail on the upcoming slides.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter Other Automotive loss was $298 million, reflecting primarily net interest expense of $292 million, which is comprised of about $350 million of interest expense, offset partially by net gains associated with our investment portfolio and interest income.</p>
          <p>Slide 15 shows the change in fourth quarter pre-tax operating results compared with 2008 by causal factor. Overall, fourth quarter results improved by $4.4 billion compared with a year ago. Volume and mix was $1.7 billion favorable, explained primarily by an increase in dealer stocks to match demand for our products, higher global industry volumes and market-share improvements.</p>
          <p>Net pricing was $1.7 billion favorable, explained by improvements across all of our business segments, including our continued disciplined approach on incentives and selective top line pricing in the U.S. Costs decreased by $1.7 billion, reflecting primarily lower raw material costs, including the non-recurrence of unfavorable mark-to-market adjustments on commodity hedges and structural cost reductions.</p>
          <p>Exchange was $800 million unfavorable, related primarily to North America, which consists of balance sheet valuation adjustments, and in South America, which was explained primarily by unfavorable exchange in Argentina and Venezuela. Net interest and fair market value adjustments were essentially flat. Lower interest expense, primarily associated with our debt restructuring actions were largely offset by the non-recurrence of favorable fair market value adjustments.</p>
          <p>Slide 16 shows full year, pre-tax operating results for each of our Automotive segments and for Other Automotive. For the full year, automotive pre-tax operating losses were $1.4 billion. As shown in the memo, this loss was greatly reduced compared with a year ago. We'll be discussing it in more detail on the next slide. Full year Other Automotive loss was $1.1 billion, reflecting primarily a net interest expense of $1.2 billion, which is comprised of over $1.5 billion of interest expense offset partially by net gains associated with our investment portfolio and interest income.</p>
          <p>Moving to Slide 17, which shows a change in full year, pre-tax operating results compared to 2008 by causal factor. Overall full-year results improved by about $5 billion compared with a year ago. Volume and mix was $3.7 billion unfavorable, explained primarily by a significant decline in global industry volumes, a reduction in dealer stocks and lower component sales which more than offset the favorable mix.</p>
          <p>These declines were offset partially by market share improvements. Market share improvements reflected primarily 1.1 percentage point increase in the U.S. and half-point gains in both Europe and in South America.</p>
          <p>Net pricing was $5.5 billion favorable, explained by improvements across all of our business segments and the success of our product lineup around the globe. A significant portion of the net pricing improvement was in the U.S. as we maintained our disciplined approach on incentives and selected top line pricing and continued to manage our production and dealer stocks in line with demand.</p>
          <p>Costs decreased by $5.8 billion, explained primarily by $5.1 billion of structural cost reductions which we'll discuss in more detail on the next slide and lower material costs including the non-recurrence of unfavorable commodity hedge adjustments. Exchange was $2.1 billion unfavorable, explained primarily by North America, South America and Europe. The net interest and fair market value adjustments were $200 million favorable explained by lower interest expense offset partially by lower favorable fair market value adjustments.</p>
          <p>Now to Slide 18 which explains our full year automotive structural cost reductions of $5.1 billion including, as shown in the memo, $500 million improvement in the fourth quarter. For the full year manufacturing and engineering costs were $2.7 billion lower reflecting largely the continued benefits of improved productivity, personnel reductions primarily in North America and Europe, and progress on implementation of common global platforms and product development processes.</p>
          <p>Spending related costs improved by $600 million reflecting primarily lower depreciation and amortization expense included the impact of prior year asset impairments. Pension and retiree healthcare expenses were $800 million lower, reflecting primarily the effect of the UAW Retiree Healthcare VEBA Agreements. Overhead cost was $400 million lower which included salaried personnel reductions and other restructuring actions. And finally advertising sales promotions were $600 million lower than a year ago. As mentioned last quarter, we have achieved significant structural cost reductions over the past four years. Going forward, as we increase production to meet demand we expect automotive structural cost to increase somewhat.</p>
          <p>For the next section of slides we'll cover each of the automotive segments starting with North America on Slide 19. In the fourth quarter wholesales were 631,000 units, up 147,000 units from a year ago reflecting primarily an increase in dealer stocks and market share improvements.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter U.S. total market share for Ford, Lincoln and Mercury were 16.1%, up 1.1 points from a year ago, which will be discussed in more detail later. Although not shown, Canada total market share was 15.3%, up 1.5 points from a year ago. And fourth quarter revenue was $15.8 billion, a $4.5 billion or 40% increase from a year ago, reflecting primarily higher volumes and favorable net pricing. And for the fourth quarter, Ford North America reported a pre-tax operating profit of $707 million, a $2.6 billion improvement from a year ago, which we'll cover in more detail on the next slide.</p>
          <p>Slide 20 provides an explanation of the change in North America results compared with 2008 by causal factor. Volume and mix was $1.3 billion favorable, reflecting primarily higher dealer stocks to match demand for our products, favorable series mix for F-Series and Taurus, market share improvements and higher U.S. industry volumes. Net pricing was $1.1 billion favorable, reflecting primarily the success of our new products, selective top line pricings and our continued disciplined approach to incentives.</p>
          <p>Costs decreased by $800 million, reflecting primarily lower raw material costs, including the non-recurrence of unfavorable mark-to-market adjustments on commodity hedges, lower warranty costs, reflecting primarily the non-recurrence of unfavorable warranty reserve adjustments and structural cost reductions.</p>
          <p>Exchange was $600 million unfavorable, reflecting primarily the balance sheet impact of the weaker U.S. dollar relative to the Canadian dollar. And for the full year, as shown in the memo, Ford North America reported a pre-tax operating loss of $400 million, a $5.5 billion improvement from a year ago. The improvement reflected primarily favorable net pricing, structural cost reductions, favorable mix, and market share improvements, offset partially by lower industry volumes and unfavorable exchange.</p>
          <p>On Slide 21 shows U.S. market share for Ford, Lincoln and Mercury. In the fourth quarter, U.S. total market share was 16.1%, up 1.1 points from a year ago, reflecting primarily higher share for Fusion, Taurus and Escape. Additionally retail share of the retail industry was an estimated 13.8% in the fourth quarter, up 0.7 point from a year ago, the highest for any quarter since the third quarter of 2006.</p>
          <p>For the full year U.S. total market share was 15.3%, up 1.1 points from a year ago.  This improvement marked our first full-year market share increase in the U.S. since 1995 and reflected primarily higher retail share resulting from demand for Fusion, Escape and the F-150. Although not shown, Canada total market share was 15.2% for the full year, up 2.6 points from a year ago, the highest for any year since 2001. Our market share improvement in 2009 made Ford the bestselling brand in Canada. Growing awareness and consideration for Ford products has enabled the company to achieve these market share gains while reducing incentives. In addition, customers equipped their products with higher levels of content and technology which further contributed to higher transaction prices for most Ford products.</p>
          <p>Now on to South America on slide 22. In the fourth quarter wholesales were 131,000 units, up 33,000 units from a year ago, reflecting primarily an increase in dealer stocks and higher industry volumes, offset partially by lower market share. Fourth quarter market share was 9.7%, down six-tenths of a point from a year ago. Although not shown, full-year market share was 10.2%, a half-point gain from a year ago.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter revenues were $2.6 billion, a $900 million increase from a year ago, reflecting primarily higher volumes and favorable net price. For the fourth quarter, Ford South America recorded a pre-tax operating profit of $369 million, a $264 million increase from a year ago. This increase is more than explained by favorable net pricing and higher volume and mix, offset partially by unfavorable exchange in Argentina and Venezuela. For the full year, as shown in the memo, Ford South America reported a pre-tax operating profit of $765 million, a $465 million decrease from a year ago. This decrease reflected primarily unfavorable exchange and higher material costs, offset partially by favorable net pricing.</p>
          <p>Slide 23 covers Europe. In the fourth quarter wholesales were 432,000 units, up 54,000 units from a year ago, reflecting primarily higher European industry volumes and market share improvements in the 19 markets that we track. Fourth quarter industry SAAR for the 19 markets that we track was 16.6 million units, up 1.8 million units from a year ago, driven primarily by scrappage programs, and fourth quarter market share was 8.9%, up four-tenths of a point from last year, driven by the strength of the Fiesta, the Focus and the Ka. Fourth quarter revenue was $8.7 billion, a $1.1 billion increase from a year ago, reflecting primarily higher volumes and favorable exchange translation, offset partially by unfavorable product mix.</p>
          <p>For the fourth quarter Ford Europe reported a pre-tax operating profit of $305 million, a $643 million improvement from a year ago, which we'll cover in more detail on the next slide.</p>
          <p>Slide 24 provides an explanation of the change in Europe results compared to 2008 by causal factor. Volume and mix was unchanged. Higher European industry volumes and market share improvements in the 19 major markets were offset by unfavorable product mix and lower industry volumes in Russia and Eastern Europe. Net pricing was $200 million favorable, reflecting primarily pricing in Britain and Russia to offset unfavorable currency effects. Costs decreased by $500 million, reflecting primarily lower material costs, including commodities and structural cost reductions. And exchange was $100 million unfavorable, reflecting primarily the weakening of the British pound compared with the euro.</p>
          <p>For the full year, as shown in the memo, Ford Europe reported a pre-tax operating profit of about $100 million, a $1 billion decrease from a year ago. The decrease reflected primarily lower industry volumes, unfavorable product mix, in part due to government scrappage programs, and lower dealer stocks, offset partially by structural cost reductions.</p>
          <p>Slide 25 covers Asia Pacific and Africa. In the fourth quarter wholesales were 146,000 units, up 47,000 units from a year ago, reflecting primarily strong performance in China, which was up 34,000 units. Fourth quarter industry SAAR was 28 million units, up 10.1 million units from a year ago, explained primarily by a 94% increase in the Chinese industry. And fourth quarter market share was 2%, roughly unchanged.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter revenues, which excludes sales at our unconsolidated China joint ventures was $1.6 billion, a $200 million increase from a year ago. The increase was more than explained by higher volumes outside of China and favorable net pricing. For the fourth quarter, Asia Pacific and Africa reported a pre-tax operating profit of $19 million, a $227 million improvement from a year ago. The improvement reflects primarily favorable net pricing, higher China joint-venture profits and structural cost reductions. For the full year, as shown in the memo, Asia Pacific and Africa reported a pre-tax operating loss of $75 million, a $78 million improvement from a year ago. This improvement was more than explained by structural cost reductions and favorable net pricing offset partially by low volumes outside of China.</p>
          <p>Slide 26 covers Volvo. In the fourth quarter wholesales were 100,000 units, up 20,000 units from a year ago reflecting primarily higher industry volumes and market share improvements. Fourth quarter market share in the U.S. was 0.6% and share in Euro was 1.5% both higher than a year ago. Fourth quarter revenue was $3.9 billion, a $600 million increase from a year ago explained primarily by higher volumes. For the fourth quarter Volvo reported a pre-tax operating loss of $32 million, a $704 million improvement from a year ago, explained primarily by structural cost reductions, higher volume and mix, favorable net pricing and lower material costs, offset partially by unfavorable exchange. For the full year, as shown in the memo, Volvo reported a pre-tax operating loss of $653 million an $812 million improvement from a year ago.</p>
          <p>The improvement was more than explained by structural cost reductions, favorable exchange and lower material costs, offset partially by lower industry volumes. Overall, based on significant improvements in 2009, Volvo is on track with its plan to return to fundamental health supported by a strong product pipeline. As mentioned earlier based on our plan to sell Volvo all of its financial results will be reported as special items and excluded from our operating results in 2010.</p>
          <p>Slide 27 shows automotive gross cash and operating-related cash flow. We ended the year with $25.5 billion in automotive gross cash, up $1.7 billion from the end of the third quarter 2009. Our automotive operating-related cash flow was $3.1 billion in the fourth quarter, reflecting an automotive pre-tax operating profit of $1.1 billion. Capital expenditure in the quarter there was $100 million lower than depreciation and amortization, changes in working capital and other timing differences that were $2.3 billion positive. This was explained primarily by favorable working capital of about $800 million and other timing differences related to end-of-year production shutdowns. Additional favorable timing differences and marketing payments and one-time tax refunds were offset partially by unfavorable timing differences for healthcare payments and finally the payment of $400 million to Ford Credit, reflecting an upfront payment of subvention.</p>
          <p>Based on the cost of operating-related cash flows during the third and fourth quarter, our full year operating related cash outflow was $300 million. Other major changes in fourth quarter automotive gross cash include payments of $2.5 billion on notes and amounts due to the new VEBA, including a prepayment of $500 million, for a net $1.9 billion repayment related to our revolving line of credit extension as we restructured the commitments to extend maturities to December 2013. Equity-issuance proceeds related to our revolving line of credit extension, sorry equity-issuance proceeds related primarily to our recently-announced plan to issue up to $1 billion of equity, and additional cash inflows of $2.8 million, sorry; $2.8 billion were more than explained by the issuance of convertible debt. Including these impacts, the total increase in automotive gross cash during the fourth quarter was $1.7 billion.</p>
          <p>Slide 28 describes changes in automotive debt during the fourth quarter. We ended the year with $34.3 billion of automotive debt, an increase of $7.4 billion from September 30. Significant changes in our debt balance include, as previously discussed, we concluded our agreement to transfer our UAW Retiree Healthcare liabilities to the VEBA Trust. As part of this agreement, we issued two notes, which after making $2.5 billion of payments on December 31, 2009, including a $500 million prepayment, had a fair value of $7 billion.</p>
          <p>We entered into an agreement with our lenders to reduce and extend to 2013 from 2011 most of our secured revolver credit facility. As a result of the agreement, thee extended revolving facility was reduced by $2.6 billion, of which $1.9 billion was repaid and $700 million was converted to a new term loan. At yearend we had $7.5 billion outstanding with the extended and non-extended, revolving assets. In addition we issued $2.9 billion principle amount of convertible debt maturing in November 2016. This debt has little carrying value of $2.2 billion.</p>
          <p>Slide 29 summarizes our Automotive sector's cash and debt position. At the end of the fourth quarter, automotive debt was $34.3 billion, of which $2 billion matures during 2010. Our gross cash net of debt as of December 31, was $8.8 billion negative. As mentioned earlier, the adoption of a new accounting standard related to consolidation will require us to deconsolidate many of our joint ventures. This will result in about $550 million of cash &#x2013; sorry, this will result in about $550 million of cash and about $800 million of debt being deconsolidated in the first quarter of 2010. The decrease in debt includes about $500 million of debt obligations maturing during 2010.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to slide 30 on Financial Services. For the fourth quarter, the Financial Services sector reported pre-tax operating profit of $683 million, a $1.1 billion improvement from the year ago. For the full-year pre-tax operating profit &#x2013; for the full year, the pre-tax operating profit was $1.9 billion, a $2.4 billion improvement from the year ago. Other Financial Services reported a pre-tax operating loss of $13 million in the fourth quarter, a $1 million decline from a year ago. For the full year, the pre-tax operating loss was $106 million, an $84 million decline from a year ago. This decline is related primarily to real estate transactions. For the fourth quarter Ford Credit reported a pre-tax operating profit of $696 million, a $1.1 billion improvement from a year ago, which we'll cover in more detail on the next slide.</p>
          <p>Slide 31 provides an explanation of the change in Ford Credit results compared to 2008 by causal factor. Volume was $200 million unfavorable, reflecting declining receivables. As shown in the memo, in the lower left of the slide, Ford Credit's December 31, 2009 managed receivables were $95 billion, $23 billion lower than a year ago. This decline is explained primarily by lower industry volumes, lower dealer stocks and the impact of divestitures and alternative business arrangements.</p>
          <p>Financing margin improved by $100 million, reflecting primarily lower borrowing costs and the decline in the provision for credit losses of $500 million reflects primarily a higher credit loss reserve release and lower charge-offs, and residual values declined by &#x2013; sorry, residual losses declined by $500 million, reflecting primarily the impact of higher auction values on vehicles returned during the quarter, and other was $200 million favorable. This is more than explained by the non-recurrence in net losses related to market reduction adjustments to derivatives and lower operating costs.</p>
          <p>For the full year, Ford Credit reported a pre-tax operating profit of just $2 billion, a $2.5 billion improvement from a year ago. This improvement reflects primarily lower depreciation expense on leased vehicles due to higher auction values and a lower provision for credit losses, offset partially by lower volumes. We expect Ford Credit to be profitable in 2010 but lower than 2009 based on lower average receivables and the non-recurrence of certain favorable 2009 factors.</p>
          <p>Slide 32 covers the liquidity and funding outlook for Ford Credit. The left box shows Ford Credit's committed liquidity programs in cash and the utilization of this liquidity sources at the end of the fourth quarter. Ford Credit's liquidity exceeded utilization by about $21 billion. We continue to see positive momentum for the third consecutive quarter ever since by improved market access and credit spreads.</p>
          <p>In 2009 Ford Credit issued about $5 billion of public unsecured debt that completes about $15 billion of public securitizations including a non-health retail securitization transaction of $1.6 billion in November. Outside of the United States Ford Credit has executed its funding plans by completing securitizations and issuing unsecured debt in both public and private markets. Ford Credit remains dependent upon capital market access for its funding strategy and will continue to extend the term securitization and unsecured funding.</p>
          <p>Ford Credit plans to a new committed capacity consistent with the size of its balance sheet and will continue to explore and execute alternative business and funding arrangements in those locations where it lacks diverse funding capability. Ford Credit's funding strategy remains focused on maintaining liquidity to meet short-term funding obligations including holding a substantial cash balance. At the end of the fourth quarter, Ford Credit's managed leverage was 7.3 to 1 and Ford Credit's equity was about $11 billion.</p>
          <p>Slide 33 covers our first quarter 2010 production volumes. In North America the first quarter production schedule was 570,000 units, up 221,000 units from a year ago and up 20,000 units from our prior guidance. In South America the first quarter production schedule is 111,000 units, up 12,000 units from a year ago. For Ford Europe we expect first quarter production of 440,000 units, up 97,000 units from a year ago. And for Ford Asia Pacific and Africa we expect first quarter production of 147,000 units, up 49,000 units from a year ago. And at Volvo we expect first quarter production of 93,000 units, up 25,000 units &#x2013; sorry; up 28,000 units from a year ago. Overall the first quarter production increase from a year ago reflects strong customer demand for our products, and the non-recurrence of prior year dealer stock declines.</p>
          <p>And now I'd like to turn it back to Alan, to recap our 2009 performance, and summarize our 2010 outlook and our plan going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much, Lewis.</p>
          <p>Slide 35 provides an overview of the business environment. Global economic conditions are improving, but remain fragile. Modest recoveries in some markets are held back by weak labor markets and tight credit. The consumer spending outlook for the U.S. and Europe remains weak, with below trend growth likely in 2010. In addition our suppliers and dealers have been weakened by the impacts of the global economic downturn. With the worst of the financial crisis now subsiding, global central banks are likely to remove some stimulus by retiring special lending programs and begin modest policy interest rate increases. Even with this, interest rates are likely to remain relatively low in 2010 and supportive of the economic recovery. Upward pressure on commodity prices has resumed in conjunction with the emergence of an economic recovery. This trend is likely to continue in 2010.</p>
          <p>Our business continues to be affected by currency volatility. Recently the U.S. dollar has gained some ground against the British pound and the euro. Global industry volume last year is estimated at 64 million units, down around 6% compared to 2008. This reflected weak conditions in the U.S. market, with more modest declines in Europe, owing to substantial scrappage programs. For 2010 we expect to see a gradual improvement in global industry volumes, but significant uncertainties remain. As a result of the very effective 2009 European scrappage programs, there is expected to be substantial payback in 2010, particularly in Germany. We expect to see continued growth in Asia-Pacific markets in 2010, supported by a robust economic performance in that region also.</p>
          <p>Now, on Slide 36, which shows the results of our 2009 full year key planning assumptions and our operational metrics, industry volume was 10.6 million units in the U.S. and 15.8 million units in Europe, basically consistent with our previous guidance. On the automotive operational metrics, U.S. Ford, Lincoln and Mercury brand vehicles had the fewest number of things gone wrong among all automakers. International results remain mixed, as Europe continues to address a few issues. This showed a 6% improvement in things gone wrong compared with third quarter of 2009. Automotive structural costs were reduced by 5.1 billion for the full year, exceeding our full-year target of $4 billion. U.S. total market share was 15.3%. Our share of the U.S. retail market was 13.1%, and Europe market share was 9.1%, all improved compared with 2008, reflecting the success of our strong product lineup.</p>
          <p>Automotive operating-related cash flow was 300 million negative in addition to our improved profitability. This substantial change from 2008 reflected in part a large increase in payables as we returned to balances closer to normal and inventory reductions to lower ongoing levels. Capital expenditures were 4.5 billion, the decrease from our initial guidance, largely reflects efficiency. Our product plans remain intact. On the next slide we will summarize our 2010 outlook.</p>
          <p>Slide 37. We expect full year industry sales to be in the range of 11.5 to 12.5 million units in the U.S. and 13.5 to 14.5 million units in Europe. On the automotive operational metrics, we will continue to improve quality. As mentioned earlier, we have achieved significant structural cost reductions over the past four years, and going forward we expect automotive structural costs to be somewhat higher as we increase production to meet the demand. We anticipate our full year U.S. total market share, and our share of the U.S. retail market to be equal or improved compared to 2009. Europe market share is expected to be about equal to 2009. Automotive operating-related cash flow is expected to be positive, but less than the run rate implied by the strong second half 2009 cash flow. Recent performance was heavily influenced by seasonal factors, including normal year-end inventory reductions and significant non-recurring factors, such as tax refunds and higher production to rebuild depleted dealer stocks.</p>
          <p>Capital spending is expected to be in the range of 4.5 to $5 billion as we continue to focus on our product plan. This plan essentially excludes Volvo and joint ventures that will be deconsolidated. On a comparable basis, 2010 capital spending is up about $1 billion from 2009. For the full year 2010 we plan to be profitable on a pre-tax basis, excluding special items, for North America, total automotive and total company, with positive automotive operating-related cash flow based on our assumptions.</p>
          <p>Our full year 2011 guidance remains unchanged. We remain on track to be solidly profitable on a pre-tax basis excluding special items with positive automotive operating cash flow.</p>
          <p>Slide 38 summarizes the key aspects of our plan going forward. These clearly have not changed. To sum up, we are proud the way the entire Ford team worked together to deliver results in the fourth quarter and all of 2009 including substantial improvements in profitability and cash flow across all of our business segments. Our reputation for producing best-in-class vehicles is growing around the world as evidenced by our market share growth in most of our major markets and by our improved pricing performance.</p>
          <p>In 2010 we will continue our momentum with plans to deliver substantially more new or refreshed products than we did last year even though last year was very active in terms of car, crossover and truck new launches. This year we will bring the market more products that people want with class-leading fuel economy, quality, safety and technology. This will include products like the Fiesta, redesigned Edge and Lincoln MKX and Super Duty in the U.S., the Figo in India, the new C-MAX and updated versions of the S-MAX, Mondeo and Galaxy in Europe. In addition, we will begin production of the new Explorer in the U.S.</p>
          <p>In 2010 we're also focused on continuing to lead with efficient and world-class powertrains. Ford will continue to introduce nine new and upgraded engines and transmissions in North America as part of our five-year effort to overhaul the entire global powertrain portfolio. By the end of this year, nearly all of Ford's North American engines will have been upgraded or replaced since 2008.</p>
          <p>Ford's transformation, however, remains a work in progress and is far from complete. The economy remains soft in many areas of the world and the global auto industry continues to wrestle with excess vehicle capacity, volatile commodity prices and a fragile supply base. As we look at the work we have left to do, we are more confident than ever that our plan provides a solid blueprint to transform Ford into a lean company that delivers profitable growth for all of its stakeholders.</p>
          <p>And now we will be happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alan. Ladies and gentlemen, we are now going to start the Q&amp;A session. We have about 35 minutes for the question-and-answer period. We will begin with questions from the investment community and then take questions from the media who are also on the call. In order to allow as much time as possible for questions within our timeframe, please keep your questions brief.</p>
          <p>Katina, can we have the first question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from the line of Joe Amaturo representing Buckingham Research. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Joe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One question, Alan. You did a very good job with net pricing in 2009 and I was just wondering what approach you expect to take in 2010 particularly given some of the current events with one of your major North American competitors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well the initial answer to that question, Joe, is that we are very pleased to see the customers appreciating the value that we are incorporating in all of our vehicles. So as we go forward as you well know we are continually improving the breadth of our product line plus the quality so we anticipate that the customers will continue to value that. With respect to last year itself we think it'll be a little bit less than we experienced last year but clearly that'll be balanced against the value that will be increasing for the new products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Then one other, Lewis, maybe you could explain this exchange issue and how much of it was due to the Canadian dollar particularly as it relates to the North American automotive performance? And then what you would expect in 2010 or what we should expect in 2010 as it relates to FX?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Most of the effect was the Canadian dollar and it was balance sheet adjustments. I don't know, Joe. I'm not really prepared to guess what we would expect for next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess I should probably ask you a little differently. I mean do you have any hedges in place as it relates to foreign exchange or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have some hedges on intercompany loans but not on balance sheet assessments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you and excellent quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot, Joe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Joe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Take care.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of John Murphy representing Bank of America &#x2013; Merrill Lynch.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Alan, we have a pretty good view of what happens at the end of the purchase funnel obviously in the numbers we're seeing on a monthly basis but at the beginning in that consideration set, I wonder if you could just highlight what you're seeing maybe statistically or whatever comments you can make on the expansion of the consideration set for Ford products that will ultimately lead to the execution of the sale?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, you bet. Well, it's a pretty neat story, John, as I know you know, because the Ford brand has always had tremendous recognition and one of the most recognized brands around the world.  And the neatest thing is that with the proof points, especially on the product side, the complete family, the best-in-class on quality and fuel efficiency and safety, and the neat features on each one of the new vehicles, and of course the value proposition is that we're seeing a dramatic improvement in the favorability, which is the next step on the purchase funnel. And we're starting to see that improve all the way through the funnel now. And the more the people appreciate, especially this complete family of vehicles now, that we've had that on the SUVs and the trucks as you know, but what's really moving very fast is the appreciation for the small or mid-sized cars and utility. So an upward trend that we anticipate will continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then second, just staying on the product, you've got the Explorer and the Super Duty launching in the second half of this year, which should be pretty favorable for mix. But obviously the Fiesta would be a mix down. In general would looking at mix in 2010 versus 2009 as about neutral be a fair assessment? Or how should we think about mix? Or how are you thinking about mix in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Let me just kind of look at some data. The Super Duty, just to make sure that we're together, is second quarter and the Explorer is in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay? Which is a part of your answer also is that we're seeing continuing strong demand for all the segments of our product line, and I think it just gets even more enhanced as we add some more of the small or medium-sized vehicles. So I think overall I'd say about the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just one Ford Motor...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, that's probably a bit bad, because the Explorer comes in right at the very end of the year. We really don't get much production. So I think we're going to see the impact of Fiesta more than we're going to see the impact of Explorer. So I think we're going to see a bit of adverse product mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But that Super Duty is launching in the second quarter, so you get almost three quarters of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Lewis, just on Ford Motor Credit continuing to outperform here, used car pricing is fading a little bit, but it's not dropping off. So some of that lease stuff sounds like it should be reasonably good this year. But we're also seeing your securitizations being upsized, spreads tightening. What is &#x2013; I mean how should we think about this? Because I understand there are some factors that are not repeatable, but you're doing five, 600 million in pre-tax profits there for the last three quarters. I mean should that really be tailing off that much from there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes it's a couple of quite significant items. One is our receivables take another pretty substantial hit in 2010 because of &#x2013; as the interest levels have downsized and we've rolled off some of the book but we're also rolling off Jaguar Land Rover book, the Mazda book, we're starting to roll off the Volvo book, we're making progress on that. We've found alternative business arrangements in some of the Asia Pacific and Northern European countries.</p>
          <p>There was also, and I think we talked about this in the second quarter; there was a pretty substantial currency gain on an un-hedged intercompany loan. From memory it was several hundred dollars, I think $300 million. So there are a couple of pretty big &#x2013; one non-recurrance and the other is the fact that we have been downsizing the credit company to recognize the realities of our future ability to fund and also the fact that we're no longer managing the PAG business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Rod Lache representing Deutsche Bank. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Rod.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of things. Just looking at the North American results this quarter, if I look at North American shipments sequentially it looks like they were 115,000 units higher and earnings were $350 million better. So that's about $3,000 per unit. And I was wondering whether &#x2013; it just looks like a little light relative to what we've seen in the past but can you just comment a little about this sequential walk as you've done in the past?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet, we're just looking our data here for a minute.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think the reason it's looking a little light is there are some seasonal structural cost changes on the quarter-over-quarter basis that go up a little bit in the fourth quarter. Other than that, nothing really significant. We still continue to feel pretty good about the margin before we get to fixed costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But you would include those seasonal issues in the volume line as you've broken that out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I guess maybe just switching gears a little bit, K.R., I didn't see any mention this quarter about planning &#x2013; plans for bank holding company status or looking to get any kind of support there. I was wondering if you can comment on those plans? And are there any implications that you see from the proposals in Washington vis-&#xE0;-vis taxing liabilities of financial institutions? How do you see that kind of affecting your business, if at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, just a couple things. There are no plans to become a bank holding company. That's clear. We still have a pending application on the ILC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh sorry; yeah, ILC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's a big difference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand. Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We know you do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that application is still pending but as we've always said, it was always a small piece of the business, if it goes through.</p>
          <p>As far as regulatory changes, it's really hard for me to tell at this point in time. We're getting our funding done. We're getting the securitization done. Spreads are tightening. Things are looking really good from our perspective as far as being able to compete in the marketplace and get people into Ford vehicles, and keeping our dealers funded.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're still convinced as we're going through the year that a captive credit company is a strategic asset to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep. And just back to the Motor Company, could you just talk about where your UAW cost per hour is today all in? And can you just remind us, it looks like you're starting to hire people, what is the all-in cost for new hires? Do you have any targets for the ratio of Tier One versus Tier Two? And also just given the European decline, are there any actions that you're taking to mitigate some of that decline? That'll be my last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me answer the second part first, the European decline. During the year we took out a substantial, during 2009, we had a substantial dealer stock reduction in Europe, because, frankly, scrappage ran a lot stronger than we expected, and continued a lot longer. So without a repeat of that, which we don't anticipate, we'll have about flat production year-over-year. So structurally we think Europe's about where it needs to be. If things change, we'll take another look at it, but at the moment we think we're about okay.</p>
          <p>In terms of where we are on the UAW, we're really not much different from where we've talked to you about before. We're now at about $55 an hour against best estimate, when they still had a substantial number of temps of the transplants about $50 an hour. When we got up to a 20% blended rate of new hires we'd be &#x2013; that would close the gap to the 50 bucks, but we haven't got near-term hiring plans that will get us up to that 20 bucks. So we're still less than with &#x2013; as production grows, making sure we're utilizing the people we already have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Brian Johnson representing Barclays Capital. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Two questions: one housekeeping and then one strategic about South America. On the housekeeping front, what was the contribution to cash flow above and beyond net profits from the translation balance sheet currency impact you talked about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well then I'm just asking my housekeeper. Why don't you ask the second question, we'll just...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, could you give us some color on both how &#x2013; on what you see for South America going forward, particularly in light of &#x2013; or particularly your expectations maybe for market growth, Ford position, obviously it's an important product &#x2013; geographic area for several other global competitors, and then how that might translate to profitability, in particular these 14% EBIT margins we're seeing, are those going to be sustainable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well we've just announced a very substantial investment plan in South America. It's obviously both products and we expect capacity as well as continued work on powertrains down South America. We do expect it to be a growing area and we expect it to continue to be significant contributor to our profit stream. But beyond that, we wouldn't speculate on just how much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you running full capacity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're just about flat out at the moment, yes. The Cama&#xE7;ari plant is flat out, the Sao Paulo plant I think has a bit of open truck capacity, on cars it's flat out, and we're flat out on powertrain. In terms of your question, it's pretty tiny in terms of the exchange rate effect, it's like 0.2 billion, something like that. I mean it's just about negligible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Chris Ceraso representing Credit Suisse. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of questions around the finance company. First, the size of the book you referenced in the slide deck, around 11 billion, I don't mean to be picky here. It was 10.3 the last quarter. Is that 11 a rounded number? Or are you growing the book here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're talking about the 11 billion of equity, Chris?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Exactly. Was it like 10.5 and you put it as 11 because it's rounded? Or what's the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. It's pretty close to 11. One second, I'll find it. 10.969.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So where do you see that going? Lewis mentioned the JLR and the Volvo and the Mazda. Where does the book value go, let's say, by the end of 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Real high level, we mentioned that we're going to &#x2013; the size of the balance sheet will reduce to about between 80 and 90 billion. We ended the fourth quarter at 95 billion. This is step one. JLR, Mazda and Volvo receivables will continue to wind off, which should free up capital. So the 11 billion ends up being in our profits for 2010 plus the planned distributions that we have planned. We plan to pay $1.5 billion of distributions in 2010, which will reduce the 11 billion down. Then it'll be offset by profits. It will end up being between 10 and 11 billion by the end of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then is it, trying to take away some of the noise of the different adjustments and one-time items, is it &#x2013; you guys used to do something in the neighborhood of a 14% ROE in the Credit business. Is that a good neighborhood? Is that an after-tax return on equity around 14%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't actually give any guidance on that. It's a fair long-term objective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Emphasis on long term, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just lastly then, just so I understand how you're doing the math here on the 500 million favorable that you showed in the finance company in the quarter, is that a change in the value of the lease book that you're writing up so that you depreciate differently? Or is it the benefit of the vehicles that are coming off lease that are worth more than you thought they would be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It is primarily the vehicles that actually came off lease and were sold at auction during the quarter compared to where they had been depreciated to prior to &#x2013; basically prior to the quarter. So some of it is, for example like the impairment we took, you can't actually undo an impairment when it comes to a depreciable asset. So eventually when the vehicles come back, they go through auction. We'll recognize that gain at that point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So how much more of this do you expect? How many more quarters can you continue to book, given vehicles come off lease?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, I don't have a specific forecast to give, but it'll be several more quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Several more quarters. Okay. At the same kind of magnitude?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That I don't want to get into just yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I &#x2013; just before we take the next question let me just clarify my response I think it was to Brian on the Sao Paulo facility. We are at capacity on cars but we're operating on one shift so we're at man capacity rather than at facility capacity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Himanshu Patel representing J.P. Morgan. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Couple of questions, just given what's happening with commodity costs, can you guys touch on what the outlook is for net product cost in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes we expect them to be going up. We do think we're starting to see commodities turn, so as we start doing new contracts we'll see some increased price because of that. So product costs, we expect to be going up a bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, Lewis, can you give us any help on 2010 pension expense and pension cash contributions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure I can, to be perfectly honest with you. I'm sorry; I'm just working out why I can't be helpful. We'll give you the details, Himanshu, in the 10-K when we finish the analysis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then I guess there's a story out today about Ford halting production of the China version of the Transit because of the same accelerator problem that Toyota has. Can you just gives us a sense for where are you on the analysis of this issue? Is this pretty isolated in your view or is there a chance that this could spread to North America or Europe as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet. It's our assessment right now, it's very isolated. Just a little bit more information: following our normal process, when anybody has an issue in the industry we check everything about the Ford design and production worldwide. As you pointed out it appears to us that there might be a similar design in one of the older Transit, what they call in China the Transit Connect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Classic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Classic; I'm sorry, the Transit Classic that is being produced in our joint venture with Jiangling Motors. So they announced this morning, with our support, that they're going to suspend production until they can finish the investigation. It involves less than 2,000 vehicles and it appears that the design might be similar and which kind of fits with them switching suppliers in December of last year over to the CTS supplier. So we think it's pretty isolated but we are aggressively running it to ground.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Patrick Archambault representing Goldman Sachs. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You know I wanted to just get a little bit more guidance on the impact of Volvo being put into special items. How separate is Volvo operationally as well as administratively? When you do ultimately sell it, how much penalty can we sort of expect from some of the duplicatous administrative and operating functions that you will &#x2013; that will remain with you, that you will have to sort of restructure separately? How much of a penalty in and above removing whatever future PBT forecast we would have in our models should we be thinking about both in terms of when it actually comes off the books as well as how it'll be treated when you report it as a special item?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know if you can think of &#x2013; Volvo has pretty standalone capability in terms of product development and manufacturing, some shared engines. They supply Ford with engines, and Ford supplies them with engines, and an independent sales network and dealer networks. So there are a couple of areas where we're going to have to work to make sure we don't incur, I don't know what the word is, dis-efficiencies. But I don't think it's going to be a material effect.</p>
          <p>And we will obviously, when we do the deal, it will be somewhat like Jaguar Land Rover where there will be some short-term transitional service agreements where, as they build up the capability for example in accounting or IT or whatever, that we continue to provide them with a service for a period. And then there'll be some long-term agreements on major items like engine supply both ways. But I'm not anticipating a material financial effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay great. And I guess another one, just on the cash flow, you mentioned that in this quarter some one-off tax benefits that I think were part of that sort of working capital, other. Can you quantify those for us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It was about $400 million from memory. The reason we're talking about, and not using it as a guide for future levels, obviously as we started seeing production come back to more reasonable levels, we started seeing the payables coming back to more reasonable levels, which is a hard thing to duplicate. And we've also &#x2013; the business units particularly in the fourth quarter did a knock-out job on bringing down inventory. And the challenge for us as we start increasing production, particularly in North America as we go forward, we'll be making sure that the inventory levels don't creep up a little bit. So that's why we think the third and fourth quarter are a little unrepresentative of our running rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, at this time we'd now like to welcome questions from the media community. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your next question comes from the line of Bryce Hoffman, representing the Detroit News. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Congratulations, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot, Bryce.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to ask a question about Toyota. Do you foresee any impact or any opportunity on your U.S. business from the Toyota recalls?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The way that we're approaching it, Bryce, is that we are really focused on the customers and what they want. And going through &#x2013; one of the neat things about going through 2009 was how much, how gratifying it is to see the customers considering Ford and also buying Ford and so clearly everybody realizes now that we are competing with the best in the world, including Toyota. So we anticipate that going forward in 2010 that we're going to see more and more interest in Ford.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you see an opportunity, though, from what's happened from Toyota's troubles to pick up any share from them?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think it's going to depend on how this all plays out and how fast Toyota gets this behind them. But clearly with a void right now and people needing vehicles, I'm sure that there's going to be even more interest in Ford. But the really cool thing is it's really an opportunity for our products to be viewed again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Dee-Ann Durbin, representing the Associated Press. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I was wondering if you could give me an example of favorable net pricing on a specific vehicle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. A couple of ways. As we launch new products that have increased content that the customers see as value, we can get the opportunity to price for that. And as they see the vehicle as more attractive than its predecessor, we've been able to reduce incentives, because people see our vehicles now as world class, whereas perhaps historically on some of our vehicle lines our customers didn't see that.</p>
          <p>So what we're really trying to do is, with world-class products, achieve competitive levels of revenue, which means typically slightly higher sticker price, but a significantly reduced incentive so you get a better transaction price. But it's all around the product, and it's all around getting competitive prices rather than getting prices that are high. And the Taurus is a good example. On the Taurus when we launched it, we were able to close the gap with our competitors, because we had a fundamentally brand spanking new product that the customers thought was really worth what we were asking them to pay for it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I assumed you wanted a general answer rather than dollars and cents.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, dollars and cents.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, send in your order and we'll help you out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Uh huh. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Brent Snavely representing Detroit Free Press. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys, and congratulations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess one broad question and one specific one. On the profit sharing with the UAW, do you now expect, or have they agreed to end this sort of mass, country-wide grievance effort that is under way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no comment on where they are on that, Brent. Clearly it's a very positive development as we move forward to be able to recognize people for the great progress we're making.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then broad picture on those restructuring and turn-around plans you've been on for several years. You've called 2009 a pivotal year for Ford. Just where are you guys at now in terms of the progress of completing Ford's turnaround?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh. Well, at the broadest level to your question, we're never going to be done. We're going to continuously improve forever. The neat thing about your question about the pivotal year, and it really is pivotal and historic, that during the worst economic recession in 30 or 40 years, because of the strength of the plan we put in place a few years ago, we were able not only to survive, but also to create a foundation that is delivering now profitable growth during that year based on the strength of our products and all the actions we've taken on continually improving our quality and our productivity.</p>
          <p>So the way we're thinking about it of course is that going forward we're going to, as we say, stay on the same plan. We're going to keep matching the capacity to the real demand. We're going to continue to improve our quality and productivity, and we're going to lead with the freshest lineup and most complete line of cars, utilities, and trucks, small, medium and large with best-in-class quality. So we look at this as a long-term delivering great products, ever improving strong business, and being part of the solution for everybody going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Brent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Chris Isidore representing CNN Money. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Three months ago when you reported good third quarter results, you weren't quite ready to predict a profit for 2010. What has changed in the last three months that made you more bullish about the year ahead? And do you see there being more upside or downside to that forecast right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of things. We've obviously got a good quarter under our belts, so we continue to see good performance on the stuff under our control in terms of our business and the reception of our products. I think we're seeing perhaps the opportunity of a little bit more life in Europe, because some of the scrappage programs are continuing. You know we said at the end of the third quarter the thing that was concerning us most was an inability to read the market trend, because we were exiting the third quarter when we'd had Cash for Clunkers, which really sort of distorted the running rates in the U.S. We finished with a good December.</p>
          <p>So I think we feel just a little bit more positive that the green shoots are still there. They haven't shriveled up. We remain concerned about the fragile nature of the economic recovery around Western Europe and the U.S., are very encouraged by the growth in China and our ability to participate in the growth with rapidly growing Asia Pacific sales. So it's just that a tiny, wee bit more confidence than when we finished the third quarter I think based on those factors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Joann Muller representing Forbes. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Joann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I had a question about the debt, and I'm wondering what is your &#x2013; what was the debt payment for the year last year in total? And what I'm trying to get at here is what is the debt penalty per vehicle and does it give you a disadvantage against your competitors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's no question that our net debt levels gives us a disadvantage against our competitors, because of the higher interest payments we incur. Doing a direct comparison is a bit tough, because you have to understand the net cash, not just the debt position, Joann, but you've got to look at the net cash position in terms of interest levels. So we wouldn't give a specific number, but we're acutely aware that we still have too much debt on our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>We worked at it very hard last year with debt restructuring, an equity offering, a dribble out convertible term, and prepayment of the VEBA and some payments of the revolver as part of the amend and extend strategy. And we're going to continue to work on it. The thing that we're focused on inside Ford is best way to improve our balance sheet is to improve the fundamental profitability of the company to generate positive operating cash flow to enable us to pay down our debt. So that's our focus at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you elaborate on any actions you might be taking in the coming year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I mean the thing I can elaborate on is we still have a lot of work to do to continue to improve the business. Being profitable, as we've given guidance, and generating positive operating automotive-related cash flow is the single, most important thing we do in terms of thinking about the balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Based on your projections, do you have any estimate on how long it'll take you to work that down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We certainly do, but as you would understand, it's not something we'd share outside the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Katina, I think we just have time for one more question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The final question comes from the line of Jeff Bennett, representing Dow Jones. Please Proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Just two questions. Lewis, what are we seeing for the pacing of the commodity price increases? Do you think it's something that's going to pick up in the middle of the year? Or just kind of continually rise throughout the year? And then, Alan, are you considering just an entire recall of the vans in China?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lewis will go first here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, we're already seeing commodities start moving starting in the fourth quarter or the third quarter, Jeff. So I think we'll see a steady increase during the year, but it's going to be heavily dependant upon industrial activity in China. So we're just going to have to watch this space very closely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Jeff, with respect to the pedal assembly, we have not determined whether we have a problem there yet. What we do know is that we found a similar design that &#x2013; and also the fact that they had switched suppliers to the CTS supplier. So with what we know, that's why we were very supportive of Jiangling Motors and the joint venture suspending production for those, that less than the 2,000 units. And so we're continuing with our investigation, and then we'll take the appropriate action. I would also, I would like to just point out that we have found no issues with the customers with this issue in China also. But we're going to follow our normal decisive process and understand the issue, and then we'll move on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, everyone. That concludes today's presentation. We thank you all for joining us today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes your presentation. You may now disconnect. Good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>