<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1223573" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-04-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>200</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Kathleen L. Quirk, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer and Treasurer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Richard C. Adkerson, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Michael Gambardella</participant>
      <participant id="4">Richard Adkerson</participant>
      <participant id="5">David Gagliano</participant>
      <participant id="6">Kathleen Quirk</participant>
      <participant id="7">Tony Rizzuto</participant>
      <participant id="8">James Moffett</participant>
      <participant id="9">Mark Liinamaa</participant>
      <participant id="10">Brian Macarthur</participant>
      <participant id="11">Kuni Chen</participant>
      <participant id="12">Jorge Beristain</participant>
      <participant id="13">Victor Flores</participant>
      <participant id="14">Gary Lampard</participant>
      <participant id="15">John Tumazos</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="corprep">&lt;Q &gt;</participant>
      <participant id="17">Justine Fisher</participant>
      <participant id="18">Dave Katz</participant>
      <participant id="19">Sanil Daptardar</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="corprep">James R. Moffett, Chairman</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to the Freeport-McMoRan Copper &amp; Gold First Quarter Earnings Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, we will conduct a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to Ms. Kathleen Quirk, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer. Please go ahead, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good morning, everyone. Welcome to the Freeport-McMoRan Copper &amp; Gold first quarter 2009 earnings conference call. Our earnings announcement was released earlier this morning, and a copy of the press release is available on our website at fcx.com. Our conference call today is being broadcast live on the Internet, and we'll have several slides to supplement our comments. The slides are accessible using the fcx.com website homepage link.</p>
          <p>In addition to analysts and investors, the financial press has also been invited to listen to today's call, and a replay of the call will be available by accessing the webcast link on our Internet homepage later today.</p>
          <p>Before we begin today's comments, I'd like to remind everyone that today's press release and certain of our comments on this call include forward-looking statements. Please refer to the cautionary language included in our press release and slide presentation and to our risk factors described in our SEC filings.</p>
          <p>On the call today are Jim Bob Moffett, our Chairman; Richard Adkerson, the President and Chief Executive Officer; Red Conger, who heads up our Americas operations; and Mark Johnson, who heads up our Indonesian operations. We've got a number of our senior operating team traveling this week. I'll briefly summarize our financial results and then turn the call over to Richard, who'll discuss our operations and outlook. We'll then open up the call for questions.</p>
          <p>FCX reported first quarter 2009 net income applicable to common stock of 43 million, $0.11 per share compared with net income applicable to common stock of 1.1 billion or $2.64 per share in the first quarter of 2008. Our first quarter 2009 net income applicable to common stock, including net charges of 24 million or $0.06 a share, which were detailed in our press release. But those included 31 million in charges, or $0.08 a share, associated with adjustments to our environmental reserves; 22 million, or $0.05 a share, for restructuring and other costs associated with our revised operating plans; $19 million, or $0.05 a share, associated with lower of cost or market molybdenum inventory adjustments related to the decline in molybdenum prices. These charges were partly offset by reductions to general and administrative costs associated with reduced compensation cost totaling 29 million, or $0.07 per share, and a $19 million gain for a copper derivative contract associated with our customer contracts for rod sales.</p>
          <p>Our first quarter consolidated copper sales of &#x20A4;1 billion was slightly above our previous guidance of &#x20A4;990 million, and higher than the first quarter 2008 sales of &#x20A4;911 million, reflecting the higher grades in Grasberg. Our gold sales of 545,000 ounces in the first quarter were nearly two times the year-ago level of 280,000 ounces because of the higher ore grades at Grasberg. Our gold sales during the quarter exceeded our previous estimates of 500,000 ounces.</p>
          <p>Molybdenum sales during the quarter totaled &#x20A4;10 million. Those were lower than the first quarter sales of &#x20A4;20 million and our January 2009 guidance of &#x20A4;13 million because of demand conditions in the molybdenum markets.</p>
          <p>Our copper prices recorded averaged $1.72 per pound in the first quarter of 2009. That was over 50% lower than the first quarter of 2008. Our realized gold prices averaged $904 per ounce, as compared with $933 per ounce in the year-ago period. We realized $11.52 per pound of molybdenum during the first quarter, and that was a reduction of 64% compared with nearly $32 per pound in the first quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>We've got a number of things that we'll be talking about in the call, particularly on our costs, where we achieved strong execution of our revised operating plans. Of our unit cost during the quarter, net cash cost, net of our by-product credits on a consolidated basis averaged $0.66 per pound during the first quarter of 2009; that was significantly lower than the year-ago period of $1.06 per pound.</p>
          <p>Our operating cash flows totaled the use of $258 million during the first quarter; that reflected a very large working capital use of 919 million, and that was anticipated. It was primarily associated with the timing of settlements with customers on our 2008 provisionally priced sales. Capital expenditures totaled 519 million for the first quarter, about half of that related to the initial development of our Tenke project. Richard's going to give an update on that, which is nearing completion. We also reported previously that we completed a public offering of 26.8 million shares of common stock during February at an average price of $28 per share; that generated gross proceeds of $750 million and brought our shares, basic common shares outstanding to 412 million shares. Assuming conversion of our 5.5 convertible preferred stock and our mandatory convertible preferred stock, we would have roughly 469 million shares outstanding.</p>
          <p>Total debt approximated 7.2 billion at the end of the quarter, and our consolidated cash position was 644 million at the end of March. We had no amounts borrowed under our $1.5 billion credit facility.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to turn the call over to Richard, who will be referring to the presentation materials on the website.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. In getting ready for this conference call today, I went back and glanced at the transcript for our last conference call for our year-end results, and two things jumped out of me. At that point, I said the near-term copper price was going to be driven by events in China. And by the end of the first quarter, Chinese purchases of copper had come in very strongly as they continue to spend money in building infrastructure in their country, and they face a scarcity of scrap and also have built &#x2013; been building up copper stocks, but that has caused copper prices to be stronger, even in the face of very weak market conditions in the U.S. and the rest of the developed world.</p>
          <p>The second thing, at the time of our last conference call, we were completing a process that we had literally started the first week in October, of revising our operating plans to adjust to the lower copper and molybdenum prices, and we had worked diligently right up until the time of that call to come up with new plans. And I said we had plans that would allow us to be cash flow-positive at our mines and be supportive of our business strategy, but that investors should watch how we execute on those plans. And I'm really pleased with the results of this first quarter. And Red Conger, Mark Johnson, Dave Thornton, and their operating teams aggressively went out to those plans, and the results of their activities are shown in the financial results that you see today.</p>
          <p>Page four, Kathleen mentioned that the price of copper is half of what it was during the first quarter of '08. Price of gold is roughly, it actually averaged a bit lower than it did in '08, which is a bit surprising. I know it is surprising to a number of people, and molybdenum was down 2/3. Even with that we had good cash flow generation taking into account the working capital uses that we talked about last quarterly call. And we ended up with $0.11 a share of earnings. And for those of you who model earnings, I point out that that is net of $0.06 of special charges that Kathleen outlined for you. Some of you may have picked those, some of those up, some of you may not have. But it also reflected $0.15 for the deferral of profits that we've actually already generated through mining and sales of copper concentrate. That will be recognized in future periods under the accounting rules because it's sold inter-company to our Atlantic copper smelter. And once that concentrate is processed and copper is sold out of the smelter those profits, which have already been generated in the first quarter, will be recognized in our earnings. Most of that, if prices stay roughly where they are today and operations continue as we expect, most of that would turn around in the second quarter. So all things being equal, and they may not be, but all things being equal we would have stronger earnings in the second quarter and in subsequent quarters in 2009.</p>
          <p>Page five and I'll talk about this more, I have got a couple of more slides, shows our, at the bottom, the sales by our different regions: North America, South America, and Indonesia. I point out the significant increase in both copper and gold sales in Indonesia. At Grasberg, we are operating now in the highest grade section of that mine. That changes over time, depending on the sequencing of our operations. And as we work on this pit, which is now almost two kilometers across and a kilometer deep, as we maintain the integrity of this pit over time, we manage high-grade sections, we mine high-grade sections. And other times we have to be in the upper regions where grades are lower. But we are now on high-grade sections and you can see just what kind of leverage that has on our volumes, very supportive of our business now. We knew Grasberg would be the keystone asset when we combined our company with Phelps Dodge, and particularly in times of low commodity prices, and that's exactly the role it's serving.</p>
          <p>Our gold revenues, considering the gold volumes and the current gold price, more than offset our total operating cost at Grasberg, so we were producing in the first quarter roughly 370 million pounds of copper at a net credit cash cost. But our cash costs have come down significantly in the rest of our operations as we've adjusted our operating plans to limit the marginal higher cost volumes, and as we've taken advantage of the lower input costs that have gone along with the lower copper prices, and you can see there is significant declines in these cost, even though we've lost by-product credits because of the lower molybdenum sales.</p>
          <p>On page six, you can see on a consolidated basis. In terms of our site production and delivery cost on a per-pound basis, we've had a 36% reduction from the third quarter of '08 prior to us beginning to implement our new operating plant until the first quarter of '09. That reflects these revised plans; it also reflects the Grasberg ore grade situation and how we've been very aggressive in moving to achieve lower cost and take advantage of the available lower input cost. This was particularly important for our North American operations. In the third quarter, by design because we've been pushing the production of marginal pounds, we had been aggressively increasing volumes, knowing that our unit cost would go up. And in the third quarter, at our largest mine in North America, the Morenci Mine, our average unit cost, and there are no by-product credits at Morenci, was approaching $2 a pound. And you can see that $2, before by-product credits at any of our mines, has now been reduced significantly into the first quarter of '09. Diesel prices are down, power prices are down, asset costs are down, but we had taken very strong steps to push out those marginal pounds. So our employment at Morenci has gone from 3500-4000 down to below 2000 people. We've idled equipment. We're mining higher grades. We're doing what we need to do to make that operation and our other operations cash-flow positive.</p>
          <p>Page eight talks about our provisional pricing; we always get a lot of questions on this. Under longstanding commercial practices in the copper business, copper concentrates are provisionally priced when ships &#x2013; w hen shipped, and that's the point where we record our sales. And then they are subject to a final price determination whether the price is higher or lower, which occurs, depending on the contract, from one to four months following shipment. And the accounting impact is the sales accrued initially at the provisional priced amounts and then adjusted in subsequent periods. From a cash flow standpoint, customers pay us 90% of the provisional price at time of shipment, and then there's a cash settlement at final prices.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter, we had final settlements with customers that totaled a $600 million cash requirement that we had to &#x2013; we had to return cash to our customers because of the receipt of prices at times when the price of copper was so much higher, and that was what resulted in our working capital requirement for the quarter. It's a one-time type event; there will be adjustments going forward, but nothing of that magnitude absent some major subsequent swing in copper prices. But in the normal course of business, these settlements are not material.</p>
          <p>In early April, we made a decision, and I want to be clear about this because we've had a long-standing philosophy of not hedging copper production, and that philosophy has not changed. We have not, have no plans of hedging any of our future copper production. But historically, although we haven't done it in some time, we had taken steps to lock in open pounds, and we did that at the end of the second quarter, where we locked in &#x2013; at the end of the first quarter, where we locked in $1.86 for roughly 350 million pounds of PT-FIs, provisionally priced open pounds, at the end of the first quarter. Substantially all of this will reverse in the second quarter, so there won't be any mark-to-market accounting implications of any consequence. And we did this to, as part of our overall actions to preserve liquidity of the company to give us assurance of these prices in an uncertain marketplace. It also has the impact of limiting earnings volatility. We have not made a decision to do this on an ongoing basis. We'll look at it on a quarter-by-quarter basis and make those decisions. Again, I want to emphasize this does not change our basic approach to philosophy. We believe that we should offer investors an un-hedged opportunity with respect to our commodities, and that's what we are doing.</p>
          <p>Page nine shows the copper markets, copper price. Can see the recent jump in prices from roughly the $1.40 level going into the quarter up to above $2 a pound. I talked about China being the reason for this, and as we go forward, given the market conditions elsewhere around the world, the copper price in the short term is going to be driven by China. We continue to be very positive, extremely positive about being in the copper and molybdenum business. The inventories, as you can see by this chart, are low by historical standards, and we have a much larger copper market than we had prior to &#x2013; in the historical periods prior to 2004. And even though the prices has been weak, exchange stocks are low by historical standards, and consumer stocks around the world are also low, the industry continues to face supply issues that are unrelated to price from grades at aging mines, from equipment issues. The challenges of operating mines in today's world continue unrelated to price, and then of course price has had an impact on our level of production and the level of certain other companies.</p>
          <p>So as the developing world see that the economy's recovering, and we're not in any position to predict when that will occur. And as the China and the rest of undeveloped world continue to build infrastructure and invest in the standard of living of people in their countries, the world is going to have a strong demand for copper, and the industry is going to be challenged to have the supplies to meet that demand.</p>
          <p>As I look at this chart, I think back to this same time six years ago in the spring of 2003. And although the scale of copper prices on the right side is squeezed, there are some similarities for our industry based on where the industry was then. The world itself is quite different, but in the spring of 2003, the U.S. economy was in a recession. The developed world was in recession. The copper price was roughly $0.75. Roughly 5% of the industry's capacity work was curtailed. Inventories were very high, and people in the industry didn't expect the price to reach a dollar within a three- or four-year timeframe. But in that year, even with weak U.S. economy, China's demand was so strong that inventories began to fall. And by 2004, when the U.S. economies recovered, the price of copper jumped, and it essentially doubled from the spring of 2003 to the end of 2004 and then continued upward because of the supply issue that the industry faced. So I think that's a case study of thinking what we will be facing at some point when, as China continues to develop, as the rest of the undeveloped world follows suit over time, and as the developed world's economies recover.</p>
          <p>Page 10 talks about what we've done with our company. I mentioned we started this process of reviewing our operating plans at the start of the fourth quarter, and we continue to work on it, we are continuing to work on it. We're executing on the plans, but as we execute on the plans, we are looking at ways to optimize those, and that involves changes, and will continue to change over time. But we're operating Morenci and Safford SX/EW operations in Eastern Arizona near each other at roughly half their design capacity rates; that's helping to drive their cost down. We suspended operations at our Chino mine in New Mexico, although we continue to view some copper, and adjusted the mining rate at Tyrone significantly.</p>
          <p>We didn't make as significant changes in South America, but we did adjust the mine rates at our Candelaria and Ojos district to help contain costs there. We continue to operate Grasberg aggressively because of its cost structure and the grades that we have available. And essentially the same can be said about our Cerro Verde mine in Peru, which is a large, low-cost mine. And the cash flows from those mines are supporting our capital expenditure program, our debt servicing, and our corporate G&amp;A program; and the other mines are being operated to be cash-flow positive, even with lower prices. Molybdenum business is, of course, severely affected by the fall-off in demand for metallic molybdenum in the steel industry. We sell a significant portion of our molybdenum as a chemical, and that is somewhat weaker, but not as nearly as weak as in the steel industry. And to adjust our operations in response to the lower demand for the product, we've taken stages of reduction at our molybdenum mine in Colorado, the Henderson mine, and now it is planned to be operated at roughly 40% of its capacity. To reduce the amount that we produce, we've also made some adjustments at our by-product mines, including suspending the molybdenum circuit at our Cerro Verde mine in Peru. At all of our operations, including Grasberg and Cerro Verde, we are deferring projects when we can; we are reducing cost wherever we have the opportunity to reduce cost. We reduced our administrative cost, reduced our head count at our corporate headquarters by a quarter. As I said I'm very, very pleased with the way the organization has responded to the necessities that the current market environment places before us.</p>
          <p>Page 11 shows our outlook for sales; this is similar to what we had at the end of the fourth quarter and our last earnings release. It shows that our production levels, sales levels for copper will continue at roughly the level we operated at in 2007-2008, but what that doesn't show is just a significant amount of reductions that we put in place from what we had planned to produce and sell. We have been, had a strategy up through the third quarter of adding the volumes, and we've successful in doing that. So we have cut back from what our plans are; we'll continue to have higher volumes. You can see with the gold sales the impact of the mining sequencing at Grasberg, where we will have roughly a million ounces more gold sales this year, strong sales going into 2010. And then below that, the moly chart shows the actions, the effect of the actions that we've taken to adjust our moly sales in response to the low prices in the market place currently.</p>
          <p>Page 12 shows the outlook now for quarterly sales of copper, gold, and molybdenum for our company. You can see that our quarterly copper sales will be in the range of 950 to a billion pounds. Gold sales will be strong in the second and third quarters and almost 500,000 ounces in the fourth quarter. And then the current outlook for moly sales is shown on page 12. We will continue to review that again, depending on what the market needs for that product is and determine how, to what extent we operate Henderson.</p>
          <p>Page 13 shows for the year 2009. Previously the charts, we've shown it for the first quarter, but this shows the outlook for the year for our sales by region and also our outlook for unit cost, both at site production and delivery before by-products credits, the impact of by-product credits, and our outlook currently for where we expect to be for the year. Now this reflects the new outlook for molybdenum, for example, with lower molybdenum sales. It has gold in here; that's priced at $900 an ounce, molybdenum at $8 a pound. That will have an impact on these net numbers depending on where the actual prices are. As we went into the first quarter, we were having to make some assumptions about where input costs were going. Now we are using the current outlook for those input costs and as that changes, these numbers will change. So there's lots of pluses and minuses that go into this. We're going to try to maximize our mine plans and be aggressive in finding ways of managing our cost. And we are going to do our best to try to beat these numbers as we go forward.</p>
          <p>Exploration: we had doubled our exploration spending. Between 2007 and 2008, our total expenditures were roughly $250 million, mostly spent in drilling core holes associated with our existing ore bodies in terms of gaining a better understanding of the geology with a view towards adding to reserves and ultimately adding to expansion projects, and we were and continue to be very positive about our ability to do that. Lots of drilling also at our new project in Africa, Tenke Fungurume. You can see how the budget was spent divided geographically. We were successful. We added significant reserves in '08, three times the amount of our copper production and six or seven times our moly production, and we expect to be able to continue to use the information from that core drilling to add reserves going forward and to continue to work to look to how to convert reserves in the cash flow-producing assets. But we're going to spend less on core drilling in 2009 and reduce our budget from 250 to $75 million, but not at all changing our emphasis on exploration.</p>
          <p>Slide 15 shows our EBITDA numbers and our cash flow numbers excluding working capital, but the operating cash flow is net of cash interest and cash taxes and shows that at the current level of copper and gold and molybdenum prices, we would expect on average for 2009-2010 to have roughly $4.5 billion of EBITDA and over $3 million of operation cash flow Slide 15, shows our EBITDA numbers and our cash flow numbers excluding working capital, but the operating cash flow is net of cash interest and cash taxes and shows that at the current level of copper and gold, molybdenum prices we would expect on average for 2009, 2010 to have roughly $4.5 billion of EBITDA and over $3 billion of operating cash flows, you can see the variance here to those numbers if copper and gold prices and molybdenum prices vary. I guess this is a copper price variance here that's shown on this slide, but on the next slide on page 16, we give you the sensitivities so that you can use our analysis and adjust prices to your own view of prices for both commodities, which we sell, and also some important input cost to give those to you for financial analysis purposes.</p>
          <p>Page 17 includes our capital expenditures, and in light of our steps to protect liquidity, we made a significant reduction of roughly $1 billion in our planned capital spending for 2009. Our current outlook for the year is 1.3 billion, roughly equally divided between sustaining capital and the new projects that we're continuing. We suspended our projects except for the completion of the Tenke Fungurume project in Africa, the continued development of the underground ore bodies at Grasberg. Then in 2010, our current outlook is for $1 billion of capital. We will have completed our spending at Tenke roughly by the mid part of 2009. And the projects include Grasberg, and we currently have the Sulfolix project, the project to develop the sulfide ore reserves at El Abra included in 2010. Later this year we will be making a decision about whether to go forward with that or defer it further, which we can do without losing the resource if we see market conditions indicate we should defer capital.</p>
          <p>Important quarter for Tenke; again, I'm just really pleased with our construction team and our operations team there. They beat my own personal estimate about when they would be able to first produce copper.</p>
          <p>Today we are looking at first our actual shipment of copper from that operations to the marketplace, and that's involves trucking the copper cathodes, this is in SX/EW operations, from Katanga in the DRC to South Africa to marketplace; it's sort of a test shipment. But we are producing copper there. We have an inventory of cathodes ready for shipment and as a project, continues to be completed. We are completing the copper circuit, which is essentially completed now. We're focusing on the cobalt circuit and an acid plant that we're building there. We're on schedule to ramp up to full capacity in the second half, and that involves an annual rate of 250 million pounds of copper and 18 million pounds of cobalt. Capital costs are significant; we're building this not just for this project, but to be able to expand because we're confident that the resource will allow us to do that. We'll time subsequent expansions depending on market conditions, but the resource is there, and we are adding to our reserves, still drilling there, expect to continue to add to our reserves.</p>
          <p>Some great pictures on page 19. You can see an aerial shot in the lower left of the facility. This is a world-class facility. The first line tailings disposal facility in this region, and there's copper ready for shipment, so that's a beautiful site for us, and it's going well.</p>
          <p>As I said, we are building this to world-class standards from an environmental management, occupational safety, and social responsibility. We're making investments in the community, which need investments to deal with the standard of living that the people have there. We've upgraded the road. We're investing in the power facilities to give us reliable power, doing social programs, which we will continue to expand as we earn revenues. This is a contractual arrangement that is fair to the DRC by international standards in terms of taxes, royalties, and equity participation. We are continuing to work with the government on their contract review process. Progress has been made. We anticipate that this will be successfully concluded during the second quarter.</p>
          <p>At Grasberg, we are looking forward to the time when the open pit will be fully mined. Our current plan is that to complete the open-pit mining in roughly 2015; we're continuing to review that. For the last several years, we've been building infrastructure to allow us to mine the underground reserves that lie directly underneath the open pit. It's really the same ore body. It's just &#x2013; it'll be mined with a very large block cave mine. We have expanded our DOZ mine and have significant undeveloped resources there. And so, once the open pit is mined, this will continue to be a very high volume, low cost operation extending through the current life of our contract, which is 2041. But we're continuing to develop those reserves so that we can move to the underground era as planned.</p>
          <p>Financially, our company is well situated in current market conditions. And looking back to two years ago, we're very happy that we made the decisions that we made at that time to delever. And as a result of those delevering actions that we took in 2007, we have a very attractive debt maturity schedule, as you can see on page 22. We have very small amounts of debt principle payments. For a number of years, we'll continue to review our cash flows and debt marketplace to see whether we should take actions to retire some of this debt in advance of its maturity.</p>
          <p>From a financial policy standpoint, we are committed to have a strong balance sheet, and I think our track record of the actions that we've taken to delever adjust our operations to raise capital, which we had a successful offering of common stock using a procedure called an at-the-market offering, which allowed us to place $750 million of common stock in the marketplace in a way that was not disruptive to the marketplace and gave us additional liquidity. We're managing our costs, which I keep saying over and over, limiting our capital. In this environment, we're going to continue to focus on protecting liquidity because the one thing we want to do is for our company to continue to own these assets that we own today. Because we believe those assets are going to be worth significant value in the future, and we want our shareholders to be the ones to benefit from that.</p>
          <p>So that is where we are at the end of the first quarter of 2009. That's what our outlook is. Jim Bob's [James R. Moffett 0:36:35] here on the line with me, and we're pleased to open the line for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> One moment, please, for our first question. The first question comes from the line of Michael Gambardella with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Richard. Hi, Jim Bob and Kathleen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Congratulations on the good operational quarter and on the progress you're making at Tenke. I do have a question, though, on Tenke. While you've had great progress on bringing this up ahead of schedule, at least your schedule, what's the progress, or can you tell us any progress you've made on the contract with the government?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's been a process that has taken much longer than the government had indicated it was planning to devote to this. It's been a difficult time for the country. At the end of '08, they had to face the renewed problems in the eastern provinces, which is far away from us and did not affect us at all. Most of you know that the Congo is big as Europe, big as the U.S. east of the Mississippi, and it doesn't have roads or infrastructure. So these eastern provinces are the not things that affect us, but it did divert the government's attention. Recently they've had a change in their leadership of their assembly, their parliament, and the company is facing economic challenges that, where they already had challenges. But with the drop-off in mining activities from the lower prices, that's made those even much more significant. So there have been a lot of things that have diverted the attention of the government officials during the time we were hoping to get this contract review. We have consistently worked cooperatively in discussions with the government and with the state-owned company G&#xE9;camines. We worked hard to advise the government of the benefits that our project will have for the country as a whole, for the workforce, and for the region, and we've been successful in getting those points across. They've had a process of where they had a &#x2013; the most recent process, they've had several, but the most recent process was having a contract review commission that was headed by their Senior Minister for the Economy and Financial Affairs, Vice Prime Minister. We successfully worked with that group. There was then a sub-group of the Council of Ministers that deal with the economy and financial affairs, and we worked successfully through that group. And now we are waiting for the final action for the &#x2013; by the Council of Ministers.</p>
          <p>There's one point, Mike, that I want to make sure everybody understands. We have a contract. We're not waiting for an approval of a contract. The contract we have was transparently re-negotiated in the 2003-2000 [sic 0:40:17] timeframe. It allows us to ship product. It allows us to operate our business, and we are proceeding on the basis of that contract that is enforceable under Congolese law and gives us the basis for doing what we are doing. But we're working with this review process, which is a review of all contracts, not just ours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard, have you made the first shipment yet, and how long does it actually take to get to the port?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first truck shipment is leaving today, and it takes 20 &#x2013; we are estimating an average of 20 days. This is a test shipment as we are going through different border crossings and so forth, and it'll be 20 to 30 days. But we've been shipping significant amounts of construction materials on the same route. And so it's not like it's something that we're just starting. It's just this time the trucks are going to be carrying copper cathode as opposed to bringing in construction equipment and mill equipment and sulfuric acid and all the things we've been shipping.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it 20 to 30 days round trip...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...or just one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One way. Okay, and then last...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a good question, Mike, because we can &#x2013; we can use this for this project, for maybe the next expansion project. In the long run, to develop this property to its potential, we'll need rail infrastructure, and there is construction going on now in other countries to give us that access. But we have &#x2013; we've actually just got a note that we've been averaging less than 15 days inbound so hopefully we'll be able to do that. But we've improved the roads. The biggest challenge we faced initially was the quality of the roads inside the DRC, going from where we are on the road from the border to Kolwezi. We're in between there and we were having to go through Lubumbashi down to the border crossing. And we, initially, it was with a consortium of companies, but a number of those companies have now stopped operating, and so it's basically been on our shoulders to improve that road. But we made the improvements. We continued construction during the rainy period. And now, we're confident about our ability to ship, but it will take a long time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And last question, what was the biggest surprise you saw in the first quarter on the cost, the copper cash cost coming in so much lower than I think you had expected at $0.66?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was &#x2013; I don't want to characterize it as a surprise, but I was concerned about our ability to execute on these plans that we put together. As you recall well, Mike, we announced one set of plans in the middle of December, and the price continued to decline, and we had to develop new plans over the next three weeks or so, over the next month, really, before our earnings release. And we were working hard and looking alternatives, making decisions, and we got our plans together that we announced to you with our fourth quarter earnings release, and those were dramatic changes. I mean significant reductions in people, significant reallocation of equipment use and retirement of equipment, so we had a plan, and I think I cautioned everyone that having a plan is one thing; executing on it is another. So the really good surprise was our ability to achieve that plan, and I really tip my hat to all of our operating team and our leadership for our ability to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks a lot, Rich, and congratulations again on a good quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of David Gagliano with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everybody. I just have a, just one quick clarification question. First of all, where does the $62 million hit on the deferrals between PT-FI and Atlantic Copper? Where does that flow through the income statement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what you see is we produce the &#x2013; this is Kathleen, David. We produce the copper and copper concentrate at PT-FI, and so it really shows up when we sell it. We eliminate the sale and the cost, so it's in revenues; it's in costs. So and then, where the 62 million is the net effect. It's primarily between PT-FI and Atlantic Copper, but we also have some intercompany associated with our Cerro Verde sales. But it shows up in revenues and in costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the net effect is the negative 62 million. And then the &#x2013; so in terms of the unit cost per pound figure, does that include a portion of that pit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What you see for PT-FI is actually what our costs were during the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's a cash cost basis, and it's the volumes that we sell, including the volumes we sell on an intercompany basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For that city area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, got it. And then just as a follow-up, or unrelated, actually. There was some chatter out of Indonesia yesterday regarding a presidential decree to allow underground mining in protected forests. Obviously you've got a large reserve and resource position there, and I'm just wondering if you had some initial thoughts on what the potential long-term impact could be if there was an easing of the restrictions on underground mining in the forest in Indonesia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, our Grasberg operations, including the large reserves that we have there, were not affected by the previous government ruling about this issue, so we were &#x2013; we've been free and clear to operate there. It potentially could be beneficial to us because of our large exploration acreage that we have outside of the Grasberg area, which we call Block A. Certain of those areas were already exempt from that because of the way the original ruling and their contract situation was there. But overall, it potentially could be beneficial for us. But we always felt that had we discovered a significant ore resource in our exploration area, we could have worked with the government to develop it. So in terms of saying that this was a major issue for us, we didn't see it that way, but potentially it could be beneficial to us just in terms of administratively getting clearance to deal with what we might find there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fair enough. Thanks and congrats on a good quarter. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Tony Rizzuto with Dahlman Rose.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Hi, Richard, Jim Bob, Kathleen, and Red. Richard, I've got two questions here, and first, how should we think about Tenke in terms of modeling costs as you guys are in startup right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Its cost structure will be an attractive one once we get to full production capacity and we deal with the startup-type issues that are not really unique to Tenke, but just common startup-type issues. So the cost structure for 2009 will not be indicative of what our long-term cost structure will be, and to tell you the truth, right now we have some uncertainties ourselves as to how it will work out. We have to demobilize a very large construction work crew there, and our real initial focus is to assure that we get this thing constructed in the right way and started up. So we're going to be spending some money, and some of that will go through our operating costs there, but as we go forward on a long-term basis, it will have an attractive cost structure. Some of that cost structure is going to be driven by the price of cobalt, and long run if cobalt is at $10 a pound, we should have something that should be a unit cost of something less than $0.50. But there are some uncertainties on that, Tony. If cobalt is &#x2013; and today cobalt is above $10 a pound, and that market is a very small market. We're going to be producing a lot of cobalt, but while we're doing that, a lot of other operations in the Congo and in Zambia are suspending production. So longer range, if the price of cobalt is higher, those costs are going to come down substantially.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But the process itself, Richard, is fairly efficient because I believe you guys are going to combine both the copper and the cobalt in the processing component of the facility, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there will be a separate cobalt circuit that we're now constructing. It will go through the copper circuit initially, and then the residue of the copper circuit will then be processed in the cobalt circuit. So it's an integrated facility, but the ore initially will go through, the SAG mill and end up going through the SX/EW processing to extract copper and then go through a separate process to produce the cobalt product that we will be selling.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I understand you guys, in addition to using sulfuric acid, you are using some bio-leaching there as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's really sulfuric acid, you know. It's really one of these units of where the &#x2013; as opposed to leach stacks, it's going to be a unit where the acid is in a facility that does an agitation-type leach process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The other question I have is what conditions or data points do you need to see before bringing back the North American operations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Boy, that's really going to be an interesting decision point for us. But I think what we'd really need to see is going to be a robust copper market, and that means recovery in the United States, Europe, and Japan. Hopefully, that stimulus packages and the actions to provide liquidity and financial strength to the banking system will lead to that, but we'll need to see that occurring. China can be very &#x2013; is very important, very supportive. Quite frankly, they're doing what we expected them to do, and that will be supportive of the marketplace. But we'll need to see recovery and the developed world to have a robust market to give us the confidence going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tony, this is Jim Bob. I'd like to make one comment about the cost structure in Africa, which doesn't apply to '09, but I think the way we look at Africa is much like we look at Indonesia. With the high percentage of cobalt in the ore, as cobalt prices go up and down, we could actually see production costs of zero using cobalt as a by-product. The one main difference: in Africa, it's strictly related to cobalt prices, whereas Indonesia, as you know, depending on our mining sequence, our gold goes up and goes down depending on where in the Golden Horseshoe. So in some respects, as we get the substantial ore body up and running with expansions, you're going to have a situation where you're going to have the cost structure Richard said, $0.50 at $10 cobalt. But if cobalt should strengthen and go into the 20's, we could have a zero production cost. But once again, my main point is in Indonesia, it depends on the price of gold and then where we are in the mining sequence, whereas in Africa the cobalt and the copper will flow substantially in the same percentages because of the ore bodies being monolithic as opposed to the geometry of the ore body in Indonesia. I hope that's clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very helpful, Jim Bob. I appreciate that further color. Thank you. Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mark Liinamaa with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just quickly on scrap markets. Tight scrap markets have been one of the contributors to the strength in the copper price. Would you be able to share any insights on whether you think this is cyclical, or we are seeing more of a secular tightness in scrap being that maybe we collected a little bit much relative to historic consumption at the peak of the cycle? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, our executive who runs our concentrated marketing activity was just in China, and there is a clear scarcity of scrap there. And Mark, to a certain degree it's going to be a function of price. I mean scrap comes as recovery from fabrication plants, and as the fabrication plants have cut back their operating rates, there is less scrap. But then there's also secondary scrap, and with the copper price being below $2 a pound, it just wasn't economic to collect and ship that scrap. So you could expect scrap to come back once the price rises, but it has always been the less visible part of the marketplace, a significant part of the marketplace, and the dynamics over time will and continue to change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and good luck with everything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark. Appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Brian Macarthur with UBS Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just three quick questions. Just on slide 13, where you talk about sales per region and there's a little footnote saying your sales from Africa of 100 million pounds are in there. Are they actually in one of those regions or are they, is it separate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's separate; if you add up with total, it will be a &#xA3;100 million short of our &#xA3;3.9 billion of guidance. So we just haven't separately put the Africa region on the schedule.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, that's what I thought. Second question, you talked about in North America, you know, going down another &#xA3;200 million next year, yet you talk about having fairly good flexibility to come back quickly. Why does it take so long? I mean if you're going to be &#xA3;200 million down later, that seems to be a long time to actually drop down to that neutral level and still, if you see what I'm saying, maintain flexibility coming up. Can you just explain why that occurs?  It's just the leach cycle or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, exactly. I mean the places where we've curtailed production have been our SX/EW leaching operations. We've not curtailed production at Sierrita and Baghdad, which are concentrate operations, because if you cut back there, you tend to drive your unit cost up because it has higher fixed costs. So we have reduced our mine rate, our stacking rate, and when you do that, there is a long-term consequence for that because that material is placed on the stacks and then recovered over a number of months, and so by cutting that back, we're having an impact on future production that you can't just turn around altogether. In fact, some of the things we've been doing in 2007 and 2008 were recovering from the last time that these operations were curtailed. So I think I mentioned that before when we were saying that if the price of copper dropped, and you remember we developed our plans in the scenario of roughly $1.25 copper. I said if it were to go below that, we'd have to make other decisions. And the further decisions you make, the more long-term consequences you have. We tried to balance it so that we can come back relatively quickly, but there will be a time lag between when we can recover and when we make the decision to recover and when we start really getting back to the levels where we were.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And my final question just relates, I know every quarter I ask this, but in the U.S. now you have very good cash costs, and obviously South America and Indonesia make money, and just I would have thought, you got a tax rate consolidated at 63% this quarter, and I would have thought in the U.S., even if you add $0.20 as part of depreciation, you'd have been making money everywhere. So is it just that there's a lag in inventory coming through, and the actual costs of production in North America are higher than that 122, or how did we get the 63? Because I would have thought with Grasberg being the biggest contributor at a tax rate of 50, you would have probably had a rate down a little lower?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it has to do with the fact that we really aren't going to be paying taxes in the U.S. because of the interest cost allocation and some G&amp;A cost allocation. So while we will be cash flow-positive, we still have depreciation charges, you know, which are different than the book depreciation charges.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have interest costs because of the way the U.S. tax laws relate to where you can and where you can't allocate interest costs, so our cash taxes are going to be in Indonesia and in Peru. And without any taxes paid in the U.S., even though those rates are higher on a consolidated basis, the effective book provision ends up being where it is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so say we get back to 2.50 or $3, though, at some time, we'll still have the tax rate go down, though, right? Just not in advance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. The table on page 14 that shows what our tax rate, effective tax rate would be on an annual basis at these various prices ranging from a $1.50 to 2.50.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>63% in the first quarter. If you take the, if you look at the $2 case on an annual basis, would be 48% for 2009, which means that our tax rate in the second quarter, third quarter, fourth quarter will be lower than what we had in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay. I just wanted to, but so it actually, it's just that mix. There's no lag in the fact that, like, we'd still have some inventory from the fourth quarter, which might be like $1.95 a pound Morenci that's coming through in the first quarter. There was none of that that was affecting everything this time, too. Like there's not a lag when you book it through inventory, if you see what I'm saying?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Kuni Chen with Bank of America Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good day, everybody. Just a couple of quick ones, I mean as far as U.S. operations go, can you just give us a sense on how quickly you can bring back production once you make that decision? Is that kind of two, three months or something longer than that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Longer than that, Kuni, longer than that. I mean you're talking about if we were to make the decision, let's say in the second half of '09, then it's a couple of years. The longer it goes, the more that gets extended. Now at the same time, we have the opportunity to expand, and those expansions may come in during that timeframe. So we're not really just stuck with this price schedule. We have the opportunity to expand in several places, and Africa is one where the second stage of expansion will be much quicker than the initial development because we're building a lot of infrastructure. We were pursuing an incremental production enhancement at Cerro Verde. We're also continuing to study a large-scale project there. And we have the opportunity to do some expansions at Sierrita, for example. So lag will be related to Morenci, Safford operations. In other operations, we could go back onto pushing volumes quickly, both for copper and for molybdenum, by the way. Molybdenum recovery could be much quicker than that. So the lag thing is limited to Morenci, Safford, and the longer this goes, the longer that lag time will be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. And then just a final question on China. Obviously we've seen the copper imports pick up here in February and March. What are your views on the sustainability of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we have a long-term view, it's positive about China's continuing to invest in infrastructure, you know. They've doing things to build facilities: housing, transportation, railroads, power facilities that consume copper. So we believe the consumption activities to develop internally and the standard of living, the Chinese GDP growth was stronger than some had anticipated. A number of people are upgrading their outlook for China's economic growth now, and copper is inherent to, copper demand is inherent in the consumption of copper. Their export business, which is down, is going to be affected by the world's economy. But we think a lot of the activity in China will be, is clearly sustainable. Their buying practices could cause variability. We've seen that in the past. You might recall 2006, where in May copper went to $4, and China backed out of the marketplace even though their economy and spending and consumption of copper continued to be in place, but they just didn't buy anything for a number of months, and the price of copper dropped. So their buying practices will create volatility in the near term, but underlying that is economic growth, infrastructure development that involves a real consumption of copper.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. Good luck.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jorge Beristain with Deutsche.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, Richard and everybody. Thanks for taking this call. My question was related to unit costs, and it would seem that with the unit cost hitting $0.66 in the first quarter, and your full year guidance remaining at $0.70, that you're kind of saying that the best of the cost cutting is behind you. So I just wanted to understand if that's the case? And secondly, just related to your updated guidance, I noticed that you're now using a $2 baseline copper price for 2009 versus $1.50 previously, so a $0.50 change, but you've only increased your incremental operating cash flow forecast by around 1.5 billion instead of the 2 billion one would assume, given that $0.50 change. So are you bracing for any kind of second half increase in cost or something? What changed in your thinking that you wouldn't be raising your cash flow guidance by essentially $2 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me deal with the cost structure first. We &#x2013; it's really such a combination of things. Let me say in response to your specific question, we aren't bracing ourselves for any cost increase; that's not in our plans at all. It's the combination of the by-product credits, the lower molybdenum credit has some &#x2013; production has some impact. Grasberg was stronger than planned in the first quarter. Historically for many years, when Grasberg is in this high- grade section of the pit, we have operationally been able to achieve better than planned results because it doesn't take a lot of material with grades of copper and gold at this level to improve. And as we go forward into 2009, we're going to continue to look for opportunities to do that, to do that safely. But, and we'll see if we're successful in doing that. But at the beginning of the year, we had to make some estimates on where we thought input costs would be in terms of energy, and we have not only diesel, put purchased power in coal that we deal with, and that's a big part of our cost structure, our work force reductions, our steel cost. A lot of those things were based on estimates at that time. Now we have the experience of the first quarter, and we've updated all those based on that experience.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we will see, we will see how we do, but it's a combination of things. There is nothing in our cost picture that shows some big increase, and we're going to continue to work to achieve efficiencies. One thing Red's finding is, particularly in North America, as we've reduced our workforce, we'll be getting much more efficiency. Our safety statistics are better, for example, and that's a real positive thing because we had been adding to our workforce so aggressively that we had less experienced workers, and those were the ones that we've reduced our workforce on. So we're seeing more efficiencies, quicker operations, and all those things are good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jorge, in terms of the operating cash flows for 2009, at the beginning of the year we assumed $1.50 copper, and we always show sensitivities, but at $1.50 copper, we were talking about $1 billion cash flow, operating cash flow for 2009, net of $600 million in working capital requirements. If we assume the first quarter actual results and then just update the copper price for $2 for the balance of the year, our cash flows are approximately $2.5 billion, again net of $600 million of working capital. So if you run the math, the numbers work for the balance of the three quarters, as you would expect. As Richard said, there's not any change in our cost structure that we are anticipating going forward, and everything is pretty much similar to what we had in January. We've updated some of the cost for actual diesel prices that we're experiencing. We also updated the cost for the effects of $2 copper, which you'd see an increased royalties and treatment charges, et cetera, so there's nothing unusual that you wouldn't expect at $2 copper.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Jorge, there's nothing magic about this number. We don't go through any kind of extensive process. It's not our projection of price; we don't project prices. Literally last week, Kathleen and I sat down and discussed whether we should use $1.75 or $2, and I said, "You know, the current price is above $2; let's just use $2." And so it is a frame of reference for people who follow us to use, and we recognize that everyone's going to use their own prices, and I just want you to know there's not any kind of a great insight you should get about the fact that we use $1.75 versus $2 because we're not predicting a price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's fair, but just to clarify then, again given that you reported $0.66 in the first quarter, you're still standing by your full-year unit cost guidance of around $0.70. I think you reduced it by about a penny, from 71 to $0.70, but do you think that there's actually downside risk to those costs? In other words, that they might come in better than budgeted, as you said, because you made supplies to the upside in Indonesia, or are you still comfortable with your $0.70 guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I want to say that what we try to do is give you our best guidance based on the analysis of all the elements of cost and production, and you should consider $0.70 from that standpoint. We're going to work real hard to beat that, and I do think we have the chance of coming in lower, and one of the big things is the possibility of getting some higher-grade ore at Grasberg through the last three quarters of the year like we did in the first quarter. And if we do that, then that's going to really help our unit cost structure, and all these other costs are going to be what they're going to be. But, so I can't say anything more than. That's our best guidance now. There is the opportunity to be beat it. If oil prices go from $50 to $75, that's going to be a negative, but that'll be whatever it'll be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jorge.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Victor Flores with HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you; good morning. I have one question with respect to the South American assets and then two with respect to Tenke. Just starting with South America. Richard, you mentioned that you'd be rethinking the sulfide project at El Abra later this year. Is there a possibility that you'll also rethink the expansion of Cerro Verde, or is there perhaps the possibility that you're comparing the two and might do one instead of the other?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's see, I don't really see it as a comparison of the two. We have the incentive to go forward with the project at EL Abra because the oxide ore is on a decline. And if we don't go forward with that, then we'll have a gap between when the decline in the oxide occurs and we ramp up for the sulfide. We have a 51% interest in that project, and our partners is Codelco, and those decisions are going to be made in consultation and working with Codelco. I would say the decision at Cerro Verde is going to be separate from that, and that's going to be made on the basis of the overall market situation and where we stand with it. So I don't &#x2013; we also have partners to work with there, of course, as well. So I don't see it as an either/or, really that much of a competing situation with something that will be driven by the market. I think the deferral of the sulfide would occur if &#x2013; markets would have to weaken significantly from where they are right now. And you know, when we last talked with you on one of these conference calls, a large portion of the world was predicting that even though copper prices were in the $1.50 range, that they were going to weaken substantially from that, and as always, we're running our business on the basis of scenarios. We're not predicting prices, we're just going to be prepared to act based on the different scenarios that we might be facing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. Then two questions with respect to Tenke. I guess CRU has been saying that the sulfuric acid price could head pretty low this year; we've heard instances where people basically are paying to have their sulfuric acid taken away from them. I'm just wondering whether that has any impact on the asset plan at Tenke. I realize that you're far from infrastructure, and there probably isn't that much cheap acid around, but I'm just wondering if there's any impact as a result of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the thing you said about sulfuric acid is also true for elemental sulfur. I mean its price has varied in a similar way to acid prices, and there is the &#x2013; there are sources for high-quality sulfur in that region, and over the long run as we are developing, again we are developing this project for the long run. We think it will make sense for us to build this plant and have it ready to go for further expansions and take advantage of the favorable market for high-quality elemental sulfur to burn in that plant. On a day-to-day basis, some of these impacts could indicate it would make sense to buy acid rather than build the plant but longer run, that decision is pretty clear, is very clear-cut.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a lot more efficient to bring in, to truck in sulfur than to have to truck in the larger volumes of acid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And then just finally one question. Now that you're actually producing cathode and getting ready to ship it, is there any requirement or mechanism that you have to hold back certain parts of the cash flow or the cash you received for the sale of cathode until the contract negotiation is bedded down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely not. No. We have a contract that gives us the access to the cash and the management of it, and there is no uncertainties about operations or spending or anything else related to the business there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right; thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot, Victor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Gary Lampard with Canaccord.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My question relates to Tenke Fungurume as well. How do you think conceptually in terms of expansion? I mean obviously, the resource space can support many levels of expansion, the first step probably doubling to about 200,000 tons per annum. What constraints are there against that sort of expansion? I guess power is the primary potential one. Do you have the power to double up to 200,000 tons per annum?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, power is not a constraint. We currently have the power available to us that would allow us to double it; we are making investments and restoring some generating facilities, hydro-generating facilities that are going to add reliability to that power. So there are really no constraints, Gary, to the next step of the expansion other than the issue of whether the market needs it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I guess the other general question. How would you look at Brownfield costs compared to your start-up costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brownfield costs related to the start-up costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, compared to start up. If you were to double production, do you think the cost would be half of your Greenfield cost?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of the expansion project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The capital cost to expand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It would be &#x2013; it would be substantially less. We are going through a study now of dealing with that. We're continuing to drill in different areas to understand exactly. This is a huge concession, for those of you who haven't followed it, 600 square miles. There's mineralization throughout that, and part of the decision would be made was what would be the next development location to find the ore for the expansion that Gary is talking about. So Gary, all I can say is it would be substantially less; it would be a very attractive project with a great operating cost and capital cost project. We won't have to do things like building a new town site, or we've already included the power cost in this project and a lot of the other types of basic infrastructure. But let's wait until we get a little clearer view on exactly which oil we'll be using and what the project will do before we talk about capital cost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard, this is Jim Bob. Let me just, you mentioned the size of the concession and the extent of ore. This is basically a flat terrain without any impairments going in the direction you want to go, and as you know, the ore that we have out there is at the surface. We will be basically using graters to scrape the ore; we don't have a big situation where you've got the terrain features like we had in Indonesia. When you go from one level to the other, you don't have an underground versus an open pit. For many, many years you're going to have a basically surface excavation of ore, which needs to be trucked to the existing facility. So that's a big difference just because of the fact that the terrain here is very friendly to literally move in from one end of the concession to the other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and in terms of timing, would something like two years from the time you make a decision be a reasonable assumption?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean if you really look at it, we &#x2013; there was very little construction done in 2007 on this project, so we basically built this project during 2008 and the first quarter of 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay, all right. Thanks very much for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Gary, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of John Hill with Cambrian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Thanks for a great presentation and really showing some stamina here on the call, everyone. Just a quick question, and feel free to answer very briefly. I know you've been at it for quite a while. First of all just on moly, taking Henderson down. There seems to be some differences of opinions out there; China reverted to net import status; there's other observers that see, or claim to be seeing, new orders out of North America for moly going to China. Have you received those calls, and are you suspicious of this kind of commentary, and how genuine do you regard it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, I am not going to &#x2013; John, I'm not in a position to comment on some of the comments, but we have our downstream processing and marketing facilities to deal with customers basically here in the U.S. and in Europe, and that's what we are dealing with. We have historically not shipped to China; we do have relationships there that may give us some opportunities to do that, and there have been some recent inquiries about it, but we're really not in a position to comment on it any more than that. We're basically working our plans off what we see from our traditional customers, and if this gives us some new opportunities, we can very quickly act to take advantage of them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good, very good. And then just a follow-up on something we discussed on the call last quarter. Just a thought about any thoughts or new thoughts about trying to lock in some of these low input costs? It looks like there's a pretty historic disconnect between attractive copper prices and relatively low, very low growth for diesel fuel, natural gas in United States, and coal globally. It looks like the kind of situation that does not come around very often, and particularly when we look forward to 2011 with the Grasberg grade's an 80 pushback, in some parts at a third the grade of what we're mining today and potentially. Hopefully in that environment, some of the U.S. operations coming back as great as 60 to $0.70 costs are today, they could be much, much, much higher with those old grades, those mines and higher input costs. Any further thoughts about trying to lock in long-term diesel, natural gas, or coal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me say first of all, yeah, we have included this on our website, our longer-term mine plans for Grasberg. This is something that we, of course, had a tradition of doing, and we've continued that. Now as Grasberg does get into those future years, Mark is working hard with our team to take actions to move copper ore and gold ore forward. And historically we've been able to find ways of doing that, and as those plans keep getting developed we will advise you of those, but that's a long-term plan. We always see plans as calls for action as opposed to the ends of action. So we're going to continue to work to do that. And at the same, we have the opportunity at our operations to increase production. Tenke will be a full stream, and other things will be coming up. I know that's not the basic question you asked, but just since you commented on that longer-term outlook, I want to make sure it's put in the right context for where we are. We, John, we continue to see this correlation between our input costs and commodity prices, and we then use that correlation as a way to adjust our operations so that we can be flexible to meet market conditions. And our hedging philosophy of giving investors exposure to an un-hedged marketplace is really one that carries forward to input cost as well as it does to commodity prices. I understand your logic; I'm not necessarily taking issue with it, but just philosophically, we adjust our operations to be responsive to overall market conditions. And that includes both the commodity prices for the products we sell as well as our input costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you and good luck as Tenke continues to come up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John. Good to hear from you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Peter Volkner with Fenazar Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Undeniably a solid quarter given the circumstances. I've got three quick questions. First is just a clarification, a prior comment on Tenke. You're going to be exiting the calendar year at a 750 million pound capacity, if not run rate, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's 250 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry that's what I meant, 250, that's what I meant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>250, Peter</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so okay. And you're going to be, you're actually going to be producing 100 million pounds this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there's uncertainty about that because that's based on an assumption of when we get up. We could produce more or less than that. But...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what in our plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. The next question is about, little bit about China. I'm hearing that Chinese buyers are expressing some interest in contracting for longer terms, greater than six months, for copper cathode, and I'm not positive, but possibly concentrate as well. They've done so with, for cathode with some Chilean producers. Have you heard anything about that? Have they contacted you about that? Is there any reason you would pursue some of those relationships?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you've got, we are, in Asia we're essentially a concentrate supplier. Our copper cathode is in large part produced in the U.S., where we then market it through our rod operations and supply about half the copper rod to the U.S. And then in Asia and in Europe, through Atlantic Copper, where we produce that. The Mitsubishi manages the cathode output at the Gresik plant in Indonesia. So we're not really in that marketplace of supplying cathode to Asia. Our copper concentrate contracts are long-term contracts; they are multi-year contracts, and we sell some concentrate, not a large percentage of our concentrate, into China. We're talking to them about longer-term contracts, but that is marketed in a way of where we get the current market price for the copper and gold that's in the concentrate at the time of the shipment, and then we have annual negotiations of the processing fees, and that would be the structure of any contract we would do in China.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you, and the last question. Now this announcement was made on April 1, so I'm not exactly sure what to make of that, but Bob Friedland over at Ivanhoe made an announcement down in Santiago about what could be a fairly significant find in Katanga; he calls it Kamoa. It's going to produce sulfur, potentially sulfuric acid. It's probably several years out at the earliest, but it's only 100 kilometers from Tenke, and he was talking about ore grades above three, even 4%. He was talking about 10-meter plus deep seams and 100 or 1,000 square kilometers of potentially developable resources. So I mean, can you comment on that? Are there any synergies there? He was also talking about looking for partners to develop the resources. Does this have any impact on Tenke? And the last issue there is he also mentioned that the rail line through Angola was upgraded, it was running to the DRC border. That's, I've heard stories directly to the contrary of that, but I guess my broader question is similar to a question asked earlier: what are the gating factors to increasing the production run rate above 250 million pounds at Tenke? Is it the rail line? What's the progress there, and then is there any thing synergistic in terms of sharing infrastructure resources with something like Kamoa? Maybe sulfur, is that one of the potential sources of sulfur that you were talking about earlier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me say that &#x2013; let's see, Peter, let me see if I can organize, I want to organize my thoughts about this. First of all, I said earlier that to develop Tenke stand-alone basis to its full potential, we'll need rail shipping capabilities, and the Angola railway is an important part of that. Maybe Robert has information that I don't have, but my understanding is that that railroad is not yet complete, and there is some significant bridge work and other work to be done for that. But we are engaged in some long-term planning about upgrading the rail facilities in the Congo to connect with that. And so that does look like the long-term alternative that's most efficient, certainly the closest port for us to get to. So that's important. We will always work to achieve synergies that are available from other operations that may work for us to deal with, and we would certainly work with Ivanhoe or whoever in the area might have some synergies to work with, and if something comes out that makes sense, then we will work for it. That is not the source of sulfur that I was talking about; I was talking about sulfur in the Mideast that comes from very large markets there that have the opportunity for us to access high-quality sulfur. So that was there, but we'll continue to see what happens. The development of an operation that would generate sulfur requires a construction of a concentrator mill of some sort, and that's a big project, so that is somewhere down the road before that would be available.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just in terms of the resource quality that was being mentioned, I mean does that have any bearing on the potential for Tenke?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, in no way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard, let me have this one. Why don't we just put it this way: we don't comment on things that Ivanhoe or any other producer announces, especially till we have a chance to go in and look at the resource, which we'll probably have a chance to do. But I think it'd be best if we just don't comment on the productivity of the ore and et cetera because Ivanhoe is the only one that's really done the work and got the information available to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, understood. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of John Tumazos with John Tumazos Very Independent Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably there's almost 2,000 people at Morenci or other locations that you had to let go. Were pretty good people because you hired them in the first place. What would be the timetable in terms of the copper price or economic conditions in terms of bringing some people back, first?  And second, could you describe and review your tax return by operating country? It looked like from the cash cost and volume, that copper and moly might have had $175 million contribution in terms of output times price minus cash cost in the U.S. But you obviously have depreciation and many overhead items in the U.S. Did you have a profit for taxes in the U.S.? Could you just walk us through the tax return by country?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me say first of all, the workforce, that reduction that we did was done in stages. And I mean we took steps, and it's gone very well. We tried to be as fair to people as they're leaving as when we hire them, and we had an early retirement program. We had an incentivized retirement program and incentivized severance program, and then a lot of the reductions were in the less experienced workers. And one of the, this time a year ago, the biggest challenge we had was finding workers, and we were hiring a lot of inexperienced workers. Employment for these operations in Arizona over the past five years had doubled up to almost 10,000 people. With these cutbacks, we're now down to roughly the level of where the operations were in 2006, at the time we announced the Phelps Dodge transaction. So we had the ability and we've taken steps to retain the more experienced workers. We've done some reassignments of people to different areas so that we could keep the people that were experienced in our operations. And we have &#x2013; so we have curtailed the less experienced people and then the people that were nearing retirement. In the event of economic recovery, there will be a challenge to recruit workers to work in these small towns in Eastern Arizona. I mean that's just a fact of life. Right now in Phoenix, there is significant unemployment, significant opportunities, but if the copper market recovers, Phoenix is going to recover. And so we'll be back in the position of having to take steps to recruit workers. We use some workers globally now. One of the good things that we're able to do is lever off of our operations in Indonesia and elsewhere to bring people into work here, training people in the Congo here. And so it's going to be &#x2013; but that will be a future business problem, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, on the &#x2013; this is Kathleen. On the taxes there is a schedule on page 14 of the press release that goes through, has a table that shows the income by region and the applicable tax rates. In the U.S. we did have a loss in the first quarter for income purposes, which includes the, as Richard was talking about earlier, not only the cash costs, but the depreciation, also interest costs to the parent company and administrative costs. So for book income purposes, it's a loss, and we don't record a benefit on that. So you see how that raises the effective tax rate to 63% during the quarter. But Indonesia, we're continuing to pay at our contract rate of 35%, plus we've got withholding taxes. In Peru the tax rate is 30% plus withholding taxes, and in Chile we've got a 17% income tax rate and a 22% withholding tax rate. So if you have questions after looking at the disclosure, feel free to give us a call, but it's all outlined on page 14.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for calling that to my attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Justine Fisher with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one question about a minimum cash balance that you guys would look to keep on hand. I guess 644 doesn't, to me it doesn't seem low, but it is the lowest that I think we've had since you bought Phelps Dodge, and obviously you've got the entire revolver availability left. But I just wanted to know how you guys plan to look at the cash you keep on the balance sheet versus the total liquidity you keep under the revolver going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the cash on the balance sheet really reflects &#x2013; what we've been doing since the Phelps Dodge transaction is moving as much cash flow as available from the subsidiaries as it's generated up to the parent so that we could service debt, repay debt, pay dividends, et cetera. So that's really been the focus, and while you've seen the cash balance decline since the time of the combination, it's just so that we could be more efficient with our use of cash. So what you see on the balance sheet now is what we have, and we've got some cash in South America that's not able to be distributed because of some statutory rules there. But as we generate additional cash flows, that'll be available to the parent. So we really look at our overall liquidity. As you mentioned, we have a fully unfunded revolver plus the cash. So we really try to look at both the cash and the revolver combined. And we don't have a minimum level of cash. We try to work down our cash as much as possible to be efficient with our capital, but there's not a minimum level of cash that we're looking for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and I know you guys have spoken earlier, like in the fourth quarter you said, "Oh, we expect to draw down X amount of revolver in the first quarter," but I mean it seems obviously, the copper price is the biggest deciding factor here, but it seems that if copper prices remained reasonable, you wouldn't need to draw down the revolver to fund any other major cash outflows through the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct, and that was really the basic reason, Justine, that we did our equity offering. In other words, that in effect funded this working capital requirement, and at the time we said we did it so that we would not have to use our &#x2013; make a big draw under our revolver because we want to have that revolver available for what I think revolvers should be for, and that's unexpected events.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent, thank you so much. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Dave Katz with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you talk a bit about your working capital expectations, specifically you guys have indicated that you &#x2013; at $2 copper you envisage a 600 million working capital use. By my calculations, you had a 900 million use in the first quarter, so does that imply a 300 million source for the rest of the year? And then I was hoping you could also talk about the growth in accounts receivable balances.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Dave, you got it. I mean you're exactly right. We're expecting a source of working capital to offset the use &#x2013; part of the use in the first half of the year, and just think about it: at a time when we're producing additional volumes at Grasberg and so forth, your accounts receivable are going to grow. And that's &#x2013; part of that &#x2013; that's consistent with this deferral we have for intercompany profit sales. So that's just a function of what happens to you when you're producing additional volumes at an operation like Grasberg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Both volumes and prices, higher prices during the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Sanil Daptardar with Sentinel Asset Management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks. Richard, you spoke about if American continent, European, and Japanese recover properly, then there might be a better copper price. But if that all occurs properly, do you need to raise your CapEx that you have outlined for 2010 if the recovery happens sooner than expected, your CapEx around $1 billion, do you need to raise that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, Sentil [sic 1:41:53], we don't need to raise it. I mean because we're doing certain things with our capital expenditures right now. We're maintaining our business, we're not letting our business deteriorate, because we're not having to defer necessary maintenance capital, and we are working to complete Tenke; we are working to continue the underground development at Grasberg, and we have in our plans that I talked about earlier the Sulfolix project at El Abra. So there's no requirements that if that happened to do it. But we will be evaluating the marketplace to see if investing additional capital gives us really strong returns, and that'll be the analysis that we'll go through. But there's nothing out there of some kind of hidden capital requirement that pops up if prices rise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so that raises another question, basically. If that's the case, the forecast that you have shown, free cash flow or cash flow thing, even if the copper goes back to $1.50, you still will be free cash flow positive in 2009. And if it go dollar &#x2013; if copper goes up to 2 bucks, you would be strongly free cash flow positive in 2010 with the CapEx that you outlined. So does that mean that if your priority remains debt payment, you can start resuming your, or you can resume your dividend payments to common stockholders?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that'll be something that our board will review ongoing on a basis as we go forward, and that'll depend on the market outlook. I will tell you we are going to be committed to protecting liquidity in this time of economic uncertainty. And our industry is benefiting by Chinese activity, but there is still a great deal of economic uncertainty in the world, and we're going to be prudent about maintaining liquidity in light of that. So we couldn't be more positive about what we're going to see in the future. This...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The inventories are low. The industry is having a tough time producing copper. You can read current news accounts about that. And the world is going to need copper, and we've got the assets and the resources to produce it. But we're going to be, continue to be prudent about managing our operations in this time of uncertainty because we feel so good about where we're going to be at some point in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, just a last question on the debt levels. You currently have about $7.2 billion. Where do you want to reduce to by the year-end?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're comfortable where our debt level is right now. So any decisions we make to retire debt before its scheduled maturity will depend on the cash flow that we have available and the decisions about how we use that cash flow. But we are very comfortable with our current level of debt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your final question comes from the line of Ross Cardan with Polygon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys, just on Tenke. Do you guys get the 100% writing down allowances for tax?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do we get what now? I couldn't hear you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Are you able to write-off CapEx 100% against taxable profit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, in other words you...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, there...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Depreciation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How does that work?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a depreciation. Within the tax code for the DRC, like with other countries, there's depreciation schedules that are defined by the tax code, which is reflected in our contract. So it's not a 100% write-off, but it is an accelerated depreciation method that's an accounting-based determination of income, which is not unlike that of the situation in the U.S. or other countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Is there any guidance you can give me? For example, is it over a four-year period, or how accelerated is it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll tell you. Let's follow up with that. It's kind of a typical deal, and I've seen analysis on it, but I don't want to just comment off the top of my head as to how it works. But for the group as a whole, this is kind of a standard tax depreciation methodology that's typical for what we see in the U.S. and Indonesia and South America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Ross, give us a call, and we'll follow up with you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, will do. Second question, again relating to Tenke, is on the power. Earlier you said that that you have it available, it's not a constraint. I just wanted to ask you, let's say tomorrow you decided that you were going to do 200,000 tons of copper, would the power be available? Or is there more work to be done both by yourself and other parties? And if so, who are the other parties that are involved in the power projects?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the power is available. The question is extended reliability, and that's why we've entered into this arrangement with a government entity called SNEL [Societe Nationale d'Electricite], which is the Congolese power authority. And under that arrangement, we are investing in the restoration of hydropower facilities that will improve the availability and reliability of power over the long run, and that's in progress now. We're doing this in the form of a loan that will get repaid based on our uses of power over time. But there is a great source of hydropower in the country, and that will be an advantage because of that. In terms of its availability and its cost, it'll be low-cost power for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, other parties other than SNEL and yourselves involved in that project, are you relying on other people to put up the cash as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, not for this project. There are others who are also have had plans to make investments in other facilities. And some of those have been deferred and so forth, but our project is a Tenke Fungurume mining project, and it's going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, just a third question, again on Tenke. If Lundin Mining do not have the cash or cannot raise the financing available to fund, let's say, a second-stage expansion, would you provide them with a free carry? And then, once that's paid off, then they would start receiving dividend. Is that how it would work?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no we have &#x2013; there's no obligation for us to provide any free carry to our partner there. They've indicated an ability to fund their cost going forward. And if they're unable to do that, our joint venture arrangement covers how we would handle that. But we have no obligation to provide a free carry for our partner, Lundin, who I will say has been a good partner for us in our project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Okay, and just one last question, again on Tenke. I was looking at the feasibility that you put out in March, and it looks like &#x2013; when you look at the tons that you're mining, so the tons of ore versus what you're sending to the mill, there's a big difference there, and it looks like &#x2013; when you look at the grade that you're sending to the mill versus the head grade that you're mining, so you're screening what you send to the mill, but would it not be more cost effective to be more selective in the mining, rather than the feed that you send to the mill, because there's a huge amount of material that you're stockpiling?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ross, we didn't put out any feasibility study in March.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, it was the Lundin report, the one on the Lundin side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, so we didn't put it out. We are managing the project to give us the grade of ore to make this initial project feasible and attractive. As in mining operations, it's typical. We also have to mine some ore that we then are stockpiling that's lower grade, and then we'll be developing longer-term plans about how to deal with that ore in the processing, but this is all in accordance with our long-term life-of-mine plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Okay, all right. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Everyone, we really appreciate your participation in the call. We know we had a lot of questions, but if you have others, we're available to respond to them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard let me just make one final comment. We didn't talk a lot about if questions had come up; we had a slide that showed that we reduced our exploration expenditure significantly to $75 million. I want to remind everybody that we made a policy decision during the acquisition of Phelps Dodge that we'd go in and spend almost $300 million or driven drill holes that, outside the traditional areas, had been drilled by Phelps Dodge. I just wanted to report to you that we continue to, even with the expenditures for actual drilling operation cut substantially to get to the $75 million level, all the data that we picked up during the $300 million expenditure to try to better understand what kind of ore we had, it was outside the existing ore body developed by Phelps Dodge. It continues on a daily basis. Our whole group is focusing on analyzing information that we acquired over that 18-month period when we were drilling unprecedented amounts of wealth, and we continue to see ore grades continue below the bottom of the pits that were existing and areas adjacent to it, even the bridges between the existing pits. So you can, you will be happy to know that there's a substantial amount of ore that's going to be brought into proven category over the years as a result of the intense drilling program that we did. So exploration is alive and breathing, and the amount of money we're spending has no impact on the potential of adding new orders in 2009, 2010, 2011. We continue that in a very energetic way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks to you, Bob. That's the future of our company and one that we're all just tremendously excited about. We saw, when we were doing initial due diligence on Phelps Dodge and then after we got into this, it was a great opportunity to make an attractive purchase based on what was known at the time, but this ability to add values that are not reflected today [end tape 1:53:40] in our stock price and for our shareholders to have the opportunity to capture all of these values in the future, is what we are really focused on and it's a lot more accretive than going out and trying to acquire any kind of existing operation. So, it's a real exciting part of our future. Once again thanks, thanks to everybody and we'll look forward to speaking with you about our year as it progresses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that concludes our call for today. Thank you for your participation, you may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>