<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1242805" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-21</date>
    <companies>
      <company>200</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Kathleen L. Quirk, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Richard C. Adkerson, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Michael Gambardella</participant>
      <participant id="4">Tony Rizzuto</participant>
      <participant id="5">Kuni Chen</participant>
      <participant id="6">Jorge Beristain</participant>
      <participant id="7">John Tumazos</participant>
      <participant id="8">Charles Bradford</participant>
      <participant id="9">James Moffett</participant>
      <participant id="10">Mark Liinamaa</participant>
      <participant id="11">Wayne Atwell</participant>
      <participant id="12">Lawrence Smith</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to the Freeport-McMoRan Copper &amp; Gold Second Quarter Earnings Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, we will conduct a question and answer session. [Operator Instructions.]</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to Ms. Kathleen Quirk, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer. Please go ahead, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and good morning everyone. Welcome to the Freeport-McMoRan Copper &amp; Gold second quarter 2009 earnings conference call. Our earnings announcement was released earlier this morning, and a copy of the release is available on our website at fcx.com. Our conference call today is being broadcast live on the Internet, and we'll have several slides to supplement our comments this morning. The slides are accessible using the webcast link on our fcx.com website homepage. In addition to analysts and investors, the financial press has also been invited to listen to today's call, and a replay of the call will be available by accessing the webcast link on our Internet homepage later today.</p>
          <p>Before we begin today's comments, we'd like to remind everyone that today's press release and certain of our comments on this call include forward-looking statements. Please refer to the cautionary language included in our press release and slide presentation and to the risk factors described in our SEC filings.</p>
          <p>On the call today are Jim Bob Moffett, Chairman of the Board; Richard Adkerson, our President and Chief Executive Officer; we've also got Dave Thornton and Red Conger with us today. I'll start by briefly summarizing our financial results and then turn the call over to Richard, who will be referring to the slide presentation material that's on our website. We'll then open the call for questions.</p>
          <p>Today FCX reported second quarter 2009 net income attributable to common stock of 588 million or $1.38 per share compared with 947 million or $2.25 per share for the second quarter of 2008.  For the six-month period ended June 30, 2009, FCX reported net income attributable to common stock of 631 million or $1.54 per share compared with 2.1 billion or $4.89 per share in the six month 2008 period.</p>
          <p>Our sales in the second quarter for copper were 1.1 billion pounds; that was higher than last year's second quarter sales of 942 million pounds and our April 2009 estimate of 955 million pounds. The increase from the prior year reflects the mining of a high-grade section in the Grasberg open pit, partially offset by our reduced operating rates in North America. The favorable variance to our prior estimates reflects the accelerated mining of a high-grade section in the Grasberg open pit during the second quarter, which was previously planned for future periods.</p>
          <p>For gold we sold [sic] 837 [837,000] ounces during the quarter; that was significantly higher than the 265,000 ounces sold in 2008 second quarter. Again, we were mining in a very high-grade section of the Grasberg pit, which enabled us to exceed our April 2009 estimates of 650,000 ounces.</p>
          <p>Molybdenum sales of 16 million pounds in the second quarter were lower than last year's level of 20 million pounds, but higher than our 2009 estimate of 11 million pounds. Our sales during the second quarter reflect increased sales to Europe and Asia compared with the first quarter levels and with our previous estimates.</p>
          <p>Our recorded copper prices averaged $2.22 per pound in the second quarter; that was a significant reduction from last year's second quarter. Gold prices of $932 per ounce were slightly above $912 per ounce in the year-ago period. We realized $10.11 per pound of molybdenum during the second quarter of 2009, significantly lower than last year's level of just under $32 per pound.</p>
          <p>We &#x2013; the results reflect our strong performance really across all of our operations and particularly in the Grasberg mine, where we operated at, where all of our gold revenues offset all of our, all of the costs of production there. Our unit costs on a consolidated basis averaged $0.43 per pound during the second quarter; that was significantly lower than last year's $1.25 per pound net of by-product credits.</p>
          <p>The operating cash flows in the second quarter were significant at $1.2 billion; on a year to date basis that brings our operating cash flows to 896 million in the first six months of 2009, that was net of nearly $1 billion in working capital uses that we had earlier this year primarily associated with the settlements on our provisionally priced prior-year copper sale.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditures during the quarter totaled 375 million and year to date 894 million; our spending is expected to decline in the second half, reflecting a substantial completion of our construction activities at the Tenke Fungurume project, which Rich is going to talk more about.</p>
          <p>We ended the quarter in a strong financial position. Our total debt approximated 7.2 billion and our cash balance grew to 1.3 billion during the quarter. We had no amounts borrowed under our revolving credit facility at June 30. We also announced separately today that we are calling for redemption our 6&#x215E; senior notes due 2014. Those have a principal amount of 340 million. What that will allow us to do is to reduce our interest expense by roughly 23 million and reduce our debt levels and improve our financial flexibility.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to turn the call over to Richard, who will be referring to the materials on our website.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Kathleen. Before I turn to the quarter, I'm going to take just a few minutes to review the recent events in Indonesia that you've been reading about in the paper. Last Friday, on July 17, bombs were detonated at two hotels in Jakarta's downtown business district. These hotels are used by international travelers, and we had several people staying there; fortunately they weren't injured. However, two of our senior people who reside in Jakarta were at a business breakfast meeting and they were injured, they are now being treated, and are in stable condition.</p>
          <p>This is in the backdrop of a situation in Indonesia where there's been a very peaceful environment for a number of years now. The President, Yudhoyono, has been credited for his actions against terrorists and he has indicated a very strong response to this recent event. On July 8, there was a presidential election, the final results are going to be announced later this week, but SBY, based own polls that are deemed to be accurate, has won by a wide majority, and he ran on a platform of anti-terrorism, anti-corruption, pro-business investment, and has great support in Indonesia.</p>
          <p>At job site on the day of the election, we had a group of people attempt to block our road leading to our mine, and they committed some vandalism, they were unsuccessful with that. However, beginning on July 11, further down the road in the lowlands, we had several days with an isolated incident of shootings. Unfortunately, one of our employees, a contract security personnel and an Indonesian policemen were killed in these attacks, several people were injured. Yesterday the Indonesian police &#x2013; and we were very pleased with the response from the authorities; they brought in additional securities, undertook investigation and now in a very short period of time they announced that they have arrested 15 people and charged six of them with murder and have indicated that one of those has admitted to being the sniper in these events. And we appreciate really the quick and firm response of the Indonesian authorities to this event.</p>
          <p>We've been assured from the highest levels of government in Indonesia that they are committed to provide safety for our people and for our operations. Throughout this period of time, our mine and milling operations continued unaffected by this. We had some travel restrictions on the road, but we have been able to continue operations.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the quarter. When you look at the totality of our operations, it'd be difficult to imagine a better performance. I have &#x2013; I'm very proud of the way the operating team responded to the plans that we established earlier this year, and across the company, in North America, South America, Indonesia and in Africa, we have &#x2013; we've performed very well. Of course we've benefited by the fact that copper prices at today's levels and in the second quarter are higher than most anticipated and that's positive for our cash flows and our earnings. And we also benefit from the fact that based on our planned mining sequence, we were in a very high-grade section of the Grasberg mine, which we'll be in for some time now, which gave us strong volumes of both copper and gold, and that benefited operations. But underlying all of that is the fact that we had good plans and we operated to meet those plans.</p>
          <p>On page four, Kathleen talked about our numbers. But when you look at the outlook that we gave at our last quarterly call, our copper volumes were 15% higher, our gold volumes were 29% higher, that's driven principally by the fact that we were able to optimize our access to the high-grade ore at Grasberg, some of it is moving some volumes forward, but we always try to do that as we operate while we meet our long-term objectives with our mind of maintaining stability in our long-term mine plan. We had higher molybdenum sales. Some of this came from inventory, but with demand out of China, we were able to sell more moly than we anticipated going into the quarter. Strong operating performance, we had initial copper sales out of Tenke. I'll talk about that. We have not included any sales in the second quarter. We'll be ramping up that operation to designed capacity in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Our revised sales outlook, we're staying with our previous guidance for copper sales for the year, but we are showing some increases in both copper and molybdenum for the year, and we'll be trying to maximize opportunities to increase sales as we go forward.</p>
          <p>Page five shows by region what our unit cash cost performance has been. Now for our company, combined taking into account gold and moly credits, our net unit cost was $0.43 a pound for the second quarter, and that's a strong performance. It reflects the high volumes of copper, the high volumes of gold, the strong gold price in Indonesia, where we had a credit of more than $0.50 a pound. But also in North America, where we've seen the moly price drop have a negative impact on unit cost. We've been able to offset that by taking advantage of lower input costs but also adjusting our operations to be more efficient. And to have an experience of $1.12 per pound is very strong with also good performance in South America. That's for the quarter.</p>
          <p>On page six, you can see the details of that; it reflects a 35% increase on a consolidated basis of our site production delivery costs before by-product credits for the second quarter of last year to the second quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>And page seven, where we have the particular issue associated with these large, low-grade deposits that we operate here, we had a particular focus on reducing high-cost volumes, aggressively pursuing lower input costs and aggressively seeing efficiencies and that really has resulted in a reduction of a third on the unit cash cost before by-product credits, which helps offset the loss of the molybdenum credits because of price actions.</p>
          <p>From a market standpoint, the recent upward movement in copper prices reflects some important fundamentals about this business that are going to be important for the long run, and that is the requirements for copper in China and the developing world. I mean, that's an important feature of our industry that's become apparent in the 2000's and it's going to be something that's long term.</p>
          <p>To build infrastructure, to expand economies, requires copper. We're certainly seeing that in China, as China has been doing that, and it's in the context of a very tight market. Exchange stocks have dropped dramatically, but inventories around the world today, outside of accumulations of China apparently for their strategic reserves of copper, but inventories of consumers around the world are very, very tight; and even in the United States where market conditions remain weak, we have orders from customers when they do have requirements of copper that they aren't able to fill from their inventories. And so in the context that of a weak environment in the U.S. and the western world, inventories are very low. The industry has and continues to face issues with new projects maintaining supplies out of existing mines.</p>
          <p>So the supply situation for copper is very well situated for miners, and all of this indicates a very bright future in our view for copper, and we're committed to being a very strong supplier of copper with great growth projects as we go forward.</p>
          <p>In the moly markets, the price dropped. We now had a period of destocking. Demand from China has emerged for western molybdenum. Their Chinese mines are relatively high cost, so they're buying copper from the western &#x2013; I mean, buying molybdenum from the western world. The market remained tight, the prices picked up, and we are, adjusted our operations and prepared to be able to provide the moly that the market needs. Gold prices are strong, that's a big benefit, as I indicated, for Grasberg and for our overall company.</p>
          <p>Page nine shows our current outlook for sales volumes. We're looking at roughly four billion pounds of copper as we go forward in future years. Of course, we had plans and we were operating to have substantially higher volumes, but we adjusted those plans as we went into 2009 in response to the lower prices, but that's &#x2013; this is our current outlook. You can see in the gold sales chart the impact of moving from the low-grade section of Grasberg to the higher-grade section, as I said we'll remain there for some time; and our molybdenum sales are a reflection of the requirements of the marketplace.</p>
          <p>On a quarterly basis &#x2013; in terms of our plans, this looks to be our largest volume quarter for copper sales. We advanced some copper sales out of the second half of the year into this quarter for Grasberg. We'll continue to try to find opportunities to do that as we go forward into the second half of the year, and you can see the impact on gold sales in the chart on the right hand side.</p>
          <p>By unit as we look to &#x2013; by region as we look forward for sales and unit production costs for the year 2009, we are continuing to look at strong performance from a cost standpoint. Our consolidated unit costs net of by-product credits is anticipated to be $0.70 a pound, that's at $900 gold and $8 molybdenum, which provide the credits. And so in North America you can see that we're looking at sub-$1.20 pound for our unit cost, roughly $1.10 in South America, and in Indonesia for the year, we're looking to see our gold revenues totally fund our operating costs for that operation.</p>
          <p>Page 12, even though we're spending less dollars on exploration, we're not at all reducing our emphasis on exploration. The dollar reduction reflects the fact that we have curtailed some of our core hole drilling. We have done substantial amounts of drilling both in 2007 and 2008, and our exploration team is using the new data that was received from that drilling to evaluate opportunities to add to our reserves and then to add to future development projects, which we see as being very substantial as we go forward. So it's a question of using the data that we have gained previously and limiting the amount of current expenditures on core hole drilling.</p>
          <p>Page 13 shows just the strong cash flow generating capacity of our company; the chart at the top is EBITDA, at the bottom is operating cash flow excluding working capital changes, but it takes into account cash taxes and cash interest. At $2.25 copper before working capital, we would be generating on an annual basis over $3.5 billion of operating cash flows. We did have some working capital requirements, as previously reported in the first half of this year, and you see how that would vary depending on changes in the copper price.</p>
          <p>On the next chart we give a series of important input elements to determination of cash flows, both in terms of copper prices, molybdenum prices, gold prices as well as certain important input costs, so that you can get some sense to how leveraged we are to these various factors. And of course the biggest leverage factor for our company is the price of copper, where every $0.10 change means $260 million of cash flow variance for our company.</p>
          <p>We have limited capital expenditures; page 15 shows how we reduced CapEx from 2008 to now our current estimate for 2009 of 1.4 billion. That includes our ability to reduce some of our sustaining capital. And in 2009 we have two projects we are pursuing: the completion of construction of the Tenke Fungurume project in Africa, and construction is essentially complete on that project now. And in 2009, 2010 we are continuing with CapEx for the underground development at Grasberg for the transition in the future in roughly 2015 from open-pit operations to mining fully underground there with our very large undeveloped underground reserves.</p>
          <p>In 2010, we have included the commencement of a project at El Abra in South America to develop a sulfide orebody there. We're going to make a final decision on that this fall, but with copper prices being where they are, we're very likely to go forward with that project; we had retained the ability to defer it if we needed to do that.</p>
          <p>In Africa, I want to report on the status of the Tenke Fungurume project. As I mentioned, during the second quarter we did commence copper production and we sold 36 million pounds of &#x2013; we produced 36 million pounds of copper and sold 26 million pounds. Copper circuit is complete from a construction standpoint, we are working through startup issues now. We are &#x2013; we've completed and are commissioning the cobalt circuit, and the sulfuric acid plant is starting up as we speak now in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>By some time in the second half of the year we will be up to design capacity; the aggregate annual production over time for this is 250 million pounds of copper and 18 million pounds of cobalt.  We are continuing to conduct exploration analysis, and our expectations are that we'll be adding major amounts of reserves to this project over the years and that there will be opportunities for a series of expansion opportunities to build this up to be a world class &#x2013; world-class mining operation.</p>
          <p>You can see just how rapid we made progress there with the pictures on the next series of charts. January 2006, that was after we had announced the Phelps Dodge acquisition in December, PD's Board had approved the project, but you can see there was nothing there except African landscape. During the next year there was some work done, but limited amount of work, principally earth work that was completed during 2007.</p>
          <p>Early in 2008 we began construction in earnest, and in a 15-month period constructed a world-class mining operation that involves agitate leach processing, a cobalt plant, acid plant, world-class environmental management with lime tailings, dams, et cetera and now we have this &#x2013; this construction completed. You can see pictures of the processing facilities on page 20. I'm very pleased with the way this construction has gone.</p>
          <p>This is the largest investment in the DRC. As I said, we're building it to world-class standards, just as we would build a project anywhere in the world. We've built the infrastructure there to support future expansion opportunities, spent more money than we would have otherwise in doing that, and also investing in social community programs that will provide benefits to the local people and to the country. And this is a region of the world that's, needs employment and needs the kind of support that we're providing.</p>
          <p>The schematic of the Grasberg mine is mining operations, and it's shown on page 22; there is further information that's in our slides that we will have available to us for questions. But for those of you who have followed us, it's a traditional set of slides we've presented for Grasberg. Right now we're mining from the Grasberg open pit as well as from the underground DOZ mine. The DOZ mine has been operating at better than 70 million tons a day, which makes it one of the world's, if not the world's, largest block cave, 1,000 tons per day, that's &#x2013; that makes it one of the world's largest underground mining operations.</p>
          <p>The pit is scheduled to be operated until roughly 2015, and then we have substantial reserves from this ore body, same ore body that extends underground with the Grasberg block cave. We are &#x2013; we've constructed access to those reserves and we'll begin mine development &#x2013; are beginning mine development. And over time we have the Grasberg block cave, the Kucing Liar mine and further expansions of the DOZ mine that will allow this operation to be a very large, low-cap-cost producer, large-volume, low-cost producer for decades to come.</p>
          <p>Page 23 shows our debt structure and our maturities. Today we are using some of the cash that we've made with the operations and copper prices to call $350 million of our 6&#x215E; bonds that were callable under their terms. Pro forma that transaction you can see just how little debt requirements we have for a number of years. Essentially, the debt we have left is the &#x2013; is the $6 billion of high-yield bonds that we incurred in the Phelps Dodge transaction, and we'll be looking to &#x2013; looking for opportunities, if they're available in the marketplace, to further reduce our debt potentially.</p>
          <p>At this time, we're going to continue to maintain a strong balance sheet and liquidity position, and we have one right now. We're going to continue to aggressively manage costs. Some of the efficiencies in cost savings that we have are driven by lower input costs, and they may change over time, but some of these efficiencies that we have are going to be sustainable. And so we are going to have a &#x2013; we are going to have a better cost structure for the future because of the actions that we've been required to take now in response to lower prices.</p>
          <p>We are limiting capital expenditures for the present time, we are going to be prepared, if market conditions warrant, to go back to these projects. And we've retained all the rights, we still have the ability to undertake all the projects we had that we were looking at a year ago. They're still there, we've developed plans to reinstitute those to upgrade our curtailment on production when market conditions warrant.</p>
          <p>So near term we are going to continue to protect our liquidity as we preserve these large mineral resources and growth opportunities; we review every Board meeting the Board's financial policy; our company has a tradition of paying shareholder returns in the form of dividends and stock buybacks. And again, at the appropriate time, I feel confident our Board will, will be back in executing that policy.</p>
          <p>With that, we'll be pleased to respond to any questions that any of you might have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen we will now being the question and answer session. [Operator Instructions.] Your first question comes from the line of Michael Gambardella of JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, and congratulations on a good quarter and especially good results on the cost side even at the &#x2013; at the site. Two questions, one on the buyback of the bonds, which I also liked very much. Could we anticipate restoration of the dividend in the short-term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike, that is something that we will be reviewing with the Board, and here's sort of the context that we will be looking at that. We have some very attractive investment opportunities for capital in our projects. And we'll be balancing the amount of cash that we have being generated, potential opportunities that we might have with further debt reductions, although the structure of that debt will provide some limitations to that. And then the &#x2013; if we have additional incremental cash, that would be available to look for potential restoration of the dividend.</p>
          <p>So it's a combination of all three of those factors. A lot of it depends on how the world unfolds right now. It's &#x2013; China is setting records with their imports, it's been supportive of prices, and we certainly hope that the western world's economies recover. If they do, we're going to be in the position of generating a lot of cash and we'll be able to probably execute on all three of those objectives.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the second question, as regards to Tenke, what are the chances of getting of rail connection for Tenke?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think ultimately that's &#x2013; that will happen. The rail connection, while there will be some restoration of some rail connections elsewhere, the primary one we're looking to would be a railroad connecting to the Angolan railroad to give us access to the port in Angola. And for some time now the Chinese have been working in Angola to restore that railroad, there's some plans to upgrade the railroad within the Congo. That will be necessary for us to achieve the kinds of expansion opportunities that we have with this ore body, because we are looking at, we are looking at growing it to be, to have very high volumes, and the rail connection will be a necessary element for that to occur.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's really the optionality on Tenke, the rail connection.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The optionality comes from the ore body, of course...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In that, we feel...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then in getting it out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But yeah, when you start talking about this being a four or 500,000 ton copper production, you are looking at sulfide production and you will need the rail to do that. We are, we are being successful with our trucking operations in getting product to market; of course we've used those trucks and those roads to bring in the, bring in the components to building the construction project, but to get to be the kind of mine we think this mine has the opportunity to be, that rail is going to be a key factor for it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Mike, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Tony Rizzuto of Dahlman Rose.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Congrats, Richard and team on the excellent progress and results in the debt reduction and everything too. I have got a couple of questions for you, the first one is I wonder if you could share with us your current thoughts on restarts of copper output, and with copper prices up near 2.50 per pound and the Chinese imports being very strong this year, do we still need to see the rest of the world contribute to the global demand at this time, Richard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Tony, in terms of returning to the expansion projects that we were pursuing, the answer is, yes. We're going to need to see recovery in the U.S. and the western world to warrant going back and going for the expansion opportunities. But Red Conger had his team here last week. We went through each of the mines and we're looking at opportunities that we may have to increase some volumes without &#x2013; without spending expansion-type capital. But, as we're learning and evaluating the experience we've had now for six months in operating under our new plans, we're going to see some opportunities to have some incremental volumes, and we will be reporting on the results of those as we develop and complete those plans.</p>
          <p>I think absent any real negative change, we're highly likely to go forward with the Sulfolix project at El Abra, and we will have the opportunities to look for, to look for the chances of adding some volumes from our other operations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So we should think about it that you're going to be able to certainly flex your production as you can do in moly very well and continue to look at it from that point of view with copper as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly. We're going to &#x2013; we were focused on the long run about where we need to be with these operations. One of the things we've found is, we'd expanded so quickly that now as we've scaled back production, we've gotten much more efficient with our workforce. Our safety statics are improved. And we're learning some efficiencies that we can gain by having &#x2013; having on average a more skilled workforce now. And so now we're just, we're going to take advantage of that and see how can we efficiently do things to optimize, I call it more than optimization, of the ore bodies and so forth.</p>
          <p>And with moly, with the Henderson mine, it's a very efficient mine, and it would be a mine that Dave Thornton and his guys could scale back up. We have some moly inventory right now, but it's a mine that's more easily scalable upward than something of where we'd have to go out in a significant way and go out and add to our workforce like we'd have to do if we were to significantly scale up Morenci, for example.</p>
          <p>But we had a good quarter with volumes and we're going to focus on the second half of the year. Opportunities at Grasberg to advance volumes, we do that continually, we're going to look for optimization of our mines in North and South America, we're going to look to see Tenke ramp up to its design capacity, and all the time we're going to be focused on our costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Richard, my second question, I was just thumbing through here in the, on slide 28 and it looks like the PT-FI mine plan in 2013, it looks like it is a steeper, a little bit steeper drop than in the previous estimate. How comfortable are you with all the opportunities you have and the flexing of your various mining operations throughout the world and certainly the excellent potential of Tenke that this decline at the Grasberg can more than be offset by these other opportunities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the 2013 number that you're seeing actually reflects the positive news of our mine plan of moving some of those volumes forward. At last quarter, we were showing a drop-off in 2011. And as part of our ongoing mine plans, we keep looking to try to adjust those in ways to accelerate metal and at the same time achieve the safety factor in terms of geotechnical factors in the long-term mine plan.</p>
          <p>So you're seeing the results of a lot of work that we've been focused on in trying to deal with what was a significant drop-off in 2011. Now we're working on 2012 and other numbers, and you know the years 2014, 2015, the last years of this operation will be very strong years because we will be mining &#x2013; much less waste will be down in the core of the ore body. So all of this is just part of our ongoing process of trying to accelerate volumes and improve the net present value of cash flows from these, from this great ore body.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Yeah, that is correct. I mean, I'm looking at 2011 and 2012 and you have raised those estimates there as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, excellent. Thank you very much, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line Kuni Chen of Banc of America Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good day, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Kuni.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just hoping you could &#x2013; we could dig into Tenke for a little bit. I think last quarter you guys said that the contract review process would be coming to a resolution near term, just want to get an update there and see what you, what's new with that process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kuni, truth is, I didn't predict that it would &#x2013; when it would come to completion. There were signs at the time of the last quarter that the government was moving towards that, and nothing negative has happened since then. But during the summer months, there has been some changes within the government in Indonesia, and indication that there'll be a further realignment of the cabinet responsibilities and so forth. And as a practical matter, there's been a period of time that not much has happened from an overall government policy standpoint during these summer months, and we have really heard nothing for some time now about any activity related to the contract review.</p>
          <p>I just want to remind everybody on the call that we have a contract; our contract is a binding contract that has been renegotiated, that is accepted by the government of the Congo as being a contract in force, and we're actually running our business and selling product under the terms of that contract. But there has been no, absolutely no recent commentary or developments with respect to the contract review.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And just as a follow-up, I don't know if you had commented earlier in the call, perhaps I missed it, but as far as the copper sales outlook here in the second half, sequentially it's lower. Is that due to mine sequencing or is there another factor that's <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> it's all...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's all Grasberg, and it reflects the fact that we were successful in taking some second-half volumes and producing them in the second quarter. So this is our current outlook. We're going to work to optimize that as we go forward. And over time our team has been very successful in adding volumes, particularly when we're in this high-grade section that we're mining now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you're still in the same high grade in the second half or you've moved to a sequence in a different part of the Grasberg mine?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's been a real simplification to talk about this being in high grade. We are in the bottom of the pit with substantial mining equipment. It's &#x2013; the pit is almost three kilometers across and over a kilometer deep. So and we're moving 700,000 tons a day of material. So it's a very large operation but we will continue in the second half, into 2010 and some in 2011 of mining in the lower reaches of this mine, where the grades are very high.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jorge Beristain of Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Richard and everybody, again congratulations on a strong quarter. My comment or my question was really more to do with the guidance page that you have on page 11 of your slide packet. The implied site production costs for the, if I'm reading this correctly for the full year, still stand at $1.15 for site production and delivery unit costs on a consolidated basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct, Jorge.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Which would imply the second half to be roughly $1.25 a pound for site production if we just take the average of what you've already done in the first half versus your full year estimates. I just wanted to understand is that, is there upside to that number? In other words, do you think that unit costs could come in lower than that guidance, or will this be a function of the fact that you are expecting lower copper sales going forward and therefore, just the &#x2013; there'll be less dilution over less volumes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's more that second point that you just said. If you look back to page 10, we are showing at Grasberg a drop of roughly 200 million pounds of sales for each quarter. So you have &#x2013; your denominator is going to be lower. There's also energy cost assumptions that we've made here that has an impact; you know, the price of energy has ticked up some in recent weeks. So we've factored that in there. End of the day it will be what it will end up being, and we have a very attractive cost structure, given the nature of our mines and where we were as late as third quarter of last year. But in terms of calculating that number, that factor that you mentioned of having the lower volumes out of Grasberg is the most important one of the factors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the year, the $0.70 average cash cost is similar to &#x2013; is exactly what we reported at the end of the first quarter call, but it does reflect higher by-product credits from having more gold, we added 100,000 ounces of gold from Grasberg in 2009, and it also includes the factors Richard was talking about. We've seen some increases in our energy costs, we've also seen the impacts of the weakened U.S. dollar from earlier in the year, and then we've also got slightly higher TC/RCs, which is a function of the price increase that we've experienced.</p>
          <p>So the second half is expected to be higher than the first half just as a function of volumes, but on average for the year it's very similar to what we reported in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Jorge, if you just go back to page five and compare five to 11, you can see that, you know, in the second quarter Grasberg pre just site production delivery cost was $0.93, and now we're showing $1.11 for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And my second question was just related to Tenk. From an accounting point of view, I gather right now you are still in the inventory accumulation phase with the production, but I would expect in the third quarter we'll start to see some actual sales volumes. If you could give us some kind of guidance as to what kind of sales volumes do you expect to reflect and also what kind of implied unit costs you are now seeing out there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We actually, as I mentioned, we had $26 million of sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pounds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pounds, 26 million pounds of ships of sales in the second quarter. We do have still some start-up costs that we're treating as sort of inventory like costs. But by the second half of the year, all of our production costs will be flowing in. We will be up to design capacity. At design capacity and with $10 cobalt, we are looking at unit costs being less than $0.50 a pound.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the year, we're estimating sales of 100 million pounds from that operation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, and by the third quarter do you think you'll start to reflect Tenke in your overall guidance for unit costs on a consolidated basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just say we'll do that when we get to this design capacity. That could be third quarter, it will be in the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of John Tumazos of John Tumazos, Very Independent Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Rich, congratulations on the good results. And sort of following up maybe on Mike's initial question, what &#x2013; how good do things have to be for share repurchases, higher exploration spending, maybe relaxing the cut-off grades at some of the lower-grade mines, finishing Climax, finishing Tenke? In your initial remarks you talked about the strength of Asia and the developing world, and how much further do you want to see the copper price advance to begin investing or to prepare for that more aggressively?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, I think it's simply a question of when we see economic recovery I'm going to say in the U.S. and the western world. It's just that simple. It's not so much a function of the copper price; at the price we have today, it would warrant a number of the actions you just mentioned. But that price is really driven by China, and there is obviously risk in the Chinese situation depending on their buying patterns, etcetera. So it's going to be a question of recovery in the economies in the U.S. and that's talked about every day in the newspapers and on cable TV. So that will be what will drive us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When you see the western world recovering, what do you guess your target dividend pay-out might be vis-&#xE0;-vis the various good investment opportunities on several continents?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the initial focus is going to be on investment, because we will &#x2013; we have such great opportunities to invest. They are not greenfield projects, that has this enormous amount of capital in today's world, but they are brownfield expansions, and those will really be projects around the world. So we'll do that, and then as we've always done, and you can just look at the history of the Freeport organization, after we've determined what's the appropriate allocation for capital, what the right financial structure of the balance sheet is, some of that capital might be financed by debt, then we're going to be very aggressive in returning cash to shareholders. The Board will make that decision, but I am confident that's the policy, that's what the Board will decide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Charles Bradford of Affiliated Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chuck.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Bing primarily an equity guy, I have a question on the debt side. I mean, clearly buying back the senior notes makes a lot of sense, but why not go after some of the higher rate notes for the following couple of years? Are there some covenants that inhibit you buying back those securities? Or is the premium too big or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's just the structure of the notes, the notes we called back, number one, they were callable under their terms, the other notes aren't callable yet. But the second point was these were some of our older notes that had more restrictive covenants than, and our covenants even in these weren't very restrictive. So, but in terms of the relative covenant package in these notes versus others, these are good ones to get out of the way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good answer, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Chuck, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Terence Ortslan of TSO Associates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Terence.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>2010, you paid about half a billion dollars for El Abra and also for Grasberg underground. That assumes again that third quarter this year or second half of this year you are going to make a decision on El Abra, am I right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and from a point of your parameters for El Abra, the time it will take to get out the sulfides and the scale you're talking about is roughly what, Richard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the timing for the development of the sulfide project is roughly two years. And if we make a decision later this fall we have all the environmental permits in place, we've dealt with our partners, we probably could start spending money as early as later this year. And it's a very attractive project. The ore body has been defined and metallurgical work is done, it would add 300 million pounds-plus copper for 10 or 12 years to the project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It replaces the oxide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The oxide that we've been mining has been the traditional source of ore for this operation.</p>
          <p>We continue to drill at El Abra, and continue, in fact one of the things that's happened over this past year with the drilling that I mentioned earlier is that our view of El Abra is changing. The ore body is larger than we had anticipated. There's more volumes. And so that leads us into longer-term studies about how we might expand that operation further with potentially a milling option. And so that is something that's currently under study, and it's just one of the many opportunities we have with this company, to think about even a bigger operation than the Sulfolix project conditions. And of course milling gives you much higher recovery rates than a sulfide leach project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Given the....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Jim Bob. I might just jump in and just say that the description that you've just given of El Abra pretty much goes across the board on our properties. As you've reported already, we're spending lots of geologic time and mine planning time looking at the results of the big program that we instituted several years ago right after the merger of the two companies and the &#x2013; as I say, the El Abra description that we just talked about can be really taken across the board on all of our properties. And the reason why that opportunity is there is because in lower copper price environments, as you know, the big reason why people went to the oxide ores was because they could be leached, and which for all of you, as all of you know, you don't have to have a mine that has to have a mill, you don't have to pay smelter costs, etcetera, etcetera. You just take the oxide ore and everybody knows on the call, but for those who don't, the only difference between oxide ore and sulfide ore is a portion of the ore body has been eroded and been basically oxidized by erosion.</p>
          <p>So if you can just imagine these ore bodies and imagine an ore body that's buried underground, the portion of the ore body that's exposed to the atmosphere and from the groundwater leaching, etcetera, etcetera, to basically create this oxide peach, if you will, it's kind of a, to use a illustration it's kind of like a big peach that's starting to get overripe, and you get to use the ripened areas on the outside of the peach and the inside of the peach is still unaffected by the fact that it's being reached by oxygen. So we got big peaches sitting around, to make a simple comparison for you.</p>
          <p>And if you look at the overripe part of the peach, that's what we've taken and put into these leach pads because of the lower price of the copper. As copper prices go up, we can go into the good part of the peach, take that peach, and go from a leach to a mill. And we've got some very big reserves across the board, not just at El Abra but at Cerro Verde, Morenci, Safford, on all these projects that you've identified over the years that have been leached by using oxide ore.</p>
          <p>And our drilling across the board has shown that the big part of these ore bodies are the sulfide ores, and there is unbelievable opportunities for expanding the size of the pits. At Morenci, for instance, you are going to basically end up with <mark type="inaudible" /> the whole Morenci area where you've had a series of pits through the years is going to become one big pit, and some of that involves the same kind of oxide to sulfide ore identification.</p>
          <p>So we have years of those kinds of reserves available to us, and it's really just a question of when we decide to put in the mill, to expand the mill, to go get that sulfide ore. But that's really why we've said our brownfield-type opportunities principally going from oxide to sulfide ore are bigger than most greenfield projects around the world. And I've just been, overall, the new interpretation of all this core hole drilling that we did and putting in the big models, you'll be very impressed as we start to give these models to you, like the slide you saw on the Grasberg in this presentation, where you see all of the potential, both in the pit and underground or just the enlargement of pits.</p>
          <p>So that's really the story of this company right now, is the big growth of ore and adding ore and replacing production over a number of years by bringing those kinds of things into production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jim Bob. Thanks, Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Terry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mark Liinamaa of Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, through the last few months there has been all kinds of speculation about the China SRB, what they are up to, what the impact of them pulling a little bit out of the market, they seem to have done that or at least reports are, and yet copper continues to hold up. Can you just comment a little bit if at all about any of the supply-demand fundamentals you're seeing re: China demand and elsewhere in the world? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark. We're not the best source of information on that. We are not currently a major supplier of copper cathode or concentrates into China, although we are &#x2013; we've recently entered into some new concentrate arrangements with the Chinese. But beyond potential buying for strategic reserves, I think you can just look at the performance of the Chinese economy and the recent reports of their GNP growth and their IP growth, the extent of their copper imports, where they've set records now for a series of months clearly reflects something other than strategic reserve buying or the absence of scrap. They're physically consuming copper on infrastructure projects and to support their growing economy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, and is there anything to be read, if at all, into the decision not to hedge any of the provisionally priced copper this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, you know, our Freeport's traditional philosophy is not to hedge and even last quarter where we did lock in the open pound prices, we did not hedge any of our future production. The decision last quarter was not any kind of outlook about copper prices at all, and we are not taking any outlook at the end of this quarter. It was simply a step that was part of our overall strategy of protecting liquidity; and as we looked at the situation at the end of the first quarter, we felt that that was an appropriate incremental step to protect liquidity. Our liquidity position is much stronger now at the end of the second quarter, and so we concluded that it wasn't a step that we would take at the end of the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, and good luck with continued progress.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks a lot, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Wayne Atwell of Casimir Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Once again, congratulations on a great quarter and a good execution. You have a gold property near Grasberg, which if I am not mistaken is somewhere between four and six million ounces. Why don't you develop it, or why don't you joint venture it or sell it? Gold prices are fairly strong, it would take several years to bring it on, it seems like this would be an ideal time to start an initiative there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Wayne, the Wabu project is a project that we've had exploration over the years, we've done economic evaluation. And because of the cost of infrastructure, the indicated size of the opportunity there, we've concluded it is not economic for us.  And from time-to-time we have interest expressed in it, and we will follow up on any opportunities that develop from it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So we won't see you put it in production but you might sell it or JV it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And what's the ultimate size of Tenke, do you think? How big could that property get, and how big could be...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't know. It's a very, very large concession area, 650 square miles, roughly. There's mineralization indications throughout it. We've done enough drilling to support the current project that we're constructing. We clearly see oxide ores that are available, not all which are in reserves, but are either in reserves or near reserves that would allow for a doubling of the current type project, roughly a doubling of the current project that we have. There might be an intermediate step of where we could optimize the current project, and we're looking at that.</p>
          <p>Though longer range, to get to the kinds of world-class status that we think is available to us, we need to do more drilling and exploration analysis, and our guys are working on that now. There is a, coral drilling indicates a very large sulfide deposit; there's some mixed ore that we need to decide how we're going to technically process. But over the years, people involved in this project have talked about four to 500,000 tons. It's certainly &#x2013; those are not unreasonable expectations, it could be more, but it depends on the work we need to do there.</p>
          <p>We have another nearby exploration project called Kansanfu that has a very large potential and attractive indications of mineralization, as well. So if we're able to get the right infrastructure, I feel confident that there will be major expansions in Freeport's operations in the Congo looking out for a number of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard, just to comment for Wayne, when we got into the Congo operation after the merger, there were 1,500 core holes that had been drilled over the years. This thing had been drilled by other people for years. We've added 1,500 core holes to that database. So we doubled the amount of information, and that's because the area is so wide, and so long. And most of the stuff we've done is just going to the ore that's visible by satellite. You can, it's a vegetation anomaly, and we followed that vegetation anomaly for miles. And so most of the stuff we've done is near-surface drilling, just trying to confirm the ore that can be reached right at the surface.</p>
          <p>This ore body goes underground <mark type="inaudible" /> we followed the undergrounds for a few areas that there's new potential for this thing to go underground. And as I said about all of our projects and Richard just mentioned again, the ore that's being looked at at Tenke is oxide ore, and the sulfide portion of this ore body is going to be bigger than the oxide ore for the very same reason that we talked about with the peach: it's got the ripe area and the unripe area. So we haven't even started to drill deep enough to develop that, but that will be there for a hundred years or more and can provide all the expansion we need.</p>
          <p>As we've said, we have to go with pit, more and more pits with deeper pits, but we also have to add mill. So it's unlimited at this point, based on my observation, and 3,000 core holes is a lot of core holes, but there's a lot more to be done on following this thing underground.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>While we're looking at those long-term opportunities, we're going to focus in the near-term on getting this first project up and running, getting a business process set up to operate in a very difficult part of the world and optimizing what we spent this initial capital on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Lawrence Smith of Scotia Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[audio break] on projects. One on Tenke, the very useful cost guidance under $0.50 at $10 cobalt. Under $0.50 is a big range, I mean zero to 50 or $0.49, I'm wondering what's the impact of grade on that? I guess I kind of thought you'd be mining higher grade early on and costs would be lower. Is that sort of a reasonable cash cost until the first expansion?</p>
          <p>And then second question relates to Climax, I read your quarterly quickly. I didn't actually see any mention of Climax. I mean, are you still planning on bringing that into production at some point, or is there a chance that will just sit there and not go ahead? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, with respect to the cost structure that we commented on with Tenke, that number that we gave you was a cost structure over time based on current cost levels, $10 cobalt, and the design capacity to produce 250 million pounds of copper and 18 million pounds of cobalt. And obviously to the extent as we see with the Grasberg operations, to the extent that we have periods of time where we have higher-grade material available to us or more cobalt, that is going to have impact on cost in any particular period.</p>
          <p>We expect to have the opportunity to have, for example, higher cobalt grades early in the project. And to the extent we have that, that'll have an impact on unit cost at any particular point in time. But what we were trying to give the guidance on is what the overall cost structure of this looks like in terms of the design capacity that we built the project to. It'll vary period-by-period, and this is what we have now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. And on Climax?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Climax, yeah, no question. I mean, it's a great project. We had spent capital, I mean, the mill is there, a lot of the building construction, all of that is in place and none of it's going away. If the market responds, let me say when the market responds, because I'm confident that the market's going to require Climax volumes at some point, when that market responds, we will go back and resume construction.</p>
          <p>We think we spend roughly $350 million and within 18 months we are adding 30 million pounds of cobalt a year, poly a year, molybdenum, and we've done enough drilling there, this is another theme of what Jim Bob has talked about, we did additional core drilling at Climax, and we can see the opportunity to increase that production to twice the level of what the 30 million pounds are.</p>
          <p>So it's still there, we own that land and sea, we are continuing to manage the historical water drainage off the mining site, and as I've said we have, we are certainly not walking away from that project in any sense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your final question comes from the line of Jeff Carmer of UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm in the big times now. Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeff, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, I don't know what that was. Good morning, and congrats again on the quarter. Just wanted to follow up on the bonds you guys are calling. Are there certain, I guess covenants within those that I guess incentivize you a little bit more than others to call these?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the 6&#x215E; bonds...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>These were issued prior to our transaction with Phelps Dodge, these were non-investment-grade covenants, the notes were secured, and they did have some restrictions that don't exist in our other securities, that was one of the factors that played into our decision to call it. The other factor was that these notes were callable, and we could take out the whole issue with the cash that we had; we do have some notes that are also callable, the floaters, which are a billion dollars, those are due in 2015, but those are callable now, and we'll continue to look at all of our debt securities and see what makes sense to retire as we go forward. But this 6&#x215E; was the one that really from a first step standpoint made sense for us to go after.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I guess then regarding expansion projects. The mine acquisitions are not on the drawing board or there is not really any plan to divest properties either than, I guess other than potentially the property next to Grasberg?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The &#x2013; with respective to acquisitions, we have such great opportunities of investing in our own assets and growing volumes and adding to shareholder value without having to pay premium prices that you have to pay when making acquisitions. So we don't have any strategy of looking for acquisitions. Now having said that, we're constantly made aware of what's going on in the industry and we'll monitor it, and if an exceptional opportunity comes to us we could be in a position to do it, but that's not our strategy.</p>
          <p>And in terms of divestitures, with same way, we're always looking to see what would make sense with our portfolio of assets. We have good contacts within the industry and so forth with people who are interested in participating on a joint venture basis with our &#x2013; with us; we have joint venture partners now in Grasberg and in our mines in North America, South America and in Africa, around the world. People are looking for opportunities to add copper exposure. So we're plugged in to all those things and we'll go forward and see if anything makes sense from our view of creating shareholder value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no further questions at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks everybody for participating. We look forward to continuing to report to you our results as we go into the second half of 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that concludes our call for today. Thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>