<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1491070" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3053</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; VP-Strategic Development">Javier Gerardo Astaburuaga Sanjin&#xE9;s</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Securities USA, Inc.">Lauren E. Torres</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Casa de Bolsa Credit Suisse Mexico SA de CV">Antonio Gonz&#xE1;lez</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch, Pierce, Fenner &amp; Smith, Inc.">Robert E. Ford</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Alan Alanis</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Harding Loevner LLC">Margaret E. Kalvar</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays CTVM SA">Gabriel Vaz de Lima</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep" affiliation="Investor Relations Officer">Juan Fernando Fonseca Serratos</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Jose Juan Yordan</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome, everyone, to FEMSA's Second Quarter Earnings Results Conference Call. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise. After the presentation, there will be a question-and-answer session.</p>
          <p>During this conference call, management may discuss certain forward-looking statements concerning FEMSA's future performance and should be considered as good faith estimates made by the company. These forward-looking statements reflect management expectations and are based upon currently available data. Actual results are subject to future events and uncertainties, which can materially impact the company's actual performance.</p>
          <p>At this time, I will now turn the conference over to Javier Astaburuaga, FEMSA's CFO. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thank you and good morning, everyone. Welcome to FEMSA's second quarter 2012 results earnings conference call and Juan Fonseca and Jose Castro are with us today as always.</p>
          <p>It is customary in our calls we will focus on the consolidated figures for FEMSA and on FEMSA Comercio's results, since many of you probably had the opportunity to participate in Coca-Cola FEMSA's conference call last Tuesday. As you have also may have seen our detailed results, we will use this opportunity to share some of what we see as highlights and main trends on our business.</p>
          <p>As we mentioned in our release, our performance in the second quarter was mixed. On one hand FEMSA Comercio delivered strong revenue growth driven by dynamic same store sales and new store openings, while margins continue to expand. On the other hand Coca-Cola FEMSA faces a challenging environment and made the most of it.</p>
          <p>Top line growth was achieved through pricing, but we continue to see short term pressure on margins, particularly in Mexico, reflecting among other things raw material and FX pressures, difficult weather comparisons and the expenses related with the integration of our new territories in Mexico.</p>
          <p>However, I am following up on comments made by H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o during his conference call on Tuesday. Given that Coke FEMSA's top line is behaving well and that several of the pressure points of the income statement should be short-term in nature, we expect profitability to recover during the second half of the year and beyond.</p>
          <p>As you know at the end of March, we reported our 2011 quarterly and full year financial information under IFRS to facilitate comparability. If you have any questions about these changes, please get in touch with Juan on our Investor Relations team who will be glad to follow-up on that.</p>
          <p>In terms of our perception of the environment and the drivers for consumption, particularly in our key Mexico market, we continue to see encouraging trends that are consistent with what we saw at the beginning of the year. Manufacturing activity and GDP growth continue to be healthy and consumer confidence remains high, while unemployment is under control.</p>
          <p>The one variable that has changed in trend recently and that merits monitoring is inflation, which did spike above 4% for the first time in several months here in Mexico. However, the overall economic environment in Mexico is positive and funds seem to be flowing in the right direction in the form of both direct and portfolio investment.</p>
          <p>And looking briefly at the macro environment in other markets where we operate, the standouts regarding GDP are Argentina, Venezuela, Colombia, all of them posting mid-single digit growth in sharp contrast with Brazil where we are still seeing a deceleration.</p>
          <p>Moving on to discuss our consolidated quarterly numbers, total revenues increased 23% and income from operations grew 13%. On an organic basis, excluding the integration of the new bottlers, total revenues and income from operations increased by 16% and 7%, respectively.</p>
          <p>For the second quarter, the line labeled participation in Heineken results the percent of FEMSA's 20% participation in Heineken's first quarter net income, which was reported last April, using now the average exchange rate for the euro during the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Net income increased 29% in the quarter. As we explained in our press release, this increase reflects growth in income from operations, the positive effect of the devaluation of the Mexican peso on the U.S. dollar denominated component of our cash position and the lower effective income tax rate.</p>
          <p>Our effective tax rate was 24% for the quarter, resulting from a tax shield related to interest on capital included in a dividend declared in the South America division of Coca-Cola FEMSA. Normally you should expect our tax rate range to be in the low to mid-30s. In terms of our cash position, during the second quarter we went from having a consolidated net cash position of 2.6 billion pesos at the end of March to basically zero net cash levels at the end of June, reflecting dividend payments carried out during the month of May at both FEMSA and Coca-Cola FEMSA.</p>
          <p>And moving on to discuss our operations and beginning with FEMSA Comercio, we opened 290 net new stores during the second quarter. This number is lower than the comparable figure of 2011, and if we look at the full first half of the year, we are running a bit short of the comparable number as well. However, the run rate for the last 12 months is 1026 stores, and we expect openings during the second half of the year to maintain at least or perhaps slightly increase that run rate.</p>
          <p>In other words, 2012 will turn out to be somewhat backend loaded in terms of openings. But our confidence is very high that we will surpass 1000 net new stores for the year and possibly approaching 1,100 in line with our expectations.</p>
          <p>Loading of the backend of the year with openings is not ideal, but the focus continues to be on maintaining the highest level of quality in the new openings and that remains the first priority for the whole organization.</p>
          <p>On a related note, our store number 10,000 was opened a few days ago in the state of Chihuahua. We would like to take this opportunity to congratulate our colleagues at FEMSA Comercio for reaching this major landmark.</p>
          <p>Revenues increased 17% during the quarter in FEMSA Comercio. Same-store sales were up &#x2013; were again up a healthy 8%, reflecting improvements in average traffic as well as in ticket. Our traffic increased 4%, continuing to reflect progress in our management of category and purchase location mix, and the continuous fine-tuning of our value proposition within the store.</p>
          <p>Our average ticket also rose 4%, aided by price increases taken in the first quarter by several of our suppliers for important categories. For the quarter, gross margin expanded 60 basis points, again driven mainly by a positive mix shift due to the growth of higher margin categories, a more effective collaboration and execution with our key supplier partners, combined with a more efficient use of promotion-related marketing resources and a better execution of segmented pricing strategies across markets and store formats.</p>
          <p>In terms of operating margin, this quarter FEMSA Comercio posted an expansion of 60 basis points as operating expenses grew slightly below revenues. As you know, operating expenses have been growing ahead of revenues for a while, driven by certain initiatives related to the strengthening of the organizational structure and to increased marketing investment behind certain consumption locations.</p>
          <p>The fact that during the second quarter this trend did not materialize results from a temporary decrease in the pace of such expenses, partly related to the calendarization of certain marketing programs and to the moderate slowdown in the pace of store openings for the quarter</p>
          <p>But we should expect operating expenses to grow slightly ahead of revenues in the short to medium terms as we continue to strengthen and support our business. Having said that, FEMSA Comercio's results, particularly the growth in same store sales and the expansion of the operating margin, are currently running a bit ahead of our stated medium term expectations of mid-single digit sales growth and 10 to 20 basis points of expansion per year.</p>
          <p>Since we are not expecting a major deceleration during the second quarter of the year, it is likely that our full year results will come in ahead of plan. However, this should not signal a change in our medium term expectations for next year and beyond.</p>
          <p>Moving shortly onto Coca-Cola FEMSA. Revenues for the quarter increased 28% versus the comparable period of 2011, as a result of double-digit total revenue growth in each division and the integration of our new territories in Mexico.</p>
          <p>On an organic basis, revenues for the quarter increased 16%, operating income 8%, driven by double-digit operating income growth in each division and including the integration of the new territories in Mexico as well.</p>
          <p>On an organic basis, operating income remained stable compared to the second quarter of 2011, reflecting higher fructose prices in Mexico, the average depreciation of the Mexican peso as applied to our U.S. dollar-denominated raw material costs, and certain other items, many of which are related to the development of new lines of businesses and the support of Coke FEMSA's new commercial model. If you were unable to participate in their conference call on Tuesday, you can access a replay of the webcast for additional details on the results.</p>
          <p>And finally on the strategic front, we're excited about Jugos del Valle's recently announced acquisition of Santa Clara, a well-known, premium Mexican dairy company, building on the positive learnings from our Estrella Azul dairy operation in Panama. And also we continue to advance on our assessment of the Coca-Cola Philippines operation.</p>
          <p>So all in all, taking into account the challenges we face during the quarter, we feel we will be approaching the second half of the year with a good degree of optimism and a lot of hard work as always.</p>
          <p>And with that, I would like now to open the call for your questions. Operator, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We'll take our first question from Lauren Torres with HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Javier, you mentioned &#x2013; hopefully you could talk a little bit more about this operating margin improvement that we're seeing in the first half out of OXXO. You've always talked about 10 to 20 basis points, maybe that's a longer term growth rate as far as improvement in margins, but we are tracking ahead of that, so I was just curious if you could kind of break down the components of that. Is it something that we're seeing now that's going to somewhat dissipate and lessen as the year goes on or looking into next year, or is it a lever that you are able to pull as a result of weakness at Coke FEMSA. I'm just trying to get a sense of how sustainable these improvements are over the near-term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Sure. Over the near-term we feel positive. The expansion might not be as strong as it was in the first semester, but we do feel that it will be above the long-term 10 to 20 basis points expectation that we always share. And again, a number of factors driving that. We feel very, very good about how the different categories or products occasion &#x2013; consumption occasions we are trying to build within the store are reacting very, very, well to both marketing campaigns as well as a redesign of the assortment and the pricing architecture that we have been bringing into the store.</p>
          <p>And I think that's a trend that going to be there for I hope for a long time. But on the other half, Lauren, as I explained also as well, we have a different calendar for some of our marketing efforts during 2012 as compared with 2011. And when you put that together with again a slightly decrease in the store openings for the first half of the year as compared with 2011, that creates also some support for the margin expansion you are looking at June.</p>
          <p>So going forward, my summary would be we might see hopefully a stronger margin expansion than the long-term run rate that we expect for the business to develop in a healthy way, but not necessarily as strong as in the first half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if I could also ask just on same-store sales growth at OXXO, it seems year-to-date two-year trending 7% to 8%, maybe higher than mid-single digit expectations you had heading into this year, I was just curious if that's also sustainable and if growth is coming in better and should continue if you think over the next couple of quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To tell you the truth we are performing ahead of our own expectations, so it is a good point to be in, but again still some of the forces behind that growth, I mean at least the one that is above our expectations, it is very hard for us to predict if it's going to be sustainable or it's at least partly influenced by again the development of new occasions of consumption that we are trying to build within the store. And as you know, it takes time to really create a habit on the consumer. So, I wouldn't dare to say much about same store sales. On top of that we are very, very pleased and happy with the performance so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Moving on, let's go to Credit Suisse, Antonio Gonz&#xE1;lez.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, thank you for taking my question. Javier, I wanted to see if you could comment, and I know it's preliminary, but in light of the discussions in Mexico after the elections of potential structural reforms, is there anything that you could comment on what's the structure of OXXO today, how much of the revenue mix is actually paying VAT, subject to VAT and how much is not? And is there any general comment that you could share with us on how would you foresee any impact on OXXO from potential VAT on food and medicines specifically, which is something that of course is not subject to the tax today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say that in OXXO most of the products are charged with VAT, I'm just getting north of 70%, 75% mainly. And I think that again sensitivity on VAT will depend a lot on again if first there is really a consensus on doing something on that, there's again some of the products that will be we think more hit by that are not necessarily a big component of the other products that we sell in the store. So according to our estimates it shouldn't be a big deal for us if that takes place, Antonio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Javier. And if I may very quickly, could you give us an update on what's the latest you've been thinking with respect to OXXO growth in formats other than convenience stores in Mexico? Is it something that you would be exploring in the short-term, you probably wouldn't comment on that or can you give us a little bit more color if it is something that is more feasible in the 24 months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we've shared, I would say in the last year or year and a half whatsoever, we have been doing a lot of work in terms of again looking at potential opportunities trying to leverage both the footprint but most importantly the capabilities that FEMSA Comercio possesses regarding the operation of small-box formats and as we shared as well, we are thinking through that, we are even exploring and trying to develop some of those opportunities and for sure we will announce whenever we have something to say about that to the market in due time.</p>
          <p>What I might share as well is that again the rationale behind that is again &#x2013; what I can anticipate is again you guys not to expect big things from the start in terms of any big transaction regarding that but a more gradual approach in terms of again &#x2013; be now FEMSA Comercio participating in new small-box formats.</p>
          <p>So I can confirm to you that we are interested in again tapping new opportunities that might have a good fit with FEMSA Comercio's capabilities, but that we are going to take that with a proper cautious in terms of again entering new formats and taking very well-calculated risks in doing so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much, Javier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's go to Robert Ford with Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Good morning, everybody, and congratulations on the quarter, Javier. I was curious if you are seeing any delay or any additional requirements in obtaining new licenses or authorizations for space following this fall out of the Walmex bribery allocations in Mexico?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not at all but it's as hard as always. You know Mexico well. You've lived here so you know what I am talking about. And there is like close to 15 different permits we have to get every time we want to open a store. This is &#x2013; most of them are locally, so you might find very, very efficient counties that processes these in a speedy and very straightforward way and some others in which it takes a long time to really comply with all the requirements, but we haven't seen anything yet. You might also take into account that we are a very, very different kind of format, animal whatsoever. We have very, very little I would say major considerations regarding neighborhoods or environmental considerations and the likes as when you're thinking very large box formats, so no, we have not seen anything there at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to verify, you don't use <mark type="indiscernible" /> (19:43) anywhere, is that correct, it's all your own people?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's all our own people.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then with respect to the pricing segmentation that you're implying: can you discuss a little bit about how you're going about segmenting the market whether they're contiguous clusters that are &#x2013; or something that maybe is classified by levels of income, or densities, or surrounding areas? I was just trying to get a sense of how advanced you are and how, I guess, tailored you are to this specific neighborhood?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You should work here, I mean you mentioned most of the variables we take into account on our segmentation. It's pretty much a lot of what you said and I may add that once you take into account all of those variables and some others, you end up by seeing with a view of what's really &#x2013; what we like to call here the vocation of the start, what it was made for because of where it was located. So the essence of the start &#x2013; I may put it in better English I think. So that drives a lot of again the sign of the assortment of the store. And of course if you look at the social economic level, as well of the price architecture, that we would like to have in any different store, it's &#x2013; I mean, let's say the aim in a very utopical world would be to really have segmentation based on 10,000 stores that isn't practical and it's not actionable.</p>
          <p>But we have developed, I think very broadly at least three big frame works of format segmentation that works for us. Some of those stores are much more into what we call a recess &#x2013; kind of a people which are having a certain routine or activities and go to the store to either have a bite, or having a coffee, or having something more directed with immediate consumption.</p>
          <p>As opposed to some other stores which are, because of the location and environment, in terms of not only density, but the nature of the shopper; you might find some stores which are more skewed to categories which are used on a daily basis and kind of a pantry re-loading on the small quantities. And we also have what I may call the playing store, which is a little bit of everything.</p>
          <p>So I think this is &#x2013; this is a journey, this is a never-ending journey. And &#x2013; but if you look at what we were doing maybe three years ago and we were doing very little stuff of what we're doing now in terms of store segmentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thank you very much. And then just one last thing, it's a little one. On the bank deposit business, I know the cash management is pretty expensive, where are you in that? I would expect that there has got to be great adoption from small businesses to ratchet the trader areas of your store and I was wondering if that's &#x2013; that the system is in place, if that's the case, and how that's progressing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't, I mean we're not betting high on that to happen because, again, we have limits on the amount of money that people can deposit to their credit accounts. So, that's not really the driving for us, we find this idea of being more a one stop shop for even some financial services. So, you shouldn't expect really a big chunk of our business going into that line of businesses. It's really what I might say a service to our consumer, which makes it easier for them to satisfy some of their needs or requirements.</p>
          <p>And it's coming I would say slowly but surely building and with very, very different behaviors depending again of the nature of the consumers. In some places, such as Mexico City, this concept has been sticking very well, and I'm just getting, people don't want to be in long lines in some sucursales in Mexico City, but in some other places really going to the bank and make a long line to really present the excuse to have a good chat with your friends, or with someone you might want to know better. So, this is not really something that is I would say behaving in the same pattern all across the territory.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> Alex Robarts at Citi (24:20) has our next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks. Hi, everybody. I wanted to go back to the idea of the openings. You talked about kind of the focus, and what's important for you is that high quality new store openings. And I know &#x2013; I guess, a few months ago the idea was to hit 500 new stores, you've got 428, and I guess from an earlier comment, this is not an issue of getting new permits to open. Could it be a function perhaps of just the proliferation of new SKUs as you diversified your sales and such? Is there something else that maybe you can share with us that for some reason you are not hitting that high quality opening benchmark? That would be the first question.</p>
          <p>And the second one really relates to the international element here of OXXO, I appreciate it's not a big part of the business. 20 or so stores I guess are in Colombia; how is that going? And just if you could give us any color on just generally the aspirations internationally, outside of Colombia and Mexico, for OXXO that would be great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, sure. Alex, how are you? In terms of openings, when I'm talking about quality it is kind of &#x2013; it meant what really reflects that people in OXXO are incentivised, again, for openings stores at a certain pace, which we have clear objectives for that. But they are not paid on opening stores. They are paid on opening good stores. So in order to do that, first criteria is, I would say, a combination of location and the right terms for that, Alex. So that's where it all starts and we think we have developed skills both in selecting good sites, as well as negotiating, and we have also built a reputation of being a very, very good renter. So that's what I mean by quality.</p>
          <p>And to your point I think you have a right view. The whole effort of the company is really to have a balanced approach to keep developing the business. So while you listen to me explaining to you all sorts of things happening in OXXO, the guys which are running the expansion operation have to coordinate very, very closely with the guys opening the stores, in order not to have a great site with a great building which is not going to be properly managed.</p>
          <p>So I tend to believe that some of the slowdown in the first quarter has to do little bit what I just said, which is a number of things are happening within the company. And there might be some, again, slowdown in some of the coordination activities between the two organizations that might create a temporary slowdown. But as we said, we are not obsessed neither with opening more stores this year as we did last year. We are not, again, preparing this company to move to a different level of store openings, such as going to 1200 or 1300. We are pleased with the balance that we have reached in opening at least above 1000 stores a year, and both continue to make improvements in the way we are managing the business and hopefully delivering results as the ones we just shared with you this morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of Colombia, as you well point out, we just have 26 stores in Bogot&#xE1;. We plan to open about 10 new stores this year as well. We are opening those in places in which we are going to have, I would say, different environments on which we are going to hopefully get a lot of learnings. But at the same time we continue to develop the value proposition in, what I should say, a second round of adjustments in which we are, I would say, bringing &#x2013; particularly to small scale limit in number of stores &#x2013; and new and much more wider and, we think, attractive proposition for fast food into the stores.</p>
          <p>And what I might say to you is that same store sales in Colombia still are growing very, very good, I mean I wouldn't like to share numbers, but we are very pleased with the performance of the same store sales performance in Colombia as well, but still we think that we need to keep on the perfection in the value proposition, learn a little bit more in order for us to really move to on a stage in which we would start opening a significant amount of stores on a year basis, so that's pretty much what I can share, Alex.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We'll take our next question from JPMorgan's Alan Alan&#xED;s.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, how are you, good morning. I have a few questions, some of them are not directly related, the first has to do with, if you have any view, as owner of 20% of Heineken, regarding the bid that they announced for Asia Pacific Breweries, and the &#x2013; let's keep it like that, very simple and I have a couple of others regarding your business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our opinion, regretfully I cannot share it Alan, but I do have an opinion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am sorry for that, but I am sure you'll understand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I do, okay. Let me see if I can ask one more question or &#x2013; or see if you can give me an opinion. The first one has to do with the acquisition of Santa Clara by Jugos del Valle: I understand that this dairy company has, what, 150 outlets &#x2013; retail outlets, like small coffee shops in very premium locations. When you were talking about OXXO entering into smaller format et cetera, is there possibility that &#x2013; that OXXO, I mean, that OXXO would take over those 150 or so coffee shops?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Possibility in long-term always is possibility, and probability short-term, no. We're not -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the right thing to do. We have &#x2013; we think better ideas, or priorities and, for the short-term that's really not something that we will be looking at. It's as you've said franchise-based; these are working well, and we think it might be a good idea to keep that moral at least for the short, medium term. I don't -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...something that &#x2013; has to be decided by the Coca-Cola bottlers and the Coca-Cola Company, not by us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair. And another quick question, I mean, if you stabilize the number of store openings at around 1,000 to 1,100, like you mentioned, instead of keep growing like the previous year, like you did in the last 10 years. I mean your cash flow generation is just going to &#x2013; is just going to accelerate tremendously: what's the preferred use of that cash?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hopefully finding opportunities to keep expanding and, as you know, I mean, FEMSA commodities are wholly-owned subsidiaries. So we have &#x2013; we have discretionary and the freedom to really do whatever that might be used better for our shareholders. So again, OXXO expanding into small-box formatting is one of the first thing within FEMSA Comercio, ideas that we privilege. But that doesn't necessarily mean that we might not use some of that excess cash to any purpose we might think are appropriate such as, again, increasing the payment of dividends, or acquiring more Coca Cola FEMSA shares, as we said in the past, or even fueling higher growth rates on our FEMSA logistics business as well, which is performing extremely well. So, hopefully we find good opportunities to reinvest most of that excess cash that FEMCO might start generating, as you well point out, if we stabilize openings and continue to grow the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. That's useful. One last question regarding &#x2013; I mean, could you remind me what is the status of the exclusivities of beer antitrust investigations in Mexico? And where I'm coming with question is, could you help us understand if one day exclusivities were to be banned in Mexico, I mean, may or may not be that related because of now that the imminent change of control at the largest brewer in Mexico? What would be the impact if exclusivities in Mexico would cease to exist for OXXO Javier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bob, it will depend &#x2013; first on the first question, the status is basically the same: there is not a lot of noose around that, it's very lengthy process and we don't think it has a lot of, again, merits. At least the investigations or the cases that some other brewers have been bringing into the table. We have what we think is a commercial, contractual obligation for the next close to eight years to work on an exclusive basis with the products of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (34:30) here in Mexico. We don't think &#x2013; there is nothing to really challenge about that contract under the existing laws under it was signed. So I don't really see anything, at least for the next say years, Alan; discussing potential scenarios going beyond that is beyond my limits really.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Understood, understood. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Allan, good to talk to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Margaret Kalvar with Harding Loevner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. Yes, just following up a little bit on the international expansion topic, there are just some speculations you might be looking at Brazil, and there is a somewhat different format or occasion, experience, characteristic of what we would call convenience stores there, and that you were investigating that. Can you comment at all on whether you are still interested in that market and if it's a short or medium term goal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Margaret. I wouldn't pinpoint Brazil as the only market in which we might have interest in the future, and for the only market in which we have done some analysis to really understand how consumers satisfy their needs in terms of small box retail. Of course, we have an interest in Brazil. What I've showed in the past is that short-term, we are not necessarily thinking of anything, but that might change as we progress in our own analysis and understanding. What we definitely know for sure is that in every market we might need to look at again what might be the winning formula.</p>
          <p>We don't think the Mexican formula works well particularly in Brazil. So I would say that within that message what you might be reading is that your point of &#x2013; if and when the company decides to do something in Brazil, it might need to be something which is good and light and required by the Brazilians, not by whatever we have been successful in doing in Mexico.</p>
          <p>But I would say that also has again, as I shared, this intention of, again, leveraging its skill sets and capabilities to, again, tap into opportunities in related small-box format opportunities. And that the international expansion, which is today really limited to our Greenfield operation in Colombia, if you ask me medium-to-long term would it be possible to see additional countries or formatting which also will be present, or FEMSA Comercio will be present, the answer should be yes. But, short term, I think that we are focusing on the opportunities that I just shared.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Margaret.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And a question now from Barclays Capital, Gabriel Lima.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks. Good morning, and congratulations on the results. Javier, my question is very much related to the very first question in the call, about margin expansion, but it's more on the gross margin expansion at OXXO, so I just -- you mentioned in the release that you were seeing a better mix shift. So, I want to understand what you have done and what opportunities you see going forward, such as implementing this new mix in other stores and how much you have already implemented, and you also mentioned here that execution with key suppliers is also helping, so just curious to better understand that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Gabriel. As I said some of the margin expansion, or most of it comes from basically from three things maybe, it's a better mix in terms of the shift of the mix is moving to categories which we are trying to build, which happen to have a higher gross margins. Another factor, which I didn't mention in the earlier, is that growth rates all across geography in Mexico tends to be a little bit stronger in the north, and that we think has a lot to do with the related economic activity that the north has with the U.S., and that's also factored short-term, and we don't think that's going to be there forever.</p>
          <p>And the third one is the one you mentioned, which is, when I say working in a much better way with our suppliers and partners it's a combination again of developing specific packages for the occasions that we serve for our consumers in the C stores. And looking at, I shouldn't say magic price points, but the right price points for consumers, and, as well, we have been learning a lot, taking advantage of our better basis of again, purchasing habits and looking at how consumers satisfy their needs, at fine-tuning our promotional activity. So we're getting much more bang for our bucks in terms of putting sometimes even less money than in the past, and getting much better results.</p>
          <p>And I would say that's pretty much what's driving gross margin expansion. We have come to a point where we have very, very healthy gross margins. And we have &#x2013; we think fair terms with most of our suppliers, we still have a lot of work to do with some, but those are not the majority of the suppliers. So you shouldn't be looking at margin expansions of this rate to be there for the long term, and as we say it, if you translate gross margin into then net margins, we are, I would say, surpassing our own expectations for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. In fact it was very clear. But specifically about the product mix, can you share with us a rough idea of this better mix, I suppose for example your food service, you have already implemented in your stores, and what else, or how much you can further implement in your total store number? Again, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no. I would say still in the early stages of developing the fast food category in Oxxo. We have done &#x2013; and I mean if you look on an incremental basis what we have achieved, I would say that we have been, I would say we're pleased with the results, but we're still a long way to go in terms of implementing the offerings that we are thinking are the right ones for the store. For the medium term, we are very far away from that, and we are even farther away in terms of having that offering implemented in -- I shouldn't say the 10,000 stores because we, as I said, are segmenting a lot around the offerings on the different occasions that we serve, depending on each store.</p>
          <p>But we still have there, Gabriel, I think a long way to go. But I shouldn't as well send the message that this is going to be so huge that it's going to impact in a high and a very significant way in the short term gross margin expansion. This is a category that takes time to build, this is not products that you just barcode and you scan at the cash machine. So, you need to work a lot of your internal procedures on your supply chain. So it takes time to build these kinds of categories.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would just add, Gabriel, this is Juan, if you think about the services category, which is another one that we've been talking about in terms of coming from a very small base, but showing very good growth trends, and obviously getting a lot of focus from the organization, that service is basically our own margin, right. I mean every time you receive payment for a utility or a bank deposit or a transportation card for the buses or whatever, that's basically 100% margin and it flows direct to the bottom line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay, thank you, Juan. Thank you, Javier. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Gabriel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And a question from Jose Yordan with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everybody. Most of my questions were answered. But I just wanted to see if you could provide an update on what your total CapEx will be for the year for all of FEMSA, and if, to the extent you can talk about next year, that would be great as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jos&#xE9;, this is Juan. I mean the numbers we've put out are $710 million for COFs, $350 million for OXXO and $50 million for the ancillary businesses, basically the refrigeration business and logistics. So that's basically where we stand for this year. We haven't really put a number out for 2013. I would think it's probably going to be in line with this, because, as you know, there's a couple of plants being built by Coke FEMSA and those are multi-year projects, at least two-year projects. So, I would think the numbers for this year are probably pretty close to what we'll be talking about next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But essentially the number of $710 million and $350 million for OXXO, etcetera, those are all numbers that you still expect to hit, or are based on recent developments, especially the slowdown in growth in OXXO stores?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm just interested in getting a better estimate as opposed to what the budget was?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, as you recall, normally we talk about maximum levels, and this is a number that is put on the 20-F. And sometimes we end up not hitting that number, and there is always also the issue of calendarization, right, and cash flow. I mean sometimes you have the budget and then you are still carrying over a little bit from the previous year, and some of the expenditures for this year are probably going to be made in the beginning of 2013, but like I said, the number is usually the high end of the range. And sometimes we end up not hitting it.</p>
          <p>I mean, I don't think, when you talk about OXXO specifically, certainly if the number of stores at the end of the day comes in within the range we've been discussing, there is not going to be a big difference in terms of the cash that those stores will require. There are a couple of new distribution centers. There is a component of it that goes to store refurbishings. There is a component of that that goes to the supply chain, and the logistics involved and development of the fast food initiative. So, I don't think we're in a position to say, to revise those numbers down just yet. I think we're going to keep them where they are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Sounds good. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no further questions at this time. I will now turn the conference back to Mr. Astaburuaga for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, everyone. Have a great weekend and see you hopefully in the next three months. Bye, now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, if you wish to replay the webcast for this call, you may do so at FEMSA's Investor Relations website. This concludes our conference for today. Thank you for your participation and have a nice day. All parties may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>