<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1186620" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-10-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3053</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Javier Gerardo Astaburuaga Sanjin&#xE9;s, Chief Financial Officer and Vice President of Strategic Development</participant>
      <participant id="2">Robert Ford</participant>
      <participant id="3">Javier Gerardo Astaburuaga Sanjin&#xE9;s</participant>
      <participant id="4">Lauren Torres</participant>
      <participant id="5">Celso Sanchez</participant>
      <participant id="6">Alan Alanis</participant>
      <participant id="7">Loredana Serra</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jos&#xE9; Yord&#xE1;n</participant>
      <participant id="9">Juan Fonseca</participant>
      <participant id="10">Carlos Laboy</participant>
      <participant id="11">Alexander Robarts</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and welcome to the FEMSA's Third Quarter 2008 Earnings Results Conference Call. As a reminder, today's conference is being recorded, and all participants are in a listen-only mode. At the request of the company, we will open the conference to questions and answers after the presentation.</p>
          <p>During this conference call, management may discuss certain forward-looking statements concerning FEMSA's future performance, which should be considered as good faith estimates made by the company. These forward-looking statements reflect management expectations and are based upon currently available data. Actual results are subject to future events and uncertainties, which can materially impact the company's actual performance.</p>
          <p>At this time, I'd like to turn the conference over to Mr. Javier Astaburuaga, FEMSA's CFO. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, everyone. Welcome to FEMSA's Third Quarter 2008 Earnings Conference Call. Joining me today are Alfredo Fern&#xE1;ndez and Juan Fonseca, both of whom you know well.</p>
          <p>The third quarter for FEMSA turned out to be somewhat of a transitional quarter. From a very solid first half of the year into what is clearly a softening consumer environment across our markets, that makes us a bit cautious as we head into 2009. In the middle of worldwide economic and financial turbulence, central banks across the region continue to revise our forecast downward. In Mexico, GDP growth expectations for 2008 that started the year at above 3% had accelerated. They will descend by a full percentage point to a little bit more than 2%.</p>
          <p>General inflation has crept up well above 5%, with food inflation approaching 9% and yet, wages only rose by 4% on average and the expected inflation at the beginning of the year. Still, the expectation for the rest of year and for 2009 is still one of moderate growth in our key markets. And despite some of the challenging environment during the quarter, we were able to grow our consolidated operating income in the high single digits. And for the first nine months of the year, we are showing double-digit growth on operating margin expansion. These results underscore the strength of our integrated beverage platform and our continuous improvement efforts at every stage of the value chain.</p>
          <p>For the quarter, double-digit operating income growth at FEMSA Comercio and Coca-Cola FEMSA more than compensated for a decline at FEMSA Cerveza. In terms of business highlights for the quarter, as we anticipated, FEMSA Cerveza increased prices for a second time during the year in Mexico, helping to mitigate cost pressures. While the third quarter results don't fully capture the effect of this second increase, we believe we are well positioned in terms of pricing as we begin the fourth quarter and head into next year.</p>
          <p>For its part, Coca-Cola FEMSA made progress in the integration of Jugos del Valle and Remil into its platform and started implementing selective price increases in the Mexican market, as you know. Meanwhile, FEMSA Comercio opened 237 net new stores to reach almost 6,100 stores nationwide, managing to smoothen the store opening core by accelerating the openings ahead of the busy fourth quarter, while delivering strong earnings growth for the tenth consecutive quarter. Altogether, FEMSA consolidated operating income growth was close to 9% for the quarter, reaching 5.7 billion pesos and 12% for the first nine months, delivering 15.5 billion pesos. Below the line, we recorded non-cash items derived from the appreciation of the dollar against local currencies as applied to our liability position and as a result, their net majority income declined to just under 16% in the quarter.</p>
          <p>And finally, before moving on to our business units, let me remind you that beginning this year, according to Mexican FRS, we have discontinued the use of inflation accounting. For comparison purposes, the figures for 2007 have been restated in Mexican pesos, with purchasing power as of December 31, 2007 and our results from 2008 are in current pesos.</p>
          <p>Let me start now with FEMSA Cerveza. As you recall, during our first conference call, we talked about how the first half showed no signs of a slowdown in consumer demand and for the first six months, our domestic volumes grew by a healthy 4.8%.</p>
          <p>In addition, even though the industry pricing has not fully recovered raw material pressures in recent years, this created an environment that was conducive to a second price increase, which we carried out during the third quarter. However, the third quarter proved to be more challenging than we expected, as the consumer environment softened and the heavy rains impacted us negatively in some key geographies, particularly during the month of September.</p>
          <p>In the end, this combination of GDP slowdown, adverse weather and strong pricing resulted in a contraction of our domestic volumes of 1.9% in the third quarter. Outside of Mexico, our beer exports continued delivering solid growth, with another quarter of double-digit growth in spite of the challenging economic environment. We believe these are remarkable results considering that according to the reinsitute and consistent with the previous trends we shared with you, the imports category in the U.S. was down by 2.9% during the first eight months of 2008.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, our volume performance continued its positive momentum and we grew 8%, outpacing the industry growth for another consecutive quarter. Most of our brands had good results with Kaiser, Bavaria and Sol contributing over 90% of our incremental volumes.</p>
          <p>In terms of Mexico pricing, in order to recover some of the real price that was lost in recent years and particularly in 2007 and to mitigate the impact of rising general inflation and steep raw material inflation, we increased prices during the third quarter, on top of the price movements implemented at the beginning of the year. Both price increases combined with incremental volumes brought into our distribution network resulted in more than 6% higher average unit prices or over 2% above inflation.</p>
          <p>As we enter the fourth quarter, we expect lower levels of promotional activity than in previous years and that, together with the strong pricing, bodes well for our performance during the key holiday season. We should also note that as we mentioned during Coca-Cola FEMSA's call last week, times of consumer slowdown have historically provided us the opportunity to shift our packaging mix back to a higher returnability without any major or significant impact in profitability, as well as a shift in channel mix further toward the traditional channel, which is also a potential positive in certain markets for us.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, revenue per hectoliter increased 4.5% in local currency and 5.6% in Mexican peso terms. It was driven by selective price increases implemented in the last 12 months and the appreciation of the Brazilian real against the Mexican peso. And as for exports, revenue per hectoliter in Mexican pesos declined 6.5%, reflecting a strong peso during the quarter, while in U.S. dollars, it increased by 2.2%, reflecting selective price increases implemented in the U.S., mainly in our Tecate brand.</p>
          <p>Cost of sales increased 8.2%, well ahead of revenue growth. The significant grain pressure experienced across our brewing operations was partially offset by favorable aluminum hedges in Mexico and by higher fixed cost absorption and a strong Brazilian real as applied to our dollar cost in Brazil. In the end, we saw a 6.8% increase in average cost of goods sold per hectoliter. Gross profit increased 3.7% for the quarter, however, gross margin contracted by 110 basis points.</p>
          <p>Income from operations decreased 8.2% to 1,508 million in the third quarter. Selling expenses increased 13.5% versus 2007, reflecting heavy brand-related spending that's scheduled for the quarter and that includes the first new ad campaign for Sol in three years and the first ever media campaign for our fast-growing brand Indio. As was the case in the second quarter, selling expenses also included distribution channel investments, as well as incremental expenses related to volume taken over from third-party distributors, mainly in the state of Chiapas.</p>
          <p>When analyzing the growth in selling expenses, it is useful to look at not only the growth versus 2007, which was a year when we spent the second half return the damage of a very weak first half. But also look at the growth versus 2006, which was a much more normalized year. <mark type="inaudible" /> we see that the growth of selling expenses for that two-year period has been coming down percentage-wise every quarter of this year. And we expect the growth in the fourth quarter will show a meaningful sequential decrease that puts it more in line with the expected growth in revenues looking at this two-year period.</p>
          <p>Conversely, administrative expenses declined 4.2% in the third quarter. And as a result, operating expenses added 100 basis points to the gross margin contraction, with the operating margin decreasing 210 basis points to 14.2% of total revenues.</p>
          <p>Let me stop here for a minute to talk a bit about selling expenses a little bit more. Clearly for a long time, we have been investing heavily behind our brands and behind our position in the marketplace. And we remain convinced that our strategies are very important to short as well as the long-term. However, we are also aware that the macro and microeconomic environments are changing rapidly and we are taking immediate and decisive actions to adjust our spending levels to the current situation.</p>
          <p>This means the deployment of aggressive efficiency programs, the rationalization of spending without jeopardizing the gains that have been made in recent years, a proactive approach to managing packaging mix towards return ability and generally keeping maximum flexibility to adjust our strategy to a rapidly changing environment. In other words, the amount and timing of the cash flows allocated to our marketing and selling efforts, as well as our capacity-related and non-critical capital expenditures will be consistent with the evolution of the market dynamics.</p>
          <p>Now turning to our soft drink business, Coca-Cola FEMSA. Coca-Cola FEMSA delivered double-digit growth at the operating income level, lapping an 11.5% increase in the third quarter of 2007 in spite of unfavorable weather conditions in certain markets and a more cautious consumer in Mexico. Contrary to what we have served in our beer business however, September volumes saw a moderate improvement in the performance of our soft drink products relative to July and August, driven by brand Coca-Cola.</p>
          <p>The operating leverage achieved in those markets was offset by raw material pressure coming from PET and sugar prices, as well as by the integration of Jugos del Valle and Remil, which today generate lower margins, resulting in 60 basis points of operating margin decline to 16.2%. Higher average prices in Mercosur and Latincentro, combined with volume growth driven by brand Coca-Cola and our non-carbonated beverage portfolio, resulted in strong 14.5% growth in revenues to over 19.7 billion pesos or close to $1.8 billion for the quarter.</p>
          <p>We have strengthened our presence in the non-carbonated beverage business in Latin America and once again, it represented more than 40% of our incremental volumes in the quarter. The Coca-Cola brand delivered another 40% of the incremental volumes and water was balanced.</p>
          <p>In Mexico, average prices excluding the fast-growing jug water business were stable, in spite of incremental soft drink volumes in multi-serve presentations. Volume growth, stable pricing and tightly controlled operating expenses partially offset cost pressures, driven mainly by higher sweetener and concentrate prices, resulting in a slight 0.8% decline in Mexico's operating income in the quarter.</p>
          <p>However, the strong growth in the Mercosur division, mainly due to the integration of Remil, more than compensated this decline and Coca-Cola FEMSA delivered another quarter of double-digit growth in its consolidated operating income. If you were unable to participate in Coca-Cola FEMSA's conference call last Thursday, you can access a replay of their webcast for additional details on the results.</p>
          <p>At FEMSA Comercio for the quarter, a strong growth &#x2013; a strong traffic growth of 11.9% partially offset the reduction in the average ticket of 13.6%, resulting in a decline of 3.2% in same-store sales in the quarter.</p>
          <p>As had been the case in the fourth quarter of 2007, the reduction in the average ticket is being driven by a migration from consumer purchases of prepaid cellular phone cards, for which we book the full sale price's revenue to the new electronic air-time purchases, from which we only book the amount of our commission, as opposed to the full amount of the recharge. Therefore, average ticket figures are not comparable to 2007. For comparability purposes, if we book the full amount of the electronic recharges, average ticket would have grown in the mid single-digits during the quarter.</p>
          <p>In terms of new store openings, we accelerated the pace during the quarter in order to take some pressure off the fourth quarter, adding 237 units for a total of 851 net openings in the last 12 months. This number is running well ahead of schedule and you should expect the full-year number to exceed the full-year number of openings of 2007. Probably it's reaching a little bit over 750 new stores. Revenues increased almost 10% during the quarter, reflecting a slight dip in the trend, again reflecting a more cautious consumer as well as some favorable weather in some important markets.</p>
          <p>Gross margin improved 340 basis points, largely driven by the change in the way we would book prepaid cellular air-time, as I just described, as well as by a strong performance from high margin categories such as coffee and alternative beverages and to a lesser extent, by better commercial agreements with our suppliers.</p>
          <p>Sequentially, operating expenses increased slightly above the previous quarter, reflecting the accelerated number of store openings and higher operating costs at the store level, mainly energy, as well as expenses related to the strengthening of FEMSA Comercio's organizational structure that is being carried out throughout 2008, as we discussed in previous calls and that is anticipated in our plans for the year. Despise the rising operating expenses, operating income increased a little bit over 30%. Comercio expanded its operating margin by 110 basis points to reach 6.5% of revenues for the quarter.</p>
          <p>And so summing it up, we have reasons for caution as well as reasons for optimism. On the one hand, there are clear signs that the consumer is becoming increasingly cautious across our markets and we are not immune to global deceleration trends. On the other hand, we enjoy today a stronger competitive position than ever before in more markets than ever before. We have a better understanding of consumer behavior and we are confident about what needs to be done.</p>
          <p>We have time-tried tools to use in difficult times, such as dynamic packaging mix and broad segmented brand portfolios. And we have a management team committed to driving efficiencies across the organization and maximizing the return of every dollar of investment. As I mentioned before, we are making a priority of our flexibility to deploy resources in a way that is consistent with the evolution of our businesses and we're proud that we will emerge from this environment stronger that we are today.</p>
          <p>And with that, I would like to open the call for, now, questions. Please, operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Javier. The question-and-answer session will begin at this time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question will come from Robert Ford with Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, Javier, good morning, everybody. I had a question with respect to your hedging positions and I was hoping you could just review those for us, commodities as well as anything you might have in terms of swaps and rates, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Bob. Let me start by saying that we do follow a very conservative approach to risk management. We make very limited use of derivative instruments, basically to reduce the volatility and uncertainty of some operating results, basically by hedging rates. I would split this in maybe three, interest rate, foreign exchange, price of raw materials.</p>
          <p>Let me try to expand a little bit on both the policy and the nature of the different derivative processes we have. First, in the case of foreign exchange and interest rates, the primary objective here is to actually remove those risks from the balance sheet and our income statement. As an example, I can share with you that, for example, the majority of our revenues and profits are denominated in pesos or other local currencies. So a very small component of our debt is expressed in dollars, something like around 20% and mostly &#x2013; most of our debt are basically fixed to interest rates. About 70% of our debt is basically swap to fixed interest rates. That to start with.</p>
          <p>Second, I would say action is, particularly for the beer business on Mexico, we do hedge all the dollars &#x2013; we have a short position in dollars. We do export significantly less than we need to import. So we also have hedging positions on the deficits, on the dollars the operation has, both on the purchases of raw materials and CapEx. So we do hedge those among time and we basically have for this year and next year, hedges on the short positions at around 11 pesos. So that's also the second component of our hedging strategy. And as I said, these two have a lot to do with managing risk and bringing certainty to the operations of the company.</p>
          <p>The third component is basically hedging raw materials and here, the objective is to a short and certain level at which we can be able to source the inputs in the future, taking volatility out of the cost structure and giving us better visibility on our margins. In this case, basically, we do hedge our positions in the key raw materials that we can, which is basically aluminum, natural gas, indirectly, some of our needs in barley and sugar in a very, very small amount. And for those, we have different time frames of hedging. For aluminum, we have kind of a couple of years ahead of us hedged a significant portion of our needs, close to 70% maybe. And I think that basically covers up all the things we do in terms of our hedging strategy. It is important to remind you that as a matter of policy also, we do not engage in any exotic derivative structures at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And, Javier, just to get a sense, you're long aluminum above $1 a pound, right? Is that fair to say?  Closer to like $1.10, maybe $1.20?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, in terms of tons, Bob, it is about $2,800 per ton, thereabouts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from Lauren Torres with HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. I was hoping you could just talk a bit more about some of the consumption or the consumer trends that you've been seeing in Mexico, I guess just over the last couple of months? If you could talk about the frequency of consumer purchases or the price of products consumers are purchasing, what noticeable trends have you seen as a result of this over the last couple of quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Lauren. I would say that pretty much in line with financial markets, pretty volatile. I couldn't really talk about a trend that is starting to emerge. The only trend that we can talk about is a slowdown, but it doesn't really have a pattern. We can have a good month and then we can have not a such good month. And as I just expressed in the opening remarks, a good month in September for the soft drink business doesn't really mean a good month for either also beer, plus July and August being a different picture.</p>
          <p>We have not seen a shift in packaging so far, which can tell us that consumers are starting to behave in a very significant way, but we're assuming that, that may be the case going forward a little bit down the road. A number of still external noises out there, very complex times in terms of media, so people again are being impacted by all this pessimism. Of course in Mexico, there are also other phenomenas which are now present, on security and things like that.</p>
          <p>I talked about weather. We've increased pricing. We are now starting to redirect some of our promotional resources taking into account how consumers are now being impacted by food inflation and the slowdown in the transfer from the U.S. and unemployment rates. And so I would say that still it's a quarter that all in all, it was not a good one, definitely. But if we look at trends now, going into October, I would say that it's still the same picture. There is not a clear pattern still emerging.</p>
          <p>So I couldn't be able to really to talk about whether the frequency of purchase is slowing down or the transaction is reducing or people are shifting. So we still have a number of mix effects within the evolution of the three businesses and the geographies within Mexico, so I would say that it'll take a little bit more time to really know where this is heading in terms of changes in mix and transactions or frequency of purchasing going. So I think we will need to wait a little bit more on, I hope that at least the comments I have made have been some help for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. And I guess thinking another quarter or two ahead if we could, if these trends soften further, I was just curious and I know you mentioned a few ways to offset them, but as far as priorities and what you will lean on most, is it further pricing, is it on the cost side? I think &#x2013; I just want to get a level of your comfort of where those offsets will be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, no, I think we've done our job in terms of trying to manage the pricing agenda in the industry and we feel comfortable with the level of pricing. We think these prices are there to stick with, but we don't see any rolling back whatsoever. We think again we're looking for the next months also a number of &#x2013; I mean, a large bulk of population in Mexico being reviewed the wages in the fourth and first quarters. So we are pleased with the amount and the way we executed the price increase, even though the numbers of third quarter are not the best. But I would say that I think we have done pricing for the next month at least.</p>
          <p>As I said, we think that we have a number of opportunities to look at the programs that we had originally in place for the full year, both the fourth quarter and going into the first quarter of 2009. And we will need to review a number of those to really look at those, which we can either optimize or defer or bring efficiency into it. So we will definitely work much more harder on the cost side than on the price side. I think on the price side, it will be more the typical revenue management kind of activities, that the time we see a tactical or marginal opportunity, we will go for it. I do not have any doubts on that.</p>
          <p>But definitely the big work of the worlk we need to do is going to have to come from the spending on the markets and the spending internally in the company. We think we have been able to bring a lot of productivity and efficiency on the manufacturing side of the business for a long time and even recently. And we have made a number of decisions in order to strengthen our competitive positions and drive innovation and bring to consumers new propositions. And I think that will be the part of the business that we will need to review in light of the new environment, Lauren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Celso Sanchez with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Just to keep up on this slowdown theme over the next several quarters at least, it would seem, can you give us a little bit more color on specifically within the packaging mix shift, is that going to require additional CapEx to invest in bottles? I know the shift for years has been moving more towards non-returnables, so do you have the inventory available to meet those needs, should the shift become more accelerated than perhaps we're all expecting now?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, I imagine with 70%, if I heard you right, of your aluminum hedge that gives you some wiggle room if non-returnables end up being a lower percentage of your mix, so you are not locked in by aluminum that you might not necessarily need, is that a fair assessment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Celso, could you repeat the last part of the question in terms of the aluminum and relationship to the volume that is hedged?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. If I understood you correctly, the aluminum needs were about 70% hedged and that would seem to leave an appropriate gap in case the non-returnable portion does shift more quickly away towards returnable and therefore you'll need less aluminum?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so you're saying we might end up needing less cans or fewer cans, if the mix indeed shifts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the two &#x2013; hi, Celso. First on the CapEx. I mean, we have enough flexibility both on the bottling lines for managing the shift, which we tend to believe that it may happen. So there's no need at all in terms of CapEx, nor in terms of inventory of bottles at all. So we are fine with that and the shift of mix that we could be expecting, we're going to be able to manage that without basically an investment on it.</p>
          <p>And the second part, yes, that may be the case of the shift. These times have proved to also in the past that the people again move a little bit from convenience and the most expensive presentations, which definitely are the non-returnables. So we may be less exposed to that, because of a decline in the shift.</p>
          <p>I would close the statement just by saying that we are not anticipating a major shift for the people which have been following the company for a number of years. This is not a situation similar to the ones in Mexico, when we suffered either internal or external economic shocks in which the structure of the population, the critical wage mass of people changed dramatically. So I would just alert people not to think of major shifts in terms of packaging, but I would say a moderate one. That at least are going in position where we'll need to see how things evolve. And of course, there is a &#x2013; I mean, a lot to be seen still in terms of the dust being settled, but we will feel that trends in packaging are going to be much more moderate, as opposed to some other times of the company in which changes in mix have been very, very strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just a follow-up on the same, is there &#x2013; can you give us a little more color, I know you gave us some helpful comments in the prepared remarks about potential for marketing, privatization of marketing expenses. Can you give us some examples that we might be able to think of, whether it's order of magnitude or types of programs that may have been on the agenda that you perhaps have less immediately necessary and therefore disparable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sure, Celso. We're not going into magnitude, because I think that's both critical and it's something that we wouldn't like to share. But in terms of &#x2013; for example, I can give maybe a couple of examples. We have been and we have said this in past that we have worked in order to reinforce the strength and the equity of our brands and that is a very long-term consistent process.</p>
          <p>And for example, to build the brands, you use a number of elements of the marketing mix as well, as when for example, you use advertising, you try build at the same time general attributes for the product and some specific attributes for the product and your share of voice objectives, the mix of the advertising you put in the media in order to build those attributes for the very long-term, for example, those are areas in which we can think we can slow down a little bit in the short-term without jeopardizing the efforts we have been making, without really impacting either short-term volumes or overall brand equity of the brand. That's one case.</p>
          <p>In some other cases, when we do prioritize the promotional activities, also we have always in mind volume objectives and brand equity also objectives and in some cases, we can also change a little bit the prioritization so we can maybe slow down a little bit on those promotional activities that offer the less and which have the less returns on investment, as opposed to the most important ones. So I would tend to say those are the ones. Also, the way we deploy our program to support specific retailers in order to have a very different model of relationship with them that would allow us to capture more of the top line of those retailers, but we will need to invest more in those.</p>
          <p>Those are the things that are very important, we think, for the long-term, but that in the short-term, we can take a different approach when the situation is getting to a point as we are looking at it. So those would be maybe three examples of the things that we are going to be looking at in terms of things that we can either rationalize for good or at least postpone until we see a more healthier environment for bottom growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very helpful, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Celso.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Alan Alanis with JPMorgan, your line is open, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning to you. I have a question regarding operating cash flows and returns on invested capital. As I'm seeing year to date results in the three business units, Javier, I mean, if I just subtract the EBITDA, the CapEx from the EBITDA, I get that the operating cash flow is growing 10%. At Coca-Cola FEMSA, it's growing more than 30% at OXXO, even despite the record number of openings. But it's declining almost to 20% in the beer business. How should we think about operating cash flow from the beer business going into 2009? And could you remind me what are the returns on invested capital of each of the three businesses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, sure, and hi. First, I think it's approximate not a very good one just taking EBITDA and then subtracting CapEx, because also it's a business as you well know that demands a lot of working capital, so that should be taken into account. So actually, as we've said, it's a business that grows I mean, a very, very high growth rate, but still do not generate excess cash flows because it basically reinvests whatever it produces. So it doesn't really require financing but it doesn't really produce excess cash flows. And Coca-Cola FEMSA of course is a business which &#x2013; because the structure, the margin, their investment needs, the profitability, it creates, I mean, the excess cash flows in a significant way, which basically are used to from time to time deleverage the business and then take advantage of acquisition opportunities.</p>
          <p>The case of beer is different. The case of beer under severe margin pressures basically for both largely buy raw materials and slow volume growth combined with the gearing, which we've started to build facilities both in beer and glass. I think that's the gearing which you are looking at, what you're looking because of that.</p>
          <p>Long term and there are &#x2013; I mean, the history of beer, the beer business is therefore for you to check on that and to validate what I'm saying, the beer business is a significant excess cash flow generator also as well. So '08 is the year in which we will need to take a little bit more cautious look into what's going on within the three different business in terms of the stage of development specific for each of those three. And in terms of return on CapEx, I mean, our own capital invested, also was, we do know it's very high double digits, for Coca-Cola FEMSA, it is low double-digits and for beer, it's high-single digits.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So would the increase of cost that we're seeing in the cost of capital, then I guess start to say that the beer business is almost again not covering its cost of capital, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we are there. I think we are there. I think we are basically there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I would just &#x2013; one last point on this, would this situation, I mean, could you expand a little bit more, what are the kind of things that can be done in, when you're saying we're going to review the investments in for 2009, I guess specifically on selling expenses and CapEx, could you give us a little bit more color in terms of what are the things that can be reduced and can be cut for next year in order &#x2013; yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, sure. I'll use again numeric exercises or dimensioning, but maybe a couple of examples. One significant source of efficiency that we think we are going to be able to capture is deploying alternative root to market models, which are, I would say, at least for the beer business, kind of a third generation market.</p>
          <p>If you remember, we used to be a company who would manage our route to market pretty much 100% based on traditional sales, basically seven years ago. We went into a first wave when we started in a selected way to do pre-sales and we then refined pre-sale, adapting pre-sale to the different realities of the market structure, both in terms of drop sizes, fragmentation, density and things like that. And into 2009, we will be deploying a number of the new models that we have been both developing and testing, such for example as face and cold pre-sale models, which bring efficiency to the table in a significant way.</p>
          <p>Once we have been mastering some of the management techniques for the sales force, we are now being able to increase the span of control of the supervisory people. So now a supervisor can have a larger &#x2013; an ample span of control on the number of presellers that he can manage. We are still making a lot of projects in which we are taking non-value added activities from the sales force and the probably administrative offices on the distribution centers, into the share service center here in Monterrey and that is also producing a number of benefits. And that &#x2013; I am speaking a lot about efficiency which are &#x2013; which is embedded in the operating model of the company. There are some others in which we are rationalizing some of the programs that we are bringing to the marketplace, in some cases, because some of the programs we have been executing have accomplished its objectives, in terms of covering a certain amount of retailers in certain areas, in which we have been establishing this specific relationship model with some of them.</p>
          <p>And in some others, as I said, we have been increasing spending levels largely driven by marketing because of a number of decisions that we have been making in terms of the strategy behind the brands, both in terms of packaging and in terms of geographies. And the best example I can use is, this is the year and we defined this basically three years ago in which we were launching the Indio company. This is a brand that has been growing very, very fast in a number of geographies that is -- have been increasing brand equity in a very significant way, that now we're putting a very large, very different, I think very good advertising campaign in Mexico, and we're putting a lot of money into it.</p>
          <p>So we think next year, we are going to have the ability to slow down a little bit on both the investment &#x2013; both some of these efforts that we have been pursuing in the past. So all in all, those are examples that I hope give you a glimpse of where we are coming from when we say we're going to bring efficiency to the business in both operating expenses and marketing expenses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from Lore Serra with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I wondered if we could just go back to the theme of CapEx. I think your budget for CapEx this year, at the start of the year anyway, was about $1.3 billion. I wonder if you could give us any update as to whether or not that's still a good figure for '08? And also, you mentioned in your press release that you intend to generate internally the funds you need to further short-term debt. Carlos talked a lot on the conference call last week about their plans on that regard. If I am not mistaken, I think there is about $315 million of short-term debt that's at the FEMSA non-cost level, and I just wonder if you could comment on whether you think you'll generate that kind of cash over the next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, sure. The &#x2013; for the CapEx story, I think the best number to use, at least the one we are using internally, and I mean, this is something that we are reviewing basically on a weekly basis. CapEx is a process that now in the company is being managed, I think in some businesses on a weekly basis and some others maybe bi-weekly. But the best number I can bring to tell maybe something like 900, 500 &#x2013; I mean, 950, a little bit less than the 1 billion instead of the 1.3 as we shared on the 20th mid-year.</p>
          <p>And in terms of the cash needs, in order to refinance and pay maturities in 2009, you're correct. Basically the maturities in Coca-Cola FEMSA that have to do with the <mark type="inaudible" />, that's pretty much going to be covered by excess cash at hand today and the cash flow that's going to be generated in the next seven to eight months. And there are very small amounts in local currencies, which are revolving liabilities that are refinanced on a regular basis, as the case of Coca-Cola FEMSA. In the case of the rest of the system, as I said, we don't see still OXXO generating excess cash flow. We would like to keep reinvesting whatever cash flow is generated in that business into OXXO itself.</p>
          <p>And in the case of beer, it will have a lot to do with the speed at which we will keep the investing process in the new brewery and in the glass factory.  Time will tell if the business will generate excess cash flow not in the first six months of the year, but at the FEMSA level or I mean not at the FEMSA level, but at the beer business, all the maturities of 2009 have already been refinanced in anticipation of all this financial turbulence.</p>
          <p>So we feel pretty much comfortable with the &#x2013; with having the ability to basically comply with all the maturities that we have in front of us. So again, the answer is it's very different when you look at the three businesses on a one-by-one basis, but all in all, we feel very, very comfortable with the flexibility that we have at hand in order to do the right things for the business for the long term, but managing the short-term accordingly to the situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But I guess I am still not sure. You're saying that of the 315 million short-term debt that it's not a cost you can generate that cash flow over the next year or you're just assuming you can refinance it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we have that of a short-term maturity ex-cost. I think maturities for cost plus the maturities ex-cost are basically going to be either paid by excess cash at hand and cash generated by cost and the rest are pretty much already refinanced.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the cash flow that the business is going to generate, I mean, ex-cost is going to have to &#x2013; I mean, is going to depend a lot on the reason of investing in CapEx at the beer business. That's specifically the new brewery and the new glass factory.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if I could, I wanted to ask a question on OXXO. If you adjust for the prepaid calling cards, it looks like the math would suggest that you're still growing double-digit in terms of same-store sales growth, which is really a remarkable level given the retail sector in Mexico. And I just wanted to confirm that, that is still the case, that you are seeing that kind of growth in your sort of core categories, ex the phone cards? And I know it's difficult to think about 2002 because OXXO was 2,000 stores in 2002, and now it's 6,000, as you mentioned, but how do you think that business ought to hold up as you face a more difficult environment in Mexico over the coming year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, yes. The third one is a yes. That still is the number, that was the trend. And again if you look at the quarter for OXXO, we may have had a dark September, but still good July and August. So we don't see still people trading convenience for price, at least in the categories that OXXO is the leader in the marketplace by far.</p>
          <p>And on the second part, I tend to believe that people have come to be a destiny by itself. OXXO has been a &#x2013; come to be a destiny by itself. Just as you're saying the large mass, the coverage that OXXO presents to consumers is there. We are very, very competitive in pricing in the categories which really makes the bulk of OXXO. So we have been saying this in the past, this is not the typical convenience U.S. store in which you overprice some of the categories as opposed to some other channels and you really charge consumers a lot for convenience. We do charge consumers for convenience, but not in the way most people are used to it, at least in the U.S. market.</p>
          <p>So we think that both the scale that OXXO has reached, the competitive pricing in the main leading categories that OXXO is basically the destiny of consumers. And also the &#x2013; I would say, the fine tune on the consumer offer that OXXO presents to people in these times, these three elements put together, we feel very optimistic that OXXO is going to be very, very good at navigating turbulence in 2009. So I would say those are the main reasons why we are still feeling optimistic about these, Laurie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would add to what Javier mentioned, Laurie. It is theory at this point, but we think it makes sense and we'll see if it plays out this way. But as consumers &#x2013; as conditions make consumers more cautious, there should be a shift from somebody that's going to the store and buying the inventory for the full week. In the theoretical case, they go to the big box and load up the trunk with goods, to a situation where you go back to kind of the daily purchase of your staples, because you don't have the cash available for the large purchase or you just don't want to invest in an inventory and you would just rather go to the store on a daily basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and I'm sorry, to go back to beer, and I know you've commented a lot. So maybe I could ask just a couple of real quick questions. One is that you didn't give updated guidance. I assume that was intentional. You had them thinking about a flat EBIT margin in beer. Is there any reason to think that your updated views for this year would be very different from what the nine-month trends have been?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it will have to do a lot with volumes, Laurie, for the quarter. I think we're going to do our best in terms of managing costs and selling expenses for the quarter, considering the environment. But I think it will have to do a lot with the volume. I'm not skeptical about pricings holding up, as I said. I'm not skeptical about the level of promotional activities. I think we're going to do our job in terms of managing costs and selling expenses for the quarter, but in the end, I think volume will tell the story when we close the year.</p>
          <p>I'm sure that we're not going to be able to be flat in terms of margins, just because of what happened basically in the past nine months, both in terms of slowdown and pressures. Of course, we are in a good place in terms of our hedging for the quarter, both in terms of FX and aluminum, but we feel that volume is going to be the decisive part of the story here. So that's where we are heading, I think. We will need to wait a couple of months to see where we end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just, you've answered already a lot of questions on the selling costs, but I'm wondering if you could just help us understand, for the quarter, as you mentioned, your selling expenses were rising at double the pace of sales, and clearly sales fell short, as you mentioned, on the volume side.</p>
          <p>But could you help us understand, it sounded like you were pretty intent in the second quarter conference call on sort of stabilizing the selling costs? And it doesn't look like it happened in the third quarter. So, if you can help us understand why it didn't happen? Was it Brazil? Was it Mexico? And I guess, if you think of an environment next year where maybe your top line in beer grows low to mid single-digit, can you contain your selling expenses to that kind of a level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Again, I made the comment on the opening of the mic that it is for us, it is much more &#x2013; I mean, I'd like to try to both explain and communicate the message that the reference on a quarter-to-quarter basis for us is just a consequence of how we laid plans for last year and how we are laying plans for this year.</p>
          <p>So my take on this is, if you look at a two-year period, which now normalizes more, I would say, 24 months as opposed to only 12, you see that the combined growth rate of those two years are looking at first, second, third and hopefully four, that's our plan at least, has been coming down, the growth, accumulated growth rate for selling expenses.</p>
          <p>So on a quarter-by-quarter basis, you may find a number of explanations not on what we're doing this year, but on what we did last year and it's a very, very short timeframe to really judge if &#x2013; where we're heading to.</p>
          <p>The objective for the future as we stated beginning this year is basically to bring selling expenses growth more in line, as you correctly stated, in line with revenues. We were not expecting, to tell you the truth, a decline of 2% on volume in Mexico this quarter. We were expecting a moderate increase. So that, yes, produced a disalignment between the growth rate of revenues and selling expenses for the quarter. But if you look again at a 24 period instead of a 12-month period, you will see second quarter growth rate declining against the first, then third quarter declining against the second and hopefully, you will see the fourth quarter declining against the third. So those would be my main comments, Lauren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>In the interest of time, we ask that you please limit yourself to one question in order to allow everyone an opportunity to signal for questions. We will go next to Jos&#xE9; Yord&#xE1;n with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone. My question is about Brazil, I mean, in a unit that basically where selling expenses are a much greater percentage of sales and where, let's say, the cost pressures or the currency pressures at least could end up being worse than in Mexico, how has the strategy if at all changed for next year or for the fourth quarter in how you approach Brazil, Brazil with Mexico or is it the same, is it exactly the same thing? But I would think that it perhaps requires a deeper look at the strategy there. And then if you could just update us on, when do you expect to see the grains cost beginning to come down on a per hectoliter basis in 2009. Is that in April, is it in June, any idea you can give us there would be great?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Jos&#xE9;.  You are positively right in terms of the main issue for Brazil going forward being the foreign exchange rate. I would say first that if you remember, grains and I will talk a little bit about grains, aluminum hedging and then our going in position for selling and marketing expenses in that market, as well as the competitive dynamics.</p>
          <p>Because first, if you remember grain pressure in Brazil this year has been enormous, to say the least, I mean, close to 60% of pressure because again, '07, we were very good at hedging that. But going into 2009, we feel more comfortable with grain prices leveling off mid-year maybe and when I talk about the hedging strategy of the beer business, we have less hedging in Brazil than in Mexico, so we will be more favored in Brazil because of the aluminum declining prices. So grain and aluminum will &#x2013; should give some room to move that should be able to compensate or mitigate at least some of the FX impact on Brazil.</p>
          <p>Having said that, the other thing that we are going to have to monitor a lot is precisely &#x2013; this is going to be a reality for all businesses in Brazil. So competitive dynamics are an important thing to look at. Specifically in terms of how in the end these facts change &#x2013; impact the different players on the industry and we think in the &#x2013; at least at beer, we think that we're much better off than the leader in the market, but not maybe much better off than the other two brewers, I mean, in Brazil.</p>
          <p>So the spending in Brazil will have to do a lot with again a relative position to the share of voice in terms of advertising and promotional and sponsoring activities by the three main brewers in Brazil and that would be the leading indicators for us to really make our minds in terms of how much money we will need to put behind our brand.</p>
          <p>We feel comfortable that we are going to be manage and of course we have assumptions of the real &#x2013; of the Brazilian real being below the actual levels, but we will need to again look at how that develops, but only now that we think we have some positives that will help us to mitigate some of the negatives. And so far, what we're doing now is working very hard in order to have different action plans for different scenarios, both in terms of microeconomics for the country as well as for the competitive positioning of the three main players in Brazil. So that's where we are today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would add, I think, I mean, we talked in the past of how in Brazil, we are spending behind the brands a significantly higher percentage of sales than we would if we had a mature brand portfolio. So that gives us a little bit of a cushion, I guess, in terms of the ability to adjust the spending levels. We've talked about as much as 10% of sales being quote-unquote "overinvested", just because, as you know, Kaiser and Sol require more investment than a stable brand. But it does give us some flexibility to react in times such as these.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how do you see AmBev, I mean, with their, let's say, situation being perhaps affected more by the new tax law and with the need to generate as much cash flow as possible in light of the parent funding needs and so forth, have they been, let's say, acting as you would expect in a much more &#x2013; in much less aggressive way into the fourth quarter or no change?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think both tax and the transaction that their cash flows are facts of life, and the way they're going to manage those, I think it is still early to tell and it's of course their own decision. But on the other parts, I think that the competitiveness in the beer industry in Brazil I would say still remains the same. I mean it &#x2013; there is no irrationality in the marketplace, but there is a fierce fight for every case of beer that is being sold, not only by AmBev, but by everybody including us there. So it is still a good fight to fight, Pepe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question will come from <mark type="inaudible" /> with Lucite Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone. Just very quickly, I mean you did say that you feel comfortable with the grain price leveling off middle of the year. I'm just curious to know, at what level do you think they will level off? And in terms of &#x2013; do you think they will level off at what prices are right now, your hedged prices are right now? And also, I wanted to know if you think prices would start coming off at some time in the future and if you're prepared for that?</p>
          <p>Secondly, with regards to OXXO, just a couple of things. First, if your target for the current year is still 700 stores, what your target is for next year? And how do you see same-store sales growing in 2009, given that there will most likely be a softer economic environment in that year? So yes, these are the three questions I have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Sylvie, this is Juan. First on the grains, I mean, I think one, I wouldn't want to speculate on where prices will end up, but obviously we've built our plans for next year and we've made assumptions. And for example, I can tell you that the aggregate impacts from raw materials for the beer business, which is probably what you're most interested in or where most of the variability perhaps could come in, we are expecting a mid to high-single digit growth, not a per unit basis, but an aggregate number, so obviously there are some volume assumptions embedded in there. But it's coming from &#x2013; where we're coming from this year, where we're seeing 30s, 40s percent in terms of increments for individual commodities, obviously talking about an aggregate impact of mid- to high-single digit. It's not a bad place to start.</p>
          <p>Talking about OXXO, the number this year is probably going to be close to 750, that &#x2013; it's kind of a rule of thumb that's usually to open more stores on any given year than we opened in the previous one. So this year, we are certainly going to achieve that and perhaps by a wider margin than originally expected. And having smoothened the curve going to the fourth quarter, I think the pipeline is pretty robust and we feel pretty good at this time that we can again exceed that number next year. So anything that is higher than 750, we could perhaps throw out at 770 or something like that. I think obviously we're going to have to watch the evolution of the environment. At this time, there is no &#x2013; we don't see the need to pare down the number of store openings. I think right now we're going as planned for more stores than this year.</p>
          <p>In terms of the same-store sales figures, as of next quarter, we're going to begin to see slightly cleaner numbers in the sense that we will be lapping the first quarter, where we have the electronic air-time shift. I don't think it's going to be 100% clean. I think there is still a bit of a ramp up as users are adopting the electronic recharges and the fact that the smallest size of the recharge is 30 pesos has brought more people into the store. And so when you look at same-store sales, I think traffic will continue to be impacted by the telephonic category, but at this point, we see no reason to expect same-store sales to decline materially.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. So just on the commodity side, would it be fair to assume that your per unit grain cost might actually come down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It might, it might. I mean as Javier mentioned, we do have probably a good 30% of our aluminum needs system wide that are not hedged. We are not 100% hedged in any commodity. So there is definitely the potential for upside, especially the second half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from Ola Salimo with Legg Mason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, the question was answered already. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And we will move on to Carlos Laboy with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Javier, I want to go at Laurie's question a little differently. I think that several years ago when you set out to transform the beer business, a key business adjective was to invest more behind brand pull capability, so that you could get away from having to buy the trade with spiraling exclusivity spending. Yet here we are, you have rising brand spending and you are on a course for rising exclusivity spending as well.</p>
          <p>So if the brand pull strategy is working as you say it is, why haven't you been able to decelerate the reliance on the rising exclusivity spending? And I guess related to that, how do you see push and pull spending behaving looking out over the next couple of years? Because it sounds like the best we can hope for really is for less visibility of operating leverage at FEMSA Cerveza  than at other brewers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Carlos. I would say that our view for the Mexican beer business for the long term has been definitely all the time a shift volume from more push-driven activities to pull, and I think that's been the case. I think that the business has been in the previous, I would say three to four years, mainly after a first stage of, I would say, building the tools and developing capabilities. I think it has been in a stage in which we have been investing heavily in both, to tell you the truth. It's not like there has been a significant shift, but I would say that a step up in both.</p>
          <p>And this was, I would say partially in recognition of these being what the business needed in terms to compete effectivity in the marketplace. And I think that if you look at us four years down the road after this process began in terms of the step up of spending, I think that we feel comfortable in both dimensions, in the way we have now a platform on the marketplace in which we have relationships with retailers and the expansion of OXXO. That makes us feel pretty good about what we've accomplished in that regard.</p>
          <p>And also, if we look at how are the results of &#x2013; on brand equity and brand performance, all across the board in terms of brand equity indicators and attributes of the brand that allow us to differentiate now truly in a significant way of portfolio brands, we're also seeing that the money we have been putting, the money &#x2013; how the money was spent.</p>
          <p>Going forward, I think that considering the stage at which we are and considering the environment we're going to be facing, I think that we will need to do our job in both dimensions in order to optimize and be more efficient in the management of both levers for the business. Will that represent a major shift in the next two years between push and pull? I don't think so. Will that continue to be a shift in the right direction, that is the pull, the driven activities? Definitely, yes. So that would be my answer to your question, Carlos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Javier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question will come from Roger Deabrie with Tweety Brown.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This must be a mistake.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Roger.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Yes, I never pushed any button so. Glad to hear you and to see you, but I didn't have a question, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And sir, your line has been re-established.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Sorry about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And sir, we will take our next question from Alex Robarts with Santander.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everybody. Thanks. I guess, I wanted to go back to the hedges with a clarification, and then a question on the beer export. With the hedges at the 11 peso FX rate with the dollar for '09, are you basically saying that the export sales that you have next year, you will book them at an exchange rate of 11 pesos? Is it all, is it 50%, I mean, if you could kind of give us some color on that? And also, if there is anything on the fourth quarter?</p>
          <p>As far as the grains, if I could just understand on the grain bit, so for the next two quarters, 4Q and 1Q, I do understand that you have hedged the malt. And if you could give us a sense of what would that average &#x2013; your average cost be in 4Q, 1Q '09 on a year-on-year basis? And then, the export question really just relates &#x2013; I mean, you've had some very strong growth this year and I'm wondering, who do you think in the U.S. and specifically since most of your exports are in the U.S., who do you think you are taking market share from? And I guess as I understand this trading down trend in the U.S. import segment, is it safe to kind of think about your export business now as pretty much being driven by Dos Equis growth? I mean, I guess the sense is that Heineken, Corona, maybe to copy the larger brands, getting kind of more impacted by this trading down effect. And what kind of growth can you give us kind of as an outlook over the next couple of quarters in terms of the exports?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, sure. First, the FX, it doesn't work that way, Alex. Basically we will keep recording, as I explained, the export sales at the expense rate when we account for the sale. What we do is we do hedge only the deficit when we compare whatever we export to whatever we import. And whatever we import is basically either raw materials or CapEx, so the hedge we have on the deficit of the dollars, the short position on dollars we have, are going to be basically recorded partially on cost of sales and partially on the acquisition of the CapEx that we make importing equipments from abroad. So those will be the specific lines at which the hedges will materialize.</p>
          <p>On the grain side, the comment would be that next year, we think prices should ease off to a point at which they can be at the level of, as opposed to this year, maybe at the mid of 2009. And yes, we do hedge some of those barley and malt needs, and basically barley, I should say, not malt, basically the sourcing &#x2013; the domestic sourcing in Mexico, that's the one we pretty much hedge using as an indirect hedge the wheat.</p>
          <p>In terms of exports, I think the performance on the export side, we think it's not entirely driven by Dos Equis. If you look at our numbers on Tecate, they are pretty good, basically in the regions in which Tecate is a strong brand. We think that depending on the brand in the region we may be taking some share. Considering the scale of our brand, that is not really a share play, it is basically creating critical mass, we think.</p>
          <p>And depending on the brand, as I said, we may be taking a little bit more share with Tecate on the domestics premium mentioned kind of products and to the low-priced imports from some other geographies and as well, we are now, I think, now having campaigns for the general market on Tecate also in english, is helping a lot to address the general market as well. And of course, Tecate &#x2013; I mean, Dos Equis is performing extremely well in all key indicators, such as distribution, velocity, our native brand awareness, sales consumption.</p>
          <p>So I would say the export growth is &#x2013; it's pretty much the result of a number of years now, this being basically the fifth year that we are working with Heineken, both in terms of aligning the organizations and doing the job with the wholesalers, which in the end are the guys which are delivering the product to retailers. So, all in all, growth in the export market, we feel comfortable with a sustained growth rate for the year that would get us to the objective and the aspiration we had at the beginning of the year to be close to 10%.</p>
          <p>And of course 2009, it's pretty much a very hard number to talk about because of the situation specifically in that market, both in terms of the economy and the competitive landscape changes that are taking place in the beer industry in the U.S. So I would rather not talk much about the growth perspectives into 2009 for our U.S. business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Chris Svezia with MetLife.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, most of my questions have been answered, but one thing that I would like to clarify a little bit more is in Brazil in the beer business, just wanted to know what you think about your positioning in terms of your brands, how, what you can see, if you can sort of quantify it or give some qualitative indicators of how that's improved in terms of the strength of your brands and how defensive you feel in that market, given the outlook? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Chris. Without giving any specific numbers or either papers brand equity like, dislike, any indicator that we follow on a monthly basis with a very large survey market system that was deployed in Brazil, using the one we use in Mexico. But what I can share with you is that brand indicators are growing steadily in the right direction. It's not a spectacular growth, but if you look at the state of the brands that we bought from this business Kaiser and Bavaria specifically and the very, very young launch of Sol, we feel pretty optimistic about that we are making progress in the right direction.</p>
          <p>And I would say that volume growth, as I just expressed with Kaiser being the brand that is contributing the largest part of growth in Brazil today, it's a good example of a brand that was pretty much declining at double-digit growth rate for five years in a row, and now it's growing in absolute terms, and providing a bulk of the growth for the business.</p>
          <p>So all in all, my general message would be we're making progress with the portfolio, not with only one brand delivering the growth rates that we're experiencing. And we are confident that we have the right strategy both in terms of the definition of the brand portfolio basically on these three brands, playing a very different role in the portfolio each of those and complemented with very, very good brands also doing the job much more lower scale, such as Heineken, Shingu and some others. But all in all, we are feeling good about what we're looking at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And at this time, we have no further questions standing by. I'd like to turn the program back to Mr. Astaburuaga for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Just thanking you very much for your participation today. And have a good week everyone. Bye now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We thank you, everyone, for your participation on today's conference call and you may disconnect at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>