<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1187088" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-11-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>596</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Patrick de la Chevardi&#xE8;re, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2">Alastair Syme</participant>
      <participant id="3">Patrick de la Chevardi&#xE8;re</participant>
      <participant id="4">Michele Della Vigna</participant>
      <participant id="5">Neil McMahon</participant>
      <participant id="6">David Thomas</participant>
      <participant id="7">Jon Rigby</participant>
      <participant id="8">Mark Gilman</participant>
      <participant id="9">Kim Fustier</participant>
      <participant id="10">Colin Smith</participant>
      <participant id="11">Dominique Patry</participant>
      <participant id="12">Neill Morton</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen welcome to TOTAL's third quarter 2008 results conference call. I'll now hand over to Mr. de la Chevardi&#xE8;re. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Hello and thank you for calling in. I'm sure you have heard the major oil companies comment on the changes in the environment that we have seen over the past weeks. So let me go directly to the third quarter results. And after that, I will describe how we have prepared TOTAL to weather the storm, even one like this.</p>
          <p>For the third quarter, TOTAL posted a new record for results. Compared to the third quarter 2007, adjusted net income increased by 48% to $6.1 billion, thanks to the high oil price in the third quarter. Earnings per share increased by 50% to $2.73, as ROACE [Return On Average Capital Employed] as a for the business segments rose to 29.5%. TOTAL is benefiting strongly from its integrated model with the Downstream and Chemicals performing particularly well.</p>
          <p>Looking at the cash flow for the quarter, cash flow was $11 billion, an increase of 126%, including a positive working capital effect following the drop in the oil price. CapEx was $5.1 billion, which is in line with of 2008 budget of $19 billion. And we sold $0.8 billion of non-strategic assets.  Essentially this was the sale of Sanofi sales. So our net cash flow was very strong at $7.1 billion.</p>
          <p>As a result, we have reduced our gearing from 25% at the end of June to 15% at the end of September. This is below our target range of 20 to 30%. And it reflects our desire to be prudent in the current environment by strengthening the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Finally for buybacks, since the beginning of the third quarter we have bought back close to 12 million shares for about $0.8 billion.</p>
          <p>So our third quarter results are pretty clean and straightforward. I will comment briefly on the business segments, then the environment, and how we are positioned for the coming months.  And after that, we will go to your questions.</p>
          <p>Starting with the Upstream, adjusted net income, which is after tax and includes the equity affiliates, was $4.4 billion for the Upstream segment in the third quarter 2008.  Our reported production volume was 2.23 million a day. This represents a decrease of about 5% year over year and sequentially. The difference is largely in Chemicals.</p>
          <p>Compared to the same quarter last year, we had the benefit of starting up Moho and Jura plus the production ramp-ups of new fields like Dolphin and Rosa. These positive effects were globally in line with expectations.  They were partially offset by normal declines on existing positions, which are on average running close 4% per year.</p>
          <p>Another offset was a negative price effect for about 2.5%, and this is in line with our published average sensitivity. So the remaining decrease reflects mainly one-off impacts.  In our case, this was the shutdown of Al Jurf, which we talked about last quarter, the unscheduled shutdowns on Bruce and Alwyn in the North Sea, and more disruptions in Nigeria.</p>
          <p>To get a better picture of our performance in production, I think it is best to look at the year-to-date comparison.  For the first nine months 2008 versus 2007, production decreased by 1.5%.  The price effect had an impact of minus 2.5%. Changes in the portfolio had a negative impact of 0.5%. So in terms of underlying production, we have increased by 1.5%, and this means that our new field startups have more than offset the natural decline and these one-off items.</p>
          <p>Looking at the fourth quarter, Jura recently reached its plateau on time and Moho Bilondo will continue to ramp up into next year, but at a slower pace than initially anticipated.  The Al Jurf field offshore Libya was shut down in the second quarter and it should be back in production at the end of the fourth quarter. In the third quarter, we had some problems with the Bruce and Alwyn fields in the North Sea and also OML 58 in Nigeria. They are all back in production now.</p>
          <p>It is too early to say how the price effect will impact the fourth quarter because of the offsetting effects of lower prices on cost oil versus the threshold effects.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, we are on track to start up Yemen LNG and the Akpo field, which is deep offshore Nigeria, in the first half of 2009. By the way, the Akpo steel arrived on site on October 18.  We expect Qatargas II will start up soon after Akpo.</p>
          <p>We also had some exploration success this quarter, including a very promising well on West Franklin. This discovery will allow us to increase recoverable reserves by about 120 million barrels and double production capacity with only one well. We are currently completing a few other interesting wells and we should have some updates for you soon.</p>
          <p>As part of our strategy to make targeted acquisitions, we completed the Synenco deal in Canada and we bought 60% of the giant Bemolanga heavy oil field in Madagascar at a cost that is very competitive with our finding costs. These are nice long-term options that do not require significant CapEx in the short term.</p>
          <p>We have made several significant final investment decisions since the end of 2007, including Pazflor, Usan, the Anguille development in Gabon, and OML 58 in Nigeria.  These projects are well into development now and they will create significant value, even with oil price at 50 to $60 per barrel.</p>
          <p>The next wave of FIDs for large, capital intensive projects is not expected prior late 2009 to early 2010. These include Joslyn in Canada, Shtokman, Ichthys LNG, and some new deep and new deep offshore projects. We have a lot of time to assess how the environment including costs may adjust and to determine how we can capture any potential benefits. If our analysis indicates that we should delay a project, then we will delay it. It is that simple. But at this point, there is no significant risk of a long-term project being postponed or delayed because of the current environment. So despite some one-off impacts, we are continuing to execute our strategy well.</p>
          <p>Let me switch to the Downstream and Chemicals segments. As I said at the beginning, we have reported a new record level of results and this was made possible in large part due to the very strong improvement in the Downstream and the Chemicals. Comparing the third quarter of 2008 to the second quarter, the adjusted net operating income was $1.4 billion for the Downstream, an 88[%] increase.  This is a new record level for the Downstream; and $0.4 billion for the Chemicals, which is 18% above last year.</p>
          <p>We have said many times that we believe strongly in the integrated model for major oil companies and these results clearly support our position.</p>
          <p>In the Downstream, turnaround activity was low. Downtime was limited, and even with the negative 3% impact from the shutdown of Port Arthur for hurricanes in September, refinery throughput increased by 4%.</p>
          <p>Refining margins went up to $45 per ton in the third quarter.  This is an increase of 88% compared to last year and 12% compared to the previous quarter. We benefited from the strong capture of these margins and we had pretty good performance in optimizing the supply of our system.</p>
          <p>Marketing performed well largely because of good margin and lag effects.  Marketing volumes on average were 3% lower than last year.</p>
          <p>Base chemicals in Europe benefited from prices that were set when naphtha was at a record level and from olefin-based projects despite a decrease in demand. And Specialty Chemicals performed well also despite some signs of a slowdown in demand.</p>
          <p>Finally, in the fourth quarter, Downstream and Chemicals are performing well.  Volumes are weakening a bit, but margins are still good, and there is no significant maintenance planned until the beginning of next year.</p>
          <p>Finally on corporate and strategy guidance, we are in very good shape with a strong balance sheet and plenty of cash to execute our strategy. We have reduced the gearing, which is a prudent course in a volatile environment.  Our net debt-to-equity ratio was 15% at the end of September.  We will pay an interim dividend on November 15 and this should have the effect of bringing the gearing back closer to 20%.</p>
          <p>You have our balance sheet and you can see that we have $19 billion in cash at the end of the third quarter. In addition to this cash, we have several billion dollars of standby credit lines available to us that are essentially untouched, and we have about $10 billion of Sanofi shares that we are selling progressively.</p>
          <p>On the debt side, we issued about $4 billion of bonds earlier of this year, so we are in a position now where we can wait for an improvement in market conditions before we issue new bonds. So that is liquidity.</p>
          <p>Now what is our view of the medium to long-term environment?  Despite the recent and very dramatic fall in oil prices, we continue to believe that the supply/demand balance will be tight over the long term and our investment vision is long term. Obviously, we expect to see some near-term weakness in demand related to a slowdown in global economic growth. But OPEC seems to be serious about maintaining a proper supply/demand balance on all the markets.</p>
          <p>There are declining rates for existing production and a potential slowdown in project development in the near term because of the current oil price.  So, we have some difficulties supporting the argument that the market should price in an oversupply of oil for the long term. Having said that, we are running two main scenarios for the 2009 budget: one at $80 per barrel and another one at $60 per barrel.</p>
          <p>For CapEx, the budget for 2008 is $19 billion, and I think we will end this year close to that number. We have not approved the 2009 budget, so we will have to wait and present the numbers to you in February. Our near term CapEx reflects mainly the portfolio of long-term projects that we are currently developing and preparing to start up.  We are not in a situation where we need to make significant changes.  All projects currently in development create substantial value at 50 to $60 per barrel.</p>
          <p>And as a last point, it is too soon for us to estimate the impact of falling costs on our CapEx program. We will do our best to push them down but it is too soon to say. What I can tell you about CapEx is that we are very serious about financial discipline and we will not launch a project if it does not meet our strict criteria.</p>
          <p>For OpEx, we have a cost advantage because we are the low-cost major. On average, our technical costs are about $5 per barrel lower than our peers, and this advantage has been increasing over the past years. This is important in the current environment. We are always reviewing our cost base and implementing performance plans to maintain and increase this advantage. And Christophe de Margerie recently asked the group management to formally and specifically address this point in the 2009 budgets.</p>
          <p>In closing, let me also say that 10 years ago when the oil price was at $10 per barrel, we maintained our CapEx and continued to increase our dividend. We believe that consistently investing for growth is the best way to create wealth over the long term. Let me emphasize again that we have a great deal of financial flexibility, and I am confident that we will be able to maintain our dynamic dividend policy over the long term, even if oil price remain in the current range.</p>
          <p>So now, we can start the Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator instructions" /> And we have the first question from Mr. Alastair Syme from Merrill Lynch. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, two quick questions.  One, in the countries that you operate within OPEC, have you been asked to scale back on production in line with the OPEC cuts recently announced?  And secondly, you mentioned two oil price scenarios for next year. I know you're not going to call out the absolute CapEx number, but is there a substantial difference in the CapEx that you would run under those two scenarios?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Alastair. The first question was on OPEC.  As far as I am aware of, we have not been asked for any cut of production. This does not mean that we will not be asked, but as of yesterday, I have no information about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You asked me then if we will change our CapEx program depending upon the pricing of oil.  Is this correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's basically the question, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, for 2009 you have to keep in mind that most of our CapEx program is already committed.  About 80% or more than 80% of that is already committed; so whatever is the oil price, those CapEx would be implemented. Are we going to adjust?  I mean we are in the budget process and I cannot comment more because we haven't seen yet to the degree that I know that the E&amp;P division is working on how to compose and maintain our CapEx program as far as we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As a related question, can I ask as you look into 2010, how much of the CapEx is committed?  Does it drop off a lot?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know the exact figure, but what you see is there is less among committed for 2010 than 2009.  I can't say more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mr. Michele Della Vigna from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Patrick. I would like to ask two questions. The first one is did you announce yesterday that you have locked in the margin of about 50% of the LNG supply?  You have a lot of new LNG coming on stream in 2009. Are you thinking about the similar strategy of locking in a margin, therefore '09 and 2010? The second question is relating to the large present on new process that you have and.  Are you planning to function any of those into next to 6 to 12 months or would you prefer to keep flexibility on future spending?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Michele. On our LNG strategy, as a policy, what really is the energy isolated LNG, gas, or oil, we do not put in place any coverage issues. So it is not our strategy to lock in price in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mr. Neil McMahon from Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I still have to answer the second question of Michele.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's okay. For new projects, we have big projects like Joslyn in Canada like Shtokman, Ichthys, Brass, which will be at FID by year end 2009 or late at the beginning of 2010. So let's say roughly we have more than one year to assess the environment and maybe &#x2013; I don't know, maybe to review our assessment for those projects. The main question is our deep will be the consequences of the financial crisis on the economy and we need to have more time to see what will be the consequences on the economy of the financial crisis.  And in parallel to that, we need to see what will be the consequences on the costs of our projects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Michele.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mr. Neil McMahon from Sanford Bernstein. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Neil McMahon with Sanford Bernstein. I've got a few questions. First of all, given the recent weakness in demand in Europe, could you give us an up to date view on how diesel demand is being seen in France through your retail operations and also across Europe?  I also have a few other questions, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rough figures, coming from the top of my mind from the months of July and August, I think it's up. In Europe it's about 5 to 6%, if I would remember.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you've got no more up to date data points than that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm sorry; I don't have any figures for September.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, maybe just turning to Madagascar and your new lease there, maybe you could describe a bit more in detail of about the lease in Madagascar and why in particular you are getting involved in the onshore rather than the offshore permits?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, it's an onshore heavy oil field, which we bought at an extremely reasonable price.  It is more than a billion barrels of 2B reserve and more than 10 billion barrel of resources basically.  It is a long-term option for us and we need time to study it so that we can figure out how to develop it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Will you be able to book any of these reserves for 2008?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not yet, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then I have just the one last question in terms of oil service contracts.  I know Christophe de Margerie has been very vocal on his feelings about oil service price inflation.  What flexibility or potential do you have within the oil service contracts or more specifically your drilling contracts to renegotiate over the next &#x2013; for drilling contracts over the next few years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know how to answer precisely your question because we usually when we are committed to something, we fulfill our commitments.  What is obvious is that when we use the time we have for the FIDs I mentioned in the previous question, to put pressure on the contractor so that they reduce their costs. That should be my answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mr. Dave Thomas from Citigroup.  Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi guys, good afternoon gentlemen; Dave Thomas with Citigroup here. I've got three questions, please.  Firstly, in the third quarter we saw the run rate on your sales of Sanofi shares accelerating.  Is this to ensure you divest all your stake by 2012? And so, can we anticipate a similar quarterly run rate in terms of cash flow from share sales?</p>
          <p>On the second question, you mentioned obviously a question back on not having any major FIDs before the end of next year and into 2010.  Can you comment on what impression this may have on reserves bookings as a consequence?  And the third question is around acquisitions. These were flagged at the midyear review and equity values have obviously dropped since then. Can you say what type of acquisitions you might be interested in that makes strategic sense for TOTAL; in other words, any regions or type of resource?  For example, I presume the oil sands are less attractive given oil prices are currently half the level you need to meet hurdle rates and returns?  Any comment you could provide there would be much appreciated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Dave, thank you for your questions.  I will start with the last one first about acquisitions. I'm not going to tell you where you should invest to enjoy the premium. But we -- I would say that we are open to plenty of opportunities.  We are interested in long plateau production.  That's what I would like to say.  I don't want to make the whole list of potential acquisitions we could make.  We are open to and that's it.  And the market is obviously a little bit tolerable currently.</p>
          <p>Your second question was FID and is there booking.  For this year, we would book Usan, OML 58, some reserve in Gabon, and maybe even West Franklin. I think you should wait until February to have more precise data because we will process off the booking reserves made in December in our company.</p>
          <p>Your first question was about Sanofi.  You should remember what I said last conference call about Sanofi, that we will do the job.  That's what we are currently doing. Are we going to maintain this straight or are we going to take opportunity to sell a package of shares? I don't know; this will depend on the market condition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In regards to the Sanofi question, it was just that 500 million round terms were sold in the third quarter.  I guess that's the rate that you'll need to divest the remaining stake by 2012.  So can we anticipate it will be something around that, not less than that from now on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The objective is to have no more Sanofi shares in our balance sheet by 2012, and we will use all means available to us to do it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mr. Jon Rigby from UBS. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I have two questions. The first relates back to 2010 CapEx again.  I think you FID-ed Pazflor, which is a development that I think you were so startled with the inflation that it was actually named the Pazflor effect. And also I think you indicated that you are in the process or have been in the process of ordering long lead time items for your Saudi refinery. I just wondered whether you have any ability on the activities or items that you have already ordered to revisit costs in those developments. And the second is I think there are some news stories yesterday concerning a supplementary review of the gap in your manufacturing capacity across Europe.  You have the largest refinery in Europe and I think notable ex one sale of a refinery of not really participating in any restructuring so far.  Is there a process of review taking place on your downstream assets?  Thanks</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Jon.  Your first question about can we eliminate some costs, it is partially done.  As I mentioned, when we are committed to something, we fulfill our commitment. And I remind you that Pazflor is extremely profitable given the $60 per barrel scenario.</p>
          <p>On Jubail, we may play a little bit with time there to push the costs down. We are currently discussing that with our partner.  Finally in Europe, we are in the process of thinking how to adjust our refining system to the market. We have already sold our refinery in UK, if you keep that in mind,   and we will adjust if necessary and when necessary our refinery system.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it focused on what you're producing or would it be a wider view of that? Would it be extended beyond just trying to reduce your exposure to the global gasoline market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your line is really bad. I'm sorry, Jon, because I can't hear exactly your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, is that better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll finish then, maybe come back offline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, sorry for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have question from Mr. Mark Gilman of the Benchmark Company.  Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick, good afternoon. I had three questions if I could, please.  First, in your comments you refer to a slower than expected ramp at Moho Bilondo. I wondered if you could give us a little more color as to the reasons for that. Secondly, the release refers to losses at the Dalian refinery in the third quarter, which given my understanding that's it's an export refinery and with the expansion currently not having come online is surprising.  I wonder if you could discuss exactly why that had occurred.  Third and finally, could you give us some idea how the renegotiation of fiscal terms in Libya will impact your volume and financial reporting with respect to operations in that country?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Moho Bilondo first, Mark. You &#x2013; the point is that one well was lost at the beginning, and that roughly explains why the ramp-up will slow down &#x2013; the ramp-up will be lower than expected. An additional well will be drilled by November in order to the recapture volume we don't have today.  Roughly, we are missing about 10,000 barrels per day, basically today by this missing well. So that's all on Moho Bilondo.</p>
          <p>On WEPEC [West Pacific Petrochemical Company], it's all about the refining margin which is effectively under the control of the Chinese currently, so it has nothing to do with operational performance, but it is only due to the regulations in China. And now that we see the oil price going down, I think &#x2013; I should expect at least that we will recover some flexibility into the last quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>The last question was about Libya.  Just to give you an Idea of what it was, we have fields operated by Repsol and those licenses are being renegotiated already. And we booked that in the third quarter. The overall impacts &#x2013; and these negotiations have been in effect since also January of this year. To give you a magnitude of that, the retroactive effect involving negotiation for our share is about -- net operating income of about 150 or &#x20AC;170 million. For our operated fields, negotiations are currently on but there will be less effect, less impact than for the Repsol those so-called Repsol fields, which were much larger than our fields.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick, could I just follow up?  Is my understanding incorrect that the Dalian refinery is strictly an export refinery?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[laughter] It has been initially.  The initial contract was that Dalian was an export refinery but also products are going well all &#x2013; at least 70% of the products are going on the local market. And one follow-up on Libya, implied with the retroactive effect of the new terms, we also enjoy the benefit of an extension of the licenses by 15 years for some blocks and five year for other blocks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. With respect to that 150 to &#x20AC;170 million impact, I assume that's a one-time negative in the third quarter results.  Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Kim Fustier from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, good afternoon gentlemen, just three questions. The first one is on Nigeria. Could you comment on Nigeria and what potential do you see for production returning in '09?  How confident are you in being able to make the FID in '09 on and LNG Train 7 and Brass given the increased emphasis from the Nigerian government on prioritizing domestic gas supply? Secondly, it feels like, over the years, you rely more and more on some of the tiebacks as Marshall Field to the North Sea.  And when taking FID on these sorts of projects, do you use the forward curve, or do the economics have to fly on your own internal assumptions?   And thirdly, you've talked in the past about your preference for dividends over share buyback.  Can you just clarify your share buyback policy?  It's obviously linked to disposals in some way; for example the Sanofi disposals, or more generally, to your overall cash position? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I will try to answer slower than you asked the questions, Kim.  On Nigeria, currently we -- the situation is extremely difficult as there are field security issues. I mentioned the one we had on OML 58 during the third quarter.  In our assumptions, we are not assuming recovery in Nigeria for 2009.</p>
          <p>Your question about FIDs of Brass and LNG Train 7, for LNG Train 7, what I now know is that the feed, the front-end engineering has been completed.  As far as the FID is concerned, honestly I don't know.  I'm sorry.  And I would make the same comment on Brass, where the feed also has been completed.  This is all that I know though.</p>
          <p>Your second question was about if we use a forward curve or if we use a flat price assumption of our own. We don't use forward curves to assess our projects. So, we have our own oil price and we use it.</p>
          <p>For the buyback, as we said, we have no policy on buybacks, I would say. We use cash available if in excess to buy back some shares and that's it. And currently, today we are not buying back any shares, but we will see what will be our cash position in two months' time, and then we'll adjust in terms of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mr. Colin Smith from Dresdner Kleinwort.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Patrick, a few things. One, you commented in the release about several non-strategic holdings and we can see as was mentioned earlier that pickup in</p>
          <p>Sanofi share sale. I was just curious as to whether there was anything else you had in mind that was non-strategic that you're holding up from sale. The second thing was just in your remarks you mentioned the loss of volume from Bruce, Alwyn, and OML 58 in the third quarter. I wonder if you could just give us a feel for how much volume you would expect see return in Q4 as a result of this issue being over.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do we have non-strategic assets in addition to the Sanofi shares? The answer is yes. Do we have in mind to sell these assets? I don't think there is anything significant that could be expected now.  But as I mentioned, there are assets we don't believe are strategic, and if there is opportunity to divest them, we will divest them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you maybe provide a little bit of color as to what you consider those to be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, Colin, you ask too much for me. The loss on Bruce &#x2013; the loss of volume -- obviously we faced technical problems in the third quarter on Bruce and Alwyn.  We lost something about 2 to 2.5% of production. Those problems are solved.  Those fields are back on stream today. On OML 58, we lost something like 1% last quarter and again OML 58 is back on stream today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have a number in barrels of oil equivalents for example that we could use for shorthand on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On OML 58, it is in the range of 20,000 barrels per day, I would say. And on Bruce and Alwyn, it is between 40 to 50,000 barrels per day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Ms. Dominique Patry of Cheuvreux. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, again a follow-up question on the shutdowns of the third quarter.  Given the fact that Alwyn is a high-margin field, could you maybe quantify the impact on the net operating results in upstream of the temporary shutdown of Alwyn during the quarter?  And then I have a second question.  You have mentioned the two oil prices under which you are going to base your 2009 CapEx, 60 and 80? I was just wondering with regard to the exploration spending, given the fact that you have quite sharply increased your exploration as you talked about in past years, do you see your 2009 exploration maybe under those two different scenarios? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on the shutdown on Bruce and Alwyn, we lost about 40 to 50,000 barrel per day.  As of now, what is the exact impact net operating income, it is something significant.  Return to the IR and they will give you the exact figure that I don't have; I am sorry. For the budget, I remind you that in '98 or '99 when the oil price was at $10 per barrel, we did not cut our program. And I remind you also -- what I said is that most of our programs for 2009 is obviously at 80% at least already committed.  That would be my answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I suppose that it's the same for exploration, for your exploration spending of 2009, it's mostly committed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is not only fund that is committed. I don't know what is the percentage of &#x2013; I am assuming that we may have more flexibility in our exploration for CapEx program.  But as of today, there is no intention for us to reduce our programs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mr. Jeffrey Tarrant from Cheuvreux. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. I just have a quick question.  You mentioned earlier in the conference call the potential impacts of lower prices on the production sharing contracts in Q4.  But could you clarify a bit this point please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Jeffrey. As you know our sensitivity, which was given when the oil price was around 80, the sensitivity is that for $1 per barrel, the volume effect is between 1,000 to 2,000 barrels per day. In addition, I would like to mention that we have some special effect, which will start in Q4, on Dalia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mr. Neill Morton from MF Global. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, just a couple of issues left, please. You related your $19 billion of CapEx for this year. There has been a strong move in the dollar recently.  Just so that we can better model that number in euros, could you remind us roughly what proportion of your annual CapEx is in currencies other than the US dollar?  And just secondly on the Sanofi, you have always been quite clear about your long-term commitment to sell down your stake, but Sanofi does have a new CEO starting I think at the end of December.  I understand that both TOTAL and L'Oreal were quite instrumental in his appointment, so I just wondered as a sign of support to him, would you perhaps envisage slowing the pace of your buybacks, or is it just business as usual? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For CapEx, roughly 70% of our CapEx are denominated in US dollars. The rest is denominated in sterling, Norwegian kroner, and euro basically.</p>
          <p>On Sanofi, keep in mind that we always make sales of shares without regard to the market.  We do take care of the Sanofi share itself. It is not for us &#x2013; we are not going to change our policy of divestment of our Sanofi shares because of the change of management in Sanofi. We made this policy to clear 1.5 years ago and this policy is still valid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a new question from Mr. Mark Gilman from the Benchmark Company.  Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick, in response to a prior question, you mentioned I believe a threshold impact on Dalia in the fourth quarter.  Could you give us a rough idea of the barrels per day impact of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>15,000, you got it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And in response to my prior question regarding Libya, is there a retroactive volume impact associated with the 150 to &#x20AC;170 million that you quoted, and is that an operating income or a net income figure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a net operating income figure I mentioned to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the volume impact?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is no volume effect by the way because when your book volume it's already done &#x2013; it is done. So, you cannot retroactively will change your production, technically speaking I mean.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no questions at the moment. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Thank you. We have no further questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much everyone and have a good for both into US and good afternoon for in Europe. Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for attending. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>