<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1287011" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call - London</title>
    <date>2010-02-11</date>
    <companies>
      <company>596</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Patrick De La Chevardi&#xE8;re, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Christophe De Margerie</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst">Irene Himona</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Colin Smith</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Iain Reid</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Theepan Jothilingam</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Jon Rigby</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">David Thomas</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Alejandro Demichelis</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Richard Griffith</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Neill Morton</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>So thank you, everyone, for coming. Christophe had trouble with his flight. His flight was diverted to Heathrow. So it will take him, let's say, half an hour more to be there. And I will make a short presentation, half an hour, basically, and Christophe hopefully will be there for the Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Maybe we'll go, start for slide number one. Basically, on this slide, we mentioned to you that we started this year five major projects. You will see that later on, on another slide.</p>
          <p>We added significant position in our North America portfolio. We progressively &#x2013; and believe us, we progressively transform our Downstream and Chemicals portfolio. And we have some sustainable development strategy going on; for instance, CO2 sequestration.</p>
          <p>Our adjusted net income was $10.9 billion, minus 47%, which is a quite good performance in comparison to our peers. The return on average capital employed is about 13%, which gives a return on equity of above 16%. We strongly believe that our financial strength and the cost reduction allow us to continue and develop our strategy.</p>
          <p>Despite new discoveries made in Brazil and new contracts signed in Iraq, we believe that by mid of the decade it will be difficult to continue and increase the production capacity of the world, which we see capped at something like 95 million barrel a day.</p>
          <p>You see on the left side of the slide that the demand is moving from OECDs countrying, where the demand is going down, down in the U.S., down in Europe and moving up in to the east &#x2013; Middle East and Asia.  This trend by which emerging markets are going up and strongly support the oil price by their demand.  The growth will come from Asia; China, of course, being one of the main countries where the growth of the demand will be seen.</p>
          <p>For gas, this is another picture. Currently we are facing some kind of gas bubble and it will take some years for this over-supply market to become more stable. We believe that LNG, thanks to its cost, I remind you that a project like, for instance, Yemen LNG or Qatargas 2 enjoy construction costs much lower than the one we are facing today.  So thanks to this construction costs made at that time, LNG projects have low breakeven. And that LNG is quite competitive, including in the U.S., against domestic gas and pipe gas. And we believe that LNG gas will push, displace some coal consumption and maybe some higher cost pipeline gas production.</p>
          <p>But being honest with you, this gas bubble will take another two, three years to be solved and this will &#x2013; we do not anticipate high gas price on spot markets in the U.S. or in Europe in the forthcoming years.</p>
          <p>So just one slide on the financial. We are definitely convinced that the strength of our balance sheet allows us to continue and maintain our investment program at about $18 billion a year, and the same for the dividend policy. The last two bars on the right show the balance of cash in 2009, so we spent gross investment in green at about $18.6 billion. The dividend expressed in dollar is about $7.6 billion. The cash flow from operation was above $17 billion. We divest assets, mainly Sanofi shares of $3.5 billion. But in aggregate we divest $4.3 billion, and then we increased our net debt by $4.7 billion, maintaining the gearing in the range of 25, 30% namely at 26.6% at year end.</p>
          <p>And this is the strength of this balance sheet, which give us confidence that we will continue both to invest in our development and in the growth of the company and to maintain the dividend policy.</p>
          <p>I remind you, prior we move to that slide, I remind you that, we still own 7% of Sanofi. This give us some financial flexibility, obviously. We are continuing to sell, and selling Sanofi shares. The portfolio was about &#x20AC;5 billion and we are divesting about &#x20AC;2.5 billion a year so there is about two years of cash coming from this divestment plus maybe a little bit more by 2012.</p>
          <p>So, moving to the Upstream. Actually we did a lot of small, medium size transaction, but in aggregate we added something like a billion barrel of 2P [proved and probable] reserve. I remind you further we have launched five big project. We will launch five new projects in 2010. We have decided the FID for Surmont Phase II in Canada. We've signed an agreement with Cobalt for exploration in the Gulf of Mexico. We recently signed an agreement with Chesapeake, which give us access to shale gas assets and which will, for our share, produce something about 30,000 barrels per day starting now.</p>
          <p>We've signed an agreement with Sonatrach for the Timimoun <mark type="inaudible" /> field. We signed a contract in Azerbaijan on Absheron. We've launched FID for all the project, and in aggregate, this is adding 1 billion barrel of oil equivalent in 2P reserve.</p>
          <p>We have more than 12 years of O&amp;P reserves and more than 20 years of 2P reserves and a resources base above 40 years. There will be obviously some growth in our production by 2010, and we will see that later on.</p>
          <p>This is a rather difficult slide to be described, but on the top left side on the production, of course, we are not very happy with the minus 2.6% decrease in our production this year. But minus 3% was due to OPEC and the effect on low gas demand, and then minus 1.5% was due to portfolio changes and security effect in Nigeria.</p>
          <p>The underlying growth, the growth coming from our own new project, was about 2% and what is important to note is what is mentioned at the bottom left side of the slide, is that when we increased our volume by 2% we increased the net income by 4% and basically our new production is accretive to our net income.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned to you &#x2013; this is the right side of the slide &#x2013; we are, we showed a very good resilience this year. Only BP is ahead of us, and our net income per barrel, about $10.7 per barrel, is quite close to Exxon, even if it's only a little bit higher than us, but it decreased less than Exxon, Shell and Chevron.</p>
          <p>Our replacement rate was 103%; this is including some acquisition. Organically the replacement rate excluding acquisition is at 93%. We have more than 12 years of 1P reserve. By region on the right side of this slide you see that Americas grew substantially. Africa remained stable and Asia is stable also. By type of assets, you can see a small line mentioning the Unconventional Gas, this is the Chesapeake transaction. LNG resource base is larger, much larger in 2009 than it was in 2004 and obviously there is a big change in heavy oil.</p>
          <p>Something you have to think and to remember is that, we increased and &#x2013; increase our portfolio in North America, basically willing to increase our share in OECD countries.</p>
          <p>This is the usual slide we shows because we are quite proud of it. Total has the lowest technical cost of the industry at $15.4 per barrel. We don't know what will be the technical costs of our competitors for 2009 but we have continued to be still the best one. Among this $15.4 per barrel is OpEx 5.8, which is down by $0.5 per barrel, 8.2 for DD&amp;A, up by $0.7 per barrel and 1.4 for exploration.</p>
          <p>We tried to understood where the other are reducing their cost and we try to establish cost reduction and the operating expenses reduction on assets where we are co-venturer and not operator and compare it to assets where we are the operator. When we are the operator, we establish that our operating expenses went down by 13%.  Where on assets we are not the operator, we only can find minus 3%. So I don't know where the others are reducing their costs, but not in the field where we are partners.</p>
          <p>We actually reduced our overall costs by $2.2 billion and obviously ForEx has a great impact on it. It's about 60% coming from ForEx among this $2.2 billion.</p>
          <p>So we are launching five major project in 2010. Surmont Phase 2 is already decided; FID was taken in January 2010. CLOV, which is the fourth pole of development in Angola, Block 17. Laggan/Tormore in the North Sea and then Ofon II and Egina in Nigeria. The Upstream CapEx will be next year slightly above $14 billion including some CapEx for gas and power branch. This $14 billion is excluding Chesapeake, so if you add Chesapeake, Chesapeake we already paid $800 million, so Chesapeake will cost more than $1 billion this year.</p>
          <p>Last year, as a reminder, we were, last year in 2009, we were at $13.2 billion.  You see on the right side of the slide that CapEx per barrel on Surmont Phase 2 went down by 25%, which allows us to decide the FID.  Basically, this is the cost reduction effect, which help us to decide to run the project. And you see same type of effect for CLOV, which has not yet launched, the FID.  We see subsea equipment down by 15%, the FPSO cost down also by 15% and some risers and flexible asset CapEx down by 20%.</p>
          <p>We are maintaining the investment to sustain the growth.  The CapEx budget is at $14 billion excluding acquisition, as I mentioned to you.</p>
          <p>Something which is worth mentioning also, is the number of projects, which will start up during the period 2010, 2014.  The Chesapeake is starting producing for us now, the Barnett shale joint venture at about 30,000 barrel per day. Pazflor will start by beginning 2011, then you have Usan, Bongkot in Thailand, Angola LNG, Halfaya in Iraq, Kashagan Phase 1, OML 58 in Nigeria, Ofon II, CLOV, Laggan/Tormore and Tempa Rossa. All those projects in aggregate will contribute by 2014 at about 800,000 barrel per day.</p>
          <p>Something important is that we have been able to sign new partnership, namely the Barnett Shale JV with Chesapeake; Ahnet in Algeria which with Sonatrach, where we own 47%. The Termokarstovoye project I mentioned to you, with Novatek, and the Halfaya project in Iraq. It is our view that we have been not selected for the <mark type="inaudible" /> field which was one of our target, but if we didn't do it, it is because of the condition at which our competitors agrees to do it, does not allow us to make enough profit taking such a risk.</p>
          <p>So we have and we'll continue to demonstrate our ability to establish relationship to access to new resources. We are building new position for the long term; obviously the Deep Offshore is one of our strengths and you  have it on the left side with new project coming, like Egina or Block 32 in Angola, Egina being in Nigeria. For the Heavy Oil we are learning quite quickly thanks to our cooperation with ConocoPhillips in Surmont. We are the operator on the Joslyn mine with an ownership of 75% and I remind you something that you have maybe forgotten is Bemolonga assets we own in Madagascar which is Heavy Oil also, obviously for the long term, but this will add value to our portfolio.</p>
          <p>The Unconventional Gas, we started our corporation with Chesapeake. We also signed the Ahnet gas transaction with 47 percentage of ownership in Algeria and we applied for new permit for Unconventional Gas in Europe and in Argentina. Obviously you  know that LNG is one of our strengths, we started two projects this year; we will continue, we have other project in our pocket, namely Ichthys in Australia and Shtokman in Russia.</p>
          <p>All those new position represent about 50% of our total resource base, about 10% for the Deep Offshore, about 20% for the Heavy Oil, about 10% for the Unconventional Gas and about 10% for the LNG.</p>
          <p>So this year we started two big project, Qatargas 2 and thereafter the first train of LNG in Yemen. You know that there will be a second train to be launched by first of this year in Yemen LNG. The breakeven price of Yemen LNG, just to give you a flavor is about $2.5 per MBTU after regas in the U.S. So this gas is extremely competitive everywhere.</p>
          <p>On Qatargas 2, the liquid component of the gas is so rich that we are still making money on this project even if we give the LNG to the buyer; we'll not give it, but the breakeven is extremely low thanks to the liquids component we are selling on the market.</p>
          <p>We have a last thought for you of LNG assets. Our phase increased by 60%. And we are basically number two behind &#x2013; I don't care so much to be number two, but both project will contribute substantially to the net income of the group next year, and they start already, but there will be a plateau next year.</p>
          <p>In the meantime we are still willing to propose a complementary development in low CO2 energies. This is basically Solar, where we own two medium, small size company, one being Photovoltec, making Solar cell, and Tenesol making Solar panel. We have a project of Solar farm in Abu Dhabi and that way we will continue our R&amp;D effort in that sense.</p>
          <p>Biomass also we have a large R&amp;D project. We &#x2013; the share of Total &#x2013; sorry the overall amount of this research is about &#x20AC;110 million, our share in this program is about 25%. And on nuclear, despite the disappointment we had in Abu Dhabi we are acquiring some expertise with our 8% interest in the Penly project in France and we are still thinking that we will continue and try to increase our exposure to the nuclear industry.</p>
          <p>The Downstream, obviously if you remember where, the first quarter of 2009 was a good quarter. The refining margin were good at that time and then the market collapsed and by last quarter 2009, the margin was as low as 10 to $12 per ton.</p>
          <p>There is obviously a large overcapacity in the world and in Europe, where we are. We believe that additional closure are needed in the OECD countries. On the opposite, we strongly believe that our Jubail refinery project in Saudi Arabia will be extremely profitable, because it will be dedicated to the growing market.</p>
          <p>Currently, the overcapacity is too big. This overcapacity has to be reduced and we will try and reduce our exposure to this market. This is why &#x2013; sorry, I don't know where is my slide &#x2013; this is why we will continue and restructure our Refining and Downstream business. Our commitment to the financial community is to reduce our capacity by 500,000 barrel a day. This is about 20% of our current capacity.</p>
          <p>We will do it.  We cannot be too loud about that and basically just be confident that we will do it. I remind you that in 2007 we already sold the Milford Haven refinery. We already announced reduction in our Normandy capacity, Normandy refinery, the capacity was down by 80,000 barrel per day. We have signed a new JV in Italy with Erg, and this will be also for us to match this objective.</p>
          <p>So this is a slide on marketing; marketing is very important. You know that basically the Refining was losing about another million euro a month, the second half of 2009.</p>
          <p>Now the margin are a little bit better because it is cold weather. But this year, thanks to the marketing that we balance our net income of the Downstream business. You see that the return on capital employed in marketing is quite good, something above 20%. And we need this marketing; we are proud of it. We are not willing to reduce our exposure like this just to avoid this business. I remind you that we are number one in Africa.  And we will maintains this exposure in Africa. We are obviously number one in France. The market condition are correct and the same, namely in Germany and in Spain and in Italy; might be not exactly the same in the U.K. where the market is difficult.</p>
          <p>Maybe you can come to previous one. Just a reminder, that the Petrochemical sector was extremely difficult in 2009, despite the Chinese demand growth.  The margin were extremely low; basically if you compare this year in Europe the margin was about &#x20AC;350 per ton, where in the past it was in the range of 400 to &#x20AC;500 per ton. The competition in the OECD countries were extremely strong and the growth was coming from Asia. We enjoyed this growth in our joint venture in Korea and with our assets in Qatar.</p>
          <p>So next one. So the market is difficult. We started five years ago a restructuring program for our Petrochemical sector. We completed &#x2013; in 2009 we completed the plan launched in 2006 in Europe. We will concentrate our assets on three world-class platform, namely the one in the Gulf of Mexico, the one in Belgium, and Normandy in France. We &#x2013; without saying it, we reduced our workforce by 20% for the period 2006-2012.</p>
          <p>Maybe we can say a word on the Specialties because this is thanks to the Specialties that the Chemicals sector of TOTAL was making some positive results. Those specialties made and put in place very heavy restructuring and have been able to maintain a return on capital employed close to 10% in average, which is a great achievement. The average EBITDA of those assets, namely ATOTECH, Bostik, Cray Valley and Hutchison is above $1 billion a year for the period 2007-2009.</p>
          <p>It's worth saying it, but sustainable development is part of our project. For those who were with us in the field trip in Yemen, you may remember how efficient was our team in helping the local communities along the pipeline and around the project itself. We &#x2013; on top of that we transplanted coral reef for the terminal. This is something which has never been done in the past and 95% of all coral reef were surviving after a year.</p>
          <p>Pazflor, Angola is a great experience to be able to work with the local communities The CCS pilot in Lacq is one of the few projects which we showed the efficiency of the sequestration of CO2. And our project in Abu Dhabi shows how much dedicated we are to offer other producing &#x2013; produced energy than oil and petrol.</p>
          <p>We are giving you there the figures for 2009 and 2010 of our CapEx. The 2010 figure of $18 billion is excluding acquisition because we did not know them at that time. So this one is excluding Chesapeake. Upstream is about $14 billion, Downstream is about $3 billion and Chemical about $1 billion. This is the same level than in 2009. It will be a year including acquisition, obviously. We have several project which are described on the right side of the slide, the biggest one being Kashagan where we will dedicate more than $1.5 billion this year. Pazflor, we will dedicate about $1 billion, Ekofisk about $800 million also. So this gives you the magnitude and the size of the several project which are going on in the Company now. And those costs shows us that we need to maintain our discipline and our expertise to develop big project  if we want to be one of the leader of the industry.</p>
          <p>You see on the left side the gearing, which is moving anywhere. Currently the gearing is at 26.6%. It has been in the past as high as 35% and as low as 15% in 2008. We show you the sensitivity $1 per barrel give cash flows of about $180 million a year; $1 per ton give us $70 million a year; and $0.1 per euro give us a sensitivity of $360 million. We are quite happy to see the dollar strengthening currently, moving below the 1.40.</p>
          <p>We maintain a proposed dividend at &#x20AC;2.28 per share, this is plus 9% in dollar, which compares us favorably to our peers and we will continue the investment program as I mentioned to you at $18 billion a year, excluding acquisition, and we already have done one acquisition, being Chesapeake.</p>
          <p>And this is the last slide, and I am sorry, but Christophe will be there soon, hopefully. We are quite good in giving social content to our investments and this is definitely a part of our strategy and we strongly believe that we need it to be successful. We show you how able we are to establish and form partnership in Nigeria, in the U.S., in Russia, in order to give access for us to new reserves, new resources.</p>
          <p>I think what is important to give access to new resources is to be recognized as a good operator and a good project manager and I think that's the case today for us.</p>
          <p>We still maintain the objective to be an integrated company despite the fact that we want to reduce our exposure to Downstream, as it was mentioned to you, but we still believe it is important that we maintain both Downstream, Chemical and Upstream business in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>The objective is obviously to improve the return on capital employed in Downstream and Chemical and we are working on for that.</p>
          <p>And I think we can move to question, now. Can I have a glass of water, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's okay, I have got one. Sorry.  Good to see you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You, too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Irene.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have two questions, please. First, in the fourth quarter, in the Downstream depreciation you had a special charge, 285 million. Can you say if any of that was an asset impairment, please?</p>
          <p>And my second question, on cost reductions, I think excluding FX you achieved your original target last year. Is there an explicit plan for 2010 for the internal cost reduction then? In terms of external supplies and cost environment, with oil at 70 and pretty stable are you still looking for cost reductions externally? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On cost reduction, I mentioned to you a cost reduction of $2.2 billion last year.  We see unfortunately a trend where cost has a tendency to go up again, so unfortunately we are not expecting a big cost reduction in 2010, to be frank with you. We are still maintain our program on cost reduction, but we have to face a market where some cost are starting to go up again, this is as the market is today.</p>
          <p>On the impairment, yes, there was an impairment on Refining assets in Europe, basically prior tax, it was about &#x20AC;350 million, pre-tax.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Colin Smith from ICAP. Just on the Downstream reduction there is &#x2013; just doing the maths, so it looks like you've got another 350,000 barrels a day of capacity that you need to close from here in the timeframe that you have given us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You compute well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think you mentioned that some of that might come from Total <mark type="inaudible" />, on the terms of the deal. Before that deal you had about 60-odd thousand barrels a day net and I think after it you have about 55,000 barrels a day net. That's maybe one thing to be thinking about. But beyond that, there is still quite a lot to go even if the Rome refinery is at risk. I know you won't comment directly on that. Is it your intention to sell to or to shut down that capacity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you know I can't talk too much because we have signed some confidentiality agreement with potential buyers, and we have received some interest from some buyers, not 10 of them, but some buyers, for some assets we have and obviously I won't tell you which refinery are involved in this process. We are making it not noisy, we make it smoothly and we will make and work out to try and achieve it. Of course, it is better for us to be able to sell than to close and this is currently the objective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I had a second question as well, and that was in previous presentations you've shown plans to be involved in a cracker in Algeria and that seems to be off the slides now.  Can you just confirm that that's not part of your future investment plans anymore?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This project is going down and up, like this. It's currently up. Based on discussion at the top level in Algeria, give a new start to this project, hopefully we will do it. The timeframe is quite short now to decide or not to launch this project and this will be done this year in one sense or the other, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Iain Reid from Macquarie. Can I ask couple of questions about the Iraq volumes, can you describe the mechanism which you're going to use to book the reserves and production and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll answer your question first then you ask the second question, if you don't mind, so that I don't forget the first one. Actually due to the framework, the legal framework of those contract, you only book volumes related to the margin you bid for. So this is definitely limited volumes that you book actually, because you only book the 1.50 or 1.60 or $1.70 per barrel that you enjoy with your margin. So even if your project is producing 800,000 barrel a day, and shows two, three, 4 billion barrel of technical reserves, your booking is extremely limited.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. My second question was going to be about the net income impact. So do we assume pre-tax is going to make the 1.6, $1.7 on this limited volume?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I mentioned to you we have not been awarded the <mark type="inaudible" /> field. This is due to the fact that there is a current condition offered. You can hardly make big money on this project. And that, we decided that it was important to have an exposure in Iraq to be there, because we believe that things are going to move and to change. But it was not our objective keep to get a large exposure where project &#x2013; the return on capital employed was &#x2013; maybe reasonable. But taking into account big risk you are taking, the reward/risk balance was not so favorable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Patrick, Theepan from Morgan Stanley. Just a couple of questions, firstly on Chemicals and then the dividend. Can you just clarify, I think you that 20% reduction in head count by 2012, could you just give us a flavor of how much of that has been done? And then I mean, you've announced today a disposal. I was wondering how much more aggressive could you be in the Chemicals business and so where do you see capital employed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We disposed Mapa-Spontex, which is gloves and sponges, which is definitely not our core business. So we received an offer for $500 million for this asset and we are positive on our ability to close this transaction prior, let's say mid second quarter this year. We ran our Specialties business in such a way that both companies are independent. They are making good profit and they are extremely currently useful to balance the net income of our Petrochemical sector, which is negative this year, close to zero this year. So even if they are important, they are managed independently. I'm not saying they are on sale, but if we need it, why not. But they are not on sale today.</p>
          <p>We can also divest some over, let's say, small assets if needed in the E&amp;P sector. This is not in the framework of what we have in mind today, but let's take the situation where we have an opportunity to make an acquisition, I think we can divest it. We have already identified some assets we can divest, if necessary, to maintain the strength of the balance sheet, so to both make the acquisition and then divest on other more mature assets.</p>
          <p>The 20,000 number reduction you mentioned is done without saying it, basically, because we can't say it. So we do it on a regular basis. This is a process by which we increase our profitability by trying to reduce our cost step-by-step without making big announcements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just the question on the dividend, you've left that unchanged. I was just wondering, could you talk a little bit about the framework on the dividend? Did you consider an increase, you haven't done that because you're taking a more pessimistic view on the macro environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a big uncertainty today on the oil price. You have two force opposite. On one side you have the financial pushing the price up. Then you have the physical market, which is oversupplied, pushing the price down. So there is some uncertainty of what would be the oil price. We believe that it will be in the range of 60 to 100. So it's a large range, but I can't give you more precise figures. But there is some uncertainty in that range.</p>
          <p>Maintaining our dividend in euro, to comment on that, for this year this gives a payout of 66%. And this is plus 9% if you compute it in dollars. And this compares favorably to our competitors. It would not have been reasonable in my view to increase the dividend this year.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, I'd like to mention to you that we still own 7% of Sanofi, which give us &#x20AC;2.5 billion a year of financial flexibility. So for the forthcoming two years, maybe two years and a half as the share price of Sanofi went up, we have sufficient resources of cash to both continue and maintain our CapEx program and to maintain the dividend policy. I remind you that dividend policy is namely in a stable environment, which never happens, but that's the objective, in a stable environment, to have a payout ratio of about, around 50%. So when the oil price and the refining margin are low we increase the payout, namely 66% this year. And if the oil price goes up again, above 100, we may reduce the payout ratio down to 40% for instance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick, hi.  Jon Rigby from UBS. Can I ask a question on the Downstream, then come back to the comments you just made about the dividend and Sanofi.  On the Downstream, I was reading on the wires this morning and it seemed to capture the paradox completely, was that Christophe on one hand said, Europe and the OECD had to shut refining capacity to get the refining sector back into balance. You're the largest refiner in Europe, yet your chosen route is to sell. So how are you curing the problem? If you don't exit completely, all you do is give someone a lower cost base to operate against you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Something what was not said but, this morning, but it was said in the past, is that the Dunkirk refinery will not anymore refine crude oil. You can understand it, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay. Second question on the Downstream, then I'll move on to the finance -.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They like the downstream now <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to clarify, I mean, you highlighted the marketing earnings that you make. Any exit from refining capacity, is that going to compromise in any way the marketing business that you have, just simply because the contract nature of supplier to competitors or the links between your marketing and refining business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Something which I was not aware, let's say, two years ago, is that there are people able to be a marketer without being refiners. And we had example of buyers, one I can't remember the name of this company from Israel, buying marketing assets in Europe. And they do &#x2013; their job is to market, not to refine. So there is a way to continue and maintain marketing asset even if you don't have a refinery, mind you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you think the marketing earnings can stay intact post the reduction in refining capacity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It might that a buyer is willing to buy the marketing with a refining asset also to be integrated and then we are open-minded in that respect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just going back to the Sanofi stake and dividend, et cetera. Would you envisage that your exit gearing in 2011 or 2012, whenever it is you've sold down Sanofi, will be lower than the 25 to 30% target you currently have. Especially, given the fact that your Downstream footprint will have also reduced by that stage as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I need to refer to our so-called long-term plan to give you some data. If we use the $70 per barrel about in scenario, without anymore Sanofi shares by 2012, the gear is still maintained is at 25, 30% range after 2012, 2013, according the CapEx program we have at that date, which include some provision for acquisition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. It's Dave Thomas of Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Where are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am over here, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Returning back to Irene's question on the cost side, could you just differentiate a bit between OpEx and CapEx where you are seeing cost trends? Because if it is on the CapEx side, I'd suggest it should incentivize you to be moving forward with project sanctions faster.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I can't give you general figures for all of our CapEx, but I gave you the example of the Surmont project where we reduced the CapEx by 25%, which allows us to launch a project. So there are area in the world where we have been able &#x2013; another example is the Jubail refinery, where we drastically reduced the CapEx as it was initially quoted by the contractors and the magnitude of the reduction, cost reduction in the CapEx was about 20 to 25%, but as I mentioned too, Iran also we see some trend today where the cost are slightly but are moving up today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that in any way because of things like commodity prices or is actually contracted prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Honestly I don't know. There is an obvious link between the commodity price and the contractor quotation, it is obvious. Our work elasticity between those two, a parameter I don't know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I move on to a question then on technical costs? I think you said that DD&amp;A in your technical costs was around $8.20 or so per barrel, could you give us an indication of how you expect that to go moving forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It will go up obviously because new projects are going onstream with higher CapEx than in the past so that will continue to go up. It goes up to this year at about $0.8 per barrel I think and it will continue to go up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much and finally a question on return on capital employed. If we stripped out your non-productive capital could you say what your ROIC actually would have been in 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you repeat the question because I was diverted  by Christophe who making some noise in the room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just &#x2013; the question was if you strip out non-productive capital from your capital employed base, what would the capital -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the top of my mind, it will be, I'd say something like 20%, because basically one-third of our capital employed is non-productive. Please come to answer some question, Christophe. They are waiting for us &#x2013; for I was &#x2013; for once, I've been there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Alejandro Demichelis from Bank of America/Merrill Lynch. Just one question. You described the gas market as a bubble and we're not going to see spot prices recovering anytime soon. But when you look at your new projects coming into investment, most of,  50% of those, are basically gas projects going to spot markets. So is it that you taking a complete different view on the commodity prices there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you repeat the question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The question was that you described the gas market as a bubble over the next few years. But if we look at your projects coming to FID and some of the partnerships that you signed, most of, half of those, are basically gas projects. So is that you're taking a completely different view in terms of the dynamics of the market medium-term there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. First, sorry for what happened and it's all the fault of Bertrand. And it's not French technology because the plane we had is a Learjet, and it's not French. I don't know what it is, by the way, but it doesn't work.</p>
          <p>On &#x2013; it has been all the debate recently on our projects. And especially the price, you probably heard about Shtokman, which is a good example that some people use, the fact that we were scared or worried about the price, and that was the reason why we were delaying the startup of the project. I mean, no, the reason is we have to go through more detailed engineering before we can launch a very complex project and make sure that it will be well-defined, it will be well-developed and then producing even better.</p>
          <p>Now we are today in 2010, but we talk about Shtokman and Total FID 2011, which means the project started producing in 2016/2017. The bubble, the one we know today at least, will be over. So I mean, it's the right time to decide those projects and not the time where the price are high. It's an old subject we had on oil and gas. I mean, when do you start? Frankly to tell you the truth we have to do it whenever it comes.</p>
          <p>If you have a view, especially for project with 20, 25 years plateau, with two, three &#x2013; one, two, three phases like Shtokman, which means probably more than 40 years, don't think that you have to decide on the date depending on the price of gas. Either you believe the price of gas will be higher and you go through, or you forget it. But I mean, never think that you will have to make your decision based on the price of gas. I mean, the reason our delays because of cost, because of non-approval, because of environment, because of whatever, political, geo-political, but not because of price of gas. So today it's very important and especially for those years that we are now, I would say pushing ourselves to develop those projects and the price of gas, I don't know what it will be in 2017, but whatever, it's a project which will be profitable if we launched it at prices which are our long-term view and that's sometimes a reason of why people are thinking about the price, because they are told that, oh they are delaying because of the gas price. Honestly, it's usually face saving.</p>
          <p>So on the long term, just do and develop your project as quickly as you can, if you're not being hurt, especially if what you see today is more and more project being delayed, more and more project in Africa being maybe suspended, maybe just totally stopped. Remember about OK &#x2013; it's dead. Brass we still hope it's alive but I am not even sure and at the end of the day, I still believe that we will be short of LNG in the years to come.</p>
          <p>Now there is the big concern in the good science  about shale gas and those nonconventional reserves, but I don't know what it is, we don't what it is and if you talk about the United States, in any case, until there is an LNG plant in the United States, which will be developed by, maybe the same person who said that there will be gas for more than 100 years from shale gas, no name, it will stay there.</p>
          <p>And for the time being in Europe and Asia where we're looking for shale gas, which is certainly there, because there is shale gas everywhere, but is it profitable, is it doable for environmental reasons?  I mean all of this still needs to be discussed and developed and in many case would not come as a sudden additional capacity of gas. So in the states, question mark. Rest of the world, definitely more than a question mark, so as far as you can, as quickly as you can develop your gas projects, especially in the UK when you get some tax incentives.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This was not the question, but it's my answer &#x2013; on taxes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Talking about Shtokman you had said, previously that you were going to be able to book the reserve. Now that we have new SEC guidelines, could you talk a little bit more about that, are you actually going to book them as reserves 100%  or are they going to go to somewhere else? I mean how are you going to book them and can you book them?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't see what in the new SEC guidelines could change our position. I would say the opposite, the new SEC guidelines are not, I would say, softer. They are just more pragmatic and the contract we have with Gazprom is very, I mean classical copy of what could be production sharing contract. So we definitely can book our reserves on Shtokman when the FID will be taken, which remains the way we are doing it, i.e., no FID, no booking. And today the FID is not taken. Otherwise, I mean no reasons not to take our share of the gas which is the share of gas which belongs indirectly to Total, just like through any production sharing contract.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so even though you don't have ownership of the reserves it doesn't affect...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I mean, production sharing, you don't have the ownership of reserves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I &#x2013; my answer is not to say we shouldn't book the rest of our reserves, so just, I have to take care of this, but it's an old subject. What is important in booking reserves is just to make sure that you have an impact what you're doing and your reserves are depending on the price of what it is, gas or oil. That's exactly the case in Shtokman and we have Gazprom in front of us, the same way we could have the state of Qatar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Richard Griffith from Evolution. I just want to come back to the issue of CapEx and the service costs, because if I looked at your presentation correctly, and I apologize if I missed this, you've got CapEx guidance for one year 2010. And I look at your slate of diversified portfolio of major projects, and an awful lot of the very big projects are basically parked in FEED of pre-study.</p>
          <p>You talk about service costs going up. One of your major competitors back in the autumn was talking about wanting to book capacity in the service sector ahead of what they thought would be a lot of FIDs later this year. So I mean where do you see your CapEx going in '11, '12, '13, if &#x2013; I mean would you really, coming back to David's question, are you going to push harder on the FID to make sure you have all that capacity because otherwise a lot of your big projects might be walking into a lot of inflation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good point. And again, I wish we could say that our vision on our own projects will be decisive on the cost of whatever it is, I mean the cost of developing projects like the one we have in our portfolio. We had this debate in this room last time on what do we think about the capabilities of companies to reduce their cost through pushing the service companies in reducing their cost. And I was challenged by people telling me, don't you think it's the right time to just don't take the risk of waiting, and if you think it's doable, do it.</p>
          <p>And I deeply see that's where we are. I.e., when you look at the CERA figures, you see already that they have been stopping the decline, taking any individual items and they restart growing, talking about inflation. And effectively when you see the list of projects, not only Total but others, this definitely going to put pressure on those service companies and they are not more than what they were two years ago. So definitely there will be a real risk of additional inflation of our projects. So what can I say on this? Do you believe that one company like Total can, in stopping its own projects, being, doing something which will have an impact on inflation? Maybe yes, but just for the benefit of others.</p>
          <p>So just like for when you discover oil, produce it, when you have a good project, even if it will be part of a risk to increase inflation, do it. If you think that when it's decided, you go to FID, you have all the contracts signed and you can keep those contracts under control, being sure that it is economical, do it and don't wait. Otherwise, the risk is the others will take the opportunity and will not wait for you. So except if you think that it's possible to have a big, real good OPEC meeting with Big Oil to decide when to launch the project, to do it, the best way to control the cost, which is first undoable and illegal, forget it.</p>
          <p>Now, I said this this morning, it's not a reason not to be better than what we have been doing in the past and letting the cost, I would say, scaling up, reaching the whatever. And I say we run around the crisis, I think that our partners, because I've changed my words also, talking about contractors. They are our partners and they understand this, and frankly I can tell you I have been having discussions with both of the big ones and we have decided to change "the rules."</p>
          <p>This means yes, everybody has to take its share of the cake. But what happened between 2006 and 2008 has been extremely dangerous, and it was definitely linked with the price of oil skying up to 147. But otherwise, it would have been dreadful and killing for all of us. So I think things have changed. I think that those companies have understood that they have also to be careful about the way they control their costs, about the way they control their subcontractors.</p>
          <p>And maybe I am a little bit too optimistic but I don't think so, we are not going to revive the same huge inflation we've seen in 2006. For the same reason, I don't see either the price of oil going quickly to 147. Now, if we can and when we can develop a start-up project, don't wait.  If it's doable, launch it and don't wait for BP, Shell or some now newcomers to take your role and develop their own projects, but at a definitely normal reduction in cost in the sense of market price, at least for high-tech projects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Neill Morton, MF Global. I just wanted to clarify, a couple of the slides in the presentation show longer term production levels that are suitably vague, which I guess is appropriate given the current uncertain environment. But do those numbers or those bars include, firstly, Iraq and secondly, include the Chesapeake joint venture? And the second question is that in the last couple of presentations, Bolivia has disappeared. There used to be a project called Itau which I believe is starting up middle of this year, what's happened to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Itau?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Bolivia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Bolivia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bolivia is &#x2013; you want to know about Itau?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well it disappeared from your list of projects. Is it something too small that it's not material or ....?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I mean, it's not a big one as such. What is important is our strategy on Bolivia. Itau is the first discovery we've made in Bolivia. That was in the year, early 2000. And we were extremely proud of the discovery, the problem has been how to work with our neighbors, San Alberto and Petrobras and at that time Repsol and then you know what happened with the change of regime to say the least and the renegotiations which took place.</p>
          <p>Itau now, in our portfolio is a way to join our efforts with <mark type="inaudible" /> to make a common development and doing it in a way where we can sell the gas through the Bolivia Brazil pipeline. Now what is more important is our strategy of Bolivia and especially the new discovery we've made and the one we want to develop to sell gas to Argentina. So the message for Itau is we do believe now even if it's difficult to say that Bolivia is the most, I would say, attractive country for its contractual terms. But the one we have negotiated and especially if they wish now to get the benefit of the gas and to sell it to Argentina, is becoming a pressure on us, which means good news, because we can now negotiate terms to make it profitable.</p>
          <p>In fact what is important is to develop Ipati, and not only Itau, which is another discovery we have made with an Argentinean company, and the idea is to sell gas to Argentina in the years 2015 plus. So Itau is just the first sign of, yes, we can invest in Bolivia with acceptable terms, but this one is still a small project compared to what we can do with huge reserve.</p>
          <p>Bolivia is &#x2013; country with huge reserve of gas and you have, next door, Argentina, so it's a big change with what I was telling you ten years ago, which was it's all for Brazil with the new discoveries in Brazil, it's definitely becoming Argentina the new market.</p>
          <p>There are already some sales, like 5 million cubic meters of gas, which is very little, but the capacity in Argentina is immense, but consider the price &#x2013; price of gas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And your production assumptions, do they include Iraq and Chesapeake?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Again I said that, first Iraq, it's a question mark on when and how. I don't know what Patrick said about this, but we do appreciate the opening of Iraq, but we definitely don't consider that the target of having all those project be developed at the same time, all starting middle of 2010, all being at the plateau in 2016, is doable. I hope that if there is only one, is Halfaya, with CNPC, Total and Petronas. But at the same time, we didn't take neither Chesapeake nor this in our targets.</p>
          <p>Chesapeake today is 31,000 barrels per day and plateau, with the view we have, and I am sure that we can do better in the future, is reaching something which is close to 60,000 barrels in a few years time for our share.</p>
          <p>There's more questions when it's Patrick answering, yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, monsieur, because you were late.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not late.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll put you out of your misery, Christophe. I've got another question.  Nigeria, I noticed that two of your projects for FID this year are in Nigeria. A number of the partners or other companies that do operate in Nigeria have been saying quite bearish things about the ability to get projects off the design board and get them under way with the uncertainties over the petroleum law, security, et cetera, et cetera. How comfortable are you that those two projects will actually get away this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We honestly are more comfortable with one than with the other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Which one's that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The deeper water one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Egina.  We have Egina and Ofon II. Why? First I mean Egina is deeper, to the deep offshore. So I would say physically it's safer in terms of security. But the other reason, it's typical production sharing contract or PSA, it's a mix of PSE and PSA and it's not part of the contracts which are to be reconsidered into the new law even if they are still questions about that, what could be the new terms of PSEs, but for the time being it's probably seen, there is no more discussions on terms and much more discussions on who is going to be leading the country which is probably the first priority.</p>
          <p>So Egina, I would consider this in terms of security and in terms of contractual terms, the classical one we always are faced to potential reopening of terms in production sharing contracts.</p>
          <p>Ofon II it's a little bit different, because it's part of our &#x2013; what I call the traditional core business of Total Elf in Nigeria. And we have been negotiating what was needed to cover the share of the state. Now there can still be outstanding problems we don't know. But for the time being it's all approved and as you remember the question was much more the cost of the project and are we capable to get, I would say, from contractors, should we go back to one of the previous questions. Price for the project which are acceptable to be decided as a project ready to launch. Those two projects are not in my opinion, in our opinion part of the concern that we also have with our partner, E&amp;I and Shell in, and as a joint venture.</p>
          <p>So we don't consider Nigeria as a place where you have to stop your activities. It's certainly a concern for what we call the traditional joint ventures, but at the same times that's where it is and we have to continue to produce our share of oil and we need the gas for the liquefaction product.</p>
          <p>So I think again that what you hear about sometimes about Shell is probably a little bit outspoken not by Shell, by the system.  We are partners and they cannot sell without our approval. And as far as I know, and I know they respect their agreements and their contracts with their partners. There is no such big sales in front of us.</p>
          <p>But that's what I'm reading in the press, but I'm not aware except the small sales, which took place and which definitely were, I would say, nice to be done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Christophe, Dave Thomas again at Citigroup, just a quick question. Can you say what your position is with respect to Venezuela heavy oil. I don't think you're participating in the moment although there's no news around that in Carabobo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It took me a long time to remember the name Carabobo. I don't know how much time it will take to forget it. Probably heard that the result took place just today, I received the message through mail in the car.  Patrick, instead of talking to your neighbor, that was the reason why I was late. I was just taking the time to answer to those important questions. I'm saying this because Carabobo, you probably know that we decided not to make a real offer with our partner PetroChina, on the Block 3, we decided that the terms were not, I would say aligned with our concept of what is doable. So we decided to say that we were interested and we will still be interested. But we have to revisit terms and the data we have to make something which is more, I would say in accordance with the bid. I've heard that two groups have been doing bids unsuccessfully. So if you don't know the results, on the first one, it's Repsol and if I'm understanding well, Repsol, Petronas and three Indian companies. And the second one is Chevron and Impex and I don't know who. Good for them if this thing is doable.</p>
          <p>On the first one, the bonus is $1 billion plus $1.5 billion carrying and the second one is $500 million and $1 billion carry, and we don't consider today that those term are aligned with our criteria for developing our skills in a good professional manner. Again, it's not giving lessons. We just see what people are doing, but definitely we are not in agreement with this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You have emphasized that if you have a good project you should go ahead and do it, regardless of what's happening in the spot market. But if we have a depressed gas market for about three years, are there any projects that you would consider delaying for a couple of months? And secondly, can you talk a little bit about your Solar project in Abu Dhabi?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I love you because you always are having two questions which are totally opposite. On the first one, if it's three years you have the answer. We cannot develop a field in three years time. So if I have to decide now, you tell me the bubble is for three years, which is maybe good news, maybe not. Definitely it takes, like in Shtokman, five or six years, so we will be beyond this period. So I will say for not one single project three years is a concern. Concern will be if the bubble lasts more than three years. And that becomes a real subject. Now, three years, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>More than three?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Four? Still no problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Five?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Five, we get close to the problem of &#x2013; but I mean frankly, five years with the assumptions we have, with the return of the economy to growth &#x2013; and I say again I leave the States apart for one simple reason. It's a very important one, subject, but I mean no capacity for re-exporting gas, so it's a market by itself.</p>
          <p>On the rest of the world, I still deeply believe &#x2013; we do deeply believe that there is more than a chance that this bubble will just disappear smoothly and slowly. But as far as we are cautious persons, for the development of Laggan/Tormore, I put pressure on my own teams, including  <mark type="inaudible" />. I like to talk to him and about him, which, each time we come he was pushing to say, no, we can't go. No, this project is going to be developed much quicker than five, six years or seven years' time, it's nothing to do with Shtokman and it's true that if we are maybe wrong on the timing of the end of the bubble, there is no reason why we should take additional risk. It's why we insisted we'd go to see British Government to get some &#x2013; not incentive but some discount on the existing tax regime. So that if we're wrong we have the cover through reduced taxes. And that's why we take the decision to develop Laggan/Tormore right now without waiting.</p>
          <p>But again, except for this, and if we find the same concern, we will also ask for the same changes in tax regime to make sure that we are not putting the Company at stake. But again, there is a strong demand for gas in the world, especially because of environment concerns about CO2 emissions and more and more, not only Exxon, is considering that developing gas is our way to be part of this concern about the global warming.</p>
          <p>On Solar in Abu Dhabi, it's ma&#xF1;ana, but of course ma&#xF1;ana was yesterday. Even if today we have &#x2013; maybe I shouldn't say this, but we have initialed the contract. So it's really now a question of timing, but I'm very optimistic that the contract will be approved soon and it's an important project, first because it's Solar, and also because it's in Abu Dhabi and especially in Masdar. So we are very keen to see this project, the way it has been structured to be launched as soon as possible, but again we are in a country where sometimes it takes longer than what we should expect to see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ah, we go it.  I am thinking about the tax.</p>
          <p>No more questions? Last one. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. In the last 20-25 years there has been only one occasion when the oil price has averaged above $80 and I note that in one of your slides you run your kind of base case economics on $80. Can you just indicate at this point in time, does all of your portfolio make money at $60, which I think is your low case? Not suggesting that this will be the average price; I'm just saying that we haven't seen 80 except in one year and it therefore seems a little bit of an aggressive assumption, perhaps.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In our existing portfolio, producing portfolio, I'm just trying to think of what could be not working at 60, but I don't see. They all are because they were developed with prices which were usually below 60 and those projects usually were launched at 40 or $50 per barrel. Remember we have been always very transparent on the assumptions we were using to launch projects. And what is important today is to make sure that we get the benefit of higher prices to increase the return we have on projects which were launched at 40 and that we don't lose the additional profit coming from additional prices.</p>
          <p>And using the $80, it's true that we've been recently reaching again the $80, much more for, I would say market consideration, expecting that the price will remain high, but not because of the result of offer and demand. I'm sure that Patrick covered that point.</p>
          <p>Now, we are in a different world. Costs of projects are different. Requests for efficiency, requests for security, requests for everything are different. Costs of projects are higher. And still the need for hydrocarbons is there. And hydrocarbons plus coal, i.e. fossils. We are now extremely, I would say, knowledgeable on what can be done with solar, what can be done with most of those so-called new energies, maybe not yet with nuclear, but at least with biomass. And we don't see with the five, 10 years, 20 years time, any change, is what is the slide that you've been seeing, which says 75% of fossils energy is still being needed by the year 2030.</p>
          <p>So if you believe in the assumptions of what we'll be using again, now when you see the demand in OECD, but expanding it still in an emerging countries, you reach this level very quickly. And except if somebody tells me how, we don't see how Solar and all of the new sources of energies, even they are not new, cannot replace, but just complement the traditional energies.</p>
          <p>So I strongly believe that $80 is something we can use without taking a risk as the way to decide the launching of new projects. I would even say that I consider 80 as probably low case.</p>
          <p>What is the concern of companies like us and probably others? It's not the price of oil, it's the margin you will be getting on the price of oil. And that's why we feel far better with 80 than with any other consideration like 120, 140, even if I &#x2013; not sure, but I strongly believe that we will see those price again, and you are saying that we've seen it only once. But just like for other things, you see it once and then you'll see it again, that's life. And there is no reason, especially on this domain, when you talk about scarce resources, about very strong environment rules, there is no reason to think that you will go back to 20 or $30 except in a world which will be a total disaster. And I repeat it the same way I said it last year, that's not our strategy number one. We still have to be careful on a crisis, is it possible, and then what will be the impact on everything, including the 80.</p>
          <p>But then it will be not only the 80, it will be the price of gas, it will be demand, it will be growth and it will be probably to be &#x2013; I would say developed in totally different way. But that's not our scenario number one, it's what we call the worst case scenario, not because of the price of oil, because of the crisis linked with economy dropping because of how to get rid of those extra debts in countries and all of those things.</p>
          <p>And that's important because I mean we are part of the world, we are part of the system and we have to take care of the environment, because if something happens in this areas we will be hurt by it. Now without this margin is the only concern we have. Where we keep the same margin at higher prices, because with margin you are making your profits on cash flow. But on price, no problem. Offer and demand will definitely trigger higher prices. And we prefer to say this in advance, still not knowing exactly what will be our share. But with $80, no. I feel confident and I don't want to have the same problem that we faced. And you were one of those and I appreciate this because we have learned from this, telling us you have always good views on the future, but you are not doing it.</p>
          <p>And now we definitely believe that it's the right time, when we say something and we believe in something, is to develop it the way we're seeing it. That why we have made those three, let's call them acquisition, at the end of the year with Nigeria, with Iraq, with Chesapeake. And probably with the rumors which exist, and they are sometimes not totally wrong, maybe something more. That's frankly because we believe in higher prices and I don't want you, among others, to tell me you said price will be higher and you didn't move your ass.  This time &#x2013; I'm sorry, Robert, I promised not to use this word &#x2013;  to move &#x2013; and just to move, because we think it's the right time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Just again, if no more questions, very sorry to being late and gives an opportunity for Patrick to prove he's not only a good CFO. I will see this with the stock value tomorrow morning. So, we have to consider which part is responsible for the result.</p>
          <p>But seriously, I frankly feel much more safe the way I am presenting you the Total view this month than last time I was in this same room. And I think going through all of the elements of the Company, from Upstream to Downstream and including Chemicals, the way we see the integration of our company being more and more stream, but still if we can achieve a profitable Downstream, adapted to the new environment, the same way we are doing it for Chemicals, and our search for new energies, even if I know we don't yet answer totally to your questions, I really see a very strong potential for our company, not only for 2010, which will be as usual over a short term. The more complex time where you have to say is it going to be 80 or 70 or $90, and even more for gas. But for the medium and long-term, I think that the decision we've been taking recently are the one which will help us in the world which is in total  move and change, at least to put the Company in the position to not only grow, but to adapt itself in a more easy way than some others.</p>
          <p>Thinking about new technologies, thinking on how to be more acceptable, thinking on finding ways to reduce CO2 emissions by ourselves or through sequestration of those CO2 emissions, i.e. prepare the company for the future.</p>
          <p>Now, if you ask me do I know what will be the position of energy in 2020 and 2030, I can only answer one thing. Without energy, there is no growth. If there is no growth, it's true that we have a question mark. But I mean Total will not be the first hurt.</p>
          <p>But energy is a source of life and being present in all the segments in a profitable way today, being adapted and being ready to adapt yourself and with a strong financial position, the way we're keeping it, it's leave us in the best way to prepare ourselves for the future.</p>
          <p>And that's a strong message which I feel far easy to deliver this year with new production than it was last year with still this debate on when and how. Now it's when, more, and how, we know.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>