<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1134704" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2007 Earnings Call - Paris</title>
    <date>2008-02-13</date>
    <companies>
      <company>596</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Robert Castaigne, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Philippe Boisseau, Executive Vice President &#x2013; Gas and Power</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Michel B&#xE9;n&#xE9;zit, President of TOTAL Refining and Marketing</participant>
      <participant id="4">Yves-Louis Darricarr&#xE8;re</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I didn't come in last, just as you were waiting for the curtain to go up. It's sometimes little bit hasty.</p>
          <p>And welcome to the presentation of the 2007 results and for the 2008 outlook, 2008 and beyond. Number of things which change and others which don't. You have the same consideration up here, all the members of the COMEX who will be taking the floor in turn to talk about the results of their business in 2007; Robert Castaigne, of course, our CFO will be presenting the financial results for 2007 and I shall ask Philippe Boisseau, who is in charge of the Gas and New Energy Division to present his line of business.</p>
          <p>First of all, if I may, a few words about the company as a whole, before I give the floor to Robert for the financial results.</p>
          <p>We had a good performance in 2007 that's of course for you to decide, but we believe that we've put in a good performance among the best of the managers. Very clearly this time we are able, with great pleasure, to announce production growth plus 1.5% in 2007 with underlying growth of 4.5% and we'll come back in a few moments time to deliver the details of that in the up-stream business.</p>
          <p>It took time to do that, we have to change the bulk of exploration production, that's done. And the production is now increasing. So production is fine, but it has of course to deliver the goods in terms of good results. And the results are there, almost $17 billion of adjusted net income in dollars, plus 6% in the recurring parts. Clearly you have to invest to produce results in the future. And our investment, our Capex was more or less in line, in fact slightly lower than what we announced at $16 billion.</p>
          <p>We have forecasts of increased Capex for next year. Net cash flow, which is also necessary for Capex, plus 27%, $10.3 billion and even though this is not a significant issue, but it was asked of us, so I'm now happy to answer positively by saying that we are starting the gradual sale of our sanofi stake, we started at the end of 2007. We sold about 0.4% of our stake, which is not very much of course, but that's in line with our adopted strategy, which is to sell little by little to &#x2013; our stake in sanofi without having an impact on that company's share price.</p>
          <p>Dividends, we are suggesting that it will be increased by 11% to &#x20AC;2.07, that's an increase of 23% in dollars, using the exchange rate of 145, of course that will depend on the exchange rate on the date of payment. You will see that we are the only one of the majors to increase our production in 2007; in the fourth quarter, it's even higher than it was in the fourth quarter 2006. Only PP is slightly up.</p>
          <p>You have the results of TOTAL and the other majors and I think that it shows that we are among the best of the majors and the figures bare that out.  The growth strategy of TOTAL, which is &#x2013; I think I'm right in saying is the fruit of long-term constant strategy, which adapts of course every year to the environment which is based on the fact that to produce results today, we needed to invest yesterday.</p>
          <p>And I insist on this once again that it's important. TOTAL has always been in a position to carry out a strategy which is somewhat independent of the environment. That doesn't mean of course that we don't take account of the environment, but our strategy is a long-term strategy. It takes a long view and it has to be a right strategy whether the oil price is as high as it is today or much lower. Whatever the environment, our view is that we must continue to deliver the goods both in upstream and in all the other sectors, we must remain profitable which create value in the long-term.</p>
          <p>Now I'm not going to go through all the projects on this slide because my colleagues on the Executive Committee will go into that in more detail later on. But as you can see we have projects in all areas: upstream, downstream, chemicals, including the environment, which is becoming a major component of our strategy with the CO2 capture pilot project in Lacq.</p>
          <p>We have also put in the results of negotiation strategies; Sincor is a case in point and it's successful.  Obviously it's a one-off; we can't do that everyday because we're likely to lose a little of the portfolio, but given the circumstances we're managing to remain in that project with more than 30%, which enables us to believe that we might continue to be able to develop in a country which has high reserves of heavy oil, it was the right strategy in this particular case.</p>
          <p>Independently of that, chemicals, gas refinery, 2 billion barrels from exploration and new business, that again shows the success of our strategy in an environment which is more favorable in terms of prices.  But that of course has a downside; higher costs and the cost of accessing new reserves, but TOTAL's advantage compared to other majors is that we have a portfolio which enables us to develop production with our existing resources. And thanks to the strategy initiated by our upstream team, we can bring new businesses online, new areas online as we've done with Shtokman.</p>
          <p>And the major sources of value creation for the long-term strategy, I'll say and repeat that once again; I know that people tend to have different sensitivities but my priority is safety, whatever we say, whatever our communication efforts, it's not just a question of communication.  We are one of the best in the business in the safety of our major projects. And I think we focused a great deal on improving safety particularly in refining and petrochemicals and that is also a way of managing projects.</p>
          <p>The preservation of the environment, that is also something we are focusing on very much, how can we improve the situation of climate change, how can we reduce greenhouse gas emissions? The growth targets, we'll come back to that, we maintain our target of 4% on average from 2006 to 2010. Beyond 2010, we'll give you the information for you to do your own sums, but I know you'll be able do that. But for this year we shall not be giving you any new targets because we have the projects, we know that, and even at $80 a barrel, our aim is to continue to grow production, and to grow production at a higher rate than the growth in world demand. And we want to ensure that we are able to meet increasing demand.</p>
          <p>The consolidation of European refining, we shall benefit; we'll talk about that later on. We need a refining plant, which is more and more up to the latest state-of-the-art. We need to improve the energy efficiency, which again is a way of reducing greenhouse gas emissions and then there is a policy of course based on new developments, new projects, and this is a part of the strategy that you're familiar with; presence in countries with a high rate of increasing consumption in countries which give access to feedstocks in the long-term, and that clearly is the case of Saudi Arabia.  And Michel will say more about that as well as the coker project, that we have just decided, the press release was released yesterday on coker and that shows that we intend to continue our investment in all sectors; these projects are of course profitable by our own standards in petrochemicals. The strategy is exactly the same. We wish to consolidate our existing businesses. We adapt it to changing markets and we put ourselves in a position to continue sustainable growth in countries with a high rate of consumption to petrochemicals or which give access to high quality feedstocks like Ukraine and Algeria and that &#x2013; was necessary to say that.</p>
          <p>TOTAL strategy is also a strategy of diversity. We also intend to be involved in development of new energies so we are not in the process of substituting for fossil fuels and hydrocarbons in particularly.  What I do mean, because we are an energy company, is that we do need to be involved in the development of new energy sources, look to the moment when they can be cleaner, more profitable and that of course will contribute to our policy of sustainable development. And that is &#x2013; but one of our first commitments, of course, is to respond to energy demand; and in the years to come, oil and gas will not be enough simply because there won't be enough access to those new reserves.</p>
          <p>So what we have to do for the time being is to maintain our focus on the new technologies. As we've done in all our businesses, we need to be present with consuming countries, with producing countries, develop our strategy of partnerships, which has shown that it's a tried and tested method, even if it's not always easy and that is the key to success in the future. All of that of course requires capital spending, more capital spending, up in 2008 from 16 billion to 19 billion. This is shared out among all of the businesses and each one of the managers of that business will tell you more about that as we go through this set of presentations. But it's all about profitable growth.</p>
          <p>And I'll now give the floor to the Robert Castaigne, our CFO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. I will focus my comments on the breakdown of our results in Q4, 2007, expressed in dollars.  As for the environment in the fourth quarter 2007, well, we saw a 32% increase in hydrocarbon prices, gasoline prices, and refining margins. In the fourth quarter, and in the view of the rise in crude oil prices, there was a squeeze on our refining margins, largely due to the sharp rise in NAFTA prices.</p>
          <p>Production increased by 2.4%, as a result of an overall increase of 5.5%, offset by price effects, scope effects, and the accidents in the Congo, which altogether had a negative impact of 3% bringing us back to net production growth of 2.4% in the fourth quarter of 2007. Now our costs also increased in particular in the upstream sector with some productivity effects in downstream and the chemicals. The net effect on the fourth quarter was a net decompression, it was $4.7 billion, up 28% on the fourth quarter of 2006.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share in dollars were $1.99 per share; that is 29% growth in view of the moderately accretive effects in the Q4, thanks to the share buyback program. And for the full year, net income was $16.7 billion, up 6%. Earnings per share rose 8% over the full year.</p>
          <p>And this brings me to an analysis of the group's performance. I am going to look at our adjusted net operating income from the segments expressed in billions of dollars here. The first thing I would like to say is that our average tax rate was in fact the same in 2006 and 2007 at 56% which makes a comparison that much easier.</p>
          <p>Now we have a breakdown here of the impact of adjusted net operating income after taxes. In 2006 our adjusted net operating income was $15.5 billion that rose to 16.8 billion, that's an increase of $1.3 billion. The increase breaks down as follows: Environment, the increase in the price hydrocarbons and refining margins, petrochemicals increases, all had an after tax impact of $950 million.</p>
          <p>Now the costs after tax had a negative impact of $500 million mostly in the Upstream, which accounted for 400 of those $500 million. Then our exploration costs increased, which had a negative impact after tax of $350 million. Maybe I should point out that from $1.2 billion in 2006 we increased our investments in exploration to 1.65 billion in 2007. And then of course, the combined effects of growth and productivity accounted for $1.2 billion, mostly, in the Upstream, which accounted for $850 million of that 1.2 billion with a new production with a higher margin than the previous operations, not to mention various impacts on our scope of consolidation.</p>
          <p>Elsewhere, Downstream and Chemicals accounted for a further $350 million through our pre-adjusted net operating income, but the combined effects of growth and productivity, I said was $1.2 billion on adjusted net operation income, which gives us the overall increase of $1.3 billion in 2007.</p>
          <p>This is a benchmarking slide. First of all in terms of net operating income of our Upstream segment, now TOTAL is in red on this graph; we have the red line and you'll see that net operating income has increased among the best of class, that we have continued strong growth here, and that we have really reached the benefits of the oil price increases between 2004 and 2007.</p>
          <p>As for the net operating income of the Downstream and Chemicals segments again for the purposes of simplification, we have shown you this chart here, but broadly speaking concerning Downstream and Chemicals, the net operating income has been very good, strong, with very little volatility despite the rather sharper volatility in the refining margins and in the petrochemical sector. Slightly negative growth followed by a return to growth, broadly speaking this curve had been on the rise and with a very low level of volatility.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share have increased continuously between 2004 and 2007. The growth rate is comparable to that of Shell; it's higher than those of Chevron and BP, slightly below admittedly &#x2013; than slightly less strong growth than our net income, but you'll see that the variance between Exxon and TOTAL is due to the fact that Exxon is investing a lot less than TOTAL. In fact ExxonMobil is using its available cash flow to buy back shares which has an immediate accretive effect in terms of enhancing earnings per share.</p>
          <p>As for TOTAL's investment program compared with that of its peer group, you see that on the whole, TOTAL invests between 25 and 27% of its capital employed every year. Now this level of investment is substantially higher even than of its peers, Chevron, Royal Dutch Shell, BP and Exxon, and in the case of Exxon in particular &#x2013; well, by comparison with Exxon in particular, TOTAL invests approximately 85% by comparison, which means that by comparison TOTAL is investing &#x2013; as being equal about twice as much as Exxon.</p>
          <p>Now, the consequence of this high investment program has an impact on our profitability, again by comparison with our peer group. TOTAL's profitability is substantially higher than that of Chevron, BP and Shell, but is well below that of Exxon, which as I said invests not an awful lot by &#x2013; in terms of its size and is using its available capital to buy back shares.</p>
          <p>Now, adjusted cash flow up 12% to 24 billion; now looking at the histogram, to look at TOTAL resources we need to add the proceeds from disposal or divestments, which was slightly lower in 2007 than in 2006.</p>
          <p>In 2007 the divestments accounted for, well, included the 0.4% stake in sanofi, which we disposed of in the last quarter of 2007, plus our stake in the interconnector pipe and our stake in development Feyzin refinery and a number of other smaller divestments in the various segments.</p>
          <p>This constitutes our resources and after resources we have gross investments, up 8%, again expressed in dollars, the dividend grows 20%. This is all dividends combined; the dividend we pay to our shareholders but also the dividends that are subsidiaries paid to minority shareholders when they minority shareholders. But overall the dividend rose 20%, share buybacks down 53%. Because in 2007 we bought back approximately 1.4% of our shares, the previous year we had bought back 2.8%.</p>
          <p>Now the balance was used to reduce our leverage. At the end of 2007, we found ourselves with the net-debt-to-equity ratio gearing of 27%. Remember that at the end of 2006, our net-debt-to-equity ratio was 34%.</p>
          <p>For a certain number of reasons, maybe I should remind you that the gearing ratio is usually at its highest at year end. This brings me to the dividend, we will be moving that the AGM approve a dividend of 2.07 euros, that leaves us with a balance of 1.07 euro; balance of 1.07 after the 1 euro interim dividend in November.</p>
          <p>Now in euros, that is an 11% increase; in dollars that is a 23% increase. What I should point out that in euros the pay-out ratio is approximately 39%, expressed in dollars the pay-out ratio is situated between BP and Shell, closer to Shell than BP in fact, but substantially higher than the pay-out ratio of Exxon around 20% and Chevron, which is slightly below the 30% mark.</p>
          <p>Now over time, between 2004 and 2007, the TOTAL dividend increased by an annual average of 21%; that's in dollars. That's a slightly lower level of growth in euros; you see that over the periods our dividend pay-out go through as much sharper than that of our peers. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning to you all. What is basically the heart of our Upstream strategy in TOTAL is operational excellence and 2007 confirmed this whether we're talking about the growth in production, the start up of new major fields or the preparation of the future. Our strategy is based on our capacity to bring online the main growth projects and that capacity results from a mastery of the technologies we need, and the technologies which concern the techniques of the industry where we are going to get major growth: LNG, sour gas, deep offshore, heavy oil and so on and so forth. And that capacity also results from our very strong discipline in project management.</p>
          <p>The strategy focuses on exploration and development, which brings new fields online as quickly as possible to optimize resource recovery and illustration is Jura, which was a discovery in a mature zone, very quickly brought online because Jura will come online at the end of the first half but it's also illustrated by a number of other development projects in the two areas which come from the upgrading of resources that we initiated some years ago, Mahakam in Indonesia, Bongkot in Thailand and Anguille off Gabon.</p>
          <p>Our strategy will also benefit from our historical leadership position in a number of major petroleum basins, particularly the Gulf of Guinea and the Middle East and it's also based on the implementation of major strategic partnerships to access new resources, that's of course <mark type="inaudible" /> and showing creativity where that's necessary in terms of contracts and that's the case for Shtokman and also to a certain extent in the deep-offshore blocks, 17/06 and 15/06 in Angola. That strategy has really delivered the goods in 2007. Can I go back to the previous slide, please?</p>
          <p>In 2007, just taking the three majors projects which came online at the end of 2006: Dalia, Rosa and Dolphin at the end of 2007, perhaps 160, 170,000 barrels of oil equivalent a day, and it could be more then than 200,000 barrels of oil equivalent a day, in the middle of 2008. Now that clearly goes through to our financial growth and $12.1 billion in 2007, up from 10.9 billion in 2006. That's a fairly considerable growth. The environment of course, was responsible for 1.1 billion. But the increase in costs, which of course is linked to the price, a cost of $750 million, and the growth in volumes was worth $850 million.</p>
          <p>34% ROACE in 2007, if you look at the net income of the equivalent of oil equivalent between 2006 and 2007, net income has increased by 80% per barrel over the past three years, where it's increased by 60% for Chevron, ExxonMobile and 40% for BP. So there has been a continuing improvement in our performance calculated per barrel of oil equivalent.</p>
          <p>Robert and Christophe both said that among the majors, TOTAL is the only one to have increased its production by 1.5% in 2007. That figure of 1.5% growth results from two countervailing forces, first of all, environmental factors, which of course has pulled production down 3%. The price effect, the quarter effect, the scope effect and safety issues in Nigeria, but that's been more than offset by the underlying growth of 4.7% from new production net of the decline in existing production and that decline has been very modest in 2007.</p>
          <p>What is perhaps even more interesting is that the underlying growth of 4.7% has contributed net operating income $1.10 billion, whereas the 3% decline in the environmental factors only deprives us of $250 million at the operating level. So that shows you the contribution and the importance of the new production and the underlying growth which it generates.</p>
          <p>The Upstream is well leveraged to the environment. If you look at 2003 to 2007, over the twenty quarters of that period, the price of Brent was between 25 and $85 per barrel. The average price per barrel of oil equivalent that we produced, including gas, were between $22 per barrel of oil equivalent and $65 per barrel of oil equivalent. And over that same price range, our net operating income per barrel has varied from 5 to $15 per barrel with a strong correlation illustrated by the left hand graph.</p>
          <p>Today, our sensitivity to the dollar is $200 million. Our net income varies by $200 million every time the price of Brent varies by $1. In fact, there's $200 million on net income. If you look at it by type of contract, what we can see first of all is that the share of production with a fixed margin is falling in our production mix. Secondly, a third of our production is under PSCs but within that third of PSCs, 30% only, which is 10% of our total production, is subject to a threshold test.</p>
          <p>And one final point that I wish to draw your attention to. You can see here that the net operating income per barrel in our PSCs is very much higher than the net operating income from our production under concession arrangements. We believe that in 2008 &#x2013; as we head into 2008 and we'll continue to keep in 2008 our competitive advantage in terms of technical costs, even though of course our technical costs have increased up from 9.9 barrel of oil equivalent to $12.4 per barrel of oil equivalent in 2007. The increase of $2.5 is due to affect some price effects, extra exploration effects of $1 per barrel inflation and the rest is $0.3 per barrel is taken up by maintenance and 0.3, $0.30 for investment in new products. So globally &#x2013; and this is what you see on the left hand side &#x2013; we believe that we will retain our competitive advantage, which is quite a substantial one, on technical costs and that it's due to two effects the portfolio effect which is of high quality and also very strong project management discipline.</p>
          <p>On the 2 billion as Christophe said earlier on, 2 billion barrels of oil potential resources unlocked in 2007. 1 billion was added by exploration in 2007 that is the result of about 44, 45 exploration wells, which were positive in all areas of the world, and you can see the map here, in the Gulf of Guinea of course, in the North Sea, in Asia and that Far East, but also in Azerbaijan.</p>
          <p>Parallel to that, we have continued to prepare the future by taking about 20 new licenses and you can see those also on this map. If we look at what's been going on over the past five years since 2003 that 5 billion barrels, so 1 billion barrels a year, which have been unlocked by exploration. And what I think is more interesting than that is that this very good exploration record and leads to actual projects very quickly, and you can see that on the histogram. Of those 5 billion barrels, 500 million barrels are already in production. Up to 900,000 are in projects in preparation, 2.5 in development, and only 1.5 in the appraisal stage.</p>
          <p>So 2007 has been good a exploration year with an average cost of $1.7 per barrel of oil equivalent and that performance plus future projects has led us to spend more than $1.8 billion on exploration in 2008, that's what we'll be spending, which is about 10% more than what we spent in exploration in 2007. $1.8 billion slated for 2008 in production.</p>
          <p>Probable and proven reserves are $20 billion of oil equivalent, well distributed through the world oil basins, 13 countries in which we have more than 500 million barrels of oil equivalent of proven reserves, 9 at the end of 2003. And since 2003, we've added one country per year to that list, Congo, Canada, Yemen and the last country to be added was Australia, since 2003. That portfolio, we believe offers a very good balance of risks and opportunities. It has a very considerable source of long-term potential growth. And it can be extended by extra resources in Russia or in heavy oils.</p>
          <p>A word or two about the renewal of reserves; our oil equivalent reserves were 11.1 barrels of oil equivalent in 2006, with the prices at the end of 2006, $58.73 per barrel. Our exploration has contributed in 2007 894 million barrels of oil, we produced 873 million barrels of oil. So that is a net balance of 21 million barrels of oil at the same price, $58.73 per barrel.</p>
          <p>So that's a rate of renewal of 102% at constant rates. The rules are that we assess our reserves in 2007, at December 2007. And therefore, the price effect reduces our barrels by 25 million barrels and the rate of renewal is 78%, and we also made a number of divestments at Sincor, 45% down to a little more than 30%. And that has now been enshrined in an agreement. And including that non-recurrent effect, our rate of renewal of reserves is 23%, with a 10.4 billion barrels of oil equivalent in reserve, we have 12 years of production ahead of us, our proven and probable reserves are about 20 billion barrels of oil equivalent with the sensitivity of between 60 and 90 dollars per barrel. So our probable reserves, I think give us more than 20 years of production. As far as our resources, they are 40 billion barrels of oil equivalent, higher than 40 years of production. Those are the resources.</p>
          <p>Production growth should be sustained up to 2010. We maintain the target of 4% reduction growth on average from 2006 to 2010 as Christophe de Margerie has already said this morning. We are confident in being able to achieve that. First of all, because of the decline in the core of our production, which is lower than that of most of our competitors, 3 to 4% a year. And we also, of course, above all, have a list of the projects which you see on this slide, the ramp-up of the production <mark type="inaudible" /> brought online in 2007, and a number of new projects which you can see here, which are being developed and which will come online between now and 2010.</p>
          <p>Beyond 2010, production should continue to increase at a fair clip because of the 23 projects which you can see here. All of them have been identified. Some of them already have a fairly high degree of maturity. And this should enable us to continue to generate growth of our production, which is higher than that of our competitors.</p>
          <p>I think it's also interesting to point that there is an increase in production through 2010. 80% of that is production that we are operator of, which is considerably more than what we operate today. So we have a tighter control over our production in the future. That's basically what that means. You can see the projects considered here on this slide. These will be the main contributors to our growth between now and 2010. And for each one of them, you have the kick-off dates, the progress and the production plateau we're expecting. If you add to those eight projects the three projects we started up in 2007, which they are continuing to do the ramp up, Dalia, Rosa and Dolphin in 2010, that will give us 500,000 barrels per day and you can see the percentage of operated and non-operated. 80%, as I said, is resources where we are operator.</p>
          <p>The operational excellence is also perhaps above all human resources and that's why we have this slide, which is a little new on our human resources and our skills. On the right-hand side, you can see that we have the breakdown of human resources, 30%, basically in support operations, 60% in operations, 3% in geoscientists, 10% in management. You have the geographic breakdown of those human resources and you can compare them to our productions and our CapEx locations.</p>
          <p>We are in hiring mode. We intend to have 3,000 hirings between 2007 and 2012, and 80% of those hirings will be in management and basic technologies, geosciences and operations. 65% of our management is local, in our subsidiaries, and that's continuing. And we are making a big effort to train, first of all, to maintain our core skills, but also to increase the internationalization of our human resources and to honor the partnership agreements we have with our host countries.</p>
          <p>Our turnover is fairly low compared to our major competitors. It's about 2% a year on average. So basically we are making a big effort to make sure that we have and retain skilled teams, who are more and more locally based and locally hired. And that of course, we believe, is absolutely essential to succeed our future projects. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for that exhaustive presentation of exploration and production, and I would now like to give the floor to Philippe Boisseau, who is in charge of LNG and new energies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Let's begin with the LNG market. Since last year, and as of now, the three largest regions in the world, Europe, Asia and North America, are importing more gas than they produce in the quarter. LNG is making up the shortcoming. This market is growing very rapidly. A very high growth market because the additional amount required is increasing by an annual 10%. So against this broader backdrop, our portfolio of assets has always been very well positioned geographically, because we have LNG production facilities in Africa, in Europe, in Asia, and in the Middle East.</p>
          <p>Now, our portfolio &#x2013; the portfolio we're building up is expanding, as you can see on this slide here. The assets are in red and confirms the geographical diversity. And on the right hand side, top right, you'll see how well balanced our LNG production is, with the parts of the world where LNG is produced.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the Downstream, and we have five terminals, either <mark type="inaudible" /> or being built, two that are working perfectly in Altamira in Mexico and Hazira in India. Between 2008 and the start of 2009, we will be putting our share of Fish Hook, Fos Cavaou with a 3% stake and our re-gas rights in the Sabine Pass terminal that will all come on stream within the next year, as a result of which we will have re-gas capacity of about 12.5 million tons per annum. As I said, the downstream assets are also well-positioned, meaning that we have good marketing capacity Downstream of these terminals.</p>
          <p>As a result, I think we can say that our portfolio of assets is very well positioned in the context where gas prices would be under a certain amount of pressure in the future with the certain volatility of prices, but I'll come back to that in just a second. So, how do we foresee the LNG prices developing? Traditionally in Europe and the U.S., prices have been at a comparable level. Gas price is approximately 70% of their energy prices. Now for the so-called Atlantic markets, we'll have a similar proportion at 70% of the energy market.</p>
          <p>But global prices are converging more and more, be it the stock prices which predominate in the U.S. and Europe, but average prices in Asia are very comparable. However, in a market where the LNG supply is finding it very difficult to meet demand, we are beginning to feel the effect of a certain pressure. That's shown on the right-hand bar chart; this is the markets of the contracts signed in the market at present. Not looking so much at the market, or the bar for the contracts signed in 2007. This is a certain guidance because we have a very long-term contract in Asia.</p>
          <p>But the fact that buyers are now prepared to sign at price levels that are very close to energy parity is a clear indication of the fact that they are perfectly aware of the fact that there is a certain tension in the market, and that LNG projects are finding it difficult to meet demand, whence the pressure on prices. So, if we look at that broader context, we can expect a relatively tense market over the next 10 years, but with nonetheless quite sharp variations from one year to the next because obviously demand fluctuates as a function of climatic effects.</p>
          <p>Now with our highly diversified and highly balanced portfolio, this means that we will be able to reap the benefits of this type of arbitrage. LNG represents approximately 20% of our operating profits and the capital employed, ROACE is slightly over 30%, that's return on average capital employed, the same as in 2004. Except that in 2007, this includes average non-producing assets at a quite substantial level. These are assets that are being built and are more numerous than in 2004.</p>
          <p>As a result, we have good growth potential. The three components in the growth potential; first of all, the fact that these non-producing assets will be brought on stream; secondly, the tension on prices; and thirdly, as you will see in the next slide, a lot if not all of the projects we are currently investing in are grassroots projects, which have considerable debottlenecking and expansion potential which again give us quite a lot of upside potential.</p>
          <p>Now for our production we get an average annual growth guidance of 13% between 2006 and 2007. In actual fact, this average level of 13% will be exceeded by two projects; Yemen LNG and Qatargas II. The construction is going very well for the latter.  But overall on those projects we need to compare for the future. Angola LNG was launched this year, as you know.  Here we've included four major projects for which we expect the final investment decision to be made over the next three years. That's this year, 2008, or next year, 2009.</p>
          <p>So in terms of pace, we've really stepped up a gear. This is why we are talking about changing the scale of our LNG portfolio. Well, that process is already underway and will be gathering pace over the next three years.</p>
          <p>On final point, that's new energies. Our view of the global energy situation is one where energy will not be competing with one another. In fact they will be helping balance the supply and demand for energy worldwide. We need to use all resources available, beginning with energy efficiency, but adding on all other forms of energy as required; it's not if/or, one/or, it's and/and. And in this context as an energy group, we are preparing for the future.</p>
          <p>We've begun by identifying a certain number of additional areas to focus on top of our core business which will continue to be for quite some time the production of hydrocarbons. There are, however, a number of prerequisites and strengths I would like to talk about. First of all, ours is a group that has succeeded in entering into partnerships with the major producing countries. We've proved our ability to efficiently manage major projects and we have technological excellence.</p>
          <p>For all this reasons, we are very, very legitimate partners, but I think that also counts from likening the type of energies we'd like to work in. Let me mention the prerequisites. The first is profitability.  The profitability criteria must be the same when deciding whether or not to invest in these assets. So, same as for our other assets in the group. Second prerequisite is that they must help us fight against the greenhouse gases, that's important to us. And the final prerequisite; when we develop or expand into new areas where we do not have all the technological capacities, it is very important to work alongside people who have those same capacities. As our current state of our thinking in this area, we've moved forward on &#x2013; in two areas.</p>
          <p>First of all, solar energy, which are assets that are &#x2013; work well, Tenesol, which manufactures solar panels and Photovoltech, which manufactures photovoltaic cells. This is a company with very good shareholder return, a very efficient company and one that we feel will help us step up our investment in solar energy.</p>
          <p>You have the production of Photovoltech capacity as we foresee it in 2007, 2009, and we expect to increase our version capacity 240 megawatts and of course production acceleration after that and we believe that Photovoltech or Photovoltech should I say will be able to help us reduce cost sufficiently to make Photovoltech energy efficient without any subsidies in the years to come. For cell producers profitability is already very good.</p>
          <p>In the nuclear sector, we have been working with AREVA and SUEZ. Now, we will be providing to this consortium &#x2013; we'll be providing our ability to manage large projects, in Abu Dhabi for instance, we are also investors and of course, this is only a very early stage when the time comes when the Emirates want a tender we will be ready, we are working at that already. This is an area, which is for the moment restricted to Abu Dhabi, but there's clear evidence of our ability to manage very large projects and enter into partnerships. This is experience that we will be capitalizing on to gradually determine how to move forward. In all events, our mind set is based on a certain eagerness to move forward rapidly, but cautiously all the same, because this is a new area, and we don't want to run before we can walk.</p>
          <p>One final point, the whole array of other areas we will be looking at, we've decided to reorganize the branch. We organize the division, we organize our R&amp;D around a certain number of areas that have been identified here. Clean coal, because we believe coal will be playing an important role but we do not wanted to be generating greenhouse gasses, XTL that's quarter liquid. Second generation biomass not competing with food waste and of course CO2 sequestration, I think the <mark type="inaudible" /> pilot project is evidence of our eagerness to make progress in this area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Philippe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Michel will talk to us now about refining and marketing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning to you all. Performance of our downstream business in 2007, shows that in spite of somewhat mixed environment that we still have a capacity to resist, a mixture of audacity and caution has contributed the results we wanted, because we have an adjusted net operating income at the end of the year, equal to that of the previous year, 2006.</p>
          <p>And that in spite of a very sharp deterioration in the market conditions in marketing, which cost us $230 million, offset partially by a slight improvement in refining margins, $50 million, so that's not very much. Inflation cost us $100 million. There was a specific effort focused on maintenance in 2007, there were major shutdowns for our European refineries in 2007 that cost us $150 million, TOTAL 300 million, entirely offset by growth and productivity efforts, $300 million, 120,000 of which comes from the Normandy DHC, which came online in the last weeks of 2007.</p>
          <p>So, stability basically is the message and that major stability conceals a very considerable rate of volatility of refining margins and particularly gasoline conversion margins. And this you can see on the right hand side of the slide. You can see that the gasoline conversion margins remained fairly seasonal and will probably continue to remain fairly seasonable. It's a very different picture in the summer and in the winter, as far as gasoline conversion margins concerned, as far as diesel conversion margins are concerned they will continue to be very strongly correlated with the price of crude and some of our investment projects are designed precisely to accommodate that correlation as best as possibly &#x2013; as best we possibly can.</p>
          <p>Our profitability in 2007, was 21% on the downstream business. We were number two in the industry, behind Exxon but ahead of three other majors of the panel that we benchmark against. It's important of course to remain number two, to continue to generate productivity, to contain the downside effect of inflation and the continuing erosion of distribution margins.</p>
          <p>Our aim is to be able with our self-help efforts to compensate for 90% of the impact of inflation in the next few years, basically between 2008 and 2012 at least. Also, I'd like to point out that we are also concentrating our refining on the principal selection, that's part of the picture as well, in 2007 we sold the 70% interest we had in the Milford Haven refinery.</p>
          <p>Could I go back to the previous slide please. ROACE downstream was 21% in 2007 compared to 15% as you can see on the left hand curve in 2003. And I basically think that we could sum it up in the following way, profitability of the downstream business in this period has basically been characterized by the fact that in 2005 &#x2013; in 2003 it was 20.9 refining margin up to 30.2, that of course increases profitability mechanically by 5%. That is compensated by marketing margins, which have been squeezed by 3%. So the 15% of profitability in 2003 is 17.5 and the difference between 17.5 in 2003, environment the same, and the real performance of 21% in 2007, is the self-help which contributed 4.5%, reduced by 1% by the $150 million of extra maintenance costs that I pointed out earlier on. So self-help represents most of the improvement in profitability that we have had in the downstream business recently and we intend to continue along that path.</p>
          <p>And in order to do that we have to adapt our refining business by making targeted investments, to adapt our European refining business to market changes. You have four photographs here of the four major projects we have that will contribute to achieving that objective in Europe, the DHC in Normandy that you're familiar with which started up at the end of 2006 and which is now working nominally &#x2013; even better than nominally.</p>
          <p>The two desulphurization parts which we are building in Lindsey and in Leuna, those installations will start up in 2009 and DHC in Huelva with CEPSA, which is currently being built in Spain and we'll start up in 2010.</p>
          <p>These investments will make it possible for us to improve the flexibility in the crudes we refine, but at the same time to reduce our production of heavy oil and to increase our production of medium distillates, in particular diesel, that the European market is consuming more and more of. You have the paybacks of the projects on the right hand side of the slide, you'll see that the paybacks are pretty quick, particularly if the crude price is high.</p>
          <p>This is due to fact that the conversion margins for diesel at least, as I said, are correlated with the price of crude and also due to the fact that sulphur premiums also depend to a large extent on the price of crude. High sulphur crude is discounted all the more so as the price of oil is high in general. This is why the HDF in Leuna has about the same payback at $60 &#x2013; $80 a barrel because the feedstock for Leuna, which is not a custom refinery, is less flexible than for the other refineries where we are modernizing the installations. And we can, as I said, refine a wider range of crude.</p>
          <p>You will have noted I am sure that we announced yesterday the launch of the modernization program for Port Arthur. What we are going to do is to build the coker of 50,000 barrels per day with an HDF of 64,000 barrels a day and a VDU of 55,000 barrel per day, which will balance the production of this refinery. This will make it possible to have heavier crude to make it easier to deal with high sulphur crudes 80% to &#x2013; close to 80% to 100% high sulphur crudes can be dealt with in this refinery and to get rid of heavy oil that the market doesn't want any more and increase more medium distillates, in particular diesel, and we think the demand for that will continue to increase in the years to come.  But that will not make any change to the gasoline output.</p>
          <p>The investment there is robust with various feedstock scenarios even if the overall refining margin is low. The fact that the conversion margins remain substantial will make it possible for this type of project to resist the low end of the cycle very well. The coker is scheduled to start up in 2011. The civil engineering work is starting this April.</p>
          <p>We are continuing as Christophe de Margerie said earlier on to look at grassroots refinery in Dubai in south-east Saudi Arabia, in partnership with Saudi Aramco. The technical characteristics of that refinery haven't changed since our last presentation. It is a 400,000 barrels per day facility with local dedicated crude with products basically distillates, gasoline, no heavy products at all. All the production will be exported basically.  The start up is expected in 2012.</p>
          <p>The economics of that particular project are also robust, thanks to the quality of conversion that this project can deliver, not very sensitive to distillation margins. The Jubail project will have a final investment decision taken by the middle of 2008. Thank you very much indeed, Michel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon ladies and gentleman. As you can see on the slide, 2007 was a year when our net operating income reached a record level in chemicals, but a very good divide between petrochemicals and base chemicals and of course specialties as well.</p>
          <p>In 2007, the prevailing environment was highly favorable particularly in Europe where the demand for polymers increased by 3.5% over 2006. The environment in the U.S. was not strong where the growth in polymers was zero, flat markets and where our main markets saw the &#x2013; biggest markets, the construction sector and automotive sector actually both reduced their demand.</p>
          <p>We considerably increased our performance in base chemicals, thanks to three things. First of all, higher hydrocracker production volumes, which rose by 3.5%; secondly, the fertilizer business; and thirdly the closing down of our elastomer business. Now all this enabled us to overcome a significant handicap, namely the continued closure of our Samsung platform for debottlenecking in mid 2007.</p>
          <p>Now we did particularly well in the specialties where our growth rate was over 19% in mechanization chemicals, 6% at Hutchinson and 4.5% in the adhesives sector. We now have a portfolio of worth over 7 billion euros. As you can see on the right hand chart with the curves, our performance could have been a lot better had we had a sharp increase in NAFTA and Europe. This increase drove petrochemicals performance down in the fourth quarter but nonetheless, over the full year 2007, we were able to maintain profitability at 12%.</p>
          <p>Now our top priority was to reduce our breakeven points in Europe. Four main items on our agenda here. The first was to improve our utilization rates in ethylene. In 2007 we reached a record level of production as I said and over the years to come, we expect a natural annual creep of 1.5% to which we can add the investments we are making in debottlenecking as a result of which our production should post annual average increase of 4% at pretty much constant fixed costs.</p>
          <p>The second important component is the restructuring of our industrial assets. In 2007 we discontinued the elastomer business in Antwerp and at the end of this year, the end of 2008, we will be discontinuing <mark type="inaudible" />, which are our least efficient efforts. In early 2009, we will start up a new modernized facility for the production of styrenes in Gonfreville, which will have a capacity over 600,000 tons.</p>
          <p>Thirdly, we are implementing energy savings programs in all our facilities. We have put the targets of achieving energy savings of 2% per annum.</p>
          <p>We have also declared our mission to reduce our consumption of energy by 2012. Fortunately, the cracking of raw materials that are less expensive than that. As you know there is an increasing scarcity of crude resources, so we have invested in the cracking to crack more butane now that &#x2013; so we've significantly increased the proportion of butane cracking in Gonfreville and Antwerp. We're prepared to invest in the cracking of olefins from refining, but this is an investment that we will not make as long as gasolines are more costly than ethylenes. But if the market were to turn around, we could invest in that field.</p>
          <p>Certainly, in 2008, we will be starting an industrial pilot project at Feluy of cracking of olefins, the idea being to crack methanol, which is easily produced from natural gas and coal. This is a technology that's of interest to countries that have small gas deposits but high coal deposits, like China.</p>
          <p>We also plan to reinforce safety projects &#x2013; safety programs should I say. I think it's fair to claim that we have reached the very best level in industry in terms of accident rate. We have fewer than four accidents per million hours worked. We are completing ISO certification of all our high risk sites or high risk facilities, which will all be certified by the end of this year, they will all be certified either for level 8 or higher.</p>
          <p>We are investing in the growth of petrochemical in general, ethane in particular. Over the last five years, the projects we have implemented have proved to be particularly profitable. And 2003, as you know we bought a significant stake in the Samsung platform in Korea. Now we expanded that by 30% in two stages and first of all in 2005, we extended the aromatics and <mark type="inaudible" />. In 2007, we then de-bottlenecked the vapor cracker to increase capacity to 800,000 tons, styrenes to over 12000 tons and a new polypropylene unit with the capacity of 300,000 tons.</p>
          <p>All this should make our design platform one of the most efficient of its kind in Asia. We have increased our stake in the <mark type="inaudible" /> to 20%; and in 2007, we de-bottlenecked the <mark type="inaudible" /> vapor cracker to increase its capacity to over 700,000 tons. Downstream of that we are building a low-density polyethylene plant which should be on stream in 2012.</p>
          <p>We're completing the Qatofin construction project that is the biggest ethane vapor cracker in the world with 1.2 million tons capacity; that's in Ras Laffan. Downstream of that we will have the polyethylene plant with a capacity of 500,000 tons. Both of these units should be on stream in early 2009, the second one just two months later.</p>
          <p>Finally, we've decided to build a petrochemicals complex in partnership with Sonatrach. This is a methane ethyl poly vapor cracker with a capacity of 300,000 tons. These units should be on stream in 2013. This is good that it is not very capital intensive because petrochemicals use less than $1 billion a year, which is substantially less than our main competitors.</p>
          <p>2008 to 2009 will be a turning point for petrochemicals in the group; four start-ups: the <mark type="inaudible" /> field in Qatar, a <mark type="inaudible" /> furnace on the Port Arthur vapor cracker, the end of the Samsung extension projects with the start up of the <mark type="inaudible" /> that's the ethylene to polypropylene scheme and the starting production units in Gonfreville which should make the Gonfreville one of the most competitive facilities of its kind. Then we will be starting up our project in Algeria.</p>
          <p>In 2015, we expect 50% of our ethylene production to be based outside of Europe and in the year 2000, the rate was zero. By 2015, we expect that over 30% of our raw materials will be so called advantage, that is at a lower point than NAFTA; and by 2015, our net operating income should show a good balance between Europe, the U.S., Asia, Qatar, and Algeria. We also do have considerable upside in terms of crude prices because at $80 a barrel or more, Qatar and Algeria should account for half of our TOTAL results. But in 2015, we should also have considerably reduced the fixed committed costs on our European facility. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Fran&#xE7;ois. Well, we're running a little late already. So I'll try and cover the last six slides fairly quickly and leave you some time for questions. This slide, our excellent capacity to realize new growth opportunities I think we've shown you that in the four presentations you've heard so far this morning from the business units, it concerns in terms of resources all the areas in which we work, LNG to heavy oil, I think we have a good diversification here and this gives us good potential for growth.</p>
          <p>Everything has been said about leadership, the operation excellence of these projects, and I think it's important to say this, are in the pipeline, whether it's an oil or gas pipeline, so to speak and should enable us to develop 5 billion barrels of oil equivalents of resources by the end of 2010. And that's real tangible results and that is the result of our operational excellence, you have upstream, downstream, petrochemical projects, so this is basically all the projects from all the businesses, which contribute to our future growth.</p>
          <p>Second thing I'd like to say is that we focus particularly on controlling cost. Now I am not going to say that we found the philosopher's stone to reduce costs, but it remains nevertheless one of our major problems and therefore we are determined not of course to change the market, you can't change the market, but at least when we commit to a price, when we've committed to a budget, we want to deliver on that basis. And when technology of course as it is at the moment becomes more and more complex, we have to also fight environmental issues and we have to do that, all that without comprising on quality and that is not an easy thing to do. Because we're asked to provide more safety, be cleaner, be softer on the environment, control our costs and we're trying to do all that, bring all that together by implementing new policies with all our contractors for EP contractors and others. So don't think that because oil and gas prices are higher that we are any less determined to control our costs, nothing could be further from the truth.</p>
          <p>I think we have also talked at length this morning about our Capex program. I said that we had stuck to our commitments in 2007, I think we committed to 16 to $17 billion in 2007; that was what we publicly announced Robert Castaigne we are projecting $19 billion for 2008, 25% of that increase is due to an exchange rate effect. Our Capex of course quite logically is spent in dollars, so you have in dollars &#x2013; so you have the euro effect or everything linked to the euro effect and it's a good thing for European contractors. But most of our Capex comes from Europe and therefore, you have that very significant exchange rate impact. 70%, however, of the increase in Capex is due to &#x2013; 50% is due to cost increases, rather, I don't like the word inflation, because the rise in costs of our projects from the time they are launched so there is clearly an exchange rate effect. But there is also clearly an effect that capital spending increases with higher costs, but at the same time the price of gas, the price of oil is also higher. And it has grown far more quickly than the increase in costs that we have incurred. These are all the projects listed one-by-one 300 million to $1 billion in 2008. These are really tangible investments to which I would add $1 billion in research and development.</p>
          <p>I think it's increasingly important in all our businesses to boost our R&amp;D effort. These figures of course are not in our results, they are in our cost accounting, but our determination is to increase that budget by 20% in 2008 up to $1 billion and these are absolutely essential expenditures in order to rise to the challenges we have in all our businesses.</p>
          <p>Growth creates value &#x2013; thanks to capital discipline, I think we have proven that throughout 2007 and hope to continue to do so. Just a rather new graph on the left hand side of the slide. The profitability of our major new projects is good, and on this theory you have both enrichment and profitability, deep offshore which has good IRR and which reacts well to the increase in oil price rises. But the enrichment is lower than for LNG. So basically, the combination of the IRR and the enrichment is basically what our portfolio is all about.</p>
          <p>But all of our sectors are above that dotted line there, which we don't insist on too much, but it's nevertheless all the same. It's a minimum profitability level as we call it. So if you have question on that, we can answer that. But all of our projects to are above the minimum profitability threshold, and what is even more important is that all our projects, whether they are downstream or upstream and are also above that level, but also sensitive to the rise in oil prices, particularly to downstream deep conversion.</p>
          <p>Capital employed in segments, an extra message to the one I've already given you. In 2008, about 20% of our capital is not yet productive as I've said. This is important, but it shows that we can have both profitable growth with productive capital, because we have to invest before producing. And in 2010 that tendency &#x2013; and that's quite natural because we're continuing to invest intelligently &#x2013; 30% in 2007 of our capital will be non-producing. And that is the share that you see in yellow on the right hand side of that slide.</p>
          <p>So I think what is also important, and that is also a part of the success story behind our strategy, we try to find a good balance between sharing the rent between ourselves and the producing countries. It's clear that &#x2013; clearly it's rather unpleasant to have our share reduced as was the case in Venezuela, but when the price rises to $90 per barrel, you can't hope as an oil company to keep all of the rent. So what we try and do is to maintain a reasonable balance rather than a confrontation. And I'm not referring to anyone in particular, but that good balanced strategy contributes to a successful growth strategy.</p>
          <p>The dividend Robert has referred to that in some detail, this is just to give you another way of looking at it. You can see the sensitivity on the cash flow of Brent refining margins and so on and so forth. As far as production growth is fairly aggressive for 2008, higher than world demand, higher than that of the other majors.</p>
          <p>On the payout ratio, I think we have a position to maintain a competitive pay-out policy as Robert has pointed out earlier on. Here you have in euro the payout. The payout is slightly lower than 40%, 39% to be precise. And I very much hope that if the results are good in 2008, we shall be able to maintain that strategy in the long term. We wish to focus as a natural priority on the dividend, after investment, rather than buying back share. This is something we have announced and this is something I think which clearly comes through from these graphs.</p>
          <p>The final slide, I would like to have commented on this a little more detail, because it's very interesting but it takes a little more time than what we have. I'd like to insist on one or two points. First of all, the supply/demand tension, I think we've referred to this on several occasions. I think, we are the only &#x2013; one of the majors to stick our necks out on this. The rise in oil prices is not only due to speculation as some people have claimed but also to major underlying trends. And that imbalance in supply and demand, when one looks at the balance in supply and demand, we have to look at alternative energies, as Philippe Boisseau has referred to, which will be on top of our fossil energy business, which will remain most of our business in the next years to come.</p>
          <p>But you can see that we must also do our part to fight against climate change. That is the reason for our research and development policy that is our reason for doing a lot on energy efficiency that has a lot &#x2013; that is why we are involved in CO2 sequestration and that will be good for the group and good for the profitability of the group. We will only remain profitable if we implement policies, which are both accepted and acceptable. So we have to have an eye on our civic duty but we also have to have an eye on our financial duty. And I think those two things are not incompatible.</p>
          <p>Far from it, it's necessary to go ahead on those two fronts together. So, I think as our strategic response to the long term is concerned, you know about that; technology, research and development proved that we have a strategic response to the long term. Integrated gas projects, as Philippe pointed out with LNG projects, another resource based on the mix, quite apart from the issue of gas and oil, you have to be able to meet demand for fuels and we are thinking a great deal about how to give priority to oil for fuels but use perhaps other feed stocks for petrochemicals.</p>
          <p>In other words to be able to replace crude oil in other areas, like petrochemicals and that's what Francois has shown in Belgium, something which is very new for us in this form. TOTAL is also very clearly interested in trying to reduce demand, that may seem somewhat contradictory for the run-of-the-mill capitalist but we're not run-of-the-mill capitalists. We have to produce products which make it possible to consume less. And that doesn't necessarily mean growth, it means taking market share and Michel has understood that when he talked about marketing.</p>
          <p>Attain critical mass in new high-tech energies, Philippe Boisseau referred to that. I would perhaps qualify a little bit what he said about profitability. We certainly expect it to be profitable in the long term but solar energy is not likely to have a similar profitability to exploration and production and the other businesses of this company but we have to get there and as all &#x2013; in all strategic projects you need to invest initially and we do that in everything, especially in exploration and production. But clearly when you want to get into an area you have to pay the price. It won't necessarily be profitable immediately but it has to become profitable. So the message is the same but I don't think you should expect a 30% profitability on organic next year, I don't think it will happen next year but you never know.</p>
          <p>And as far as the energy arbitrage, gas, oil versus coal, nuclear this is a debate in which we are very heavily involved as Philippe has said that doesn't necessarily mean that we are going to rush headlong into business which is not our business today but it not something that we can simply ignore.</p>
          <p>So if that model of growth, which is basically sustainable growth. That's what sustainable growth is all about. And this is what we have tried to show you this morning with our results for 2007, our plans for the future and on that basis I believe that we shall continue to generate sustainable growth, generating competitive and good return for our shareholders, while ensuring the long-term future of this company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And it's now time for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />. You didn't mention the chemical specialties, does that mean that there is no news or that it's not a strategic issue for you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, maybe we could dwell on specialties a little bit longer. While I did mention them, just to say that the performance in 2007 was appreciable insofar as our growth rate was significant, 10% in methanization, 6% Hutchinson, 4.5% in adhesives, so a satisfactory growth rate. And it's also important to say that all our specialties are putting profitability in excess of 10%. So we'll continue our strategy, which consists in focusing on our strengths and over time we will be, let's say, making our portfolio less diversified than it is now while continuing to be equally profitable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> First question on production growth, because your production growth is very high, again announced over 2 or 3%, at what price per barrel would that be, leaving aside Nigeria? Second question, concerning your profitability rate, it used to be a minimum of 11%. Are we still talking about an internal rate of return of 11%? And my third question is on Saudi Arabia, are you withdrawing from gas &#x2013; well, you have withdrawn for gas but shell is still involved, what is the situation there? We will led to understand that the idea behind gas was to have relations with Saudi Arabia, particularly with a view that you buy a refinery, what are we conclude about your withdrawal from gas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Your first question concerning production. I clearly will want to avoid discussions such as, well, it will come from <mark type="inaudible" /> or whatever. We have all our projects there working towards our growth. There can be mishaps from time to time here and there, but fundamentally our position is based on about $80. It is difficult to believe that oil prices will drop to $60 in 2008, particularly in view of the &#x2013; what's happened from the start of the year, clearly the underlying assets are there, we want our projects to start-up on time.</p>
          <p>Now Nigeria well, we'll see. Unfortunately, we do not have full control over the situation in Nigeria. We can make mistakes as we have in the past in terms of communications. I think we've sometimes quoted figures that were too specific and we've made a mistake, but we are going to avoid being too specific about figures. We have to with investments, but with production not so, I think our projects will be what they'll be. We'll try to avoid any additional unnecessary mishaps.</p>
          <p>Now profitability 11%, it's very, very close to that figure, but as I said this is in constant currency rates. Saudi Arabia, I think one of our strengths is the fact we do things when we feel it's the right time to do them. We also discontinue when we feel that it's appropriate to do so. When we withdrew after three dry wells &#x2013; unfortunately, the three wells that were dry and our geologist, experts and geophysicists concluded that unfortunately, even though the deposits are huge, unless we were to drill a very, very large number of wells, we'd have very little chance of finding a lot of gas. So in our, as we usually do, we simply explained to our partners that we also have a big, refining project not far away, which is of great importance to us, I think it's important to say we are withdrawing but that doesn't mean that it wasn't on a friendly basis.</p>
          <p>I think the Saudis understood that very, very well. Now, they would have a different point of view because they are in their homeland, so it's always interesting for them to have better understanding of their subsoil. We are not in the same situation. It's a question of when to stop, when to back down.</p>
          <p>So exploration yes, but not exploration for the sake of making people happy. Either you explore to keep your partners happy, unless they have a different analysis of their geology. Well, I leave up to you to ask them which of those two it would be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> If I can come back to the Erika lawsuit, there's something I didn't really understand, does this mean that the so called fact that you were condemned severely because you were maybe bigger and richer, does that mean that your partners, if your partners do not honor their commitments, does this mean that you would have to pay everything or is that a misunderstanding?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would doubt very much if you misunderstand anything. We are jointly and severely liable. According to the judgment this may or may not come to pass, or come into being. It so happens that the judgment of the different people ruled against is different and we are less &#x2013; sanctions against us is not as big, but because we are jointly severally liable, it's true that TOTAL will act as deep pocket in the situation because we have deep pockets, but I'm sure that's not very surprising. But lately speaking, that's it. But when, if that's the case, the claimants can now claim compensation from any of the so called severally and jointly liable parties, in which case it would be up to TOTAL to then file a case against the other parties involved or the other parties ruled against. I find our presentation absolutely exemplary about really talking to our financial communications people there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> I had a question about your CapEx, you said you're keeping a very close watch on costs, but in the downstream segment you have a number of big investments in 2008 and 2009. Could it be said that your CapEx budget has peaked and based on that, what about your expected production? In view of your projected production at what stage will you be generating positive free cash flow? I have a further question on Nigeria; could you give us an update on the situation in Nigeria, both in terms of onshore aspects given the assets that a number of your peers have depreciated, and how the contracts have evolved as it is seen from <mark type="inaudible" /> point of view?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll answer the first question and then Yves-Louis will take the second question. First of all, don't forget what I was saying earlier on, as regards cost. With the exception of new projects who are by definition, as in the case of Port Arthur for instance, can costs, that's rolled under past costs, new investments are about at the time they were decided, then you have to discipline your spending and keep them through this costs. We've costs on projects that were decided upon back in 2002, '03 and '04, even in 2006, there are fewer these days. There is a lag effect definitely, but concerning the fundamental part of your question, as I said earlier on, yes, we continue to be very, very tuned to the fact that projects stick to budget, even for lump sum projects that may seem curious but it is nonetheless quite a feat to be able to keep to budget.</p>
          <p>Contractors have taken advantage of the market and from time to time, I know some people don't always approve of what I say on issues like these, but sometimes the oil companies are held hostage, particularly towards the end of the contract period. Sometimes we are told either you give us a little more or we'll simply delay the start-up of your project, of your production project. I can assure you that that happens. But we try to avoid finding ourselves in that type of vulnerable situation. And secondly, we ensure that once the project is up and running, it sticks to budget. But still we have the issue of how to avoid being, having a pressure bought down on us by the market. Now, the explanation will be quite complex and lengthy, but we need to talk more with our contractors to find ways and means of ensuring that money is not wasted and unfortunately, in some cases, my fear is that the money will not be in the pocket of the oil companies but rather in the pockets of the contractors, which is a little bit of a problem.</p>
          <p>Broadly speaking, I want all our projects to bear in mind new cost and decision investments &#x2013; or  investment decisions rather are all based on profitability, which hinges on these same costs. Now there is no magic formula, it varies from one project to another. As I said, the internal rate of return is not constant from one project to another. It varies from one of our projects to the next.</p>
          <p>Okay, on Nigeria. We have worked on production hypothesis for 2008 that are quite cautious. Now admittedly at the end of 2007, the recovery of production capacity to the west of the Niger or west of the Niger Delta actually exceeded our expectations at the time. We recovered more than we thought we would. A number of incidents that you referred to, the bursting of a gas pipeline, which was a case of a force majeure, an act of God, but up till now most of the incidents enable us to stay within the limits of the hypothesis we've worked on.</p>
          <p>As for the contracts being renegotiated, it's true that the Nigerian authorities have asked that certain production sharing contracts be renegotiated. Most of our contracts are associations, a formal association with the National Oil Company, which counts its share of expenditure be it operating costs or CapEx while deducting its share of production. Now, these contracts, which are autonomous, 93 contracts are not a cause of concern.</p>
          <p>Your final question concerned provisions booked by a number of our peers. As I understand it, this is largely due to problems funding other contracts. These would be concession and association contracts. But we have no late payments that would push us to book any such provisions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd like to come back to a comparison you drew earlier on, sorry, my name is <mark type="inaudible" />. The comparison you drew earlier on between yourselves and the other majors. I think the fact that you outperformed them in a number of areas is very much to your credit. You've maintained CapEx at a very high level even eight years ago when crude oil prices considerably saw the Anglo-Saxon majors reduce their CapEx. I would however like to point out that this comparison only goes so far, particularly when you make a very detailed comparison as you did with Exxon, particularly in upstream CapEx. I think the only conclusion you would be justified in drawing from this comparison is the one that gives you a marginal result in terms of savings. At Exxon size every extra dollar invested has less impact than an oil major of TOTAL size. Now Exxon's rational, whereby it's better to buyback its own shares, it's something that you might well have if you reach Exxon's size, it must be put into the context of size.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that's your conclusion. When we reach Exxon's size that would be something to celebrate. I am sure you'll have noticed that we haven't criticized Exxon and in fact Exxon is often ahead of us in the charts we show. So we lay no claims to be better than Exxon, we simply say that our strategy is different, but I don't think these choices are determined by size and when you talk about the idea of buying back shares or not, I think it's a case of capacity and I think if Exxon had deposits that enabled it to invest more, it would. It's buying back shares or they are buying back shares because &#x2013; I don't know how many billions they have in cash &#x2013; the debt level is negative, but you have to do something with that cash. But first of all, we are in admiration at the way Exxon manages its projects, we're simply saying &#x2013; I mean, its probably more difficult for a big major to find new business because you have to invest more and its not a good time to be investing. Briefly, as were quite right to point out, they do not have the same stabilization policy as we have had and they have been fluctuating, the so-called yo-yo effect so to speak.</p>
          <p>But as for other issues, I think that we have simply decided to go for profitable investments because this is how we can add value to the company for our shareholders and while buying back shares is not a bad idea when you have no other projects, in fact, it tends to have a very positive immediate and accretive effect on earnings per share, but that's not the way to manage a good future. But to finish on this particular point, I hope that some day we're as big and beautiful as Exxon, but I think we could do that without buying back capital.</p>
          <p>I remember a very, very big company called Exxon some time ago, which was actually much bigger than anybody else when compared to the rest of the world, relatively speaking and over and beyond the absolute values. I don't remember that at the time they bought back their shares, but as you say, that was another period and we did differently in those days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd like to come back for a second on your disposal, the disposal of a 0.4%stake in Sanofi. Was this just to show that it's not a core business? You don't need the money, you sold your stake at a price that was below your expectations. What are we to expect? As you're more dividend driven than buyback driven, well, you know, a few years ago you used to say we will sell Sanofi to buy TOTAL, so is there any sign of that rearing its head again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I was expecting that question. In fact, if we hadn't disposed of some of our stake it would have been worse. But now you are telling us, now, you've done it just be able to say you did it. That's what you wanted to hear. Okay?</p>
          <p>Yes, we did it. We disposed of that stake, particularly as we believe in that. We didn't do that to keep our analysts or shareholders happy. We disposed of part of our stake in Sanofi because we felt it would be appropriate to gradually sell some of our stake, because it's not part of our core business as you said. And secondly, we've no urgent need of cash, so no urgency there. And secondly, the share price, the Sanofi share price is not as high as we would have liked. That's also true of the TOTAL share price by the way.</p>
          <p>But it's an interesting question. Clearly, if we felt that our &#x2013; we feel that if our share price is very low, it could be worthwhile to dispose of Sanofi shares at a very low price to buyback TOTAL shares at a price that is below what it should be. So, that's the financial rationale when we apply, but that doesn't mean we are going to change our overall strategy. Our overall strategy is not to sell our stake in Sanofi in bulk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just an accounting question, if I may add to that. At what level would you have to de-consolidate Sanofi? There is a certain restriction there, is it another 1%? At what level of capital ownership?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With a 13% stake with voting rights that brings it to almost 20%. Assuming we have a certain degree of, a certain leeway in reducing our stake while continuing to consider Sanofi an equity affiliate. So, I think at 14, 15% of our voting rights, particularly in view of the group's involvement, we should be able to continue to account for Sanofi by the equity method. That however would not be the main reason behind our strategic decisions in this particular area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> has asked; you have announced a substantial increase in your CapEx budget, up 25% in fact, but through Sanofi and your disposal of Sincor and Kashagan; there are a number of disposals and divestments in the offing, which will offset these acquisitions. Have you got a budget for this? And secondly, another question; last year you announced, at the same time of the year, in fact that a particular project would be starting up very, very soon. It's mentioned in some slides but not in others. Could you tell us more about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the Usan project. No, we haven't voluntarily disposed of a share of our holding in Kashagan or in Sincor, but we can make that involvement smart. We can ensure that we get good compensation, and that the remaining investment is worthwhile for the group, particularly as we continue to be involved in countries where there's considerable upside for the group.</p>
          <p>These investments will resume sooner or later in the future if we want to reach 95 or $100 million a day, but I'm not going to give you a lecture on that. That should be very basic. But if these projects don't materialize then we'll even start asking questions about the 95 mark. It's very difficult to have a budget on things that you don't anticipate. I'm not going to ask Yves-Louis to come up with a budget for disposals or divestments in West Africa, for instance. He is forbidden from even thinking about that. When these situations arise we talk about them, but there is no budget.</p>
          <p>We'll be paying a little more for Kashagan, but that wasn't the plan. We were perfectly prepared to fully fund our share; particularly as it wouldn't have any great impact on our 2008 budget. Kashagan, on the 2008 budget is almost negligible. Of course, we have a share, but not a very sizeable one. While Sincor was the outcome of negotiations, but we felt that we should include it in the highlights as a positive highlight; 30% compensated. We felt this was a good deal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Usan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is not in the slides anymore. Usan is not in the slides, it's mentioned in 2010 as one of the projects being developed. For Usan, three of the main contracts have already been approved, and we're well underway with the fourth contract. In fact only yesterday, to comply with the rules, we withdrew this from the presentation because it's in the offing. All the parties have approved, it's just to be put before the authorities. That's the way it is for the fourth project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd like to ask you two questions. First of all, your projects, even if they are longer-term projects on nuclear energy, I am not exactly sure what role you could play in any significant way because you don't manufacture the hardware; you are not an engineering company; so the only thing you could possibly do would be to provide some kind of engineering consultancy, unless, of course, you wish to be involved in the production of electricity. So could you tell us exactly what the outline of your longer-term projects would be in nuclear energy? And then a more short-term issue, the share price of Elf Gabon, your subsidiary, has gone down quite a lot recently. Is there any reason for that change in the assets controlled by that subsidiary?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yves-Louis, could you answer about Gabon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. On Gabon, this is Yves-Louis Darricarr&#xE8;re I think the main issue is the redevelopment of the Anguille field, which was started up in 1966 and as I said earlier on in my presentation under the resource upgrading project that we're continuing to implement, there is of course changes in technology, changes in prices, our knowledge of the region and we have a fairly sound project of redeveloping Anguille &#x2013; $2 billion CapEx project, that we shall be launching fairly soon. That being said, the rest of the Gabon subsidiary is witnessing a decline in production and the redevelopment of Anguille will enable us to offset that declining production for a few years. And then as far as the share price is concerned, we don't determine the share price and it tends to be fairly volatile on the basis of oil prices. Some experts have said that the oil price is heading downwards and I think TOTAL Gabon share price has been impacted by that, as is the case with all companies which are entirely upstream companies rather than being insulated companies.</p>
          <p>On nuclear energy, our policy on nuclear energy is basically to look at the situation and to see how we could prepare to enter into nuclear energy. We have no strategy to invest directly in nuclear, as an operator we don't have the capacity, nor the human resources to do that. But there are a lot of things we don't do one year and we do other years. Deep shore, deep offshore is not what we were doing thirty years ago. Solar energy is not something &#x2013; well, we've been in solar energy for quite some time but on a very, very small scale, but we ought to be able to bring new businesses into TOTAL over time, but this is not any decision which is right today and that's why we are looking at this in association with the experts who know about this business, and who have the teams to explore it. We shall in the fullness of time decide whether we can become a player in that area and in that business or not. But as you say, it's far too premature for us to take a decision on that today, and I can't therefore answer that question more specifically because we have no decisions to take nor decisions which we've taken. We'll need to give it another four or five years before we can see more clearly. When one looks however at the prospects for nuclear energy in the context of the supply demand balance, in spite of all the problems that nuclear energy generates it's one of the sources of energy which will certainly be part and parcel of the sources of available energy in the future and that's why TOTAL must look at it, but TOTAL is not looking at it in any concrete way at this stage. We're a little pressed for time and we're running out of it, in fact. It's our fault to a certain extent, but is there one final question or two final questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> once again. You didn't give us very much news about the affairs booked in 2007 in your resource renewal program, what are the new businesses or the new fields that you are expecting to launch in 2008 and 2009 and the corollary to that, could you tell us something about the heavy oil project in Canada?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sure I can answer the first part of your question and Yves-Louis will answer your question on Canada. As far as 2007 is concerned, Sincor is clearly the field, but that wasn't budgeted, it's a non recurrent issue and we're not going to find another project which covers our shortfall in Sincor. That would certainly not go down well with <mark type="inaudible" /> and that's not the way we manage this company, so it is and should be considered as an exceptional event which is the result of a contract renegotiation. The projects which are not yet booked, I mean you have a list of them that Yves-Louis presented to you in his presentation, but we only book our projects of course when the final investment decision has been taken. The FID, the Final Investment Decision. There's a list of them there. Australia, exists, the projects in the Gulf of Guinea, a whole series of projects which are not yet under development and which will come into our bookable reserves as they progress.</p>
          <p>Perhaps your question was the relationship &#x2013; the ratio between exploration and new fields. Yes, okay. If that was what your question was, you saw that in my slide in the rate of renewable reserves, but between the time when the reserves were identified, valued and booked, some considerable time elapses, and we have to look at the project for some time before the final investment decision is taken. A lot of our renewal comes from reserves which were linked to new fields. When we booked Elf in LNG, for instance, most of that comes from exploration. In the pipeline however, and looking at it over the longer-term, when we decide on the final investment decision on Shtokman, then the reserves will be booked and that will be a new business.</p>
          <p>So if you look at the entry to the pipeline, Christophe mentioned that there were $2 billion of potential reserves which were contributed by our performances in 2007; 1 billion from exploration, which will be booked later of course, and 1 billion from new business including Shtokman. And today basically, it's 50-50; 50 exploration, 50 new business, the business is a third type. And to match Shtokman, we have to find a new project and that's something that we've been doing for some years now.</p>
          <p>But there was another question that you asked on Canada and the heavy oil business in Canada. It's going to be a little lengthy for a last question. As you know, we have two projects and the upgrading project. First of all the Surmont project where we have 50%, Phase I, which was 27,000 barrels per day, we have 50% of that, 27,000 barrels per day that is in production since the end of 2006. And we're ramping up and that ramping up is going well. We are drilling the wells at the moment and the drilling operations are going well. The second phase, which is 83,000 barrels per day in plateau for 100% output and there, the design and pre-project studies are completed and we shall be starting in 2008 to do the engineering surveys and part of the basic engineering.</p>
          <p>We should give the final go ahead to that project in the third quarter of 2009. And then there will be a third phase of 90,000 barrels per day. And we're in the process of starting up the design studies for an FID in 2012, something of that kind. All these projects amount to 200,000 barrels of oil per day, when they are ramped up, and we have 50%. But the operator, ConocoPhillips, thinks, and we share that view, that there is a higher potential there. The second project, and we are an operator there, Joslyn there are two mines. The northern one, 100,000 barrels per day, and there we are in the pre-project studies. We should be starting the engineering work in 2008. Again, the FID will be for the third quarter of 2009. And then there is what we call the southern and western mines, 100,000 barrels per day, a potential 100%, and we are in the process of starting up the initial design studies in 2008. Parallel to that, we have a third component to these projects in Canada, which is the upgrader, and there we have upgraded 250,000 barrels per day in the first phase. And we are in the process of looking at the pre-project studies &#x2013; they're completed by the way &#x2013; and we are in the process of starting the basic engineering. There, again, the FID will be some time in 2009. And all that, of course, is consistent with the other projects. And there will be undoubtedly a second phase of the upgrader of slightly less than 100,000 barrels a day. Just to give a copy of your notes. One final question, and then we can close the meeting and answer some questions more informally over a glass of whatever.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you talk about Venezuela, the fact that the Sincor has been there &#x2013; is no longer in the portfolio, but I believe a new more long-term project is to be signed. Now, what are we to expect in terms of future results? What generation are we talking about? How can this be developed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, very clearly, when we decide to remain in Venezuela, it's for the future there. Not saying we're going to invest a very substantial amount in Venezuela, as things stand I think we need to see how <mark type="inaudible" /> the new mixed economy company is going to do. But for quite some time, we've been looking at an exploration zone that is right beside the area where the former Sincor project was located. And this is an area that should in due course enable us to develop new reserves, which will either complete the Sincor reserves or be a source of new upgrader projects or enable us to work on dilution but non-upgraded heavy oils. To increase Venezuela's production more rapidly &#x2013; that's what we're working on. It's right beside our existing fields. We know the geology of the area very well, but we're really only in the very early stages. I think we need more data if we are to analyze the situation properly before deciding to work on a 50,000 barrels a day project. But in all events, this will be within a restricted call for tenders. So admittedly, the figure is now 30. But that doesn't mean that in the years to come, we won't be looking at other areas of Venezuela. It would be a pity to leave Venezuela and to leave room for our competitors. So there you go, once again, we're focusing on the long-term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, all. Thank you all for attending. We apologize for being a bit lengthy. But this is the price we have to pay for trying to give you a very complete presentation. Time for a drink now, if you'd like. We'd be very pleased to take any other questions that you have over a drink. Thank you. Meeting adjourned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>