<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1226678" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-06</date>
    <companies>
      <company>596</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Patrick de la Chevardi&#xE8;re, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2">Theepan Jothilingam</participant>
      <participant id="3">Patrick de la Chevardi&#xE8;re</participant>
      <participant id="4">Jon Rigby</participant>
      <participant id="5">Mark Gilman</participant>
      <participant id="6">Lydia Rainforth</participant>
      <participant id="7">Jason Kenney</participant>
      <participant id="8">Paul Spedding</participant>
      <participant id="9">Lucas Hermann</participant>
      <participant id="10">Neill Morton</participant>
      <participant id="11">Irene Himona</participant>
      <participant id="12">Robert Kessler</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Total First Quarter 2009 Results Conference Call. I'll now hand over to Mr. Patrick de la Chevardi&#xE8;re, Chief Financial Officer. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This is Patrick speaking. And as usual, I will comment rapidly on the first quarter results, plus some insight, and then go to the Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter 2009, the environment was weak with the drop in the oil price and weak demand for refined products and chemicals. From that perspective, our performance was very resilient and good relative to our peers.</p>
          <p>Adjusted net income was $2.8 billion, a decrease of 44% compared to the first quarter of 2008, and 27% compared to the fourth quarter. Earning per share was $1.23 per share, a decrease of 43% compared to the first quarter of 2008 and 27 compared to the fourth quarter. Among the other major oils, BP, Chevron, Exxon and Shell, earnings per share declined on average by 60% year-on-year and 40% compared to the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>In terms of profitability, the ROACE for the past 12 months was 24%, and the annualized third quarter ROACE was about 15%. This is clearly at the best level, when you compare to our peers. In this weak environment, it shows the strength and the sustainability of our model.</p>
          <p>In times like this, we are focused on managing our cash and gearing. Excluding acquisitions, CapEx was $3.6 billion, in line with Q1 of last year. Asset sales were close to $500 million, mainly from selling Sanofi shares. Free cash flow after CapEx and asset sales was $2 billion.</p>
          <p>We did not make any buy backs in the first quarter. As a result, our gearing at the end of the first quarter was 19% compared to the 23% at the end of the fourth quarter. We issue bonds three times during the first quarter, raising more than $4 billion to refinance some debt at attractive rates in the current environment and for longer maturities.</p>
          <p>Another point is that the in the Fall in the stock market on our pension plans is not significant, less than 100 million euro of an overall cash contribution in 2009. Our exposure to the U.S. and UK is limited, and in fact, most of our pension assets have been invested in bonds.</p>
          <p>Now, I will make some brief comments on each segment. In the Upstream segment, the average Brent price fell by 20% to $44.5 per barrel, and our average hydrocarbon realization including natural gas fell by 18% to $38.8 per barrel of oil equivalent. We have low exposure to the U.S. and this works to our advantage clearly in term of natural gas prices.</p>
          <p>Compared to Q4 2008, our adjusted net operating income from the Upstream segment decreased by 27% to $1.9 billion, mainly due to the price decrease. Compared to usual measures our Upstream portfolio is resilient.</p>
          <p>Our net income per barrel of oil equivalent is at the best level and our Upstream ROACE was 31.2% for the past 12 months and 17.5% on the annualized basis which is also amongst the best.</p>
          <p>Another positive point is our exploration success, which is key to our organic growth strategy. Exploration expenses were $226 million in the first quarter, a decrease compared to the same quarter of last year and also to the previous quarter. Also we slightly spent less money, we were in fact very successful in terms of finding new reserves. We have just announced the discovery of Moho Nord in offshore Congo that is close to being a new giant field.</p>
          <p>In addition, we have made other discoveries, but they are not public yet, notably in South America and North Africa.</p>
          <p>Operationally, production was down by 1.4% or about 30,000 barrels per day compared to the fourth quarter 2008. The main reason is OPEC cuts. The impact on us was 90,000 barrels per day in the first quarter compared to 15,000 barrels per day in the fourth quarter 2008, a comparative decrease of 75,000 barrels per day. So the OPEC cuts alone represent a decrease of more than 3%.</p>
          <p>I should remind you that on average these are not high margin barrels. It is important to note that the impact on net operating income from the OPEC cuts was less than $50 million. There were many other items positive and negative that had a combined effect of increasing production by about 1.5%. Mainly these were the price effect for us and the line growth of ramp-ups and the re-start of Al Jurf in Libya.</p>
          <p>What can we expect to go in. In March, we started up the Akpo field in Nigeria which is expected to reach plateau position of 225,000 barrels per day late this summer. Second quarter maintenance compared to the first quarter will be seasonally higher and include a 30-day shutdown of Alwyn.</p>
          <p>We have just announced the start up of Tahiti and in the coming weeks we should have Yemen LNG. And later this year, we should have Tombua Landana and Qatargas II. So, excluding the OPEC cuts, I am confident about extreme position volumes. In addition to new start-ups in 2009, we are continuing to secure opportunities for future growth. Last month, we announced a deal with Cobalt to jointly explore the deep Gulf of Mexico. Cobalt has an established track record of discoveries in the deep Gulf; they will operate the exploration phase. We have five very interesting sub-salt prospects and we will begin drilling this year.</p>
          <p>This has also been a good quarter for us in terms of existing position. We signed a very important 20-year extension for Gasco in Abu Dhabi. We also renewed contracts in Libya and signed a 10-year extension for concessions in Argentina. And also, we signed a head of agreements with Japanese buyers to extend some contracts for Bontang LNG.</p>
          <p>Of course, we do not get everything that we go after. I'm referring to our bid for UTS in Canada. At the end of the offer period, we did not have the participation that we wanted. This was our last and final bid, so we close it. This is proof that we are consistent with our discipline.</p>
          <p>The Upstream segment is strong; we have a high quality portfolio in producing assets that were developed when oil price were below 50. You may recall from our presentations in February that our cost per barrel of oil equivalent is already is the lowest among the majors. Nonetheless, we have launched a major cost reduction program in the Upstream. We can already see the first effects on &#x2013; of lower price for materials and services on our cost as well as the effect of our own efforts.</p>
          <p>Our first quarter 2009 OpEx as per FAS 69 has decreased by more than $1 per barrel of oil equivalent compared to the average of last year. We should be able to give you more details on our progress when we report on the second quarter. So I am confident again that the Upstream is adapting to this environment and facing the challenge.</p>
          <p>Now I will comment on the Downstream and the Chemicals. The main point is that weak demand in the first quarter had a severe negative impact. Downstream net operating income was $0.8 billion down 23% from the fourth quarter. The fourth quarter included the lag effect on the marketing sign that we did not have in the first quarter and this exaggerated the decrease.</p>
          <p>The TRCV margin indicator was down 16%, throughput volume were down by 6% mainly because of higher turnaround for maintenance and our decision to shut down the Port Arthur refinery in March because of very depressed margins on the Gulf Coast. These negative effects were somewhat balanced by good resistance of marketing and a strong heating oil season plus very favorable market conditions for supply optimization at the beginning of the quarter that increased net operating income by more than $100 million compared to the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>Chemicals, however, were hit even harder than downstream. Chemicals had a net operating loss of $42 million in the first quarter compared to net operating income of $233 million in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Base chemical margins fell below breakeven mainly due to a lack of demand. Normally the contribution from our specialties would provide some cover but our specialties are leveraged to automobiles and construction so they also suffered from weak demand.</p>
          <p>We are consolidating our refining and base chemicals and contemplating our activities at our best sites. In March, we announced plans to invest more than a billion euro to upgrade our refining and petrochemical in France.</p>
          <p>As part of this plan, we will reduce gasoline production by eliminating four million ton a year of European distillation capacity when we close down some units and further upgrade others at the Normandy refinery.</p>
          <p>In January, we started up what is now one of Europe's largest and most efficient styrene units at our facility in Gonfreville after a very significant revamping and expansion program.</p>
          <p>On the corporate side, at the Annual General Meeting next week, we expect the shareholders to approve the 1.14 euro per share remainder of the 2008 dividend for payment on May 22. The ex-dividend date for the ordinary share is May 19, and the ex-dividend date for the ADR is May 14. If we annualize the first quarter results and consider the 2008 dividend, this will imply a payout ratio of about 60%, and yield is currently above 6%. It is important to note that in the first quarter Total was net cash flow positive after CapEx and after a theoretical dividend allocation to the quarter.</p>
          <p>On CapEx, the budget for this year is $18 billion. Falling costs and potential project delays may allow us to spend less; however, there could be new opportunities to add. But I can tell you now, that we are working hard to optimize the development cost of all our pending projects. I think we will be able to do more with less. We will provide an update in September.</p>
          <p>Since the end of the quarter, oil prices are situated around $50 per barrel, slightly higher than first quarter of 2009. Refining margins are depressed in Europe and Chemicals continue to suffer with weak demand and low margins. While we do not know how long it will take for the global economy to recover from this recession, we are pursuing a strategy to emerge from this period as an even stronger player.</p>
          <p>More than ever, we are prudent and very disciplined. We are implementing cost reduction programs and will continue to divest non-core assets. We will invest through the low end of the cycle to capture good opportunities. Our intent is to maintain gearing in the 20-30% range, and we are committed to the dividend.</p>
          <p>And now, I think, we can go the Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We have the first question from Mr. Theepan Jothilingam from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Theepan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a couple of questions, actually. Firstly, with the expiry of the &#x2013; of your offer for UTS, I wondered if you could make some comments on sort of what the next milestones are in developing your heavy oil business in Canada?</p>
          <p>Secondly, just in terms of &#x2013; I think, you talked about maintenance in the Upstream for Q2. I was just wondering whether you could give any indications on what you expect in the Downstream.</p>
          <p>And then, lastly, just on the corporate tax rate, with the lower oil prices &#x2013; clearly, that's been coming down. At a sort of $50 environment for this year what do you &#x2013; what would you sort of anticipate that tax rate to be? Would you &#x2013; are we looking around the 52% mark? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. First question about our Canadian strategy. I mean, what's happened to UTS is &#x2013; it's over. We continue on the Joslyn project to reengineer this project in order to mitigate costs and in order to be able to make a decision to invest in this project by late, say 2010.</p>
          <p>On Surmont Phase II, we are working together with the operator in order also to reduce costs. Basically, I would say that our overall objective is to produce by 2020 something like 250,000 barrels per day in this area of the world. That was for the Canadian question.</p>
          <p>On the maintenance, in Upstream for second quarter, usually the second quarter maintenance is <mark type="inaudible" /> maintenance in the first quarter as you know. On top of that, as I mentioned in my speech, there will be the shut down of Alwyn and those are I think the two elements you should consider.</p>
          <p>On Downstream maintenance, I think we have two refineries having some maintenance, of course, during the second quarter, namely Donges and sorry I don't remember the other one, and Lindsey in the UK.</p>
          <p>For the corporate tax rate in this $50 per barrel environment, I think you were right with the assumption you made in Q1 it was due &#x2013; this fall of tax rate was due to the fall of the oil price. When the oil price is lower, the tax rate is lower. And your estimate of the potential tax rate of the group was correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The following question is from Mr. Jon Rigby from UBS. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Patrick. It's Jon Rigby from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Two questions. First is on the Downstream. Can you go into a bit more detail, characterize what the exit conditions were in March or perhaps even just sort of compare January to March, so we get a better idea for the shape of the quarter was in the Downstream around your TRCV and marketing performance?</p>
          <p>And the second question is it goes back to the comments you made about start-ups and confidence for the outlook on production. I mean obviously, your production's been up and down, positive and negative and a lot of that's been impacted by OPEC and maintenance issues et cetera. But also one of the key drivers is obviously your ability to drive growth above decline. So do you see that growth above decline or new additions above decline increasing significantly over the next three quarters i.e., the controllable element of your Upstream business improving? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Your first question about defining margin. What we saw during the first quarter is that in January and February we had pretty good margin and let's say between 40 and $50 per ton TRCV, so pretty good margin. And both margin were falling completely in March down to another rate of about $15 per ton. So this gives us you the shape of the curve. Coming back on the production, something you have to keep in mind is that on this first quarter we have no start-up production. Akpo started in April. The second comment I would make is that you know that we are more exposed to OPEC than the others. If I look at our program of launching project in 2009 this year, we should be able to beat the decline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And then we can make our own minds up about OPEC effects etcetera, etcetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, OPEC is decided by the oil and then the sheiks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Keep in mind also that when we were cut by 90,000 barrels per day by OPEC this quarter, this only had an effect of $50 million on the bottom line because those margins &#x2013; those barrels are low margin barrels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Useful number, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mr. Mark Gilman from Benchmark Company. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick, good afternoon. I had a couple of questions. First, with respect to the downstream restructuring which you referenced in France, it has almost seemed to me, given the government's rather harsh reaction to this announcement that there may be some quid pro quo with respect to your involvement in &#x2013; your involvement with Electricit&#xE9; de France in the nuclear power segment. Is that an accurate characterization of the way the relationship with the government is working?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, when we decide our restructuring and modernization of our refining and petrochem sector we decide it on our own, and that's it. This had nothing to do with any approval &#x2013; prior approval by the government. Of course, when the decision was made we make the announcement to the government so that it is aware of. But we were not asking for any approval for that. And our participation in the nuclear power plant, it is a first move of a long-term strategy which is to try and step-by-step increase our exposure to this nuclear sector.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me follow-up if I could with just two others. Could you give me an idea where things stand with respect to the negotiations to extend the East Kalimantan concession in Indonesia? Also could you address the liquefied natural gas, LNG realizations which you had during the quarter, either in absolute terms or relative to prior periods? Thanks Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean &#x2013; for the &#x2013; with the extension of the Mahakam we have started the discussion. I remind you that the expiry date is late 2017, so we have time to discuss that, and I think there was a first initial talk started in 2007 if I well remember. I think so things are going smoothly in that respect, and I am not particularly concerned about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the LNG price realizations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me &#x2013; that's a difficult question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's why I asked it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You should know that for &#x2013; I'm sorry, I don't have the figure but what you should know is that for our LNG, mainly produce for instance from Bontang we have a large lag effect of, sort of, for three to four months, because all those formulas are related to old price backed quarter amounts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The lag for your other LNG deliveries and the price realizations comparable to that three to four months, say for NLNG in Nigeria?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think that is the same. There is a lag effect, but I can't tell you if it is three to four months, but there is one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mrs. Lydia Rainforth from Barclays Capital. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good afternoon, Patrick. It's Lydia Rainforth from Barclays Capital here. In terms of the cost savings, I think you mentioned $1 to barrel cost savings compared to last year, that's quite a significant saving. Can you just talk us through how you achieved that so quickly and how much further you see cost being able to come down?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, just going back to the time lag on the natural gas realizations, are you able to quantify what sort of impact that had on your Upstream profitability this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the cost reduction, I mean, the action to reduce the costs started late last year. And as, I mentioned, I think, the actual effect of the environment and our power cuts program reduction was about $1 per barrel of cost reduction. And we can measure it and we saw it in the first quarter. I can tell you that there is no one in this tower which is &#x2013; who is not working on cost reduction. Everyone is dedicated to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Second question was again on LNG realization I think what you should &#x2013; what you should know is that the average gas price this quarter &#x2013; the average gas price was roughly at oil parity, if you take both LNG and gas price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just going back to the cost saving data. If you've $1 per barrel so far what do you think you can achieve by the end of the year? Is it $2 per barrel, $3 per barrel, or is $1 per barrel where you think it will end up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The objective and everybody is working on this objective is to reduce the operating cost of the Upstream segment by $850 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The following question is from Mr. Jason Kenney from ING. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Patrick, Jason from ING.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just following up on an earlier question on the TRCV, you mentioned January, February, and March. You may as well give us some detail on April I suppose, if you can? And then, secondly on the equity income in affiliates and other, I can understand the Upstream, Downstream divisional bits but the corporate part of that was quite strong. I was just wondering if you could maybe give some color on that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your line was very bad actually Jason, but I understood the first question, the TRCV in April is in line with the one opportunity with one we had in March, as of today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The second part of the question was on the equity and affiliates contribution in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Break down the corporate part of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sanofi made really good results and I think that most of the equity impact we had this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What's, kind of, repeatability of that kind of support?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know we are selling Sanofi shares on a daily basis. So gradually, the impact of the Sanofi net income on our result, we go down and on top of that it is difficult for me to comment on Sanofi as I am a Board member.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I now have a question from Mr. Paul Spedding from HSBC. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I have two quick questions. Firstly, in terms of the cost cutting you are seeing coming through, is there any evidence yet that you are seeing the cost for deepwater rigs and sub-sea work beginning to come down. And the second question is on demand trends, whether you're seeing any stabilization in the weakness in demand for refined products or for chemicals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On deepwater rigs, what we see is that some contractor are able to extend the duration of their contract at a lower rate coming from about $700,000 per day, down to something like $500,000 per day.</p>
          <p>For the demand, very frankly speaking, as of today &#x2013; and I am discussing this matter with our people from the supply &#x2013; we see inventories going up, again. So it seems that the market &#x2013; there is another overflow of oil on the market currently. That's what we saw at least until late March.</p>
          <p>You should remind &#x2013; remember that the inventories are product plus oil are up to 60 days of consumption today, where OPEC target is at about 53 days of consumption. So 60 days is a very high number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in Chemicals?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And in Chemicals, currently, what we see is that the capacity is used at about 80%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Iain Reed from Macquarie. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Patrick. I have two questions. Firstly, I think, you talked in the Downstream part of your speech about supply optimization of about $100 million. Can you confirm that this is effectively a trading gain due to a contango effect, and it's &#x2013; it'd be less repeatable with a flatter oil curve, going forward?</p>
          <p>And secondly, on your LNG volumes, you had, say, a 9% decline year-on-year. Can you say what the reason for that was? Was that a function of the market or the customers not taking or were there some plant-related shutdowns?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On trading, your assessment is right about the contango and it is less capitable now. That's why we make it clear to the market, this figure was something like not normal, I would say. On LNG, the main decrease is due to Nigeria LNG because as you know there were some unrest and Nigeria LNG was not running at full capacity. That's the most of the explanation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you just say what the situation is on the &#x2013; on <mark type="inaudible" /> moment? Is it coming back up to full capacity again? Or is it still running at lower capacity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is ramping. People are working to reestablish the pipeline in order to feed the plant. It is ramping up, but it is not at full capacity today, I can't tell you how much they are today. But the ramp up is quite slow actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The following question is from Mrs. Katie Rivens for <mark type="inaudible" />. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. I just wanted to ask quickly, have you seen any knock-on delays in Qatargas train <mark type="inaudible" /> from the delays we saw in <mark type="inaudible" />. And could you give us an update of when exactly you're expecting it to come online later in the year?</p>
          <p>And secondly, just going back to sort of Downstream, what is your outlook for the European diesel margin this summer? And what's the risk of lower utilizations having a knock-on effect for potential gasoline exports to U.S. in the summer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On first question on Qatargas II, actually in Qatargas II we are still maintaining our target to have our train starting by late this year and for further detail, you should ask or to operator I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we are expecting, and we believe this start up will take place prior the end of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And on the impact for lower utilization in Europe this year, because of diesel margins, do you think that's going to have a knock-on effect for gasoline exports to the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we saw for the last figure is that actually, the gasoline demand in the U.S. was not as bad as what we initially thought, so it might be but &#x2013; I can't be sure of that. It might be that it we'll be able again to export gasoline to the U.S. But this is very premature data, and I will not rely on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then finally &#x2013; can you just confirm what your Sanofi stake stands at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're at about 8%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>10, sorry, 10%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>10, okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mr. Hermann Lucas from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick, hi. It's Lucas Herrmann actually from Deutsche Bank. A few, if I might, just going back to cost, quick to make sure I understood. Were you talking about the running rate being 850 million at the year-end, or by year-end, or were you talking about 850 being the actually achievement? And either way given you're producing about 800, 850 million barrels a day, and you're telling us that a dollar is basically what you've taken out production cost so far. The objective doesn't seem, hugely ambitions at this stage, given what you've achieved to-date.</p>
          <p>Staying on cost and the environment, CapEx, just wondered if you can give me some better guidance on the phasing of CapEx. Again, if I look at the run rate through the first quarter, it's clearly well below 18 billion for the year and given that the majority of the project drop out through the first year, or through the next three to six months. The question becomes, how realistic is 18 billion or so dollars of CapEx spend for the year as a whole at this moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On cost, the $850 million figure I believe &#x2013; I gave was for operated activity on the full year basis. On CapEx, the figure you show for first quarter '09 was the same than first quarter '08, so the realization is quite comparable to the one last year and last year we roughly match our budget, nevertheless, thanks to cost reduction and to the fact that when you want to push a cost down you take time to renegotiate the contract with the contractor. It might be that some projects will be pushed in the agenda. So intuitively, I would say that there is a probability that the overall budget is not matched but it would be for good reason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Patrick, so we should view your 850 million target as being on cost savings, as being pretty conservative at this stage, given what you've achieved to date?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Mr. Mark Gilman from Benchmark Company &#x2013; sorry. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick, just two follow-up questions, if I could. On the joint venture with Cobalt in the Gulf of Mexico, did any cash change hands as a result of the formation of that venture?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you repeat the question? Is there any what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Did any cash &#x2013; did cash change hands, either a payment by you or cash which you received in the formation of the joint venture with Cobalt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It works by carry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It works by carry. We will carry Cobalt partially on the new wells to be drilled.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How long did that carry continue or how many wells, Patrick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we have five wells to be drilled by year-end 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. One other question on Libya. Can you give me an idea what the production volume impact of the conversion to EPSA IV was based upon current producing rates and was the $500 million payment for the conversion and extension of the contract was that made in the fourth quarter or the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I ask you to refer to the IAM, because I don't have the exact figure with me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no more questions at the moment. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have a question from Mr. Neill Morton from MF Global. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. It's Neill Morton from MF Global. I've just one question left, from me, these new Venezuelan heavy oil projects, seem to be moving slowly towards a conclusion, could you perhaps give us an indication of when you expect a timing of an award, could you perhaps confirm that you are in talks with the Chinese. And also what sort of oil prices do these projects need to fly, economically? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On those Venezuelan project, I can confirm that we are in talk with some Chinese party &#x2013; the project, the partnership is a key element of the strategy of Total. So we are currently discussing with CNCP, but nothing is confirmed at that date. The agenda &#x2013; the exact agenda for this <mark type="inaudible" /> project, I'm sorry I don't know it exactly. I don't when the Venezuelan will want these licenses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you have a feel for economics, sort of oil prices required et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, this is mostly depending on oil price and we are currently making the studies to prepare the bids. So it's a little bit too early to say what will be the profitability of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll leave it there. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And I have question from Mr. Johan Terri from Terri Company. Please go ahead, sir. Mr. Terri, you have the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I didn't quite hear my name was up; I'm not used to hearing it. Are you finding that your trading activities in terms of the breaking of pogos and whether if cruder products are more profitable in these times, or are they simply been not used as a profit center but more as a defensive center in these times?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean the supply team is completely integrated in the group. It is in charge of selling the production of the group and to supply our refineries. So it has been, this quarter particularly profitable, sunk to the contango as it was mentioned by one of your predecessors, but that's it, the overall extra income made by those people was about $100 million for the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And I also had one other question on a <mark type="inaudible" /> the fluctuates rather strongly, I was wondering as to whether your firm had found its tanker position had been working to its advantage, or whether it has been in fact a trifle &#x2013; having too large a tanker position and therefore had been hurt by the current volume metric and changes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I can tell you is that I follow quite carefully, as being also in charge of the shipping, the result made by those fleets and currently it is slightly positive income. So our exposure is I would say something less than our profit on it and it is quite balanced.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I appreciate the help.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Joe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The following question is from Mrs. Irene Himona from Exane BNP. Please go ahead madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Patrick. I had a number of questions. First of all, I think you mentioned that your cost cutting applies to operated production. Could you just remind us how much of your volumes is operated?</p>
          <p>My second question concerns Argentina. I think you, referred to it in your prepared remarks. Argentina is two to 3% of your volumes, but can you say something about the financial results of your Upstream business, given the high expo taxes and low local prices.</p>
          <p>The third question concerns minorities. It's a very small number, but in Q1 there was 60%-63% drop in the minority on the P&amp;L. I wondered if there was something special or whether the trend will reverse.</p>
          <p>And my final question concerns your comments about the inorganic root to growth. In Q1 obviously, we were at low point in the energy cycle, $45 oil, loss making chemicals. You ended up with securing below your targeted range. 13 billion of cash, you are delivering free cash flow. I mean, can you just remind us of your criteria for M&amp;A in terms of portfolio GAAPs, potential size and hurdle rates. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Your first question about cost cutting, we are operating about 50% of our production. I move directly to the inorganic growth as you call it. Currently, we are facing a world where many people are still thinking in a world of $80 plus per barrel scenario, and they're not ready &#x2013; and I mean, UTS is one example. They are not ready to accept offer based on a $50 per barrel.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, we continue and review potential targets. There are many of them. I'm not saying that we will do something. I am just saying that it is normal business to review that. And the area where we have some gap to be filled, namely Canada, non-conventional gas, Gulf of Mexico as we did tie with Cobalt. If any opportunity in Brazil, of course. That &#x2013; maybe other, like in Australia, there are many potential area where we could be interested in. But the main question is, if the seller is thinking in 80 or $100 per barrel scenario, there is no transaction feasible.</p>
          <p>On the Argentina result, the ROACE is slightly below the average of the portfolio but not so bad. But you know that usually we do not comment country-by-country, but the costs are very low in Argentina, everything is good. And this balance effect of the gas is sold at quite a low price. The 60% up on our minorities mainly come from Total Gabon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Robert Kessler from Simmons Company. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Patrick. A couple of clarifying questions, if I could on the OPEC exposure. Of the 90,000 barrels a day effect for the first quarter, were there very many of those barrels in Angola in particular.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, looking forward at the second quarter, any thoughts on your part with respect to the likely OPEC curtailment. Obviously, we have to, to be able to project OPEC volumes for the quarter, but I'm more interested in the ratio of your share of the OPEC curtailment. In other words, was there any extra catch-up in the first quarter that would not persist into the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very frankly speaking. I am strictly unable to assess what would be the next decision of OPEC. On Angola, on the 90,000 barrel per day, Angola represents something like 20,000 barrel per day. The other country being Libya, Nigeria and Abu Dhabi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no question at this time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Thank you. We have no further question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much all of you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you all for attending. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>