<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1129958" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2007 Earnings Call - London</title>
    <date>2008-02-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>596</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Christophe de Margerie, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1">Christophe de Margerie</participant>
      <participant id="2">Robert Castaigne</participant>
      <participant id="3">Irene Himona</participant>
      <participant id="4">David Cline</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.  Thank you for being present and thank you specially Jean to have the courage to be once more here.  But I mean you have no choice because at the same time you organize our trips.  So, but still if you're ready after the meeting.  Just to tell you that the strategy of TOTAL is consistent including vis-&#xE0;-vis Jean.</p>
          <p>First, I hate to say that we are the best, but what is true is good to say it and definitely 2007 has been good result and good result not only because it's 2007 because it is a result of a long-term strategy which proved to be successful.  And I hope to convince you still we'll be fruitful and profitable in the future.</p>
          <p>First item, and that has been one of our challenge in the past, we are back to growth in our production.  We are the only one in 2007, 1.5% but much more than the 1.5% was important is what is the real growth of 4.5 you should not forget that we don't take into account what is linked with the price of oil, what is linked with sales of assets and at the end the Nigerian problem.  It is 4.5 and you will see it later not only real in terms of percentage, they are extremely important because those 4.5 are really bringing additional cash, additional profit in our bottom line.</p>
          <p>The adjusted net income, plus 6%, almost $17 billion.  That is the best results for TOTAL.  Of course and as part of the strategy, high profits but also high investment; this is why we consider our strategy to be successful.  Consistency in developing our projects being absolutely adamant to be consistent in the criteria we are using and also managing our projects in a way, which helps to deliver on time and within budget.</p>
          <p>Net cash flow, we are spending a lot of money for the good and for the additional value to the company and our shareholders.  But still the net cash flow in huge increase, 27% above $10 billion.  That give us all the flexibility to continue the development of our successful strategy and even if it's not to be highlighted, but it was a subject of debate, the sales of sanofi have started at the end of 2007.  That's not for me a major point for the year, but at least when we are committed we deliver and that's much more the message than the 0.4% we have sold in itself and on the top, I will come back to it.  This strategy helps to continue to have a competitive; I would say almost aggressive, dividend policy plus 11% in euro and even more, 23 in dollars.  We'll come back to this later on.</p>
          <p>We have a lot of slides, but to go quickly to the Q&amp;A, I will not escape slides, but try to get the best to deliver the message I want to deliver.  The improved performance thanks to growth, and that's very important, that's where you see that when you increase production you effectively get additional profits and it's not only linked through the environment.  The environment is still representing an important part, almost $1 billion; additional cost, but that's still less what we get in terms of benefits through higher price of energy, almost $500 million.</p>
          <p>Exploration, which I like to see as a cost, but I mean frankly that is the limit of those presentations.  It's not a cost, it's a success, but it's true that when you invest more you have this kind of charge to be passed in your books.  But at the same time when you bring an additional 1 billion barrels even if we have a budget, which has been increased at 1.7 or $1.8 per barrel as the exploration cost is far beyond all expectation and especially compared with external growth.</p>
          <p>Growth and productivity, and that's where all the segments of the group are participating to this real added value.  To start with, of course upstream, but also downstream and chemicals 1.2; that is the highest region or the highest part of the increased profit and that's definitely why we will continue to have a strategy based on additional investment, but for more growth, more production, and more profits on the top, but we will come back to it</p>
          <p>We are still and that was our goal, sensitive to the environment which means when the price of oil is climbing, which has been the case, TOTAL and all of our activities are taking the benefit of those additional level of the price of Brent and gas, even if the gas as you know has not been as successful as the price of oil.</p>
          <p>Our policy, which is again I insist a long-term one, we can adapt ourselves, we have to do it to take into account the new concern about environment, about global warming, about sustainable development but at the same time, it is a result of the strategy which was started in the past.  We are investing more than our competitors, but that's not the reason why we are doing it.  It is a result of the comparison, but definitely, our capital expenditures program is continuing independently of the environment and that's what we need to continue to do being extremely conservative and disciplined on the way we are managing, not only the decision to launch our investment, but also the way they are managed.  It's extremely important that we keep our project within budget and we start production, I would say as quickly as possible, if we all know that the industry is facing some delays, but definitely, I think that TOTAL is doing better than others.</p>
          <p>And profitability, well it proved that you can be at the same time investing and profitable.  I hope you are not surprised because that was the intent.  The intent is it's good to buy back your shares.  It gives an immediate relative impact on your earning per share, but it doesn't give additional value to the company and to your shareholders at the end.  So on that slide, TOTAL is on almost the top of the list, Exxon being above, but I still prefer and it's nothing to do in terms of comparison the way we are doing the profitability of the group, which is in continuing an investment strategy based on the long-term.</p>
          <p>So, which slide is this?  Eight.  We're up to slide number 8.  Cash flow increasing plus 12% $24 billion, that's how we finance our growth.  As you can see, we have used this cash mainly for investment that is a long-term strategy.  We will come back to it.  Dividends and we have decided not to reduce our buyback program, because as you remember it's not a program in itself, buyback for TOTAL is what we are doing when we think that it is the best way to use our cash, i.e. in the past, we had much bigger program because we had money coming from projects which were done at $20.  We've received the benefits at 40.  This "extra cash" we thought the best way was to give it back to our shareholders.  Now we have much more sustainable growth in our project and we will keep the buyback program as still a balance to keep our debt-to-equity ratio at an acceptable level.</p>
          <p>So you have the debt-to-equity ratio on the right part of the slide.  It's at 27% at the end of the year.  It was a little bit above 30% last year.  Taking into account that end of December is always the peak of this ratio, as you can see we have reduced our indebtedness and at the same time there is no change in the strategy, it was between 26 and 30 as our target.  It is in this target.</p>
          <p>Dividend policy is the policy we have decided to make sustainable, i.e. we have decided to increase the dividend to 2, I mean that's in euro so always we still have a small problem between euro and dollars for this, but we increased it by 11% with 2.07 euro per share, which give in fact an increase of 23% in dollars, which is the amount to keep in mind, especially when you compare it to others.</p>
          <p>TOTAL is, as you can see, except BP this year, the company having the most important payout of our competitors.  We'll keep this position, Exxon being below 20, we are a little bit above 40.  And at the top, if you take the dividend per share, TOTAL is the one which is distributing the major part of its profit and we consider that it is the best way to give to our shareholder what they deserve to receive as part of our successful strategy.</p>
          <p>On upstream, go to which slide, on upstream which is the sector in which we have the most -biggest part of our investment and good success production, plus 1.5%, I started with this because it's really one of the main important results of 2007.  And we remain &#x2013; well you have on this slide, but I will not comment it, it will take too much time.  We have the capacity to continue our growth and even if we don't give you any figure for 2008, it has been the long lasting debate including in this room. I don't want to face any more comment on, are you above 2.1 or at 2.05.  We give you all the reason to find why.  We know that we will be doing better in 2008 whatever the price is, being at 60 or 80, we will be above the 2,000% increase and at the top above the increase of demand for oil which is a little bit below 2%.  Now no figure, but we have not only expectation, we are confident in the capacity of the company to continue growing.</p>
          <p>And on that slide just for you to remember that we have been having "only" 1.5% increase which is the best of the measures.  But the part which has been not present is having a very small impact on our bottom line.  We had the additional production which we call the 4.5 really had  positive impact of in our let's say profits and that's what you have to keep in mind.  When we lose for instance production in the Middle East because of OPEC, if you lose $1.00 per barrel when elsewhere you can get 6, 7, 8 or more what counts at the end is not only the production rate but the results it has on our profits.</p>
          <p>Exploration remains the first strategy of the group. When you have decided to go through internal growth, it's always better to start with exploration.  It gives you access to all the rent at different levels of the development.  We have increased the budget, thanks to the success of our teams.  Remember we had a budget of something like $900 million.  We have almost doubled it in three years' time, 1.8 billion for 2008.</p>
          <p>The average discovery cost has been increasing, but at 1.7 or 1.8, whatever the figure is at a price of $90 plus, it's easy to explain, but it's better to go through this route till we can do it, than having access to new reserves through external acquisitions.  So definitely, we will keep working hard on having the skill to be maintained in the company and getting with 1 billion barrels almost the amount of one year of production replacement.</p>
          <p>So I come naturally to our growth.  Keep in mind that our growth is coming roughly still 50% from exploration and 50% from new projects, what we call the "troisi&#xE8;me type", third type.  I know that Jean doesn't like to use this expression because it's "pas comprehensible", but the difference is exploration is what you do through exploration, plus "troisi&#xE8;me type" is when it has been discovered by somebody else, but you are more clever than others to develop it.</p>
          <p>So, proved and probable reserves, we are at 20 years roughly life of reserves, it's &#x2013; what is the future of the company.  Those projects are quite often underway, but what is even more important is, we are at the same time the most diversified company in terms of geography.  And at the same time, we have been capable to be even more present in a few numbers of countries and that is the result of this strategy, which has helped us to be successful.</p>
          <p>Never forget that especially in to today's environment, when access to new reserves might be a little bit more complex except for TOTAL to be present is a real plus.  It is much more difficult to answer as a newcomer than when you are present.  Now at the same time, it is also good to be big because it helps synergies and to be efficient.  So, definitely you've seen the result of this with an additional four countries with more than 500 million barrels of 2P reserves.  I always forget the list, but if I remember correctly, by heart, Australia is one, Congo another one, Canada third one and Yemen the fourth.</p>
          <p>Thank you.  That's for Jerome.  But definitely, we have to continue on this strategy.  It works and proved that we have to continue bringing additional countries in our portfolio of long-term reserves.</p>
          <p>Reserve replacements for 2007, the consistent figure is the replacement rate of 102. This is based on consistent price for oil, the one we use at the end of the year as it is a rule with SEC.  It was 20, sorry, $59 per barrel at the end of 2006.  We are at almost 94 at the end of 2007.  This has I would say an arithmetical impact, which bring the 102 to 78% and there is a special item in 2007, which will be quickly covered by other booking in the future, which is the forced sale of one part of our percentage in Sincor in Venezuela.</p>
          <p>But the importance thing is the capacity of the group to replace its reserves bringing new projects in and as you see on the second part of the slide, we have resources at close to 40 years life and as I said with an impact coming from the price of oil, which is limited which means that even at 80 it will not change more our resources for on the top one reason.  Today, you could think that being at 80 or more, it will change the cut-off date of production.  Well, let's say that for the time being we are not being too, let's say paying attention of the impact of this, but definitely there is a conservative part in this assumption which we didn't take into account what could be the potential for more production at those level of prices.</p>
          <p>We give you here and I will not spend too much time, the way to find what is the rate of growth of our production for the future, we keep our commitment with the 4% as an average from 2006 to 2010.  Then if you look at the slide, you can calculate what is the rate growth or growth rate for the future.  Much more important we keep giving you the list of all of our projects with the status of development being at the project stage or development and we have in hand everything we need to continue to be successful in our growth of production.</p>
          <p>And more than this, it's not on the same slide but most of this additional reserves &#x2013; additional production are coming from projects which are operated by us.  So it's true that we consider that being operated by us, thanks to the success we have had in the past, give us even more chance to secure those additional production in the years to come.  And we have, okay, you used it, so you have this.</p>
          <p>The focus on LNG, even if LNG and gas is not part of the E&amp;P division, it's part of our upstream.  The LNG for TOTAL is more and more important in terms of not only of growth in production, but also profit.  We want as we told you to make out of LNG one of the plus of the company.  We continue that success story with growth rate of almost 13% per year.  I am not at the right slide by the way, you &#x2013; you could use the other one first.  Okay, I will come back to the one after this.</p>
          <p>So we still have the 13% growth rate, which was announced last year.  We have all the elements in hands to continue the growth.  The market is growing roughly at the rate of 10%, so we are above 10% rate, which is already a huge one and definitely we will continue in this.  LNG has all the benefits, gas cleaner than oil, long term, longer term than oil, and also flexible, getting a chance to go from one part of the world to any other part which is not always the case by definition when you use gas pipe.</p>
          <p>When we see the numbers of projects we have ahead of us and to answer in advance about how can we book new reserves, well you see we have a long list of projects which are not yet booked by definition because the FID &#x2013; final investment date &#x2013; is not yet there.  But we have projects all over the world from Australia keeping on our African policy in Stockman, which decision to develop will be taken next year.</p>
          <p>So that is the scale going back to the potential for creating value.  First, what is important is to see, thanks especially to the price of gas which is prevailing in Asia, the net back to the company is extremely important, of course it's a net back than it is what has been shared with the oath countries, but it is always easier to share big cake than small one and that's the message.</p>
          <p>On the top, the impact of the price of oil is very important, especially because of those contracts in Asia.  It's not really is the case for the time being in the United States and with the aree hub.  But I will not comment on this, but even more you have the impacts on the profitability of TOTAL and definitely you can see that it's above the average of the return we have on our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Now, by definition at the same time, it's an important part of our non-employed capital.  And to give you a figure which might not be in one of our slides, we have 20% at the end of 2007 which are non-employed or non-productive, sorry, capital expenditures.  And this figure of 20%, we raise to 30 in 2010.  That's part of what you need to do when you want to grow, but at the same time it is part of what we use to make the profitability of the group, which means that our profitability is resisting and more than this to this necessary need in increasing non-productive capital expenditures.</p>
          <p>Two slides on downstream.  But you have all the documents in hand to see what is needed.  First, definitely before talking about growth what is important in any long-term industrial business is to have the best quality of assets, not only to beat the criteria for demand, but also to be sustainable for the future.  So definitely we have through different investments being in Normandy or in the U.K., in Germany and in Spain.  We have the capacity now to process more heavy crude, more acid crude and at the same time to produce less fuels and more distillates.  That was our targets, that's what we continue to do.</p>
          <p>And at the same time, keeping projects having a chance like for the upstream to get the benefit of higher price of energy.  And we use this payback criteria, where you can see that in most cases at $80 you increase the profit, which means you reduce the payback time.  It's true for the DHC at Normandy, things are little bit less.  While Leuna is already so short in terms of payback that you cannot see the impact of the 80 versus 60, but that level of payback is better not to comment anymore of what could be the impact of the price of oil.</p>
          <p>But definitely, we want just like for the upstream to keep our capacity because we believe in the high price of energy to keep this capacity to get the benefit of higher price.  The risk, otherwise, just to add one word on this is, people in any case they think you are getting a benefit of higher price.  So if you are not getting the benefit and being charged for it, then you know what it means, it means a real nightmare.  So that's why I always insist, I have been asked why are you insisting on this, but it's not to please, but it's just to say it's working.</p>
          <p>On the future of the refining, on the side of keeping our existing portfolio in good shape even if deciding to be flexible, I fear the Manager of our Milford Haven refinery, last time I was here we were discussing about this possibility, it has been done, and congratulations for the job you've been doing.  It's a way to prove that it can be done without making any noise, any concern, and on the top of it having our staff absolutely not only under control, I hate this word, but happy with the continuity of the way this refinery is run.</p>
          <p>So at the same time, definitely if you want to have new grassroots projects, it will not be in Europe.  And we are still looking for countries with higher growth, like Asia or &#x2013; and I am sure we will come back to this &#x2013; or the project we have in Port Arthur, which is not in what we call an emerging country by far, but at the opposite being present in Canada, in the heavy oil being present in Venezuela, the heavy oil.  I think only one refinery in the United States, there was only two options.  One is to get one of the best refinery, first of the class, or to sell.  We have decided to fundamentally not only upgrade the refinery, and making for this refinery one of the best of the class and making sure that it will get the benefit of this additional different version and on the top capacity to swallow a lot of heavy oil, acid oil and maybe for the future of being a way to get potential linkage association with producing country.</p>
          <p>The project of Jubail in Saudi Arabia you know it, you know why it's closed now too, so basically we have to take the decision.  All the studies have been almost completed.  It's definitely a well-placed refinery where the reserves are, where we can have access to heavy oil.  We are close to the markets.  Now we just have to make sure that the economics, thanks to the contractual terms are there to make it a profitable project for Saudi Aramco and TOTAL and I hope next time to be able to give you more information on our decision to proceed.</p>
          <p>On petrochemicals, also two slides.  Even if it's a different business, the strategy is very close to the one of the refining.  First priority to the existing portfolio and when we want to grow, we grow in countries where at the same time we have access to demand and to feedstock at good price and good yield, which is the case with ethane.  So you see on the four projects, which are on that slide four are based on ethane, one is still on naphtha in Korea, but this project has been benefiting of such low costs, first when we've entered into the deal, we could do it at a very, I would say competitive price.  And the debottleneck and the additional development of the project has been also so competitive that even with high price of naphtha this project remained one of the best and capable to get additional profit for the company.  So the Capex are increasing but bringing additional profit to the company.</p>
          <p>And you have the same example with the payback, of the impact of higher price on this payback.  So all the projects made on ethane by definition are getting the benefit of the oil price.  Korea not really, but as we can see they have been so "well negotiated by the payback" is already extremely short and I wouldn't say it doesn't need to be helped even more by higher price, but it's true that with naphtha it's not possible.</p>
          <p>So this slide is just giving the same, I mean, explanation with one comment.  In 2005, we will have more than 50% or almost 50% of our petrochemical results based on ethane.  So it's a little bit complex and I will leave this just to Jerome, Robert, Reilly and all, the others to give the explanation of why we don't see the impact on the Capex where you see still a little Capex in Europe and all the development out of Europe.  But it's just for technical reasons i.e. we are using leverage system like in Algeria or in Qatar when we don't have this in Europe.  At the same time in terms of real investment it's not at all like this, it's much more investment in Middle East and in Algeria than in Europe.</p>
          <p>Outlook.  Well, you know this slide almost by heart.  Each time we are bringing new projects, those are the projects which will be launched through 2010.  You have had the list before.  As we can see, I mean it's not only in E&amp;P, its mostly in E&amp;P, but also in refining and petrochemicals.  And to give you just a small highlight of what is represented in terms of category of projects, we have the resources for the upstream which is a good mix of different category of resources.  And again I think in spite of the good thing with TOTAL, we are not only in one specific sector of the liquids, we are good in almost all sectors and with this 40 years of life of resources.  This should give us the possibility and will give us a possibility to put into development an additional 5 billion barrels equivalent by the year 2010.</p>
          <p>Growth means investment, and you have on this slide all the projects which will be, if I can use this word, fueling the program of 2008.  Those are spending between 1 billion and $300 million per project.  It's all underway, it is a result of decision which had been taken in the past, but which we are still carefully following now.  It explain how we go from the $16 billion of investment in 2007 to 19.  Remember that we committed ourselves on 16 to 17 billion for 2007.  We are within this bracket at the lower end, but part of it is due to certain delays in our investment, so that's normal.</p>
          <p>But more important is out of this investment program increase, 25% is coming from Forex and that's mainly due to the euro versus dollar, euro increase versus dollar and not only euro, kroner, sterling to a lesser extent.  This in fact is what it is.  We cannot do anything about it, but it can become a plus and not a minus in the future.  And out of the 75% remaining, which is not remaining, which is a real part of our investment, keep in mind that roughly half of it is coming from the increased cost coming from these two environments, higher price of oil, higher cost, but still the higher price of oil and gas has been having a far better impact on our result than the increase in cost.</p>
          <p>Growth creating value, we already spoke about this non-producing versus producing capital employed.  As you can see it's slide 36, you have roughly 20% of non-producing capital employed in 2007-2008, and it will rise &#x2013; raise, sorry, to 30% in 2010.  That's part of what we need to do to contribute to fuel our growth.  It is at the same time linked with the increased profitability of our operation. And you have interesting slide explanation on the left part, where you see at the same time what are our projects when it is at $60 versus 80 by "category of investment" and you have on one side the rate of return IRR and the other side the enrichment. It was a mix of the two.</p>
          <p>We have long-term projects with larger enrichment and of course less return in terms of profitability.  But in any case, all of our projects are first above what we consider as being the minimum profitability requested and second, all of them being from upstream, downstream, or petrochemical are getting the benefits of increased oil prices, that is and was our strategy and it proves to work, I would say beautifully well.</p>
          <p>Last slide have been much longer than expected as usual.  I would not go through this slide, which is even probably one of the most interesting one.  The message is to be successful in this business, which is not always the most appealing one in terms of what it represents, i.e., we are faced with concern about c emissions, environment, price of oil, super profit, I mean everything that, some I like, some I don't like and still insist we like super profit because they are not super profit, they are necessary profit to continue our growth, our strategy of being at the same time bringing added value to the company and our shareholders and paying dividends on a regular basis and a competitive one.</p>
          <p>But keep in mind first that this strategy will be continued, but we have by definition to take into account the environment which is we are asked and that's normal to be more involved in the concern of the global warming and we will do this not as being considered as a burden, but as a way to be even better and just don't exist only as words.  It's not words it's real.  First, you can be more efficient, which means less fuel to emission and by definition being more efficient, more profitable.</p>
          <p>Second, we are part of this world and we need to be understood.  We need to take part of the decision making process.  And if we are not accepted to be part, then we will suffer of things in which we will have no possibility to have a chance to discuss.  That is the case for what will be the  post-TOTAL in 2013.  So definitely, instead of trying to have a kind of war between those being "green" and the oil and gas companies being not green, we will just try to make it, as it's important to make sure that both can work.  Well, that is the only way to get at the same time what we want to do in terms of environment and also to get access to energy, because without energy there will be nothing and in that case the problem of global warming will not be anymore the subject.</p>
          <p>And the last thing in this new, not world, but new environment, TOTAL will be even more than ever willing to find ways for research and development on how to bring on to the market, products which will bring a way to reduce consumption.  We started with the Excelion.  We have to work on other ways to reduce consumption, i.e., you can drive longer with the same tank, but it seems to be strange to have a person in charge of the company to say let's try to reduce the demand, first it's not the message.  We can be better in efficiency and increase our share of the market and at the top of it using this to increase our share.</p>
          <p>And in any case now that we know that we would be short of I would say classical source of energies like fossil energies, well in just reducing this gap we are helping to reach a solution, which in any case will come back to our responsibility. You all know that if there is no sufficient energy, definitely the request on what to do will be charged to us.  So, it's better to move before we are requested to make a move and prove that it can be done in a proper manner, profitable and environmentally friendly.  That's what we call acceptability.  Acceptability is not in opposition with profitability is at the opposite.  The only way to continue to develop this company successfully, sustainably for the long-term and I hope with having the chance to come back next time with even better results, which is a challenge, but doable and our target.</p>
          <p>I'll leave you the floor, except to Jean.  That's democracy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  It's Theepan from Morgan Stanley.  Just three quick questions on your LNG business actually.  Firstly, how confident are you in particular on delivering on the near term growth on Yemen and Qatar? If you could give us a progress update there.  Secondly, yourself and a number of other of your peers have indicated that it's a very tight market in LNG at the moment.  I was just wondering how flexible is your own LNG business?  And then sort of lastly, I was just wondering, it's becoming a very important part of your earnings stream, over 20%.  Have you considered actually reporting that business as a standalone business?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, for the third one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The third question, just on whether you have actually considered reporting the LNG business as a standalone earnings stream within your accounts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Robert, you want to answer on the last one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh I think the idea is two other reporting, which is at a peak to the way the company is managed.  The issues at LNG, in fact, is a segment that is essentially managed by the E&amp;P for the industry and aspect and for the commission aspect by Gas and new Energy Division.  So I think it's &#x2013; at the end of the day it's very &#x2013; it's so integrated in E&amp;P, so we do not envisage to report separately for this business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>True, true.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's too much integrated in E&amp;P.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very important that we have this reporting.  At the same time, we will keep on purpose two different divisions, one for gas and one for E&amp;P because for all, which is linked with construction, with management of projects, there is no reason to make a split.  But as far as you talk about marketing, trading, it's definitely another business and thus need to be outside of E&amp;P.  And that's why for instance the trading activities on gas, which are by the way located here in London, are out of the E&amp;P division.  So at the same time, we don't want to split the result of the activity, but definitely we want to split the responsibilities because it's a different business to build and manage a huge project like those projects at the same time to let's say market and trade the energy itself.</p>
          <p>On Yemen yes, we are confident, things are underway.  There is no real delay.  Costs are under control after a period where we had to take into account the new environment, but that has been already disclosed to you.  What still remains to be done in the future is probably, but it's not the right time to do it, is that the appropriate time is to reopen negotiation of our sales contract with Korea to take the benefit of what has been recently renegotiated by Indonesia.  We have to reopen clause in our contract and we will certainly exercise it to get the let's say benefit of higher price of gas especially in this part of the world.  Your second point was ...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Inaudible" /> Just on how much energy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Well, for the time being we definitely give priority to the upstream and what is important to us is, because that is where we think the real long-term benefit will be, is not only to get profit out of trading activity, but really to get profit from the project itself.  And when you see our result, that is the only part coming from the upstream.  If we have trading profits, if we come on the top of it, and that's definitely something we are working on, we are having a lot of purchase of gas to trade, but at the same time, I consider this as something on the top, but it does not &#x2013; it's not part, let's say, of a long-term strategy like some others of our competitors.  We always consider that it's better to get the revenues out of the upstream.  It's a way to secure our benefits much more than through trading activity, which might be beautiful one year and not good the next, because I mean you will have different ways of finding where the additional profit is.  That doesn't mean that we are not interested to get the benefit of, let's say, playing with the market.  Next time we will make a presentation with our, by I mean long-term purchase of gas and what we are doing with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon, two questions.  Brazil &#x2013; it's been a very exciting area in the deep offshore and that seems to fit your skill set.  Can you talk about any thoughts that you have in terms of getting exposure to some of the acreage or exciting discoveries that we've had out in Brazil?  And then the second question, the energy costs are still rising, the euro has appreciated, and at some point we may also have CO2 costs.  You've talked about strengthening some of your key assets in the downstream, in chemicals, but would you be more aggressive in terms of reducing exposure through disposals?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I am sure you raised the question about Brazil because you know we are not present.  We tried many times to develop our activities in Brazil.  And I must say that the results have been like for most of our competitors not as I &#x2013; as what we expected.  We have made a discovery, which we have with Petrobras.  We don't know yet what will be the future of the discovery, when it will be developed, but at least we have a presence there.  There have been announcement about discoveries recently, oil and gas.  I hope it's true and I don't like to say something nasty, because we are not in, but I mean at least what is true that in the past there have been a lot of big announcement and still there were good result, but not as high as what has been announced. So for this we'll just wait and see, to see what it is.  If we can find new opportunities with Petrobras, we will do it, but it's true that in the past we tried the opposite of what we're doing elsewhere, to do things by ourselves.  Just like for what we have been doing in Russia, I think it's better to do it with Petrobras because they not only know where it is, because we know where it is too, but they have a certain kind of priority on those zones and those who have been doing discoveries recently is because they were with Petrobras.  So it's not by their capacity of finding oil and gas themselves.  But again, we will see what it is and we are having, as you probably know, strong relationship with Petrobras on research and development on LNG.  We hope it will bring us one day in being closer to them for participating to this success in their recent exploration works.</p>
          <p>On your second question, I don't think there is any difference between the first thing that when you have something it needs to be adapted to the market, it needs to be not only adapted, it needs to be, let's say acceptable, i.e. we have to be committed with assets, which are secured, which are respecting not only the safety, but which are first class in terms of safety and environment.  It also needs to be adapted to the market.  When you know that we need to reduce still the sulphur content that's why we are doing those HDS investment.  At the same time, we see still potential for higher profits, but definitely if we want to grow in other parts of the world where we are closer to the markets, definitely we would have at a reasonable period of time to consider reducing our size in Europe where the demand is declining.</p>
          <p>So Milford Haven has not been used as an example, Milford Haven was the result of &#x2013; if we want to have a long-term view on our investment, we have to choose the refineries where we think there is a need for TOTAL to invest on additional, let's say for instance, upgraders, cokers, or whatever.  Something can be good for Norco, that's what we discussed yesterday, and not interesting for TOTAL.  Why?  Because we have already our own portfolio which is different of the one of Norco.  So one investment can be good for a company and not interesting for another one.  But definitely, if we want to be more aggressive, like we are doing today in Port Arthur, or in Jubail and maybe one day in China, we will certainly have to reduce our size in part of the world where the &#x2013; that the demand is not at all at that level and the opposite might certainly be decreasing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Lydia from Lehman Brothers.  Firstly, just on the Jubail refinery, you mentioned the listing on the Riyadh Exchange, I was just wondering why you were considering that and how much of the project you would list?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, if I go back to the production list for 2006 to 2010, some of those seem to have changed from a year ago in terms of Dolphin and Nigeria Energy contribution being higher and yet some things like Tempa Rossa have been delayed until 2011.  I was just wondering why have those changes happened and does that make you more confident about the 2006 to 2010 target because you've got those projects on stream now? Or have you removed a cushion of comfort from some of the production guidance in the past?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well on production, I mean, that's exactly the situation &#x2013; sometimes you have project which are proving to be better than expected and some which are still good but delayed.  With Tempa Rossa, don't ask me why; I am still upset to see this project being delayed in a country which has no oil. But, okay, that's life but I am still confident that &#x2013; if there is one reason why I don't give any more precise figure is example of Tempa Rossa.  A good project, which finally might be much more attractive that what it was at the time because starting producing the time when the oil prices were higher than what it was four years ago.  At the same time, it's still depending on a few things which are always delayed and that's, I would say, just a little bit like the weather.  You can say what it will be tomorrow, maybe, but certainly not the day after tomorrow.  But Tempa Rossa will start, but being delayed.</p>
          <p>And we have some other projects which are better than expected, bringing more oil, more production and that's the good thing with the portfolio.  Remember when we're using 2P, the 2P is the possibility to be less or more, and when you have more than one project in 2P normally on the size you should have better, let's say, good surprise than the opposite and that is the case of TOTAL.  So, really, for the year 2010 we feel comfortable, even if we know there will be problems like the one we faced recently.</p>
          <p>My friend here for the E&amp;P of the UK, I mean all of his talk can tell you what happened in &#x2013; on the Junea Franklin. Good thing is that Junea Franklin is far better than expected.  Reserves are higher.  The plateau is higher and it's all good news.  Now we have had a small technical problem, which will be solved quickly, but in between being on, having an important percentage in this project it will have an impact on our production.  But I cannot say, I mean, its bad news.  Yes, it is bad news, but it will not change the, let's say, future of to the company.</p>
          <p>So we feel, really TOTAL and myself, confident in taking, even with that figure, the commitment of increasing our production more than our competitors, more than what has been done in 2007 and more than the global ask for additional demand in the world.  Now what will it be at the end exactly, it depends on Nigeria, it depends on a lot of other factors, but these projects are now well in place and will be with production sooner or later.  Your first point was....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Inaudible" />. Sorry, just in terms of why you were considering a listing on the Riyadh Exchange for the Jubail refinery, I think you mentioned?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh. Well I was confused, because at first you said the Riyadh refinery; and that's one of our projects, but in the year 2018.  It's still in Jubail, close to the shore and we prefer this refinery than the one which is on the other side of the country and certainly not in the middle.  So for the time being it's clearly a project, which is 50-50 during the studies time between Saudi Aramco and TOTAL.  As soon as we start the development, TOTAL will keep its share and as far it is intended to have an IPO that will be covered by Saudi Aramco until the time this is open for the public.  We think this IPO is a good idea, not only in terms of acceptability and even if it was not our first target it's not to reduce our exposure, but at same times to be sharing risk with locals and especially in countries where they don't like to lose money in the stock exchange.  Nobody does like by the way, but in those countries you don't &#x2013; it's just like the dividend of TOTAL.  It can always increase.  It's a little bit the same in those stock exchanges.</p>
          <p>So I think it's good news, and especially as far as they remain below the minority, which is having a voice, we still keep the control with Saudi Aramco on how this refinery will be run.  The subject today is we have been faced with higher costs than expected, and we have to make sure that this project, just like all the others we have been developed, is giving the normal return which is acceptable by TOTAL and at the end by all those new potential shareholders.  Patrick when is &#x2013; is there any date on...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, the funniest thing is &#x2013; I mean I don't know about you, but I hear better when you talk outside, without the micro.  I am sorry.  It's not your fault.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The listing is scheduled either at completion of the project or one year after FID.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But what we only spend our share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. You only have to <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>More or less.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Irene Himona at Exane BNP Paribas.  I had a couple of questions please.  Firstly, you showed a very interesting slide, slide 34, on falling inflation in 2007 by different types of equipment and you talked about controlling your development costs.  Yet, quite a big percentage of your capital expenditure increase was due to cost inflation and I was wondering if you can share with us your views as to what is going to happen in '08,'09 to that inflation problem?</p>
          <p>My second question, you highlight the fact that 20% of your capital is not producing, that's I think quite normal in an industry with a long time lag.  So are you highlighting it because it's well above normal or are you highlighting it because you expect it to go up even more, which would obviously have implications for your returns?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. This time I will start with your first question because otherwise I will forget what it is.  You will see we will start dropping the word inflation on cost because, I mean, first &#x2013; I mean when you talk about 15 or 17% per year that's not inflation.  Inflation is 2 or 3%.  So here we are talking about the new environment.  And just like we have a new environment with oil price and gas price, we have a new environment in construction costs.  And I prefer to say that we are integrating those new costs, these two environments in our decision-making process and by definition in our budgets not only for 2008, but for years to come.</p>
          <p>So definitely, what's important for us is when we decide to launch a project and we know the cost because most of the contracts have been signed before we start. Then in that case, we want this project to remain under budget.  And then, if we do it and if we start on time, we will get not only the benefit of the investment the way it has been decided, but also thinking that the price of oil will still be little bit higher than expected, we will get this "additional upside."  And what is important again is "can I or can't I decide to launch a project."  If these additional costs, new costs, not inflation are above our, let's say, capacity to decide to launch a project, then we will not launch it. And then everybody will have to sit and discuss whether or not is it stupid to not do something because of costs being too high.</p>
          <p>But that's not inflation anymore and I really prefer that we say that are the cost, you like it or if you don't like it.  Let's do the best on our side to reduce them if we can or to reduce the growth, because I don't think we will be able to cut them, but if we can at least decrease the rate of growth, it will be already a success.  We're working with the contractors on this, on how to find ways to avoid that we lose money, which will be loss-loss i.e. we spend too much and they don't get the benefit in their profit. At the same time, we prefer to have solid contractors keeping their skills than as we've done in the past having very, very shaky contractors and then they collapse before the end and that is extremely difficult to replace them during a developing project.</p>
          <p>So, once more, if we cannot launch a project because it's too expensive, then we will say it, but for the time being, it's not yet happened.  At the same time, it's part of the reason why we see price remaining at the high level on the side of offer and demand, plus the protection of OPEC.  Now, we know that a lot of projects cannot leave, i.e. cannot start without having high price of oil and gas, and in that case a cost problem is one element of the decision making process.  So, I would not choose anymore inflation, because again this word doesn't fit with what it is. But it's true that we have to find ways to keep those costs under control because we know that on the top of what has been impact of higher technology, more complex fields, we are now faced with, I don't know who said this, but before about &#x2013; with the cost of environment, eventually the cost of CO2 and that has to be taken into account at the time if we decide to launch a project. And that is all of these which will make it "can I go or not go?"  So, I think it's important even if we can still launch a project to find ways to keep those costs below of their today's level and that discussion is going on with certain of our main contractors. Your second?</p>
          <p>Well, it's -- I would not take it the way you say i.e. 20, 30, 40, 50, 60, and if we go to 100, then we stop.  It's much more the opposite is to say that that is first our way of presenting things.  We are transparent and we say "Okay, when you want to grow, you need to invest and when you invest and invest more, that has an impact on your nonproductive capital expenditures."  At the same time, as far as part of our CapEx and our capital employed, when we calculate the ROCE, when we calculate the rate of return, it's part of the company's model.  So, the message is just the opposite.  Even if we know there will be, by definition an initial percentage of nonproductive assets, it's part of what we consider as needed but also to be accepted in what is the return and the profitability of the company.  So, it's not a message of "Be careful, it's going to get worse."  Is, "We know what it is, it's under control and it's part of what is the profit of the company," including this part which is necessary when you want to grow.  If you remember in the old days, TOTAL had much higher percentage of nonproductive capital employed.  Thanks to God, we have better split between the two.  But at the same time, again, you cannot have the cake and eat it.  What is important is we prove the way we are absolutely certain on our side, that the project we are launching will bring additional value and not only as I showed you with the 2007 profit or extra profit is not coming only for environment, as the opposite the majority of the increase has been coming from the growth of TOTAL, i.e. the company is taking the benefit of its growth and not just getting the benefit of environment in which we can do nothing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's David Cline from ABN [ABN AMRO].  Two questions.  Firstly on CapEx, I know that CapEx beyond 2008 is difficult.  But if you put aside FX and you put aside industry cost inflation and just focus on the activity aspect of the equation, how do things look going beyond 2008 or to put in another way, does 2008 look unusual in the medium-term on an activity basis?  The second thing is, I guess there is a school of thought, which might say that you've made a tactical error in Venezuela that you will pay for in due course elsewhere in the world.  I wonder what your thoughts are on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Don't say that I pay you for the last question.  We start on that one, because that's really the strategy of TOTAL and that's really I think the success of the strategy of TOTAL is to be consistent, to be un-flexible when you talk about return, about decision making process, but the same time we see the world moving, we move when the world moves and sticking on something which does not exist anymore has a name.  It's called stubborn.  I am not saying this for anybody else, but using your answer as being don't you think you have been doing a mistake?  I'll say no.  I think we have been doing the right thing.</p>
          <p>We would have preferred to keep our existing percentage.  The choice was between as we did for Jusepin.  If you remember Jusepin last year we decided and we were the only company to quit, because I mean the percentage we were left with, the condition of the contract, which we were left with were not to respect our criteria, fulfilling what we need to continue to develop our activities.  And it has been a shock to see TOTAL quitting.  When Chevron was staying, when Repsol was applauding to say that's beautiful, I mean I am not saying by the way, that is beautiful to be reduced to 30% and I have heard some of our competitors with those first service contract to say it's not only normal.  It's good.  We like it.  That's a little bit too much.  We don't like this.  And I would have preferred as we tried to discuss with Pierre Le Fay a way where we could keep our percentage in renegotiating the terms and especially the fiscal terms.</p>
          <p>In all countries of the world, the tax authorities have the right to sign to change the taxes.  We don't like it, but they have the right in the UK, in the States.  Why couldn't they do it in the Venezuela?  Because it's Venezuela and those countries have no right to change their taxes?  I mean I cannot have said this kind of a statement.  But again, I would have preferred to find a solution without having to reduce our share.  We couldn't do it because of the stupidity of certain of our partners a year before where they have accepted everything with their service contract where we decided to quit because we knew it would have an impact on Sincor, and because we knew it will have an impact on Sincor there is somebody behind you which can tell you I had a lot of pressure inside the company to stay in Cuza Pin. Because I mean that is traditional in companies they don't like to quit.  I said too much is too much we quit.  Here it's different.</p>
          <p>Yes, we are not happy with being forced to reduce our share, but I mean the terms we have for the remaining 30% and 30% is not remaining is still a large portion of a huge investment on the top with the new terms we have for the future, we consider it's a good investment.  On the top of it, even if we have lost maybe potential value with the 17% we have been forced to sell, we have received compensation, which is above what is in our books.  So which will create some capital gain.  I mean two choice in that case, one is to say we are strict on and strict and stay in our shoes and we die, or we consider because the terms are acceptable that we can continue, but I mean only because the terms are acceptable.</p>
          <p>And I can tell you the impact will be much more difficult for those who are giving lessons than for those who are trying to find solutions.  But you can find solution in being extremely strict on return, on investment and the way you do your business.  And if to be pragmatic is dangerous, I think that when you are not pragmatic that you are taking a risk and especially when you test national oil companies i.e. States, just always be careful. States are States wherever they are in all countries including in Venezuela.  Remember what happened to a company in Qatar?  Ask Shell they will tell you.  When they sued the ruler of Qatar, they had been out of the country for more than 20 years.  That's not what we want to see.</p>
          <p>Now to be very clear, we would have not received an acceptable compensation for the 17% and terms which are acceptable for the 30% we will have left the project because that will have not be considered as following our criteria.  But I mean frankly to say that it might have a negative impact on the group outside? No, the opposite.  Jean has a right to say something because he wanted to, I don't want to give the feeling it was serious.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Say this is trepidation.  Can we just talk a little bit, or get you to talk about Nigeria for a couple of minutes, just I guess there's three issues, one just some of your insight into where we stand on the onshore concessions and the problems around that?  Second is any of the issues around the two LNG schemes that are queued up in LNG 7 and Brass?  And thirdly, if you can give us any insights into, I guess Usan, but also issues around local content approval et cetera on the deepwater projects as well?  So those kind of three areas in Nigeria.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your first one was on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The onshore concessions...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Nigeria?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In Nigeria, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, easiest Usan, Usan is next to start, and as I said, I mean we had it in the presentation and unfortunately we had to take it out because I mean we thought it would have been approved before and then for one single contract it is not approved yet.  So we have to fold negotiation with one contractor to get the final approval of the Nigerian authorities, but frankly I think it is only a question of weeks, I hope, days.  But there is nothing serious behind it.  For, globally being onshore or offshore or new terms or whatever, but it is true that first concern we have in Nigeria is the insecurity, the instability of the region and that is the number one concern.  It has been the reason for I mean having ups and downs in our production forecast.  That's why we have taken this out of what we call the production on which we have a certain form of responsibility.  But today it is not the insecurity, which is the major concern is just to make sure that NMPC and the State respect its commitment to finance their share of the development.  And that's particularly the case for onshore concession, because they are part of the concession and they have to finance their share.  When offshore they are production-sharing contracts, I mean not all, but mainly and in that case they don't have to pay anything, they are carried by the other partners.</p>
          <p>So we have discussions going on, on having them to clarify their position in all of those aspects, i.e. funding their share, in particular, the part which they have not yet paid.  And then we will see if there is a need to reopen the discussion on past production sharing contract.  But definitely, I think they are using the second part to put pressure on the first.  It's typical in negotiation, but on our side to prove that we can be also strong when it's necessary, we certainly not accept to open discussion on PSEs until we have solved the problem of the past.  And that's where we are.  So Usan almost done.  The other new projects, I hope that we will be able to solve quickly our negotiation with NMPC and the State, so that we can continue this necessary program of investment for the long-term of Nigeria.  That covers your point? John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what we've heard is apparently okay.  Petroleum is having some, let's say delays, which is, I mean to certain extent good for the others and there is effectively a new sign of wish on their side to develop Brass.  But for the same reason, we have to clarify; I mean how they will fund their share.  So it's a little bit like the other concern about Nigeria.  And NLNG 7, that's in my view the most attractive projects because they have the finance already to cover their share of the funding and we certainly would like to have this project to become a priority.  The good thing is it's back in their program for the next development.  But for this one, there is no concern about funding their share, the opposite without entering into too much details we wanted to try to use NLNG as being able to raise money which could fund some other project, but that's a little bit too early to talk about it.</p>
          <p>One final word just not to be misunderstood on the strategy, because I mean what you've raised about the position we have been taking in Venezuela is very important in today's environment, i.e. at the same time as we are enjoying good price of oil, still good price of gas even if they have not been as good in 2007 than oil.  We are "suffering " on not inflation but higher cost, but it is still less than the benefit we get and what is important then is a relationship between consuming countries and producing countries.</p>
          <p>And we know what it is with consuming countries.  It's called acceptability and acceptability means to make all of our, all of our efforts to be more environmentally friendly, to take into account this global warming problem, to be more talkative and vocal on how to explain why we need those profits, why they are not super profits, but profits needed to be those being able to continue to bring energy to our clients, to the consumers and in a cleaner way.  That's doable even if it's not always easy.  We have the same problem of acceptability with host countries.  And host countries today they have the tendency to close their doors because they consider that with what they have already in hand, what they are already producing and they've discovered that in producing less it has a direct impact on increasing price, they finally no need to really do more for let's say opening their doors.</p>
          <p>TOTAL first get the benefit of a long-term strategy and you know this.  At the same time, we still need, like others, to bring new projects onboard for the long-term.  And I think that Venezuelan case is a very good example of just be careful, not to be arrogant, aggressive and then bring exactly the opposite result i.e. you see those guys, they are so difficult why should we work with them.  It's a mistake they are doing, but even if it's a mistake if they are doing it, you are doing a mistake if you don't listen.  And we have to listen.  It's called acceptability and the opposite really and then it's not controversial of what you say, what will be the result is sending the message in other countries that those companies are taking note of anybody other than TOTAL, those companies if they behave this way it means we will not work with them anymore.</p>
          <p>And just be careful not to give lessons.  That's something we have learned long time ago, even I am still doing it from time-to-time, but less and less. No lessons, be pragmatic.  If you don't like it, if you don't want it, you go out.  That's what we have been doing in Saudi Arabia when we decided not to stay in Shrak when some others have decided to stay, it's because we told them we don't see anymore reason to stay because there is no thing we are viewing with our geologist and it's better to tell your partners that when you don't see something, you quit.  I don't want to spend an additional 300 or $400 million on exploration, which I can use somewhere else and that is pragmatism.</p>
          <p>And you can still keep good relationship with the country.  It can be done as far as you talk; you prepare it in a nice way.  In Sligall, we can quit, we are not going to spend money for nothing.  That's the way we try to develop our strategy for the future of TOTAL and I deeply think that it is the way especially in the today's environment.  Nothing mean about being na&#xEF;ve, nothing in terms of dropping anything serious, but just being consistent, long-term, wise and you cannot say at the same time the world is changing but you don't change.  Thank you very much for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>