<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1468126" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-04-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>596</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Patrick de la Chevardi&#xE8;re</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Tudor Pickering Holt &amp; Co. Securities, Inc.">Robert Arthur Kessler</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Lydia R. Rainforth</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Theepan Jothilingam</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Kepler Capital Markets SA">Bertrand Hod&#xE9;e</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior Vice President-Business Development, Total Exploration Production">Michel Hourcard</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Martijn P. Rats</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies International Ltd.">Iain S. Reid</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Oswald C. Clint</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="CM-CIC Securities SA">Jean-Luc Romain</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Howard Weil, Inc.">Blake Fernandez</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Jon Rigby</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Alastair R. Syme</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (United Kingdom)">Neill W. Morton</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Lucas O. Herrmann</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Earning Results Q1 2012 Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in listen-only mode until we conduct a question-and-answer session and instructions will follow at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And just to remind you all that this conference call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand the call over to the Chairperson, Patrick de la Chevardi&#xE8;re. Please begin your meeting and I will be standing by.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, this is Patrick de la Chevardi&#xE8;re speaking. Thank you for taking the time to join this conference call. Before commenting on our first quarter results, we will start with an update on Elgin. Events like this remind us that safety must be our top priority. And so I have asked Manoelle Lepoutre, Senior VP of Sustainable Development and Environment, and Michel Hourcard, Senior VP of Development, to be here today in case you have any technical questions.</p>
          <p>The latest update on Elgin. We believe this situation is now under control from an operational standpoint. The leak has diminished substantially from its initial flow rate and we have put in place a diverter to channel the gas away from the platform. This is a key step in improving the safety of the installation and we are preparing to start the well intervention next week. We remain confident that this will stop the gas leak. As a precaution, we will continue with drilling the relief wells. The first one was started last week and the second one should start in the next week or two.</p>
          <p>From a financial standpoint, I can confirm the estimates we share with you during our April 2 conference call. The response and remediation effort is costing about $1.5 million per day, net to Total before taxes and insurance. The estimated impact on production is about 50,000 barrels of oil equivalent per day, and the financial impact of the shutdown on net operating income, net to Total is about $1.5 million per day or around $50 million so far. We are working in close coordination with all the relevant authorities and we will maintain close contact on all matters pertaining to this incident and its remediation.</p>
          <p>Also, as you know, we reported incidents on OML 58 in Nigeria and the Yemen LNG pipeline. We are preparing a snubbing operation on the Damas well in Nigeria. The pipeline in Yemen was repaired a few days ago but we received news last night that it has been blown up again. So we will repair it. The financial impacts and production shutdown from these events are expected to be limited. There were no injuries or loss of life in any of these events. And our remediation response has been carried out in a timely and professional manner. Total has a consistent track record of technical and operational excellence, and we continue to see this as one of our key differentiating factors.</p>
          <p>It is too soon to provide an update for the 2012 production forecast, but it is clear that we must take certain factors into account. For example, we will not restart production from Elgin-Franklin until we can do it safely and in accordance with the requirements of the relevant UK authorities. Our teams are working on several scenarios and there is a possibility that we could restart gradually some time before the end of the year.</p>
          <p>We are losing 0.2% of our production growth for each months that Elgin-Franklin is shutdown. If we take the conservative view that Elgin-Franklin does not restart before year-end, then 2012 production could be flat. We will have a much better perspective on all of these things in coming few months.</p>
          <p>For 2012, we are on track with the new project startups. The Usan field started up in February as expected. Pazflor and Usan, both operated by Total, are now the two largest FPSO's in the world. We are very proud that these projects had been delivered and started production either ahead of schedule or on time. In April, we also started up Islay in the North Sea and also Bongkot in Thailand. The three new startups will contribute more than 60,000 barrel per day net to Total at plateau.</p>
          <p>For long-term production growth target of 2.5% on average for 2010 to 2015, we have started up or have under construction 95% of the volume we forecasted for new projects. So far this year, we have launched three major projects. Ofon 2 in Nigeria is one of the last projects we needed to launch that is expected to contribute to the 2015 target. We also launched two other projects for longer term growth. Ichthys in Australia and Hild in Norway. In addition, we acquired an interest in wet gas windows of the Utica shale and finalized our entry in Uganda as an E&amp;P operator there.</p>
          <p>Let me move then to our first quarter results. Adjusted cash flow from operations was $6.7 billion in the first quarter. Compared to 4Q 2011 adjusted EPS increased by 10% during the quarter to $1.78 per share. The upstream had a very good quarter, reflecting the high commodity price environment. The upstream segment generated $3.9 billion of net operating income or 96% of the group's net reserve for the quarter. This represents a 3% increase from the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>Let's recall that in 4Q 2011 we had a positive one-off item for $139 million related to changing the way we report over and under lifting. So taking this into account, the increase would have been 7%. The first quarter upstream results were also affected by higher taxes. Upstream production was nearly unchanged at 2.47 million barrel of oil equivalent per day in the first quarter versus 4Q 2011.</p>
          <p>As you know, we have implemented the reorganization of the downstream businesses so the group's results are now presented based on new segments: Refining and Chemical, our downstream industry oil activities on one end; and Supply and Marketing, our downstream commercial activities on the other.</p>
          <p>Refining and Chemical reported a small profit and showed some improvement from 4Q 2011. But the main message here is that the environment for European refining and petrochemicals remains very challenging. Margins were squeezed by high feedstock costs <mark type="indiscernible" /> (8:09) and lower demand. European refining margins, however, are trending upwards. Supply and Marketing again delivered consistent results and this segment continues to perform well.</p>
          <p>Operationally, in the Downstream, we are making progress on the restructuring of the Refining and Chemical segments. The first units of the Dubai refinery are on schedule to start in early 2013. We are focusing on better integrating the Normandy refinery with the gulf rail petrochemical plants. And we have launched a major expansion of the Daesan petrochemical plant in South Korea with our partner Samsung.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter, net investment amounted to $5.6 billion, in line with the budget. This includes acquisition of $2.4 billion, mainly as a result of the closing of Uganda and asset sales of $2.0 billion coming from our continued disposal of Sanofi shares, the sale of our interest in the Gassled pipeline in Norway and the sale of upstream assets in France.</p>
          <p>Our gearing at the end of the quarter amounted to 22% at the low end of our target gearing range and essentially unchanged from the end of the year. Our liquidity position is very strong with more than $17 billion of cash and cash equivalents on the balance sheet at the end of the first quarter. We announced that we will pay the interim dividend of &#x20AC;0.57 per share on September 27, 2012. This is stable compared to the previous quarter. As a reminder, it is our policy to maintain the payroll threshold of 50% on average over time. Our balance sheet remains strong and we are confident in our ability to maintain this competitive policy and return to shareholders.</p>
          <p>This conclude my comments. And we are now ready to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from the line of Robert Kessler from Tudor, Pickering. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good afternoon, Patrick. I was curious, in your &#x2013; what you characterized as a conservative outlook now for flat production in 2012. Can you say what you've assumed for Yemen production on average for the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Robert. For Yemen, we assume a loss of production in aggregate of 5,000 to 7,000 barrels per day when we made this assumption.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On a full year, just 5,000 to 7,000 barrels a day net to Total?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, for the full year net to Total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what was it in the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About 90 for the whole year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>About 90? 19? I'm sorry, could you repeat that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our share of Yemen LNG is 70,000 barrels per day, and the overall for Yemen is 90,000 barrels per day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And for the first quarter of 2012, that was the average output?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that was the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Lydia Rainforth from Barclays, please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good afternoon, Patrick, one question, if I could, please. Just on the dividend policy, the fact that it's flat year on year, should we take that as a &#x2013; should that be &#x2013; the payment that it will be for the rest of the year, as well as for your flat full-year dividend, or is it just too early in the year at this stage to think about lifting the dividend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Basically, what we think about the dividend is that it was too early and that we need time to control the Elgin situation prior in deciding to increase the dividend. So it is not because we haven't increased the dividend this time that we will not increase later on. We will see according to the situation. And I remind you that what we said in the past is that we have room to increase the dividend. This remains valid, but it's just a matter of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Theepan Jothilingam from Nomura International. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Patrick. Three questions, actually. Firstly, do have any further color on any other liabilities outside the costs of fixing the Elgin gas leak. I'm thinking about any sort of regulatory charges that may come up against Total. Secondly, could you give any color on the performance of Total's LNG business this quarter relative to Q4 and year-ago levels? And then lastly, just in terms of any color on the performance of the solar business and the contribution or negative contribution to EMP. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll start on solar and as you know we cannot comment on solar because our affiliate is a listed company and we cannot comment prior their announce their own profits and losses.</p>
          <p>A few comments on the liabilities. I don't know if we have a clear view today of the type of fine that could be imposed on &#x2013; from the UK authorities. As a matter of principle, it's up to the court to decide on the amount of any fine which may be charged by UK authorities. And we don't know yet if the company shall bear any liability in this specific case. At this stage, we are not aware of any prosecution that would have been initiated by the UK authorities in connection with the Elgin incident.</p>
          <p>Your second question was about LNG, if I would remember, Theepan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the first quarter this year, the net operating income contribution from LNG was &#x20AC;766 million, an increase of about 25% from the contribution in first quarter 2011, which was close to &#x20AC;600 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you &#x2013; remind me what the Q4 result was as well, please, Patrick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x20AC;730 million. I don't have any more figures, Theepan, for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's all right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Bertrand Hod&#xE9;e from Kepler, Paris. Please go ahead. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hello, Patrick, good afternoon. Two questions, if I may. Can you come back on the Nigerian incident on OML 58, the causes of that incident, your understanding to date? And how could that affect production going forward and also especially OML 58 upgrade that was scheduled to be started this year?</p>
          <p>And the second question I have is when I look at your Middle East production, especially on the gas side, it's sharply down year-on-year. Can you give me some color and the reason behind that sharp fall in the Middle East production?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Bertrand. I will leave the floor to Michel Hourcard to explain you technically what's happened on OML 58 and then we'll come back on the financial consequences of &#x2013; or production consequences of these events.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bertrand. We had &#x2013; on Nigeria, we had &#x2013; on OML 58 an intersection between two wells at the surface drilling phase, one well perforated the one existing gas-producing well. The well was shut off, but anyway we had some gas release on surface, on the cluster, and outside the cluster. The situation is on the monitoring at the moment. We mobilized equipment to treat the situation by two-folds. First of all, the snubbing unit is being prepared to being able to intervene on the gas for this well. And we have as well some relief wells in preparation. We could start in a few weeks.</p>
          <p>So the situation is under control. It is critical because we have sea gas, potential gas release on the surface but we are making good progress and the equipment is on &#x2013; is in Nigeria at the moment on OML 58. So that's the situation today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the consequences, we currently estimate the loss of production at about 20,000 barrels per day. The cost of the remediation operation is about net to Total $0.4 million per day before tax, which is to say, $60,000 per day after tax net to Total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and do you have any schedule on the expected restart of operation that was &#x2013; because the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, for the snubbing units, it's a matter of weeks. If we have to perform the relief well up to the end, it will be a matter of months. Hopefully, the snubbing units will be effective on this case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on the Middle East question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Basically, the drop you see in our report is related to Syria. You know that we are not producing anymore in Syria. This &#x2013; in last year, we were producing 55,000 barrels per day of oil equivalent in Syria. And on top of that, you have the price effect on Dolphin, which is about 10,000 barrels per day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the price effect on Dolphin, I would say, is an irreversible price effect. It's a profit threshold?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's above threshold and cost story.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Martijn Rats from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon. Three questions, if I may. First of all, in the statement you said the production in second quarter will be impacted by the events in the UK, Nigeria, Yemen, and also plant maintenance. I was wondering if you could be a bit more specific on the magnitudes of the combined impact of all of those? Can we expect 2Q production to be actually down compared to 1Q, for example?</p>
          <p>The second question that I had relates to Usan. I believe it's producing something in the order of 100,000 barrels a day, but I was wondering if you could also mention what the cash contribution of that project was in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>And finally, in 1Q, I believe acquisitions were still outstripping disposals, but if I remember correctly, the guidance for the full year is for that to reverse. How would you expect the balance between acquisitions and disposals to be over &#x2013; over the next three quarters of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Basically, for the second quarter, if you assume that we do not start again producing neither in Nigeria, neither in the UK, these will aggregate about 70,000 barrels per day. The maintenance is about 93,000 barrels per day, 90,000 barrels per day. That's the overall effect I can give you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Usan was ramping up and started quite late in the quarter, so its contribution for first quarter is negligible. And what was your third question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The balance between acquisitions and disposals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sorry. First quarter we acquire more than we sell assets for about $500 million. Our commitment is that the net asset sale would be $4 billion this year. We have some sale in our mind and there is three quarter coming on, so we maintain that our target will be a net sale of $4 billion. And I remind you that in first quarter we acquire our interest in Uganda.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Iain Reid from Jefferies. Please go ahead, your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Patrick. A couple of questions, please. I saw on the wires that you've acquired a bit more on Novatek. Can you confirm that, 15% and how much you paid for it?</p>
          <p>And secondly on the comment you made on Sanofi, can you just remind us how much of Sanofi you still own?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We still own about 2.2% of Sanofi. As Novatek, we &#x2013; what I can tell you is that we acquired 0.3% of Novatek on the market at the price of $120 million. Our current stake in Novatek is 15% and, sorry, but I can't remember exactly how much we paid for the 0.6% which are missing in my computation. But roughly, for 3 &#x2013; 0.3% to $120 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how soon do you think you're going to get to the 19% you talked about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do have time to do it. There is no emergency for it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Oswald Clint from Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, yes. Just back on the LNG business, please. Obviously, with some of your volumes in that business flat in terms of LNG sales and the earnings are up quite strongly. Can you just confirm that you're diverting a lot of cargos or really capturing some of the better pricing available within the LNG market and your business model is able to actually capture some of that?</p>
          <p>The second question was just on the Utica, some Anadarkos and Chesapeakes have released some of the well data &#x2013; in the last few weeks and months. I wonder what your thoughts are on those and of your investment within the Utica shale? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We start with Utica. Basically we are shifting drilling rigs from first just Chesapeake joint venture and conserve them to the Utica shale area. On the LNG &#x2013; the Total LNG sale in first quarter was 3.24 million ton, 3% higher than 4Q. For the redirection, we direct 10 cargoes versus nine cargoes in the 4Q And we divert six cargo first quarter 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Perfect. And next, can I just confirm there's no Utica volumes included within the 2012 production guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Honestly, I don't think so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Minor effects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Jean-Luc Romain from CACSEC (sic) [CM-CIC] Paris. Please go ahead. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I would like to come back on the Utica Shale acquisition. There were some reports mentioned a few weeks ago that oil production was disappointing compared to what was expected; there was more gas and less oil. Could you comment on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, I don't have any information with that respect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Blake Fernandez from Howard Weil. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick, good afternoon. I had to jump on a little bit late so I apologize if this was covered, but some of the press reports I've seen recently suggested that you had a discovery on Brunei CA-1 and I was hoping you could maybe provide some color there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We made some discovery, but I don't have enough information at that step to comment on and you should wait a little bit for more details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. Thank you, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Jon Rigby from UBS. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Hi, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Two questions. Could you just clarify for me in a little bit more detail the process now at Elgin? I think you said that you'd start the intervention work next week and all being well, if you would sort of set out how long that might take? And then what the process would be if that were successful? And sort of reconcile that with your guidance that production would probably not start towards &#x2013; until towards the end of the year. That was the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question is on your downstream, the Refining &amp; Chemicals business, when you look at the current operating environment and your target to increase profitability by 5 percentage points I think on <mark type="indiscernible" /> (28:38), would you expect in the sort of future world that Total's Refining &amp; Chemicals business, ex the specialties should be more than breakeven in the conditions that you saw over the first quarter? Those are the two questions. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I answer first on the downstream question and we'll ask Michel to answer on the technical question you asked on Elgin. We faced a very depressing environment first quarter this year. I don't think anyone could be at breakeven in such an environment. So, even after having improved our profitability in the downstream sector, I don't think we could be at breakeven at that in such an environment</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on Elgin, Michel will answer your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're making good progress, as you know in Elgin. We installed the diverter on the well head, which enabled us to work more safely on the place and to make sure that our people are safe. And so that's been done.</p>
          <p>We've got now overboard lines for the flow from the well. They are setting up the flow lines and the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:05) between the well head and the process platform. And the next step will be to bring alongside the West Phoenix and to connect to the mud pumps of the West Phoenix to <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:15). That could be done next week depending on weather conditions and the killing operation could start on the following days.</p>
          <p>That will lead normally &#x2013; people are pretty optimistic &#x2013; worldwide control specialists &#x2013; to get the stoppage of the leak as soon as the killing of the well. And then we'll proceed probably with the follow-up with definitely abandonment of <mark type="ph" /> OJ4 (30:43). We'll resume the operation from the rig, the one leaking as &#x2013; if possible.</p>
          <p>Well, that of course depends on the success of the killing operation and then we'll discuss with the authorities to get all the permits to resume work with the rig and then to perform complete abandonment of <mark type="ph" /> OJ4 (31:00). That's where we are at the moment, Jon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Thanks, Michel. But then theoretically, you would normally expect to be going through the process of a normal well abandonment and still have production operations ongoing, wouldn't you? So presumably, there must be a point at which the process of all of this is normalized and you can restart some production operations. I guess...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand your question, Jon. But let's be particular, let's do the killing first and then we'll assess the situation on the wells with the authorities and we'll certainly come back to you with some more guidance, as Patrick said, with regard to resuming the production. But today, we are progressing as per plan, some good success, and we hope the killing to be effective very soon now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Michel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd like to make two additional comments to be clear enough. My comment on downstream was including the petrochem sector. That was refining plus petrochem. And in order to be precise, also, I did not say that we will not restart before year-end. What I said is that in certain circumstances then our production could be flat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, right. Thanks for clarification.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line from Alastair Syme from Citi. Please go ahead. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Patrick. Can I just ask about the timetable for project sanctions to see if you've got a few notable things outstanding? I just wanted to know when we might expect some announcements on those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alistair. There is <mark type="indiscernible" /> (32:49) this year. Then you have Tempa Rossa, which is pretty soon. What's missing next? <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:08) end of this year. I think that's it for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The Shtokman, do you think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, you know, on Shtokman, the partner have decided to postpone any decision now to end of July. We are currently envisaging a project which will include only LNG, and the board of directors have decided to extend the agreement until first of July to evaluate the feasibility of this new project. And on top of that, the tax treatment is still under discussion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And were you anticipating to sanction anything in Canada at any point this year? On the heavy oils side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Next year. Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question comes from the line of Neill Morton from Berenberg. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good afternoon. Just one question, please. I was listening to the earlier questions on net CapEx and the dividend. I just wondered in this environment of rising capital intensity, whether Total would consider introducing a scrip dividend, as you used to do back in the 1990s. I just wonder what your thoughts were with regards to the pros and cons of a scrip dividend. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Honestly, this is not on the agenda.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A quick answer. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It was a short question and a quick answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Lucas Herrmann from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead, your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good afternoon, Patrick. Point of clarification and one other question. Clarification, maintenance, when you talk about 93,000 barrels a day of maintenance in Q2, is that relative to last year, is that relative to the first quarter, how do we think of that in the context of movement?</p>
          <p>And secondly, just on the downstream business and the specialties activities, how do they really fit within the organization as a whole now. How should we think about those activities over, say, or given a, say, four- to five-year view on where your downstream may or may not be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We always said that those are not core business of the company. But we are happy to have them within our business. They are delivering a good return on capital. They do not bring too much attention from the management. They are managed independently as they report to us and we check their reserves and the way they are managing the company and that's it. So it does not &#x2013; it's not a big deal for us, I would say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the maintenance, the 90 million &#x2013; sorry, the 90,000 barrel per day I was mentioning for Q2, we had in Q1 about 40,000 to 50,000 barrels per day. So you can compare the 90,000 barrels for Q2 to 40,000 to 50,000 barrels in Q1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's great. Thanks for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> It appears we have no further questions at this time so I'll hand the conference back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and I would like once again to thank you for your time. It has been an eventful time for the industry and for us, Total. We have said that we will be faced with challenges. And we know that we must respond quickly, professionally, and completely. I'm proud to say that Total has reacted with safety as our top priority. And that is for today and have a nice weekend. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation. This concludes today's conference and you may now disconnect your lines. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>