<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1532262" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-02-13</date>
    <companies>
      <company>596</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Martin Deffontaines</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Christophe de Margerie</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Patrick de la Chevardi&#xE8;re</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Peter W. Hutton</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies International Ltd.">Iain S. Reid</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Lydia R. Rainforth</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA (Broker)">Irene Himona</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">Alejandro A. Demichelis</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Martijn P. Rats</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Oswald C. Clint</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Jon Rigby</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Lucas O. Herrmann</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (United Kingdom)">Neill W. Morton</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (Europe) Ltd.">Jason D. Gammel</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Theepan Jothilingam</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, it's time to start now. Welcome to Total 2012 results and outlook. I'd like to welcome also those of you who are joining us via webcast.</p>
          <p>A few reminders before we start, in case of emergency you have two exit doors in this room, on the left of the room. Also per courtesy for everyone, if you could keep your electronic device on silent mode. Today we will have a presentation that will be followed by a Q&amp;A session. Again, thank you for your attention, welcome. And Christophe, the floor is yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Before I start, I'm very pleased to be back in this room. If you remember we were there before and then the floor fell, not on you, thank God. And in France we don't like when the sky falls on our head. So in Poland, a good one. That's okay. Martin?</p>
          <p>Okay. Well, good afternoon, everyone. Thank you, Martin. So Patrick, our CFO, you know him well, will present our 2012 results, and I will come back afterwards to summarize what we call the outlook. But first I will make some brief comments, sort of introduction.</p>
          <p>Compared to a year ago the worldwide economic situation is improving, and this creates a better environment for Total. The market in terms of oil prices has been relatively stable and well above $100 per barrel for more than two years now. Looking at 2012, despite the unexpected challenges we faced in the U.K. and in Nigeria and in Yemen, the Group delivered strong and competitive results.</p>
          <p>So as I say, I'm proud of our many accomplishments for the year. For example, in Upstream we started up six new projects and made significant discoveries in Argentina, Norway, Nigeria and in the Gulf of Mexico, I would say a plus. In the Downstream, our marketing activities remain robust. The Normandy upgrade was completed, and we are on track with the Jubail start-up. We reduced our gearing, strengthened the balance sheet and increased the dividend, which helped to give us for 2012 the best total shareholders return of the supermajors.</p>
          <p>What are we doing now? Our path forward is clear and we are focusing on execution. We are committed to delivering on time and in budget, the portfolio of more than 20 high-quality projects. We are moving fast with our $15 billion to $20 billion asset sale program. We have an exciting exploration program. We are restructuring the Downstream and before passing the microphone to Patrick I want to be clear that I am, that we are, very enthusiastic about our near term.</p>
          <p>Production is set to increase, and I'm pleased to announce that we are in the process of restarting Elgin in the coming days or weeks. I hope days. We are working on several giant exploration prospects, for example Ivory Coast and Kenya are drilling. We spudded in the last days and now soon Gabon. And we are on track to accelerate the growth of free cash flow to fund future growth and dividends. We have improved our visibility for growth, and we remain committed to being a safe and responsible world-class operator.</p>
          <p>It's an exciting time at Total. Now we'll have to prove it. Patrick, if you want to present the 2012 results, and I will follow up with the outlook.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. I'm quite pleased to have actually a strong set of results to talk about today. That's why I am presenting our results without any concern.</p>
          <p>Let's talk first with health, safety and environment. You know the priority of Total is to be a responsible company. We made significant progress in the rate of injury. Starting 2006, we were down by 18% last year. Of course, we had those big incidents in Elgin and Ibewa, but I think our response to these incidents were appropriate and efficient. We have incorporated lessons from both experiences in our safety culture. We have also improved our impact on emission, energy efficiency and we limit our footprint on local environment. We believe that acting responsibly is good for the business and good for the company.</p>
          <p>A few words about the environment, as you see, 2012 environment was generally favorable to our business. The average oil price for 2012 was about $110 per barrel. This is partially due to the growth in oil demand of about 0.8 million barrels per day despite the related weak economic environment we were facing. Natural gas price in Europe was about $9 per million BTU, $16 for Asia. Those are the two markets where we are more playing, that's why globally for both oil and gas, the environment was favorable to us.</p>
          <p>The competitive performance for 2012, Total 2012 adjusted net income was $16 billion. Our &#x2013; you see that on the graph in yellow or orange. The Downstream performance is improving. We captured the margin given by the market. The Upstream contribution is slightly lower due to partially weaker volume due to Elgin-Franklin and Ibewa and also Yemen disruption on the pipeline.</p>
          <p>There were also an impact of rising costs, mainly higher DD&amp;A, also on the new start-up. If you compare Total to the major companies, you see that we do compare favorably. The one on the left side is Shell; the other being Exxon, Chevron and BP. Basically what I'd like to say on this slide is that we were able to overcome the negative one-off event we had to face and that our stable performance was in fact very competitive in comparison to the others.</p>
          <p>We are on track to execute our $15 billion to $20 billion divestment program. We announced the Usan sale last year. We recently announced TIGF for &#x20AC;2.4 billion. The $15 billion asset sales program is already closed or well in progress. At Total we completely integrate the divestment program into our strategy, all terms are fungible, and we will reinvest the money for future growth.</p>
          <p>We had solid cash flow generation last year. We basically fund our organic investment of $23.8 billion, a dividend of $6.8 billion, maintaining all in all the gearing at a low level of 21%. We are pleased to report this strong cash flow in line with the previous year. We maintain our financial flexibility, and we are preparing for future growth without negatively impacting the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>A word on production, we think initially that 2012 was a tough year, particularly due to the Elgin-Franklin and Ibewa events. We also lose production from Syria. We had issue with the pipeline in Yemen. But in fact if you look at the right side of the slide, we compare favorably in comparison to our competitors.</p>
          <p>A word on exploration, we are continuing to a prospective acreage around the world, both onshore, offshore, in established area or frontier area. A few area which was pointed out by Christophe is Ivory Coast, Kenya, Gabon is not on this slide but we will drill it this year. We had successful operation in Argentina. We made &#x2013; this is one of the first discovery we made, discovery in the Gulf of Mexico, the North Platte discovery. And then we have in our garden I would say discoveries in Nigeria and Norway. The drilling campaign we have scheduled for 2013 gives a very high potential for important discoveries.</p>
          <p>You know the reserve is key for us, this is what we own. Our proved reserved base of 11.4 billion BOE represents more than 13 years of production. The organic replacement rate was 100%. Replacing reserve organically remained a key target for the company. The fee average on the right side of the slide, all in reserve replacement for the last three years, 2010 to 2012, was 136%, quite high figure, this includes Novatek.</p>
          <p>On the project you have the usual suspects that you know delivering the major project to achieve our targets. This is what we are focused on today. You are familiar with first name. I will point out CLOV, Laggan-Tormore and Ichthys. CLOV and Laggan-Tormore are examples of two major offshore projects, that's where we are the operator and that we are pushing hard to stay on time and on budget. Both projects are two-thirds complete and both are on schedule today. In fact, all the new stuff that we need to achieve our 2015 production target are either already producing or well advanced into development.</p>
          <p>LNG. LNG continues to be an important part of our Upstream story. This is representing 25% of the Upstream results today. Using 2007 as a basis, we increased LNG production by 40% if you compare 2012 to 2007 and by 2016-2017 we anticipate 17 million tons of LNG capacity for the group. About 70%, this is on the right side, 70% of our LNG is sold in Asia today. You remember the LNG price in Asia is quite high. And about 50% of our LNG cargo are currently redirected to Asia or to other destinations.</p>
          <p>Refining &amp; Chemicals, the downstream restructuring is having a positive affect despite volatility of the refining margin that you can see on the left side. The Refining &amp; Chemicals segments increased net operating results in 2012 up to $1.8 billion, up to plus 38% in comparison to 2010. Improving margin capture is key to sustain a better performance for the Refining &amp; Chemicals.</p>
          <p>Jubail, the Refining &amp; Chemicals segment is concentrating on major integrated platform. Jubail is one of them. We have a 37.5% interest in this project. It's 400,000 barrel per day refinery. The pre-commissioning is about 40% today. The start-up is proceeding as planned and the ramp up to nominal capacity should be achieved by end of this year. Once Jubail is fully operational, let's say by end of the year, it will be one of the most modern and efficient refineries in the world, able to capture the highest margin available in virtually all markets and all environments.</p>
          <p>Marketing &amp; Services, this include network specialties and other businesses, including solar and new energies. This segment contributed up to more than $1 billion of net operating income. This segment has a track record of delivering a stable stream of results and represents valuable assets for the group.</p>
          <p>What about our exploration for the next 12 months? And then I will give the floor to Christophe. This is one of the most exciting part of the Total story for 2013 with the high potential exploration programs that we are showing: Ivory Coast, Gabon, Angola, Kenya, Brazil, Argentina, French Guiana, Libya, Egypt, Australia and Indonesia. This map shows the location of the Big Cat and the Elephant-sized prospect we are targeting. We intend to drill more than 60 exploration well this year. We increased the budget by 10%, up to $2.8 billion, and 90% of the rig we need to drill those well are already under contract. And this finish my presentation.</p>
          <p>No, I have one more, about our net investments. Our budget for this year is $22 billion of net investments, $28 billion organic minus $6 billion of net asset sale. 80% of the budget is dedicated to Upstream. It is important to point out that we have expanded the resource base in the past years and now we are relying on exploration to create future development opportunities. We are confident of achieving the $6 billion net asset sales target. I mentioned to you that we announced Usan, we announced TIGF and those assets are currently under negotiation.</p>
          <p>Our strategy is to reinvest for future growth according to strict return criteria, which are based on conservative assumption of $80 per barrel for short-plateau conventional project and $100 per barrel for long-plateau projects. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, Patrick. It's good you ended with investment because I'd like to say that without investment, there is no cash and no profit, and especially when those investments are well controlled and definitely profitable. Well, that is the way you build the future of a dynamic company.</p>
          <p>So the outlook &#x2013; I like the title of this slide, because it means that in our world everything changed, but finally the impact on the, what we call, fundamentals is limited. What is changing you know, new production of tight oil, shale oil in the U.S., even more production of shale gas, all of this is having an impact of course on the U.S., especially on North America as a whole, but globally at the world level, it still remains, I would say, not only under control, but with limited impact on our view of the long term.</p>
          <p>You cannot have a vision, you cannot have a strategy of a group without having to tell your investors what are your views on price of energy. Here to make it short, Patrick told you that 2011- 2012, it was almost flat, average, at $111 per barrel for oil. Today we are at $120. We definitely consider in Total that to launch our projects to make budgets and plans is too high, and we need to be more conservative. So we're still using the $100 per barrel and even less when we consider that plateau might be short and maybe a little bit more risky. In that case, we use the $80 per barrel. But otherwise we don't see any reason to change this forecast when we see the result of all of those changes on the fundamentals.</p>
          <p>Fundamentals are clear. A lot of resources, much more than we thought, which is good news for our Energy sector, which is good news for the oil and gas companies, but at the same time concern about having accessible resources, having the capabilities to develop them and definitely it's the geo-politics, which is taking more and more importance in our business.</p>
          <p>If you look at this, you see that the capacities remain almost at the same level. We still consider that by the year 2020-2025 the not peak, because there is no more peak, thanks to all of those resources, but the capacities available will stay probably a little bit below $100 million per barrel, which means at the end, long-term dues, long-term projects, but at the same time still I will say little available capacities to cover the needs of the additional demand if needed.</p>
          <p>We consider the display capacity today, which are somewhere below 5%, and by the way, it's almost only Saudi Arabia, all other countries are producing at full speed. We see this for the year 2013 at around 2% to 4%, which is relatively low and historically low. And with this, and still I would say a strong demand coming from the world population growing; well, we definitely consider that, that is the best report for the price of oil the way we see it today. If we had to have something on the top, on the top it will be the cost of developing those resources and to move resources into reserves is getting higher and higher. And even if it's not the best part of the explanation, it's also give us report to those relatively high level.</p>
          <p>We like also to make a focus or zoom on LNG; first, because we always did it, so it will be surprising that we suddenly stopped. On the top there is a lot of debates on what could be the price of LNG with those new exports coming from the U.S. Well, first, that still needs to come. I've been told recently, but why don't you buy HH gas for export. I said, because there is still not yet an export. Now, it will come, that's part of our assumption. But when you look at the need on the right part of the slide, well, you see that for the demand the way we see it, which is almost double of what we have today by the year 2013, there's still almost 50% of the projects which have not yet been sanctioned.</p>
          <p>So, it's good to say that there will be gas available, but it still need to be developed. And you know that it's not always the easiest thing to do. So, we continue to invest. Yes, we will look for new opportunities. At the same time with a strict discipline, we are having on all of those giant projects, keeping our costs within budget and delivering on time. Today you know that production of LNG, the LNG business as a whole represents almost 25% of the result of our Upstream.</p>
          <p>Exciting pipeline of major start-ups, well I'll come back afterwards on our target for production growth. I know a lot of you here and I know a lot of you have still some concern about are they going to deliver? Well, we are going to deliver. Those projects by definition 2012 are already in production, but they are moving into, I would say, increased plateau. 2013, I mean, all the projects you have here have been or will be starting in the weeks and months to come, and the same for 2014, 2015 and 2016. All of this represents the 750,000 barrel per day of additional capacities, which means in fact production for Total, and that's where our new production are going to come from.</p>
          <p>On the top, there's been a debate on are we sufficiently OECD, non-OECD. Well, today we have from those new production, 50% coming from OECD. When you look at the total production of Total today, it's 45% OECD, 55% non-OECD, and our reserves, 2P reserves is almost 50%-50%. So with this, definitely we are moving into a production, which will be 50%-50% between OECD and non-OECD countries. What's important is, those projects are good, sound, profitable projects all over the world, and in all of our, I would say, skilled.</p>
          <p>So with this, that's why I started with the project and then I come to production and production targets, which is our commitment. We have announced last time when we have been discussing our strategy that our target for the year 2017 will be a production capacity target of 3 million barrels per day, which is a real challenge in a way. Today, you know that 2012, we have been producing 2.3 million barrels per day, but it represents, in fact during the two period 3% annual average growth of &#x2013; during the period 2015 &#x2013; 2011, 2015 and then reaching with remaining 2015, 2016 and 2017 the 3 million barrel per day target. Of course, it's not oil, it's oil and gas, which means oil equivalent.</p>
          <p>90% of the projects which are going to bring the 2017 production, now already in production or under development. It was 75% last time when we discussed it and projects still remaining to be decided, FIDs. One is in Angola and second one is Egina in Nigeria, and should be starting not production now, but getting the approvals which are still needed. And at the same time, we continue to reduce our lead-time rate. We used to talk about 4% to 5%, now we are at 3% to 4%; 2012, I think Patrick it was just below 4%, 3.8%. So, on track to achieve our targets. The same way for production; we did it for our investment.</p>
          <p>High-quality Upstream project, well that we continue with the message that you heard by Patrick. They still lot of say on the new project of Total are not profitable enough. They are. And definitely, they are better than the one of our competitors. That's not coming from Total sources, I insist on this, it's coming from Wood Mackenzie and that's where the figures are coming from. So, if you look at the rate of return, we are the best-of-the-class in terms of NPV among the leaders, which is important as that represent definitely large investment program, but under control, especially on a net basis.</p>
          <p>And what's even more important, we still are moving on a very strict discipline for those projects first, at the time of the decision-making process, and then in the way we operate those fields. So, of course, you can tell me we don't operate all of the fields, but even when we don't operate, we are looking carefully at the way our partners are doing it. So, investing with discipline and expertise for profitable growth, that's definitely the strategy of the group, definitely as Patrick said it again, in the Upstream first, we use 80% of our investment.</p>
          <p>What will be the foundation for 2017 plus? Because I mean that's already what we are working. I won't say that 2017 is already done, but at least it's decided, I told you 90%. Here Patrick told you about the expectation we have for 2013 in terms of exploration, exploration targets. Here we're talking about risk exploration, the figure &#x20AC;5 billion was non-risk; risk which mean that we have this percentage which is usually depending on what time we're drilling, what between 15% and 30% of the probability of success. That give us for the period after 2017 with the new acreage we have been taking, potential of 6 billion barrels equivalent. That will be definitely an important part of the replacement of our reserves.</p>
          <p>Production base of our resources. Our resources have been continuing to increase. Now, we are at more than 45 years of resources. But again, it's true, they are only resources, but our 2Ps have been also increasing the same way our 1P. What's important is to continue to deliver our potential growth on where we have today, what we call our production base, which is the deep offshore brownfield development like in the North Sea and satellites tie-backs, which are important to bring what we call small fields, small reserves connected with existing facilities and on a marginal basis, even if they are not used.</p>
          <p>Figures in terms of size, it represents a lot of cash and a lot of profits. And still keeping what is needed for a company like Total, keeping this long-term plateau projects which are making the cash and the sustainability of the company, giant fields, LNG, unconventional, oil sands in Canada. That's the long term, but if we can do it as we presented in an acceptable way, a sustainable way, that's definitely also part of what will be the future of the energy industry and the one of Total.</p>
          <p>Not to talk only about Upstream, even if Upstream is the priority of our businesses, we decided at the beginning of 2012 to restructure our Downstream and especially to bring together Refining &amp; Chemicals to get the benefit of what we call important industrial platforms, but even more, to get the synergies and definitely to see that definitely this businesses are really very, very equivalent, especially when you compare the Refining business and the Base Chemical business. When you talk about, I mean, polymers, it becomes a little bit different, but at least that is what we're doing today in Gonfreville in France or in Antwerp or in other places like Jubail. We always try to move more and more into integrated platforms, which means Refining &amp; Chemicals.</p>
          <p>Next slide, we'll not make it in &#x2013; I mean, I think it's better to be commented on a one-to-one, but just keep something in mind, we said, let us note what we said, we have 6% ROACE in 2010, and we said that we will try to achieve a 13% ROACE in 2015 using the same environment of the one in 2010. If you do this, we still keep the four categories of where we see the improvement of our profitability. It starts with what we call the new major projects on main platform, plus 1.5%, then Specialty Chemicals plus 1%, portfolio changes 2%, and synergies and efficiency 2.5%. That's not new. What's important is we are now producing it and showing it to you in the most transparent way what has been already achieved since 2010, what is to be achieved in 2013, that's the light blue, and what remains to be done, which is the white part.</p>
          <p>So glass half empty, half full. Some prefer that it is already all blue, but if it is all blue as far as at that time I will be not only surprised, but I will be sad. It proves that we still have to improve, especially things on synergies, and if we follow this program, we should definitely get this 13% target done as we've said by 2015. What is important again is to see that it has been working, and what was still considered as something new and a kind of challenge moving together the refining and the petrochemical proved already to be a success. And we can say now after a little bit more than one year of experience, it's working as one group, one entity, just like it would have been always like this.</p>
          <p>Cash flow to support our investment strategy, while it's a follow up of 2012 and 2013, we have been using a different period, which you know. Today we are in the period 2012-2014, where we still are investing large amounts, keeping the investment that's under control at $22 billion. But at the same time we see the benefit in 2015-2017 of the large cash flows coming from the projects, which will be on production at that time. And you see, if you see the right part of the slide that the &#x2013; what we call the cash flow coming from operations is definitely covering much more than what we need to pay a dividend. So then it will be to be discussed on what will be the best way to use this extra cash.</p>
          <p>But what is important, it gives us all the flexibility to pursue our competitive dividend growth, our strategy based on dividend. And at the same time keeping our financial position, our balance sheet, as strong as it can be which is the case today. You notice that our gearing at the end of 2012 is at 21%, it went 2% below the figure of 2011. And definitely on the top with very low interest rates. I mean, that give us at the same time the flexibility and definitely very low cost of financing.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we are executing our $20 billion, $25 billion program. It's clear today that we are moving much more to the $25 billion than the $20 billion. I would say that the $20 billion is not already in the pipeline, but almost; so this is considered for us as being part of our strategy. The strategy of the company is not plus, minus to be compared in different way, it's a combination of the two.</p>
          <p>We have been successfully doing important divestment recently. That will continue not only 2013, but also in 2014 and 2015, and probably more because as you know, the intent in this strategy is not to reduce our investment; even if it does, but it's much more also to have real, I would say, wish to sell and buy assets when we consider that they should be sold, good market is giving it probably more value than we can and we don't see any long-term benefit in keeping them in our portfolio, which just mean making it a lively, I would say, management of our investment. And that will continue over the years.</p>
          <p>So, rebalancing our capital employed, well, that's just a result of what has been our strategy during the past years. Well, two figures to keep in mind. In 2007 we were at 50% of capital employed coming from Upstream. In 2017 it will be 80%. In 2012, 75%. At the same time, Patrick told you we have capital employed at 75%, but investment at 80%. That's why we moved to 80% in 2017. And what's important too, and which is linked definitely with the startup of our new projects, what we call the non-producing assets percentage, is going back to the figure we had in 2007, so 22%. It's at a peak in 2012 at 35% and goes back to 22% in 2017. What is the right figure for this? I don't know. In the past we used to say it was between 20% and 25%. That's what we are.</p>
          <p>At the same time, I think it's important that we can explain to our investors, to our shareholders why sometimes it's better to be with a higher level and sometime with a lower level. It also depends on opportunities. And what is important again is to bring new projects and new production with cash and profits.</p>
          <p>On the Upstream capital employed, while that's just a small look on OECD and non-OECD, we are in 2017 at 45% coming from OECD, 55% coming from non-OECD. At the same period reserve will be 50%-50%. So you see, which is normal, but there is a link between the two. But again I still think it's more important than to be OECD or non-OECD is to be in countries where you feel you are confident to be in a position to respect your code of conduct. Definitely be I would say in a position to secure your people and your business, and of course to be almost certain that the government will be keeping some long-term views on the way they tax companies. That's always the message I'm delivering here in the U.K., but I know the message has been already received by the Chancellor.</p>
          <p>So strong financial position and dividend policy, well that's the result of the past years, gearing and moving from 27% in 2009 to 21% in 2012. We keep our target between 20% and 30%. It's clear today that we are much more on the 20%, 25% level. The net debt is by definition in line with what I'm saying. We have good access to the capital markets. Patrick and his team have been doing, I would say, quite successful emissions in the recent past, especially on the U.S. domestic market. So it give us, if needed, an even more good defense of confidence and trust for the future.</p>
          <p>You have the Total shareholders return. We call it TSR. On that one, it's the opposite of some of the slides we've seen. We have the name of the companies because it's official peers. They are not published by Total. So you know that the return is based on the mix of the yield and the value of the stock during a year. Well, on 2012, Total has been the first. Okay. You can tell me in advance, what about 2011 or what about &#x2013; okay. But let's take it one by one. In 2012, that's what it was, and not what I've heard. So that's good news for our shareholders. I am talking with what we call <mark type="indiscernible" /> (45:17) in France, well they know this figure and they are quite happy with it.</p>
          <p>Well, of course we don't take into account the buyback shares program. I leave it as a debate for the one-to-one meetings because it's much more philosophy than anything else. Here we're talking about cash directly to our shareholders with the, if we can, improvement in the share value. So committed to operating in a responsible manner. Well, that's as we told you not only communication, it's really now part of our strategy. It's based on commitments vis-&#xE0;-vis the population where we have to operate. It's not always an easy subject.</p>
          <p>On the left part you have a lady who represent in a brilliant way the country which is famous, Myanmar. It proved that without being provocative, our long-term strategy to say that it will be working, it's worth staying. Well, we were pleased to hear this directly from the mouth with the voice of the lady Nobel Prize. We have to make it note of this a source of pride, but I mean it's true that if we can prove that it's worth continuing developing our activities even when countries are entering into difficult periods, we can't make it in respecting people and being at the end respected.</p>
          <p>Respecting the environment is always respect. That's part of our commitment and to start with everything which is linked with CO2 emissions. So we have a lot of new commitments that you will see in our, what we call SER report based on flaring, based on water and all concerned about emissions and definitely the climate change.</p>
          <p>Access to energy; well, that's our first commitment is to deliver energy to our clients, to the people on earth. It's building our strategy and relationship on long-term partnership, that's what we're doing in a lot of countries, in Africa, in Middle East, but also in Latin America. Well, I will say everywhere we operate, we definitely try to be always in close cooperation with local companies and local governments. At least then we can talk to them and definitely, which is important and expected from any company when you work somewhere, it's important that you are part of the local development, local becoming more and more country and less and less only the local part surrounding your activities.</p>
          <p>In a lot of countries, being recently in Africa, we are developing this new philosophy, new politics is to really go and help for what is needed. One of the best example is those five schools, which we have been creating and developing in Angola. It's not only good for us; it's good for the country. But at the end, it could also become one day employees of Total. So that means definitely if you fast-forward, we have to make this exploration strategy for success.</p>
          <p>Plus we told you about all the new acreage we took, the more than 60 wells in 2013, several wells being already spudded. That's to give results after the one of 2011 and 2012. And we might even see the possibility of being more active also on how we could buy and sell acreages, which we have been taking quite often at 100% basis. They are a source of commerce, a source of swaps, a source of making money and looking for the best, I would say, future reserves.</p>
          <p>Delivering the next generation of projects; well, that's 2017 plus. Already, we have large scope in front of us. I would say most of our teams are well under, I mean, doing their job properly, but it takes time. We have now to prepare the longer term, that's underway, and without forgetting that we still are an integrated company, moving quickly on improving the profitability of all of our Downstream. That is the case on Marketing. On Refining &amp; Chemicals we have to pursue this program of being ready to be faced with probably more and more competition. And that's the reason why we need to start not only now, we need to continue and to be in a position where &#x2013; I mean including with the additional competition we proved and we can prove that even if it is a small part of our capital employed, it can be a way to make money.</p>
          <p>And at the top, never forget that most of the countries where we operate, we are asked to come as a global partner and not only as a team; they're looking for partners knowing on how to invest in petrochemicals, in refining. It doesn't mean that we will always say yes, but when we can help and definitely making it profitable, it's a plus. Never forget this, especially when you want to answer it to new countries or to restart your investment in countries where they need help to restart the development and the growth of countries which have been hurt by wars like Iraq, like Libya, like some others, but again, in a responsible and sustainable manner and giving priority to the security of our staff first.</p>
          <p>That's the end of the outlook presentation after the presentation of 2012 and 2013 made by Patrick. And now we are ready, the two of us, and if needed some other person in this room to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Peter Hutton from RBC. Just two quick questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Wait a moment, wait a moment. Ladies and gentlemen, for the Q&amp;A once given the go ahead by Christophe, I will ask you if you don't mind to stand up to present yourself. And please restrict yourself to one questions &#x2013; to one question in order to give the opportunity to your colleague to participate. Okay. Sorry for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. I'm sorry. Peter Hutton from RBC. Just some definitional questions on the cash flow guidance that you give on page 25, can I just check what exchange rate you're using? Is it $1.3? Because when I'm looking at the average 2012 to 2014, it looks like about $28 billion average. So about $21.5 billion, 22 billion in euros, which it looks around flat from where you were in 2012 over the remaining two years in that period. So just questioning what the exchange rate is? And also I note that last year was $110 Brent and you're using $100 Brent. What's the kind of sensitivity of that extra $10 on Brent?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We use 1.3 euro-dollar exchange rate. For our project we use two oil price scenario, the $80 per barrel scenario for short plateau, the $100 per barrel scenario for long plateau. That's basically the main sensitivity we use to assess our project. The sensitivity for $10 per barrel for our cash flow is $1.7 billion of cash flows.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the top, the euro-dollar rate has a limited impact on our accounts, of course not for the &#x20AC;1, but you know that our dollars accounts now will be much more reflecting the situation of the company. The euro-dollar rate has an impact on refining and for all activities which are in Europe, so it's mainly Downstream. What I said that in Upstream the impact of the euro-dollar is really, really limited to nothing except for converting the dollar into euro.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. One can add that the Brent sensitivity increased because of taxes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Iain Reid from Jefferies. Christophe, couple of questions, please. You don't talk much about the Canadian oil sands mining projects any more, and also Uganda, two projects which have obviously got some challenges. Could you explain where you think the challenges are from your point of view? And what sort of volumes you're expecting from those two in your 2017 target? And a kind of related question, in Nigeria, Egina, which has also been delayed in terms of FID, is that purely a kind of project management issue? Or is there any influence of the PIB on your decision making there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On Canada and Uganda, I mean, it's not that I want to avoid it. We are working hard on it because it's not the easiest part of our portfolio, not only in terms of environment, but also in terms of cost. So we have been, as you know, working largely with Suncor to see the synergies between our two groups, and to in a way rejoin the development of Fort Hills and Joslyn. That's underway. As you probably know, there are discussions on what we should do or not do with the upgrader we wanted to develop, which is Voyageur, but you know sometimes it's important that you take the time to keep your cost under control and to make sure that you are taking the right decision.</p>
          <p>Things have changed when I said the globally the fundamentals have not changed. Well, they have changed in North America, as I said. And not only for the price of oil WTI versus Brent, but also with the fact that bringing new additional condensate from the States to Canada, it's changing the probably the environment. And due to this, some aspects have to be reviewed. But at the same time, it's still part of our production by 2017. So we've delayed it. It's part of our also forecast, so it's already included, I mean the delay.</p>
          <p>But what's important is to see the existing production moving along. That's the case of our project with ConocoPhillips and for the rest it will take a little bit more time. But when we talk about the potential development of long-term plateau for after 2017, definitely you will find Canada. And I hope at that time, based on a sustainable way of developing those reserves, which as you know today are at a cost per barrel, which is not far off $90 per barrel. So it's always worth making sure that we are not making any mistakes. But again, it's part of our long-term reserves. So we will discuss it on a regular basis, but there is nothing to hide on that.</p>
          <p>You talked about Uganda, too, no?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on Uganda it's a little bit different because it's not heavy oil, even if it's waxy but that's not the same. Well, the discussions today are much more with the government. So everything is ready to start, but they still are discussing at the government level and between the parliament and the government on what should be the development of a refinery, you know the subject. And we've said very clearly to the authorities that if the outlets of the production of Uganda are &#x2013; is a refinery in land, I mean, there will be no project. So I can't be more transparent than to say, if we cannot achieve to have a pipe to be able to export the production to the seas through Kenya or Tanzania, but more probably Kenya, this project, I mean we'll be, I don't know, we might have to consider of what we do. But no pipe, no project. Today we still are waiting for getting the approval of the pipe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Egina?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Egina?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Egina.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Egina. Well, Egina is going to be starting very soon. I mean that's &#x2013; I mean the last question was on the tendering of the EPC contract between two Korean's company, I'm not going to answer in too details. It's classical in our operation. We have now reached an agreement with the authorities. So, the announcement of the FID is really a question of not months, less.</p>
          <p>This lady first and then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Lydia Rainforth from Barclays. I have &#x2013; my question concerns cash flow, it comes in two parts, if I could. Firstly just following up on the earlier question on the cash flow levels, it does look like to achieve the average $32 billion to $33 billion you're talking about, 2012 to 2014 that you do need quite a big step-up in cash flow from 2012 levels. How comfortable are you that, that is actually achievable with the production levels that you have? And then secondly just picking up, Christophe, on something you said about it being a dollar company and just around the dividend and that it's set in euro terms. Is there any consideration of actually setting that in dollar terms?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can answer about the cash flow. Yes, we are comfortable with the cash flow average for 2012-2014. We show in the back that our net investment was maintained at $22 billion level, and we will continue and maintain it. And as I was mentioning in my presentation, sale of asset is definitely part of our program. The dividend in dollar, you want answer this? This is your favorite question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is, but just because it give us a chance to talk for hours on something which I cannot predict because I mean definitely the dividend is still and has to be assessed in euro because we are a French company. So we have no right to say it's a dollar dividend. And then it's true that when you receive the dividend, you might have plus or minus, depending on the euro-dollar rate. So that's why we tried to tell our investors, we give you in advance date when you will be receiving your dividend in dollars. You know that it's in euro. You know in advance the amount which will be paid by the company, so try to find a solution if you want to avoid the exchange risk to cover the dividend.</p>
          <p>But I have no way for the time being of telling you that we could make it a dollar dividend. It's not legal. Sometime we try to improve things in making it in a quarterly basis, so it helps for the &#x2013; our, I'd say, U.S. investors or those who are using dollars also as their currency to predict everything, because it's smaller amount and with definitely dates the chart shorter than being just on a year basis. But again, I'm always very happy when I see that you receive more in dollars than you should, because of the improvement of the euro, which is the case today. But if it's not the case, so for the time being no chance we can escape from the euro dividend. But we like to do, but we don't do it anymore, I remember we used to say when it was good to say that the dividend was increasing thanks to the dollar/euro rate, we were making it as you see it's an important increase. We don't do this anymore. So 3.5% increase in euros.</p>
          <p>You, and then &#x2013; please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Irene Himona at Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Christophe, you referred to the 2017 target of 3 million barrels a day as a capacity target. Of course this is an industry where things like Yemen and Elgin can and do happen. So I just wanted to clarify, is the 3% targeted growth to 2015 capacity or a production target? And if it is production growth, then what sort of capacity utilization do you internally assume in terms of contingencies? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It helps to give additional explanation. That's why we are splitting, if I could say this, the period in 2015 and then 2017. The 3 million barrels per day capacity is in 2017. So, looking at all the pipeline of new projects coming on stream, and those projects are delivering their production. Those projects are part of the investment if we are talking about today, and those are going to bring the additional cash to the company.</p>
          <p>Now it's true that it's difficult to predict what's happening in Yemen, even if we think the situation is improving there. I mean, recently, I mean, two attacks have been stopped by the army before they had any damage on the pipe. So we hope that we are now entering into a new era. Cross your fingers. But that's definitely not part of the capacities as you can imagine.</p>
          <p>For 2015, where we have this 3% increase, I mean, that is based on production. Now, I mean, if there is some major events stopping it, it will be stopped, but the impact is not the same that not bringing production from new projects. I would insist to say, what counts are those new projects, because that's those on which we're investing. So it's important that they deliver the growth and value. But when we say, and you know this, I've been discussing this often with you, that we first replace our production, which is roughly 900 million barrels equivalent per year. I mean, that's already new production. So the decline, when we face it, is with new production, new investment and new value. So, in fact, the additional production doesn't start from the level you had the year before. It starts including the decline, and we are today capable to reduce the decline. So yes, the 3% average we believe in it.</p>
          <p>Now on the 3 million barrels per day in 2017, as I told you, it's a challenge. What I mean, as far as we are working on existing new projects, that's what will be delivered, and we are absolutely confident in bringing those projects on stream and on time. Now all those things which might happen in between, well, I'd like to say that we are capable to predict or to make it as an average of &#x2013; no, I will never do this. I mean, I don't think it's good to say, we'll have a percentage of problems on our fields and that's part of our dividend plan. I have difficulties with this.</p>
          <p>Again, Elgin, we've said it, when we had the switch, the leak has not changed the reserves, so the value of the company has not changed, depending what I have been reading. I mean, I don't know, still by the way how those figures have been produced, but we stopped the leak. We are now restarting the production. It will take a little time to go back to the previous level, but the reserves are still there.</p>
          <p>So there is no reduced value certainly in terms of cash, to get in now, but on the long run the value of Elgin remains what it was. And as you know, before this explosion happened, we were &#x2013; at that time we were announcing that reserve would be probably more than expected. Well, it's not the right time to say this anymore, let's restart, and then we will re-discuss on what is the future of the additional reserves of Elgin-Franklin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Alejandro Demichelis from Exane BNP Paribas. Coming back to the cash flow and dividend question, given your 2015-2017 target of cash flow at $40 billion, is quite a big difference between what your net investment is going to be and what your cash flow is going to be. So what's your priority for that cash use? And probably as a follow-up is, what is the level of disposals that you're using in terms of getting to that net gain investment level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You mean after 2017?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. You target is 2015-2017.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, our priority today is &#x2013; there is no priority, I mean, the priority &#x2013; I mean, the company has its long-term plan. We cannot change it every day, so we have our investments, as you call them organic, then divestment, that's investment based on which we are very strict, and we keep it at $22 billion, and that's the commitment of the company and proved to be realistic. Then we have our strategy on small policy on dividend. We increased the dividend by 3.5%. We have a payout, which is just below 44% in 2012, which give us certain flexibility on the average on the long-term, which is 50%.</p>
          <p>So the priority is to do everything. I mean, I cannot say priorities to pay dividend and not doing investment. Definitely, I mean, if we do provide the company, which means our shareholders with good projects, well, there will be the return to pay additional dividend. And when you see the period 2015-2017, you see that there is an additional cash on the top of the $7 billion, which represent the level of the today dividend. What will be at that time the use of those "additional cash flow," but I don't like the word additional cash flow. It's not additional. It's the cash flow available. So what you do with it? Well, either you reduce your gearing or you increase dividend, or you do both, or you think about something nice. But I mean, I shall not say even this, because when we say, he said, oh what is he having in mind? Nothing at all. Organic growth is for the time being absolutely enough to cover our pressure to deliver growth in a profitable way to our shareholders, but no priority. If I could say in a way that the priority are first salaries, we need to pay our employees, especially the one of Patrick, he is very stingy, but &#x2013; I was joking on this...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm waiting to 2015.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Better wait. But seriously, I mean, dividend and investment are the same priority, and have to be living together. I will never tell you that I will pay dividend without investment and the opposite. So, we have to prove that, we have the cash for delivering the two, and when you see the gearing at 21%, frankly, I mean, it's difficult to consider that the group is facing any concern about its flexibility to cover, I mean, even things which today could be considered as in our view not doable. I'm talking about a short drop on oil price, maybe, you never know; you cannot predict. We're in a world which is becoming more and more volatile. But at the same time, when you look at the assumptions, what is difficult also to see certain people are going to see that the barrel might be back one day at $75, I don't know what. Well, for the time being it's more than $110. It's $120. We don't take it as for granted, but at least what it is. So before talking about $75, let's enjoy the $120 and be optimistic.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Lanugage] (01:13:11 &#x2013; 01:03:14)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, hello, it's Martijn Rats from Morgan Stanley. I just wanted to ask you brief two questions. In terms of the improvement in the guidance for operating cash flow that you're thinking at, what share of that is coming from the downstream, particularly with the Jubail refinery coming on stream? Is there any way sort of giving an order of magnitude? I know the &#x2013; you've quantified the improvement in return on capital employed, but in terms of additional cash flow, something sort of an indication would be helpful?</p>
          <p>And the second question I wanted to ask is about the macro outlook, where you have a bullish view on oil markets. At the same time over the last couple of months we've seen various forecasts from the IAEA, EIA, OPEC, the BP Energy outlook which at least maybe not between now and 2030, but at least over the next couple of years are calling for a much more significant build in spare capacity, and a declining call on OPEC. Between your internal forecast and those forecasts, where would you see the difference that sort of gives you the confidence that that spare capacity build will not happen or at least not to the same extent, is it in Iraq or is it somewhere else? Any comments on that would be much appreciated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, I wouldn't say that we are bullish, because when we use $180 and the price is $120, if you call that bullish, well, I don't know what it means, that's the opposite and it's at a time where we decided Total to be even more drastic with our teams to say don't forget that it's $100 and not more; and don't be too much focusing on the price today because this might not be sustainable at that level. It's the time where the price moved to $120, okay, can I say bad luck, no; it's good luck, especially if you work on $100, because it means that all the $20 is additional cash. And that's what happened last year. And this was last year we had finally better results on cash because we have been getting the benefit of the $111, which is not $100. So I would not say that we are bullish.</p>
          <p>Now, you hear so many things in the market which is normal. I was in Davos and we have had this discussion, Saudi Aramco which is now one of our best partner, we exchange all information, and extremely good relationship. But we are surprised to hear that OPEC did not exist anymore, but they are existing, because today which is the country which is making all the move? It's Saudi Arabia. And they have been very well driving the problem we face with Iran. If they were not able to increase their production very quickly to face the fact that Iran dropped its export by more than 1 million barrels per day, the price of oil would have been at $200. And I don't know who would be saying it's going at $60, but I can tell you if Iran stops exporting it will go up. And that's life.</p>
          <p>When we talk about spare capacities, look at IAEA. They are absolutely in line with what we say, for two reasons. First, they have been creating some kind of nervousness recently in raising their targets for production of coal, but instead of using the same 2013 year for the target, they've been using 2020. So it's very difficult to match the two because they have one of 2020, one of 2030; of course it's done on purpose because they don't have the answer. But they've increased finally the proportion of coal versus other sources of energy. Why? Because the price of coal is very low. And whatever you say about being bullish or not bullish, I don't know what it is, but when the price of coal is so cheap in the U.S. and can go to Germany at a cheaper price than gas, people are using coal and not gas. And that's not Total, that's the market forces.</p>
          <p>So just to go back to these capacities available, we have and will use it again the slide which we usually use for the, what we call the, strategy meetings which are taking place in September. We have the slide when you see the spare capacities with a line, which is more optimistic, and a line less optimistic. On the more optimistic, you we have efficiency; you have the additional production, which means that the 5% is moving to 6% or 7%. And then we used something which has just delayed the projects, thank God not of Total, but of our competitors, by what was it, six months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>By six months, you lose more than 3% spare capacities. I mean, I think that people don't have in mind those things. They talk about fundamentals, just like if it was based on X billion. It's behind operations. Behind you have capacity to develop those fields, behind they have the cost of project we have been talking of, behind this you have a lot of delays in FIDs, behind of this you have geopolitics triggering a delay in approvals. And when you take all of this, it's nothing to do with being pessimistic/optimistic. It's just being real. And what I'm trying to do when I speak, being in Davos or elsewhere, I speak as a man of the industry. I'm not using billions of reserves coming from I don't know where. I use the U.K., I would say, formula of dividing an acreage by reserves, and you will find the production. That doesn't even work in Saudi Arabia. I've been told many times that I mean, Saudi Arabia would be 20 million barrels per day. I've been treated almost of a liar if not stupid. I mean, now nobody says anymore, it will be 20 million barrels. Nobody. But I've been hearing it for these 10 years. 20 million barrels, 20 million barrels, 20 million barrels. Now it's 12 million barrels. And everybody says it's 12 million barrels. You're right. Even the Iraqi government decided recently for all of their projects one-by-one to reduce the production target. Is that Total? Is that Christophe de Margerie saying that's what we want? That's what it is. So nothing to do with being bullish, just being pragmatic, looking at fear, being conservative in what we use to launch our new project, 100% with 80%, that's we consider sound. If we can get more, it's good for us. If it will be less for a period of time, we have also flexibility to cover this kind of momentum. At the same time, looking at the cost of projects, the cost of developing new barrels, the resistance will be certainly there. First and second OPEC, because at the opposite of certain brilliant spirits, OPEC still exists. It's called Saudi Arabia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm trying to answer your first question about cash flow coming from downstream. In 2012, the cash flow from operation coming from downstream was about $4 billion. By 2015 with the expected increase in the return on capital employed by up to 13%, we expect to increase the cash flow from operations by $2 billion to $3 billion. Just to give you a magnitude, Jubail in 2012 environment will generate about $800 million of cash flow per year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To give you an additional vision, I will say the, for the downstream we are entering a period where downstream will be source of cash for the rest of the group. I know sometimes we have a problem to explain that it's not because you have high levels of return that it means no cash. If you remember the old days of Total, during the 1990s, the downstream has been financing the upstream, thanks to the cash from downstream, thanks to the depreciation, et cetera. So I mean, what's happening to Jubail is very good example. We have with Jubail with now Gonfreville and Port Arthur in the U.S., made most of what we had to do in terms of new investment. There are still investment to come probably if we can reach an acceptable agreement with all the parties involved in Antwerp, but most of our big investment is now behind us. Now we want to get the benefit of the new organization and also new project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Oswald Clint, Sanford Bernstein. Question on exploration please, you've added a lot of acreage in the last couple of years in quite a lot of countries. You've got a big reliance on exploration to fill the hopper at the back. Could you be a bit more specific and say how much oil and gas did you find last year in those four significant discoveries? And is it enough? And does it give you confidence and a reliance on an almost greater exploration from here? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's on the OpEx.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:23:01).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:23:02). Well, I mean in 2012 we have not been drilling a lot of what we call new acreages. The real start is now on with Ivory Coast, with Kenya, with even if it is not being announced yet, but soon to be announced, Togo. So that is part of what we call our new additional volunteer of increasing the exploration program. So we will see the result there. What Patrick told you that it represents for 2013, 5 billion barrels of oil equivalent. What is the mix in those 5 billion between oil and gas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>55% oil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Be careful, it's exploration. So 50%/50% is not bad. 55%/45% or more is a little bit embarrass, but again if you remember in our production of gas, today we have 40% of that gas coming from oil-related formulas. So when you see the split between oil and gas in Total in terms of production, you have to look at it also in terms of what is the marketing of this gas. Is it on local market? Domestic prices? Or oil related, Oil related today is 40%. Jon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Jon Rigby from UBS. Can I &#x2013; in the old days you used to talk about technical costs. I understand why you've dropped them, because it doesn't really measure what you're doing. But I note that your depreciation charge in the upstream has gone up by about 20% this year over last year. So a two-part question. So part A is, can you just explain what the moving parts of that are this year? Is it just new projects coming on that have dramatically changed your DD&amp;A, and what would those be? And then the second is, I note that your CapEx in the upstream is now running at over three times your depreciation. So, can we expect this sort of profound change in DD&amp;A to impact earnings over that period, so the 2016-2017 that you tend to refer to in the framework of cash flow? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will leave it to Patrick for a part but first on exploration, it is true that in 2012 while we have been increasing the exploration being depreciated, and if I'm correct it represents something like $500 million additional of charges. But I mean, when you are more active on exploration, well it's normal that you have more charges. As far as you are not always successful before you get the benefit of the new barrels, you first have the non-benefit of drilling more, so the unsuccessful part is being charged to your profit and loss. But I mean, I don't consider until further notice that it is bad news. It's just the result of our strategy. When we increased the budget from $2.2 billion to $2.8 billion, I mean that's part of the reason.</p>
          <p>On the DD&amp;A before Patrick answers, we have been not disclosing the technical costs this time. We will do it again in September. The reason was we didn't get the figures of our competitors; so we have ours, we don't have theirs. Definitely you're right in saying that they are increasing for the DD&amp;A reason, but we are totally certain that's the case for everybody. So Patrick, maybe you might say more now, but you will get the full presentation as usual in September.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you're right that DD&amp;A increased. The technical cost which is about $23 per BOE include $2 per BOE increase in DD&amp;A in 2012. We expect the DD&amp;A to increase by about 10% in 2013 and then to plateau.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is linked with the capital employed producing, non-producing. I will not forget you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Lucas Herrmann, Deutsche Bank. In a way following on from Jon's question, when we look at cash flow we can see that your expectation is for broadly a 50% or so increase in operating cash over the course of 2000 &#x2013; or through the 2015-2017 period and now. If I was to ask you what your expectations are for net income over the same period, wherein I'm trying to take account of what's actually going to be happening to depreciation and what's going to be happening to the difference between tax paid and accounting tax, could you give us some indication, Patrick, of how you see accounting profits for want of a better phrase, nice income moving over a similar period relative to that 50% improvement in cash?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Net income will grow, but at a lower pace than the cash flow. The return on capital employed will increase beyond 2015, 2016, 2017 and as I was mentioning to you, the net income will grow at a lower pace because of the DD&amp;A. But the DD&amp;A will plateau at 2015 and beyond.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look at the slide with the high-quality Upstream projects, so you will see that our new projects are getting an IIR which is at the upper level and that's how you calculate your income at the end. But be careful with technical cost. Technical costs cannot mean directly that you will have less profits, it depends where it is and by whom it's spent. and sometimes people are seeing that we have too many production sharing contracts. Well the good thing with production sharing contracts, the technical cost is paid by the government. So for instance in Angola, if you have an increase in technical cost, it will not have a direct impact on your bottom line. It will have one, of course, but less than because it's not directly $2 less, it's $2 after tax, after splits between profit oil and between the different partners. So to answer to this on the technical cost, you really have to look at it on a contract-per-contract basis.</p>
          <p>But I mean I will not be so pessimistic to say that, of course, if you have higher technical costs, you cannot have a positive impact on your profits. But at the same time, it can be really reduced, even sometimes to nothing, if it is part of a system where you recover all of your cost through allowances. So again, look at it in details. That is the only way. I always say this when I'm presenting the different figures between Total and our peers because it's good to say that we are usually below them. And it's good, and we have to continue, all the industry is definitely climbing. But again, look at it on a case-by-case basis because it's very different when it happens in the North Sea or when it happens in Angola, and especially today with higher taxes, it's not good for our today's results, but then the impact of additional cost is also less important because it's probably paid by states.</p>
          <p>And you really need to have a look at it like Norway; in a way where in Norway we have 78% of tax rate marginal. You have had very high price of very high cost recently, huge inflation, but on the bottom line the impact has been relatively limited, thanks to the system where you can start depreciating at the time you start developing and not at the time you stop producing. So one-by-one you have to go straight, and at the end you will see that the impact is not as big as this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Patrick, I'm just going to come back to you on tax. Is there a build in the differential between accounting tax, for want of a better phrase, and tax paid as we move through this period of very heavy investment, much higher capital allowances and a significant benefit one would have expected to your cash flow statement relative to your P&amp;L?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The tax rate for Upstream, I'm talking about, remain about &#x2013; if I have a look to the long-term plan, the tax rate for Upstream remains stable at about 59% over the period. This answer I think your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For $100?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For $100 per barrel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If it moves to $120, it will be more, but that's good news, I mean for the producers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Neill Morton with Investec. You're clearly moving into a higher growth phase over the next few years, but one of your slides shows that the capital employed not in service is falling back to a more normal level by 2017. Is it fair to assume then that your growth rates will fall beyond that period? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you remember first that &#x2013; I mean that's why today we are faced with an organic investment, which are relatively high. It's based on the fact that we had at the time to make certain acquisition and to have to face the investment which are linked with it because we were a little bit concerned by a sudden drop in our at the time 1P reserves. That's not the case any more. We made the necessary acquisitions, which were not really acquisitions. It's what we call the DRO, which is you buy non-developed resources, that you have time to change into reserves, and then into developing reserves, and then into production. So that's why today we are faced with organic investment, which are today higher than they were and higher than they will be in the longer term. Why? Because we will go back to a more sustainable development planning of our investment.</p>
          <p>But it doesn't mean that we will stop investing after 2017. Total still considers that the stop-and-go policy is the worst that we can do in our industry. It has always been hurting those who have been following this strategy, because I mean, when the price of oil or gas moves, it never moves at the time you wish. So let's be conservative on the criteria you use for launching your projects, and then you run them on the longer term. But more and more we'll be talking on after 2017. Today we're focusing on the first par, because that has been the concern of our investors, about cash flow are we capable to. We are, we deliver, and then definitely we'll have to say a little bit more about the future of our industry for the years 2020 plus, which is I insist tomorrow. But when you talk about exploration, that's exactly what you're doing. Because the exploration of today, it doesn't mean production. At the best before 2020 plus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to add one point, if you have a look beyond 2017, you will have projects like Canada oil sand or Ichthys. And keep in mind that our capital employed will basically double from today to 2017. And so the overall amount of cash available is great, and the big project I was mentioning to you are part of the beyond 2017 production and project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe the last question? At least <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:36:09) sometimes it's risky to be on the front line. Nobody sees you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks. Jason Gammel with Macquarie. Just a couple around the LNG portfolio. First of all the level of flexibility you maintain in the existing portfolio has clearly been beneficial in the current spot pricing environment in Asia. But given that we're in a pretty tight market right now, are you strategically looking to put more term structure around the portfolio while prices are high? Second part of the question is, you would look to be growing beyond the 17 million tons per annum that you have targeted in 2017, if you look at the project list. Would you be able to put any priority around Shtokman, Yamal, Brass LNG? And perhaps even an expansion trade at GLNG? Just which had the best economics? Or which seem most likely to move forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's not the easiest part, I mean, using Brass LNG and Shtokman. I'd like to know what it is. Frankly, on Brass in Nigeria for those who don't know, it's a big question mark. But I mean, as Patrick said, it's after 2017. Before, no chance. And again, it's a place which is not very secured, safe, but it's a strong wish of the today's president. But no decision has been taken yet. We know that one partner has decided to quit, and we don't know who would be replacing it; so I mean, no dates for Brass, no date for Shtokman. I don't know if you read the press recently, but they said it was a typo, but something has been published in Russia saying that Shtokman will be starting producing in 2030. That was in newspapers. When we called them, they said, no, it's a typo it's 2019. Strange typo error.</p>
          <p>But, just to give you my feeling on those two projects. They are there the reserves are there. They will be developed, but when? It's impossible to say. But, we don't count on them for more than the longer term. It's not part of our short-term or even medium-term targets. Yamal is different. Yamal is really, I mean, now moving; the FID is not yet taken. It should be taken before the yea-rend. And we got already a lot of good answers to our request. There are still a few missing as you know, discussions with Gazprom on the monopoly of exporting gas, especially when it is LNG. But, if you know the subject, you know things are moving in the right direction, which means that the government ask us, Gazprom, to enter into discussion with Novatek and Yamal LNG. And I can tell you that's underway.</p>
          <p>So, when will it be sorted out? Difficult to say. But I am relatively optimistic on this project. On the top it has a lot of potential because what we're developing today are really one part of the existing reserves. So, the good thing with Yamal, if it starts in a good way, it's long-term positioning for Total and Novatek, and you have Total as a partner in Yamal, but as a partner in Novatek, where we're getting the benefit of the two.</p>
          <p>But, for this LNG project long-term, that's what I said when I presented the slide of LNG, and that's why we're confident that, yes, the demand is there. Yes, the resources are there. But before it will become really LNG available for the consumers, it will take a longer-term period. So all those thinking that all of those projects will start and then LNG on the top coming from the U.S., well it mean that the price will be decreasing a lot. As I was saying for oil production and oil development, we cannot say at the same time that the energy industry is facing problems to develop their project, but they will be all developed, and then it will make a crash on prices. That's not the way we see it. So, we remain extremely positive on LNG. So, if we can lock more, yes, we will. Theepan? Well that is the last question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you. Theepan Jothilingam from Nomura. Just a question coming back to disposals, but since your earnings numbers last year were very resilient, just going forward though, could you talk about perhaps the impact of the disposal program, sort of looking at the 2014 cash flow number relative to 2012? And then, sort of a follow-up question to that, I guess, is that if perhaps the impact on earnings from the current disposal program is relatively muted, if you were to pursue a disposal program, would that eat more into, sort of, cash generating assets or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The impact on earning of the sale of assets...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's already done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's already included in our forecast. If you take the example of TIGF, which will bring another whole enterprise where you have &#x20AC;2.4 billion, TIGF provides little income, actually the return on capital employed of this regulated business is quite small. So, all-in-all the overall impact of the asset sales program is not big. The magnitude of it is maybe $100 million in aggregate, something like this, either side Usan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the others. As far as I told you, we know now most of the disposal we will be doing until 2014. It's easy to say how much it will represent in terms of reserves and production. It's by definition limited because we are targeting projects which are having a little impact on production and reserves. But, at the same time it's all including in our forecast, so it's good you say this because we cannot use this as an excuse; if we cannot meet our targets to say, yes, what we are selling, now that's included. And for what we present, for instance the next to come, we already also have reserved part of this for it will not be part of the $3 million.</p>
          <p>So, to be very clear, we will not use as an excuse, except if we go to additional sales, but today in the $20 million to $25 million sales program, it's all included in our targets and forecasts. And when you have our internal presentation, I don't know if we do this for everybody. We have a detailed explanation on what are the plus and what are the minus compared with our budgets and planning. We have something which we call pyramid, and that is we're, okay we sold or we acquired something, so we are putting those category as independent from what we call organic production coming from existing developments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To be precise enough, we have no formal target of asset sales beyond 2015.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What did you say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the part of the target.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no target. But as I told you, not in terms of amounts, but in terms of strategy, I think the strategy which is to make your portfolio of assets moving will be continued. It makes sense to continue to &#x2013; not to keep in your portfolio assets when you consider that they don't have real potential, that they will become more and more costly. And on the top, some people will make a better use of those assets than you are. So, for instance, when we sold Cameroon, it had nothing to do with balancing our cash. It was really based on well, Cameroon is a nice country, we stay in the marketing, but as far as oil reserves and production are concerned, it can only be dropping.</p>
          <p>So companies who don't have any concern about commitments on production, they continue to do it. For us it was becoming a burden, so disposal. And I think we need to continue to work on this as being part of the way this company needs to be managed in a dynamic way, not to please, but just because we consider that this is the best way to bring value to our shareholders, but without targets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Martin says that's the end of the session, so he must be right. Well, thank you for being the time with us. Thank you for your attention. We really think that Total is moving ahead in full transparency, meeting our targets, our commitments. But, I wanted to say something very clear. It's important to meet your targets vis-&#xE0;-vis your shareholders, investors, financial analysts. But if we're doing it, it's because we trust in it as a long-term strategy. So, it's not a strategy to please. It's a strategy which has been supported, approved by the board, that the management consider the best opportunity to bring value to its shareholders, and that's the reason why we are committing ourselves to those targets. So, of course, we will answer always to your questions, and especially to be as transparent as we have to be, but at the same time don't think that we do this or that because we are told this or that. We'll listen to you, but at the same time, it's important that a long-term strategy has to be driven as a long-term strategy.</p>
          <p>So, when we ask what do you change? We changed our habits, we changed our way of doing business, we changed the company organization, we have been reinforcing this momentum on using more our skill that we were doing in moving our portfolio of assets, and definitely in being more proactive. But at the end, we are strong supporters of &#x2013; as far as you've seen that price of energy will remain at levels we make it profitable. Energy is the only thing which is on earth which stood the way to continue to grow in the world. So we consider that we are in one of the most fascinating industry with a huge potential, with a huge potential for additional technology, for young engineers and with a very long-term bright future.</p>
          <p>So that's the reason why we were pleased today to offer you the result of 2012, which have been as Patrick said, good and definitely we expect to redeliver this kind of news, even better, in the years to come. Thank you for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>