<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1385215" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-04-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>596</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Patrick de la Chevardi&#xE8;re</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Theepan Jothilingam</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="The Benchmark Co. LLC">Mark Gilman</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International Ltd.">Alejandro A. Demichelis</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Kimberly-Clark Corp.">Ian C. Read</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Kepler Capital Markets SA (France)">Bertrand Hod&#xE9;e</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Oswald C. Clint PhD</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole Cheuvreux SA">Dominique Patry</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Lydia R. Rainforth</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Jon Rigby</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="corprep">Patrick de la Chevardiere</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. And welcome to the Earning Results Q1 2011 Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in listen-only mode until we conduct the question-and-answer session and instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And just to remind you all that this conference call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to handover to the Chairperson, CFO, Patrick de la Chevardi&#xE8;re. Please begin your meeting and I will be standing by.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello and thank you for calling. I will make some comments on our first quarter results and then go to the Q&amp;A. Before commenting on the results, let me say a few words about the proposed acquisition of the solar energy company SunPower that we announced yesterday. I'm sure that you have seen the terms so I will be brief.</p>
          <p>By acquiring the majority interest, Total will have the scale and international footprint we need to establish a significant presence in what we believe is one of the fastest growing segments of the energy industry. We have an excellent fit with our existing Solar business and certain on the activities, plus we'll bring our financial strength to a growing business. We have a great deal of respect for this company, its workforce, its management and its technological leadership. This adds a new dimension to Total and we look forward to working with SunPower.</p>
          <p>Now, for Total first quarter results, we have more good news. We are showing healthy improvement not only versus the first quarter of the last year but also versus the fourth quarter. And I remind you that the fourth quarter was already very good, especially compared to our peers. Compared to the fourth quarter, adjusted earnings per share increased by 22% to $1.89 per share; compared to the first quarter of the last year, adjusted EPS increased by 33%. Excluding the impact of moving Sanofi from equity affiliates, the increase would have been 45%. Specific to this quarter in our results I should point out certain items.</p>
          <p>For CEPSA; effective at the beginning of March 2011, CEPSA has been moved from equity affiliates to assets held for sale. Under the IFRS rules, we no longer include the financial results for CEPSA. For comparison, CEPSA generated about $25 million per month on average in 2010. The first quarter results include charge of $244 million to increase the deferred tax provision due to the change in the U.K. tax rate. This item is not included in the adjusted results. You will also find a new item for the mark-to-market impact related to the valuation of the gas and power inventory, but this is not included in the adjusted results.</p>
          <p>Moving on, a lot you know about the environment, so we'll not spend too much time on it. Oil and gas prices moved higher and faster than expected. European refining margins were squeezed by the increase in oil prices, so margins fell back to low levels. Chemicals performed well despite higher <mark type="indiscernible" /> (00:04:01) costs. Product demand was strong enough to allow us to pass on the higher costs.</p>
          <p>World events have affected our industry, specifically, our production in Libya of about 55,000 barrel per day were disrupted in March and is now completely stopped. The impact on our first quarter volumes was only 15,000 barrel per day. Despite the unrest in Yemen, Yemen LNG has not been affected. We have no other areas where civil unrest is affecting our production to-date.</p>
          <p>Upstream production in the first quarter was 2.37 million BOE per day. Compared to the previous quarter, we are down by less than a percent, mainly as a result of normal declines, the disruption in Libya and the <mark type="ph" /> BSC (00:04:58) price effects. These impacts were partially offset by production ramp-ups, mainly in Yemen, and increased production in Abu Dhabi. Excluding the BSC price effect, production would have been flat.</p>
          <p>As for price realization, liquids averaged 94% of Brent, slightly lower than 2010, due to wider price spreads. Gas was $6.19 per million btu reflecting vast improvement in U.K. spot prices and the oiling long-term contract in the portfolio with a lag effect.</p>
          <p>Just to remind you again, Total has very little exposure to WTI or Henry Hub and about 40% of our gas is sold as LNG. Extreme profitability improves significantly in the first quarter. Compared to the fourth quarter, net income per BOE increased by 28%, to more than $18 per BOE, versus a 16% increase in our average hydrocarbon price. First quarter ROACE on an annualized basis was very strong at 26%. This is at the level of the best in the majors.</p>
          <p>Overall, we are pleased with the way that the Upstream is performing, and we are in the process of making the portfolios stronger for the future. We have recently closed three major deals: Novatek in Russia, the Synenco Strategic Alliance in Canada, and Santos in Australia. We signed the deal with Tullow to enter Uganda and should close the Yamal LNG deal sometime this summer.</p>
          <p>The Sulige Thai gas project has been approved by CNPC, and is now ready to get the green light from the Chinese authorities. Production should start in 2012, in advance of the previous forecast. In addition, we are moving closer to final investment decisions on Shtokman in Russia and Ichthys in Australia. These are giant projects that add visibility and a lot of trends to our production profile.</p>
          <p>I understand that many of you are more focused on the near-term production profile. So, we consider then 55,000 barrel per day in Libya will remain offline, probably for quite some time.</p>
          <p>The sale of Cameroon closed in April, and the impact will be less than 10,000 barrel per day. The sale of CEPSA should close in the third quarter, and the impact will be about 25,000 barrel per day. Novatek closed effective April 1st, and this adds 120,000 barrel per day, starting in the <mark type="ph" /> second quarter (00:07:59) more than offsetting these impacts.</p>
          <p>In addition, we have four new projects starting up this year, including Pazflor in Angola, that has received its FPSO and is on schedule to start early in the fourth quarter. And we will have to wait and see how the normal decline and <mark type="ph" /> basic (8:18) impact develop over the year.</p>
          <p>So, despite all the changes, we are still very comfortable with our guidance for this year and for the period 2010 to 2015.</p>
          <p>In the LNG business, where Total is one of the top player in the world, demand continues to be strong in Asia and Europe. Total prices are currently around $12 per million btu in the Far East and close to $10 million btu in Continental Europe.</p>
          <p>We are currently in discussion for long-term sales and purchase contract, mainly with Far East buyers, and we see no signs that the link to crude prices is at risk. More broadly, the fundamental for gas are growing, outside of the U.S. of course, as a result of the event in Japan.</p>
          <p>On the Exploration side, we have an important drilling campaign this year, and I will point out three examples. In Azerbaijan, the Apsheron well is currently drilling. And considering the depth, we should know something by end of this year. We spud the well in French Guyana in March, and this is interesting because it is similar to the Jubail discovery.</p>
          <p>And Deep Offshore Brunei, we plan to start drilling on CA1 block in the third quarter. Of course, there are no guarantees on exploration. But these prospects are examples of the type of high potential wells we have added to the Exploration program.</p>
          <p>In the Downstream segment, refining was squeezed by the increasing oil prices and weak product demand in Europe, but supply optimization and marketing outside of Europe balanced it.</p>
          <p>The first of last year and also the fourth quarter were affected by strikes in France related to the Dunkirk closure and the French pension issue.</p>
          <p>Apart from the result, the main story here is that we have significantly reshaped our Downstream profile over the past year. In France, the Dunkirk refinery has been closed and we have reduced the distillation capacity at Normandy.</p>
          <p>In Italy, we have merged our refining and marketing operation with <mark type="ph" /> Elf (00:10:48). We have made a deal to sell CEPSA and this will represent an exit of the Iberian Peninsula. And we expect to finalize the sale of our Lindsey refinery and our U.K. marketing network fairly soon. So we will be out of the U.K. Downstream business as well.</p>
          <p>At the Port Arthur refinery in Texas, we started up a new contract in March. In Saudi Arabia, we are on schedule with the construction of the Jubail refinery, and we are open to other opportunities mainly in the non-OECD world.</p>
          <p>In the Chemicals, margin improved despite higher raw material costs and product demand was good in both the specialties and the base chemicals. Compared to the previous quarter, net operating income increased by 41% to $326 million, and we are quite pleased with this. We have recently announced the sale of our Specialty Chemicals Resins activity and we expect this production to close this summer.</p>
          <p>Finally, at the corporate level, the balance sheet is very strong. Gearing was 19% at the end of the quarter. In the first quarter, we recorded the acquisition of GLNG plus 75%, Fort Hills and Voyageur. The first quarter cash flow does not include the acquisition of Novatek, Uganda and SunPower, although sales of CEPSA, Joslyn, Cameroon although is in. All of these transactions combined should come sellout and have no material impact on net cash flow.</p>
          <p>Some of you may have noticed that we now show net CapEx in earnings release. This is CapEx including acquisition and asset sales. I think we have been very clear about increasing the level of asset sales and then reinvesting the cash into new and better assets. But we understand that because of the number of new projects we are adding to the portfolio, there may be some concern about cash flow and CapEx. Over the next few years, I would expect the net CapEx to move from the range between $20 billion to $23 billion. With net CapEx in this range, we can manage our gearing within the target range, continue to the level up the portfolio and maintain our dividend policy. On dividends, we have announced that our first quarterly dividend will be &#x20AC;0.57 payable in September.</p>
          <p>Now, I am ready to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from the line of Theepan Jothilingam. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Patrick, good afternoon. I just wanted to ask three questions actually. Firstly, just on taxes, I saw that mix effect in the Upstream bought a lower tax rate for this quarter. I was just wondering, do you think that persists through the rest of this year or not? And do you have any thoughts on sort of group tax for 2011?</p>
          <p>And secondly, I just wanted to come back to your comment on net CapEx of $20 billion to $23 billion. Are you suggesting therefore the gross CapEx could be higher sort of going forward on the next two, three years and that you could sort of, on a gross basis, be up at sort of $25 billion? And then just thirdly in terms of refining and the R&amp;M result, all else being equal with the macro, was Q1 a satisfactory result on an underlying basis or not? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Theepan. Your first question about the tax rate. Our Upstream tax rate has decreased from 57.6% in Q1 '11 compared to 59% in last Q 2010. This is explained by two main reasons: the IO weight of Gas &amp; Power, which has lower tax rate, as you may know, and the mix effect of production between countries. In the future, this will &#x2013; this tax rate will depend on what is the exact weight of Gas &amp; Power and basically the tax rate, the average tax rate, for Upstream will be in the range of 58% to 60%. That was for your first question.</p>
          <p>Your second question was suggesting that our growth CapEx could be up to $25 billion. This is not what I said. What I said is that we intend to monitor our net CapEx figures in the range of $20 billion to $23 billion. This is to say that if we made some acquisition, if any, we could sell some asset so that so that the net CapEx should be down to the range of $20 billion to $23 billion.</p>
          <p>On refining, the average operating rate of our refineries remain low in Q1 '11, about 79%, 80%. Lindsey still running at half capacity since June 2010 incident. Port refinery were disrupted to connect to new <mark type="ph" /> cocker (00:17:07) and then we are starting to turnaround at <mark type="indiscernible" /> (00:17:09) refinery in March. So overall, the operating rate was quite good in first Q 2011.</p>
          <p>I would add something into that, and you saw that in our application that the refining margin in Europe were quite low, and I think this is answering your last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. Just coming back to that CapEx, just in terms of, I mean on an underlying basis, I'm just trying to <mark type="ph" /> understand why (00:17:47) you believe your organic CapEx number could go. Maybe I sort of missed that, but &#x2013; missed that point. I was just trying to understand that if you're on a net basis, yes, you're acquiring and disposing of assets. I was just wondering what you think that the underlying run rate on CapEx should be. What do you think the ongoing disposal rate should be assumed at?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean I can answer you retaining to our long-term plan, which is dated a little bit. But excluding acquisition, our gross CapEx excluding acquisition were below the $23 billion I mentioned to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Mark Gilman. Please go ahead, your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick, good afternoon. Just a couple of things, if I could, please. It looks as if the pace of selling the Sanofi shares is once again fairly low. Could you comment on that regarding completing it by year end 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Mark. Good to have you with us. On the Sanofi shares, I just need to explain you some things technically, is that the date we sell Sanofi and go below 5% stake will trigger the value of the Sanofi share which will be used for computation of the future capital gain. So when the Sanofi share was at 47, we were waiting for a better price to materialize these future events for future capital gain tax. Actually, we sold yesterday sufficient amount of Sanofi shares so that we materialize this 5% target. And now, we will continue and sell Sanofi with the usual trend so that by end of 2012, it will be completed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. A couple of other ones, Patrick, if I could. You talked about the deferred tax adjustment for the U.K. tax increase. What did you do in terms of the operating tax rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. For the nine forthcoming months because of the new rules started late March, our estimate for cash plus deferred tax is an overall cost of &#x20AC;150 million, using $90 per barrel scenario, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And did you record at the higher rate in the first quarter, Patrick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, because it was not applicable at that time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You commented on the French Ghana well as being similar to Jubilee. I wonder if I could just ask you to be a bit more precise in that regard. Is this cretaceous prospect? Is it stratigraphic along the lines? And you are targeting similar horizons?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's an average margin concept, which is similar to Jubilee. Of course this is exploration and there is no guarantee on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just one final one for me. Did you do anything in the quarter with respect to the Venezuelan tax increase announced several days ago?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we booked nothing in that respect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Alejandro Demichelis. Please go ahead, your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, Patrick. And just one question. Maybe you can give us a better indication of the rationale of the SunPower deal and how this kind of relates back to your comment saying that you're investing in better projects than what you have currently given that the ROACE in SunPower is so much lower than what you have at a group level today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have always make clear to the market that we wanted to extend our exposure to the solar market. Over the last two years, we have been benchmarking a significant number of solar players and we have seen about 200 companies. SunPower is one of the market leader in the solar industry. It is number one in the U. S. It is a vertically-integrated company which offer visibility and growth potential.</p>
          <p>The company has a technically &#x2013; technological, sorry &#x2013; advantage for its highly-efficient technology, which is the efficiency of their sale is 24% where the average of the industry is 16% to 18%. So we choose and by chance we have been able to crystallize this joint venture with them because those guys are the best technically speaking on the solar industry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And so should we assume that this completes your aim in the solar market? Or should we expect something more from you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think for the time being that's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And that's just for solar or just renewables in general?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. Can you repeat your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When you said that's it, does that relate just to solar or does that relate to renewables in general?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, that's related to solar. I think for solar now, our solar footprint is good enough with the SunPower acquisition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Ian Read. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Patrick. I've got a couple of things. I think I heard you say that following the Novatek acquisition, you want to confirm your 2010 to 2015 production growth target. Purely from 2010 to 2015, it's risen somewhat. Do you want to kind of tell us what the production growth rate would be on that basis including the net of the &#x2013; the net impact of Novatek minus the disposals?</p>
          <p>And secondly, you say you're going to dispose $10 billion of assets this year. Can you say how much of that will be Sanofi? And what is the exact Sanofi percentage now? You said it was gone below 5%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your first question about the growth target, our target is to grow our position by 2% a year on average over the period 2010, 2015, and we are still comfortable with this. And this figure does not include the Novatek deal. But we will update you with this target in September, taking into account also sale and including the Novatek. The Sanofi amount we include in our asset sales, which is close to $10 billion, is in the range $1.5 billion if you use the $10 billion sales target.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And your exact percentage right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just below 5%. It should be 4.99% something.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Bertrand Hod&#xE9;e. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Hi, Patrick. Can you give us some &#x2013; an update on the status or progress you've made on the expected final investment decision you may take this year? And especially, I was thinking about progress and status on Egina Nigeria, Ichthys LNG and Shtokman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Bertrand. Start with Shtokman, you know that the Board of Shtokman decided to re-merge the two FID. Initially, we had two FID; one for the pipeline project, the second one for the LNG project. Those two FID has been merged, and it is anticipated that the new FID will be taken prior year-end.</p>
          <p>On Ichthys, it is roughly the same. We have been able, recently, to finalize broadly all necessary sale purchase &#x2013; sales and purchase agreement for the LNG. And we should be ready to FID this project prior end of 2011. On Egina, the FID is also expected prior year-end, with the first oil in 2015.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just one follow-up on Egina. Does &#x2013; compared to what you were expecting at the beginning of the year, does this project experience some seepage for any reason?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know that basic engineering has been transforming Nigeria, invitation to tender has been launched after the approval of newly-installed Nigerian content development and monitoring board, and this has been secured now. And that's why we could expect FID by late 2011, in this year. And of course, we might have been facing some delay due to the election process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Thank you, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bertrand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Oswald Clint. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you, Patrick. I have two questions. First one on LNG, you've mentioned in the last year, certainly, about 25%, I think, of operating income coming from LNG. Can you say how &#x2013; what percentage that was in the first quarter?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, on Novatek again, you have your &#x2013; the 12%, but you have indicated trying to go up to 19% over time. Can you just clarify what that time period is? And would you expect any increase in the equity holdings through 2011? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know that actually, the LNG, net operating income coming from LNG, was 25%. You were right; last year, we did not give breakdown every quarter. For Novatek, I can't remember exactly the date, but I think we have 12 months from the signing, which was 1st April this year. We have 12 months to bring our shareholding up to 15%, and I think we have three years from this signing to go up to 14.4% &#x2013; sorry, 19%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Dominique Patry. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. I would like to come back on the Upstream profitability on an operating profit basis, given the fact that the operating profit was better than what the sensitivity would have expected. So maybe you can give us more color, maybe, on the cost trend that you are currently experiencing?</p>
          <p>And after that, I have a question on the dividend, given the fact that it is the first time that you're moving to a quarterly dividend. And even if the gearing did decline during the quarter, you have kept the dividend stable. So I wanted to know if you are maybe in a position to give us maybe more background with regard to this decision to keep the dividend stable? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Dominique. The first question about Upstream profitability; basically, first quarter this year versus fourth quarter, the net operating income per BOE increased by $4 dollar, about.</p>
          <p>The price effect explain a little bit less than $3 per BOE. The tax rate that we were discussing at the beginning of the conference call explained about $0.50 per BOE. And the Gas &amp; Power &#x2013; you should not forget about the Gas &amp; Power division &#x2013; explained about $0.70 per BOE. This is the way you can link net operating income of the last quarter with net operating income of this quarter.</p>
          <p>About dividend &#x2013; and it is not a surprise that somebody asked the question. I mean, we have been always clear about that. Our dividend policy is to target an average payout of 50%. We're currently establishing this dividend using the $80 per barrel scenario. I know that the oil price is at $125.</p>
          <p>In first Q '11, we announced a dividend of &#x20AC;0.57 per share, stable basically. I think what we need &#x2013; and of course, we have room to increase it; mean, the payout is currently 41%. What we need is more time to see how the oil price will stabilize, so that we could take a decision to purpose to the Board to increase the dividend on this quarterly basis. But we need some time to see how the oil price stabilize.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And just, if I may, coming back to the <mark type="ph" /> variable (00:33:10) breakdown you provided us in terms of the profitability evolution versus Q4; would you describe the operating condition of the Gas &amp; Power division in Q1 as a kind of normalized or quite exceptional level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say that it is &#x2013; it was a good quarter. We had higher volumes traded, about 24 cargos of LNG.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This quarter, it was a good quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Okay. Thank you. And just, if I may, a final one. You have been very active, in terms of acquisition of undeveloped Upstream assets. Given the oil price that we have today, would you say that it is clear and attractive option? Or is that just there for you maybe to make a kind of pose on these fronts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I remind you that those acquisition were made at very reasonable prices. And basically, we were making those acquisition when we were able to contribute our know-how and expertise to the project. In exchange to that, we were given access to resources at a reasonable price. If there are other opportunity of this type, we will catch them for sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line Lydia Rainforth. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good afternoon, Patrick. A couple of questions just on the portfolio restructuring, if I could. Firstly, on the Lindsey Refinery, can you give us an update on sort of where that process currently stands? And then, just go back to the CapEx issue from Theepan, the $20 billion to $23 billion, should we think about that as the $20 billion of organic CapEx that you gave in February, and then $3 billion of net acquisitions? Or is that a reflection of the increased spending associated with the acquisitions you've already done?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First question about the Lindsey oil refinery, which is, you know, which is still on for sale. We have signed an exclusivity period with a buyer. This period is for one month, and hopefully, we will be able to finalize this transaction, I would say, in one to two months. But there is no warrantee on it. It's not so easy to sell a refinery.</p>
          <p>About the CapEx guidance, most of the acquisition we have made were partially or totally included in our long-term plan as potential projects. So the guidance I gave you includes, basically, the acquisition we have made and the exclusion of SunPower, which was not included.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Perfect. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Jon Rigby. Please go ahead, your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Hi, Patrick. Two questions. Just going back to SunPower, can you contrast what you'd expect the rate of return would be from this acquisition, compared to doing something similar in the E&amp;P business? I'm just trying to get to the idea of how you look at the allocation of capital, the appropriate allocation of capital.</p>
          <p>And second, why do you feel comfortable with a fairly high degree of participation in the U.S. in solar, where you've been very shy of participation in the U.S. to-date in E&amp;P? The second is just on Downstream; obviously, the results were pretty robust. And all equal, and in a normal trading environment, what would you expect the delta to be? I.e., if we were to roll forward to the second quarter in trading &#x2013; or supply optimization, I should say, were to be more normal? What do you think the difference in earnings might be? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your first question, honestly, you &#x2013; we don't compare solar and E&amp;P and you can't compare. But I can tell you that we expect more than double-digit return on capital employ from this acquisition. We are positioning ourselves in what in think is a growing and technological market where we could make some money and we will make some money. The second question is a little bit the way you make them usually I would say. I am comfortable with this acquisition. I am not comfortable in acquiring U.S. E&amp;P using $120 per barrel scenario as it is at given time for those assets. And with the return on capital employed and we check that every quarter, the return on capital employed for potential acquisition on existing resources and reserve in the Upstream, it shouldn't bring your expertise. It's so high that the return on capital employed is extremely limited and lower than what we'd expect for SunPower.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And on the Downstream?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you repeat your question on the Downstream?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I was just asking you, it looked like you'd benefited from a good quarter I think like a lot of your peers. And in terms of supply optimization, I just wondered in terms of sort of benchmarking sensitivities moving forward into the second quarter, what you might kind of give us as a sort of benefit above and beyond the ordinary from supply optimization this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It might be that our trader are not as good as the other &#x2013; some other companies. But our trading result were slightly better than in last Q, 4Q 2010 this quarter and that's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was not a big deal this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Perfect, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line Mark Gillman. Please go ahead, your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Patrick, have you finalized yet the terms of your entry into the Yamal project?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome back, Mark. We haven't finalized our, the term and condition of our entry in Yamal and we expect to complete this transaction by July.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Patrick, just so I understand regarding the accounting for CEPSA, I assume that given what you've said that CEPSA's results are included in January and February. Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct, but not in March.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Can you help and give us just a little bit of granularity on the scale in absolute terms of the Gas &amp; Power contribution in this period relative to others?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. We do not give them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Let me try just one more. It would appear you may have encountered a tranche effect in production-sharing contracts perhaps rose up in the first quarter because the PSE sensitivity seems to be a bit higher. Is that true?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we trigger any new thing this quarter. I mean we will trigger on Dalia. I think, no, no, no. In 2011, we do not trigger any threshold at $80 per barrel. Sorry, but I don't have the figure at $120. It might be that we will reach the profit oil tranche, a new profit oil tranche on all the &#x2013; at $120, but I don't have the timing for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But nothing in the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nothing in the first quarter, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>[Operator Instruction] We appear to have no further questions at this time, so I'll hand the conference back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you, all of you, for your questions and your comments about Total. I just would like to leave you this brief summary.</p>
          <p>The first quarter result shows that operationally, we are performing quite well. Financially, we are, of course, benefiting from the current environment and the balance sheet is very strong. We are well into the process of positioning Total to be a stronger and more competitive player around the world. And honestly, we are pleased with the first quarter result and we are looking forward to a good second quarter as well. And hope you have, all of you, a good weekend and thank you very much for calling here again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>