<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1459731" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-04-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2060</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Deputy Chairman-Management Committee">Alexander Nikolayevich Kozlov</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Deputy Chairman of the Management Committee">Alexander Ananenkov</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Investment Bank">Kathleen Middlemiss</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Russia)">Pavel Kushnir</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities CJSC">Maxim Moshkov</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Citibank CJSC (Broker)">Ron P. Smith</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="ING Bank NV (United Kingdom)">Igor Kurinnyy</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Bank International LLC (Moscow)">Andrey Gromadin</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep" affiliation="Director">Andrei Igorevich Akimov</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the Gazprom 2011 IFRS Financial Results Conference Call. At this time all participants are in a listen only mode until we conduct a question-and-answer session and instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to hand over to your Chairperson Alexander our host, please begin your meeting and I'll be standing by.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="audio gap" />...financial reporting standards. Today, the conference is Chaired by Alexander Ananenkov, First Deputy, Chairman of the Finance and Economics Department, and please let me pass the microphone over to him.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon ladies and gentleman. Today in this room, we have present the representatives of the Department for Economics and Pricing, the Department of Accounting, the Department for Foreign Economic Activities, the Department for Marketing, Gas Processing and Liquid Hydrocarbons, Finance And Economics Department and Gazprom Export.</p>
          <p>Let me remind you that for the purpose of teleconference, we prepared a presentation which is available on our website. Let us begin with a short review of the results of Gazprom's operations during that period. During the reporting period which is 2011, the company has demonstrated growth of its finance and operational results. The net revenue from sales grew by 29% compared to the similar period in 2010.</p>
          <p>Considering the results of 2011, the net profit grew by 35% amounting to RUB1,300 billion, which if we calculate it into dollars amounts to more than U.S.$44 billion, We remain the biggest company in the world within this indicator. The EBITDA grew by 42% and near the record to almost to RUB2 trillion.</p>
          <p>By the end of 2011, the overall debt of the company grew by 17% compared to 2010. And at the same time the correlation of the overall debt to the adjusted EBITDA went down to 0.8. Gazprom continues to confirm its status as the biggest company in terms of the size of its reserves, following the Gazprom group reserves all debts under the P&amp;S standards as of December 31, 2011. The proven and probable reserves of the group amounted to 149.7 billion barrels of oil equivalent, which is 2% higher than what it had in 2010.</p>
          <p>The current net present value of the reserves of the hydrocarbons by cost from group was diluted to U.S.$299.2 billion, which is 11% more than the level of 2010. The hydrocarbon reserves of Gazprom Group under the Russian classification, grew by 6% through 2011, which is primarily related to licensing activities and specifically with the extension of the Gazprom of the licenses for the right to develop &#x2013; the reserves in the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:38) group of fields. Apart from that in 2011, we noted the record growth of the gas reserves through exploration activities.</p>
          <p>Traditionally in Q4 with the starting of the heating season, we are growing our output. And I would note that considering the results of 2011, the production of gas grew by approximately 1% amounting to 513.2 billion cubic meters.</p>
          <p>The production of liquid hydrocarbons grew similarly, and Gazprom group produced 12.1 million of the gas condensate which is 7% higher than the level of 2010. The production of oil was 32.3 million tons, which is 1% above the level of 2010.</p>
          <p>The year end of 2011 showed production of power by our generating assets which are more significant, DGK-1, OGK-2 and OGK-6 amounted to 173.2 billion kilowatt hours of power, having gone down compared to 2010 by 1%.</p>
          <p>The production of heating amounted to 100.2 million calories, which is 6.3% lower than the results of 2010. The basic reason behind the decline in the operational results were weather factors.</p>
          <p>Slide number seven demonstrates the balance of operations of our gas transportation system, and I should remind us that this particular chart describes the physical movement of gas through pipeline rather than commercial operations of the Group. In 2011, the amount of gas transported through the system grew by 5% compared to the previous year.</p>
          <p>Now, let us move over to our financial results, slide number eight, please. The net revenue from the sales by Gazprom Group through 2011 grew by 29% and amounted to RUB4.6 trillion.</p>
          <p>Considerable positive effect in terms of the net revenue growth came from the extra sales of gas as well as the growth of export prices as well as domestic prices. One should note that with respect to all other lines of operations by the company, one witnessed positive dynamics in terms of the net revenue.</p>
          <p>In Q4 2011, the revenue from the sale of gas in the domestic market grew by 19% compared to a similar period in 2010. This was brought about by a better price environment.</p>
          <p>In 2011, the regulated wholesale prices for gas were raised for industrial consumers by 15% as of January 1, and for households by 5% from January 1, and by 9.5% as of April 1.</p>
          <p>The main consumers of gas remain such industries as power generation and electricity, Metrology, utilities which in aggregate consume more than 50% of all of the gas volumes.</p>
          <p>During 2011, Gazprom supplied 156.6 billion cubic meters of gas into European countries and a thaw abroad, which is a 5.7% higher, than the volumes of shipments from last year.</p>
          <p>In the environment when its own production of gas in Europe and the imports from other countries during 2011 seriously went down, Gazprom grew each share in the European market from 24% in 2010 to 27% in 2011. The growing supplies also happened due to consistent steps to adapt contracts for the supplies of Russian gas to various changes in the European market while keeping their basic terms. About one quarter of the exports of gas by Gazprom to Europe is for Germany. The second largest importer is Turkey whose share is 17% of gas exports.</p>
          <p>The net revenue from the sale of gas to the former Soviet Union countries during Q4 2011 grew by 12% compared to Q4 in 2011. The revenue growth came from the growing average prices from the sale of gas into those destinations compared to the previous period which primarily is related to work being done by the group to change from, with the basic buyers in the regions to contractual prices which demonstrate the equal to European prices kind of parity more than half of the export volumes to the Soviet Union &#x2013; former Soviet Union countries go to Ukraine and about one-third to Belarus.</p>
          <p>A few words about the oil and power business by Gazprom Group.</p>
          <p>In the fourth quarter, they demonstrated growth of the net revenue year-on-year by 26% and 20% respectively. In 2011, 26% within the overall structure of net revenue came from the sale of crude gas condensate and the refining products into 7% for heating and power generation.</p>
          <p>The main line items of our operational expenditures traditionally were acquired oil and gas. And because of the considerable growth in amity, the tax line item grew in part from the profit tax. And I would like to note that in 2011 the HR line item grew lower than inflation.</p>
          <p>Let's consider in detail the tax subject. The mineral extraction tax grew by 51% and amounted to RUB266 billion in 2011 compared to 176 billion in 2010. This growth can form higher amity taxes in growing from RUB147 up to RUB237 for 1000 cubic meters as of January 1, 2011. The excise levies grew because of the higher crude extraction tax because of the growing international market prices.</p>
          <p>Let's move over to slide number 15, when developing our investment program we are being guided by strategic priorities for the development of the company and the expected fiscal indicators. We adjust our investment program based on actual results of the work of the company covering the first half year.</p>
          <p>And in 2011, we considerably grew our capital investments up to RUB1.6 trillion, which was necessitated to execute the production to expand our capacities in the production and transportation of gas, which I will mention towards the end of my presentation.</p>
          <p>In 2012 we plan to invest about RUB800 billion into the gas business and about RUB130 rubles into the oil business, and about RUB80 billion into power. The Gazprom group completely entirely finances investment results out of the operational cash flow which beneficially stands us out from the peer groups elsewhere.</p>
          <p>Over to slide number 16. Considering the results of 2011, the net amount of debt grew by 19% compared to 2010. The reason behind this particular indicator growing comes from bringing in new long-term and short-term loans, as well as with the growing euro and dollar exchange rate to the Russian ruble.</p>
          <p>The debt ratios are considerably below the allowable levels, and continue to go down. And so the relation of the net debt to the adjusted EBITDA was 0.5%, while the correlation of the overall debt to the adjusted EBITDA, 0.8%.</p>
          <p>The end of 2011 shows that the average interest rate in all our borrowings was 6.5%. The structure of the repayment of debt by the group is well balanced in terms of all the periods, and currently Gazprom has the credit rating of BBB with a stable outlook by S&amp;P, as well as BBB with a stable outlook by Fitch</p>
          <p>In the concluding slide, I would like to summarize the results. 2011 became for the company a year of achievements and success. With point I can repeat that the net profit on Gazprom became the maximum one amongst all the global public companies.</p>
          <p>We continue to implement the biggest world investment projects. In November we commissioned into operation the first line of the Nord Stream pipeline and started commercial shipments of gas. We grew, the control stake in Beltransgaz will further strengthen Gazprom's positions in as far as the continued supplies of Gazprom's consumers are concerned.</p>
          <p>In September, we launched the gas transportation systems to Sakhalin-Khabarovsk-Vladivostok, which would enable to supply gas to big industrial consumers simultaneously in several far eastern districts, and similarly would create conditions for the shipments of gas to the Asia Pacific regions.</p>
          <p>The arrival of the regulated gas prices and their growth to the equal parity ones is continuing, but at the same time the growing high risk for the transportation storage of gas is ahead on inflation, but being a global energy company Gazprom continuously is facing external challenges.</p>
          <p>In 2011, the tax burden for the Gazprom Group started growing, and at this point in time we continue our dialogue with the government to identify a well-balanced MT level which wouldn't threaten our investment plans and wouldn't threaten our dividend payment.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much for your attention. For Q&amp;A session we will have 45 minutes. Myself and my colleagues will be eager to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker>
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from the line of Kathleen Middlemiss. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi, it's Kathleen Middlemiss from UBS Investment Bank. Can you perhaps give us some guidance on if you intend to borrow from the international capital markets this year and if so what is in the pipeline for the amounts of borrowing. Thank you.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
          <p>The balance sheet for 2012 shows that the amount of planned borrowing will stay at a traditional for Gazprom level, which is RUB90 billion. And at this point in time, there is no rationale which could push us towards adjusting this figure and so we would follow the logic of keeping up with the figure exactly as it is specified in the budget. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of <mark type="ph" /> Timur Salikhov (15:26). Please go ahead with your question, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. This is <mark type="ph" /> Timur Salikhov from Nomos Bank (15:32). Just doing some research. And my question is related to the increase in MAT taxes for 2012. I was wondering if you can quantify the impact on Gazprom's EBITDA in 2012 standing from new increases in MAT taxes as well as any further guidance on 2013 and 2014 respectively?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
          <p>Deputy Head of the Economic expert assessment in pricing, is responding to this question. Right now we can only be guided by the rates for entity tax which are specified in the law which is RUB209 for 2012, RUB582 for 2013 and RUB622 for 2014 and we are in continuous dialogue with the Russian Government and various ministries which are part of the process where the taxes may be reconsidered, trying to prove that this particular tax rate is already high enough for a normal economic development in the industry and as well as the country.</p>
          <p>And in this way we may say that as far as any changes in the tax rate may be subject to discussion after the official decision is made. And currently there is a process going on which would follow the results of the meeting which took place on March 23 in the city of <mark type="ph" /> Kirishi (19:55) chaired by the prime minister where it was stated that the entity for tax should be defined according to the formula which will somehow be related to any possible changes for the domestic gas prices. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you clarify the amounts again please for 2012? You said 2009, is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] 509.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's fine. That's what I thought.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And 2013 is 622?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] No, 582. [Foreign Language] 622 for 2014.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. That's fine. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of <mark type="ph" /> Yakhya Azashikov (22:48). Please go ahead with your question, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign language]</p>
          <p>So there are two questions, the first one is related to the export shipments. Approximately two weeks ago, the media mentioned information with respect to Gazprom Export creating an impairment in its budget in the amount of US$10 billion related to various compensations because of the reconsideration of the gas prices for a number of European buyers, but at the same time it is not clear whether that relates to the shipments of 2011 and part of potential payments related to subsequently reconsidered conflicts. So could you please introduce clarity into this issue? Are you planning any regional active payments with respect to domestic contracts and if you are then how that will be reported in terms of accounting? Will that reduce the amount of revenue in 2012, or will it be an adjustment of the results for 2011 and will there affected through an undistributed profit? Thank you.</p>
          <p>And the second question as well, as far as the capital expenditure is concerned in your presentation, it states that you kept those spending for 2012 planned at RUB1.1 trillion and as far as I can recall last year approximately within the same time, your budget was at RUB1.2 trillion but because although more effective in favorable international market environment, you raised the outlook for your capital spending up to RUB1.600 trillion if I am correct. So, do you think &#x2013; what will be the outlook this year considering the fact that the majority of the projects in your model are nearing completion? Is there a probability that against a better environment in the international gas markets the price might grow again, and respectively your capital spending would follow suite?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] The first question will be answered by [ph] [indiscernible] (25:14) from Gazprom Export and Mikhail Rosseev representing the accounting department.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] So the first question, first will be answered by Mr. [indiscernible] (25:50) and principally speaking, there is already an increment in place where there are buyers with respect to the retroactive payments which amongst other things also related to 2011 but in as far as these specific figures are concerned, they are subject to confidential information and commercial secrets and so we are not going to disclose this. So let me now pass the microphone over to my colleague.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] Mikhail Rosseev shall continue answering the first question and out of the way we currently see the status of agreements that won't require changing the indicators of the previously disclosed reports or any adjustments to the undistributed profit, that will be reflected as the transaction to operations of 2012. And as you correctly assumed, most probably that will be simply just the decline of the amount of revenue. Thank you.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] And as the second question is concerned with respect to the amount of capital spending program, I can say that RUB1.1 trillion relates to Gazprom Group which includes power sector and oil business. As far as the parent company is concerned, the amount of investments for 2012 is RUB777 billion, which considering the results of our operations by the end of Q1, the decision was made to adjust it and to raise it up to RUB677 billion -- RUB667 billion -- by RUB67 billion, and that is going to be the correction or the adjustment which will be introduced into the budget of the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] And an additional question is in terms of the average gas price outlook by $415 per 1,000 cubic meters which was announced during the Gazprom Investor Day, as far as I understand does not include this potential reduction of the payment by the amount of retroactive payment. Is this correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] [ph] Andrey Kruglov (29:42) from Gazprom Export will answer this question. [Foreign Language] I would not directly make a connection between the output for gas prices under the existing Gazprom Export contract, which was estimated some time ago and retroactive payments, simply because retroactive payments are part of the revenue for the gas that is going to be flowing in the course of the year. And the price outlook is part of the currently existing terms agreed with our partners, particularly since some of the contracts are currently being reviewed. And there is no final decision yet which has been made about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Pavel Kushnir. Please go ahead with your question, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Pavel Kushnir at Deutsche Bank. [Foreign Language] There are two questions from the Deutsche Bank representative. Could you please explain what was the reason behind the reduction of prices in European Q4 down to US$400 for 1000 cubic meters compared to US$411 in Q3? Based on our estimates that was supposed to happen but in terms of then rather growing. And my second question is an extension of the previous question. Now as far as I could understand from the previous management comments, retroactive payments their negative effects going to influence Gazprom's revenue throughout several years rather than just within one year period. Could you please offer us a comment with respect to this particular question? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] Andrey [indiscernible] (33:23) from Gazprom Export will answer this one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
          <p>So, it is difficult to comment as to why this decline took place. Particularly according to our reporting data there was no reduction of gas prices in Q4, 2011. On the contrary, this price in terms of the average level under our own contract, if we are to consider it from this approach, it on the contrary slightly went up compared to Q3. And so as far as the projection or the outlook for 2012 is concerned, you've heard it, is going to be 415. Thank you.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
          <p>That was also the reason behind my question, because on slide number 10 in your presentation, it's stated that there occurred a decline from the level of 411 down to 400. That was why I asked for an explanation.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
          <p>And the way we usually doubted, and you should also be able to follow, was that not necessarily in the previous reports you could have seen it that there are some discrepancies, and specifically as far as we can look at an average counter value, it usually is different from the contract. That comes from the exchange rate differences and the fact that not always the way the accounting reflects what's written in the contracts because, by the end of the year, usually the majority of adjustments occur, reflected to the way we count for the transactions and operations throughout the year, that is one thing.</p>
          <p>And secondly in our work and in the operations of the group, we reflect not only the existing long-term contracts, but also we reflect the spot contracts and I would say that the marketing with respect is that to the average estimated price not being able to fit the expectations. So I would explain it simply by a certain technical approach related to the expected value of the revenue, as well as the ultimate year-end price that we average this way.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
          <p>And additionally, for example, if you take a look at the average estimated price fix as capacity in rubles, you would see that the prices of Q4 were RUB 12.4,000 for 1000 cubic meters compared to RUB 9.9,000 for 1000 cubic meters during Q3. Basically, the price went up.</p>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] And could you also please ask &#x2013; answer the second question, in terms of the distribution of retroactive in our payments for within the next several year period or just whatever?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] Well, that could well depend upon what are the specific agreement that was reached with the buyer, because that can affect the subsequent pricing mechanism, which could really happen within one year or several years, and that is defined by the way the negotiating process with a particular buyer comes out.</p>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Maxim Moshkov. Please go ahead with your question, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] Maxim Moshkov with UBS. There are several other questions. And as far as the gas conflicts are concerned, would you explain what is the share of reviewed contracts re-estimated by the revenue or the volume of what is expected to take place in 2012, but in terms of what is spent for sale in 2012?</p>
          <p>The second question is when do you expect the final government resolution, in terms of the growth of amity as related to the formula, which is in itself connected to the growing gas styles in Russia?</p>
          <p>And the third question is about the cost of acquired gas in your report. Could you explain how much out of the cost that you disclose applies to the gas acquired from the Russian independent gas producers? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] [ph] Dimitry [indiscernible] (41:50) will be answering the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] It is not very much correct for me to be able to try and answer this question, because it is difficult to be certain. Some of the agreements already being released, others are undergoing through additional discussions or are being improved by the senior executives while other processes and agreements are being reviewed by the buyers.</p>
          <p>So, right now it is very difficult to identify any specific share of the already reached agreements, particularly so, since as far as the acquisition of gas until the end of year is concerned, the ultimate figures mainly are GAAP adjusted to buy then. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] As far as the second question is concerned in terms of when we expect the Russian Government to decide about energy, I would like to remind you that a couple of weeks ago, the Russian Minister of Finance came out with his expectations in terms of the timeframe, within which this decision may be made, and that didn't come true.</p>
          <p>So I believe that it doesn't make sense to get engaged in this ungrateful gas work and I won't be quoting any particular timing, particularly since these don't have any direct or critical bearing upon Gazprom's operations within the period, so I would say that this question should probably be directed to the Russian Government.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] And Mikhail Rosseev will answer the third question from the accounting department.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] We are not making any separate disclosure in terms of our cost related to the acquisition of Gazprom with the Russian Companies, which are not part of our consolidation period, but during 2011, they amounted to about RUB130 million, RUB135 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Ronald Smith. Please go ahead with your question, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Ronald Smith, Citibank.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
          <p>The question is this. You had different plans last year in terms of the capital spending, and of course, during the year I know the figures were growing and growing, and so it is interesting to note that during the past two to three months, I shall remind you, that there were about 5, 6 billion that the overall spending went up. So what this money was spent upon, could you be as specific as possible and where are these amounts and so it's just interesting to see how this relatively big amount of money can be spent within such a short period of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
          <p>Regrettably, today amongst us we don't have representatives from the departments of capital construction. So, I guess that we would be sending you the response to this query as a separate mailing because we don't have the kind of people who would be in a position to give a detailed explanation.</p>
          <p>However, we might have additional viewers recognition from Mikhail Rosseev representing the accounting department who states that one I guess should take into account that in any case all the spending that the company is carrying as part of its investment activities are done in compliance with the investment program of the company itself and some major subsidiaries that are part of it and without doubt these programs contain very detailed itemization per different facilities. We are all familiar with the priority projects that Gazprom was pursuing in terms of presentation through 2011. So, there are no unexpected or kind of expenditures that occurred, but as far as itemizing all the line items of course within the individual construction project is something that the company doesn't do, because otherwise we shall be discussing these things at very real length. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Igor Kurinnyy. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] And the first question from ING Bank. Could you please specify the information about CapEx, because the figure you mentioned RUB1.1 billion, does it already include RUB67 billion, which is possible increase of capital expenditure, or this is something that surely might happen in the future? The second question is also related to the first one, and how and when are you going to review your capital expenditure program in the future. Are you going to do that on a quarterly basis or possibly in September you would share with us your new outlook? And the third question is also about CapEx, and that is about any possible increase of amity, will it affect in your investment plans for 2014 and 2015?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] Yes. As far as the first question is concerned, yes, it does include this figure 1.1 trillion, inclusive added amount of 67, or to be exact RUB67.1 million.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] As far as the second question is concerned, yes indeed, most probably considering the results of our operations by the end of Q2 and as result of possible changes of the shifted volumes of gas, we may reconsider the amount of capital investments upwards, but that decision is going to be made after we finalize the results of Q2. And so, the ultimate decision will be made considering the results of H1, and the figure 67 may be reconsidered towards a higher level.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] And with respect to your third question, the answer is yes, certainly, amity will affect the decision making with respect to the amount of capital spending in 2015 and later on, but in terms of what will be to the extent of it, we will be able to decide once the final amity raise is identified or is decided by the government. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next comes from the line of Andrey Gromadin. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] There are two quicker questions, which we have chance received. The first one is about the export of the gas, following the statistics, covering the first four months and we are talking about the decline of the volumes of exports towards Europe. And the last time which was quite recently, as far as the expected suppliers were considered 150 billion cubic meters, approximately that is at the level of the last year. Are you planning any foreseeable in future to reconsider this particular figure downward and considering very weak results of the first four months?</p>
          <p>And the second question is also related to amity tax, the Minister of Finance already voiced its intention, so to say to have 80% from the future revenue from the domestic market to stay in the government budget. Could you somehow in an indicative way explain which level you believe to be acceptable? And is it possible for such level to affect the plans of the company which are about paying 25% of the profit as dividends.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] Andrei Akimov from Gazprom Export will answer the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] I should say that if considering the European statistical data during Q1 overall in Europe the consumption of gas went down by approximately 8%. And therefore it certainly affected the taking of gas within our contracts, although one should take into account some very drier and difficult weather conditions, which took place in February, when the cold covered virtually all of the European states which is seriously undermined this supplies of gas by Gazprom.</p>
          <p>However, again, following the April data when they take gas unexpectedly recover through the winter months and we expect 12.5 billion within April, I mean, as far as the gas supplies to their new destinations are concerned. So frankly speaking, we still expect by the end of 2012, the exports to be at the level of the previous year, which is 150 billion. Certain adjustments may take place or some weather conditions overall may affect the year-end figure. But so far this is the projection that we keep.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now with respect to the third question, it is highly likely that one can see a thought out understanding of what the acceptable level of amity for Gazprom is concerned. If one should take a look at the economic essence of amity and the dividends, one should agree that the government, which is the majority owner in Gazprom through dividends and amity extracts the added value. And so the extraction of 80% of amity for the company is related to the subsequent amount of capital spending becoming closer to something which is at zero level. So this is the question of an equilibrium between the extraction of additional revenue and the amount of funds necessary to dedicate to the capital construction. We still have one instrument in our disposal, such as financial borrowing, but we are also aware of the restrictions that this instrument has. So this question is rather in the political area than the economic one and so the ultimate decision is going to be made by the government. Now with respect to the 25% dividend it is something that all of the government companies have to comply and so that would hardly change depending upon which energy rate we would finally see coming.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] And ladies and gentlemen, we've now gone through the 45 minutes which we allotted to Q&amp;A. So I guess that we would now have one final question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of <mark type="ph" /> Koren Costillian (63:02). Please go ahead with your question, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] Now, two questions. The first one is about there being some information in the media that Gazprom had a meeting with CNPC and the shipments of gas were discussed, alluding to China. Could you please explain what is the current status of negotiations, and would you expect that you would be able to complete this process this year?</p>
          <p>The second question about Ukraine, do you expect to &#x2013; the finalization of negotiations with Ukraine as well? And what is the phase that this process with Ukraine is now at?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] The first question will be answered by [ph] Oleg Ivanov from the Department of Strategic Development (65:42).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] Thank you very much for this question. Yes, we are continuing to negotiate with CNPC. As you might know, we are currently discussing two possible corridors for supplies, the Western and the Eastern. Our priority corridor is the Western one, which is the supplies of 30 billion cubic meters from Western Siberia. And of course the purpose for these negotiations is to enter into a contract and that is what we are after. Now as far as the status of it is concerned, we have currently agreed practically all the terms and conditions except for the price and we now continue to negotiate a good price for our shipment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] The second question will be answered by [ph] Viktor Warnok (66:20) which is the Department of the Foreign Community Service.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] What kind of negotiations do you have in mind? I had difficulty in understanding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] Yes, let me repeat the question again. There has been quite a few news that as far as the Ukraine is concerned, there is a talk about a discount, and which is almost half price, like was the case of Belarus, in exchange for either the controlling stake or a 50% stake significantly in the joint venture with this country, which is about the pipeline connection to Europe. Could you please tell us what is the stage that you have currently going through in these negotiations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
          <p>So, I guess that the way you phrase it, you got this information from the Ukrainian media in terms of this price reduction? I don't have any information like that, but I'm very much for a very close co-operation with Ukraine, because this is our strategic partner right now and in the future, we hope. And now as far as the gas transportation system is concerned, that's what we had in mind. According to information available to us, by the end of March a tender was finished to define the company, which is supposed to do the valuation of the Ukrainian gas transportation system; that was initiated by the Ukrainian party.</p>
          <p>And so, under the terms of this tender, this valuation is to be completed by August 1, if my memory serves me right. So in terms of any relationship to the points and to the valuation of the gas transportation system in the Ukraine, this is something that I really don't have any information at all.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] Dear ladies and gentlemen, many thanks for this joint work with us. And once again, I would like to say that from the financial viewpoint Gazprom has enjoyed the best possible past year, which is something that I would like to congratulate yourselves as well as ourselves. I would similarly like to congratulate you on the coming holidays, and I guess, wish for the 2012 not to be worse than the previous year, although it is going to be definitely harder than previous years. Particularly thanks to [indiscernible] (71:07) for this translation. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>