<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1515611" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-11-08</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2060</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Finance &amp; Economics">Andrey Vyacheslavovich Kruglov</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities CJSC">Maxim Moshkov</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Bank International LLC (Moscow)">Andrey Gromadin</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley Bank LLC">Pavel Y. Sorokin</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Renaissance Capital CJSC">Artem Kvas</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="VTB Capital CJSC (Broker)">Alexander Kirevnin</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International">Abhimanyu Talwar</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon ladies and gentlemen. Thank you for waiting, and welcome to the Half Year 2012 IFRS Financial Results from Gazprom. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode until we conduct a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> I'll just like to remind you that today's conference call is being recorded on the 8th of November, 2012.</p>
          <p>And I would like to hand over to your speaker, please begin your meeting and I'll be standing by.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, ladies and gentlemen, we are happy to welcome you here to our teleconference focused on H1 2012 IFRS consolidated financial results, prepared inline with IFRS standards. My name is Andrey Kruglov; I am Deputy Chair of the Management Committee and the Head of the Financial and Economic departments.</p>
          <p>The meeting is attended by my colleagues who represent various departments and we can access representing the partners of accounting, expertise, liquid hydrocarbons activities as marketing departments, financial and economic departments and selected companies Gazprom experts as well.</p>
          <p>I'd like to remind you that we have provided presentation for the teleconference which is available on our website.</p>
          <p>So traditionally, we will start with the short term review of the Gazprom Group activities over the reported period. As of Q2 2012, we observed a reduction in number of indicators and in the financial period the company's net sales dropped by 2.5% compared to the similar period back in 2011. It could be explained by a reduction in the volumes of sales of gas in the main markets of the company. It was especially compensated with growth in sales from oil and gas condensates in Q2 of 2012.</p>
          <p>And we took into account the effects from the adjustments of price within the framework of long term contract regard to gas suppliers in 2010 and 2011. With regards to which the cost was adjusted in 2012 retroactive adjustments was reflected in reporting a reduction in sales to the amount of RUB54.7 billion. And it has become the key factor for the transaction that being accounted for RUB390.7 billion being by 3.6 less than that of Q2 on year-on-year basis.</p>
          <p>In Q2 2012, net sales of the company dropped by 50% and so accounted for RUB150.8 billion or almost $5 billion. As of the 30th of June 2012, the total debt of the company remained in the same level as of the end of 2011. And the rate of the total debt as adjusted to EBITDA grew to the level of 0.9.</p>
          <p>As for production, in Q2 of 2012, it dropped by 15.8 billion cubic meters, compared to the previous year, because of a drop in demand in the main markets and liquid hydrocarbons production remains at the same level. Gazprom Group produced 3 million tonnes of gas condensate, average 3% as compared to Q2 2011. Oil production accounted for 8.2 million tonnes which is about 3% end of Q2 2011. As a result of Q2 of 2012, production of electricity and heat by our generating companies dropped compared to similar period in 2011 by 11% and 3% respectively.</p>
          <p>Slide five, shows balances our gas transportation system. Let me remind you that this table reflects the physics on transportation in gas along with the main gas pipelines and not commercial activities made by the Europe in Q2 2012 the volume of gas that's transported along the system dropped by 7% compared to similar periods in the previous year.</p>
          <p>Slide six shares trends in our sales in our main markets. In Q2 of 2012, the revenues from selling gas in the domestic markets reduced by 10%, because of the drops in sales which was partially compensated to adjust the domestic parts. And as a result of Q2 2012, we observed a reduction in the volume of sales of gas to Europe and reduction of average price into oil equivalents. However, due to the depreciation of the ruble versus dollar the revenues of company remained more or less at the same level as it was in Q2 of the last year. And net profits from selling gas in the FSU countries in Q2 2012 dropped by 11%. This reduction can be explained by reduction in the volume of sales of gas 28% in the region, it's accompanied by somewhat growth in the average price level.</p>
          <p>Slide seven, shares that in Q2 of 2012, the profits from selling gas condensate and crude oil grew by 18%, compared to 2011 and net profit from selling electricity and heat energy, a significant drop because of a reduction in price and drop in generation of electricity. Operational costs in Q2 of the reporting year significantly increased, compared to similar periods of the last year by RUB16 billion or by 2%.</p>
          <p>Mainly the operational expenses grew because of the tax cost grew as well as for the purchase in gas and oil cost grew by RUB 21 billion and the gas purchase price was of course grew by 11% because we supported outside the Russian Federation and oil related expenses grew by RUB 10 billion or by 15% because of the oil price grew transport and taxes. Profit tax fell by RUB 35 billion or by 33%. This growth is mostly related to increase in the energy tax rates as for gas from RUB 237 to RUB 509 for 1000 cubic meters as of the 1st of January 2012.</p>
          <p>And expenses grew and partially were compensated and eventually it resulted in the drop in operational cost by RUB 56 billion besides as for a reduction in operating cost in Q2 2012 is caused by the changes in the value of gas reduction. Other factors amounted to the RUB 37 billion in total.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, considering the operating results let me just briefly elaborate some changes in the working capital. In Q2 of the current year, the negative impact of the changes in the working capital resulted in reduction in operating cash flow by RUB 128 billion, such an effect was recurrent by these following factors: increase in the value of gas reserves by RUB 77 billion because of the seasonalities in Q2, meaning injection gas into the, underground storage facilities were higher than withdrawal increase in the accounts payable and receivable by RUB 25 billion and RUB 74 billion respectively. Mostly, with assumption of the liabilities on retroactive and it's for gas and this was also impacted by our growing tax liabilities.</p>
          <p>I would invite you to take a look at slide 10. Last week the Board of Directors of Gazprom introduced investment program for 2012 and its new version. Also the program that's also refining investments accounting -- will account for RUB870 billion adjustment in finances investment trading as of 2012 is determined mostly by the investments to increase the volume of investments and in piloting projects production, transportation and other storage facilities.</p>
          <p>Additional investments will be used to implement two of main mega projects, the Yamal and Western Gas program. Within the framework of the Yamal development the main investments will be focused on further development of building infrastructure fields official launch which took place on 23rd of October 2012.</p>
          <p>So investments within the framework of Eastern Gas program commutation 2012 are related to a development of Kazak campus five fields and transportation of Gazprom Sakhalin rigs and capital investments into oil and energy business as of the end of year would account for about RUB10 billion to RUB15 billion.  The amount of capital investment for the Group would account for about RUB1.2 trillion which is one-fourth below the last year volume of capital investments.</p>
          <p>Slide 11 now please. As of the results of H1 of 2012, the net debt dropped by 2% compared as of 31st of December 2011. The reasons for the reduction are related to repayments of the long and short term loans, as well the interest in the financial means and their equivalents. The debt ratios are significantly below the financial level and the ratio of net debt to EBITDA accounted for 0.8 somewhat the ratio total debt to EBITDA is 0.9.</p>
          <p>As of the first half of the year 2012, the average weighted rate on overall borrowings accounted for 6.44%. The structure of debt to repayment of the Group is well balanced by the year.</p>
          <p>This is just very briefly what I wanted to tell you regard to the results of Q2 and the first half of the year. Now we could get down to Q&amp;A part of our session, and we have about 40 minutes left. My colleagues and myself are available to answer your questions if any. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator instructions" /> Our first question comes from the line of Max Moshkov. Please go ahead announcing your company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maxim Moshkov from UBS.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (12:21 &#x2013; 13:20)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So there were questions. Thee first one was related to the rate, plus expectations with regards to the outcome of H2 in the current year? The second question was about the pricing changes which changed significantly as we know and in particular the question was how it affected the Ukraine pricing?</p>
          <p>The third question was about the CapEx expectations and since the program of capital expenditures were already made for this year; the question is whether it's going to be the final one or whether it's going to be used somehow?</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (14:01- 14:20)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let us start with answering the last question. And so the first two questions I will ask my colleague, the Head of the External Economic Departments to &#x2013; Department to answer these two questions. So as for CapEx, let me cover this particular point.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (14:40 &#x2013; 15:09)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as Alex has already mentioned the adjusted CapEx program has already been approved by the Management Committee and the Board of Directors. And it will likely be within the remaining one and half month of the current year, there will be another session held by these bodies in order to review this plan. So we will take it just the final program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (15:31 &#x2013; 13:36) And now as for the retroactive payments and the Ukrainian prices.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (15:43 &#x2013; 16:27)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as for the prices for Ukraine, so they are established with an agreement of long-term contract. So and they are attached to the market's indices and indicators but as they closed for the oil price in particular and we also abide the so-called of hunt for discount that's why we say that we do not foresee any changes with regards to the prices offered to Ukraine.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (16:54- 17:00)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As for retroactive payments I can comment on that briefly.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (17:03 &#x2013; 17:30)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as for retroactive payments actually as they represented today, those reflect our &#x2013; those negative potential expectations and developments, which might be occurring sowing effect. They reflect exactly what turned out over the last six months and it has <mark type="indiscernible" /> (17:50).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (17:52 &#x2013; 18:08) So as for the reflected costs most likely it's still be probably related to the liabilities in terms of our payments which we have to make that taking into account illustrated as payments and most likely since they are reflected in the full in terms as they will be viewed because of the changes in the exchange rates.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (18:32 &#x2013; 18:37)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What are the accepted accounts receivables as of the Q2?</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (18:47- 18:55)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the total account is about RU133 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rubles.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We move to next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (19:12). Please go ahead announcing your company.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (19:15 &#x2013; 19:47)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So there two questions from <mark type="indiscernible" /> (19:48) from Merrill Lynch/Bank of America. So thank you very much for the presentation and the questions, are related to Gazprom plans with regards to Nord Gas company given the recent acquisition of 49%? And the second question is about any expectations regards to the progressing negotiations with China on gas supplies and that you got it?</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (20:15 &#x2013; 20:35)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So <mark type="indiscernible" /> (20:36) will answer these questions respectively.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (20:40 &#x2013; 21:44)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on the 6th November, we signed a contract with Nord Gas. So with regards to those 45% of the share which are not under control?  so the question is whether Gazprom will claim a potential acquisition of 49% in the company. So we still have a capital monthly for giving the final answer to this question and this matter should be discussed internally with the Gazprom.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (22:11- 22:40)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the Board of Directors of Novatech is supposed to consider this tomorrow at their meeting, and probably Gazprom and Nord Gas will be more actively considering the issue after the 15th of November,</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (22:59 &#x2013; 23:31)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as for your question regarding the China supply. So we have two corridors to supply product to China, so-called eastern corridor and the latter is <mark type="indiscernible" /> (23:45) corridor. And we've been regularly discussing the method of Chinese planning so and the regular meetings are held at the senior management level, which are attended by our senior managers and the corporate representatives of the China Gazprom.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (24:02- 24:16)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far the eastern corridor, so we are mostly planning to make use of this corridor for LNG supplies. And we are aimed at succeeding in our discussions and negotiations with our Chinese counterparties.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (24:34) Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (24:37) Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Andrey Gromadin. Please go ahead announcing your company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (24:47 &#x2013; 25:15) The representative from JP Morgan is asking two questions. This is one related to the south stream, and how the 16 billion euro total which was just we announced today is distributed among the participants in the consortium?</p>
          <p>And the second question is related to the retroactive payments and in particular, whether the figure which has been highlighted today includes the payment made to Poland.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (25:45 &#x2013; 27:09)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So -- and so the first question really got to the distribution marketable expenditures amongst the participants and the south stream project. So it is spread into two parts the maritime parts and the land part of the infrastructure element. So -- as we know the sea or maritime section has covered by the participants in the consortium which are represented by Gazprom any ideas and the German company to call. So as for the land section of the front-line, so it is implemented by means of number of joint ventures which are included respectively with Gazprom and national representatives of the industry.</p>
          <p>So -- and this, as I said, so this obligations obviously give you the pro-rata spending on the participation in the project and on top of everything else. The project is implemented on the project finances or financing, basis at the classical ratio of 30 to 70.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (28:22 &#x2013; 28:40)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as for the second question, the question you asked to whether the represented figure includes the retroactive payments involving the published part of this amount. So it has been calculated, but it was not included into the figure which has been highlighted and probably we'll have to review and readjust this figure when we consider the outcome of the nine-month metrics.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (29:10) Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from the line of Pavel Sorokin. Please go ahead announcing your company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (29:22 &#x2013; 30:06) So two questions from Morgan Stanley, if is that okay? So, the first one is related to on the Gazprom sales on the domestic market. The second one is related to the &#x2013; is related to the Alti pipeline project. Whether it is actually going to be careful to somehow change, because of the plans with regards to Vladivostok LNG pipeline supply project or Itochu Vladivostok pipeline project? Thank you.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (30:46 &#x2013; 31:00)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Mr. Kruglov will cover these two points respectively.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (31:05 &#x2013; 31:52)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as you know gas supplies on the domestic markets via Gazprom Michigan gas, so and thus for the current 2012 year, so the 40% of the contracts which we haven't in the portfolio are long-term projects, are which effective through 31st of December of the current year. So, we are currently negotiating the next year long-term project, but we do not know yet which or how many of these projects will really fall under the qualification of the long-term projects.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (32:28 &#x2013; 33:07)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So for the second question with regards to our projects related to our development into China so the Alti Vladivostok LNG projects are not really competing projects, because they are shooting at various and different markets. So Alti is supposed to provide products to the northwestern part of China. And this will Vladivostok LNG project, it is mostly suppose to provide the product LNG basically to east coast of the continental China. So, eventually, these two projects do not really conflict and the do not compete at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (33:47) Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (33:50) Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Artem Kvas. Please go ahead announcing your company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (34:04 &#x2013; 34:34) So two questions from Artem Kvas of Renaissance Capital. So the first question is now regarding your expectations of the potential input Gazprom Central Asia, taking into account the situation of the domestic and European market? And the second question is about the spot component in the gas price with reference to the well impact on the pricing? Thank you very much.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (35:07)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Mr. Medvedev from Gazprom Export representative will answer these two questions. Please.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (35:18 &#x2013; 35:37)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as for the Central Asia gas so we have current obligations on the current contracts we have with our suppliers for that. So -- and we are going to actually withdraw gas under this contract based on this minimal rate which we have under the contract. So they are correspondent to what we withdraw with this.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (36:04 &#x2013; 33:12)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Since it's about component and the price I would actually invite Gazprom representative to answer this question.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (36:22 &#x2013; 36:52)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Mr. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (36:55) who is the Head of the Department at Gazprom Export is answering the question. In regard to the spot component and the price, so actually it will slightly increase but we are liable both direct and indirect mix to actually calculate the spot component and the price but in any case the spot component and the price is not critical.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (37:20 &#x2013; 37:40) If I may, I would like to ask to clarify two points to the asked questions which you had answered already. As for the business question, so whether the figure of 35 corresponds to what you call the minimal obligations or liabilities under the installation input contract. The second one is, second verification is whether 18% is the fair reflection of these both components?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (38:09 &#x2013; 38:24) As for your first question, so we are still negotiating currently the figure. But to give you a short answer to the question, yes, the figure you mentioned is a fair reflection of our expectations.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (38:45 &#x2013; 39:04)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as for the second clarification, first of all, I'd like to specify that the book component is mostly related to our contract with North Western European countries. And let me reiterate my previous point that this fourth component in any case does not really make any critical impact on the output pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (39:25) I got it. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Alexander Kirevnin. Please go ahead announcing your company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (39:38 &#x2013; 40:00) So I would like to clarify the two figures, which I saw in your reporting and they're related to the financial obligations. So I have the figures RU2.3 billion, while there is a number which is RU2.7 million. So how do these two figures correspond to each other?</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (40:17 &#x2013; 40:25)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the difference includes the capital wise component, which is related to the capital construction.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (40:34)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So. Mr. Rosseev representing the Accounting Department answered the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. [Foreign Language] (40:44)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Abhimanyu Talwar. Please go ahead announcing your company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for the call. I am Abhimanyu from Nomura. I have a couple of questions. The first is regarding to the retroactive payments for second half of 2012....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think an action. Could you speak slower please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes Sure......</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's very noisy on the line, so I cannot hear what you say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry about that. Can you hear me now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a little better. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So my first question is about retroactive payments for second half. So I am sorry but I missed the figure. So can you repeat that figure again, the retroactive payments items for the second half? My second question is, if you could give me the unit costs of production for gas and it would be great if you can give me the cash costs. And my third question is regarding your CapEx figure for RU1.18 billion, so what is the level of flexibility around this CapEx figure? Is it 15, minus 15%, minus 22%? Can you give an idea of that as well? Thank you.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (41:56 &#x2013; 42:39)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you please repeat your third question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Sure. So my third question is around the flexibility which you have at reducing your CapEx if required. So is your CapEx figure of 1.18 billion for the whole of 2012? Is that flexible?</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (43:04 &#x2013; 43:32)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So let me start with answering your last question with regards to whether we have any flexibility in order to be capable of implementing our capital &#x2013; our CapEx plan. So we do have this flexibility and we have enough potential for actually successfully implementing the capital investment program we have approved.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (43:55 &#x2013; 44:00)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As for retroactive payments which was your first question, Mr. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (44:04) will answer this question.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (44:06 &#x2013; 44:27)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So let me repeat the previous point, which I made with regards to the retroactive payments. The current figure, which represents now report this next all the potential retroactive payments we made as of the month of October of this year. We do not expect any serious changes in this figure. [Foreign Language] (44:47- 45:01)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Miss Karpel, who is the member of the Board of Directors and the Head of the Economics and Expertise Department who will answer the question with regards to the cost of production.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (45:14 &#x2013; 45:37)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So this year, we expect to have the -- this year, we expect to have the figure which corresponds to our cost of production unit of gas to be delivered of RUB966 or approximately US$30 and 53% and this figure is taken by the mineral extraction tax.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (46:02 &#x2013; 46:20)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as -- for that I would like also to add that Gazprom is continuously trying to optimize the cost of production per unit and if you involve the production and transportation of gas so -- and actually the actual cost of production per unit is lower than the indices which are published by the Ministry of Economic Development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Just to confirm regarding my question on retroactive payments. So, do you mean that the figure of RUB54.7 billion, that figure is as of October and it is not expected to change materially, is that what you suggested?</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (47:08 &#x2013; 47:46)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually 64.7 is the figure which corresponds to Q2 in terms of the retroactive payments we assume, and the total amount is RU133 billion. As for answering your question, whether this figure is going to be significantly changed or not, so we might foresee some adjustments to the ultimate figure. But indeed, as of the outcome of the nine months and 12 months of the current year, we do not think that this figure will be significant compared to its total value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (48:24 &#x2013; 48:31)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Distinguished ladies and gentlemen, we have time left for two more questions. So go ahead with questions if any please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:40). Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for the conference call. I have two questions. The first question relate to the existing dividend policy and dividend policy with respect to the change in reporting of the accounts into IFRS. What are your thoughts or plans to payout dividend? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question relates once again to the process of budgeting for CapEx and dividends. Can you highlight some idea about how you will go about for the short-term budgeting, which is for the next yea and long-term or medium-term budgeting for 2015 onwards, long-term plan, please?</p>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (49:29 &#x2013; 50:02) Let me answer those questions.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (50:04 &#x2013; 50:34)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's for introduction on our transition too of international financial reporting standards from the Russian economic standards. We are very much focused on ensuring a successful implementation. So, and we recently discussed this matter with a one-on-one meeting with investors. So we do reaffirm our readiness and our interest in successful implementing this transition.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (51:02 &#x2013; 51:15)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we hope that in 2014 we will be able really to see our dividend policy based on the IFRS standards.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (51:26 &#x2013; 52:04)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so as for the dividend policy for 2013, so, yes, we are going to really consider it and take into account the developments and as for -- or in light of our plans for CapEx for next year, so we are expecting to hold Emergency Meeting, a meeting shortly. So -- and we will consider this figure there. Closer and closer, but we expect the figure to be comparable to the current year, the amount which is RUB800 billion.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (52:39 &#x2013; 52:54)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And thus for the dividends payable in 2013, we expect them to be at a similar level of 25% as we did it last year.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (53:12)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And one more point. One more question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question comes from the line of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (53:22). Please go ahead announcing your company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (53:27 &#x2013; 53:53) So the question is about your borrowing plans and policy. So how you are going to resolve the method of funding for your CapEx, dividend policy needs, and repayment be made, because as far as I understand, cash flow which we observe currently not going to be sufficient for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (54:15 &#x2013; 54:35) So as for an exact figure, answering the question regarding boarding plans for the next year so the figure -- so the year is going to remain similar as it is this year which is RUB98 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (54:55) Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (54:58 &#x2013; 55:44)</p>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, I would like to thank you for the interest you demonstrated in participating in in Analyst Day teleconference and if any of you didn't have a chance to ask your question or if there are some clarifications to the slides so you are welcome to address those to our corporate finance department and to those who are in charge of our relations with investors. So, and I would like also to thank my colleagues who actually came to the teleconference and provided the input throughout the day. We would also like to thank our interpreter <mark type="indiscernible" /> (56:22) for his assistance and his endeavors to help us to understand each other. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation today. This concludes today's conference. And you may now disconnect you lines. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>