<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1202925" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>FY 2007 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-01</date>
    <companies>
      <company>2060</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Pyotr Bakayev, Head of Financial Markets Division</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Andrey Vyacheslavovich Kruglov, Deputy Chairman of Gazprom's Management Committee, Head of the Department for Finance and Economics</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Elena Alexandrovna Vasilieva, Deputy Chairman of Gazprom's Management Committee and Chief Accountant</participant>
      <participant id="4">Vadim Mitroshin</participant>
      <participant id="5">Scott Darling</participant>
      <participant id="6">Pavel Kushnir</participant>
      <participant id="7">Oleg Maximov</participant>
      <participant id="8">Ronald Smith</participant>
      <participant id="9">Dmitry Loukashov</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for standing by and welcome to the Gazprom Results Announcement Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. I must advise you that this conference is being recorded today, Tuesday the 1st of July 2008. I would now like to hand the conference over to your first speaker today, Pyotr Bakayev. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Good afternoon, good evening, distinguished ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to the conference call. Gazprom indicated finance accounting, on international standards for <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
          <p>The participants will include from the Finance Department, Andrey Vyacheslavovich Kruglov, Member of the Board of the Governors and the Department of <mark type="inaudible" /> and the Elena Alexandrovna; Head of the Main Chief Accountant, Alexander Ananenkov, Chief Accountant of Chief of the Technology Department <mark type="inaudible" /> the Department of Acquiring, <mark type="inaudible" /> Strategic Marketing also Power Energy. My name is Pyotr Bakayev. I'm Head of Department on Market Activities.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>All departments are here, our colleagues of the aforementioned departments and the subsidiary bodies.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>At this time, I will move on to Andrey Vyacheslavovich Kruglov for a brief statement. Then, after Krugov's and Vasilieva's addresses we'll be happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Good afternoon, distinguished ladies and gentlemen <mark type="inaudible" /> for the presentation and <mark type="inaudible" /> the phone conference call. <mark type="inaudible" /> today <mark type="inaudible" /> on the basis of the presentation <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Let's have a look at the first slide we have.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Over several years, Gazprom has shown the main revenue being on the rise as regards those indices. However, hence that year 2007 was temporarily slowing the real growth of those prices.</p>
          <p>Demand on gas on our key markets has turned out to be a quite difficult year for Gazprom which we have mentioned on several occasions already.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>However, even under the circumstances we faced in year 2007 versus say year 2006, we have showing the revenues growth by 11% in 2007 compared 2006 with the cash from operating activities being on the rise by 10%.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Now as regards the finance and investment activities, we have to point out that even with quite a large volume of borrowings which were carried out in the year 2007 to domestic acquisitions which occurred, the net debt to EBITDA was maintained at the level of 1.4 despite those domestic acquisitions. We've mentioned the fact that to us, as we perceive it, the limit of that index would be no more than 1.5.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>I'd like to draw your attention to our next overhead. You could see that the market environment was far from unequivocal.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>In Russia, the regulated prices on gas were indicized at 15%. At the same time, in the FSU, Former Soviet Union countries, the growth of those prices accounted for 25% in dollars and only 18% in rubles. At the same time, in our most profitable European markets, the average prices in dollars in year 2007 virtually did not change, having been added only $8 and are remaining lower than $270 per 1000 cubic meters.</p>
          <p>In ruble, that would -</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>In rubles that accounted their plummeting more than at 2%. And at that in the year 2007, the growth of average prices of selling gas at the European market expressed in dollars accounted more than 36%.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>With consideration to the &#x2013; well known to you &#x2013; prices lag and link between the prices of our export-oriented contracts in the basket of oil products, the feeble dynamics of prices on export contract year 2007 was a consequence of landslide plummeting of world prices on hydrocarbon commodities in the second half of year 2006. This was the picture of the main markets we've been dealing at in the year 2007.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>In this overhead, you can see that the overall volume of sales of gas last year shrunk approximately at 1%, going down to 572 billion cubic meters which resulted from the shrinking demand basically at the domestic market and in the markets of the countries of the Former Soviet Union having to do with the extremely warm winter of year 2006 and 7.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Having said that, we have augmented the volumes of sales of gas at the European market more than at 4%. That is coming from 162 and going up to 169 billion of cubic meters of gas. Such increase has become possible mainly thanks to the substantial growth of sales at the new market for us in Great Britain.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Now, the volumes of sales in UK have grown up in year 2007 by 75% versus 2006 and exceeded 15 billion cubic meters, including the supplies for the spot market and to the end users.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Now, at the next overhead you can see the revenue reconciliation and I would like to point out that irrespective of the fact that there was a shrinking of sales at the domestic market and the markets of the Former Soviet Union republics and also the plummeting of the average price of sales at the European market expressed in rubles, we have been able to balance those negative effects of the market situation.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>This was achieved correspondingly through the growth of prices in Russia and in the countries of the Former Soviet Union and through the increase of volumes of sales in Europe. According to the results of the year, Gazprom has shown growth of its revenues from sales of gas and the net revenue as a whole. That's the net revenue in year 2007 has been increased by 11% and accounted for almost RUB2.4 trillion.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>In the next overhead, you can get acquainted with the operating expenses of our group over the past year which has increased by 24%. The growth of operating expenses has been caused mainly by the following factors in play.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Now, as regards those increases, they boil down to the following factors. Those were costs borne for the oil and gas imported which have grown by 36%. Now those were expenses on wages and the salaries also increased by 25% and also expenses on maintenance and repair works of the equipment going up by 24%. Those were the factors I've mentioned as playing into this increase of operating expenses.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Now the next slide, will really reveal that we didn't have a very smooth sailing this year. As has been mentioned before, in this period, the dynamics of the indices of EBITDA and the net revenues as well as the following indices of cost efficiencies have suffered. Thus, the EBITDA in year 2007 has gone down by 7.5% versus year 2006 and cost efficiency of EBITDA had shrunk to the level of 37% only.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Now the net revenue over that period with regards to all the revenues and losses has still grown up by 7% &#x2013; 7.3%, which has to do with the fact that over the past year, quite a large part has been played by the non-finance onetime options and operations, including reassessment of the cost of option to purchase 20% of shares of Gazprom Neft. Also, it reflected the transaction on the swap of the assets with BASF AG and deconsolidation of the pension fund, Gazfond.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>While having said that, in the context of the past three years, the dynamics of EBITDA and of the net revenue still remain quite impressive. Such indices have revealed the growth of 2.4 to 3 times correspondingly. In the current year, thanks to the drastic growth of the world prices on energy sources, we expect restoration of the powerful positive dynamics of our financial outcomes.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>At the last overhead, you can get acquainted with the operating cash flow over the past three years.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>On this slide, you can see our debt structure and in the year 2007 utilizing the attractive character of the situation emerging in the market, we have carried out several purchases, including in the power sector, in the development and transportation of gas which we regard as strategically very attractive and potentially profitable.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>In this regard, we might as well say that in the year 2007, we have attracted quite substantial finance resources. Resulting from that, our overall debt has grown by 40%, exceeding RUB1.5 trillion; and the net debt has grown by 52%, going up to more than RUB1.2 trillion.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>And I'd like to stress once again, which you have already mentioned, that it has been possible for us to retain the net debt versus adjusted EBITDA at the level of 1.4. And the ratio of the borrowed and owned capital has been possible to maintain lower than the established by the Board of Directors' limit of 40%. The structure of debt, and the terms of payment have not altered drastically either. The share of the secured debt has gone down lower than 2%.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>We are positive that despite the substantial growth of the burden of our debt, our group is capable to generate sufficient cash flow to service that debt. And, also, we believe that the growth of the net debt-adjusted EBITDA in this is caused by the temporary events.</p>
          <p>This growth was caused by coincidence in time of the moment of attracting substantial finance resources, and shrinking EBITDA having to do with the unfavorable market situation, and we are pursuing our effort to reduce this index to a comfy level of 1.0, 1.2.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Distinguished ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your attention. I'll give the floor to the Head of the Department of Finance Accounting, and after that we'll be prepared to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Russian]</p>
          <p>Good afternoon or evening distinguished ladies and gentlemen depending on where you are right now.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Prior to dealing immediately with the indices of the accounting report presented to you, allow me first of all to stress the fact that the information which is given in this Note 38, Factors of the Financial Risks, has been given according to the requirements given by the new standard, MSFO 7 Financial Instruments Disclosures.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>It is important to point out that the consolidated accounting of the group Gazprom over the year 2007 has been prepared in correspondence with IFRS and MSFO. And it is important to point out that its factors have been very instrumental, and were explained by several circumstances.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Some of these circumstances really have an impact on the results of the Gazprom Group constantly. They include dependence in part of our results from the pricing situation regarding main products of our line.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Other circumstances are fairly temporary -</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>These onetime factors would include the following. That's the reconsideration given to the order and procedure of consolidation of the results of the pension fund, Gazfond, in the accounting of Gazprom Group.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Completion of the transaction on the assets swap between the Gazprom Group and BASF Group.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Change of fair cost of the Gazprom Group option to purchase 20% of shares of Gazprom Neft.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Now, I'll briefly expand on those onetime factors, and their effect on the overall results.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>The change of the procedure of consolidation of pension fund, Gazfond, was considered in detail while discussing the consolidating accounting of Gazprom Group for the first quarter of year 2007.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>The effect of this factor regarding the results of the report on the profit and loss were given expression in acknowledging the profit to the item of change of the sequence of those Gazfond, which has totaled RUB45 billion.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>In year 2007, Gazprom and BASF have carried out a swap of their assets.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>According to the signed agreement, the Gazprom Group has increased its share in the company Wintershall gas 50% minus one share, and also has acquired the share to the tune of 49% in the charter capital of Wintershall AG Group and accordingly, 598 billion euros.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>BASF, in turn, has acquired share in the charter capital of Severneftegazprom to the tune of 25% minus one nominal share and one privileged share.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>The profit acquired by the group in the result of such transaction was shown as a separate item in the consolidating report on profit and losses to the tune of around RUB51 billion.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Now, recognition of this profit is about the fact that the acquired assets actually were reflected on the market price, whereas the lost &#x2013; the sold share to Severneftegazprom in this consolidated report was reflected according to the historic costs.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Therefore, in this consolidated report, the assessment of these sold shares is representing the value of 25% of the whole accounting, whereas in the net assets of Severneftegazprom -</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>In April 2007, any company has represented Gazprom an option to purchase 20% of a share of Gazprom Neft, which is in effect until April of year 2009.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>The change of fair price of this option since the time of signing of the corresponding agreement until December 31, 2007 was justified by the growth of the market quotations of shares of Gazprom Neft.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>According to the requirements placed by <mark type="inaudible" /> of the corresponding financial asset was reflected among other out-of-operation assets of consolidated balance. As regards profits of consolidated reports on profits and losses, it was reflected as a revenue resulting from the change of costs of options to the tune of RUB51 billion.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Now, on top of these onetime factors, which affected our operation, of note 12 on certain indices of report on losses and profits, change of which might be of interest substantially to the users of our reporting information.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>First, in the structure of revenues of Gazprom in year 2007, we have witnessed substantial growth by 62% of the returns on other sales.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>First, in the structure of revenues in the overall growth this index of RUB62 billion versus year 2006, the most growth has been &#x2013; and that is RUB38 billion, included in the reporting document having to do with the results of Mosenergo after we had established supervision, and control over the aforementioned company. Another RUB12 billion are accounted for other sales pursued by Gazprom Germany Group.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>The sales of these groups primarily include sales of the purchase of sales of power.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Mr. Kruglov, before me in his presentation has pointed out that the growth of operational expenses on main items, which have resulted in the growth of overall value of operational expenses has been observed.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Now, I'll expand on such expenses.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Now, as regards expenses on the volumes of oil and gas purchased, they have increased by 36%, mainly thanks to the growth of prices on gas in Central Asian producers Central Asian republics as well as growth of trade transactions to purchase sales of the gas immediately in the European market, and correspondingly growth of volumes of gas pressures there.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>The latter operations are carried out according to the market prices, and relate to the activities of Germany Gazprom Group. Pure growth of volumes of purchased gas accounted for around 31%.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Generally speaking, the growth of payment of wages and salary in the Gazprom Group have grown up by 25%.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Now, in the overall group of such expenses accounting for RUB49 billion, it can be fleshed out in the following groups.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Approximately RUB7 billion are explained by the growth of expenses on pension reserves, which is explained by the change of economy parameters used for computing such reserves. RUB4 billion relate to the activities of Mosenergo indices of which are included in the consolidated report, starting from the second half of year 2007.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>And RUB10 billion are related to the activities of Gazprombank, which has started in year 2007, its payments in the frameworks of new system of material support of workers providing the bonus program for the staff members.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>As the RUB7 billion are rounded, relate to the increase of expenses to paycheck given in Gazprom Neft Group and Sibur Group. And this growth of paycheck has to do with the growth of the strength of their personnel as well as the need to do away with the lagging behind as regards on their part wages and salary payments and to reach the level of competitiveness with other companies there.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Now, discarding the effect of the aforementioned factors, still, the growth of expenses for wages and salaries accounted for 16.6%, which is not very much different from the rates of inflation for the period of 2006 and 2007.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Miscellaneous operational expenses, I will touch upon those as well a little bit here.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>First and foremost, I have to point out that the year 2006, those miscellaneous operational expenses included the impact of the operations carried out by the pension fund, Gazfond. I will explain those.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>The pension fund placed and allocated the assignations and made disbursements of pension reserves first and foremost and invested those savings in the securities -</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>- according to the procedure established by the government of the Russian Federation.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Due to the fact that from the perspective of Gazprom group as a whole, the purchase of such securities in the process of placement and disbursements of the reserve were not the main core activity and was carried out in the frameworks of the pension insurance of the staff members of the group. The losses and profits from the effect of sales of such securities was reflected only briefly as a part of the operational expenses.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>In year 2006, we have got some profit on the basis of such transactions.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>And this profit has helped to compensate for other operational expenses of the group.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>In year 2007, these results of the fund of pensioners that were not included in the consolidated reporting documents of Gazprom Group.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Therefore, the financial outcome of the change of the procedure of consolidation of Gazprom Group &#x2013; insured rather of consolidation of pension fund, Gazfond, insured around RUB40 billion of growth in miscellaneous operational expenses since they were no longer reflected as the aforementioned transactions.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>On top of that, thanks to the changes of the exchange rates of foreign currencies, the growth of expenses of the group on those exchange rate differences related to the operation activities accounted for approximately RUB2 billion.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Some RUB11 billion in the overall sum of the growth of expenses relate to the activities of Mosenergo.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>The growth of expenses based on the reassessment of the trade options at fair prices accounted for some RUB7 billion.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>On top of that, thanks to the growth of works done in geological survey and exploration, those have grown expenses, accounted for the growth of around RUB4 billion as well.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>That's the end of the presentation.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Thank you very much for your time and attention.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>We'll be happy to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>From Credit Suisse your first question comes from Vadim Mitroshin.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have basically the limit working these questions saying two questions. First is not exactly about the results of the last year. Since we already are in the middle of this year and on the basis of the first six months, perhaps it's possible to get a clearer sense of the current perspective with respect to the average prices on energy sources in Europe. Could you tell us what your imagination and expectation is about those prices?</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The Gazprom expert <mark type="inaudible" /> will answer this question.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have witnessed much better results over the past six months this year compared to previous one.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The same relates to the situation with pricing.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the idea is quite clear since our gas prices are very much dependent on oil prices.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The leadership of Gazprom has already cited the figure of the expected average price on gas in the year 2008.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And this figure was not less than US$400 per 1000 square cubic meters.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A point of clarification if I may. I understand that very recently, Mr. Miller himself stated the fact that already those prices on gas have reached the level of $410 per 1000 cubic meters. Can we expect that by the end of the year, this price will go up to $500?</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe it should be suffice to limit ourselves  with the price we have stated here.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, at different parts of European markets, you can be confronted with different prices at this point in time.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, on the one hand, there are long-term prices linked to oil.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the other hand, there are spot prices as well.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And in some cases, there is a trend to be noted that those spot prices sometimes could go above the level of the long-term oil-related prices.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Even here it's very difficult to predict the spot market, that being too volatile. That's about it to answer your question.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, my second question about those miscellaneous prices -- I've been listening to the remarks on that matter and I believe even with regards to this deconsolidation of the pension fund still miscellaneous expenses seem to appear quite substantial.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, if you could, please give us a fair idea regarding what other miscellaneous expenses can be expected this year and what they will include and to what level in addition to the fact you've mentioned that the exchange rate difference, Mosenergo and visitation with the fund?</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The accounting report, <mark type="inaudible" /> will take this question.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, before the new report is to emerge, we're not in position to give you the indices and data on those items.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what in substance it includes is as follows. It includes the travel expenses on business trips for the staff members. It includes such matters as providing security and safety of worker at the working place. It includes also geographical survey and prospecting and etcetera. And all of them being small amounts, I give you the overall amount of expenses as given in the report.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. From Lehman Brothers, you now have a question from Scott Darling. Please ask your question sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon everybody, Scott Darling from Lehman Brothers &#x2013; just to really clarify what you said before: in simple terms, how do you expect operating expenses to increase in 2008 from the '07 level? Is it 15% like you said on the last conference call? Or is it nearer to 24% that we saw in your last results? And if it's towards the higher end, what measures are you doing to materially reduce your costs?</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, to answer your question, first and foremost, there are certain operational expenses which are within the purview of the management of our group which we can really have our say on. Then there are others which we have no influence whatsoever and they have to do with taxation. They have to do it with the costs on the materials and metals. Those costs have been growing as you know as well as costs of oil purchased from the Central Asian republics. And all of them are included in those ongoing operational expenses, and are well beyond the realm of any effect to be given on behalf of our management to mitigate them.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, as regards those expenses which are under the control and command of the management, they are within the limits of the indices of deflators which are being regularly adjusted and are presented to us on behalf of the Ministry of Economy and Development.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to give you one example, the growth of wages and salaries is according to the collective agreement concluded by the management and the staff is to be compensated to the tune of the inflation which is presented to us by the Ministry of Economy and Trade and Development.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, as regard to our effort to control those expenses, we've been pursuing this policy of better management of the budget and introducing better discipline on behalf of the subsidiaries. And on the yearly basis, we've been stringently following the results so that they will not exceed the limits of their expenses and they will follow through on the planned indices and the outcomes of their operation in those subsidiaries.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, since we have started this year, our program of the bonus that is stimulating the productivity on behalf of the staff. We have also introduced the discipline measure whereby those leaders of the subsidiary organizations if they're failing to fulfill the limit of the budget in their purview, then it will be telling on the reimbursement of such staff members. That is not to allow that to happen.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And even one month ago only, we had a special meeting of the management dedicated to the results of the abiding by the financial discipline on the part of the structural entities and subsidiary <mark type="inaudible" /> over the year of 2007. However, exactly this term of reference was reinforced and the matters pertaining to financial discipline were thoroughly discussed. And the proper conclusions were drawn, to become even more stringent on observance of those rules and regulations.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please go ahead with your next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just follow-up on this?</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I appreciate there's control &#x2013; costs out of your control like materials and taxes, etc. but we're still continuing &#x2013; and wages &#x2013; we're still continuing to see high inflation of those non-controlled costs. Is it fair to say your cost inflation of '07 of 24% is representative going forward?</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The Accounting Department representative will answer your question.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, I would like to clarify one point here. Talking about this 24% you have to make distinction and really to set apart this figure from certain one-time expenses, which are not market dependent at all. And just to give you an example, that is the growth of purchase of gas in its volumes from those Central Asian republics, which have nothing to do with the inflation processes or other political matter. And had that been fleshed out and separated then, this figure would differ from this 24% in the first place.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Indeed, if we again will take away those tax items and the exchange rate differences item from this figure, then this figure will go down to 16% only. The fact that we have 12% of the index of growth of consumer prices and then if it were taken not for the past year, but also for accumulated again, would give you a different number.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Any other questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes indeed there are, sir. From Deutsche Bank you now have a question from Pavel Kushnir.  Please as your question sir.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My first question is: with regards to your presented early expectations on CapEx, and you said those would be to the tune of RUB330 billion in year 2007; but, according to this report, these capital expenses are rather to the tune of 540, which is a 64% growth.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What is the question?</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How can you explain such a difference?</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, we have to sort it out where you found this figure. Probably and most probably, that was an info given in the section on budget expenses for reference primarily.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And there in small letters, it was given that that was the budget for the main group, which did not include such organizations as Mosenergo investments and others.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But over the second half of the year, we have included in this reporting the consolidated expensing including Mosenergo this time.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And subsidiaries were also included with their investments, which are not pursued through the investment of the main group.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm clear about that. But still, you will have US$9 billion here on the non-main group investments of Mosenergo and the Sibur Group. And still I'm hard to believe that they would come up to such a figure here. So could you please spell it out for us in a little bit more detail?</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that is a quite thorough question. I'm not in position to give you entire answer on all of those. Just give you one example here. RUB60 million were invested by Mosenergo &#x2013; billion.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, another thing concerning these other sales with regards to Mosenergo, you've also mentioned that between the third and fourth quarters there was substantial growth of 100% from 29 billion to RUB34 billion. Could you explain that since we understand that consolidation in Mosenergo all that occurred in the second half of the year?</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This can be partially explained by the fact that in the fourth quarter some sales by Gazprom Germany was also carried out. And they also included some sales given to our subcontractors who were working on our sites as well. And that was both done within the terms of the fourth quarter too.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes indeed sir. From Troika Dialog you now have a question from Oleg Maximov.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes my name is Oleg Maximov from Troika Dialog. My question is concerning CapEx'es. In the press, you had some articles on the plan to increase the involvement of Gazprom with CapEx'es in the coming year. First, they started to talk about RUB100 billion in some press articles and most recently in Kommersant, they mentioned already RUB200 billion of CapEx'es. Could you explain those numbers?</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, to give you an answer, I must first and foremost tell you that the final decision on those budget disbursements have not been adopted yet by the management. And we're in the process of putting together these finalization situation to occur. And once and we have it, we'll inform you accordingly. And yes, we have expressed our intention to increase those numbers.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Other questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes indeed sir. From Alfa Bank your next question comes from Ron Smith.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ron Smith, Alfa Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes gentlemen. Actually, if you wouldn't mind, let's turn our attention a little bit to volumes and what's going on in Europe. Now I know we had a very warm winter last year. Assuming that this winter is normal, not exceptionally cold, not exceptionally warm, what kind of volume bounce back are you looking for? Should we be putting into our models merely what you had two years ago or should there be some kind of significant growth beyond that? In other words, a pretty sharp increase year-on-year for two reasons, one, ordinary growth and second the &#x2013; just a return to normal weather?</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gazprom expert will take your question. We still have time for one more question only.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one more question, did you say sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. From UBS, your last...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Wait a minute.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This question has not been answered yet. And the gentleman is going to give an answer to the asked question before this one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I beg your pardon sorry sir. Ron Smith's line is back open, that's my mistake.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>True to say, last year was exceptionally cold whereas the year before that was more back to normalcy.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Still, we're planning for the growth of volumes this year.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Approximately to give you a fair idea, this growth as compared to last year would be at the level of around 5 to 6% growth as a minimum.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Wonderful.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And again, the concluding question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Shall I take a question from another party gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your final question line comes from UBS from Dmitry Loukashov.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Dmitry Loukashov.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have two questions and I don't mind if you ask &#x2013; I ask two questions and you answer at least one of those. First is from the figures you gave on those purchases of BASF transaction with the given figure of 50,853 million and then with the exactly the BASF given earlier is 51,379 million. There is a difference of 400 million and of rubles, which is around $50 billion. Therefore, it has to do we believe with the Yuzhno-Russkoye field, and it's hard to expect that Severnefte were operational expenses to that tune as they were carried out. So, this needs to be clarified the difference.</p>
          <p>And on miscellaneous expenses, we've given 2 billion as a big number for fourth quarter with expectation of 100% growth for the third to fourth quarter and expectation of 100 growth at the average, which is a big expectation, needs to be explained. Otherwise, you need to give a breakdown, which will spell out the dynamics. Otherwise, it will be hard for us to expect this 100% growth on the average basis to go. And the cost of the whole company will be really getting out of comfortable range.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, I would perhaps on your question specify and spell out one point made early in the presentation on the so-called historic expense of 25%. More probably to say that they were rather accounted expenses of the net profit of Severneftegazprom.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This difference of assessment is not about the difference of the assets, which we have transferred them they received.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's not the difference between the cost and the fair price of the purchased assets.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's the difference between the fair assessment of the assets we have obtained and the accounted values, which are shared in net assets of Severneftegazprom Company. Gazprom is still on the stage of exploring this item and haven't got any substantial returns. Don't expect them to get some net profit of substantial value; it's pretty much Europe. I don't know if I have clarified your point, but this is what I have to tell you.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Information of net profit here. I believe that's enough for me as an answer. Thank you.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For your second question, I would like to clarify one point. Truth of the matter is my miscellaneous expenses are now giving you some food for a thorough discussion as it were.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is the story of how dynamics of those expenses were revealing themselves in the previous year, 2006 that is.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In 2006 and the fourth quarter, we recognized certain reduction of those miscellaneous expenses as it will show in the report.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Overall, for 2006, these miscellaneous expenses were cut down by 35 billion.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have discussed this at the press call before.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This year, at the same time, we didn't have any onetime operation, which would have such a long-term effect in future.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Therefore, we're not currently prepared to warn you of any other consequences because we're simply not aware of those right now. Thank you.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, have I answered your question?</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So my question was whether we need to expect such double increase on a quarter basis from now how we can forecast and compute on our part such possible double increase like you gave an answer about this company's &#x2013; or isn't &#x2013; which was about year 2006. But you're giving us this augmentation in the third and fourth quarter of year 2007. So what we need to do, what we should expect, please tell us with regards to such a possibility of a double increase of such miscellaneous expenses on the quarter basis.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, it's a very traditional thing that in the fourth quarter, those expenses will grow in our practice. Therefore, we cannot give you any advice and recommendation how you can forecast those expenses in future.</p>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Advice you give to the analytics, which will be satisfactory for them. Anyhow, thank you for your kind response.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10">
        <plist>
          <p>[Russian]</p>
          <p>Thank you very much for your participation and all the best to all of you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much indeed to all our speakers. That does conclude our conference for today. Thank you for participating. You may all disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>