<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1230850" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-17</date>
    <companies>
      <company>223</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Trevor A. Schauenberg, Vice President, Corporate Investor Communications</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jeffrey R. Immelt, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Keith S. Sherin, Vice Chairman and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Brackett B. Denniston III, Senior Vice President and General Counsel</participant>
      <participant id="5">Terry Darling</participant>
      <participant id="6">Scott Davis</participant>
      <participant id="7">Nigel Coe</participant>
      <participant id="8">Stephen Tusa</participant>
      <participant id="9">Robert Cornell</participant>
      <participant id="10">Jason Feldman</participant>
      <participant id="11">Jeffrey Sprague</participant>
      <participant id="12">John Inch</participant>
      <participant id="13">Steven Winoker</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the General Electric second quarter 2009 earnings conference call.  At this time all participants are in a listen-only mode.  My name is Noelia, and I will be your conference coordinator today.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded.  I would now like to turn the program over to your host for today's conference Trevor Schauenberg, VP of Investor Communications.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Noelia.  Good morning and welcome, everyone.  JoAnna and I are pleased to host today's webcast.  Hopefully you have the press release from earlier this morning, and the slides are via the webcast.  The slides are also available for download and printing on our website at www.GE.com/investor.  If you don't see it, please refresh.</p>
          <p>As always, elements of this presentation are forward-looking and are based on our best view of the world and our businesses as we see them today.  Those elements can change as the world changes.  Please interpret them in this light.</p>
          <p>We will be reviewing the GE press release that went out earlier today and have time for Q&amp;A at the end.  For today's webcast we have our Chairman and CEO, Jeff Immelt; our Vice Chairman and CFO Keith Sherin, and our Senior Vice President and General Counsel, Brackett Denniston.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to turn it over to our Chairman and CEO, Jeff Immelt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Trevor.  Good morning, everybody.  On the first page, the overview: despite a difficult global economy, we're pleased with our results.  Overall earnings of 2.9 billion Energy and Technology Infrastructure continue to perform.  GE Capital is profitable and Media and C&amp;I [Commercial and Industrial] basically were down versus last year.  Our execution is very good.</p>
          <p>Our cash flow is ahead of plan.  We have generated $7.1 billion of industrial cash flow year to date.  We were able to do substantial restructuring in the quarter.  Our margins were basically flat year-over-year and our backlog remains strong.  And we announced during the quarter several investments, new products, technology centers.  Our R&amp;D spending in '09 is greater than '08.  We're pursuing stimulus projects.  So basically all the things that we said we were going to do in the last period of time we've really executed on in this cycle.</p>
          <p>If you look at the environment and the global landscape, not much has really changed from how we saw it at EPG [Electrical Products Group].  Unemployment, CapEx, commercial credit all remain challenging.  And we're seeing growth in selected markets.  Parts of the globe are still robust.  China, the Middle East, India, places like that.  Deflation is helping our margins.  Importantly customer usage helps our service business.  Existing assets are being utilized early and we get great traction in services.  Stimulus was really a nonfactor in the first half but we see momentum building.  And the Capital Markets are improving.  And all these things we talked about at EPG are underway.</p>
          <p>We talked about on the next page how we were going to execute through the recession, the operating framework for the company.  I'll give you an update on where we stand on each one of these fronts.  We really talked about three things: making GE Capital safe and secure, outperforming in a tough economy, and strengthening the balance sheet.  And I'll go through some of the details and updates in the second quarter in the next few pages.</p>
          <p>The first one on GE Capital safe and secure, we really have made substantial progress on leverage, funding and the balance sheet.  First on long-term debt funding, '09 is done.  '10 is partially done, and 2010 we plan to have done by the end of this year.  And we plan to issue more unguaranteed debt this year.  Commercial paper is already at our year-end target, and cash plus back-up lines are more than double our commercial paper, so we're very strong there.  We have reduced our leverage to 5.6 to 1.</p>
          <p>Our Tier 1 Common Ratio is equal to the strongest banks.  Our Ending Net Investment that we have already achieved at roughly $500 billion, our '09 goal, we expect that to trend lower in the next two quarters.  Our collections are strong.  And we'll show you a lot of detail about GE Capital on July 28.  But we feel very good about how we're executing in this cycle.</p>
          <p>On the next page just talking about orders and backlog, we had about $18 billion of second quarter orders, slightly below first quarter and down about 23% FX adjusted versus last year.  We're down about 16% year to date.  The backlog remains strong.  The orders were about the same level as '06 and '07.  Backlog remains very strong at $169 billion.</p>
          <p>If you just look at the orders in some context, we had a record first half of '08.  That was really the peak of what we saw for major equipment orders.  We built $30 million of backlog over the last four years so we really expected orders to be down even without the recession.</p>
          <p>A couple positives about where we stand with major equipment.  Our cancellations are very low.  Our cancellations are like $100 million, so extremely low.  We're holding almost $12.5 billion of progress.  And a couple things though bode well for the next six months.  On Energy, we're really working the commitment to order conversion.  The production tax credit on wind just was clarified in the last week or so, so we think that's going to improve the order scope in the second half.  And the roughly $8 billion we took in commitments at the Paris Air Show will convert to orders over the next six months.</p>
          <p>If you look at our backlog conversion rate and current orders and look forward maybe 12 months, and you think about the fact that about two-thirds of any given year's revenue convert from backlog and the other third represent current year orders, we look at a rough estimate for 2010 at about with equipment revenue down about 10 to 15%, somewhere in that range just because we have such extremely high backlogs right now.</p>
          <p>Meanwhile, service continues to perform at a very high level, up 4% orders year to date.  We had $4.3 billion in new CSA [Contractual Service Agreement] additions in the second quarter.  And the service story continues to be very strong.  If you look at the next page, we'll just take little bit of a deeper dive on service.  Service in the quarter grew in revenue, margins and backlog.  Four of our five major service businesses will be profitable for the year.  Energy, we see momentum building in the second half of the year as contractual services continue to accelerate.  Oil and gas would have been positive in the first half on an FX adjusted basis, but we see good momentum in the second half.  Aviation had spares orders up 10% in the first half, so again that bodes well for the second half.  And Healthcare we're seeing customer outsourcing, so we're seeing good service revenue growth there.</p>
          <p>And transportation, you guys have all read about the fact that there the industry has maybe 5,400 locomotives parked, about 30% of those are GE.  And despite that, our service earnings were only down about 5%.  So this is about a little bit more than 75% of our total industrial net income with high visibility, well positioned for the future for 2010 and beyond.  And we just think from an investor standpoint, this just gives us great strength when we think about where we are and positioned for the future.</p>
          <p>Quick update on the stimulus and global growth.  First with stimulus, we talked about at EPG having about $190 billion of potential from a stimulus standpoint.  Almost nothing has come out from this so far.  The major buckets are clean energy, affordable healthcare, and then a scattering of other projects.  We're seeing some early wins in smart grid with orders up 70%.  Again, as we said, the wind tax credits have been clarified.  China's spending is very strong.  We're starting to get some bidding on health information exchanges and we're seeing some decent activity around the nuclear business.</p>
          <p>If you look at it from a global standpoint, you know some of the global regions are still extremely strong.  China was up 31% in the quarter, India up 46%, the Middle East up 10% despite the fact that we're only beginning the Iraq shipments and order completion.  So the major initiatives are underway.  Our 2009 product spend is up.  We think it's in the right places and we think this bodes well for the future.</p>
          <p>The next two charts give you an update on execution in the quarter.  And again we feel pretty good about how the team is executing.  The second quarter margins were basically stable at about 16.3%.  We saw good margin expansion at the contribution margin level.  Our service margins expanded by 3 points.  The headwind really in NBCU as Keith will cover in a minute come fundamentally from impairments.  We had very aggressive base cost reduction.  We're on track for 10% base cost reduction for the year.  Our second quarter base cost reduction was 14%, and we see a lot of this momentum carrying forward into the future.</p>
          <p>And lastly on restructuring, you know, we have done about $5 billion restructuring since 2007.  We're evaluating another $2 billion of restructuring with about a two-year payback.  These are more structural and focused, and again we think the more restructuring we can do this year positions 2010 for improved outlook for earnings and beyond.  So that's really what the goal is is to continue to take cost out of GE.</p>
          <p>Lastly, you know, cash has been a very strong story in the quarter.  We generated $4.3 billion of cash in the quarter.  As you all know, the GECS [GE Capital Services] dividend is zero for this year.  Our working capital was reduced by 2.3 billion, more than offsetting the reduction in progress payments.  You know, historically we generate about 40% of our cash in the first half of the year, so at 7 billion that puts us well on our way to the 14 to 16 billion-dollar goal for industrial CFOA [Cash Flow from Operating Activities] for the year.</p>
          <p>You know, we have about consolidated cash of $52 billion at GE, an addition of $5 billion in the quarter.  And with the dividend reduced from 6.7 to $2.3 billion starting in the second half, that generates really surplus cash in the second half and we'll save $13 billion of cash in '09 and '10.  So this is a great story, and again the team is executing well, and I would say we're ahead of plan here with very solid prospects for the rest of the year.</p>
          <p>So with that, let me turn it over to Keith to take you through the business and the business performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeff, thanks a lot.  I'm going to start with the summary of the second quarter and on the left side is the summary of continuing operations.  Revenues of 39.1 billion were down 17%.  They were down 12% ex-FX and I know there has been some discussion on our revenue number.  We're not giving guidance on revenue.  We haven't given any and revenues were right in line with our Q2 expectations as we went through the quarter.</p>
          <p>Industrial sales of 26 billion were down 7 and financial services of revenue of 13 billion were down 29.  We earned 2.9 billion of net income in the quarter which was down 47%.  Earnings per share we earned $0.26 and that includes the cost of the preferred dividend, about $75 million.</p>
          <p>As Jeff covered, the total cash flow from operating activities was 7.1 billion, which was a great result for our first half.  For tax rates, the consolidated tax rate for the second quarter was 7%. This rate is down from 2008 due to significantly reduced pre-tax income, and as you know the lower pre-tax income is principally driven by the GECS loss provisions.  For GE the second quarter rate of 26% was flat with last year and for GE Capital because there is a large tax benefit and a pre-tax loss we're dividing a negative by a negative, and we end up with a very high positive rate for the quarter.  There were no significant one-time tax items in the second quarter as we had in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>On the right side are the segment results.  Our infrastructure businesses had 3.6 billion of segment profit and that was flat with last year.  NBC was down 41%.  I'll cover the details of that in a few pages.  GE Capital Finance earned $590 million, including 149 million pre-tax income which was a good result for the quarter, and C&amp;I [Commercial and Industrial] had 111 million of segment profit, also a pretty good result for them.  So I'll cover the businesses over the next several pages.</p>
          <p>And before I get into the specific business results, I wanted to do a summary of the second quarter items that impacted the quarter.</p>
          <p>First we had a transaction gain, a $200 million benefit from a gain in GE Capital.  We acquired a controlling interest in BAC, which is a leading Central American bank where we already owned 49% of that.  That change of control resulted in a fair market value gain that was reported in capital finance.</p>
          <p>Second we continued to fund restructuring projects to lower our future costs.  You know, we're taking out a lot of costs in the company as Jeff showed you on the base cost improvements and we had $0.03 of after tax charges in the quarter.  They were recorded at corporate, and the reductions were aligned by business.  I thought it would be helpful to just give you where the cost out activities were: Tech Infrastructure had 77 million, Capital Finance had 74 million, C&amp;I had 37 million, Energy Infrastructure had 24 million, NBCU had 8 million, and the balance was in corporate.</p>
          <p>And then third we had $400 million of after tax marks and impairments which included several items.  I've listed the biggest items on the right side.  The largest items, negative items, were a $110 million write down of our position in Cosmos Bank in Taiwan.  We had 96 million of commercial real estate equity impairments.  We had an $85 million treasury negative mark as our credit spreads improved in the second quarter.  And we had a $56 million write-down of our after tax remaining stake that NBCU held in ION.  We wrote off the rest of the stake 100% written off now.  And those were partially offset by a positive mark of 139 million on our stake in Genpact.  So we continue restructuring as Jeff showed you.  We're going to continue to do restructuring in the second half and in 2010 and in the quarter the restructuring more than offset the gains that we had which were principally the BAC gain in GE Capital.</p>
          <p>I'll start with a few pages on Capital Finance.  You should be aware that we have a webcast scheduled for Tuesday, July 28th, from 8:30 to 10:30 in the morning and we're going to give you a much more detailed update on GE Capital.  For the quarter, Mike Neal and the team earned 590 million.  That was down 80% from last year, but we think it was a solid quarter given this environment.  Revenues of 12.8 billion were down 29%.</p>
          <p>The revenue decline was driven by lower assets, that's 12 points, so as we shrink GE Capital that has had an impact on the top line.  We de-consolidated Penske, that was about 6 points, and foreign exchange, with the stronger dollar, hurt us about 7 points.</p>
          <p>Assets of 557 billion were down 11%.  Year-over-year, assets are down $71 billion, and they're down 5% ex-foreign exchange.  So if you just look in the second quarter, assets were down $10 billion ex-exchange, so we continue to make progress with collections exceeding originations.</p>
          <p>The business results are in the bottom left, and let me start with consumer.  Consumer you can see had segment profit of 243 million.  That was down 77% from last year.  The decline in earnings was driven by higher credit costs of $660 million, and $200 million of lower tax benefits partially offset by the BAC gain and the Cosmos write-off which I covered on the previous page.  That's a consistent theme.  It will be higher credit costs throughout each of these businesses as we go through the individual segments.</p>
          <p>And in terms of the specific consumer business, I don't have these numbers on the page, but I'll cover three pieces: one, the U.S. consumer, two, U.K. home lending, and then three, our global bank.</p>
          <p>So U.S. consumer had a very strong second quarter.  The U.S. consumer business earned $153 million positive in the quarter.  That was still down 88 million from last year, but and that was driven by higher credit costs of 190 million partially offset by lower operating costs in the business.  But the U.S. consumer losses and impairments are trending below the outlook case that we showed you on the March GE Capital meeting, so a very good performance in U.S. consumer.</p>
          <p>U.K. home lending had a loss of 155 million in the quarter. That's driven by higher credit costs of 293 million.  We increased our reserves as a reflection of the higher delinquencies that I'm going to cover in a few pages, and if you look at the total non-U.S. mortgage losses for us globally, those are trending slightly below the Fed base case, and there have been some recent positive signs in the U.K. housing market lately, but the U.K. book is the one out of the global mortgages that remains under pressure for us.</p>
          <p>Our banks made 251 million in net income in the quarter.  That was down 48% again driven principally by higher credit costs up 190 million, and if you look at the banking businesses, the losses and impairments are trending slightly above the Fed base case that we showed you in March.</p>
          <p>Moving to commercial real estate, you can see the business had a loss of 237 million in the quarter, down from almost 500 million of earnings last year.  The decline is driven by 275 million of higher credit costs and impairments, and $380 million of lower gains.  We did sell some properties in the second quarter. For the quarter we sold 49 properties for 245 million with a small gain, $23 million.  We also increased our reserves by 175 million in real estate.  That's a reflection of the higher delinquencies and non-earnings we're seeing and for real estate our credit costs and impairments if you compare to the outlined cases that we did in March, they're running below the Fed base case.  But we're still very cautious obviously about the real estate outlook.</p>
          <p>For commercial lending and leasing [CLL], the business earned 233 million in the quarter that was down 74%.  Again the earnings decline was driven by higher credit costs of about $300 million and then lower core earnings as assets are down about 14%.  In terms of the loss outlook for CLL, it's trending to just slightly above the Fed base case.</p>
          <p>For the verticals, you can see GECAS [GE Commercial Aviation Services] had another solid quarter.  Earnings of 286 million were up 3%.  We ended the quarter with only two aircraft on the ground, and Energy Financial Services earnings of 65 million were down 60% driven by $100 million of lower gains in the quarter.  So the portfolio quality is good there with flat non-earnings.</p>
          <p>And if you look overall, the summary for the overall losses and impairments for GE Capital through the first half, we're running just slightly below the Fed base case that we outlined in March, and we're also running ahead of our overall cost out projections.  For the year, we expect cost savings to be more than $3 billion that we said we would have in the first quarter, so the team is doing a really good job of controlling their costs.</p>
          <p>And next I'm going to turn it over to Brackett Denniston, our Senior Vice President and General Counsel, to talk about financial services regulatory reform.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Keith, good morning.  As many of you know, the Treasury issued a White Paper about a month ago which outlines a sweeping proposal for financial services reform.  It's probably the most sweeping proposal in U.S. financial services history.</p>
          <p>Its main features as many of you know are it designates the Federal Reserve board as a systemic regulator including of what the paper calls Tier 1 financial companies.  And it will be advised in that capacity by a council of regulators, the bank regulators, the securities regulators, and others.  It includes consolidation of the banking regulators, the Office of Thrift Supervision and Comptroller of the Currency, but not consolidation of the other agencies like the SEC and CFTC [Commodities Futures Trading Commission].  And in connection with the consolidation of banking regulators, it calls for the conversion of thrifts and ILCs [Industrial Loan Companies] to national banks regulated by that national bank supervisor.</p>
          <p>It has market reform over things like securitization and credit default swaps.  It includes resolution authority over big financial institutions, a bankruptcy-like process run by the FDIC.  And it has very broad consumer reform regulation proposed in it, including a consumer financial products commission.</p>
          <p>Now, one of the dozens of proposals in the white paper is one that would require separating existing financial from non-financial companies, whether they be Tier 1 financial companies however that ends up being fleshed out, ILCs or thrifts.  And there's a five-year transition period.</p>
          <p>Now, we're quite clearly opposed, as we've said publicly, to this proposal.  These structures were certainly not a cause of the crisis.  And the proposal would also unnecessarily affect important sources of lending at a time when the country needs lending.  And in the past, these existing structures have been traditionally handled by grandfathering them.</p>
          <p>We've talked to a number of people in Congress, and we've heard considerable skepticism about many of the features of the white paper, but particularly on this aspect of the white paper.  And we have also heard considerable support for the idea of not breaking up the existing structures for grandfathering.</p>
          <p>Now, the proposal is of course just the beginning.  And what will emerge from Congress will be quite different from what is proposed, as is often the case.  Congress will take over now and it will be a long and complex process, probably lasting into 2010.</p>
          <p>At the same time, I'd make two quick additional points.  First, we're supportive of systemic regulation, and more regulation is certainly something we've prepared for.  Second, nothing in the proposal changes our moving forward with a smaller more focused GE Capital.  So as I said, the proposal is still early stages, and we're advocating very intensively for our point of view.</p>
          <p>I'm now going to turn it back over to Keith.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Brackett.  I'm going to cover a few more pages about GE Capital volume and asset quality and reserve levels and then wrap it up and go into the industrial businesses.  The first page is about how important GE Capital is as a source of liquidity for U.S. businesses and consumers.  If you look at the first half of 2009, we have done $69 billion of volume, and these have been at attractive returns for us.  The financings are critical to our customers as we continue to support them through the downturn.  And more importantly, if you look all the way back since January of 2008, we have extended 155 billion of new financings to our commercial customers and 127 billion of credit to over 50 million consumers.</p>
          <p>Importantly we're not just supporting existing customers but new customers as well.  In first half of this year, we added 16,000 new commercial customers, and now support 23,000 new small businesses through our retail program.  So we have broad reach.  We provide a lot of funding to a lot of capital that funds a lot of mid-market and small and medium-sized business in this country.</p>
          <p>And lastly, we have maintained our leading position in larger key markets where we have deep domains supporting -- we're supporting virtually every U.S. airline and we have been maintaining our leadership position in debtor in possession bankruptcy financing, healthcare financing, and energy infrastructure financing.  So still a lot of lending activity going on, and providing a lot of capital to the markets, especially in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Next is an update on our delinquencies and non-earnings.  On the left side is the commercial equipment finance data.  You can see the 30-plus day delinquencies for equipment are down 6 basis points in Q2 versus Q1. This is a positive signal obviously for the commercial book.  That was driven by a decline in delinquencies in the Americas where 30-plus went from 2.81% to 2.45%.  So we're very interested in watching this trend and seeing how this develops as we go through the year.  That was partially offset by we had some increased delinquencies in our Asia and European equipment books.</p>
          <p>We continue to see pressure on non-earnings.  They're up 18 basis points versus the first quarter, but again the pace of that growth has also leveled off a bit, and it's driven by senior secured loans where we're well collateralized.</p>
          <p>In terms of real estate which is not in the delinquency and non-earner for the equipment bar up above, the line-up above, delinquencies increased up to 4% on the real estate book and non-earnings are up to 2.9%.  You can see we continue to see pressure in the commercial real estate book, and then finally for the verticals, the delinquency and non-earnings were basically stable with Q1 which continues to perform very well.</p>
          <p>On the right side is the consumer data, and this is really developing into the two different categories by type of exposure.  We broke out mortgage, global mortgage, and non-mortgage, because the loss dynamics are so different.  You can see the improvements in the non-mortgage delinquency as the delinquency went from 6.02 in the first quarter down to 5.73 in the second quarter.  And that's really driven by North America.</p>
          <p>The North American delinquencies are down 14 basis points to 6.96%.  We're seeing better entry rates into delinquency.  It's the lowest we have seen.  We're seeing improved late stage collection effectiveness.  The non-earnings balance was flat to the prior quarter, and the reason the rate is up a little bit is because the balance is down.  So as a percent, it's a little higher, but we are getting the benefit of all the underwriting actions that we took last year as well as some seasonality benefits.</p>
          <p>And then the second category here that you look at are the mortgage -- the global mortgage assets.  We continue to see growth in 30-plus delinquencies and non-earnings.  The U.K. mortgage book drives most of the changes, and I'm going to cover our reserves versus non-earnings in a minute.</p>
          <p>So overall in a pretty tough environment, we are seeing some leveling off in both the equipment and the U.S. consumer delinquencies.  And we're going to be monitoring those trends through the third quarter to see if we can really see that they're really solid trends here as we go forward.  But some positive spots in the book.</p>
          <p>Next is an update on reserve coverage.  We had a very good quarter for reserve strengthening.  Our provision for losses was $2.8 billion in the quarter.  And while write-offs were up $300 million to 1.9 billion, we still added $900 million to our loss reserve.  So a 50% increase in provisions versus the write-offs.  We increased our reserves in both the commercial and the consumer book.</p>
          <p>Reserves increased by $500 million in the commercial book, increasing our coverage rate to 1.13%.  We increased our CLL reserves by $350 million and we increased our real estate reserves by $175 million quarter 2 versus quarter 1.</p>
          <p>If you look at the consumer, we increased reserves by $400 million.  And you can see the consumer coverage rate increased for both the U.S. retail and the non-U.S. mortgage.  So overall coverage with $6.6 billion of allowance is up 22 basis points versus the first quarter up 74 basis points versus year ago, and we're well on track to get to the 2% plus coverage by year-end.</p>
          <p>Next is an update on how we think about the non-earning assets and our reserve coverage.  These are basically the same charts that Jeff Bornstein covered during the March 19th meeting.  I showed you these charts for Q1 and now we've updated them for the numbers through Q2.  So the left side is commercial.  Non-earnings ended the quarter at 6.4 billion.  It's up 1.9 billion from Q1.  It represents 2.9% of our financing receivables, and the bar shows the benefit of being a senior secured lender.</p>
          <p>We expect 1.9 billion of the non- earnings to have 100% recovery.  We have another 1.2 billion in some type of workout where we expect full recovery.  We'll have a renegotiation, some changes to the documents and terms.  And then we have another 1.9 billion where we're protected by the collateral value.  So a significant amount of work our risk teams are working on to make sure they work through this loan book.  At the end of the day that leaves you with what we think of as 1.4 billion of estimated loss exposure today, and you can see we have 173% coverage against that with our reserves.</p>
          <p>On the right side are the consumer non-earnings of 6.6 billion.  They were up 1.1 billion over Q1 and represent about 4.7% of the financing receivables.  The consumer dynamics as I said are very different between the mortgage and the non-mortgage asset so the green bar represents our non-mortgage non-earnings.  Principally the U.S. retail business the credit card business and retail sales finance. We have $1.7 billion of non-earnings in that book, and we have 3.3 billion of reserves against it, 189% coverage.</p>
          <p>And then the remainder of the non-earnings are the global mortgage book, we expect 1.5 billion of that to cure.  With our underwriting positions, we expect to recover 2.9 billion of exposure based on our loan to value position.  You remember we underwrite these at about 70 to 75% loan to value.  Today they're at about 85% loan to value as house prices have declined globally and that gives us a lot of recovery value.  And we have some mortgage insurance that we expect to recover on leaving us with an expected, estimated loss today of about $500 million and 173% coverage about that.  So we believe we're appropriately reserved for our non-earning loss exposure, and again we'll cover more of this in detail on the 28th meeting.</p>
          <p>So let me wrap up GE Capital with a recap of where we stand through the first half.  You know, this framework is the stress case outline that we gave you in the March 19th meeting, and we have given you an update now on each of our major businesses, where they stand relative to the stress case.  Some are higher or lower than the Fed base case in terms of where we're going on credit costs, but overall we're trending to slightly below the estimated Fed base case for 2009 on losses and impairments.</p>
          <p>And more importantly, we have completed a number significant actions that we said we were going to do.  We're dealing with a tough loss environment, and we strengthened our reserves while we have remained profitable.  We have injected capital and strengthened our capital ratios.  We have dramatically improved our liquidity profile with commercial paper down and cash balances up.  We have completed our 2009 long-term funding.  We have already pre-funded over 30% of our 2010 needs and as Jeff said, our plan is to complete the 2010 funding before year-end.  In 2009 we have issued $9 billion of non-guaranteed debt.  That's more than any other issuer and we're shrinking our balance sheet while we're still providing a lot of credit to consumers and businesses, and finally we've been transparent.  And we're going to cover more detail about GE Capital at the next update on the 28th and continue that trend.</p>
          <p>So next let me turn to the industrial businesses.  I'll start with NBC.  Jeff [Jeff Gaspin] and the team continue to operate in a very challenging environment.  For the quarter, revenues of 3.6 billion were down 8%, and segment profit of 539 million was down 41%.  I think the first thing to point out is the overall performance is not as negative as it looks.</p>
          <p>I've tried to highlight that with the numbers on the right side.  200 million of the decline year-over-year was driven by two items.  First there was no repeat of the gain that we had last year from the sale of Sundance.  That was about a 113 million benefit in '08, and second we wrote off the balance of our investment in ION, which I said was about 95 million this year.  Adjusting for those two items, NBC was down about 24% in the quarter.</p>
          <p>So if you look at operations as we go around the four different numbers on the page here, cable continues to deliver strong results.  Revenue of 1.2 billion was up 3%, and op profit of 595 million was up 7%.  USA remains No. 1 for the 12th consecutive quarter.  Oxygen had a good quarter; Bravo had a good quarter, and the cable news channels had a very good quarter.  MSNBC beat CNN in Prime ages 25 to 54 and total viewers for the full quarter. It's the first time ever, and their op profit was up 8%.  And CNBC remains the clear leader in business news and profit was up 7%.</p>
          <p>Broadcast had a tougher quarter.  Revenues of 1.4 billion were down 9%.  Op profit was down about $100 million and that was driven by lower revenues on House versus last year and higher investments that we have made in new programming, plus the local media continues to be down year-over-year.  We're very pleased with the transitions with Jimmy Fallon and Conan.  They have been better and very successful.  The new development that we have done for the fall shows have received very positive feedback from advertisers, and the upfront is very slow.  I think everybody knows that.  Basically we're planning on retaining more inventory as we go into the 2010 season.</p>
          <p>Film did have a tough quarter.  Revenues of 950 million were flat and op profit was down about 80 million.  The main impact here was driven by fewer significant film releases to DVD year-over-year versus second quarter last year and then our second quarter movie performance was less than we expected.  So that was down.</p>
          <p>Parks actually had a good quarter.  Parks were up 13% in op profit.  They had good cost controls and they had some timing benefit from spring break going into the second quarter versus first quarter last year.</p>
          <p>Digital is a very good story.  It continues to grow.  Hulu was the number 2 video site behind YouTube, and we're thrilled to have Disney have joined Hulu as a media partner.  And finally, as I mentioned, we took the final write down on Ion, which really impacted us.</p>
          <p>So if you go back to what we said in Q1, we showed the operational view of NBC was expected to be down about 15 to 25% for the year, and in the second half, we expect to have favorable comparisons from not having the Olympics costs in the third quarter plus other cost reduction activities that the teams are taking on to provide more offset to the advertising market and some of the pressure from film.</p>
          <p>Next is Tech Infrastructure.  John Rice and the team delivered revenues of 10.6 billion, down 11%.  Segment profit of 1.8 billion was also down 11%.  You can see the key businesses on the bottom left and I'll start with some details on aviation.</p>
          <p>2Q orders were 4.2 billion for aviation, down 23%.  The biggest drop is in major equipment obviously with orders of 1.7 down 44%.  We had $1 billion of commercial engine orders, and $700 million of military orders.  The good news here is we still have a tremendous backlog.  The major equipment backlog ended the quarter at 21.3 billion up 5% versus last year and only down 1% from the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Service orders were up 5% in total.  Commercial spares of 20.4 million a day were up 10% and we had very strong contractual service sales from both Southwest and U.S. Airways, partially offset by some lower overhauls on CF6 cargo engines.  None of the $3 billion engine or $5 billion service wins that were announced at the Paris air show have flown into orders yet, as Jeff mentioned.</p>
          <p>For the quarter revenue was down 6%.  We shipped 472 commercial engines which was down 19% and that was partially offset by 239 military engines which were up 49%.  Service revenue overall was down 1% reflecting the impact of higher contractual services mostly offsetting the lower freight overhauls, and op profit was up 1% with 1.4 points of margin growth in the business driven by services up 13%.</p>
          <p>We also had 79 million last year of revenue share benefits that didn't repeat, and without that the op profit for the entire segment would have been up 11%.</p>
          <p>For Healthcare, reported orders of 4 billion were down 11% down 7% organically.  They were impacted by the stronger dollar.  Equipment orders were down 15% with 5 points of decline from the stronger dollar as well.  The U.S. orders were down 13%, and the non-U.S. orders were down 7% on an FX adjusted basis.  And the pressure was pretty much across most of the major product lines: CT, MR, X-ray, clinical, and MDX all down double digits.  We did see better orders performance from life sciences, up 4%.  FX adjusted surgery had a very strong quarter, up 37%.  And service orders were up 2% on an FX adjusted basis.  China was up 11%, India was up 19%, so we see some strength around the globe.  But overall revenue for the business in total was down 9%.  Equipment was down 15% in line with orders and services were down 6%.  That would have been flat on an organic basis.</p>
          <p>Op profit of 590 million was down 21%. We really were hit by the lower volume.  We had some negative price, about 1% in the quarter, and negative productivity, and services op profit was up 2% in the quarter in that number.  It's just a tough healthcare environment the team is dealing with obviously.</p>
          <p>If you look at Transportation, second quarter orders of 600 million were down 50%.  The equipment orders are just going to remain challenging as the North American railroads have significant overcapacity, as Jeff mentioned, and service orders are also affected by that.  They're down 38% driven by both tough comparisons from some good parts orders last year as well as the idle locomotives.  Revenues down 11, driven by lower locomotive deliveries.  We had 119 this year in the quarter versus 165 last year, and services revenues were down 6%.  So the team did a good job managing all that.  The op profit was down only 2% as we improve margin rate by 2 points, offsetting the lower volume with favorable price, more deflation, and good productivity.</p>
          <p>So the entire Tech Infrastructure segment is executing a pretty strong cost out, doing a lot of restructuring in a tough operating environment, and even with that tough environment, the service op profit for the overall business was up 7% showing the strength of the services model here.</p>
          <p>Next is Energy.  John Krenicki and the Energy Infrastructure team had another very strong quarter.  Revenues of 9.6 billion were down 1%.  That's up 4% if you adjust for the impact of the FX in the quarter.  And segment profit, good leverage, 1.8 billion, up 13%.  If you look at Energy, the orders of 6.5 billion were down a third versus last year but basically flat with the first quarter.</p>
          <p>We had 1.2 billion of thermal orders.  They were down 60%.  We received orders for 26 gas turbines versus 58 last year in the second quarter and that included 10 units for Iraq which totaled about 400 million.  We still have 30 more units to book as orders for the Iraq order.  The thermal backlog is 7.1 billion.  That's down 10% from the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Wind orders of 500 million were down 60% as well as customers are basically looking for the finalization on the stimulus terms and conditions which happened last week.  I think that's going to be a positive as we go forward with a lot of wind commitments out there that need to be finalized.  The wind backlog of 4.2 billion is still strong.</p>
          <p>Aero orders of 262 million were down 69%, and again tough comparisons last year, but definitely slower.  And service orders were up 12% driven by Energy Services up 8 and Wind, Aero, and Nuclear in total up 21%.  For the quarter, revenue at Energy was down 1%, up 2% when you adjust for FX.  Equipment was up 5 and services were down 6.  We shipped 42 gas turbines versus 44 last year, but pricing was up 8% and we shipped 680 wind units versus 672 last year with pricing up 6%.</p>
          <p>Service revenues as I said were down 6, two things here.  It's driven by tough comparisons in the power adjacencies business.  That was up 23% last year, and it was down this year, and water services were down 18%.  If you look at the core energy contract service business, that performed very well with revenues up 11%.  Op profit was up 15%, and that was driven by strong pricing as I mentioned and good productivity, and we had 2.8 points of margin rate growth in the Energy business.</p>
          <p>Oil and Gas had another solid quarter.  Orders of 1.9 billion were down 10% but it's flat when you adjust for foreign exchange.  We had 390 million of orders for natural gas compression equipment.  That's up 4 times over second quarter last year and we're seeing a lot more activity in the natural gas area, and that partially offset by the lower orders that we're going to see in pipeline and refinery markets.  Equipment backlog ended the quarter at 6.5 billion.  That's up 170 million versus the first quarter so still growing the backlog in oil and gas.  And service orders were down 6% FX adjusted driven by tougher comparisons from last year in both parts and upgrades.</p>
          <p>For the quarter, the revenue was up 3.  That was strong volume growth in the petro chemical and refinery equipment segments and service revenues were down 6 but up 5% if you look at the FX flat year-over-year, op profit up 11, great volume and great productivity, partially offset by the negative foreign exchange impacting the business.  So overall, another great quarter from the energy infrastructure team, and if you look, this is another good service story.  Service revenues were down a little bit in the quarter and op profit was up 3%, so the service story really plays out in both the Tech Infrastructure and the Energy Infrastructure segments.</p>
          <p>Let me turn it back to Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, Keith, thanks.  Just want to wrap up with two charts.  One just kind of recaptures the company total year framework.  You know, when I look at Energy Infrastructure, Technology Infrastructure, and NBCU and kind of take a look at the second half and all the market dynamics we see, we see these as, you know, earnings being about flat for the total year of 2009.  I think last December we gave a range of 0 to 5.  The markets are tougher, but I think the teams are executing very well in this environment, and so we see about flat earnings year-over-year.</p>
          <p>In Capital Finance, you know, profitable in 1Q and 2Q.  Keith kind of outlined where we stand versus the various credit cost cases and we have got, I'd say, building confidence around Capital Finance, and from a corporate standpoint, C&amp;I is actually performing better than we thought and seeing pretty good momentum into the second half.  So we'll continue to do restructuring within the context of the framework, but the team is really executing pretty well in this environment.</p>
          <p>And then looking forward, you know, I think we see kind of more of the same.  I think we see lower equipment sales, but very solid service positions with very high margins.  Continue to execute on cost out and increasing margins, and we think we'll see more benefit from the global stimulus as we look at the second half of the year.  We will continue to be in a tough credit loss environment, but we'll have a profitable GE Capital and the funding is solid and originations are strong.  C&amp;I is better, and more restructuring.  So I think the combination of services, productivity, margins, strengthening GE Capital, this I think is a good context for GE as we look at the second half of the year and into 2010.</p>
          <p>And then just to wrap up, we continue to build a strong company for the future.  I think if you look at what we have done in the last three months, we have significantly strengthened GE Capital.  Liquidity is in great shape.  Funding is in great shape.  We have strengthened the capital ratios.  We have increased reserves.  We're generating profitable business.  We're able to play offense, and we are really committed to GE Capital.  All the things Brackett said, you know, we are strongly committed to our point of view and to a smaller but still strong GE Capital business.</p>
          <p>We're running GE with intensity both on a productivity and cash basis.  I think the cash story is very strong, and the margins are still, at 16.4%, very high.  Investing and technology and services, we've got a service backlog of 122 billion.  We have launched new products like batteries, our technology budget is up, we're winning globally when you look at China, India, and the Middle East, and we're well positioned in some of the big themes that I think will mean that we're working on the right things vis-&#xE0;-vis stimulus.  So I think the company is stronger and we're well positioned for this challenging environment.</p>
          <p>So Trevor, let me turn it back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks, Jeff.  Noelia, let's open it up to questions now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from the line of Terry Darling with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Terry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Terry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeff, you had mentioned 2010 equipment revenues may be down 10 to 15%, if I've got that correct.  And I'm wondering if you might make a comment on how you would feel about the flow-through on that, as well as any thoughts on the services side of the business at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Terry, it's still early days to think about '10, but again we make as we said on the page, 75% of the earnings plus, and that's of all industrial earnings, come from services.  So when I look at services, we see backlog building, we see good customer usage rates.  Things like low natural gas prices mean people that are working their gas turbines harder.  Good productivity and things like that.</p>
          <p>And then I think when you look at the equipment side, combination of restructuring, relatively low margins on the original equipment sales, very aggressive restructuring that we're doing, plus good margin momentum, we think it's a good one, two punch.  Good service growth, good service revenue and good productivity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sounds like on the services side, 2010, there is nothing that you see that would be obvious at this point to drive that business from the profit perspective when you layer in the restructuring efforts you have to drive that down dramatically, just based on what you see right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Terry, we're kind of out of the guidance business, and I'm thinking about 2010, but I sit here and say we have got $122 billion of backlog.  We've got really young, we've got the most energy efficient fleet in aircraft engines and gas turbines.  We're as well positioned as you can be in the type of environment that we see today, really, I mean with great visibility.  And the service margins were up 3 points in the second quarter.  So we're seeing the productivity fall through, we're seeing the restructuring fall through, and the assets we have are being worked pretty hard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Just try to squeak a quick one in.  On second half tax rate, industrial, Keith, can you help with that, that 26% rate, where we ought to be thinking?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, if you look at the way the accounting rules work on tax, we're supposed to be booking to what we estimate as our total year rate to be.  So if you look at a 26% for the half, that's a pretty good estimate of what we think we'll have for the year for the industrial rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you called that 29% last quarter.  Is that just mix geographically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have some lower pre-tax earnings, so that does in some way affect the rate.  We're getting a little less benefit from some of our global funding structures because of interest rates and FX.  But last quarter we had a little bit of a higher rate in the industrial as you remember because the percent of GE Capital was so low in the first quarter, so that raised it versus what we thought the annual estimate was going to be.  At the half that's a better estimate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Scott Davis with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When you have an order book that softens like this, what impact do you start to see on price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you look right now, we have got a really strong story in the order book in the backlog on pricing.  If you look in the quarter, Energy business had 5% price up, Oil and Gas had 1% price up, Engines was up 3.  Healthcare was down 1 consistent with where they have been, actually lower than what they have been in the last few years.  And overall for the company, we had 1.9% price up.  So you're seeing a very strong backlog that we're working off of.</p>
          <p>In terms of orders as we go forward, for Energy in the quarter, they were up 2.9%, Oil and Gas was down about 1%, Engines was up 10%, and Healthcare had pressure about 1 to 2%.</p>
          <p>So I don't see anything abnormal yet.  I think you have got to worry about supply and demand dynamics as you go forward, but right now we have got a very healthy backlog and we're protecting that.  And the orders in the quarter were pretty good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Good.  I'll ask kind of a similar question for GE Capital.  You talked about higher credit costs, but obviously your book, I think about a third of your book reprices every year.  What is the typical lag, I guess, between kind of your credit costs going up and your pricing to follow and strengthen to match that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, our pricing right now is already up.  I mean, if you look, everything we did in the quarter, you're getting 2.5 to 3 return on investment sort of margins on the volume that we did.  We did about in total $35 billion of on-book volume in the second quarter at about a 3 ROI.  The one-third of the book turning used to be at higher volumes than we're doing.  I think you're probably going to deal with a little bit longer timeframe before you get the book to turn based on the fact that the volumes are down about 40% year-over-year, Scott, so.  But the margins that we're getting today with the estimates of both our funding costs and our credit costs are extremely strong, and that's because the cost of capital is going up for everybody, and people need capital, and we're providing it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Scott.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Nigel Coe with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Nigel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You covered a lot of ground in the slides.  One thing you didn't mention was CIT.  So obvious question, are you seeing any early impacts from the dislocation at CIT?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a little early to have any real impact on that, Nigel.  We'll have to wait and see.  We don't compete directly with them in a lot of places, and then there are some opportunity areas where we do have overlap.  And we'll have to wait and see how that plays out.  I think it's a little premature to have any type of impact off of whatever they ultimately find as their resolution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Secondly on within GE Capital, you made a positive pre-tax income at GECC, Capital Finance, a pre-tax loss at GECS, the gap between the two was a little bit wider than expected.  Was there anything to think about in terms of why there is a gap between Capital Finance pre-tax and GECC?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the biggest thing on the corporate costs including Treasury, those were at a pretty normal run rate for the quarter.  We did have some of the costs, as I showed you, on the impairments were in the Treasury line in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Finally, I guess interest expense within GE Capital is a big drop Q-on-Q, I think running around 4.5 million dollars.  Is this the low point for interest expense, or do you think it could actually go a little bit lower from here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, repeat that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The interest expense within GE Capital has seen a big drop Q-on-Q.  I think it went from 5.1 to 4.5.  Is that, do you think this is as low as it goes within GE Capital, or do you think the scope is to go even lower?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have to see what happens with the global benchmark rates, obviously.  We have had a decline, obviously, in all the short-term benchmark rates, and that's been a driver for a benefit as well as the lower debt balances that we have.  So you tell me what the benchmark rates are going to be.  But so far we have had a very good experience here in terms of funding and interest costs have been favorable, as you said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The other thing I would say in the Cap Corp. is there is that 77 million I mentioned of restructuring, that's in the Cap Corp. line as well.  That may help you, Nigel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's after tax.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Steve Tusa with J.P.Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just getting into the zero &#x2013; flattish growth for the year now instead of 0 to 5 in the framework, I think if I'm adding the segments up right, you were down about 5% in the first half, so can you just talk about the dynamics of without giving specific guidance maybe what gets better in the back half of the year for these various segments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't I start, Steve, ask then, Keith, you kick in.  I I'd say Energy Infrastructure both from a backlog and services standpoint continues to be very strong.  Technology Infrastructure is &#x2013; again has good productivity and sustained service growth in the second half.  NBC Universal has easier comparisons and really we think the second half of NBC Universal is going to be significantly better than the first half from a run rate.  I think Keith went through some of the impairments.  So I think you're going to improve at NBC, Energy if anything gets better during the year and Technology is kind of more or less around the zero mark to in that range.  So Keith, would you...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would agree.  NBC is a big number, right?  We had over $200 million of impairments in the first half.  We have got the $150 million loss on the Olympics last year in the third quarter that we don't compare to.  I think if you look at those dynamics that's a big factor.  I think services is the other factor, Jeff.  If you look first half to second half, we do continue to see positive outlook for services as we get into the balance of the year.</p>
          <p>And I think the other thing I'd mention here, Steve, is we have also included in that zero, we have included a relook at the equipment levels that we're going to have.  And that's factored in here.  You know, in January I kind of gave an outlook for gas turbines, wind turbines, commercial engines, military engines, and locomotives, and we have included in this update that Jeff covered a view on those five categories and I think it may be helpful to put those out there.</p>
          <p>Gas turbines in January we said we'd have about 185 for the year, and right now the July estimate has 150 to 160 for the year.  Some of that is Iraq has pushed into 2010.  Wind turbines we said we'd have about 2800 units for the year.  We're around 2,700 &#x2013; 2,800 units, so pretty consistent there.  Commercial engines we had originally 2200 engines in the year, now we're down to 1930 as the airframers have reduced their production schedules even below what we had at the plan.  Military engines are on track 925 to 925, and locomotives went from about 600 down to about 500.</p>
          <p>So I think included in that zero we're factoring in the fact that we think the equipment is going to be a little less than what we had as the original estimate for the year, and that's because of the strength of services as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  That's a very helpful detail.  And just lastly on Energy and the price cost gap, do you expect that it was &#x2013; and again, a nice number this quarter.  Do you expect that 450 to get bigger over the next couple quarters, or have we kind of peaked on that?  How long, I guess going back to Scott's question, how long can you hold on to that price cost gap?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Steve, you know, look, our expectation is that as time goes on, there's going to be pricing pressure.  You know, it's hard to predict right now.  I think we're protected by a great backlog.  But when we look at the raw material productivity that we're getting and the cost out that our sourcing people are getting, it's going to be substantially better in 2010 than it is in 2009.  We have got &#x2013; we have got tremendous &#x2013; and we are able to kind of see that, so we have got really great cost down programs going.</p>
          <p>The other thing I would say, Steve, in addition to what Keith provided, I think only having &#x2013; in this environment, only having $100 million of cancellations in a quarter is pretty good.  And so I think that's a real plus for investors as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes in the line of Robert Cornell with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Pretty clean quarter for you guys.  I'm always impressed at the fire hose of information.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the commercial delinquencies going down was a surprise, maybe you could go back.  I know you discussed it being Americas driven, but it's sort of counterintuitive given the trouble that CIT is in that your delinquencies are actually going down.  Maybe you can give us some more visibility into why that is the case?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we have seen quite a bit of activity in that portfolio from customers delaying payments already for the last nine to 12 months.  I mean, I think if you're going to have an indication of how the commercial book is performing on the mid market business in the Americas, that's already been impacted by the economic outlook that we have had, and we're seeing those accounts basically already go through the first wave of what we would expect to see in terms of credit indicators, 30-day delinquency, 90-day delinquency, and then non-earning.</p>
          <p>So our credit guys are cautious about it, Bob, but I think it's a good sign that we have kind of leveled off here in the quarter.  And now we've got to see whether that trend continues as we go forward, but we have real terms and conditions and rights.  We don't have covenant light loans, we don't have no covenant, no doc loans; and as a result, people have to pay us, and we're experiencing the delinquency in line with the economic environment our customers are feeling.</p>
          <p>I don't know how it compares to CIT, but for us I think this is a good sign on the book, and we're going to have to see how it affects us going into the second half.  We have shifted so much of our front end activity into managing accounts, Bob, managing and making sure that we get our senior secured credit positions back, and I think that helps us to manage the delinquency once we get in here, and I think it's a positive sign and we'll have to see how it comes out in the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you certainly hear a lot of anecdotes about GE out there hitting hard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're a senior secured lender, and that's how we run the business...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, Bob, we have also originated a lot of &#x2013; we're originating a lot of business out there right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I heard that comment.  I'll expect we'll get into it more on the 28th call.  You know, another point is you talked about funding outside FDIC.  I mean, what are some of the indications of funding costs on that non-FDIC funding that you're looking at?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you can see our cash bond spreads every day.  You know, they've come down since the first quarter clearly.  And we think they're at levels that we can &#x2013; if you just do our cash bond spreads at five years, you know, little over 5%. We can borrow at that rate for five years and we can lend it to customers who need capital at an attractive rate.  We're trying to balance how much additional non-guaranteed debt do you do, how quickly do you do it when you already have $50 billion of cash.  You know, we have got the cash there for the insurance, so we don't need to do any, but we're committed to pre-funding 2010 before we get out of 2009, and we're going to do it pieces at a time and in markets where there is acceptable demand, and we're not going to be disruptive in the credit markets as we go forward and do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One final question for me.  I mean, there were commentators on CNBC this morning noting the evolution of the commercial real estate book, both equity and the loan book.  I mean, I'm sure you'll touch on that in some detail on the 28th, but how do you guys see those positions evolving and what level of impairments and credit losses are we likely to see, just looking out over the next, you know, three years or so, how is that going to evolve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, we're going to grind our way through it.  We're going to show you &#x2013; we showed you in March how we feel about our loan book underwritten at conservative loan to values.  Making sure that we understand the supply and demand dynamics for every market we're in.  We have been very careful and diversified on our equity book, but obviously that is under pressure based on just how the market is performing and what people have as opportunities to put new money to work at.  But again not a big supply and demand overhang, and we're going to grind our way through the real estate book.</p>
          <p>I'll tell you, we've got Ron [Ronald Pressman] and his team working on making sure every property that comes up for lease gets released.  Every negotiation point on a refinancing gets negotiated hard.  And everything that we can to help them from a GE perspective, we're doing, and I think the team has done a very good job of working through that.  It's a tough market.  We're going to have an overhang from the equity book and things we have bought in 2007, clearly.  And we're going to work our way through it over time.  I think you're going to -- you're going to have to basically -- we've said we've got a 4 to $5 billion embedded loss in that book, and we're going to grind our way through that over the next couple years.</p>
          <p>Now, you get a little over a billion dollars of that every year through depreciation.  Our net operating income is pretty good at about $1.6 billion on that equity book.  Our occupancy is good.  And the team is doing a good job of re-leasing everything that comes open.  So I think it's a grind it out.  We've got a lot of good people working on it, and I think the team is doing a pretty good job in a tough environment, and we're going &#x2013; we'll show you a lot more details on the 28th.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What's the schedule from refis in that book in the balance of the year?  You had 5.4 billion for the whole year.  Have you been through half of it or is most of it second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't remember the exact number.  Bob, we'll definitely cover that on the 28th.  We gave you an update on that in the first quarter.  I don't have it with me right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  That's all for me, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, Bob.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jason Feldman with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I know you have talked for a while now about shrinking the Capital Finance portfolio, but at least sequentially assets were up somewhat.  Was that currency or more aggressive origination, opportunistically or is there something else going on there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's all currency.  On a reported basis, as you said, the assets were up 13. 25 billion of that quarter-over-quarter was driven by the dollar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The FX translation, so we're down 12 or 13 in the quarter on an originations less than collections basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it.  And there's a lot of data all at once, but if my math is right, reserves as a percentage of non-earnings declined modestly despite the reserve build.  Reserves as a percentage, non-earnings are about 50% down from 57% last quarter.  How should I think about that?  Is it a change in the mix of kind where the non-earnings are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  It's really &#x2013; you've got to separate out the global mortgage book.  The global mortgage book has a lower percent of reserves based on the fact that we're senior secured position in the properties, and so as those go to non-earnings, they get big numbers in non-earning but really the loss percents are much lower than what we have across the rest of the consumer book for sure and then probably comparable to the rest of the commercial book.  So that is a mix effect, and we'll show you some more of that on the 28th as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  I'm sorry, just to make sure that I get this.  What you're basically saying is when the non-earnings growth comes from the mortgage side because the actual expected losses on those non-earnings are lower you don't need the same comparable reserve builds?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sorry, just wanted to clarify...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because remember, we underwrite the properties at about 70% loan to value.  When it goes non-earning the full value of the property goes in even though you have got all that asset behind your loan position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood.  Last quick thing, commercial lending and leasing, I'm kind of trying to reconcile non-earnings which were up substantially this quarter while the equipment financing delinquencies actually were down, and I know not all of CLL was equipment financing but can you explain the dynamics there of why we're seeing continued growth in the non-earnings with delinquencies that seem to be stabilizing, how should we think of about that, probably not just there but elsewhere as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Some of that actually is connected.  As something goes out of financing receivables into non-earning or goes into the non-earning category, it's not in the delinquency category.  So some of that is the book is already basically starting to season.  You're dealing with a non-earning asset and you've got to work your way through that in terms of getting your senior secured position recovered, and it comes out of the 30-day delinquency measurement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you view that actually as a sign of stabilization?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I view it as a sign of maturation of the commercial book here in the U.S. I don't know if it's stable yet.  I'd like to see the third quarter.  But I can tell you that it's nice to have it at least flatten in the second quarter, and I hope it is a sign of stabilization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A seasoning sign was the word I was looking for, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jeff Sprague with Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Good morning everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a few things.  Just on credit costs for the year, Keith, should we kind of expect we'll be in the 10 billion, 10.5 billion dollar range based on kind of the run rate and what you said a little bit below the Fed base case?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, we are just taking where we are at the half, and if you look at where we are at the half and you double it for the year, you end up in those numbers.  You know, again, in all our indicators with all the ups and downs of some above the Fed base case, some below, and especially the retail business, even below our op plan, you know, you get somewhere below the Fed base case if things continue as they are through the second half, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was just wondering, disc ops [discontinued operations], did something else move into disc ops in GE Capital in the second quarter?  The number was quite small in Q1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, nothing else moved in there.  There was a true-up on the Lake disposition with Shinsei in the quarter of right around a hundred million dollars related to the exit of our consumer business in Japan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I wonder if I might just actually ask Brackett a question since we have him on the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's why we brought him.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I would certainly agree with the notion that perhaps companies like GE had nothing to do with the core of the problem that happened, which actually then makes the language of this thing actually quite, you know, interesting.  I mean a lot of people have surmised that it actually seems to directly target GE based on your size, and other sorts of things.  And I just wonder your view on that, you know, if the strength of the administration's conviction that kind of the mingling of finance and industry is actually an underlying problem here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think it's one of many proposals.  I don't sense it's up at the top of their list.  It's not something they talk about a lot publically.  But it's, you know, it's a debate that has gone back 30 or 40 years between banking regulators and other people.  And so I think that's where that reasoning comes from.  It's an old debate that usually gets resolved in the way I mentioned, it gets resolved by grandfathering.  I don't think it's fundamental to any crisis prevention, although you could make arguments that way, and the existing structures have been well regulated by the kinds of protections you have in law and could strengthen modestly to address any kinds of risk that are covered in the couple of paragraphs in the white paper that touch on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the actual circumstances of what we have been through over the last nine months are completely the opposite.  Why is GE and GE Capital better than other financial institutions?  We have been able to raise equity as a combined enterprise, we have been able to strengthen the balance sheet of GE Capital based on the strength of the GE business model and cash flows, we had to cut the dividend that protects GE Capital going forward.  The industrial combination with our financial services business has provided the strength for us to work our way through this crisis, Jeff, and I think that's a pretty strong proof statement in one of the toughest environments that any business model has ever gone through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeff, as you can tell, we're very committed here.  Extremely committed, and just &#x2013; we're out originating new business, we're out providing liquidity, as we showed earlier, you know, even in a tough environment, you know, this industrial company is going to generate between 14 and $16 billion of cash flow.  I mean, all of that can be applied to strengthening GE Capital and doing more origination in the marketplace.  So we're very committed to this business model.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd just add one other thing, Jeff.  I don't think this thing was targeted at GE Capital.  I think this is a broader conceptual kind of thing.  And so I don't buy into the notion that somehow this was targeted.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, and just one other unrelated question.  Keith, could you give us just what the industrial organic growth was in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Revenue growth was down about 5.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thanks a lot everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of John Inch with Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys.  The equipment orders down over 40%, Keith, what was the organic results if you ex-ed out pricing and currency?  And in terms of the embedded down 10 to 15, do you presume that the down 40ish kind of reported number, does that kind of continue, or does that actually get better because of other comps or stuff that you're seeing --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>FX was only about 2 points on that, but, yeah, it gets better because the second quarter was the second highest order quarter ever.  In the second half you go down into $13 billion sort of order numbers instead the 14 or $15 billion order numbers we're comparing to.  So I think just based on the fact that the orders that we had, the absolute level were so great, you're going to see a little better comparison.  We don't expect to be down 44, 42% for the year.  It's somewhere probably closer to the 25% kind of range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Even without the recession, John, we would have had an unwind here.  We built $30 billion of backlog over four years.  It's just a ton.  So this is really within our expectations.  And what I talked about vis-&#xE0;-vis equipment revenue for how to think about it going forward, I think using all of our analytics, that seems pretty reasonable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if you look at the absolute equipment order level being down the amount, first of all, that is not what is going to turn into revenue.  As Jeff said, you do the math on the backlog conversion, and what you get in normal orders in the current year going into revenue, and you could be down somewhere around 10 to 15%.  We're giving you that framework in a non-guidance world, but it's not going to be down 40%.  On top of that, you've got the service as the other side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Well, Jeff, you're pretty optimistic on Energy continuing, yet the energy orders though, specifically, are down.  Is there something about the back half that allows your turbine business specifically to continue kind of the trend into next year, or is there mix issues, or how should we think about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, what I'd say is you've got a very strong service momentum in the second half, so I think that is a very good sign for the energy business.  Big backlogs, big global footprint.  And then I would say that a lot of the wind &#x2013; we have a very formal process in terms of how we book orders.  A lot of the wind commitments didn't turn into orders really because our customers were waiting to see how the eventual language worked on the production tax credit.  That's now been clarified, so we see a couple big orders that are out there that will probably happen in the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think 100% of what we're talking about for 2009 is in the backlog today across these businesses that we covered with those updates that I gave you, John.  We'll have to work our way through the second half and see what the equipment is for 2010, but that framework that Jeff talked about I think is pretty appropriate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just lastly, Keith, the 678 million of tax credits at GE Capital, how does that compare to the tax credits in the first quarter if you were to ex-out, or however you want to look at it, the impact of the reinvestment earnings that you did in the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's pretty similar.  I think the simple way to look at it is if you take the pre-tax loss at GECS and you tax effect it, then you end up with about 4 to $500 million of tax benefits that we get every quarter from our global structure, including the fact that GE pays GE Capital for its tax losses.  So you're talking about a 4 to $500 million a quarter run rate, and that's very similar excluding that one-time commitment to reinvesting earnings overseas that we did in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then just lastly, your deposit base, 36 billion, I think it was flat.  Is there anything going on there?  Maybe just a little bit of an update with respect to the GE Plus accounts or anything like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, there is nothing really.  I think we have had a little bit of slower growth in the core on the ILC bank in Utah, so if you don't have the assets we don't raise the deposits.  And we have had good global growth and some good bank loan growth offsetting that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, Noelia, why don't we take one more question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Wonderful.  Your final question comes from the line of Steven Winoker with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, thanks for taking the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.  Couple questions.  One just to follow up Jeff's question with Brackett on the white paper proposal, I guess it is only one option, it's early days, but it did explicitly exclude grandfathering in one of the comments.  I mean, what options have you thought about in sort of some of the worser case scenarios to avoid a split?  If in fact you did get named a bank holding company or however you sort of scenario-plan this thing to mitigate any damage other than just fighting it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think I talked earlier on about a number of things that we're doing to protect ourselves, getting smaller and more focused, number one. Number two, bulking up on regulation.  I'd say those are the two principal things.  And you talk about all the other things we're doing around capital, strengthening capital for a new regulated world, strengthening our liquidity profile, all of those things prepare you for whatever comes out of this white paper.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And on capital allocation, how are you thinking about, in light of current results, the long-term dividend payout outlook?  Is it going up to 50%, or how are you thinking about that, and over what kinds of timeframes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have said when we made the decision to cut the dividend for the second half of this year that we were going to have an assumption that we weren't going to rely on any capital out of GE Capital for the near term.  That assumption is still in place today.  We'll have to see how 2010 and 2011 look before we would revisit that.  And we think we have got a pretty good dividend yield on the dividend payout we have today based on our industrial earnings and our industrial cash flow relative to what is competitively available out there.  So I think it's something we will look at as we get more clarity on 2010 and 2011.  But we've got a pretty healthy dividend yield versus the dividend payout we have today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, the good news is that our CFOA is equal to or higher than it was when we had our December meeting.  So it gives us just a lot of financial flexibility when we look at the second half of the year to make good choices for our investors.  But our CFOA performance is very good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And as you mentioned in December, Jeff, are you still basically thinking in terms of that you're out of the market at least in terms of large M&amp;A?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, I made two comments in December that I still think are true today.  The first one is, our priority right now is just to make sure that GE Capital is safe and secure and that we have the opportunity to play offense in GE Capital in the second half of the year, and I think we can to do that.  The second comment I made is we just don't think there is going to be a lot of big transactions that take place, and I think what we have seen in the first half supports that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, Trevor.  So thanks, everybody.  You know, again, I think the key highlights are our great service strength, tremendous work on productivity, and strong cash flow.  And you have seen the framework for the second half of the year.  And again we think the GE team is executing well in a tough environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>And we look forward to giving you a good update on GE Capital on the 28th, and that should be a revisit of the deep dive we did in March on a more focused basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jeff, and Keith, and Brackett.  Just a few housekeeping items.  The replay will be available this afternoon.</p>
          <p>I'd like to close by announcing three upcoming events for your calendars here.  First we have a reminder that the GE Capital webcast will be held on July 28.  Second, we will be also hosting an investor day at the Global Research Center on September 17, so please stay tuned.  More details to come on that.  And the finally, our third quarter earnings call will be held on October 16.  Information regarding all these upcoming events also be made available on our website shortly.  And for today as always, JoAnna and I will be available to take your questions.  Thank you very much everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation.  This concludes your conference call.  You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>