<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1326373" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-07-20</date>
    <companies>
      <company>225</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Susan Hubbard, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John C. Martin, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">John F. Milligan, President and Chief Operating Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Joshua Schimmer</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Norbert Bischofberger</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Geoffrey Meacham</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Robin Washington</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Yaron Werber</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep">Kevin Young</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Mark Schoenebaum</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Rachel McMinn</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Thomas Russo</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">M. Ian Somaiya</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Jason Kantor</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Geoffrey Porges</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Thomas Wei</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Phil Nadeau</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Joel Sendek</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. And welcome to the Gilead Sciences second quarter 2010 earnings conference call. My name is Stacy and I'll be your conference operator for today. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, we will conduct a question-and-answer session. As a reminder, this conference call is being recorded today, July 20, 2010.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the call over to Susan Hubbard, Vice President of Investor Relations. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Stacy. Good afternoon. Welcome to Gilead's second quarter 2010 earnings conference call. We issued a press release this afternoon providing results for the second quarter 2010. This press release is available on our website at www.Gilead.com, as are the slides that provide much more detail around the topics discussed today on this call. Based on outreach to and feedback from our investors we're introducing a new earnings call format today. Our prepared comments on the call will be significantly briefer to allow more time for your questions. Kicking off this new format will be John Martin, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, and John Milligan, President and Chief Operating Officer who will provide some comments on the quarter and our view about the future and opportunities for the company.</p>
          <p>Norbert Bischofberger, Executive Vice President of R&amp;D and Chief Scientific Officer, Kevin Young, Executive Vice President of Commercial Operations, and Robin Washington, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer are here as well and will join John and John for the Q&amp;A session.</p>
          <p>I would first like to remind you that we'll be making statements relating to future events, expectations, trends, objectives, and financial results that constitute forward-looking statements within the meaning of the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements are based on a certain assumptions and are subject to a number of risks and uncertainties that could cause our actual results to differ materially from those expressed in any forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>I refer you to our Form 10-Q for the year ended December 31, 2010, subsequent press releases and other publicly filed SEC disclosure documents for a detailed description of risk factors and other matters related to our business. In addition, please note that we undertake no obligation to update or revise these forward-looking statements. We will be making certain references to financial measures that are on a non-GAAP basis.</p>
          <p>We provide a reconciliation between GAAP and non-GAAP numbers in the press release we just issued and on our corporate website at www.Gilead.com. I'll now turn the call over to John Martin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Susan, and good afternoon. I'm very pleased with our solid performance and productivity in the second quarter of this year despite the economic head ]winds we and our industry are facing. The fundamentals of our business remain solid. For HIV, the U.S. business continues to perform very strongly. But the environment in the European Union has been challenging. We are confident, however, that both the U.S. and international markets will remain sources of strong growth into the future because of the unquestionable public health benefit of HIV testing, linkage to care and treatment.</p>
          <p>Importantly, we continue to demonstrate the public health benefit is best provided by our fixed-dose products; the standard of care for the treatment of HIV. And we firmly believe that this health benefit will persuade the medical community to continue to use Gilead's combination products as generic competition becomes available.</p>
          <p>Over the last week, two important HIV announcements were made. First, President Obama unveiled the national HIV/AIDS strategy which acknowledges anti-retroviral treatment as a proven prevention tool and strives to increase diagnosis and early treatment for people living with HIV.</p>
          <p>The second important announcement was from the International AIDS Society which altered its HIV treatment guidelines to now specifically state, and I quote, "fixed dose combinations are recommended when possible for convenience. Tenofovir plus emtricitabine is the recommended NRTI combination in initial therapy."  And importantly, the substitution of emtricitabine with lamivudine was removed.</p>
          <p>We recognize that the success of our company over the long term is dependent upon continued innovation.  For our HIV pipeline, our efforts are focused on providing new single tablet regimens.  I am particularly excited about the progress we have made with the TMC 278 Truvada fixed dose regimen and the Quad program.  These are regimens that can extend our HIV product related revenue stream into the 2020s.</p>
          <p>I would like to thank Bill Lee, our Head of Research, for leading an effort over the last six months to restructure our HCV team.  We now have five oral small molecules from four different classes in human clinical studies.  I am confident that we have both the product pipeline and the right people in place to establish Gilead as a leader within the HCV market in the future.</p>
          <p>On today's foundation of $0.5 billion in annualized revenues, we have a growing product portfolio in the respiratory and cardiovascular areas.  Importantly, we are evaluating our existing commercial products for additional indications and patient populations, such as Cayston for bronchiectasis, Letairis for idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis and Ranexa for angina in diabetic patients.</p>
          <p>In addition to R&amp;D efforts, our strong financial position allows us to look to the outside for opportunities and judiciously use M&amp;A and business development efforts to enrich our pipeline.  We are considering acquisitions and partnerships in areas of unmet medical need that are relatively modest in terms of initial investment and have clear decision points on the near-term horizon.  These investments will have moderate near-term impact on our R&amp;D spend and expenses will only increase if we determine that the compounds warrant advancement to later stage development.</p>
          <p>An example of us executing on this strategy is our acquisition of CGI for up to $120 million during the second quarter.  While an early stage company, CGI has established itself with expertise in the area of protein kinase biology and small molecule discovery.  And we will explore the use of their lead Syk inhibitor for inflammatory diseases.</p>
          <p>At our current valuations we have been aggressively leveraging our cash to buy back shares and plan to continue this in the second half of 2010.  This is evidenced by the 44 million shares or about $1.7 billion worth of stock we bought and retired during the second quarter.  At our current price, if we were to fully execute upon the 5 billion stock repurchase plan, we would have repurchased approximately 18% of our current market cap.</p>
          <p>Before I turn the call over to John Milligan to discuss the business more specifically, I want to close by saying that Gilead remains committed to bringing forward novel products to treat life threatening diseases.  And I am confident of this lean and focused organization's ability to continue this mission.</p>
          <p>John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John.  As Susan mentioned earlier, we provided a comprehensive slide deck containing the important metrics and the information that we usually provide in the scripted portion of the call.  Therefore, I will only make a few brief comments on our financial, commercial and R&amp;D progress during the second quarter so that we may take as many of your questions as time will permit during the Q&amp;A portion of the call.</p>
          <p>Gilead posted solid second quarter 2010 results with non-GAAP net income of $761 million or $0.85 per share, representing a year over year increase in net income and EPS of 17 and 22% respectively.  Sales growth was strong across our therapeutic areas with total revenues of just over $1.9 billion, up 17% year over year.</p>
          <p>Antiviral product sales were $1.6 billion, up 13% year over year.  The U.S. contributed $887 million to our antiviral product sales increasing 14% year over year resulting from the continued strong growth of patient and market share in the United States; and was flat sequentially due to lower purchasing from non-retail outlets particularly ADAPs as we have seen historically the second quarter of each calendar.</p>
          <p>Europe contributed $601 million of our antiviral product sales increasing 9% year over year and decreasing 4% sequentially. The sequential decrease in Europe is driven primarily by the strengthening of the U.S. dollar relative to European currencies and cost containment measures in light of budget deficits in many of the countries in Europe.</p>
          <p>In addition to the solid contribution from our antiviral franchise, we had significant growth in our cardiovascular franchise.  Ranexa prescriptions in particular have grown by 54% since the first quarter of 2009, the quarter prior to our acquisition of CVT.  Ranexa's recent performance further demonstrates the increasing capabilities of our commercial organization's ability to quickly absorb a new product, tailoring promotional efforts around awareness, expanding the field force and prescriber targets and improving reimbursement and access.</p>
          <p>Our newest product Cayston achieved $10.5 million in its first full quarter of sales in both the United States and some countries of Europe.  We continued to receive positive responses from the CF community as to the importance of having an additional treatment option in an area where the last antibiotic prove was more than a decade ago.  We recently presented data from our head to head study of Cayston versus Tobi showing statistical superiority over Tobi at the European Cystic Fibrosis meeting in Valencia, Spain.  These data and a positive response from patients demonstrate that there's a clear need for a novel antibiotic to address the growing incidence of Tobi resistance or intolerance.</p>
          <p>The final piece of the financial highlights that I will speak to is our 2010 guidance which is detailed in slide 37 in the earnings call deck.  Given the impact of foreign currency fluctuations, we are reducing our product sales guidance to 7.3 to $7.4 billion.  We are also revising our effective tax rate guidance to 26.5 to 27.5% due to higher than expected U.S. revenue growth and lower than expected revenues in Europe.</p>
          <p>Turning to R&amp;D. We've also made significant progress in research and development, with many key achievements in a variety of our clinical research programs.  As John mentioned, our HCV programs continue to make significant strides. We've recently held meetings with our HCV scientific advisors both in the U.S. and internationally, which confirmed that our strategy of moving toward an all-antiviral combination therapy is the appropriate long term goal in the treatment of this disease.</p>
          <p>At this point, we have five small molecules in clinical development with two more about to enter the ID stage, which would give us six classes of small molecules that in principle can all be explored in various combinations.  We look forward to sharing more details on several of these programs and our progress to date at the AASLD conference taking place in Boston in late October including data from the Phase IIa study evaluating the combination of GS 9190 and GS 9256 with or without  ribavirin dosed for 28 days in HCV positive genotype 1 patients.</p>
          <p>To further the understanding of the potential applications of Cayston, we initiated a Phase IIIb study just a few months ago in CF patients with Burkholderia infection.  This is a pathogen that is benign in healthy individuals but devastating to patients with CF, decreasing mortality and requiring them to lead very isolated lives so as to not infect other patients.  Underscoring this need we expect to fully enroll 95 patients into this study by the end of this month.</p>
          <p>In addition, we're following the promising results from the Phase II study of Cayston in bronchiectasis and we are preparing to launch a larger Phase III study by the end of this year that would support this indication.</p>
          <p>With the setback of two of our competitors' compounds under investigation for the treatment of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, we have had even more interest in our study of Ambrisentan in the treatment of this very serious disease.  Our Phase III study is designed to enroll approximately 660 patients, and is now more than 50% enrolled.  It is an event driven study with time to progression or death as the primary endpoint.</p>
          <p>We also continued to advance our HIV pipeline in the second quarter with the initiation of the Phase III studies for both the Quad fixed dose regimen and Cobicistat, our novel pharmaco-enhancer.  We've already completed screening in Study 102, the study comparing the Quad with Atripla and we expect to continue the enrollment of 700 patients before the end of this month.  This should translate into initiating and completing enrollment in the study in about 2 1/2 months.  This speaks to the excitement about this program from both the investigators and the study participants.</p>
          <p>We also now have the 48-week data from the Phase II Quad versus Atripla study and hope to present it in an upcoming HIV conference before the end of this year.</p>
          <p>As you may know, the International AIDS Conference is taking place this week in Vienna, Austria where the data on the two pivotal TMC 278 pivotal studies will be presented by Dr. Cal Cohen during the late-breaker session on Thursday.  As the data are embargoed until the presentation, we are restricted in our comments to only the results that are included in the abstract and to what is already in the public domain. The abstract cites that TMC 278 was not inferior to and better tolerated than efavirenz, leading to fewer discontinuations due to adverse events.  There were fewer grade 2 to 4 adverse events and the difference was statistically significant with regard to some psychiatric and neurologic events and rash. There were more virological failures in the TMC 278 arms compared to efavirenz and the data are currently pending analysis to identify the predictors of response.  We look forward to the presentation of the full study results this Thursday.</p>
          <p>I'm also pleased to confirm that we are on track to complete our regulatory filings for the fixed dose in both the U.S. and Europe either shortly after or at the time of the J&amp;J filing. The introduction of this product gives patients and physicians an important new choice for a one pill, once daily regimen.</p>
          <p>As John mentioned, the revised IAS guidelines now endorse our fixed dose combination and remove lamivudine as a substitution for emtricitabine. Specifically, they recommend tenofovir with emtricitabine as the backbone of choice noting that it's available as a fixed dose combination backbone as Truvada and also available within a complete regimen including efavirenz as Atripla.  They also recommend Truvada with either of two protease inhibitors; atazanavir or darunavir and with the integrase inhibitor elvitegravir.</p>
          <p>These guidelines also now endorse the initiation of earlier treatment at a CD4 cell count of 500 or below and state that therapy should be considered for patients with CD4s above 500.</p>
          <p>And the final and important piece is that EPZICOM has been downgraded from a preferred to an alternative treatment.</p>
          <p>In totality, as Gilead's products namely Atripla and Truvada are the cornerstone to first line therapy, capturing the majority of new starts, we see this as an important opportunity along with the drive to screen more individuals to continue to grow the number of patients on a Gilead based regimen.</p>
          <p>In summary, I'm proud of Gilead's progress and strong financial performance in the second quarter of this year on the backdrop of challenging economic conditions.  Further, Norbert and his team have demonstrated a real increase in R&amp;D productivity with five new molecules now in the clinic for HCV.  In the coming quarters, you will see evidence of our increased productivity in our other franchises as well. I continue to be impressed with the passion and dedication of Gilead's employees who are deeply committed to helping patients facing very challenging diseases.</p>
          <p>To our current shareholders, we, the management team at Gilead, are individually and collectively committed to returning value to shareholders and firmly believe that Gilead can deliver much more than what is reflected in our current valuation. We will continue to work hard to deliver on our short and medium term commercial objectives, to bring forward new products and to augment our pipeline for the long-term benefit of patients and shareholders alike. I will now turn the call over to the operator for the question and answer session. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We will pause for just a moment to compile the Q&amp;A roster. Your first question comes from the line of Josh Schimmer with Leerink Swann.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks for taking the questions. I guess I'll just ask about the all-oral HCV combo regimen trials that you're considering.  And how fast do you think those can move forward in development?  Maybe you can give us a little bit of a sense of the development strategy and time lines there. You've got a number targets to choose from.  How do you decide which to combine with each other?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Josh.  Thanks for the question.  This is Norbert.  We are actually doing one study now where we're looking at the combination of our NS5B with the protease inhibitor plus/minus ribavirin to simply ask the question, how much viral load reduction can you see with two antivirals and add a ribavirin?  The conclusion from that study is as expected that these compounds are not enough so we will add more compounds to the mix.</p>
          <p>Now, how are you going to go about that?  I think part of it is, of course, guided by very simple drug interactions. Part of it is guided by in vitro synergy and additivity experiments but in the end it has do with clinical research, which is back to now doing very short viral dynamic studies to figure out are three compounds enough, four compounds or five compounds enough?  And once we feel we get the required potency then we would move that into a larger Phase II study to look at SVRs.  And in principle, I think the path is pretty clear, although it is challenging, because particularly in six classes there are quite a number of combinations that you can evaluate. But, of course we're not going to evaluate all of them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Norbert, I'd like to add to that too. One of the reasons we have so many products going into the clinic; we want to make sure that inevitably, there will be issues of tolerability.  And we want to make sure we have enough molecules that we can have a complete regimen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And any guess when you'd be in a position to move them to a larger SVR design trial, how long might that take?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is a more difficult thing to say, but, Josh, I would think if we find these two additional INDs, which we have all the intent to, then we will have six classes of molecules early next year or sometime in the first quarter of next year.  And I would say by the end of next year, we should be in a position to choose the certain combinations and move them forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Geoff Meacham with JPMorgan.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys.  Thanks for taking the question.  I have a question for you on slide 5, just on the cash flow.  And I think part of the logic here for the valuation is really a discomfort with the current pipeline and diversification away from HIV. And so a three part question here. What's your appetite for doing Phase III deals that move the dial? What therapeutic areas look attractive to you? And then what is the appetite for doing a tender offer to do even a more aggressive share buyback?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Geoff, it's John Milligan.  Thanks for the question. So with regard to the kinds of deals we're doing, we are looking for earlier stage compounds for the most part.  And I think there's a lot of value there, because it allows us to help guide the development of the programs so that we can have good input by the time it gets to Phase III, because that's really I think, where the value we can bring to a compound is, designing good Phase III studies rather than inheriting something.  I'm not going to rule it out, but it's clear that our emphasis is on earlier deals today, things like CGI.  That would be something more important to us at this point in time.</p>
          <p>In terms of other therapeutic areas, Norbert and his team have been doing quite a bit of work with the business development group over the last year, and I think they have really done a good job of outlining different kinds of areas that we'd be interested in getting into.</p>
          <p>CGI, for example, brings us into the area of kinases.  And kinases can be useful in lots of different therapeutic areas. There's kinase inhibitors on the market for cancer. Obviously, they're being explored for different inflammatory diseases. And I'm sure with over 500 known kinases and the increased understanding of the human biology of the kinases, there will be other diseases behind that.</p>
          <p>So what I think you'll see is us focusing in these areas that are similar to the ones I've described where we have a good opportunity to really further the medical -- let me try that again, where we would have the ability to tackle an unmet medical need with a new molecule and where we would have a proprietary position that would make the sales and marketing relatively straightforward.  So without being more specific, I think that gives you an idea of where we're going.</p>
          <p>And then the last question with regard to tender offers, it's one of those clear things that we can't at this point in time and won't speculate about such actions in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just a follow up to the, to your question about or to the answer about Phase II programs, so does the hiring of Dr. McHutchison speak to anything with respect to the therapeutic area?  Because I know you guys have had obviously hep C products in the portfolio for a while. And would that be something that you would look externally or would you put more resources behind the current pipeline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Geoff, hi, it's Norbert. Geoff, I would say the answer to that is both.  We are constantly looking externally as to what's available and, of course, with John having joined us, we have more insights and knowledge as to what is really available and what is, what would fit our pipeline.  But we also want to put a lot more emphasis on our own programs as well. And as you may know, we recently made the decision to close our Durham facility which allows us to concentrate everything here in Foster City and bring both the clinical development and the research efforts in close proximity.  I think that will greatly accelerate the programs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And for just what Josh was asking earlier about the complexity of the development, we felt like we needed everyone together on one site and needed to expand the team.  And it's just our recognition that we want to move this through as quickly as possible and come up with an all-oral regimen.  Robin, I believe you wanted to elaborate on something.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I was going to follow onto John's comment.  Geoff, as you know, we've done accelerated share repurchases. We also have access to the capital market and clearly capital structure is one thing we continue to look at.  As John mentioned, we can't give specifics but we'll have updates for you pretty quickly here in the second half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Yaron Werber with Citigroup. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi guys. Thanks for taking my questions. Can you help us understand a little bit the discrepancy between, I mean the IMS as we all know does not follow ADAPs and it does not follow non-retail.  When you look at your Synovate data which you've been kindly been providing to us for years now, it does look like the U.S. market has only increased 2% year over year, which is substantially down from the 4 to 5% back about four quarters ago.</p>
          <p>Encouragingly the European market is growing nicely at 7% but help us understand.  That's more of a retail business too, the Synovate data.  Just help us understand maybe a little bit what are you seeing there, and maybe a second question is, what happened with ADAP purchasing this quarter and what happened in non-retail, and are you seeing economic sensitivities there?  Or is it that the ADAP business ultimately will come back sequentially just a quarter later?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Yaron, it's Kevin.  First thing I want to say I was really pleased with the results from my U.S. organization in the second quarter.  These were really solid results, and they were very hard earned.  And I actually think they're some of the best results I've seen my organization deliver.</p>
          <p>Let me elaborate on that.  If you look at the TRx, the growth in Q2 2010 was as good as the growth that we actually had in Q2 2009, whether that be quarter on quarter or that be year over year.  And that really is the absolute test of the dynamics of our HIV business.  Are prescriptions growing, and they were rock solid and they were right where we wanted them to be.  You're quite right, the variable is always in our HIV business, the non-retail.  Non-retail in Q2 has always been traditionally the weakest quarter of the four quarters for the financial year of ADAP.  And that's because we have these direct purchases particularly from Florida, from Texas, and from Puerto Rico.</p>
          <p>So as we expected, Q2 was a weaker quarter.  When we do our historical calculations, typically Q2 is about 21% of the division of the four quarters.  And traditionally Q3, Q4, and Q1 on a calendar basis are the stronger quarters for non-retail. So it's what we expected.  It's where we expected it to land.  And, of course, we have no control over the purchase from those central ADAP depots.</p>
          <p>Let me talk a little bit about ADAP, which, of course, are the largest part of that non-retail.  We have seen a tick up in waiting lists.  Actually, over the last week, we have seen a drop actually in the ADAP waitlists.  North Carolina, actually took off over 600 patients as they had some release of state budgets into their ADAP fund.  So that was nice to see.  So just as much as waitlists can go up, they can very quickly go down.</p>
          <p>So it's something that we watch very carefully.  There generally isn't a correlation between uptick in waitlists and actual purchase, which might surprise you.  The federal dollars are still there in a very healthy way. They were an increase on 2009 and the ADAPs still want to spend their money.  So we still did see purchase from Florida and from Texas in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>And the final thing I would say is that in some ways, if there weren't any waitlists for the ADAP programs, there wouldn't be the back pressure that tries to get the extra budget.  And as you have seen about a week ago, there was an extra $25 million released by the federal government to assist some of the ADAP programs.  And it is our information that those dollars will be released towards the end of August after the ADAP programs have applied.</p>
          <p>So in short, it was a very good and solid quarter for our HIV business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mark Schoenebaum with ISI Group.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thanks for taking my question.  Thanks for allowing -- thanks for changing the call format so we can ask so many questions.</p>
          <p>My question is around capital structure.  I was intrigued by Robin's comment that I think you said something to the effect of we will have an update for you pretty quickly in the second half of the year around capital structure. Could you just clarify, perhaps, Robin what you meant by that or if I misheard you?  And related on slide 5, I was &#x2013; I liked slide 5, and I was just wondering, there's no mention of the dividend over the next three years on slide 5.  Could you just give your company's current thinking on your philosophy around dividend?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Mark, this is Robin.  As we've highlighted on slide 5, I think our focus in terms of returning shareholder value to investors right now is going to be via share repurchase plans.  It doesn't mean we would never consider a dividend but our current thinking is to use the vehicle of share repurchases.  What I meant was, again, it's very clear as John highlighted that at our current valuation, there is an opportunity with the 5 billion share repurchase program to continue to be aggressive and potentially even accelerate our repurchase of stock.  So we can't provide details at this point, but we do expect to be able to update you in the near future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How much cash do you have onshore in the U.S. that you could theoretically use to do something like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So currently we've been using a fair amount of our onshore cash to facilitate the share repurchase buyback that we have done quarter to date which has been about, or year to date which has been about $1.9 billion, so we have about 26% of that 4.2 billion is currently onshore. But, again, as I mentioned, there are various vehicles and options available for us that we can consider that allow us to continue to be aggressive with our share buybacks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks a lot, Robin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Rachel McMinn with Bank of America Merrill Lynch.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks very much.  Two very unrelated questions. Just on the tax rate comment, I guess I'm struggling a little bit here. I think the U.S. HIV sales percentage wise really didn't change much in the first half.  So I'm a little bit confused to why the tax rate is increasing so much in terms of your guidance.</p>
          <p>And then just in terms of the hep C comment, can you give us a sense of whether, what you're seeing with your combination of your triple, why you're adding interferon here, is that related to viral breakthrough or just lack of overall potency?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rachel, I'll answer the first part.  Relative to our tax rate as we tried to articulate in the slide, it's really a mix between higher U.S. and lower revenues in our low tax jurisdictions.  That's primarily Europe.  So given the weakness in the euro and pricing, and again, we're projecting our effective tax rate for the full year, right, as a result of our guidance change, we had to take our tax rate up.</p>
          <p>So when you think about an increase or decrease in U.S. profits, it usually results in about a 0.25% change in our tax rate; while when you look at decreases relative to ex U.S. profits, it's about a 50% -- or 50 basis point change relative to our tax rate.</p>
          <p>So that change or dynamic in the geographic mix causes our tax rate to go up.  The reason why you're seeing it higher in Q2 is because we have to do a catch up from Q1 to bring that in line with what we project going forward. I'll also mention that one of our assumptions in our tax rate for the year is that we &#x2013; well, we haven't assumed that we can renew the R&amp;D tax credit.  So if we are able do that, that will actually reduce our rates about another half a point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rachel, hi. It's Norbert.  I'll answer the second question with regards to addition of another arm in the study that includes interferon. The study started out as a viral dynamic study to simply answer the question whether 9190 and 9256 in combination with or without ribavirin give you good RVR responses. And we included the third arm which includes interferon, ribavirin and two anti-virals number one as a control to see how much viral potency can you get with four drugs. And secondly because of the observation that the three drugs by themselves were not enough.  The details of these, the studies will be submitted.  We intend to be submitting to AASLD and so you should see it there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Tom Russo with Robert W. Baird.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.  I just had a question on guidance.  Can you comment on what expectations for European price cuts going forward are captured, whether you still see the impact of healthcare reform in the U.S. as about 200 million or whether that's been refined?  And then lastly, what might be the biggest risk to guidance looking forward from today.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Tom.  It's Kevin. I'll certainly take the European pricing. You've seen slide 36 where we tried to highlight as clearly as we can what has taken place during the first two quarters of this year.  That includes both what we call the normal European pricing and then the result of some of the actions around decks and the intervention of governments, unexpected and in keeping with the economic environment.  These are what we can see right now.  Very difficult to make any forward predictions.</p>
          <p>Obviously, there are two of the major markets here, Spain and Germany.  I think most of the other companies have noted this.  In terms of the other three major markets, Italy did announce cuts but they were directed towards their generic industry.  They have quite high prices for their branded generics. And we have not heard any news about price decreases in France over and above the normal processes you go through with the pricing committee.  And for the U.K., that is subject to what they call the PPRS, the Pharmaceutical Price Regulatory Scheme. That was renegotiated on a five year term back in February of 2009.  Who knows what the government will do going forward?  But that's typically a five year term. So we've really noted here what our best intelligence tells us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right and so I'll chime on healthcare reform to the question we are on track relative to the 200 million that we guided to. We did provide a $29 million in Q1, and as we discussed, while we won't provide additional details, I can tell you that Q2 was slightly higher, as you would expect. And we still see more back end loading relative to that $200 million in the second half of the year as the ADAP and PHS pricing increases start to get impacted.  So we're very comfortable with that 200 million.  I think Kevin outlined the overall dynamics of the business, so we feel very comfortable with our guidance now that we've adjusted for the FX volatility.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah and Tom this is Susan, I'll just chime in.  We've got a pretty detailed slide as you've seen on slide 34 in the slide deck that outlines what we think for 2011 which should provide you a little bit more color on what we're thinking about the excise tax, et cetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ian Somaiya with Piper Jaffray.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Just a question on the caspase inhibitor.  I see that it's part of the slide deck. I was curious if you can now speak to the side effects that are seen with the; in the Phase II studies. What if anything are the plans moving forward, or were the side effects specific for that drug or is it for the entire class?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, Ian. It's Norbert. Ian, we're currently debating whether there are opportunities still for the caspase inhibitor.  Like one example is where you can have a disease that doesn't require chronic dosing and that would have some tolerance for hepatotoxicity.  We are at the, in the middle of that evaluation and haven't come to a final conclusion yet but we hope to be able to do so the end of August.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Does that include NASH or HCV or are those two indications of?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, we haven't, I'm just telling you some of my thinking.  I think it would exclude NASH and HCV because both of those would require long term chronic dosing. But something like acute alcoholic hepatitis would be something that potentially could be considered.  Again, that's something we have to discuss with experts. This is my own personal opinion. So that's where it stands.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jason Kantor with RBC Capital Markets.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.  Thanks for taking my question.  On the TMC 278 data that's being presented, we got a lot of details in the abstract.  Are we to expect more information when they present? And if so, what kind of information, new information might we be seeing?  And then also, I'd love to get your thoughts on what you're hearing from physicians regarding the differentiation, the importance of viral breakthrough versus the safety benefits and how you see this drug ultimately being commercially positioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jason, maybe I'll give you first an answer about the emerging data and then maybe Kevin can comment on the commercial positioning.  So, you know, we are actually very encouraged by the Phase III data because, as John Milligan mentioned, it's another once daily, complete regimen option for the patients.  The response rates are better than the response rates of efavirenz and they are up there in the low 80s, the highest that have been reported in recent Phase III studies and including our own 934 study and the START Merck study with raltegravir.  It's clearly better tolerated but it has more virological failures.</p>
          <p>But I want to make three comments on those virological failures. First of all, J&amp;J Tibotec collaboration with us we're looking at baseline predictors of those virological failures. And two obvious things to look at would be baseline viral load and body weight. If we could find some easy baseline predictors, that would minimize the whole issue of virological failures.</p>
          <p>Secondly, you have to keep in mind that the consequence of being intolerant to the regimen and virological failing the regimen is really the same. You know, you, Jason, worded it as tolerability versus virological failure but these are really two of the same things. And the consequence is that the patient goes off the regimen onto another one.</p>
          <p>Now thankfully, we have other good regimens that the patients can go to, particularly integrase, protease and CCL5 inhibitors.</p>
          <p>And then the final thing I want to point your attention to if you look at the publication that came out in June of this year in "AIDS" where they presented the 278, 48 week and 96 week data you may notice that the failure rate at 48 weeks on 278 and on efavirenz was very much similar to what is reported in the Phase III studies ECHO and THRIVE. However at week 96, the failure rates between 278 and efavirenz were the same.  And this is fairly easy to in a straightforward way to interpret, you simply say that efavirenz is less well tolerated, consequently patients may be less compliant and that leads to more virological failures.  So you notice this is again an example where virological failure and tolerability are really very much linked.  And this is actually something we are seeing in our own Phase III studies.</p>
          <p>We've actually done a number of studies that include efavirenz as a third agent and what we have seen is that the failure rates at week 48 are pretty much in the 5% range what is reported in ECHO and THRIVE.  But at week 96, the failure rate goes up to 9%.  So, again, if we're seeing this in these Phase III studies, then you will basically come to the conclusion that the virological failure rates between 278 and efavirenz, the study carried out to 96 weeks would be no different and then you're left with the benefits of 278.  So I personally think the emerging profile together with the expected much better pregnancy category is a selling point for 278, and it's a welcome new option for patients.  So, Kevin, do you want to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'd just add to that Jason, that obviously, this is when we really fire the gun on our prelaunch activities just as you say.  We needed the full data set to be presented.  I've got a team out in Vienna.  We'll be doing debriefs with advisory boards and this is exactly when we need to understand and hear their reaction to the data.  I think we've always said that we see this fixed dose combination as more a drug for the naive setting, a patient new to therapy. The obvious benefits are there in terms of avoidance of potential CNS side effects on efavirenz and obviously women of child bearing age.</p>
          <p>You know, those groups of patients very often go to the protease inhibitors in combination with Truvada right now, and you could certainly see them going on to a 278 fixed dose combination.  What I like about this is we will have two, single tablet regimens available to physicians to patients.  And as we've seen from the IAS guidelines really highlighting the benefit of fixed dose combination.  That's a great position to be in. The fine tuning of Bill's positioning of Atripla and 278, we're now going to start to put together.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I could just follow up with Norbert, is it generally accepted that virologic failure and failure due to intolerance are equivalent? Because that's not necessarily the feedback you get when you talk to all the physicians out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, Jason, when you look at the breakdown of virological failure, there are two categories.  There's the category of never suppressed and there's the category of rebounder. I haven't done a poll and asked people how many accept this notion, but I think it's common sense that you would say that particularly the rebounder are due to compliance.  At least that's what we are finding in our studies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Geoff Porges with Sanford and Bernstein (sic) [Sanford Bernstein].  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.  And I appreciate the chance to ask the questions.  Could I follow up with Kevin a little bit on the outlook for both the TMC based combination and Atripla.  Kevin, first of all, just how important is the M184V mutation emerging in the 48 week TMC study?  And are physicians currently willing to continue patients on Truvada even in the presence of that mutation?</p>
          <p>And then just a related question is, are you going to shift your commercial emphasis entirely over to the TMC based combination, or are you going to continue to support commercially Atripla?  And then lastly, as you look ahead a few years to Atripla, what sort of discussions are you having with payers, particularly in Europe about what their expectations are for the price of the combination if SUSTIVA is available generically?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Geoff, thanks for all the questions.  I'll let Norbert take the first part and then I'll take 2 and 3.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now Geoff quickly, you asked a question about the 184 mutation.  As you may know, it's a very labile mutation and when you stop the selected pressure, it reverts back to wild-type.  I can talk for own studies with efavirenz and Truvada. We've done two  Phase III studies that have included that as one of the arms.  What we did see is the emergence of the K103N. That's the same mutation as we saw as the J&amp;J Tibotec observed in the current Phase III studies.</p>
          <p>And on the nuc side, it was the M184V or I and we have actually been successful in sequencing those patients with a Truvada containing regimen.  So the answer is I would say the consequence, clinical consequence of the M184V/I mutation is not clear or at best it doesn't preclude the use of emtricitabine and Truvada in those patients.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Geoff, the b and c parts of your question, we continue to have a very professional relationship with Bristol-Myers Squibb. It's going very well this year with both companies incredibly committed to Atripla.  In the early part of next year, thanks to the contract that we have between the companies, we are able to move away from our association with Bristol-Myers Squibb.  In terms of our promotional emphasis of Atripla and 278, that will be the choice of Gilead. And, again, as we see the reaction to the data come out to Vienna, we'll be making some internal decisions. And, obviously, right now they have competitive implications, so that's something in detail that we'll be working out simultaneous to the regulatory pathway.  So we have the flexibility here at Gilead to put the emphasis that we decide to choose on Atripla versus 278.</p>
          <p>In terms of European payers, I actually think there's a very good news story here, and that's the value story around our fixed dose combination. We are significantly lower in terms of price in our European markets for Atripla than the combination of Truvada plus proteases and Truvada plus Isentress. And when you have cost controls and pressures coming in, in the likes of a country like Spain through their regions, it's a very good and strong position, and it's one that we are presenting to actually treat more patients with Atripla, is actually a saving opposite some of the other regimens that are used by physicians.  So that's something that we're starting to ensure that we communicate.  So we've actually got a benefit there that plays to some of the needs right now in terms of the euros spent on HIV care.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Thomas Wei with Jefferies &amp; Company.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks.  I had a question on TMC 278 as well.  It seems as though when we get to the ultimate competitive market, it's really going to be a question of TMC 278 versus these integrase regimens.  I did want to get your sense, it seems like your drugs, what you're going to have to offer will be one pill, once a day with maybe some outstanding questions on efficacy, virologic breakthrough versus some your competitors who may not have the same issues on efficacy but would be forced to provide their pills as maybe a two pill, once a day regimen.</p>
          <p>Can you help us understand how we should think about the trade off there between factors like virologic failure versus needing to take two pills once a day?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Thomas, this is Kevin.  Well, I don't think the story is quite as simple as that.  You know, I'd draw your attention to an abstract that is being presented at the IAS conference that's looking at BID raltegravir versus QD raltegravir, and I think there's some interesting results there.  I don't think it's quite as simplistic as that the integrase class has got incredible efficacy and tolerability and it's all about that versus a single tablet regimen.  So I think we're going to see more studies and we're going to see that play out over time.  So I wouldn't necessarily jump to that being the direct comparison.</p>
          <p>I think you've seen when the IAS guidelines come out so strongly in terms of commending the use of a fixed dose combination that that is very powerful. It's very powerful with physicians, and it's very, very powerful with payers. So that type of endorsement is incredibly important.  Right now in the U.S., we have a &#x2013; we see that in some ways the mindset of HIV physicians is what we call Atripla unless.  In other words, Atripla is the go-to first line therapy and in very small situations, they will look at other starting therapies.  So, I think the value around a single tablet regimen, it's so strong in this market and will continue to be so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Phil Nadeau with Cowen &amp; Company.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank for you taking my question.  My question is on the change in guidance.  You mentioned that the factor leading to the change in guidance was the foreign currency fluctuations. Can you give us some idea what of euro/dollar exchange rate is assumed in the current guidance? And in the past you've said that a 10% change in FX would impact revenue by about $100 million per year.  Could you give us an updated figure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  So that stays about the same.  If you think of it on a year to date basis, it's going to be about 60 million kind of given where we are, and the impact we've experienced overall. And I'm focused on revenue primarily as opposed to net earnings, which as you know, it also impacts to a lesser extent. But on a sequential basis, we had a decline in general, there was a decline in the euro of about 10%.  As you know, we hedge other currencies as well, but that kind of pegs overall the volatility that we saw. And it's pretty indicative of the overall market basket of currencies that we hedge.  As you mentioned, with our strategy, we hedge 50 to 60% of the revenue and 60 to 70% of pre-tax, right? And a 10% change gets us to about a 100 million impact based on how we hedge.</p>
          <p>We were, again, in terms of sequentially we were able to mitigate a portion of that so that we ended up having a sequential impact on FX of about 3%.  On a year to date basis, the euro's declined about 16%.  So, again, if do you that math, of that plus or minus 10%, it gives you the indication of what happened relative to our guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  I guess the reason why I'm wondering is when I look at the euro quote on my screen in front of me, it's about $1.29 and looking back at April 21, it was about $1.33.  So versus...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Uh hmm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand that there's been a dip in the interim but versus where we were on the Q1 call, the euro hasn't changed all that much.  So what is kind of the base rate assumed in your guidance, and are we in fact somewhat above it where the euro's trading now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You should probably go back and look at beginning of January. The rates were significantly higher than where it's trading today from a euro perspective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Fair enough.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Joel Sendek with Lazard Capital Markets.  Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.  Thanks a lot.  I have a question about the HIV sales in the second quarter.  So in particular, slide 15, if you look at the far right hand column there, 440,000 patients, that's down from the similar slide last quarter.  And I'm just wondering why that is, and I'm trying to make sense of your comments that you had a really strong quarter. Because on the basis of the guideline changes at the end of last year for earlier treatment I would have thought that that number would have been up. So can you just help me understand what's going on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure, Joel.  My comment earlier was based on TRx. Synovate is a really good database but as we've said time and time again in the past, it is a survey.  It's basically 200 physicians.  It's 4,000 patient records.  I mean, put that into perspective.  We've got over 500,000 patients on anti retroviral therapy.  So it is a survey.  It's very helpful.  And by the way, I want to come back to a very, very important data point that I haven't brought out in my answers to date.  But it's, we certainly use it for forecasting purposes, but it certainly isn't the only survey or only piece of data information that we use in our old forecasting models around market size.</p>
          <p>What I was referring to earlier is if you look at TRx, the TRx in the quarter for both Atripla and Truvada, quarter on quarter grew the mid 3%. For us we use Wolters Kluwer Health, Atripla grew by 3.5% and Truvada grew by 3.8%.  If you compare that with Q2 2009, the numbers were 3.3 and 3.6.  And if you compare it with year over year, this quarter, previous year and 2009 Q2 previous year, again, the growths were the same.  And then the other thing we look at is basically the moving annual total just as we do for Synovate, if you look at that for prescriptions, if you look at Q2, on the moving annual total basis, 2010 Wolters Kluwer Health the growth was 8.5% for total ARV prescribing; 8.5%, a very, very healthy growth.</p>
          <p>For IMS, it was just under 8%.  So, again, if you look at the real where the rubber hits the road which is prescriptions, clearly, there's very healthy growth there. I would like to come back and just comment on what I said earlier about earlier prescribing. You've been looking for a data point where we can see the impact of DHSS, HSS.  And we actually saw a very nice jump in the starting point, CD4 starting point, for na&#xEF;ve patients.  If you look at quarter 2, 3, and 4 of 2009, about 32 to 33% of HIV patients were started at 350 and above.</p>
          <p>We saw that jump to 39% in Q1 of this year.  So quite a step change in the starting points of anti retroviral therapy. So that's the first strong indicator we have seen that what we hear on a day to day basis from our field based teams, that physicians are being very proactive in talking to patients about starting therapy in line with the new guidelines is now coming through in the data.  So we're pretty pleased to see that step change.  So clearly, it's coming through in the data.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Miss Hubbard, at this point, we have run out of time for additional questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Well, thank you very much, operator.  And thank you certainly all for joining us today and for engaging in this new format for our earnings call.  I hope you found it useful and the information in the slides was additional data points for you.  And we're always working to optimize the process.</p>
          <p>So please give us your feedback.  We'll be around for after calls following this meeting and happy to help round out any questions you have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We thank you for your participation in today's conference. This does conclude your presentation.  You may now disconnect and have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>