<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1510474" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>225</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Patrick O'Brien</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Senior Vice President">Robin L. Washington</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Vice President-Commercial Operations">Kevin Young</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">John C. Martin</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Geoff C. Meacham</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Scientific Officer &amp; Executive VP-Research">Norbert W. Bischofberger</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities LLC">Matt M. Roden</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">Michael J. Yee</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch, Pierce, Fenner &amp; Smith, Inc.">Rachel L. McMinn</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">Mark J. Schoenebaum</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Wells Fargo Advisors LLC">Brian Corey Abrahams</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co. LLC">Geoffrey Craig Porges</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Chief Operating Officer">John F. Milligan</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Yaron Werber</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Robyn Karnauskas</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Marshall Urist</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Piper Jaffray, Inc.">M. Ian Somaiya</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Brean, Murray, Carret &amp; Co. LLC">Brian Skorney</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies &amp; Co., Inc.">Thomas A. Wei</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Tony Butler</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst" affiliation="Needham &amp; Co. LLC">Alan Carr</participant>
      <participant id="22" type="analyst" affiliation="Stifel, Nicolaus &amp; Co., Inc.">Joel D. Sendek</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by and welcome to the Gilead Sciences third quarter 2012 earnings conference call. My name is Ann, and I will be your conference operator today. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. And as a reminder, this conference call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the call over to Patrick O'Brien, Vice President of Investor Relations. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ann. Good afternoon, everyone.</p>
          <p>We issued a press release this afternoon providing earnings results for the third quarter, which are available on our website. You can also find a detailed earnings slide deck that will support some of the topics we will cover on today's call. For our prepared remarks and Q&amp;A, I am joined by our Chairman and CEO, John Martin; our President and Chief Operating Officer, John Milligan; our Executive Vice President of Research and Development, Norbert Bischofberger; our Executive Vice President of Commercial Operations, Kevin Young; and our Chief Financial Officer, Robin Washington.</p>
          <p>Before we begin with our formal remarks, we want to remind you that we will make forward-looking statements, including plans and expectations with respect to our product candidates and financial projections, all of which involve certain assumptions, risks, and uncertainties that are beyond our control and could cause our actual results to differ materially from these statements. A description of these risks can be found in our latest SEC disclosure documents and recent press releases. In addition, Gilead does not undertake any obligation to update any forward-looking statement made during this call.</p>
          <p>We will also be using non-GAAP financial measures to help you understand our underlying business performance. The GAAP reconciliations are provided in the press release as well as our website.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the call over to Robin Washington.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Patrick, and thank you all for joining us this afternoon.</p>
          <p>Gilead continued to deliver solid year-to-date and third quarter financial results. Product sales for the third quarter were $2.36 billion, an increase of 14% year over year. The U.S. contributed $1.4 billion to product sales, up 20% year over year, driven by strong retail demand and the expansion of our HIV franchise. Europe contributed $781 million to product sales, up 5% year over year and flat sequentially due to purchasing patterns related to the summer holidays.</p>
          <p>From an expense standpoint, non-GAAP R&amp;D expenses increased to $384 million, up 42% year over year, primarily due to the continued advancement of our product pipeline, and in particular the progression and expansion of our Phase 3 studies in both liver disease and oncology.</p>
          <p>Additionally, non-GAAP SG&amp;A expenses increased to $287 million, up 8% year over year, due to the ongoing growth of our business and an increase in the U.S. pharmaceutical excise tax, partially offset by lower bad debt expense. Sequentially, SG&amp;A expenses decreased 4% due to lower spending as a result of the European summer holidays, partially offset by investments in the launch of Stribild.</p>
          <p>Operating cash flows were $745 million. Recall that last quarter's operating cash flows of $1.29 billion included the receipt of approximately $460 million from collection of accounts receivable in Spain.</p>
          <p>Turning to financial guidance, given the strong year-to-date commercial performance, we are increasing product sales guidance for full-year 2012 to $9.1 billion to $9.2 billion, which represents a $200 million increase from the top end of our previous guidance range. The full-year 2012 diluted EPS impact of acquisition related restructuring and stock-based compensation expenses is now expected to be in the range of $0.62 to $0.65 per share, primarily due to changes in anticipated payments associated with the successful progression of our oncology and non-HCV liver pipeline. All other aspects of our non-GAAP guidance for 2012 remain unchanged.</p>
          <p>In closing, we are pleased with our financial performance during the quarter and are looking forward to closing out a strong fiscal year 2012.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Kevin Young.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Robin.</p>
          <p>I have been very pleased over the course of 2012 with the execution of the commercial organization. The third quarter was the strongest in Gilead's history, with solid performances across all therapeutic areas. The antiviral franchise grew by 13% year over year and delivered over $2 billion in product sales, while cardiovascular products delivered quarterly sales of over $200 million for the first time. HIV sales in the U.S. were particularly robust and grew by 19% year over year.</p>
          <p>As we anticipated, following record non-retail purchases in quarter one and quarter two of 2012, quarter three non-retail sales were down sequentially. At this point, midway through the federal fiscal year, it would seem that budgets will allow for continued healthy ordering, assuming little or no rollover is allowed beyond March 2013. The latest update from NASTAD shows a total wait list of approximately 100 individuals across all states, down from a high of nearly 9,300 in September 2011.</p>
          <p>We were very pleased to be in a position to launch Stribild immediately after receiving U.S. FDA approval on August 27. Upon its launch, Stribild became our first priority detail. Uptake of the product in the first few weeks of launch has been extremely encouraging. Prescriptions are almost two times better than Complera at a similar point in launch. New to brand patient starts on Stribild have surpassed Reyataz are already approaching the level of Atripla and Prezista.</p>
          <p>Access to Stribild far exceeds that of where Complera was two months after launch. Most managed care organizations now list Stribild without restrictions. Forty-seven state Medicaid plans and 37 AIDS drug assistance programs now have Stribild on formulary. Importantly, four of the big five ADAPs [AIDS Drug Assistance Programs] have full access to Stribild.</p>
          <p>We also continue to be pleased with the U.S. uptake of Complera, which sold $82 million in the third quarter. Complera is the second most prescribed HIV regimen in na&#xEF;ve patients and the fifth most prescribed HIV regimen in all patients.</p>
          <p>Turning briefly to Europe, even though the third quarter is traditionally affected every year by summer holidays, especially in southern Europe, we posted a very solid set of results. Eviplera is now in the market in 14 countries across Europe, with France and Belgium being the latest to launch. We anticipate availability in the two major HIV markets of Spain and Italy in the fourth quarter of 2012 and the first quarter of 2013 respectively.</p>
          <p>For the first time, total na&#xEF;ve share of Gilead products in the big five European markets exceeded 80% during quarter three. Total utilization of single-tablet regimens for na&#xEF;ve patients was boosted by Eviplera to a new high of nearly 30%. Eviplera is now the number two regimen in HIV na&#xEF;ve patients in the UK and Germany.</p>
          <p>To conclude, Gilead delivered another good quarter. As we enter the final months of 2012 and plan for 2013, we can have confidence in an array of growth drivers across our products and across our geographies.</p>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to John Martin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kevin.</p>
          <p>During the third quarter, significant progress was made in our development programs. As Kevin mentioned, Stribild is the first integrase inhibitor containing single-tablet regimen to receive U.S. FDA approval. FDA has accepted the NDAs for two of the components, cobicistat and elvitegravir, and confirmed PDUFA dates of April 28, 2013 and April 27, 2013 respectively.</p>
          <p>For Complera, results from an 841-patient head-to-head study versus Atripla will be presented at the 11th International Congress on Drug Therapy and HIV Infection meeting in Glasgow next month. This is the first head-to-head study of Complera versus Atripla as the previous Phase 3 studies supporting approval of Complera compared rilpivirine plus Truvada to efavirenz plus Truvada. Also at the Glasgow meeting, 48-week data will be reported from a 482-patient study, in which patients on a stable ritonavir boosted PI regimen were randomized to either switch to Complera or stay on the boosted PI regimen. Both these large studies were initiated with the intent to be included in the Complera label. The latter is particularly important because 40% of U.S. patients currently initiating Complera have switched from a PI-containing regimen.</p>
          <p>GS-7340, a novel pro-drug of tenofovir dosed at one-tenth the dose of Viread, was co-formulated with emtricitabine, cobicistat, and elvitegravir into a single pill. This GS-7340-containing single-tablet regimen is being directly compared to Stribild in a Phase 2 study. Twenty-four week data from this study will become available in November. If the results are positive, we anticipate moving this GS-7340-containing single-tablet regimen into Phase 3 in the first half of 2013.</p>
          <p>In HCV, there will be a number of presentations at the AASLD [American Association for the Study of Liver Diseases] meeting in Boston next month, highlighting the safety, efficacy, and resistance profile of GS-7977 and a variety of combinations in HCV-infected individuals. Noteworthy, GS-7977 will be the subject of two oral late-breaker presentations. One presentation will also show safety and efficacy data from a collaborative study with BMS of GS-7977 and daclatasvir with and without ribavirin for 12 weeks in genotype-1 infected patients.</p>
          <p>The second presentation is on a collaborative study with the NIH and will show data on the safety and efficacy of GS-7977 with once-daily versus twice-daily ribavirin for 24 weeks in genotype-1 HCV infected individuals. In addition, an oral presentation will provide an update on the ELECTRON study and include results of the GS-7977 plus GS-5885 plus ribavirin 12-week arm in genotype-1 treatment na&#xEF;ve patients. Both the late-breaker and the oral presentations will include data at the time of the AASLD conference &#x2013; current tests at the AASLD conference.</p>
          <p>All four GS-7977 Phase 3 studies are fully enrolled. The results of the first study, POSITRON, which evaluates 12 weeks of GS-7977 plus ribavirin in genotype-2/3 interferon ineligible intolerant patients, should be available in early December, with results of the other studies to follow in the first quarter of next year. This will enable regulatory filings for GS-7977 in the second quarter of 2013.</p>
          <p>A single-tablet regimen of GS-7977 and GS-5885 for genotype-1 infected patients has advanced to Phase 3 with the first patient dose last week. This is a four-arm study evaluating the FDC [Fixed Dose Combination] in 800 patients with or without ribavirin for 12 and 24 weeks. Initially, 200 of the 800 patients will be enrolled. Following an interim analysis of the SVR4 results of the 12-week arms, the remaining 600 patients will be enrolled.</p>
          <p>In oncology, a Phase 2 study evaluating GS-1101 in double-refractory iNHL [indolent Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma] patients closed for screening on October 10 with 120 patients enrolled. Depending on results and FDA concurrence, this iNHL study could form the basis for accelerated approval. More likely, however, approval will be based on data from ongoing Phase 3 studies.</p>
          <p>Five Phase 3 studies of GS-1101 in CLL [Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia] and iNHL are progressing. Two studies which are currently enrolling patients evaluate GS-1101 with rituximab or with rituximab and bendamustine in CLL. A third study evaluating GS-1101 with ofatumumab in CLL and two Phase 3 studies evaluating GS-1101 in combination with rituximab and with rituximab and bendamustine in iNHL will initiate later this year.</p>
          <p>In summary, the last few months of the year promise to be as busy and productive as the first three quarters have been. We are poised to continue making terrific progress for Gilead, for employees, and importantly for the patients we serve.</p>
          <p>We would now like to turn the call over to Q&amp;A. Operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And our first question comes from the line of Geoff Meacham with JPMorgan. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys, thanks for taking the question and congrats on the quarter. I have just a couple for Kevin and then one for Norbert. For Kevin, I know it's early on Stribild. But are you guys seeing uptake at the expense of PIs, and how much of a driver do you think the switching studies will be with respect to share?</p>
          <p>And then for Norbert, you guys have talked about the GS-7977/GS-5885 combo study on the last call. I wanted just to know if anything has changed and how you're thinking about the second pivotal study. What types of patients, what types of design do you think you'll employ, things like that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Geoff. This is Kevin. Thanks for the question. We are pleased with the progress so far on Stribild. It is early days, almost two months of launch. The sales you saw in Q3 were very much inventory fill for the wholesalers, and that's a very similar amount to the amount we put out a year ago when we launched Complera.</p>
          <p>I think we're particularly pleased with the access that we've got. It's very much quicker than we had for Complera. The ADAP programs particularly have taken up Stribild, and we almost have five of five. We're just waiting for a signature to have the fifth of the big five ADAP programs have coverage of Stribild. There are twice as many prescriptions for Stribild as Complera, so it's running ahead of Complera. It's running ahead of the uptake of Prezista. It's more looking like an uptake of Isentress.</p>
          <p>So I think overall, we would consider the launch here of Stribild more Atripla-like and less Complera-like. Obviously, you don't have the bolus of conversions that Atripla had. But Isentress has probably a little bit more been used in the na&#xEF;ve setting than in the switch setting. But our other sense, and again, it's early, is that the uptake is probably coming at the expense of the protease inhibitors, as per your comment earlier. So it seems to more have been used in the na&#xEF;ve setting than switch. The switch data will help and having in the label will help. But the team &#x2013; our expanded team is very much positioning this as the preferred regimen for upfront use in new patients as an alternative to Atripla and as an alternative to the boosted protease inhibitors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Geoffrey, with regard to your question about the Phase 3 program, the big answer is no, nothing has changed. As John mentioned, the first Phase 3 study, the first patient was dosed last week. And just to underscore the rapidity of involvement, we actually had to close the study for screening last week as well because we had enough patients in screening so that we can enroll the first 200. So we're going to take a look at this, the two 12-week arms, sometime in the first quarter next year, probably March. And then we'll make a decision as to whether we're going to continue to randomize patients in this study.</p>
          <p>And then with regards to the other study, keep in mind. We have other data coming in. Two data sets will be presented at AALSD. One of them is the 12-week arms of the Bristol-Myers daclatasvir/GS-7977 combination, and another one is the GS-7977/GS-5885/ribavirin in genotype-1 na&#xEF;ve patients in the ELECTRON study. Then we have a third arm in ELECTRON ongoing, GS-7977/GS-5885/ribavirin in genotype-1 null responders. We will take all this data into consideration; and based on that design, the second Phase 3 study, which would start pretty much at the latest around the same time as we're going to reopen this current study for re-randomization and reenrollment.</p>
          <p>But just briefly, this could be a very simple potentially one-arm study with a 12-week arm, depending on the outcome. It could also include treatment-experienced patients depending on what the data look like of the combination in the null responders with Ed Gane. So I hope that answers the question. So it will all become clearer over the next two to three months what the nature and the design of that second Phase 3 study is going to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's really helpful. As just a quick follow-up, Norbert...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Geoff, Geoff, that's three questions already. We're going to have to move on to somebody else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Matt Roden with UBS. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks for taking the question and congrats on the quarter, a question for Norbert on GS-7340. Is it reasonable for us to think about potential to lower the incidence of renal adverse events with GS-7340 versus the standard of care? How many patients do you think would need to be treated and for how long to really start to tease out whether or not there's a difference here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Matt, that's exactly what we're hoping to be able to show. So essentially, GS-7340 is the same active ingredient as is in Viread, but it's dosed at one-tenth the dose. And they always said unless you believe in homeopathy, it's reasonable to assume that this compound has better tolerability and safety. And the two things in particular are BMD and creatinine clearance changes. I personally think that BMD changes are easier to show because simply we saw about a 2% net BMD loss with Viread across a whole number of studies. And if this compound is better, then it should be easier to show statistically.</p>
          <p>With regards to creatinine clearance, it really depends on the effect size and the variability. But we think in a Phase 3 study, you should actually be able to show that. And this will become clearer, by the way, as John Martin said in his script, we should actually get the final 24-week Phase 2 data from the first study in a month or so, and then it should become clearer what the powering will be for the Phase 3 study.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Michael Yee with RBC Capital Markets. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thanks. My question is just for Norbert. Obviously, we've seen a lot of the data come out recently from late breakers 12 and 24 weeks with and without ribavirin from some other oral compounds. Maybe since that has always been a question as to whether duration with and without ribavirin matter, maybe you could hypothesize or speculate how you're thinking about that data and whether that changes your thinking since you found some answers from other drugs recently.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, I don't think I have a good answer for you. So as you may have seen also from our abstracts, one of them on resistance of GS-7977 that's going to be at AASLD, we have never seen a breakthrough on GS-7977 and, with one single exception, we have never seen resistance. And the one single exception was when GS-7977 was used by itself without anything else. So given that, then I would &#x2013; you would expect that treatment duration should matter. If you don't develop resistance, you don't have breakthrough and you don't achieve 100% response with 12 weeks, if you think about it, going for 24 weeks should increase that response rate. Now that's theoretical. In the few instances where we have actually tested that, we didn't see that. So that, unfortunately, is the only thing I can tell you. I can't quite make sense out of the treatment duration yet. I think it should become clearer once we see the Bristol-Myers data and also our Phase 3 results where we're directly comparing in a large sample size 12 versus 24 weeks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on ribavirin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So you know what? Michael, what overall it looks like is that GS-7977 is a very potent compound, but by itself it's not quite enough. You have to add something else. Now if you add ribavirin, it will bring the response rates up to a very respectable 80% to 90% to 100%, but not in all populations. Particularly, you may remember, in genotype-1 it's not 100%. And in null responders, it's not 100%. But ribavirin from a virological point of view adds actually very minimal efficacy. So I think by adding something a little bit more potent to it like, for instance, an NS5A, as has been shown by the Bristol-Myers data, you get 100% response rate, so that's how I look at GS-7977. It's a very potent compound, not quite enough by itself, so you have to add at least one other at least semi-potent antiviral to it like a PI or an NS5A or an NS5B.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Rachel McMinn with Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks very much. So I just wanted to better understand strategy in HCV when we think about dual therapy versus triple therapy. And, Norbert, I did listen to your comment on ribavirin, but I was curious as to how you're thinking about GS-9669. So you've talked about that as being a third agent, but you don't seem to be aggressively developing a safety database around that. And then just separate from all that, I'm curious on when you might consider starting an eight-week study with GS-7977 in either genotype-1 or genotype-2/3. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Rachel, with regards to GS-9669, it's one of the most potent non-nuc [non-nucleoside] NS5B inhibitors that has been described, very well behaved compound. Once daily seems to be safe. The reason why we're not as aggressively pursuing it is simple, because we're not quite sure what the place is in hep C therapy. We have GS-5885 with a PI. We have in preclinical in the works, a [ph] Phase 3 (26:30) NS5A inhibitor. So we're just not sure of what the role of GS-9669 is. So we are doing, as I'm sure you know, two cohorts in ELECTRON that look at GS-9669 with GS-7977 and ribavirin both in genotype-1 na&#xEF;ve and null responders, and I'm sure those data will look very good. But again, we're struggling with this issue where GS-9669 fits.</p>
          <p>I want to mention something. One role that I think triple combination therapy could have, if you shorten the treatment duration, so let's say you get really good results with two agents and you shorten the treatment duration and at one point reach a duration where the response is suboptimal, then it's conceivable by adding a third agent, then you're going to again get good responses. So that's a line of experiments that we're pursuing. And with regards to GS-7977 for shorter treatment duration than 12 weeks, there's actually one presentation at AASLD that's going to be in Ed Gane's oral where he's looking at GS-7977/ribavirin for eight weeks in genotype-2/3. So that will give you some indication of we're thinking about, depending on the outcome of the other cohorts in ELECTRON, about looking at the GS-5885/GS-7977/ribavirin combination with a shorter than 12-week treatment duration, but there's nothing definite yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Mark Schoenebaum with ISI Group. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. Hey, first of all, I want to say congrats to Patrick on landing Susan's job. I didn't put that eloquently, but you know what I mean, congratulations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, since its one question, I'll respect that. I just want to clarify. Are you gays going to give us the interim data from Phase 3 in the 1Q? It just seems to me like that is of monumental importance. Obviously, everyone is going to go to AASLD and look at your GS-5885/GS-7977/ribavirin 12-week data. But the really important data set is that 200-patient interim. Are you committed to giving that SVR4 data to Wall Street in 1Q when you have it? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, this is something we are still debating internally. On the one hand, we realize the importance of the data for the financial community. On the other hand, you have to be cognizant of the fact that this is an ongoing randomized study. And we can't really &#x2013; we would be influencing the conduct of this study potentially if we announced to the world the interim analysis. So it's something we're thinking about. I think there might be other cohorts available at that time that would answer the question. So we would make those available publicly and not make available the actual interim analysis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So sorry, what are the other cohorts, Norbert?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's still in the planning stage, but we're thinking about initiating one or two other cohorts that would answer that same question that you have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Cohorts in the Phase 3 or in the Phase 2, and I'll get off?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cohorts in Phase 2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see. Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Brian Abrahams with Wells Fargo Securities. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking my question. Continuing on the hep C front, what do you guys see as the bar for SVRs for both na&#xEF;ves and nulls that would optimize the commercial opportunity just given some of the competitive data we've seen unfold? And how much weight should we place on the predictive value of what we see coming out of ELECTRON, and then just lastly if you have any updates on the disclosure plan for what the ELECTRON nulls are? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Brian. It's Kevin. I wouldn't give you a pinpoint target of a threshold for SVR. And let's not forget, I think it should be SVR12 because those are the endpoints of the study. But clearly, you've got to be very high these days. There are going to be a number of regimens from a number of companies that are going to have high SVRs, and I think it also includes Gilead in that comment.</p>
          <p>My personal feeling is that as we get towards launch that other parameters in addition to SVR will come to play, the simplicity and the convenience of the regimens and the tolerability. And that's why approaches like GS-5885 plus GS-7977 plus ribavirin or no ribavirin becomes very attractive; at 12 weeks well tolerated. It almost becomes a Complera or Stribild approach over a three-month period. So I think we are going to see high SVRs from a number of different approaches, different molecules. But I actually think the addition of the other parameters are going to be important in the real world, particularly beyond the specialist hepatology clinic when you start to go into the general gastro treatment in the community and potentially other physicians beyond where the PIs are used today. Our expectation would be that the new regimens can go much further afield than the prescribing of telaprevir and boceprevir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And you asked as a sub-question. You said what is the predictability of ELECTRON cohorts. I think it's entirely predictable. Just keep in mind; you have to take it with a grain of salt because of the sample size. Some of the cohorts are 10, an N of 10, and others are N of 25. Neither one is particularly large; so just keep in mind, there is always variability.</p>
          <p>And secondly, you asked about a null responder disclosure. So when I talked to Ed Gane, he let me know that probably what would be available at the time of the AASLD presentation would be a total of three-patient SVR4. That's three out of ten, and we're a little bit debating internally. Is that worth showing because we don't want to mislead anybody one way or another if the result is a certain way, but it's an N of 3. Now that is a really small sample size.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much and my congrats to Pat as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Geoffrey Porges with Bernstein. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much for taking the question. Norbert, three patients would be enough to build whole companies in hep C. I just wanted to follow up with some of the questions about disclosure. Will you tell us about the results for GS-7340 in Q4, or will we just learn from the decision to start the pivotal trial? That seems important. And I'm just wondering, John, if you can give us an update on the prosecution of the patents for the combination products, whether there's any news there. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are actually planning on letting the financial community know about the results from the Phase 2 study because, Jeff, as you correctly pointed out, it has a direct consequence. If the results look promising, we would, of course, move into Phase 3, and that's something that will become public one way or another at one point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeff, the second part of your question is we don't have any update on the prosecution of the combination patents. But if that proceeds or changes, of course, we will update you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Yaron Werber with Citibank. Please proceed &#x2013; Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. So question, Norbert, just for you, I just want to follow up to really understand a little bit. You're going to have data it sounds like imminently from the Bristol combo, which is going to give you a sense of whether you need riba or not and whether 12 weeks is enough. And it sounds like from what you're saying, it sounds like you guys are feeling pretty optimistic 12 weeks is enough. And if I'm reading correctly, maybe even riba is not adding much, so I'm trying to understand. Then you're going to have data from the triple for 12 weeks from ELECTRON, but that's not a huge sample. Where I'm going with this is, is this enough for your and then have by March, you're going to have preliminary, it sounds like, SVR4 at least from your current Phase 3. Is that enough at that point to make a determination that the Phase 3 is only going to be 12 weeks? And if so, when do you think you can file for an all-oral for genotype-1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely that will be enough. So the argument that we always made and that we firmly believe in that daclatasvir and GS-5885 are very similar compounds at least in genotype-1. They're very potent, similar potency against genotype-1a/1b, behave similarly against polymorphs with really one exception. But in that polymorph, the Y93 agent is still way above &#x2013; the IQ [Inhibitory Quotient] is still a factor of six, so very potent. The only thing we're missing right now is a clinical proof of that, and that will come from ELECTRON. So what ELECTRON would do for us if the data looked promising, that would absolutely prove that it would establish the link between daclatasvir and GS-5885. That together with, as I said, the null responder data from ELECTRON and the Bristol-Myers data will give us enough confidence to design the second Phase 3 study.</p>
          <p>And then if we get the interim analysis &#x2013; by the way, the sample size again is not huge. It's 100 of the two 12-week arms, so 50 per arm. And again, this all has to hang together and be confirmed on top of each other. But each study ideally confirms the other and we would have then enough pieces of evidence that we would feel very comfortable designing the second Phase 3 study. It's essentially ELECTRON, Bristol-Myers, and our own Phase 3 study. Those are the three studies that if you add up the number of patients, about 130 total, and that's enough to give you confidence to go into Phase 3.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And at that point, when do you think you can file for an all-oral if you start the study let's say early Q2?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Yaron, you can do your own calculation. It has a very rapid enrollment, 12 weeks of treatment if that's what the treatment duration is, 12 weeks of SVR12 follow-up. And add to that three to four months for filing and another eight months for approval if it's a priority review and 12 months if it's not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Robyn Karnauskas with Deutsche Bank. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Thanks for taking my question. I guess first, you show that Atripla trends are flat. I wondered if you can comment a little bit about what you're seeing in Atripla and with Atripla use.</p>
          <p>And second, just to follow up to Mark's question on the arms that you might be adding in Phase 2 that might give us a hint about Phase 3, are you talking about maybe adding 24-week arms or maybe non-riba arms to the ELECTRON trial? Is that what you're implying, additional arms in perhaps ELECTRON that would give us a read by March as far as how Phase 3 might be shaping up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Robyn, I will answer your second question quickly before Kevin answers the first. I don't want to get into that because it would give away &#x2013; it would preempt some the data that you're going to see at AASLD. I think once you see the data at AASLD, it will be more evident what we're thinking about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Robyn, thanks for the question. Atripla is coming down. Let me try and give you just a couple of benchmarks. The Q2 Ipsos or Synovate data has Atripla at 34% of the na&#xEF;ve market. Truvada is 31% and Complera is at 25%, so that gives you a total of about 90% for Gilead, so what you have seen before. But clearly, the mix is changing, so Atripla has progressively over the last five quarters come off its high. Another marker in terms of change is that Complera gets 25% of its prescriptions from Atripla switch. So you can see that there is Atripla switching, more than likely because of tolerability, the CNS side effects of efavirenz coming across to Complera.</p>
          <p>The only other thing I would add, Robyn, is that the shift that you saw in the actual product sales in Q3 versus Q2, that was largely because of the non-retail. That was largely because of ADAP ordering. ADAP ordered quite large quantities in Q1 and Q2 this year of Atripla. They were relatively quiet on Atripla in Q3. So the actual product sale changes that you saw there were largely the result of the phasing of ADAP purchase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Marshall Urist with Morgan Stanley. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys, thanks for taking the question, so just one, Kevin, if you could give us a sense of how you think the dynamics between Complera and Stribild will play out. It seems like Complera has obviously outperformed I think a lot of people's expectations. So what's the impact between those two?</p>
          <p>And, Norbert, maybe just a slightly different question which is, has the data that we've seen from Abbott and others changed your perspective or your thinking, or at least what is your current thinking on the importance of getting rid of riba in dual therapy from the initial &#x2013; for the initial Phase 3 regimen? Or given the competitors, is there a little bit less pressure you think competitively to drop riba at this point? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Marshall. Complera we're very pleased with. I think we've proven that if you put rilpivirine with a good backbone in a single tablet, it can do very well. And we particularly hear anecdotal feedback from physicians on the tolerability, how well patients like Complera. So it has done very nicely in real clinical practice. However, Stribild in our first detail. We are positioning Stribild as first-line therapy in the vast majority of patients. So you would expect that Stribild would quickly become the lead product in the na&#xEF;ve setting. Our label is na&#xEF;ve, so you would expect it to take over.</p>
          <p>One just small piece of information that wasn't included in the script that I think is nice to add for Stribild is that we have had a late-breaker accepted at the Glasgow HIV meeting on our 96-week data, so that will be presented there. And then hopefully, we'll get that into publication quite quickly for Stribild. And then we hope going into 2013 that that will be helpful eventually for moving Stribild into a preferred setting and guideline. So the profile of Stribild is likely to become stronger. So I think we've got a very good number one product in Stribild. We're getting the data on switching for Complera, and that could well become I think a very strong second switch product. The good news in all of this is that I think we've got two options in Stribild and Complera that are superior to Atripla. So I think it's a very good position that we're in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Marshall, with regards to the competition, that's an important question that I would like to comment on it. So first of all, Abbott has a viable regimen. They obviously came to the conclusion that they needed all five agents, differing only in terms of treatment duration, 12 versus 24 weeks. But I want to mention that what we do and the urgency that we feel is not really determined by what the competition does, but rather by where we ultimately want to go with the therapy. And our goal has always been to have one pill once daily without ribavirin, and I think that's entirely possible and that's what we're pursuing. So at one point, ribavirin will disappear. People won't use it anymore because of the obvious issues. Its BID causes anemia and you don't have to use it. You wouldn't use it. And that, I think, we are going to achieve. The question is when and with what regimen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Ian Somaiya with Piper Jaffray. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I just wanted to follow up with Norbert on your longer-term vision on hep C. I think you mentioned the goal of moving to a once daily, one-pill regimen. Can you help us think about &#x2013; is the next step an addition of a third pill, a third drug that you would co-formulate into a single pill, or would it be a different combination, different &#x2013; let's say switching out your NS5A with something else?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Ian, again, I think it's clear. If you just look at the Bristol-Myers data that were presented at EASL [European Association for the Study of the Liver] that you can have two drugs, in that case daclatasvir and GS-7977. Dosed for 24 weeks get you 100% response rates in genotype-1. I didn't give you that number in genotype-2/3 for obvious reasons because daclatasvir and also our own NS5A inhibitor is really not optimized for genotype-2/3. We have very early in development a [indiscernible] (46:10) NS5A that at lease virologically looks just absolutely wonderful. It's a compound that works against all genotypes, against most polymorphs, and we think that will be the simple answer to a one-pill once daily for all genotypes.</p>
          <p>The only thing I would like to say, Ian, you said about three drugs. The only role I can see for three drugs is if you wanted to further shorten the treatment duration, so it's possible, even though the concept hasn't been shown that you could, for instance, get away with ten weeks of treatment with three drugs whereas if you had two drugs, you needed 12 or 16 weeks. That's where I'm seeing the role of a third drug. But if you have two good drugs, you can actually &#x2013; that's enough. That will suffice to cure most hep C genotypes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have a sense of timelines for the NS5A that you have in preclinical development, when that could move into the clinic and when ultimately we can see that in the marketplace?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's too early really for me to speculate on that. We're thinking about disclosing that sometime at a future conference. We haven't really decided when yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Brian Skorney with Brean, Murray. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon, guys. Thanks for taking my question. I'll jump a little off-page and actually ask a question on GS-1101 and just the potential plans for a fileable single-arm study. I just think the response rate, as I recall, in Phase 1 in indolent NHL was about 57%, but I think that included a number of higher than 150 mg BID doses. I just wonder. Have you guys broken out the responses to 150 mgs specifically for these patients? And what should we think of as a potentially fileable hurdle for this study? Is it reasonable to think of relapsed refractory indolent NHL as equivalent to other relapsed refractory hematological malignancies, or given that it's indolent, would we anticipate a closer look at a PFS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian, actually I don't think we have broken it out by dose. But as you noted, the current 120-patient Phase 2 study that John talked about in iNHL is fully enrolled. We will look at response rates very soon. And the only thing that we don't know yet and what is equally important is the duration of response, and the reason is we just haven't followed enough patients out for a long period of time. That will sometime happen next spring. But I also would like to caution you. We think it's unlikely that we will get approval or we'll even file under a single-arm study. It's more likely we will get approval based on the Phase 3 studies that are enrolling.</p>
          <p>One last comment about response rates and what's required; you may want to look at carfilzomib that got approved on a single-arm study. It was a different disease in myeloma, but the response rate overall was 22% and the duration of response was eight months. And I think it's probably an exception, but if we have something north of that, then we would definitely approach the FDA and see what they think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess that goes back to my question, and I was thinking about carfilzomib specifically. But do you think that the relapsed refractory indolent NHL population meets the same hurdles as the relapsed refractory myeloma population in terms of not really having &#x2013; exhausting all resources out there, especially with maybe increased use of bendamustine and rituximab now than previous years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Brian, they do with one caveat. So they do in the sense that they were relapsed refractory to anti-CD20s and cytotoxics or bendamustine, rituximab. One potential argument that you could use to say they are not unmet need is because these people have not been treated with radioimmunotherapy. And of course, the counter argument is nobody uses that. That was something that was brought up at the Advisory Committee meeting by Anderson. So again, this is something we don't know what the FDA would think. What they say, these people have not exhausted all their options yet because radioimmunotherapy hasn't been used or would they accept the previous relapsed response to cytotoxics and anti-CD20s; that's the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Norbert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Thomas Wei with Jefferies. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks. I wanted to ask a hep C question, just an update on how you're thinking about the genotype-1 cirrhotic population. How competitive do you think you're going to be there relative to some of the other companies that seem to be expediting development in that population? And how much more work do you need to define the right duration and regimen for cirrhotics?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Thomas, for your question. Thomas, we're actually pursuing that in all our Phase 3 studies, so all our studies mandate at least 20% cirrhotics. And actually in one study, the POSITRON study that you will hear about this year, the results, that study involved 30% cirrhotics, so we are actively addressing that question. And we always had as a goal to have a representative sample of patients in our Phase 3 study that represents the patients that are actually going to be treated, and a lot of those are cirrhotic. So those are included in all our studies, in our Phase 4 &#x2013; Phase 3 studies that are currently ending or coming to an end. And they will also be included in the GS-7977/GS-5885 fixed-dose combination.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Tony Butler with Barclays Capital. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the question. I'll be brief. Norbert, just again on cirrhotics, you did make reference to the notion that the only way you would think or you would hypothesize that a three-drug regimen would be necessary would be due to duration. Does that imply that you think that a fixed-dose two-drug combination would be sufficient for cirrhotics, or are you still leaving that door open?</p>
          <p>And then very quickly to Kevin, I'm respectful of the Stribild label for the na&#xEF;ve setting. But why would it not erode or dampen the Complera demand, especially when Stribild is in first-line, at least on those Atripla switches? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tony, you're right. In terms of special populations, we may have realized that certain populations you can't &#x2013; two drugs are not sufficient. You may need three drugs. But again, I want to point back to our observation that we have to this date never seen a virological breakthrough on GS-7977, not one for all our patients that were null responders or rebounders. Again, that convinces me that it's a function of duration of therapy rather than the number of drugs that are needed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Kevin, it's a very good point you make around dampening the uptake of Complera/Eviplera. That's certainly the case in the na&#xEF;ve setting. It might have an effect in the switch setting. Of course, if people are on Atripla, then they've already been taking an NNRTI. And if it's a tolerability issue, it's a simple switch from one NNRTI to another, simply based on the CNS. One area that we haven't talked about and we'll be waiting for data, and of course again, it's a label situation is that we have done the switching study from Truvada plus Isentress, so raltegravir. And there are over 50,000 patients on that regimen today, so I think that's more likely a potential switch in the situation that the doctor takes that decision individually to do that. So I think for Stribild, it's more likely a PI switch or a Truvada/Isentress switch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Kevin. Thank you, Norbert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Alan Carr with Needham &amp; Company. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking my question, just a quick one. Could you comment on the share buyback activity and strategy as well as managing the debt as well? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Alan. So we did repurchase shares. That's actually outlined in the deck that we provided. Our focus in terms of our share repurchase program is secondary to paying down the debt, so we actually slightly underachieved offsetting dilution this quarter. I think it was slightly under $200 million or so that we repurchased.</p>
          <p>In terms of the Pharmasset debt paydown, we are focused on paying down the short-term debt. We paid about $350 million down this quarter to bring our debt-to-EBITDA down to about 2.2 times. Our goal is by mid-2013 to get it to 1.5 times. That's our target.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from the line of Joel Sendek with Stifel, Nicolaus. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks a lot, so HIV question. I'm wondering on this Stribild launch whether you encountered any pushback on reimbursement given the price. And also regarding Europe, I'm wondering why the franchise is growing a little bit slower. I understand this particular quarter's issue. But if you look at each of the last couple quarters, it has not been growing that much. I'm wondering if there are any other reasons why. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Joel. This is Kevin. I couldn't be happier with actually the access to Stribild. To have 37 ADAP programs and four of the big five already in a little under two months is where we were really with Atripla. It's very much quicker than what we had with Complera, so we're really having very, very good acceptance. And just as a reminder, the pricing of Stribild is lower than the boosted protease inhibitor, so that's quite appealing to managed care, not by a large amount, but it is lower. So managed care likes that, so we priced it very competitively from a regimen cost point of view.</p>
          <p>When it comes to Europe, Joel, it isn't easy out there. I think we do well because we've got specialist products. HIV requires treatment. We have a great deal of support from physicians. We have good payer support and we've got good advocacy. But some of the markets are tough. Any pharmaceutical company will tell you that, particularly some in Europe. Our business in the likes of Spain and Portugal, Italy are holding up I think pretty well. So it might look a little bit quieter in terms of growth in the U.S. But on a relative basis, I actually think we're doing remarkably well. So Europe, there are still some stresses and there are still some challenges there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. O'Brien, at this point we have run out of time for additional questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ann, and thank you all for joining us today. We appreciate your continued interest in Gilead, and the team here looks forward to providing you with updates on future progress. Thanks again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation, and you may now disconnect. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>