<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1207597" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-02-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3179</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Fr&#xE9;deric Oud&#xE9;a, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Didier Valet, Group Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Robin Down</participant>
      <participant id="4">Fr&#xE9;deric Oud&#xE9;a</participant>
      <participant id="5">Didier Valet</participant>
      <participant id="6">Alessandro Roccati</participant>
      <participant id="7">Michel P&#xE9;reti&#xE9;</participant>
      <participant id="8">Guillaume Tiberghien</participant>
      <participant id="9">Pascal Decque</participant>
      <participant id="10">Pierre Flabbee</participant>
      <participant id="11">Didier Alix</participant>
      <participant id="12">Jean Pierre Lambert</participant>
      <participant id="13">S&#xE9;verin Cabannes</participant>
      <participant id="14">Jean-Pierre Sommadossi</participant>
      <participant id="15">Eric Vanpoucke</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale Fourth Quarter and Full Year 2008 Results Conference Call. The presentation, hosted by Mr. Fr&#xE9;deric Oud&#xE9;a, Chief Executive Officer and Mr. Didier Valet, Chief Financial Officer will be followed by a question-and-answer session. We inform you that the question will be taken first in the auditorium and then from the participant in the conference call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>Now, I would like to hand over to Mr. Oud&#xE9;a. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. So, let's kick off and good evening to everyone. And I'm delighted to have the opportunity with my colleagues, S&#xE9;verin Cabannes, Deputy CEO in charge of the Resource department, Finance and Risk; Didier Valet, CFO; Michel P&#xE9;reti&#xE9;, Head of the CIB and Jean-Pierre Mustier, Head of Global Investment Management and Services to comment on our yearly results for 2008 and of course, answer your questions. I will leave the floor in a minute to Didier.</p>
          <p>Let me just tell you that clearly 2008 was for the financial sector as a whole a difficult year. We had also in Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale to cope with the fraud at the beginning of 2008. I think we managed this accident well. And let me just take the opportunity to say that the remediation plan is moving on target. You know that we will comment on that more in detail during our Annual Shareholder Meeting on the 19th of May.</p>
          <p>More structurally and more importantly, we had of course, to weather the storm which started with the bankruptcy of Lehman in September and I think which effectively triggered the crisis, which has never been seen on the financial market in the fourth quarter and certainly, is a milestone for a new environment, a new world for the financial markets and more generally, the worldwide economy.</p>
          <p>Overall in 2008, one of the key lessons that I draw is that we have had a good commercial performance despite this environment, in particular, in the French retail with good resilience of our franchise. We again, suffered at the beginning of &#x2013; during this year &#x2013; of 2008 from the fraud, the impact on the image, but again, have posted good results overall.</p>
          <p>We had also very good results in the retail activities outside France, including in the fourth quarter. We decided in the fourth quarter nevertheless to book what I would call the prudent goodwill impairment of &#x20AC;300 million of our Russian operations.</p>
          <p>In Financial Services, the performance remains also decent. These businesses were affected by the downturn &#x2013; by the economic downturn, especially at the year-end in the consumer finance. And we had to also book a foreign exchange loss in Ukraine for &#x20AC;92 million. But overall, there was a good resilience of the results.</p>
          <p>In Global Investment Management and Services, as in previous quarters, we have mixed performances at the year-end with poor performance in Asset Management, which was impacted by the crisis. You know that we had &#x2013; we reviewed this business and decided to make a strategic move with the announcement of a transaction between Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole Asset Management and SGAM. We also decided to merge the SGAM AI operations with Lyxor and to sell our UK franchise.</p>
          <p>In Corporate and Investment Banking, I think that we have also showed very good resilience. And it's the second best historical commercial performance in 2008 with clients' revenues up 7%, compared with 2006. We of course, had to monitor a very difficult market environment in the trading activities. But overall, I think we have been able to show that putting aside non-recurrent items, the performance was also good. And I think in the fourth quarter, we will have to wait for more results. But we have probably fared a bit better this storm, and I think it was a real stress test for our market risk management teams.</p>
          <p>One of our priorities is really to carry on reshaping this business to put even more emphasis on the client activities and effectively further reduce our risk. And Michel can comment on that more in detail.</p>
          <p>I must say that I am very positive on these activities. Again, the consolidation has taken place very quickly in this business, but we are benefiting from that. We see clients coming to us. We can enhance businesses and franchise. The start of the year is good on this business. I remain very prudent. It is just the start of the year, but all what we see currently confirms, if you wish, our strategic vision for Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale.</p>
          <p>All in all, we end up with 2008 with a net income of &#x20AC;2 billion, in line with our preannouncement at the end of January. We have used, let me just remind you, that we have used the IAS 39 amendment, as we said, in the fourth quarter, transferring for something like &#x20AC;28 billion of assets in the loan and receivable portfolio, which meant the neutralization of something like &#x20AC;1.5 billion on the Group NBI.</p>
          <p>The earnings per share stands at &#x20AC;3.38 per share. The Board has decided to propose to the shareholders a dividend of &#x20AC;1.2 per share. That corresponds to a payout ratio of 36% with a scrip dividend option. As you know, we cannot in the French regulations, decide for compulsory scrip dividend. We have the option and this option will be open to the shareholders.</p>
          <p>Taking this into account, the dividend into account, our Tier 1 ratio stands at 8.8% with a Core Tier 1 of 6.7%. That does not include the second tranche of public money that we can potentially draw till midyear. And with this money, we would have a Core Tier 1 standing at 9.3% on a pro forma basis at the beginning of this year. I think that reflects the strength of the Group at the beginning of 2009.</p>
          <p>So, now I am going to propose Didier to comment more in detail our results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I will speak on the next slide, the slide five, which just illustrates the storm that Fr&#xE9;deric mentioned that hurt the markets during the fourth quarter. And I would comment on slide six, which summarizes the income statement of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale in the fourth quarter and for the full year.</p>
          <p>And as you can see, the net banking income of the Group in the full year '08 went down modestly by 3.9% on a like-for-like basis, compared to '07. And the increase, compared to the fourth quarter of '07 was very strong, at plus 45%. But I remind you that in the fourth quarter of '07, we did book as a negative net banking account some markdowns on the CDO portfolio and on the monolines.</p>
          <p>The operating expenses did increase by 6.2% on a like-for-like basis. And as a result, the gross operating income of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale Group for the full year went down by 22%, compared to '07. Net allocation to provision for the year stands at almost &#x20AC;2.7 billion, a multiplication by 2.8 times. And I will go more into detail on these items on the next slide.</p>
          <p>The Group has decided in the fourth quarter to take an impairment charge on the goodwill on our Russian retail banking exposure. So, for &#x20AC;300 million, this lowers, let's say, the goodwill on the overall division; so BSGV, DeltaCredit and Rosbank from &#x20AC;1.1 billion before the impairment to something like &#x20AC;800 million after the impairment.</p>
          <p>As mentioned by Fr&#xE9;deric, we applied or we used the amendment IAS 39 at the beginning of the quarter, so the date was the 1 of October. The asset transfer were decided during the month of October, are being assessed, let's say, by our risk department to ensure that the impairment risk on these assets was limited, including the markdowns that we have taken in our books as of 30 of September. And so as a whole, we have transferred &#x20AC;28.6 billion and the neutralization of the negative mark-to-market impact in NBI was 1.5 billion for the quarter.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, I will comment a little bit more on the cost of risk for the quarter and for the year.</p>
          <p>So for the French network, as you can see, for the full year, the cost of risk stands at 36 bps, compared to 28 in '07. But as you can see also on the slide, there was an increase in the fourth quarter to 56 basis points, which underlines, let's say, the deterioration of the macroeconomic environment that we've seen in the fourth quarter with a worsening, let's say, of the provisioning level, especially on the business customer component.</p>
          <p>I should mention that on the household side, the cost of risk remains totally at a very low level, as we said, due to the very, let's say, central characteristic of the mortgage market in France.</p>
          <p>On the International Retail Banking activities, the cost of risk overall for the year stands at 73 bps, up, compared to last year when it was at 44. It does include Rosbank for the full year. Excluding Rosbank, the cost of risk would have been only 56 basis points. So, a mild deterioration, compared to '07. But as you can see also, in the fourth quarter, the cost of risk rose to 123 basis points. It was &#x2013; it would be 92 excluding Rosbank highlighting so, an increase in cost of risk in the region with Czech Republic and also, Russia having seen an increase during the quarter.</p>
          <p>On the financial services, the increase is in line with what we have seen in the previous quarter, with the impact of the mix evolution with a greater component of consumer loans as part of the total loan group. And within consumer loans, more emerging markets. We have seen a slight rise in the cost of risk, but very limited in Russia and Poland in the fourth quarter, but it's something like 20 to 30 bps, compared to the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>Last but not least, in the CIB, the cost of risk for the full year stands at 84 bps. For the sole fourth quarter, it's 116 basis points. It does include certain provisions for construction, commercial real estate, complements on some financial institutions, namely Icelandic banks that we have a provision at full 50% at the end of September. But we put the provisioning level at 100% at the end of this year, looking at the evolution of the CDS, which is currently trading at close to zero. We have taken, let's say, these adjustments. We have also taken the opportunity to strengthen the portfolio-based provisions of the Group during the quarter.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, just to highlight some characteristics of the portfolio of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. So, this is the Basel II new metrics, which is the exposure at default, which is also the sum of the loans drawn down in the balance sheet, plus the off-balance sheet's exposure with the credit conversion factors. So, the total exposure at default of the Group stands at &#x20AC;773 billion.</p>
          <p>As you can see, the French and European Union, European Economic Area part, that accounts for something like 75%. So, we are three-quarter exposed to EU, Western Europe and France. Within that, France is accounting for almost 45%. So, a little bit less than half. We have a credit exposure to the retail banking and financial services, which represents almost 50%.</p>
          <p>Within French Network, we have a quite important exposure to housing loans and private individuals. In international retail banking, the scope is well-diversified among 36 countries. And, last but not least, in the CIB, 75% of the exposure at default is rated investment grade at the end of '08.</p>
          <p>Moving to slide nine and I will comment there a little bit more into detail the financial structure of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale Group at the end of December.</p>
          <p>As mentioned by Fr&#xE9;deric, so the total Tier I ratio, including the first tranche that was subscribed by the French Government in December, the form of the deeply subordinated notes reached 8.8%. The Core Tier 1 stands at 6.7%. We have presented this figure excluding the floor impact. For the first time in '08, we would &#x2013; the flow would have activated cap in the ratio. But as from the 31 of March, has the cap, we move from 10 to 20%. We will be, let's say, at the mechanical calculation and no longer being limited due to the regulation.</p>
          <p>So we have 8.8%. If we were to include the 50 basis points additional second tranche without deciding or mentioning what will be the type of instrument, the ratio will stand at pro forma basis at 9.3%. And this does include the provision for the dividends, which represents roughly 20 bps deducted from the Tier 1.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, we did also update the severe credit stress test scenario that we have presented for the third quarter results. So, the exercise is exactly the same then of course, three months ago. We have taken, let's say, our starting point the lowest estimate from the street in term of gross operating income, so &#x20AC;6.4 billion, which is a level close from what we have achieved this year despite the fact that this year we have taken some markdowns in terms of revenues. We assimilate what would be the impact of a stress test, cost of risk of 130 bps, shown one year. So, this is the equivalent to a provision loan losses level of &#x20AC;5.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Just to give you how we came to this stress test. We have taken for the French retail banking business a cost of risk of 70 basis points, which is, let's say, 120 bps for the year middle market exposure, which was the maximum reach in 1993. The mortgage banking group remained at a very low cost of risk due to its intrinsic characteristic.</p>
          <p>On the retail banking, outside France, the stress scenario, so the cost of risk of 200 bps, which does include a cost of risk for Romania and Russia in the range of 300 bps plus.</p>
          <p>For financial services, we have applied there the same amount, 200 bps. I remind you that we have an exposure, which is a mixture of leasing and credit and consumer finance. And within consumer finance, we have an important part of the book, which is located in France, Germany and Italy.</p>
          <p>And last but not least, for SG CIB, we have applied 165 basis points, which is the maximum level we have seen in CIB over the last 15 years.</p>
          <p>So when we apply that, the net profit would be based on these two assumptions, &#x20AC;600 million. We would have capacity by using the second tranche available from the French government to maintain the Tier 1 ratio at the end of '09 at 8.8% and the Core Tier 1, depending on the tranquility of the instrument that we would take would be in the range of 6.4 to 6.8%.</p>
          <p>If I now comment on the performance of the businesses, I will go directly to slide 13 to comment on the performance achieved by the French Networks in 2008. The performance as mentioned by Fr&#xE9;deric at the beginning was solid and very satisfactory both on the commercial side and on the financial side.</p>
          <p>Starting with the commercial side, you can see that we have 9.6 million individual customers, that the new customers acquired during the year were almost 90,000. This is certainly good performance, especially when you have in mind that in the first half of this year especially, the network was hurt in its franchise by the affair of the fraud.</p>
          <p>In terms of fee payout, the campaign that we have launched since fall, you can see that we have achieved very satisfactory results with more than one million new revamps opened at the end of Jan.</p>
          <p>In term of growth of the outstanding, we continue to accompany our customer base with loan increasing on average '08 to '07 by 12.6%, 11.4% for the short fourth quarter. And on the deposit side, we continue also to develop the funding structure by increasing deposit amounts by 5.7% with a very successful campaign launch on the term deposits in spring.</p>
          <p>When we turn to the financial performance, you can see that the NBI, net banking income, rose by 2.3%. This is excluding PEL/CEL and excluding the VISA capital gain that we booked in the fourth quarter for &#x20AC;72 million. This is above the guidance that we have given to the market by midyear. And you can see that the dynamic in the fourth quarter was even stronger at 3.6%.</p>
          <p>If we turn now to the characteristic of the French banking market, because we believe that it's quite differentiating to assess, let's say, the resilience of this market, compared to most of other European markets. We can say that for the individuals, they have, let's say, a prudent financial behavior with a major characteristic of high savings ratio, which is very stable 15, 16% level of gross disposable income for years. They have, let's say, a household in France has a relatively low level of indebtedness with only 70% of the gross disposable income represented by debt.</p>
          <p>And last but not least, as I said, the mortgage is characteristic, as I said, with a fixed rate mortgages and the &#x2013; a mutual guarantee for the whole banking sector coming from Credit Mange, which is a rate to reduce the cost of <mark type="inaudible" />, which is insured by Credit Mange.</p>
          <p>On the corporate side either, you can see that the indebtedness ratio of the business sector is relatively low, compared to GDP at 62% and that's as a financial structure of the SMEs in France. That compares favorably with Germany, Italy and Spain with 27 % of the balance sheet, which is equity and 26%, which is non-commercial debts. So, it does include banks and debt but not only. So, you can see that the leverage is relatively limited, compared to some of our, let's say, neighboring countries.</p>
          <p>If I move now to international retail banking, there we'll show the division has achieved a good performance and also, show that it is flexible in this economic environment. The customer base, as a franchise, has 12.1 million individual customers at the end of '08. We did acquire more than 625,000 new customers in '08 essentially in Romania and Russia to mention the two large countries.</p>
          <p>The outstandings continue to grow by 6.6% for total deposit and 25.7% for the lending side. This has led to a deterioration slightly of the loan to deposit ratio that I will comment on that.</p>
          <p>And in terms of investments, we have opened 248 additional branches, which is roughly 30% less than what we did in '07, essentially because the major contributor to this development was the <mark type="inaudible" />, which is close from the target that we have in mind to better cover the Romanian country.</p>
          <p>In terms of financial performance, you can see that the net banking income rose by 21.1% for the full year, as I mentioned, is the same for the fourth quarter where we stood. We achieved that 21.6% growth. And this 21.6% growth does include, I will comment on that, some depreciation of the equity portfolio of Rosbank for &#x20AC;59 million.</p>
          <p>The cost income ratio did improve by 2.4% at 55.3 and the average income also rose by almost 29%, compared to last year. The bottom line of the division stands at &#x20AC;608 million. This does include, as I mentioned at the beginning, the impairment on goodwill in Russia. If we were to exclude that and the impact on the impairment of the equity portfolio of Rosbank and the gains that we booked in Romania on the disposal of an insurance subsidiary is the return on equity for the full year would be 34.4%, which is in line with previous year and very satisfactory, compared to what we have in mind for this division.</p>
          <p>On next page, page 16, a focus on Romania and Russia which achieved good results and also, have started not for more than two to three quarters to adapt to market conditions. I will start with BRD, which is the second largest bank in Romania. As I said, the expansion of the branch network now has come almost to an end, because we've reached its target, which is almost or close to 1,000 branches.</p>
          <p>We have implemented now for two to three years, a very selective lending policies that you can-that are illustrated by the graphs you have on those slides. We show that on the ForEx denominated lending market share, we did voluntarily accept to lose some market share on both business and individual customers, especially over the last two years at the expense of sales more aggressive competitors which we're looking to gain market shares.</p>
          <p>In term of also quality of the loan portfolio, this is the Romanian standards NPS, you can see that BRD has an impaired ratio at the end of the fourth quarter of 3.9%, which is well below the average of the whole industry. The net cost of risk reached 41 bps in '08. It was 61 bps in the fourth quarter, and the net income reached &#x20AC;180 million for the year, an increase by 19%, compared to '07.</p>
          <p>If you will now turn to Russia, where we have some in these divisions, three subsidiaries: Rosbank, BSGV, and the two active in Retail Banking, and DeltaCredit, which is small activity in mortgages. On top of that, we have Grosse Finance, which is in the financial services division.</p>
          <p>You can see there that after let's say, the fears which triggered some deposit decrease in October, you can see on the slide that the our two retail branch networks, BSGV and Rosbank were able to outperform the local banking markets, in term of capacity to capture deposits in November and December. This does trigger an improvement of the loan to deposit ratio, as at the same time, we have put some more pressure, let's say, to contain the growth of the corporate book in Russia. And also, we have been affected overall from the attractiveness of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Even Rosbank, for example, did propose since December deposit products, which is putting aside Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale and Rosbank names.</p>
          <p>I already comment on the goodwill and on the impairments of the available for sale portfolio, &#x20AC;59 million. This mean that we have on this equity portfolio at the price as of 31st of December. And so the Russian subsidiaries did contribute for the full year for &#x20AC;103 million for the Group net profit.</p>
          <p>If I turn now to Financial Services, which have performed, let's say a very satisfactory commercial performance despite, let's say, the economic slowdown especially in the second half of the year. And I will start with Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale's Consumer Finance. You can see there that we have seen a strong developments of the new businesses for the full year with an increase of new business by 16.2%. I should mention that there was a slowdown in the fourth quarter, especially let's say for example, in Russia and in Poland where we have put on to reduced, let's say, the new lending activities, also, including a higher cost of funding, which is, let's say, putting pressure on the margins.</p>
          <p>We booked and we mentioned that during the pre-announcement that was made on the 25 of Jan. We booked as negative revenues but foreign exchange loss in the Ukraine for minus &#x20AC;92 million. I will elaborate a little bit on that.</p>
          <p>In Ukraine, we have a small activity in consumer finance, which has no deposit capacity, because it is not &#x2013; it does not have banking license. It was complicated for us to find funding in the local currency because of the very tight local markets. And so we were funding in dollars contracts that have in their clause an indexation if the currency was to devalue. But it was not a perfect indexation and in fact, following the 40% collapse of the currency since fall, we have to book, let's say, at francs and euros. This is a mixture of obviously some 92, is a loss plus the revaluation of the contract, because we have the capacity to increase the rates that will be paid by the customer base. But on the rest on a net basis, we have to book this loss.</p>
          <p>We have, of course, reviewed the portfolio, but we knew that Ukraine was an exception, because in most of the other countries where we could lend in foreign currency or in local currency, we have capacity to have &#x2013; make any call on contractual indexation, which mean that we are not carrying any foreign exchange risk in other customer lending activities in this division.</p>
          <p>Overall, let's say, to address the current environment for the Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale Consumer Finance activities, we have the set in stone adapt the changes from new lending activities. We have also implements and include in our rate condition the cost of funding, which have increased of course, for these activities over the last quarters.</p>
          <p>For the equipment finance, nothing to say as the performance is okay. And we work at our goal, let's say, over the last month to slightly increase our margins through discounted &#x2013; let's say, increased cost of funding and also, the uncertainty of the economy.</p>
          <p>In fleet management and vehicle leasing, I already mentioned during the third quarter presentation that we have to book some losses on the sale of the fleet on the secondhand car market. This has continued in the fourth quarter where we booked &#x20AC;65 million of negative revenues to discount for the loss on the sale of the fleet and also, for the adjustments of the overall fleet outstanding to convert, let's say, with what is currently the market price for this item.</p>
          <p>Overall, I should nevertheless mention that the other alternative is in the black for the year, which is quite different, compared to most of its peer. And that's the reason we put into place some measures to lower its record in points and also, to develop alternative sales channels to ensure that we are able to limit and to mitigate the decline in significant markets.</p>
          <p>On the life insurance side, the gross inflows were down by 12%, the division let's say of this social cap with the funds in line with bank order banc assurance in France. So, that's probably 11, which assured the kind of premium in the same magnitude. Overall, revenues increased by 7% and the net income decreased by 22%.</p>
          <p>If we now move to GIMS [Global Investment Management and Services], we are starting with Asset Management. Asset Management in the fourth quarter did record some further outflows, &#x20AC;8.6 billion for total for the year of 26.5. The outflows were essentially located in equity and diversified funds, highlighting, I think, the risk aversion of our customer base during this strong market decline. As a result, assets under management stands at &#x20AC;269 billion at the end of December. The perimeter that will be contributed to CAAM-well this is a project, but nevertheless, will be contributed to CAAM represents &#x20AC;165 billion as of end of December.</p>
          <p>The margin was under pressure and, as was mentioned by Fr&#xE9;deric at the beginning, the net banking income, which stands at &#x20AC;400 million &#x2013; &#x20AC;409 million for the full year '08 did book &#x2013; will be booked again, in the fourth quarter some adjustments are linked with the restructuring of funds to a depreciation of sales that we have in the asset management in IBK, a Korean bank with which we have a joint venture. And also, we booked &#x20AC;55 million in the quarter in terms of seed money.</p>
          <p>Page 19, with the private banking, which delivered very satisfactory results in an environment which remains challenging. You can see that the inflows remain healthy at 4.5 billion for the year and 0.3 for the quarter. Assets under management stand at 57 billion. We have continued to expand the division with opening of regional branches in France and also, a new location in Canada, strengthening of Ambrose in the UK and also, the partnership that we have with wholesalers in financial services.</p>
          <p>The gross margin was higher at 117 bps and, as you can see, net bank income was at 2% and bottom line was almost flat.</p>
          <p>On the security services, there you can see that the businesses are being resilient in an environment that was marked, especially in the fourth quarter, by the slump of the equity markets and the cut in interest rates. Overall, in terms of assets under custody, we have &#x20AC;2.6 trillion, which position SGSS as the third largest custodian in Europe. Boursorama, which did present its result on Monday has shown a satisfactory performance even in the fourth quarter. Newedge in the fourth quarter did realize its best ever quarter, even if we were to make a pro forma of Fimat and Calyon Financial, benefiting from the high volatility on the market and also, with great appetite for clean products from market participants.</p>
          <p>All in all, you can see that the financial performance was strong.</p>
          <p>In CIB, I will start with the comments on the non-recurring items. So, the non-recurring items for the full year amounted to 1.5 billion negative for '08. And for the sole fourth quarter, it was a positive of &#x20AC;825 million. If we look so at the underlying performance, the net banking income of SG CIB reached &#x20AC;5.5 billion, down 20%, compared to last year. As already mentioned, we have the impact of IAS 39 reclassification, which neutralized &#x20AC;1.4 billion of P&amp;L and NBI for SG CIB.</p>
          <p>Excluding non-recurring items, the cost income ratio stands at 63%. It represents or it highlights an increase in operating expense by 5.3% for the year, which is a mixed picture because we have strengthened our control procedures, especially in the first half for the fraud, which has triggered an increase of the support function that certainly will be more detailed by Michel. In due course, we have reduced also our front office staff and we have adjusted our variable compensation policy with a strong decrease and also, adjustments of the allocation policy with more deferred benefits, deferred bonuses and also, some performance conditions, which have been put into place to benefit from the deferred bonuses.</p>
          <p>On the next page, I will focus on the yearly results, which again, in term of client-driven revenues reached their second best ever performance with a very strong performance achieved by the fixed income, currency and commodities division with &#x20AC;1.9 billion of account revenues during the year and &#x20AC;639 million in terms of trading. The platform has benefited from very strong performance from the flow business and commodities.</p>
          <p>On Financial and Advisory, good results with very strong resilience, compared to the previous year despite the fact that we have seen certain segments of the financing markets like LBOs and also, commercial real estate, which have declined sharply in term of volumes. But we were able to stage opportunities in infrastructure and natural resources financing and we have also increased cross-selling between different business lines.</p>
          <p>On the equity side, the revenues went down by 57%. As you can see in term of client-related activities, we have seen a decline that is essentially explained by the poor performance in the fourth quarter that I will comment more into detail on the next slide. But overall, when we look at the performance on the year, the flow business has performed well. And on the structured products side, even if we had seen a limited decline, nevertheless, we are able to maintain our key position on this market.</p>
          <p>Overall, I should mention also that the trading businesses did perform positive revenues, for each of VIX and GES despite extremely challenging environment.</p>
          <p>If we now look to more into detail to the fourth quarter, starting with the VIX division. There you can see in grey the very strong client-driven revenues, &#x20AC;657 million, which is a record level, driven again, by very strong flow and commodities.</p>
          <p>On the trading side, the minus 360.76 represented a mixed picture with very strong performance achieved by the treasury business essentially. And on the other side, the dislocation of markets, which has triggered some losses, mainly on the credit products.</p>
          <p>On Financing and Advisory, well the picture for the quarter differs from those from the one from the year. And if I now move to the equity division, you can see that on the client revenues, we have minus 26. This doesn't mean that we paid back the client. It's essentially that within the client revenues and for years, we have some trading position, which I'll link to client exposure. So, when we put into place the structured products, we keep some exposure in terms of dividend correlation and volatility as a Group, which is supposed to be not that much volatile as you've seen over the past years in normal market conditions. But the stressed market condition that we've seen in the fourth quarter did trigger some losses on this book, which explain why we have in terms of client revenues something, which is below zero.</p>
          <p>In term of trading, there also we have seen some negative impact of the high peak in volatility and in correlation.</p>
          <p>Moving to the next slide, which also highlights the measures that we have taken in savings for more than 18 months. In term of shrinking the balance sheet, you can see that since mid-'07, so the start of the crisis, we have reduced by almost 60% the size of the security and repo balance sheet. So, moving from something like 500 billion to a little bit more than &#x20AC;160 billion. So, this has been a dramatic move, reducing position, being more constraint in term of funding, because we have clearly a path to cost of funding through the business line, which mean that they have also make some selection or greater selection in term of what the business that they want to conduct.</p>
          <p>The red part is essentially coming from the financing activity, so it's something relatively stable. And on the grid side, this is the net replacement value of derivatives. You find &#x2013; with that, you seen that most old banks reporting in IFRS, acting especially in the fourth quarter, had strong increase of this part, which is just the impact on the mark-to-market of the derivatives, of the widening of the credit spread and also, of the lower rate curve. And it does not represent any type of risk increase or does not consume any funding.</p>
          <p>In term of toxic exposure, let's say we have declined this exposure consistently over a year, over the year. We have now &#x2013; that includes a markdown sale, as well as reclassification in ABS. In ABS we have now nearly &#x20AC;1.8 billion in trading at the end of December.</p>
          <p>On the unhedged CDOs, it's &#x20AC;0.9 billion. On the monoline, the increase reflects the mark-to-market increase but the coverage is stable at 73%. And on the exotic credit derivatives, you can see that the underlying exposure has been also reduced by almost 50%.</p>
          <p>Having finished with the businesses, I would like to focus on certain realignment initiatives that have been conducted and announced by the Group over the last month starting with asset management where we have announced late January as the project merged our asset management arm with those of Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole. This would create an entity 70% owned by Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole SA and 30% by Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale with the pro forma at the end of September, assets under management of &#x20AC;638 billion. And we do believe that this is the appropriate answer to a sector that did not consolidate CDS but that will be under greater pressure in terms of margin in the coming years.</p>
          <p>We have also announced the planned merger between SGAM Alternative Investments and Lyxor to create leading players in the alternative investments industry in Europe and the disposal of SGAM UK that should be closed in the first half of '09.</p>
          <p>In this CIB, I will not go too much into detail, because of time this morning and Michel is in a better position than I to comment on that. But we reconfirm capitalized on the CIB strength.</p>
          <p>And so if I move now to slide 29, just to mention or so that we're committed to contain and reduce our operating expenses evolution with the operational efficiency plan that was announced last year, which has already achieved some benefits.</p>
          <p>We continue to push for greater neutralization, better policy of consumption, as well as also industrialization of our processes, as we are of course, putting into place some additional and practical cost containment measures which are listed on the slide.</p>
          <p>All in all, let's say we are expecting that to contribute &#x20AC;400 million of additional gross operating income this year, 1 billion next year. And we did achieve already something like 15% of the 1 billion already in our 2008 account.</p>
          <p>I have finished with this presentation. I will let Fr&#xE9;deric conclude with the slide 31.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So, very briefly, as a conclusion, I would like to highlight that I have really the feeling that Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale is a house in order, is a solid Group, well-positioned for the future and despite the obvious uncertainty of 2009.</p>
          <p>First of all, we are maintaining dynamic commercial expansion. And I think, again, we can see the benefit of these relative strengths of capturing new clients; that is clear.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we are adjusting the businesses impacted by the crisis, asset management and CIB, and of course, focusing also on our operating efficiency.</p>
          <p>Thirdly, I think we have a very sound financial structure with this 9.3 Tier 1 ratio. If I were to include the second tranche of public money and overall with this net positive income we felt that we could effectively propose a dividend of &#x20AC;1.2 per share to the AGM.</p>
          <p>Three major priorities for 2009 of this focused development: commercial development, strict control of expenses, and third, monitoring our risk and maintaining this adequate solvency level.</p>
          <p>Thanks a lot for your attention. And I will now turn, first of all, to the room and ask if there are questions. And then, I will ask questions online.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Robin Down from HSBC. I appreciate it's a relatively small part of your business but Russia seems to be having quite a big sense of an impact on your stock. So, I just thought, I'll ask you a few questions, hopefully to get a bit more color about how you're thinking about Russia at the moment. Could you tell us what the NPL levels are at the end of Q4 and how that's changed versus Q3? I think you've given us Romanian numbers but not Russian numbers at the moment.</p>
          <p>And the second question is, can you tell us what foreign exchange lending component is within Rosbank? I think it was about 35% at the end of '07, but if you give us an updated figure that would be quite handy. Third, in terms of the structure, I think Didier said that you were using around 300 basis points for Russia and Romania within the structure. I was wondering if you could give us a little more color as to why you think that's the appropriate number to use. And particularly, it looks like you were fairly close to that level in Q4 of '08, albeit there may be some accounting changes there, which if you give us any color on that would be quite useful.</p>
          <p>And then the final question, this is probably an unfair question, and by all means refuse to answer it. But could you tell us about your level of support that you're prepared to give Rosbank? Does it come to a certain point of losses, whether it's 20 to 30% of credit losses within the book where you are prepared to walk away or is it the case that there is no point at which you would be prepared to walk away from Rosbank?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the figures, Didier, you want to take -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the figure, and this is not the Russian GAAP figures in terms of NPL, this is their own definition, which is more stringent. So, the NPL level of Rosbank at the end of '08 turned out doubtful loans, not NPL. So, it's much more than non-performing than is doubtful &#x2013; that turned out 6.2%. It was 5.6 at the end of September. And it is fully provided for in our account, essentially because as I mentioned during the fourth quarter, we put Rosbank at the standards of the Group. And so this means that we have, for example, there is at least &#x20AC;21 million of additional provisioning that was passed in the fourth quarter just to adjust the case for the methodological between Rosbank accounts and our own accounts.</p>
          <p>Overall, when you look at the cost of risk for the fourth quarter, as a cost of risk for Russia, <mark type="inaudible" /> that I've mentioned stands up for 223 basis points, 223. Again, these figures include 21 billion one-offs, I would say, adjustments. So, we would be slightly below the 200 bps for the whole division. And if you were to look for the Rosbank as a cost of risk for the fourth quarter, that stands at 296 and again, excluding the 21, it would be a gain of around 200 bps. So, that's what we've done &#x2013; we've made a great effort, I'd say, to fully provide for what you can see a level of doubtful loans, again, and, which is our own definition, not the Russian and local definition to ensure that we are, let's say, well provided for in Russia.</p>
          <p>In terms of cost of risk that we stressed, of the assumptions that we have taken as you were questioning, let's say 300 bps plus that we have to assimilate, and in fact, assuming a scenario during which we would have been during two years' time, a kind of average, let's say, NPL evolution, which would be close to 10, 12% and on which we would have eligibility of something like 60%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just let me say, the way we monitor the subsidiaries is to really control the operations and the growth. And for example, in Rosbank, we basically support our existing client base, corporate client base. We also grew very selectively on the retail side, but for example, do not take new clients on the corporate side. We've been able to increase the deposit. And I think you need to keep in mind that it's a market, which is very, very fragmented. And from that perspective, there is a big difference between a bank like Rosbank or BSGV, knowing that we are now trying to capitalize on the brand of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale to collect <mark type="inaudible" /> deposits and very, very small banks.</p>
          <p>And so I think that we can sell, we are making stress tests, but the size if you wish of the operation in my view, and the impact of the stress tests, reflect the capacity of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale to absorb a potential shock, knowing that in the mid-and long-term, at the end of the day, the economy depends a lot, we think, on the oil price, and whether or not it will stay like that or on the contrary, in Asia-Pacific, according to us, to increase going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you prepared to comment on the foreign exchange -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. On the foreign exchange, on the components, so we have overall, let's say, an exposure &#x2013; let me check &#x2013; of 66% &#x2013; no, 33%, so it's 33% of the loan book is in currency. The exposure is very limited on the retail side, where the currency exposure is essentially on the mortgages, which is a tiny portion of the loan book. And we have the majority of lending in the dollar essentially on the corporate side.</p>
          <p>And the size, let's say, of the books at the end of December is &#x20AC;5.1 billion for the corporate customers. I am talking just on Rosbank and &#x20AC;3.5 billion for the retail loan book. So, a total of 8.6. And, well, we have an exchange rate movement. But if we were to look in ruble, the side of the corporate loan book was slightly down 31 of December, compared to end of September, 7% down, while we have a slight increase on the retail side, which we viewed as &#x2013; let's say, of course it makes sense to expand the franchise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, can I just very quickly just ask, in terms of that foreign exchange lending, on the corporate side, are there any sort of restrictions that are put on the sort of people that you would lend to in foreign currency terms? Do they have to be foreign currency earners, or is it -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Typically, what we do is either we lend to foreign subsidiaries, Russian subsidiaries of foreign companies or Russian companies, which have a flow of foreign currency, for example, given the structure of the economy on the commodity side typically is the dollar, which is used to pay and receive money. So, typically it's the kind of business that we do effectively.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the same actually in Romania, where you have also loans in foreign currency typically with companies which effectively get money, a flow of money with foreign currency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening. Alessandro Roccati from Fox-Pitt Kelton. Three quick questions. The first one is on IAS 39 amendment. You mentioned 1.5 billion of positive impact on the NBI. I'm just wondering whether you can give us any breakdown?</p>
          <p>The second one is on the goodwill. You were down 300 million in Russia. I'm just wondering whether you can give us any figure for the outstanding free goodwill and whether you foresee any other goodwill adjustments.</p>
          <p>And finally, going back to the cost of risk on CE, which seems to be a worry for the market, 122 basis points in the final quarter. You have a stress test of 300 basis points. Just wondering whether you feel comfortable with 300 basis points, or what level of loan-loss charge you can guide us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably Didier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the &#x20AC;1.5 billion of neutralization net income, this is 1.4 for CIB. In fact, while the overall figure is 1.454. So, it's the rounding figure, is on the wrong side. We have a very limited impact on the life insurance, where we did some very limited reclassification, but no P&amp;L impact. And so the bulk of the 1.4 is on the CIB side. And that difference &#x2013; revenues that we have neutralized.</p>
          <p>On the second point regarding the goodwill, so the total amount of goodwill in the balance sheet of the Group at the end of December stands at &#x20AC;6.8 billion. And you have the same in the balance sheet details that is available on the website, let's say you have that split between different what we call cash flow generating units, which is the method on which we assess the appropriateness on the goodwill, compared to the cash flow we could expect from these units. Also, that's it, I would say when you look at the size of the units, let's say we feel very comfortable on the goodwill, which we have in the balance sheet at this point. And the last -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>How do we look at our risk of 200 basis points? Again, this is-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>120 bps for the Financial Service business for -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well they are already incremented slightly, let's say nearly 200 bps. So, even more than 300 on Russia and something like 360. It's around 300 &#x2013; we have 200 in Romania and almost the same type of levels in Czech Republic. But <mark type="inaudible" /> in our view a serious stress test, the winning part of the portfolio is essentially, as we said, Madrid, like Africa and French overseas territory, on which we didn't see any strong movement in term of provisions over the last quarters. Just to mention something that was read this morning in the press conference. For example, in Egypt, we continue to have some write-backs of provisioning in '07 and in '06.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And one thing that the market also neglecting is the fact that you can adjust your margins also in these countries in a much quicker way than in developed countries. I mean, so even if you have a higher cost of risk, the margins also are adjusted.</p>
          <p>Are there questions in the room?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on two areas. One is on the reclassification and the amount and what it actually is because I'm struggling to get the numbers to add up. So, the 23 billion, I think I can see about 10 billion. But could you talk us through what you've actually reclassified?</p>
          <p>And also, on slide five of the kind of the monoline disclosure, could we discuss a bit the risk in the CLOs and how comfortable you are? I've noticed you've had slightly more write-downs. And whether there is a kind of issue with recovery rates as we go through a recession and what recovery rates you're assuming?</p>
          <p>And then lastly, on equity derivatives, you obviously mentioned Q4 was very disappointing. But in terms of the outlook, you've said '09 was a good start. Can we &#x2013; is there any kind of feel we can have for how that business will operate with the VIX where it is because things got a bit better, but they are still &#x2013; obviously, volatility is still very high. So, some kind of feeling, the outlook for that business versus obviously a very strong, the flow business base is very strong, so, and the dynamic in the revenues, underlying revenues for '09 would be helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, before Didier answers the first two questions, I will ask first maybe Michel, without disclosing of course, any figures, but just give a bit more flavor on the start of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And first of all, we said that the start of the year is good for the CIB in general. And although I'm not talking on &#x2013; keen to comment on every month, because you would ask us to comment on every week. The fact is the start on the equity derivatives has been slow, but it's a positive one. And it seems that the dislocation of the market we have registered in November and December is not registered since the beginning of the year. So, the volatility level, even the dividend levels and correlations are more in line with what we've seen and the business is slightly going back. I think that the flow &#x2013; we are registering a weaker flow business than last year. But overall, it's a &#x2013; for us, it's a fairly decent start to the year. And I want to say that despite the extraordinary dislocation of the market on the Q4, our equity derivative book is still showing a year which is a positive one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's &#x2013; Didier, on the reclassification and the monolines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the reclassifications. So, as you mentioned, we have reclassified for the CIB &#x20AC;23.5 billion. If we look at the different buckets of these assets, where they come from, approximately 30% of this 23.5 billion is coming from the exotic credit derivatives portfolio. This is essentially CMBS that has been reclassified from trading to loans and receivables.</p>
          <p>We have also approximately 35% of these assets which has been reclassified coming from the negative business trade monoline exposure. And approximately 10% is coming also from cash CDOs that we have also reclassified. In fact, looking at the G7 financial supplement that you have on the website, we have identified these items. In the CDOs, you will see that a certain move from trading to long-term receivables between the end of September to end of December. And also, in the exotic credit derivatives in the CMBS focus, you will see a line reclassified from &#x2013; assets reclassified thanks, to &#x2013; due to IF 39. So, this gives you the bulk of what has been done.</p>
          <p>I forgot also to mention that approximately 10% came also from the SGAM portfolio, and has been reclassified. It's partly CMBS and also, RMBS UK and RMBS Spain. And that is for reclassification.</p>
          <p>On the monoline, well, they are also in the supplement. You will find on page six the detailed assumptions that we have applied to value the hedge that we have on the corporate loan CLOs. You can see that we haven't applied to calculate this mark-to-market of the hedge, we have applied a cume loss rate, well, cumulative for five years, which is the worst scenario that has been observed over the last 30 years. So, we can see maybe we are at worse than that. But nevertheless, as we take five years consecutive, at least this is relatively steady.</p>
          <p>And you will see that according to that, the cume losses are the following: for the BBB, we have a 5% cume loss, BB 17; B 31; CCC 51% and below CCC, they were fully written off. Half what we own is essentially a senior tranche of CLOs. We have a protection by mezzanine. So, our attachment point on average is 28%. And that's why, when you look at the scenario of write-downs that we have applied on our exposure, the write-down is 8%, compared to the attachment point, which is at 28%. I hope that's clear. But if you have further questions, you can of course, come back to me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, there, that's John Fran&#xE7;ois from Goldman Sachs. I just had two questions, one on the CDS portfolio and the second one on reclassification again, just taking a question. First, on the CDS. I would like to know who are the counterparties, as in what type of financial institutions? Are the gains included in the equity base in the Core Tier 1 base of the Group? And if yes, if you were to realize those gains today, what would be the impact on the risk weighted assets, as in you don't have the CDSs anymore. What would be the impact of risk weighted assets?</p>
          <p>And finally, I reckon with 2.1 billion of gain for 2008, that's about 2.7% of risk weighted &#x2013; of credit risk weighted assets in CIB. Sounds like a nice gain to me. I was just wondering whether you had realized that. So that's for the first question.</p>
          <p>And for the reclassifications, very candidly, I was just wondering how you see reclassification and what main advantages you see for the Group by doing reclassifications? Secondly, what average duration you have in this portfolio? And thirdly, what marks on the CMBS book have you got?</p>
          <p>And finally, were there provisions in CIB this quarter related to that book, because they seem to have spiked a little bit? I was just wondering whether there was provisions for that particular book. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I will take the answer and then Didier can complete; he will be exhausted otherwise. Let me say that the CDS effectively are going through the Tier 1. Some of the benefit has been tracked live. It's not just a mark-to-market, but we have crystallized part of the profit.</p>
          <p>In terms of risk weighted assets, it's relatively limited and I will let Didier comment.</p>
          <p>Regarding reclassification, I think it's really to say and the process that we selected was to say, we started at the beginning of October and there was a selection with the risk department which has to say I am fine or not, looking at the quality of the credit, taking a credit approach on the asset, taking into account, of course, the markdown on the asset and considering again, whether or not we were happy to put that in balance sheet in loan to receivable categories.</p>
          <p>I think it's, from my perspective, it's a one-off element, which takes into account a situation, which is effectively, absolutely exceptional with a total lack of liquidity on these assets. The average maturity is probably around four years and a half roughly, I'd say, between four and five years. And effectively, we are going to carry these assets. There was no loss, actually no credit loss this quarter on these assets. But some of the risk-weighted asset, on the CDS, CDS/CDOs, because on the hedging, the credibility that we have is not only CDS, it was also on the CDOs that we use to protect ourselves.</p>
          <p>So the outstanding is &#x20AC;44 billion at the end of '09. The average maturity is 3.4 years. As you said &#x2013; the NBI impact was &#x20AC;2.1 billion. We have reduced the sensitivity of this portfolio by different techniques; some disposal, but not only that, which mean that now for a 1 bps tightening of the spreads, we would lose &#x20AC;1.4 million. Just to give you an idea, a year ago, the sensitivity for 1 bps was &#x20AC;12 million. So, we nevertheless, put into place some techniques to reduce and crystallize part of these mark-to-market.</p>
          <p>For example, what I think unfairly sold that we've seen some of what is definitive and not only mark-to-market, was approximately &#x20AC;300 million in '08 and we have also made some sale since the beginning of the year. So, that's for your point on the....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the counterparties on -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The counterparties are double rating banks or some which have been recently to a single A+ and it is a very nice status, which is rare. But nevertheless, used to be the large investment banking player which used to be AA for most of them.</p>
          <p>And your last question was on CMBS, the marks, CMBS that we have reclassified, essentially AAA CMBS. So, a very good quality. The marks were roughly a little bit less than $0.90 a dollar on the CMBS that we have reclassified.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, a few questions. Could you, on Romania, just like you did for Russia, give your assumptions for NPLs and LGD? Could you also talk about your cross debt financing of the subsidiaries in Romania and Russia? And at what point do you have negative equity? At what FX level, do you have negative equity in your FX loans in Romania and in Russia? At what currency level would you assume that you have negative equity?</p>
          <p>And lastly, on EDG, can you talk a bit about how you see the long-term development of this business on the structuring side, and on the flow side, and on the arbitrage side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, initially, we'll take your question on equity derivatives. Maybe I can turn to Didier on Romania?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Romania, again, our own definitions, on Romania, you've seen what is the local standards in our own definition. In BRD, we have a doubtful loans level of 2.7% and the coverage is 73. And the stress scenario that we have assumed is assuming in terms of loan losses on a two-year basis something that will stand at something like 4% on a two-year basis, so 200 basis points on a yearly basis. That's what we have put into place. And the LGD is roughly the same magnitude than the one we discussed on Russia, so something like 50%.</p>
          <p>Your question on the negative equity, on the level of the currency that will trigger some negative equity for the loans; honestly, I don't have the answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll come back to you on that -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the equity derivatives business, overall, the client business is down 38%, compared to 2007, which is showing a good resistance of the business. Indeed, for the first three quarters we had a fairly good, I think it was our third-best client business year. December has been very good, and the question is, is December going to be seen again? I think that what we have seen in December is a historical dislocation of the market. And everything can happen, but that's not what we anticipate again. And so far, the volumes are significantly lower than the first part of last year. But it is recovering slowly.</p>
          <p>And on the flow side, there are still some buckets which are pretty resisting. For instance, the ETS business is still a very good business. The warren business is still fairly solid. And on the structured product side we still see a fairly robust amount of capital guaranteed product. And so far we think that in a market which has corrected and also, which is as cash equity, depending on the absolute level of the stock price of the various indices. We think that we would be in a position to confirm our number one position, worldwide position and increase the gap with the competition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And let me say that we've seen increased margins. You know that when you had about 15 to 16 banks completing for structured products, we have probably half of that today, it helps in terms of margins. I will turn now to the questions online please and then I will come back to the room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have a question from Mr. Guillaume Tiberghien from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. I've got actually four questions. One relates to international retail. Could you give us the amount of lending that you, Soc Gen headquarters has done to the various international retail subsidiaries? And if you could give us a number per country, at least for the big country. The second one relates to &#x2013; it's a small question on the CDPC reserves. I'm not familiar with what it is. And if you could elaborate and tell us what to expect there?</p>
          <p>And thirdly, on the CIB for which you have sorry, on the CDO for which you have had a commutation, that CDO is only 30% covered. And that doesn't seem very big to me. So, maybe there is a reason why. And finally, on the cost of CIB, I appreciate you highlight that the bonuses are lower, that there is more cost control. But still the cost base at present is in line with the cost base that you had in '05 when the revenues were 1.4 billion per quarter without CDS gain. So, that doesn't &#x2013; I'm not familiar with sort of what to expect in terms of run rate for the cost now? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I will let Michel comment on the cost of CIB, Didier on CDPC and the commuted CDOs.</p>
          <p>Regarding the international lending, let me say, Guillaume if I may, ask you, in the appendix you have the full detail of all our subsidiaries like in the third quarter. And you will see all the size of the lending book, the deposits for every subsidiary. So, if you don't mind, you will see all that in the appendixes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fr&#xE9;deric, it's more what Soc Gen has lent to the subsidiaries i.e. does Soc Gen lend to Rosbank? Does Soc Gen lend to BRD? Can I just assume that if I do loans minus deposits in each country that gives me a theoretical inter-bank borrowing that I can assume is coming from Soc Gen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Didier will comment, for example, on Rosbank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so I would comment on the &#x2013; maybe it was also part of the question earlier. On the funding that we do provide to the subsidiaries, let's say first of all, on the International Retail Banking business as a whole, there is some &#x2013; lot of subsidiaries, which are related to the substitutions, which has essentially the Maghreb, Africa and overseas territories, and which are self-sufficient in term of funding.</p>
          <p>In term of CDs, some subsidiaries have some lines, but for example, to comment on Rosbank, the line is not drawn down. This means that Rosbank at the end of December had little bit less than US $3 billion of available liquidity. It shows that even if you were to make, let's say, the sole reduction loans minus deposits, you will overestimate just to have a fixed exposure, because of course, our subsidiaries have the capacity to refinance themselves on certain markets locally. We have a line from the Central Bank in Russia, which is not used so far by Rosbank. But this is just an example. In Romania, we have a limited amount of funding. But let's say what is currently also preventing BRB to be self-sufficient is the very high level of compulsory reserves which continue to be applied in this country.</p>
          <p>On top of my mind in lending in domestic currencies, the compulsory reserves amount to 15 to 18%, while for the foreign lending business, it's something like 30 or 40%. But it's something relatively important, which prevents Rosbank, BRD to be so self-sufficient. Komer&#x10D;n&#xED; banka, as you've seen has an important success on deposits, compared to loans.</p>
          <p>That's for the first question on the CDPC or the credulity for the companies. This is a kind of, I would say, monoline type of the assets which does provide some CDS, let's say, to third parties to cover certain type of assets. So, you've seen that in our disclosure we have mentioned that we have a 1.1 billion exposure on the CDPC, which is provided for by 10% provisioning level.</p>
          <p>On the CDO that has been commuted, your point was on the CDO level &#x2013; of the CDOs, which is 35%. Let's say again, this is depend, while we always commented that each CDO that's its own characteristic. Let's say, we do apply exactly the same scenario, which means that these CDOs commutation did not have any material impact on the P&amp;L of the Group. This means that the cash that we receive from the commutation did match, let's say, the gap between what we are provided for and what are the mechanical marks as soon as we do realize that we have no longer any coverage, any hedge. So, the impact was limited. This portfolio, which has cumulative spending of &#x20AC;1.8 billion, as we know so immediately we ratify on date on the 1st of October. And so, what you can see as a 30% write-down is totally in line with what had been made by the Group in term of scenarios i.e. the cumulative scenarios that we have described on slide 4 of the supplement, so that it keep an I-grade, it's an I-grade, two I-grade CDOs. And as you can see, they have also relatively mixed exposure to the vintages 206 and 207.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michel on the cost of CIB.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, on the cost of CIB overall the costs for 2008 are slightly up at roughly 2%. But this, in fact, translate some-despite easing the way we have been managing our costs, as you know, we've been investing after the carry forward in remediation plan. And therefore, we have sent there to recruit people and develop a system to support our plan. And overall, the staff costs are being reduced nevertheless by 4%. But this has been led by the front office staff, which has been reduced by 5%.</p>
          <p>And if we look at the comparison between Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale and some of our competitors, we see that the comparison between '08 and '06 shows that we &#x2013; our total costs have been reduced by 11%, and our staff costs by 29%, which compares quite well with the banks which have done relatively well, as we have done in 2008, such as Barclays for instance. Because there if we compare '08 to '06 their total costs have been reduced by 8%, 11% on our side and staff costs by 25% and 29% in '05. We compare somewhat less favorably with UBS, Credit Suisse and Deutsche Bank, but they have not shown the same picture.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me say that first on CIB if you wish, we still target a cost-income ratio of around 60% in cycle and again, with the return on equity of around 20%. It's clearly a view -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For this year &#x2013; we accept the non-recurring items, our cost income is set at 63%, which is a very decent one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Other questions on-line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Mamang Talif from MF Global. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. Three very quick questions. The first one is related to the book value of Soc Gen. What happened to the book value of Soc Gen from the third quarter to the fourth quarter, and what has been the main reason for the difference?</p>
          <p>The second question is about the second round of the government funding. Will you be doing like BNP and buying back your hybrids or will you just be &#x2013; you will be considering the 1.7 additional as pref shares that would count towards Core Tier 1?</p>
          <p>And the third question is about monoline exposures. You had 3.9 or 3.8 billion gross monoline exposure in the third quarter. What happened to that exposure in the fourth quarter? I would assume it had gone up because of the dollar, but please confirm that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I will let Didier comment on the evolution of the book value in 2008 and the monoline exposure. Let me say on the second tranche, we remain flexible and we have till the end of August to decide whether we take this money and which kind of instrument, hybrid or preferred share. So, we are going to see exactly, to be frank, how the first six months ago and we decide in due course. Regarding the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the book value per share, you have that on page 41 of the appendices. It stands at &#x20AC;52.3 per share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's the book value not per share. It's the full book value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The book value, not per share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, the book value total -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we come back on that perhaps a bit later and comment on the monoline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's &#x2013; the book value total is &#x20AC;29.3 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's at end of '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>End of '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what was it at end of third quarter of '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was 30 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It was 30. So, the decline has been due to what exactly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The decline came essentially from the &#x2013; well, there is a lot of factors. There is a lot of plus and minus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hence, the interest in the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, but in fact, what you've &#x2013; no in fact, you've seen that the result was close to nil. So, I would say the &#x20AC;80 million in the quarter and there is some foreign currency effect because in the conversion, and you will see that in the balance sheet detail, believe we have some exchange rate movement which triggered some conversion reserves, which were a little bit more negative than what they were at the end of June.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>There were no AFS reserves?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Or there is no write-down against equity whatsoever?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, in fact, really all the write-downs if you have to take some are against us going through the P&amp;L.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your last point was on the monoline movement -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the monocline, why it did increase -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, why it did increase. So, I will take then detail on the slide seven of the financial supplement. The increase from 3.5 to &#x20AC;4.2 billion of the fair value of the protection is a consequence of the methodology that I mentioned earlier, which mean that when we do apply a mark to stress and some liquidity add on, we have to discount for the widening of the spread, especially on the corporate side that took place in the third &#x2013; in the fourth quarter, sorry. So, this has triggered an increase on the overall mark-to-market of the protection that we &#x2013; mark to stress protection, that we bought from the monolines. We continue to deduct the same nominal amount of protection that we bought from third parties and, which is not mark-to-market. We would just take the nominal and we neutralize the mark-to-market, that will be of course, important in the P&amp;L.. As I say, we reserve that for in case of default, I would say. Then you come to the 3.3 at the end of December, compared to 2.6 at the end of September.</p>
          <p>And then based on this net fair value of protection, as we disclosed over the last two quarters, we have some write-downs, some markdowns level which are, depending on the bucket of ratings of the monoline that we'd look at. So, it's 15% for the AA and AAA, it's 49% for the BBB and 90% for B and CCC. And based on that we come to 2.1 billion of markdown outstanding at the end of December, an increase by &#x20AC;400 million. And so the net remaining exposure is 73% &#x2013; the net, sorry, coverage of the overall exposure is 73%, so for remaining exposure of 1.2. I should mention, because I forget that at the start, that of course, within this exposure, we have taken into account the commutation which have reduced protection, the first line, but also the reserve, because part of the reserves have been reallocated to the marks on the unhedged CDOs that result from the commutation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more question online?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Pascal Decque from Natixis Securities. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good afternoon. Sorry, I still have a few questions. The first one is just a follow-up from the book value, just one point I wanted to try to get clearer is the OCI plus one billion. I had in mind OCI is something like the FX reserve, negative in your balance sheet at the end of '08. And I want to try to understand what was this number.</p>
          <p>The second is you mentioned in the presentation the potential merger process of your market activities. I just wanted to have some more detail on your strategy there.</p>
          <p>Third, minor point regarding the cost in the Corporate Center, the increase, is it totally linked to the increase of the cost of the funding?</p>
          <p>And last point, the margins evolution in French retail banking, considering the evolution of the rates and your possibility to increase the margin to the client and your global policy in asset/liability management. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Didier will answer on the OCI and the cost of Corporate Center, Michel on the merger of our capital market activity, then we'll start perhaps with the margin in France and the asset and liability management.</p>
          <p>First of all, we have not changed our asset and liability management policy, which is, as you know, consistent in matching assets and resources, modeling the deposits and basically locking the margin so we do not take any risk on the interest rate, if you wish; we don't have open position.</p>
          <p>Regarding the margins on credit, France remains a market, which is more competitive than other European markets. We receive some improvements of the margins, but limited and knowing that we have passing of course, the increase of the cost of funding to our clients.</p>
          <p>Regarding on the resource side, we will benefit this year of the decrease of the interest rate paid on the lira. We had a great success in the sale of this product at the end of 2008. We have overall one million lira which were opened at the end of January 2009. So, there was a pre-reservation campaign. And you know the interest rate paid on this product has gone down to 250 basis points and might maybe go down further in August. And we of course, adjust also the interest rate paid on the term deposits that can compete with these kind of products. But overall, I would say we have to cope with a market which remains competitive, which is a market which remains dynamic in terms of credit. The French banking market still works. On the OCI perhaps and cost of Corporate Center, Didier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, on the OCI, the outstanding at the end of '08, excluding conversion reserves, stands at minus &#x20AC;1 billion. As I speak, it is as follow. We have minus 2.1 on the available for sale unrealized losses. We have plus &#x20AC;400 million on the cash flow hedge unrealized gain. And we have let's say a plus &#x20AC;650 million, which is the deferred tax asset. So, a total of minus one billion, it was minus 800 million at the end of September. So, we can see something relatively stable.</p>
          <p>On the cost side, in the corporate center, in fact, we have, especially in '08, some elements linked to the operational efficiency plan, which mean that to support the mutualization we have subsidized some cost of investments which are being taken by the corporate center. And that's part of the explanation. The rest is something, which you can find the resource for in revenues, which, for example, in term of cost paid by the businesses to use the premises and especially the new tower, they are paying a cost of course, in their cost base that we are mutualizing this as revenue because of our real estate property companies internally are getting revenues. And so we reverse that at cost, and so that explain part of the movement in term of being cost, but this is more technical. So, I would say the major explanation is coming from the fact that we have subsidized something like &#x20AC;30 million to mutualization in '08.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michel, on the merger of capital markets activities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, I want to say that we think that we have been ending up the year in a better shape than most of the competition. And therefore, we believe in our CIB model. We believe in our business mix and we strongly believe in our three pillars, which are derivatives, capital markets in euros and capital raising and then financing. But we also realize that we needed to adapt to the changing environment and therefore, we have been proposing a reflection on several topics.</p>
          <p>First, but at the center of this reflection is to further develop our client business and to take advantage of the current environment to gain market share on both the corporate side and the fixed side. And also, we think that there is probably a unique opportunity for us to step up from our very strong financing position to more investment banking relationship with our clients and in M&amp;A and advisory. And putting the clients at the center of our reflection means also more transversal approach between our fixed income and our equity and equity derivative business and also, improve our risk profile. We need to better manage our cash resources, balance sheet, capital limits and VAR, et cetera. And that we think would be improved through an idea of getting FX and JV together.</p>
          <p>Also we need to enhance our operational efficiency and security. And by aligning the market business, we think that will help us to better-to improve and better align also this information system. And last, we think that putting these businesses together, we'll be able to have a more transversal, again, reflection regarding our risk approach, which is absolutely key between fixed income and equity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Then if I read in French what is written in your slide, is... does it mean any potential matter with any other competitors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, not at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, it's an internal-</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I thought that was a JV, like you did in other businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no. It's an internal project and it's -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have another question-next question from Mr. Pierre Flabbee from Kepler Capital Markets. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening. I have two questions, in fact. The first one is regarding the asset transferred went on 28.5 billion, the 1.5 depreciation which has been avoided. Sounds a bit a lot. Could we have an idea if this figure has been impacted by the market dislocation and could we have just a color of what could be a mark-to-market as of today?</p>
          <p>My second question regards to the preferred shares. Just a follow-up. While I'm not very clear about the characteristic, which is that they are supposed to be pari passu loss taking with shareholders' equity. Could you explain us a bit in detail how the mechanic would work just in case losses would be registered for Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, first thing, we are not calculating the mark-to-market of the transferred assets every day. We will have-the rule is that every quarter, we will have effectively to update the market with the valuation of these assets. So, we do that on a quarterly basis. Now, perhaps on the preferred share, a bit more detail on how it can work.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, maybe tomorrow you will have more detail. But on the pari passu client, I think of the pref shares with ordinary share, let's say the pref shares are, well &#x2013; the French law, they are let's say capital eligible to the same statutes than the ordinary share regarding the limited capital, as well as the premium reserve, which mean that there are loss absorption, which mean that if all the consolidated reserves are wiped out by losses and then if we start to bite in to the capital and premium reserves, in that case, the principal of the pref share is also at risk. And of course, there will be some clause of rebuilding of the nominal as soon as the banks and the Group came again, into the black. So, I think that answers from what I understood to your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It does. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I will go back to the room maybe with two questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One question on investment banking. To go back to the model, historically you had around 30% of revenues from trading. Going forward, how do you think the mix will evolve with IRC and capital consumptions from the trading book? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michel, you want to take that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think we are showing that this year, the mix between planned business and trading revenues is above 75:25, at least 77:23. And I think it's around two-third to 75. Overall, it's a good mix. I am not sure that we should go further than that because you still need a trading acceptance to serve your clients in terms of risk you take on their behalf.</p>
          <p>I think that there is indeed a trend on the de-risking side and especially on the illiquid asset and something which today everybody is doing, which is de-risking businesses where-which are using a leverage to enhance a product with poor yield, the intrinsic yield. That is finished for the time being, because the cost of liquidity is too high. But I think that the trend would be to firmly stay in the 25:75 overall. And if you look at what we have been doing on our balance sheet side, it reflects our strong de-risking work, which we have started in 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of capital allocation, I think the percentage would be lower. The model we have in mind is to have at the end of the day a 25% max of capital allocated to CIB as a percentage of the Group. I would say not above 20% for sure for trading activities. So, it means probably less than 5% of the capital of the Group allocated to these kind of activity. Yeah, including potentially our assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jean Pierre Lambert [KBW]. Just first question on the cost reduction, if you could give some indication as the position of allocation, is it concentrated in some divisions or some geographical areas?</p>
          <p>Second question, you indicated that the growth of risk weighted assets will be moderate for this year. We have currency impacts, which are going to reduce your exposure in international retail and specialist finance. Where do we see the evolution, where is it, at growth or what do you mean by moderate in terms of range?</p>
          <p>And to come back to Central Europe, the slide you provide with the exposure of CIB, the loan exposure to Central Europe is including-part of it is included in European Union. What is the amount or the percentage, which is exposed to Central Europe, including the EU countries in CIB I mean?</p>
          <p>And finally, given all these developments then, the concern of the markets on Central Europe, and generally, are you thinking of diversifying your exposure or limiting your expansion in the region in the future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. S&#xE9;verin will comment in a minute on our cost cutting initiatives. Michel will answer on the Central, Eastern Europe exposure in CIB.</p>
          <p>On the risk weighted assets, first of all, and I speak under the control of Didier, we have in mind growth between 8 and 10%. That takes into account the impact of the migration of rating, in the Basel II. And we factor that into the growth. And after that we are committed to increase our lending in France by between 3 and 4% for 2009. We are going to grow also in the International Retail and on the CIB side it will be something very, very moderate and under control, but again, with potentially this migration of rating.</p>
          <p>Regarding, let me say that -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>just to complement what Fr&#xE9;deric said, this 8 to 10% does not include any depreciation of currency. So, that's constant exchange rates. And within that, let's say, we have approximately 3 to 4 percentage points of rating migration. So, linked to Basel III effect, or in terms of volume is something, which is more in the mid-single-digit figure, and in mind that France grew by something like 4. We're actually above mid-single in retail outside France and Financial Services will be the mid-singles for this year in big businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, let me just comment on &#x2013; first of all, I am-my view is &#x2013; my view on that emerging markets will resume growing more quickly than developed countries.</p>
          <p>And in emerging markets, of course, you have very different situations. I think it's difficult to comment in situations like, for example, countries like in Hungary or Ukraine where you have already a crisis, which can be related to political environment, as well as macroeconomic picture, with deficit, external deficits, more or less weaker banking system. Countries which, like in Russia, at the end of the day with the macroeconomic picture, will be very much related to the oil of price. Countries, which in Africa for example, and Mediterranean basin, will of course, have lower growth, but have the benefit of the relatively benign impact of the toxic asset liquidity issues et cetera. So, the picture is very mixed.</p>
          <p>It is clear in my view that we can grow. It remains growth story in the long term. We are not in a hurry, if I may, say. And in these markets, strong banks like our subsidiaries will be able to make the difference in a much easier way than in developed countries where competition will be very tough and in countries where again, we expect relatively sluggish growth going forward, with the need to absorb not only the immediate shock of the crisis, but also the fact that there are huge deficits in imports, significant public debts, which will have to be sorted out. And certain structural ills like in the US where probably consumer spending cannot just rely on effectively over indebtedness going forward, but a slightly different model.</p>
          <p>So, at this stage let me say that first of all, the priority for the next six months is to monitor the crisis. I personally consider that there might be still volatility, bad news, nervousness. And I think it's important just to demonstrate that we can fare properly through this period. Then I think we will be focus predominantly in the same regions, Central, Eastern Europe, Mediterranean basin. Asia is again, also a region of interest. We've made an investment in Vietnam in August 2008. We carry on developing in China, but I will say overall it is a longer term perspective. Perhaps...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have the breakdown of the numbers you've been asking in the combinations. I'd like to come back to you. Pass you on to Didier -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Didier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have not again, such detail, but just in Russia to mention that we have the &#x20AC;2 billion of withstanding CIB too and the rest is limited, because the bulk of the lending to corporate is done through the local subsidiaries. I think maybe commercial bank has certain exposure. <mark type="inaudible" /> managed as part of the synergies within the Group by CIB. But that it's also a very limited portion of CIB loan book, which is exposed to this segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>S&#xE9;verin, on the cost cutting exercise?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As Didier mentioned we have two set of initiative. We have what we call structural efficiency plan, which is long-term initiative to improve the productivity of different properties within the Bank, and which will deliver this 1 billion we mentioned one year ago after the fourth Q of year. And this will be implemented in fact, in 2010. Of course, the impact would be higher after probably start of structural gains.</p>
          <p>And we have launched in 2008 a second set of initiative, which is really the cost cutting initiatives and which are changing our consumption policies, in fact, for traveling, for anything like that including, for IT spending also.</p>
          <p>So your question in term of divisional split of this gain is we have three &#x2013; in the structural part of our action, which will deliver this one billion next year, we have three type of initiatives.</p>
          <p>We have what you call mutualizations part. And the main part of that is IT infrastructure mutualization. This will gain &#x2013; the gain will be split over or rather according to the IT intensity of each business not and it's because of all the IT spending of the company. So, you will see that it is more benefiting to the retail, which is high intensive in France mainly speaking and in CIB, which we have also a high intensity in term of IT today.</p>
          <p>The second type of initiative is process industrialization, what we call is Lean approach in terms of profit. And this would benefit mainly to CIB and to Jean-Claude's division.</p>
          <p>And the third is what we call sourcing optimization, which mean call to off-shoring capability and to designing our contracting capability. Today we have 10,000 people working for us as contractors. So, we are really asking our contractors to relocate this capability that we've got. So, all in all, really the interest in 1 billion plus is a cost cutting approach. There is &#x2013; it will be probably fair to say that the proportion of general spending of each division will benefit in the same average, all in all. You have a total spending at the Group level of 16 billion and you will have to allocate this 1 billion further cost cutting initiative regarding the portion of each division.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anymore question in the room or online? Online? Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have the question online from Mr. Jean-Pierre from Nomura. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I realize it's late. Let me limit it just to one question and one clarification. The question is on French Retail and I just wondered how much of the Q4 increase in provisions was the start of a deteriorating trend and how much was really a bit of year-end housekeeping. So, we might see that absolute number come down a little in the first part of '09? The clarification is just around the numbers that you gave us for the stress test. I just wanted to check those were percentages of Basel I risk weighted assets. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the French Retail there's effectively always a seasonality factor, but I would say the bulk of the increase is more related to the crisis and the SME-the impact on the SMEs. It is difficult to predict the cost of risk. So, I would not be that surprised to have in the first quarter something more or less the same magnitude, if you wish.</p>
          <p>Regarding effective the basis points we mentioned it's in terms of risk weighted assets in Basel I. We will, going forward, communicate progressively in percentage of exposure at defaults but we don't want to disturb you too much at this stage. So, effectively we keep the same measurement tool.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question online from Mr. Eric Vanpoucke with Oppenheim. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, just going through quickly, a couple of questions. The first one, do you intend to implement the impairment test on your subsidiaries on a quarterly basis or are you going to do it only on a yearly basis? Secondly, should we expect some one-off cost, for instance, for redundancy plans in 2009? And can you just give us some flavor regarding value at risk in Q4? And what would you expect for the beginning of 2009? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the first question on the impairment of the goodwill, we review that on a quarterly basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the restructuring cost, yes, we might have some restructuring costs in certain businesses. The magnitude should be relatively limited. Thirdly, on the value at risk, well, you have the figures. Let me just remind you that we have historical scenarios and so, clearly, we had to input in the calculation, the scenarios of the fourth quarter. We use a 99% methodology. It means that basically, we retain the average between the second and third largest loss in the last 250 scenarios. And we will keep these scenarios, these stress scenarios for basically one year. The positions are very low basically, and that's why also probably with limited risk. But let's say, we can expect a level of VAR probably of that kind of magnitude for certain period of time, before the scenarios disappear.</p>
          <p>Any more questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a follow-up question from Guillaume Tiberghien from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, the question relates to the AFS reserves again, in the shareholder equity. If I look at your financial statements in June, you had negative 152 million for a change in fair value of assets available for sale. And in the statement of shareholder equity this time, the number has gone from minus 152 to minus 2.1 billion. And I am not actually sure that I understand what has happened to explain the 2 billion difference. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So you mentioned in June &#x2013; between June and the end of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I've got the movement between end of September and end of December. But let's see, the figure was-because I don't have the detail in the whole series, but the figure was on the AFS a positive plus 1.2 at the end of '07, a negative of minus 1.1 at the end of September and then negative, as I said, earlier, of minus 2.1 at the end of December. And so there is a change that we see is essentially linked to the interest movements that we've seen during the quarter, which has triggered some negative mark-to-market in the OCI, that's it. But as I said, this is offset by the plus &#x20AC;1 billion on the cash coverage and on the deferred tax assets. The mark-to-market on the available for sale is essentially on fixed income product, I would say. Because on the equity side, from top of my mind, it is something like minus 100. And on the shareholding portfolio, we are matching the detail of the press release, we have a slide showing capital gain of something like 30 to &#x20AC;40 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With that, Guillaume, if you have &#x2013; you want to ask more questions on that, you can go to our IR department.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>No more questions in the room? Okay, well thank you very much for your attention. Good evening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>