<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1226733" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3179</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Didier Valet, Group Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Didier Valet, Group Chief financial officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="4">Michel P&#xE9;reti&#xE9;</participant>
      <participant id="5">Maxence Le Gouvello</participant>
      <participant id="6">Jean-Pierre Mustier</participant>
      <participant id="7">Jean Francois Neuez</participant>
      <participant id="8">Derek De Vries</participant>
      <participant id="9">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="10">Guillaume Tiberghien</participant>
      <participant id="11">Kinner Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="12">Robin Down</participant>
      <participant id="13">Alessandro Roccati</participant>
      <participant id="14">Mamoun Tazi</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale's Group 2009 First Quarter Results Conference Call. The presentation hosted by Mr. Didier Valet, Group Chief Financial Officer will be followed by a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>And now, I would like to turn the call over to Mr. Valet. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. I'll first comment the first quarter '09 results, and as you've seen this morning the Group Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale reported a net loss of &#x20AC;278 million. I think that this was disappointing performance.</p>
          <p> The group &#x2013; on one side, the group operating and commercial performance for all the business lines, but on the other side also the impact of the environments decline on the Group's results which was marked by write-downs linked to the fall of the U.S. real estate market that took place in the first quarter as well as downgrades as that took place for monolines in February and March, especially on the MBIA and AMBAC.</p>
          <p>Beside from that additional markdown, we have seen also a rise in the cost of risk which is partly let's say underlying deterioration of the economic environment, but also we set aside during the quarter some general based provisions for &#x20AC;221 million and also we faced some provision fortification.</p>
          <p>We also booked in our P&amp;L the impact of volatility coming from accounting items, especially those linked to as the mark-to-market of the CDS on our loan portfolio in CIB, as well as also the revaluation of our own spreads. The net negative impact of these two items was minus &#x20AC;340 million.</p>
          <p>I should mention also that the Group has and will continue to have a solid financial structure with a Q1 ratio of 8.7% across Tier 1 of 6.5%. And as you've seen this morning we have announced that we will issue as a second tranche subscribed by the French government for &#x20AC;1.7 billion, raising as a Tier 1 for 9.2% and the core Tier 1 to 7% as we will use as a preferred share instrument.</p>
          <p>I will not comment on slide four, and if you go directly to the slide five, you have the full detailed P&amp;L of the Group for Q1 '09. You can see that the top line spend at 4.9 billion it &#x2013; that includes 1.9 billion of negative non-recurring items and the decline on like-for-like basis stands at 12%.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses are down on a like-for-like basis, minus 2.5% highlighting that the efforts made by all business lines to content their cost base in this slowing &#x2013; throughout slowing economy environment. On the cost of risk, you can see that it is a multiplication by 2.3 times to 1,354. I will comment later on this item, and so the net income stands at minus 278.</p>
          <p>On page six, just to detail a little bit more as a markdown that we book in Q1 '09 in the CIB business of &#x20AC;1.5 billion, and you have the four major items that led to these negative items. First of all, we face &#x2013; and you've seen that deterioration of ABS, asset-backed securities, and this is both in US and Europe during the first quarter, which for example certain ABS classes that went down by 25%, some of them went on up to 40%. And CMB also went down by on average minus 10% in the quarter.</p>
          <p>As a result, on our asset-backed security portfolio we recorded a minus &#x20AC;166 million of negative markdown and losses. On the CDO of unhedged US RMBS, which are in trading book, we have used let's say more conservative or stressed assumption set by Moody's, which during the quarter increased it's expectation in <mark type="inaudible" /> losses on subprime vintages from 11 to 13% for '05, 25 to 30% for '06, 27 to 36 for '07. And as a result, we booked minus &#x20AC;160 million of mark on these CDOs.</p>
          <p>On the monoline, as we announced late March, not only we faced the impact of the fall in value of underlying assets and more stressed assumption, but also we increased the reserve into the CDA on MBA and AMBAC previously we were reserving 49% of the exposure to these two monolines. At the end of March, we reserved 60% of the exposure. The impact so is minus &#x20AC;609 million for the sole monoline and on top of that we have also increased our reserving for CDPC by &#x20AC;257 million.</p>
          <p>Lastly, on the exotic credit derivative book, as you have seen we have registered &#x20AC;364 million linked also to the fall of European and US ABS. So the total impact from the top line is &#x20AC;1.5 billion negative. I should mention that in the net cost of risk of the CIB. We have set aside a link to reclassified assets of &#x20AC;58 million of provisions, but this is general provisioning. At this point we do not have any real incurred losses on this portfolio. Next page, on page seven, more let's say granular comments on the cost of risk.</p>
          <p>As I said in my introduction, in this &#x20AC;1,354 million, we have set aside &#x20AC;221 million for general provisioning, as well as &#x20AC;127 million for litigation. If you deduct these two items, we will be around &#x20AC;1 billion in total cost of risk and around 100 bps compared to the fourth quarter, so almost the same level. On the French Networks we've seen an increase, a further increase in the cost of risk at 68 basis points.</p>
          <p>This increase is essentially linked to the business customer portfolio where we have seen this situation in certain sectors like auto suppliers and construction. For individual customers, especially on the mortgage market, and cost of risk remained extremely low as we were expecting. In International Retail Banking, the increase from 122 to 173 during the quarter between Q4 and Q1, sorry, is essentially linked to Russia where we've seen cost of risk increased from 223 on average in Q4 for all three subsidiaries to 381 in the first quarter '09.</p>
          <p>If you look at the rest of the scope, the cost of risk was 92 basis points in the fourth quarter and went up to 113 for this first quarter, in line let's say with the impact of the economic slowdown in this region. On the Financial Services, you will see an increase from 160 to 197, essentially linked to consumer credit risk and essentially linked to two countries, Poland and Russia.</p>
          <p>I should mention that in Poland despite this increase in cost of risk the bottom line of our <mark type="inaudible" /> compared to last year, so this was absorbed by increasing margin and increasing volumes. Lastly in CIB, as I said we have the &#x20AC;68 million, which is on reclassified assets.</p>
          <p>If I split out this item, the cost of risk underlying is 509, and within that I have further &#x20AC;127 million of general based provisioning twofold let's say watch list counterparties, and again &#x20AC;104 million for litigation. So the big underlying cost of risk, especially cost of risk of this division in the region of &#x20AC;270 million for the quarter. If I move to slide eight and I look at it a bit more into debt with the Q1 position of the Group.</p>
          <p>First of all, I should mention that risk-weighted assets were stable, even down minus 0.7% compared to the end of 2008, highlighting let's say continued growth followed the spending in fall, that I will describe later on. But also a strong reduction in the risk-weighted assets into the market risk, which went down by 15% compared to the end of '08. As a result, the Tier 1 went down by only 10 bps, 8.8 to 8.7% and the core Tier 1 from 6.7 to 6.5%.</p>
          <p>The Board of Directors yesterday approved the decision to issue the second tranche of &#x20AC;1.7 billion to the French government, leading to a pro forma Tier 1 ratio of 9.2% and a core Tier 1 of 7.0%. This is subject to the approval of the AGM that is due on the 19 of May 2009. Thanks to this capital position, we believe that Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale will be able to face a severe credit stress, and also, which is more important to our company, its customer base essentially <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>I'll not comment on slide nine, and if you go to slide 10, a brief look at the trends that we've seen in the French Retail Networks. There you can see that loans and deposit continue to report satisfactory growth, with 8.4% growth on the customer deposit. Thanks to strong activities that we're seeing on the business customer side, with an increase of the deposits by 31% compared to last year. And on the loan side, we've seen a deceleration of the loan growth to 7.3%. It's 5.2% for individual customers and 9.8% for business customers.</p>
          <p>In term of revenues, top line went down by minus 0.9%, essentially due to the collapse that we've seen in financial provision minus 17% compared to last year. We believe that this impact will fade away across the year, and also due to the cut that we see in regulated savings deposits. The targeted &#x2013; in term of top lines for the French Retail Networks for the full year is in the region of plus 1%. Operating expense under control, they went down by minus 0.7%.</p>
          <p>If I look now on page 11 to the International Retail Banking business, you can see that the measures that we have announced since mid '08 are starting to bear fruit, i.e. we continue to have a relatively good dynamic in terms of gathering of deposits, an increase of plus 1.8% during the quarter. So if you analyze these trends, you are in the region of 8% on a like-for-like basis. And the fact that we have strengthened our loan distribution, we have only a growth, which was limited to 0.5% during the quarter.</p>
          <p>As a result, the loan-to-deposit ratio has improved at the end of March '09 compared to end of December '08. In terms of financial performance, you can see that the top line went down by 10.8% on a like-for-like basis, to &#x20AC;1161 million. There you have the impact visually of the duplication of the currencies of these countries, approximately 70 to &#x20AC;80 million is the impact of devaluation of currency when converted into euros.</p>
          <p>Cost/income ratio has slightly improved to 57%, and despite the increase in cost of risk. The return on equity after tax of this division stands at 15.4%. If you look at page 12, briefly, on the risk distribution of the portfolio, you can see so that in Russia, as I mentioned earlier, we've seen a strong increase, its 381 bps for 23% of the outstanding. Russia represent approximately 50% of the provisioning in term of million of euros, so 150 out of the 300 that we have seen in this division.</p>
          <p>In Romania, we've seen an increase from 61 basis points in the fourth quarter to 91. But which is I would say, well below the worst market expectation that we hear over the recent quarter. In Czech Republic, the cost of risk stands at 170 bps. There is one counterparty that was a provision in Q4 and Q1, which is almost fully provisioned now, which explain almost of the other ones of this quarter.</p>
          <p>The results of that is <mark type="inaudible" /> we are implemented as I say tightening measures income of loan approval policies. We are in the process to realign a provision in Russia. We are in this process to close some branches and to reduce the workforce locally. And we have also transitively launched initiative to operating expenses. Just to take an example from national bank targets, as we see its operating expense stable in '09 compared to '08.</p>
          <p>Overall, we do believe the divisions continue to have a strong perfect meeting capacity pre-provision. On the financial services, there you can see the impacts of the economic slowdown with on that regime in term of new business minus 5% for <mark type="inaudible" /> and consumer lending.</p>
          <p>When we look to the revenue line, it's went down by minus 1.1%. There we have seen the slight increase in consumer finance and equity finance and we are a decrease in life insurance because of lower level of the marketing. And also in fleet management where we move this quarter &#x20AC;57 million of provisions into sales of the cost on this due to the weakness of the secondhand car market. Overall as you can see the net income of the division stands at $31 million than minus 80% compared to last year.</p>
          <p>If you move to slide 14, you can see there that in asset management, we've seen a limited decrease in AUM, approximately $5 billion during the quarter, which has been minus 2.2 billion by outflows. These outflows are coming essentially from alternate investments and equities and diversified products, and essentially from our entities SGAM, AI and TCW. The business that will be contributed to SGAM has recorded 3.5 billion of net inflows and the assets under management of this Group represent &#x20AC;165 billion still compared to the end December.</p>
          <p>In term of revenue, SGAM has achieved 137 million. We feel approximately &#x20AC;50 million of impact coming from the crisis and from seed money. And the operating income for provision of the SGAM stands at minus 41 million. All this contributed to SGAM as a course of net income stands out around &#x20AC;15 million.</p>
          <p>In private banking, debt finance was satisfactory with net inflows of 0.6 billion, high level of margins. The net banking income went down reflecting the lower level of assets because of market decrease and operating income stands at &#x20AC;48 million. I will not comment relating to debt security services in Boursorama, Newedge. This three business line are impacted by lower level of interest rates and lower level of assets as a result net banking income went down by 20% and operating income by 79%.</p>
          <p>If I move now to page 16 in CIB. As I said, the operating performance of our corporate and investment banking business this quarter was extremely strong, with &#x20AC;2.7 billion of revenues at 76% compared to last year.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses went down by minus 8.2%, highlighting that sales year adjustment of the platform that was launched a year ago, which for example, front-office reduction by minus 6.8%. I should mention that we did reclassify any assets this quarter.</p>
          <p>On page 17 you have the detail businesses-by-businesses of the revenue distribution. You can see that in fixed income, currency and commodity it was an excellent quarter, with revenue multiplied by 2.2 times compared to the first quarter of '08. There we've seen kind of current activity, a performance of flow and structured fixed income and currency products, with revenue at &#x20AC;541 million.</p>
          <p>It is slightly below Q4, but we said in Q4 that there was an extremely active markets, following the Lehman failure, in term of rehedging and in term of volatility. So &#x2013; but the 541 million is a second-best ever performance of this platform.</p>
          <p>In trading we have achieved more than &#x20AC;1 billion of trading revenues, thanks to strong Treasury product performance as well as trading on interest rates. In financing and advisory, there also a very good start of the year, up 96% compared to last year, at almost &#x20AC;500 million.</p>
          <p>Thanks to a strong performance of natural resources and infrastructure financing, as well as cross-selling, and in certain activities like ECM and DCM we have increased our ranking and we are now Top 3 or Top 4 depending on which ECM or DCM.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. This is the operator. I'm sorry to disturb you. But I need your name and your first name to present you to the moderator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>But it is satisfactory overall in this market context and a very strong trading performance with &#x20AC;354 million revenues achieved this quarter.</p>
          <p>As you can see trading was accounting for almost 50% of revenues of CIB this quarter. I should mention, and it is extremely important that we did not increase the risk appetite of the bank, because the value at risk decreased by 20% Q4, Q1 from 70 to &#x20AC;56 million, and so we have our stress test analysis.</p>
          <p>I will now comment on slide 18 and go back directly to &#x2013; go directly to the conclusion on slide 19. Overall we can say that 2009 will be a challenging year with a global recession that has been confirmed by IMS a couple of weeks ago.</p>
          <p>This environment with weaker <mark type="inaudible" /> performance of banking sectors, especially looking at credit risk environments. But we believe that for Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale, we have capacity in terms of operating resilience to absorb this recession or the impact of the recession, and deriving the cost of risk and we can also count on our sturdy financial structure in terms of both capital and liquidity.</p>
          <p>In terms of realignment that we already announced, to face <mark type="inaudible" /> environment we have put the emphasis on stronger customer realization, which will be done across the group, but Michel P&#xE9;reti&#xE9; will be able to comment later on this key in the CIB reorganization that we are currently implementing.</p>
          <p>We continue to reduce our risk; these are the troubled assets or globally our risk management and risk appetite. Operating expense has, and will continue to be under control. And lastly, for the businesses affected by the crisis, essentially asset management, as you've seen, we have announced some structural adjustments with a combination of <mark type="inaudible" /> and the merger of <mark type="inaudible" /> with Lyxor.</p>
          <p>On the longer-term, we do believe that Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale continue to have a potential &#x2013; growth potential which is intact. Thanks to its universal banking business model, and the balance between developed and emerging countries. We do believe that emerging countries, after this recession, will continue to be able to deliver a stronger growth compared to developed Europe.</p>
          <p>We will also maintain the capital allocated to our corporate investment banking franchise to 25%, including goodwill. This is in our view a good balance, and provide the CIB business the capacity to continue to accompany the customer base and to gain market share. So overall, I think we believe that the presence in the country that we have chosen, continue to offer long-term banking development prospects and so will be fruitful for Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale and its shareholder.</p>
          <p>I have now finished and I'm now keen to answer with Michel P&#xE9;reti&#xE9;, Jean-Pierre Mustier, Jean-Louis Mattei, Benoit Ottenwaelter to your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have our first question from Mr. Kian Abouhossein from JPMorgan. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. My first question relates to slide seven. Could you run us a little bit through your thinking on provisions going forward and the trend that you're seeing in each of these divisions? And in particular, do you see a deterioration? Is this an expected provisions for the year that you're accounting for and how should we see the collective provision going forward. How should we see them going forward in terms of collective provisions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Ken, good afternoon. On slide seven, I'd say, I think in term of what we mentioned collective provisioning. And say, we have currently &#x20AC;1.3 billion of outstanding of collective provisions. We <mark type="inaudible" /> that at this point there should be &#x2013; if there is an increase &#x2013; a marginal increase, but not until the <mark type="inaudible" /> doubtful or come back to normal condition is best which is consistent lets say at this point of the cycle.</p>
          <p>On top of that if you look at the underlying more specific risk in older division we can say that in the French network we could see a slight further increase in the coming two quarters intervening at 70, 75 bps. International retail banking it will be essentially linked to the trends in Russia, which was deeper lets say than what we are expecting.</p>
          <p>Financial service there also margin increase but we are not seeing and in the CID as I said if you strip out litigation and if you strip out the collective provisioning, lets say we should be in the region of &#x20AC;400 million a quarter which seems to be fair.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And but can we just go one-by-one then in terms of your SMEs in French retail, do you see further deterioration, is this related to specific loss effect you had should we see this as a level that you're comfortable with going forward in the credit crisis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At this point what we can say that the side that we &#x2013; for which we made some provisions specific into Q1, we are relatively consistent with those that we see already in Q4, so its more complimentary provisions that we set aside in Q1.</p>
          <p>But nevertheless we believe that in Q2 there could be lets some further activity depending on the debts of the economic environment, there could be some further new names and so we would have to be cautious so why I say it could go up to 70,75 points in Q2 and Q3.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in &#x2013; with respect to international retail Russia in particular, how do you see that developing as expected to increase further?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So currently in Russia we've seen a deterioration in terms of private individuals on one side where we have some consumer lending exposure, and we're showing some of let's say business customer let's say which are large to midsize corporate. The cost of risk as I said stands at 381 during the quarter and 415 for the <mark type="inaudible" />. There we continue to believe that as we said in the previous quarter, to see NPLs in the next 18 months growing to the region of 20% even if something irrelevant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that would imply further provisioning increases?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On a quarterly basis, not sure because let's say when you look at the level of provisioning that we have in Russia we have NPLs at this point which stands at the top of my mind 7% and they are let's say covered 85 or 90% by provisions at the end of March. So you should make the minor gap let's say from 7 to 20%, which is 13% on the lets say 21 months. You can see that with the cost of risk of around 400 bps, it's a little bit higher and an LGD of 53%, so you come to that level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> 7.4% NPL at the end of March, which are covered 99% by provisions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if I look at general provisions or collective provisions, do you think that as still being an ongoing trend? Will that be an ongoing trend that you will take a collective provision throughout the quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said in terms of collective provisions we believe that we make &#x2013; we made a strong default this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so the 221 is not likely to be reconducted in the coming quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If I can ask very briefly on margins, could you just talk about, French retail margins declining? Also I would have expected your international retail margin should increase, why don't we see that trend and what should we &#x2013; how should we look at this going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In domestic retail banking the margins, let's say there are two parts of the answers. On one side in the lending business, we've seen an improvement of the margin on lending either enough that's need to account the increase cause of liquidity.</p>
          <p>And I would say this is a process that took place in late '08 and beginning of '09 and since the beginning of '09 lets say we have the capacity to accompany the decline that we can see in market interest rates.</p>
          <p>Unfortunately on the other side, let's say on the deposit side, you know that on our sight deposits we have, let's say cost of resource on zero and so we place that &#x2013; that's a 10-year bond yield level index, I would say, property of that.</p>
          <p>Previous declining interest rate is biting into the sight deposit market. And on the regulatory deposit, despite the fact it has been cut twice in Feb and in May, let's say nevertheless it is not fully consistent, let's say with the level that which we replace this many. So there also we have seen a tightening of the markets also on the regulatory deposits.</p>
          <p>So on one side predictive items will be lending, on the other side, slightly negative for the positive side. If we turn to the international retail banking business, I would say we would have to look on the country-by-country basis.</p>
          <p>But on one side on the deposits, we have achieved a strong performance as you've see with 1.8% increase of the deposit base during the quarter. And there let's say this has been also linked to some pricing effort that we made to attract deposits. We continue to be below market prices, overall, nevertheless this also increased our cost of funding slightly during the last quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on &#x2013; just briefly on equity derivative revenues or equity revenues. How do you see the progression? Do you see the environment getting tougher on the flow side and can you discuss a bit over the structuring.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will let may be Michel fairy put on &#x2013; on the equity derivative trends.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the equity derivative market has been affected by a decline in volumes, which is translated directly from the decline of the value synthesis. So overall, our client production has being dropping by something like 30%. But I think in a relative basis, it's a very good performance, if you compare it with our competitors.</p>
          <p>And also, the trend we are seeing is that there is still a huge demand for the ETF market, where remain with a 22% market share. There is also a steady demand on the volume business and the flow business, where we are number one with close to 60% market share.</p>
          <p>And also, interestingly, the structured product demand has been increasing compared to the Q4 '08 by something that 40%. So we think that in a depressed market in terms of environment, the client business for us has being reasonably good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just on the structured product; is it more retail or is it corporate or is it an institution demand that you're seeing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The &#x2013; on the structured product side, it's more the financial institution drive than retail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. Sorry for taking so much time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's fine. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Maxence Le Gouvello from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon, everyone. My first question will be on the French retail. I just wanted to understand why we have such a slowdown in term of new opening of deposit accounts, because the usual run rate of last year was in the range of 20%. What we have seen in Q1 is pretty low.</p>
          <p>The second one will be on the existing derivatives. When do you believe that potentially we can have is going to end because it's roughly a fourth quarter in a row that we have hits in the range of &#x20AC;360 million. And lastly, it will be for the asset management. Would be interested to hear Jean-Pierre speaking about what the clients are interested in term of products?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon Maxence. On the first question regarding the new accounts opening in the French retail markets. Yes, it is slightly below what we've seen in Q3 and Q4. Let see what we can say that we have also seen a slowdown on the new business in term of housing loans. And housing loan is a way for us also to sort of capture new current account.</p>
          <p>And as I said, and we're going to say &#x2013; the new business in some of housing loans went down by 40% compared to last year. So definitely, we've lost a kind of tool to acquire new customers, which is expanding partly, this is the slowing down that we seen in the first quarter. On the <mark type="inaudible" /> credit achieves well, I should mention that in the fourth quarter, it went positives.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> negative, but clearly what we've seen this quarter, you're so part of a consequence of the &#x2013; deterioration of the reaching of the monocline, because on the southern top and we've mentioned the appendices that we've published on certain part of this portfolio, we were protected by monocline. And in the way we were calculating that healthy managements and the hedge of this position.</p>
          <p>We are considering up to 31st of December that the protection coming from monoline was fully efficient. We have a <mark type="inaudible" /> let's say, looking at the deterioration of switching of monocline. We have taken the decision to consider that the protection was no longer at equity efficient.</p>
          <p>So it was as it is essentially a BBB to BB production. We have too much from the first quarter that the production was 40% efficient and in that case, the things has lead us to see what was the long protection position turning to slightly long and just explain why we've seen some a negative impact on P&amp;L in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll let Jean-Pierre comment on the asset management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bonjour Maxence. We have seen the interest from actually on the US side &#x2013; from US clients going back to non-agency MDS. So you see the price today of mortgage-backed securities offering quite a good yield even if you take quite a stressed market conditions as far as potential for the loss of the real estate market.</p>
          <p>So there has been certain number of requests or proposals and interest as well from by using downward pension fund about non-agency, which it could be as well on the back of the side being willing to acquire of course the probability of private partnerships, a number of assets by launching this initiative, which match before the market.</p>
          <p>On the European side, there has been good interest on investment grade credit product with relatively short-term duration. We have launched a number of product and we have collected &#x20AC;1 billion on three to four year investment grade credit product, which gives a relatively good yield to clients with quite diversified credit exposure.</p>
          <p>In full, we have seen on the money market side, I don't think we last very long. So I think money markets rates are quite low. And we see clients willing to diversify out of that. I think the competition as well from the bank deposit versus the money market product will mean that the <mark type="inaudible" /> potentially reverse.</p>
          <p>And finally on the pension fund side, we have seen clients actually showing gain some interest on the alternative site, but clearly moving more towards a least OpEx of product on managing accounts, where they can have transparency as well as liquidity</p>
          <p>And showing interest as well on more index type of product or ETS type of product to have more liquidity, when they want to go out of position. There has been less concentrate on the value and deep value product which we push in the market to clients. I mean clearly the market conditions right now are quite good for deep value investors if they can hold the precut sometime.</p>
          <p>So we have seen in the past two months, well, I don't if it's green shoots but we have seen renewed interest from value investors, looking at value asset class and clearly willing to take a little bit more risk then compared to January and February.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Just back on the retail, your competitor yesterday has enclosed some good performance on the insurance and also on the commission fees on the retail side. Can you give us a little bit more ideas of how much has been positively impacting your commission base in Q1 in the French retail?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the insurance segments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So it seems that this fee financial commission went down by 17% and then check if I have the detail in term of commission coming from the life insurance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The way you consider it to me &#x2013; there was nothing on that, I guess, if you wait just 20 second, which will be done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so in the financial commissions the decline is essentially linked to new receipts where we've seen minus 19% from the life insurance, the decline was limited to minus 14% year-on-year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just last point -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Life insurance, that account for approximately 50% of the financial commissions that you've seen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And then, last point regarding your &#x2013; the right issue &#x2013; the issuance of the preference shares?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's not the right issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Sorry. The preference shares &#x2013; the timetable should be roughly what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What, sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The timetable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The timetable, well, we need to get the authorization, as I said, from the EGM, and I think that after that there will be above that approved issuance. So it will be in the coming, let's say, two to four weeks time as the preference shares will be issued. In term of profits, the totalment of shares was sum of pref share and ordinary share. This should represent 7% share additional.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Jean Francois Neuez from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello there. Good afternoon. This is Jean Francois from Goldman. Just one question really on the write-downs, I mean I take your point about your cash generation at the pre-provision profit excluding order write-downs, competitive provision, it's actually &#x2013; you're right a lot and &#x2013; but the thing is that this has been eaten up entirely basically by the write-downs.</p>
          <p>And my question is just about your outlook for further write-downs in the coming quarters, whether you believe that it's more or less over or whether you believe that you will have to do to provision for more in the coming quarters? And let me ask you this, maybe, just to give us a sense with the return of some recapitalizing the market, where would your marks on the assets on which your provision is about 1.5 billion stands at the end of more or less today in your way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jean Francois, good afternoon. What I can say that the level of market we've taken as of end of March are reflecting on one side the level of indices which were low, because it was a slight rebound since end of March <mark type="inaudible" /> . And those was <mark type="inaudible" /> losses that we have used in my view, let's say reflecting net interest trends said by Moody's and <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>So based on that, let's say, I cannot exclude that we will have any further knock down in the coming months or quarters. But I believe that the market that we have taken at end of March, relatively conservative and based on certain prices, which are relatively low. So if there were some message won't be definitely <mark type="indiscernible" /> magnitude of than what you're seeing in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And so what do you think your marks have done since the end of this quarter &#x2013; of the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I would not comment my daily P&amp;L during April, but let's say what we've seen just to comment in terms of market is that there was renewals of liquidity on certain ongoing assets in both UK ABS and US ABS. And I'd say we have tried to take some opportunity due to this liquidity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So just a quick follow-up here on the CDS portfolio. Have you realized some of the CDS, I mean, lots of them must have cumulative gains like to-date? Obviously they came down a little bit in the first quarter, but did you realize some of those gains? Did you decrease some sensitivity, just can you give us a sense us to where the CDS position would stand and their sensitivity to further straight tightening in a way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So in the CDS portfolio, what we've done in the first quarter, we crystallized 200 million euros approximately of budget in mark-to-market. But as you mentioned this did not prevent us to book almost 500 million negative in the income of negative mark-to-market.</p>
          <p>What I can tell you is that, you're seeing the rally of the credit spreads, corporate credit spreads in April. And so we've seen so far further negative impacts of this credit portfolio and negative mark-to-market in April.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, that's all for me. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Derek De Vries, Banc of America-Merrill Lynch [BAS-ML]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good afternoon. I actually had two questions if I might. You disclosed that 16.4 billion of doubtful loans, I was wondering if you could give some more granularity on where those set. Because I don't think they tie up exactly with where your provisions are on a quarterly basis. I think you sure about 1.2 billion in international retail and 900 million in financial services, but I'm not sure that's a like-for-like basis. So could you just give a little more granularity around that 16.4 billion of doubtful loans and where they set, that would be helpful. And the second thing is just more of a strategic central and eastern European question. I mean it's clearly a long line of Western European banks with assets in Central and Eastern Europe, because there are subscale, I didn't understand the business when they bought them. I would expect that they would be quite willing to sell. And I was wondering where you as a sort of market leader in that region said, would you be in that queue of banks willing to sell assets in Central and Easter Europe, or would you sort of do what you did last time we were in down cycle and looked to be an acquirer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So let's start with the wonderful news of 16.4 billion doubtful loan ratio of 3.8%. If I give you the ratio, let's say, the divisions, we have a 3.5% non-performing loan ratio in France, 6.8% in retail outside France. Let's say it's a &#x2013; you mentioned some trends across &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; 3.5 at end of March, it was 3.2 at the end of December. In retail outside France 6.8 &#x2013; 20.3 at the end of December. In <mark type="indiscernible" /> 7.5, it was 7.0 at the end of December. And in CIB, it is 1.9% and it was 1.8% at the end of December. So, you can see that there is a slight increase across divisions of the non-performing loan ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your second question, sorry, was on EBIT?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, essentially there is a lot of banks that would be sellers of bad business, 0because they are sort of &#x2013; etcetera. Last time you were in downturn, you were guys were a buyer. I'm wondering where you are today? Would you be in the list long line of sellers, or would you consider buying in that region? What's your view?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're definitely not a seller. As I said in my presentation, let's say, we continue to &#x2013; we convinced that for the medium term, to be &#x2013; up presenting CE, and in Russia, it's important and has a great potential. I think and to be acquirers, it's a little bit too early. Let's say at this point, it is to be a focus on our own strengths to look at <mark type="inaudible" /> and we look at certainly later on, there is some opportunities whether let's say we are willing to stays in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And there is nothing about subscribing to the pref shares from the government that would preclude you from buying assets outside of France?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. The difference in CIB was just to be able, I said, to be in the comfort zone, in the well comfort zone in term of Q1 position and to our company and our customer base.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Jon Peace from Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon, everybody. I have three very quick questions please. The first one is on the cost of risk. You guided us in previous quarters to give us a stress test where you were looking at the stress cost of risk of about 130 basis points, so &#x20AC;5.3 billion. If I have to annualize the Q1 cost of risk, I'll come to 5.4.</p>
          <p>Now, I know that there are some reserve builds signification in here. So maybe that's not quite the right way to look at it. But I just wondered if you were to reel on a stress test today, what number might you use for a really stressed cost of risk?</p>
          <p>The second question is just back to exotic derivatives. It's quite difficult to go from the five year equivalent disclosure, which is quite volatile to at this stage what the P&amp;L charge might be. But I know in the fourth quarter, you gave us a underlying exposure number for exotic derivatives, which has come down quite a lot about 8.6 billion.</p>
          <p>I wondered if you could just give us that number at the end of March. And then finally, just a question on the dividend. I know it's very early in the year to think about this, but how determined are you to hold the dividend at last year's levels, I mean if the EPS were to fall on prior year, would you countenance another cut in the dividend? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jon, good afternoon. On your first question regarding the stress test, cost of risk, yes, we made roughly <mark type="inaudible" /> the previous quarter. If we take the, let's say, range of the 130 and maybe 140, 150, looking at the fact that the economic slowdown is a bit stronger than expected.</p>
          <p>We do believe that we continue to have capacity to have a Tier 1 ratio at the end of December '09 in the region of around 9%. And of course, you want to change the region of 6.5 to 7%, which is, in our view, coherent with our business model. So we do not publish it, but nevertheless, we continue to have the same type of approach.</p>
          <p>Regarding the question on the exotic credit derivatives, you have, on page 13 of the financial supplements all the detail. Just in term of net exposure <mark type="inaudible" /> risk equivalent, as I said there is a big shift that we've seen from a loan protection to a slightly loan credit position. It's linked to the change that I mentioned in term of monoline hedge.</p>
          <p>To have the size of the underlying assets, you'll have the footnotes. We have a total of &#x20AC;6.7 billion of assets, yes 6.7 &#x2013; it was 8.9 at the end of December and it's 6.7 at the end of March. On your last question on dividends, sorry, it was -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The dividend question was, how determined are you to keep a flat dividend with prior year, if the EPS were to fall on last year, because of the Q1 loss. Would you target more an absolute dividend, or would you target a payout ratio, and therefore would you countenance the dividend paying less this year than last?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not mentioning anything regarding the trend that we're expecting this year. But clearly, what we always said is that we have a target in term of payout of dividend or payout ratio. And so it is the first indication. And then if we look back to 201 or 202, we have accepted to see the payouts are going high, that's on the upside, just to maintain the dividends in term of absolute terms which will be a tradeoff, but it is clearly too early to discuss it at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's clear. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Guillaume Tiberghien from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I've got two small questions. The first one related to your guidance for the revenues of domestic retail. You say 1% compared with last year, I think there was a &#x2013; in Q4 last year a big capital gain, I think it was 75 million. Does the 1% exclude the capital gain or -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And the second point is on the provision for specialized financial services. I think you've been kind enough to give us some sort of a guidance for all the other divisions. But I don't think you provided anything for that one. Could you give us a feel maybe as to how you think provisions would evolve from that? Because you do mention the, I think, the German SMEs that given ALB I suppose. So is there much more rise to expect in that division? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as I said on that division, if you split between the two last components, the cost of risk in consumer lending was 342 basis points in the first quarter. On the leasing it's 95 or 98 basis points. What we could say that's on the leasing we've seen some limited, we see some impact of, as you mentioned, middle market trouble in Germany. But we have seen so far  something, which is increasing but still very much under control. So nothing to carry &#x2013; to worry too much.</p>
          <p>And in the cost of risk in consumer finance, I would say that there is a kind of <mark type="inaudible" /> already seen trends in developed markets which are almost to set of our exposure. And I mentioned that the increase that we've seen in Q1 was essentially concentrated in Russia, where we've seen a cost of risk slightly above 700 basis point, that's where we would see 500 on average in the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>And the cost of risk in Poland that France also upside again also above 700 bps was absorbed, let's say by the gain and by the <mark type="inaudible" /> that we see in term of volume and in term of margin. I mentioned that our subsidiary in Poland has seen its net profit increasing compared to last year. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Lakhani from RBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Yes, hi. Yeah, I've got three questions. Firstly, want to start off with slide 17, where you provide the breakdown between client and trading NBI of the capital markets revenues. Could you perhaps remind me of the definition between clients in trading, perhaps some clues as to the driver of the outsized trading results that we saw in fixed income and the sustainability on that number?</p>
          <p>Second question relating to the loan &#x2013; the trading assets that you've shifted into the loan book, and the benefit from that, which I calculate as something like 17% of your tangible common equity that you've avoided via markdowns, what you see as the future credit risk on those assets? And final question was just to get a better feel again on the extent of the de-risking that you've done on the equity derivatives portfolio, particularly as relates to dividends?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I'll take the first question on term of definition of what we're putting in account and trading. We've maybe a too wide definition of trading of CIB, which means that certain trading activity, which are market-making or they are linked to a core business are the same tradings.</p>
          <p>So clearly, we believe that we are more maximizing our stabilities, like-for-like basis or asset values using that for years, and the definition of what we put in trading or trading related compared to most of our competitors.</p>
          <p>As I said, on the &#x20AC;1 billion of the fixed income trading, &#x20AC;500 million are mostly coming from Treasury business, so let's say a carry trade and yield curve position. The rest, I would say of the &#x20AC;500 million. We can say that's a part of that is linked to the reversal of certain business, which took place at the end of December, and the rest of it's just a very strong environment that we seen on the rate markets in Q1.</p>
          <p>Regarding the question that you had on the reclassified assets, I would say there was a &#x2013; first of all, in terms of shuttle mark-to-market, I think we should be more and more extremely cautious on that figure, while it is &#x2013; it was 2.4 billion negative shuttle mark-to-market in Q1. But clearly, let's say the five that we utilize to classify these assets, it means that we are able to change the way, let's say, we manage the book.</p>
          <p>If we were, let's say, having certain assets in mark-to-market, we would have also taken some decision in term of hedge or eventually in term of sale. Now, we believe that we hold them, I would say for a longer period of time. So we do then the credit aspect. And as I said, the revision that we made at end of March <mark type="inaudible" /> million euros but it was general base provisioning.</p>
          <p>So at this point, we didn't see any credit risk, let's say, item or event on the asset that we reclassified as of, end of October with a level of sales discount that would carry on at this point. Regarding the de-risking of equity derivative, I'll let Michel answer your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The equity derivative side, overall, I think reduction has been reaching something close to 25%, which has been targeting the dividend position, which on the peak has been reduced by between two times and three times. And now we haven't met reduced dividend position, which was lower than the &#x2013; anyway the one with the competition, and we see more than a stabilization today of the dividend trend.</p>
          <p>The second exposure on the equity derivatives is related to coalition, were &#x2013; our position has been more or less divided by two since the peak of last year. And which was already lower than most of &#x2013; what you could see in competition. In the volatility side, it's more or less flat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>May I just come back to the answer on the first question, the 500 million that you mentioned on the carriage rate yield curve. Following on from your answer, is that something therefore that we should consider as one-off driven by the shift in the yield curve in the first quarter or as sustainable, driven by the trends in yields curve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is in between we think that it's not a one-off, because the yield curve remains supportive with the type of business, which is not sustainable because I would say at some point, monitory policies likely to change. So, at lease for the coming two quarters, I am &#x2013; maybe not at the same magnitude, but the trends will remain the same in the coming two quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Robin Down for HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I had two questions, First one, can I just follow-up from Kian's question there as well. Did I hear right and say that roughly half of the trading versus the fixed income was reversible spreads from Q4?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. What I said &#x2013; I said that we have one billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Half is coming from the yield curve position and the rest we could say that between 100 to 200 million euros on the <mark type="inaudible" /> that is in reversed in Jan that was negative I think the P&amp;L in December.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay, okay. The question I had actually was just a follow-up from one of the earlier question. In terms of the CDS portfolio, maybe I missed in the response, but did you give us some sensitivity on the CDS portfolio, going forward? I know you crystallized some of the position in Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on this, I will give you the sensitivity, but there's two items. First of all, let's say that the CDS has a certain maturity and so it's positive or negative mark-to-market that we're seeing until they are crystallized from sale. I'd say, we will go back to the old at the extension of the CDS, this mean that this will amortize, although the rest of the lifetime of this portfolio.</p>
          <p>And then you have the sensitivity images which is linked to the movements in terms of spread, and then I would say for one bps change so on the upside, we will gain &#x2013; we will make a positive revenues of &#x20AC;1.2 million, so plus 1 bps of the spread so widening of the spread, plus 1 in term of revenues.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, this is let's say more kind of macro approach at the level of indices. If you're seeing in your portfolio come to top, which suddenly see its spreads housing, let's say from 1200 to 600, in that case of course the impact that got two place in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>So it's negative in terms of accounting, in terms of counterparty risk. This mean that the markets as partly overshooted or so is more confident in part of what we have in the loan book and so this means also that the counterparty risks that we would eventually face on this counterpart is improving.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So can you just remind us what the sensitivity was at the end of December?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was &#x2013; at the end of December, it was 1. &#x2013; I think 3.4. It was 1.4, sorry. It went slightly down. It was 1.4 per bps at the end of Q4 and it is 1.2 per bps at the end of Q1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the final question I promise. Do you know the rough average maturity is on that portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is three years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Three years. Okay. Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Robin. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Alessandro Roccati from FPK [Fox-Pitt, Kelton]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I have a question on your group underlying profits. Now if I take your quarter, the state of net profits are just for the non-recurring items as the slide number 11 of &#x2013; number nine, sorry, of the supplementary part. And a net of this tax rates &#x2013; or I would say 30%, I get to underlying net profits on a quarterly basis of 1.1 billion, and that's quite consistent.</p>
          <p>Now, I know a lot of these and I get to 4.4 billion on net profits for the full year. I'm just wondering whether you're comfortable with this figure if you can make any comments, and tell us that when do you think you can achieve this level of profits?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on the 1.1 billion you mentioned, I follow you on the calculation, which is to see &#x2013; probably this is a non-cash item, but we should mention that in the 1.1 billion first time that you calculate. We have this exceptional level of trading in CIB of 1 billion in the fixed income, which as I said part of that has good replicate and continue in the coming quarters. But nevertheless not the same type of level, at least can be stipulated for the rest of the year. So I think you need to be more cautious on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no further question. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have a question from Mamoun Tazi from MF Global. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. I have three questions. In terms of the capital increase from the government, would you consider like what BNP did by converting even the hybrids into prep shares, thereby adding 100 basis points to your quarter one, or will you be satisfied with just the 1.7 billion in prep shares.</p>
          <p>The second question is with regards to the timing of the kitchen sinking that you've done with regards to your credit portfolio, and the Millerman exposure, why have you waited until the first quarter of 2009 and not have done &#x2013; I know you've done something last year when the situation was getting worse.</p>
          <p>And then the third question is about the credit derivative portfolio, sorry, I didn't get the answer when you gave it earlier. I'm just trying to understand if we can expect more losses there or if the losses should be done now? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Mamoun on your first question regarding further capital increase and insurance of prep shares, felt on new share. And the authorization that we have had to TCM is just to issue of 1.7 billion, so only distinct contrast we will not convert the first tranche from IP to prep share.</p>
          <p>On the second question, regarding the say what you call kitchen sinking. As I said, we just mocked as we made in the previous quarter, our portfolio to the level of indices. That's where I said those level at the end of March and we have taken to consolidate the worsening of the situation, but I said these &#x2013; is actually the methodology that we use consistently over the last quarter.</p>
          <p>And on your third question, on this CDS portfolio, as I said, yes that was further tightening of spreads in April, and so this means that the revenues from the mark-to-market of the CDS are at a say a negative quarter-to-date.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. But the question was about not the CDS portfolio, but the exotic derivatives?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't comment on <mark type="inaudible" /> trends or on recent trends.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because if you have the exposure declined from 8.4 to 6.9.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is the underlying, yes. But then you have the question of the net position, and you can see that in the slide 13 of the apprentices, we have a slightly net long position of &#x20AC;300 million as of end of March.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What does that mean, having a slightly net long position of 300 million, does that mean that, that's the most asset risk, or is it -- should be interpreted differently?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, this means that we are almost even on this position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on the kitchen sinking, you said that you used some of Moody's ratings as inputs to your numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, Moody's count losses is the assumption that they have renewed and have dated on the February regarding to the U.S. residential mortgage losses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So those are not been on the indices, and therefore there is an element of subjectivity there. And you said yourself that you were more conservative, therefore, why wait until now to be more conservative?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no I said that we have taken some initiatives to adjust for these cumm losses across the last 18 months, and I'd say, we have taken that as of end of March. We believe that when you look at this assumption let's say, with 30% cumm loss and this cumm loss on the starting balance and this is not on the current balance. This means that there is discounting high level of delinquencies on the underlying portfolio, so that's all I mentioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from <mark type="inaudible" />. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the cost base, or the CIB division in Q1, it looks pretty high to me income to previous quarters. Can you just give us some idea or we should expect I mean for the coming quarters regarding your cost base in the sub division and the restructuring I mean, which is going on. The second question is regarding the litigation, could you give us some more ideas of what's going on, and what we should expect them for the coming months and what was the basis for your calculations and assumptions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would let Michel answer the first question regarding the trend on the cost base of CIB.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the cost has been gained down by something like 7% to Q1 '09 versus Q1 '08. And it reflects the adjustments we'll be making on the front office side and by reduction of our head count by close to 7%.</p>
          <p>The trend is that we will maintain a very strict discipline in the management of our costs, and we should not expect a cost increase and overall on the front office side and we should expect stabilization as well as the cost on the reversal side. You know that we have been investing significantly last year on a transformation and remediation program which should not be &#x2013; which did not occur again this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>May be to add a few words on that. As we mentioned also that in Q4 that trend was difficult, and so as you can see in terms of bonuses there was some low level of accruing in Q4, while in Q1 there was a kind of normal level of accruing compared to what is satisfied in Q1 of last year that you have seen that is slightly down. On your question &#x2013; your second question was related to dilution of EPS, is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. To litigation, I mean, with this -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Litigation. Sorry, litigation. On the litigation, well, this is no new &#x2013; litigation there were some data that you could find, we believe that we were provided for as of end of March, we should not expect on this points as a same type of litigation provisions in Q2. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a follow-up question from Mr. Guillaume Tiberghien from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I had just a small question with regard to the corporate center revenues. I think it was a negative 210, and that included about 70 million of negative markdown on equity. Is minus 140 a decent run rate to expect, it's obviously worse I mean in the past, is that just reflecting the higher funding cost? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no further questions for the moment. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We have a question from <mark type="inaudible" />. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, it's Anka from Execution. I just had one &#x2013; the follow-up question. Firstly, on asset quality, if I calculate correctly, I would assume loan loss charges outside of Russia will probably around 120 basis points in international retail banking. And I was just wondering, given your information about expected increase in non-performing loans in Russia, if you're willing to give us a similar indication for Romania and Czech Republic and what this could mean for the rise in other countries, a loan loss charges in other countries within international retail banking with the exception of Russia. And then in terms of the capital, I was just wondering what has made you change your mind on why to take part of the state funds as a present shares. And at year-end results you gave some helpful guidance on your expectation of risk-weighted assets growth and I was just wondering if you can please confirm that you were looking around 10% growth of which three to four percentage points as risk migration. And then lastly, I'm sorry if I should know the number, but this CBS portfolio size is just 44 billion as of year end or am I looking at the wrong number here? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. So regarding your question on the asset quality and trends as we could expect for other country. As I said so for Romania because fiscal &#x2013; in the first quarter it stands at 91 basis points, which is likely gradually increase. We believe that in the kind of stress scenario which we go up to region of 250, this year, but at this point it seems that the pace at which it is increasing is lower and so we remain more optimistic than this stress scenario.</p>
          <p>In Czech Republic, as I said, we are at 170 this quarter. Then I would say just one side is accounting almost of 50% of the total. So that's the underlying expense is 140 then we can say it is nevertheless, it is a big chunk of the total. As far we are in the region of 90, and there also we should increase and we have also some stress test something in the region of 260 but again we are seeing some more in terms of guidance in the quarters. So mind view is that we should see an increase in Romania, and maybe at least for the coming two quarters something similar to Czech Republic investments we have seen in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>On your second question on credit share, why did we change our mind. We said that we were very likely to take the second tranche at least in a hybrid form, and that we were actually waiting maybe, we were able to wait up to beginning of August looking at the timetable set by the French government. What PVD view that, assets and while the economy slowdown seems to be a little bit stronger than what we're expecting. And so we are taking that same option because we are expecting that just it and the quality one ratio is important for the markets for the regulators , that's why we've turned to pressure . I reminder you that the additions between the two instruments has been much more limited compared to our initial expectations due to a renegotiation that is placed during March. Lastly, on the size of CGS portfolio, it has been strongly reduced by &#x20AC;44 billion as of end of September, and it is 24 billion as of the end of March as I said, we made some sale and some issues of the hedge were no longer efficient Basel II that is why what I would say useless in terms of market context.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And &#x2013; thank you very much. And just lastly on the risk rate assets growth, so you will be looking at around 10% for this year or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. You've seen that we are down &#x2013; end of March compared to December. So I think that we are likely to be low single-digit figure in terms of gross or risk rated assets this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a follow-up question from Maxence Le Gouvello from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. My question was on the &#x2013; risk related asset for the year and just have been answered. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a follow-up question from Mr. Guillaume Tiberghien from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I promise it's the last one. It's on the CLOs. In Q4, 97% of the tranches that you had in CLOs were AAA rated, and I think you only have now 87% AAA rated. You have a high attachment point of 29%, but where are we at the movement in terms of underlying assets &#x2013; the underlying losses for the assets that are old, pretty much junk rated? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you mean the attachment point of 29%, it seems that we continue to have a 29% protection.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But where are we at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The 29% that <mark type="inaudible" /> because it is still protecting us. And they are not depreciated yet till now. They've not subject &#x2013; they're not support from losses, and there are at a 29% protection at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With just a write down scenario that is more extreme as you can see on slide six of the appendixes, where on top of the 29 protection, our scenario, even if nothing had happened yet, we have stress that's in 9% losses on alt functions, but it means that we can wait to 29 plus 9. So 38% of let's say, losses and still let's say we are &#x2013; we have to stress further our scenarios and as you see <mark type="inaudible" /> (72.39) slide six, as the 21% of that have (72.43) doesn't include the fact that in the CLOs, there is certain cash component. If we were to look at the cash components, the attachment points would be increased to 34% on the sole I think pretty underlying.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So you basically say that you can have 36% losses before you incur any losses yourself, but where are the losses at the moment in the underlying?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our underlying losses are zero at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And in downgrade, you've seen the AAA is following the designated Moody's (73.11) which mention that certain not senior AAA, but only AAA will be one graded. it took place, AAA we have that approximately 1 set of senior AAA and two-third of adjust AAA CLOs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And this is &#x2013; are essentially to five integer before all five or four integers (73.33).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a follow-up question Mr. Kian Abouhossein from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Just a quick one on the exotic book. Are there no options to unwind this position and take a one-off hit, have you looked into that because what form &#x2013; what I can see is you must be losing money again in the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think that on this portfolio the complexity was linked to the complexity linked to the hedge that we get from monoline especially.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As the monoline hedge is fading away, I would say, I think the management of position is likely to be less difficult I would say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you tell me, how much of the marks you have taken from monoline versus basis risk?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You mean on this -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I On the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say that just we had &#x2013; just to make that short on the 360; we have approximately two-third, which is linked to two-thirds to basis risk and one-third to monoline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm still surprised the basis risk is so high?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The basis risk is more on the RMBS, where we've seen some Alt-A underlines, which have, let's say, worsening kind of a subprime. So, we were hedged ADs, and but the basis risk got down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But you're saying the cost &#x2013; you don't think there's any chance that we see this being on round in the trade?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do our best to do to manage this position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no further questions for the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think we would say at this point, thanks very much to all of you to have attend this conference call, and see you soon on the road (75.35). Thank you. Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale 2009 first quarter results. We thank you all for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>