<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1366344" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call - Paris</title>
    <date>2011-02-16</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3179</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric Oud&#xE9;a, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Didier Valet, Group Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Sammarcelli, Deputy Chief Executive Officer and Head of Retail Banking, France</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Bernardo Sanchez Incera, Deputy Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Jean-Francois Sammarcelli</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">S&#xE9;verin Cabannes</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Bonjour.</p>
          <p>Good morning to you all and thank you for attending this presentation of our Yearly Results. I am here with the Members of the Executive Committee, General Management, Didier Valet our CFO, in particular. They will help me comment the results of the Group. Before giving them the floor, let me just make a few comments on our 2010 year.</p>
          <p>2010 was an important year for two reasons. First, the confirmation of the financial rebound of the Group, this is the case because the net income is &#x20AC;3.9 billion for the year, the Group net income. And secondly &#x2013; the second reason is the launch of our transformation program, Ambition SG 2015. I do believe that the world is really changing in debts and that banks have to change.</p>
          <p>As you know, we launched in 2010 a conversion plan project, which would like to help the bank change. What have we been doing within the framework of this change? First, we want to start building a customer driven bank, focusing on customer satisfaction. We took a series of initiatives &#x2013; the initiatives differ according to the categories of customers for retail banking, for instance innovating &#x2013; innovations &#x2013; initiatives were taken in terms of innovation of services and products, response time with regards to a loan and for the CIB just to take this example as well.</p>
          <p>I really believe that the regulation is going to lead to a development of activities on the capital markets and that the role of banks as intermediaries between loan issuers and investors will be strengthened. And therefore, we keep on building our expertise in large sector on large markets for major currencies to help our customers, to support our customers. And M&amp;A and advice is essential and gives proximity to our customers.</p>
          <p>Along with those policies, we also &#x2013; have also set up the policies to manage our talent. This is absolutely essential and for concession we have a collective policy in compliance with the rules &#x2013; the European rules with regard to the variable concessions of employees. And performance management plan for the 160,000 employees of the Group and share the objectives and it's always focused on customer satisfaction.</p>
          <p>The second aspect is the operational system. Given the situation, we have to industrialize our processes, make our processes more efficient to improve customer services and to reduce our cost. All projects have been launched in that field. The projects are quite ambitious and promising. And we have started to adapt our business portfolio with the disposal of the IT leasing and the strengthening of our franchise with the acquisition of SMC, Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; Marseillaise de Cr&#xE9;dit. This is for this transformation plan.</p>
          <p>As I said the rebound is there for the Group and commitments were held. Commitments met first dynamic contribution to the financing of the economy. We'll see that in the slide. And active policy to finance the economy, we responded to the needs of the customer. A well-managed risk profile, those results are obtained with very good risk profile in a very volatile environment. And we continue improving the risk profile with the reduction in legacy assets.</p>
          <p>So altogether Group net income of &#x20AC;3.9 billion. All business lines are making progress. This is important to outline that and there is a solid momentum for retail. The financial structure is quite robust with a core Tier 1 of 8.5% and Tier 1 ratio of 10.6%. And on this basis, the governing Board proposed &#x20AC;1.75 per share for 2010 corresponding to a payout ratio of 35% with a scrip option. So here again we're completely in line with what we announced to the market.</p>
          <p>Didier is going to give some more detailed comments on our results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric, and good morning to you all. Slide four, if we look at the major items, you see that the net banking income for 2010 has improved plus 20%, &#x20AC;26.4 billion and if we look at the fourth quarter, the progression is plus 31.8% on a like-for-like basis. As for the operating expenses plus 4.3%, reflecting the efforts of the Group as conducted in 2010 and the recruitments made to strengthen as service rendered to the customers, as mentioned by Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric.</p>
          <p>So you see the net banking income and the operating expenses, therefore our gross operating income has increased by almost 60%, &#x20AC;9.8 billion. And the cost income ratio, the cost income ratio despite in mark-to-market, you see at &#x2013; in the lower part of the slide, a cost income ratio drops and reaches 63.4%. The cost of risk has decreased over the whole year minus 30%. The net income &#x20AC;3.9 billion and for &#x2013; and you see the ROE is 9.8% for the whole year.</p>
          <p>Page five, just to put down to have a global overview, let's look at the main drivers for the Group and the efforts made to improve the operating efficiency. Since 2005, you can see that the NBI progressed on average by 6% each year. This is &#x2013; there is a regular growth, coming from the French Retail Network from &#x20AC;6.3 billion of NBI in 2005 to &#x20AC;7.8 billion in 2010, therefore plus 4% on an annual basis, which is slightly higher than 3% our growth indications for the period of 2010-2012.</p>
          <p>International Retail Banking, a more dynamic increase, plus 16%, double effect, first, the growth potential of those markets. This potential remains high in the mid-term and external transactions. During the period, we had the acquisition of Splitska Banka in Croatia and the consolidation of Rosbank.</p>
          <p>For CIB, the NBI is more erratic that over five years you see that the average growth is 7%, and with &#x20AC;7.8 billion for 2010, we are not far away from the figure and you have this crisis on the sovereign debts and <mark type="inaudible" /> during the fourth quarter. For SFS and Insurance, growth rates of 12% on average a year, reflecting the potential of this business. And for GIMS, it is &#x2013; we have a change in scope with the creation on the 1st of January, 2010 of Amundi which again came out of the consolidation scope.</p>
          <p>So in panel with this revenue growth in the long-term, let's have a look now at the improved operational efficiency. And before looking at what we have to deliver for Ambition SG 2015, let's come back to what was announced at the beginning of 2008 this operational efficiency plan. Aiming at improving the gross operating income by &#x20AC;1 billion compared to 2007. And you see that in 2010 we reached our objectives with our gains &#x20AC;970 million of gross operating income gain coming from the optimization of business processes, the optimization and the creation of GTS, pooling all the IT infrastructures in France and abroad, and the optimization of external expenses. This was possible therefore to have the savings compared to 2007 and improve the operational efficiency.</p>
          <p>Page six, 2010 &#x2013; let's concentrate on the cost of the risk, 2010 Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric said, 2010 so an improvement of the risk profile, minus 23 basis points, 83 basis points in 2010, a regular reduction in this cost of risk and excluding legacy assets. For the French network, we are in line with what we've said at the beginning of the year with cost of risk lower 53 basis points. The cost of risk is very low and very good has of individual customers and companies and the cost of risk remains a bit high for medium size companies.</p>
          <p>Abroad, you have an improvement &#x2013; a significant improvement in Russia. The cost of risk was divided by two and we have now 180 for the 86 basis points. And for the Czech Republic, we have reduction almost by half 68 basis points for 2010 against 125 in 2009. In Greece, the cost of risk remains high, and we have in Romania, since the second quarter is &#x2013; the cost of risk is higher by 300 basis points.</p>
          <p>Let's look at the CIB. The level is quite low, zero for the fourth quarter in basis points, which reflects the very good quality of the portfolio of the structured financing and conventional financing. And for the legacy assets, you see that you have &#x20AC;696 million. The NBI is slightly positive 60 &#x2013; &#x20AC;71 million for this activity. So we have low &#x2013; the guidance was between 7 and &#x20AC;1 billion of negative earnings before tax. Those assets are controlled, and we have the cautious policy &#x2013; we had a cautious policy for this fourth quarter for recovering or hedging of those risks. And for Specialized Financial Services and Insurance throughout the year, we observed a drop of the cost of risk. At the beginning of 2010, we saw this reduction for the equipment financing, and it was the case as well during the year for consumer finance.</p>
          <p>Poland is having a high cost of risk &#x2013; or used to have a high cost of risk, but since the second quarter this cost has reduced, and it is positive for the fourth quarter. So only Italy now remains a problem for 2011, before this division really becomes completely efficient in 2012. Altogether, we have strengthened the coverage ratio from 72% at end 2010 versus 68% at end 2009. So there is rise in the group doubtful loan coverage ratio. You &#x2013; and this is to an absolute level as well.</p>
          <p>Page seven, financial structure, Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric has already commented on this point. We are in line with the planning presented during the third quarter with the addition of Basel III, core Tier 1 ratio of 8.5% at end 2010. And you have provision for dividends in cash on 31st of December, 39 basis point and we proposed the payment of dividend in shares. If we have a response time of a 60%, one of the assumptions made you see that we get back 24 &#x2013; 25 <mark type="inaudible" /> of core Tier 1 in June after payment of the dividends in shares for similar RWA.</p>
          <p>Now page eight regarding the Group's structure. What's important in this structure is that we paid great attention to 2010 with over &#x20AC;39 billion of deposits which was felt in all our business lines. Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois will tell us more about that, for a good performance in France, for private individuals and corporates.</p>
          <p>Above and beyond this commercial rebalancing, we easily carried out our financing program for 2010, raising &#x20AC;29 billion. A bit more than our objective and we were opportunistic on the market, which is ready for that. So the 2011 financing plan, which is &#x20AC;26 billion of senior debt in addition to &#x20AC;2 billion in subordinated debt. At the bottom of the slide you can see that as of the 15th of February, we will have already carried out &#x20AC;5.6 billion in issuance. So, the program is largely underway.</p>
          <p>That's it from my presentation. And now back to Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois to tell us more about France on slide number nine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>2010 was a very dynamic year in terms of the financial results, commercial results with NBI up by 4.5%. SG really played its role in financing the economy with an improvement in growth in loan outstandings by 4.1% versus the fourth quarter of 2009. This growth has been mainly driven by the 8.9% increase in housing loan outstandings since the fourth quarter of 2009, supported by a record level of real estate loan origination of &#x20AC;19 billion. The gradual rebound in business customer activity has also contributed to this trend.</p>
          <p>Investment loan outstandings rose by 3.4% compared to the fourth quarter of '09. And we even exceeded the figure that we agreed with the authorities to lend to SME's by granting &#x20AC;5.8 billion of medium, long-term loans. In 2010, we also launched socially responsible contracts such as the socially responsible savings scheme, enabling individual customers to optimize their payments to charities and also environmentally responsible products such as the environmental card for businesses.</p>
          <p>With 400,000 new customers in 2010, including165,000 from the integration of SMC and Cr&#xE9;dit du Nord, the franchise therefore grew considerably. Total personal current accounts increased by 192,000 units in 2010 compared to less than 125,000 in 2009. So we're very successful therefore when it comes to deposits particularly the active for savings with private individuals with a record level of &#x20AC;4.3 billion compared to &#x20AC;2 billion in 2009.</p>
          <p>More generally, deposits outstandings or customers included &#x2013; including enterprises rose by 11.9% compared to the fourth quarter of '09, thereby, contributing to the continued improvement of the loan-to-deposit ratio, which fell by 11 points over one year. Given the 1.5 point fall in the cost income ratio, the French networks contribution to Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale's Group net income grew by 22.4% compared to 2009 to reach &#x20AC;1.2 billion.</p>
          <p>We'll now look at outlooks for 2011. The SG Ambition 2005 (sic) [SG Ambition 2015] project started in 2010 will be stepped up in 2011. The development policy for the French network is structured around multi-brand strategies relying on the sharing of best practices, maintaining the identity of the three branch companies and enabling targeted objectives to be defined for each network. Synergies have been developed in all of the Groups' businesses, insurance, private banking and corporate and investment banking. The information systems have also been pooled between the three French networks to offer a harmonized, a uniform platform with the Convergence project, which is &#x2013; which will also be extended to the main subsidiaries and broaden retail banking.</p>
          <p>And lastly, the SG iPhone application has been awarded the financial application of the year in France. Initiatives taken in 2010 to place customer satisfaction at the heart of our concerns were intensified in 2011, notably by extending the length of service of customer relations managers and by simplifying loan approval processes, by improving our product strategy and synergy with the Group's other businesses. For example, private banking already working with the SG network and will also start to work with the Cr&#xE9;dit du Nord network as of January 2011. We will also develop a new pack, the new JAZZ pack, JAZZ II with our everyday banking offering.</p>
          <p>Lastly, we'll continue to develop remote banking services, opening up a direct branch in spring 2011 and redesign the Cr&#xE9;dit du Nord and Boursorama web portal. In organizational terms our priority projects are completing the integration of SMC with Cr&#xE9;dit du Nord within less than two years. And the first deliveries of the Convergence projects will cover the CRM workstation.</p>
          <p>And now I will give the floor to Bernardo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>After this review of the French networks we must point out International Retail Banking with a fine performance given the macroeconomic situation, which is extremely heterogeneous. This result amongst other things is due to a very active sales activities with improvement in loans and deposits in our international activities to reach &#x20AC;65.2 billion and &#x20AC;66.4 billion respectively, giving us a loan to deposit level which is balanced at 98%.</p>
          <p>The commercial sales performance which we can see in the increase in the number of individual customers internationally with 12.3 million customers about, just under 2%. This improvement depends on the region. We confirm the profitability achieved in Russia with &#x20AC;13 billion in retail banking. Furthermore, we are optimizing our operations in Central and Eastern Europe, the least homogenous region opening up branches and closing down branches to support the investment efforts made by our Greek subsidiary. In the Mediterranean Basin in Africa and the French territories, we have seen an over 10% growth in the number of customers and deposits. In that region we opened up 61 branches in 2010.</p>
          <p>Now each region in greater detail, starting with Russia. Russia, we are in the process of building the first private banking network in Russia in terms of the number of branches and private customers. We are also managing an integration that is now well underway. On the chart to the bottom right, we have a presentation of the quarterly income in Russia. And we can see how at the end of the year we achieved the performance expected, exceeding breakeven at the end of the year and this result should be confirmed in 2011.</p>
          <p>This financial recovery is now managed by i.e., an integrated unified management team controlling the transformation project in the country. In particular, with a legal consolidation process where all of our entities will come together within a single economic unit with a universal bank, which should be the outcome of this merger of Rosbank and BSGV, which will be completed in the middle of 2011. This bank will hold 100% of a specialized subsidiary in finance.</p>
          <p>At the same time, as we restructure our activities from a legal perspective we cannot commercial initiatives, we've a lot of potential in the country. We are very proactive in retail banking as well as &#x2013; well, to improve our relations with private individuals. We are now working on our product offerings have a broader range, but also on the attitude of our teams and branches to bring about changes in a bank where we are adopting our methods and commercial principles to focus on customer's interest on a proactive attitude with respect to customers.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we are strengthening interaction between our Retail Network and Corporate and Investment Banking, so as to bring to Russia our knowhow in the rest of the Group, to use it as a lever to bring about improvement in our business. Operational activities or performance in Russia means merging our information systems and this will be completed by the end of 2011. In Central and Eastern Europe, we continued our policy in two areas; to strengthen sales intensity in countries where we think our presence is immature, and also to help our market share to grow in the rest of the region and to steer our business so as to be profitable.</p>
          <p>Our presence was well received this year, since we received the award for the best bank in Central and Eastern Europe, the Euromoney Awards in May 2010 with our peers, highlighting the efficiency of our operations.</p>
          <p>The Czech Republic posted a fine year with a good performance due to sales that were quite significant, supported by an efficient operational efficiency with a 28.2% improvement in our net Group income, especially with private individuals up by over 7% in customer deposits. The Group in 2010 has shown the resilience of its model in Romania. Romania is a country that's experiencing a very difficult economic crisis. And our subsidiary, BRD was able to adapt its operational mechanisms by being very reactive in its investment in 2010 and also intensifying its sales with a strict control over risks, enabling us to preserve a significant level of profitability.</p>
          <p>Whereas the economic situation is extremely in a bad situation in Greece, we are continuing with our adjustment policy with a reduction of staff quite significantly, being very cautious in any loans allocated, very strict and this is a way for us to support the very different &#x2013; difficult economic situation. We're continuing to develop our other operations so as to gain market shares in areas where we can more particularly in Bulgaria and in Serbia. In the Mediterranean Basin and in Sub-Saharan Africa, a region that clearer today is in the spotlight. I'll come back to that.</p>
          <p>But at present you should not overshadow the quality of results obtained in 2010, a dynamic region. In all these countries we achieved a Group net income of &#x20AC;352 billion up by over 7% versus the previous year, a fine performance, therefore. And we could see that in the Mediterranean Basin, in particular with our four subsidiaries in the Mediterranean Basin generating &#x20AC;253 million in Group net income with banks, with a very interesting sales performance.</p>
          <p>Almost all our indicators exceed 10%, strong banks that are well balanced, I'm looking more particularly at the loan to deposit ratio in Egypt, now at 67%, giving us room to maneuver in addition to operational efficiency and the dedication shown by our staff, putting us in a favorable position in that country. We are also well balanced in Morocco, with a loan to deposit ratio of 17 &#x2013; 117%, and a high profitability. In the rest of the zone, we're continuing with our sales efforts to support growth, and by opening up more banking services in the country. And this is reflected in our mobile banking offering, where we have started to develop an innovative offer to bring semi-banking or banking solutions to a population that's becoming more and more bankerized. In 2011, we plan to launch a light bank for people with very simple economic or financial needs.</p>
          <p>I spoke earlier about the current events and of course we're keeping a close eye on new developments in terms of the political and social situation in the countries where we operate. Situations on which we're focusing over the short-term, but that do not call into question any of our long-term strategic analysis. We are extremely well structured, robust with banks that are well integrated in the Group, with highly competent staff putting us in a good position to continue to support growth in those countries once they revert to a more stable situation. It does not invalidate our short-term actions, but our short-term views remain unchanged.</p>
          <p>In Corporate and Investment Banking in 2010, we continued our transformation program based on three priorities. The first priority was to support our capacity to help our customers, first of all meeting and improving our commercial teams. We recruited 400 new people amongst our sales teams, senior bankers, in particular, specialists in originator, M&amp;A specialists and also new market activity sales forces. This was more in the second half of the year than in the first half, and which partly explains a part of the increase in costs in the second half and the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>We also extended our product offering, you may have noted that we obtained the status of primary dealer in dollars and Sterling pounds at the end of last year and the beginning of this year. SGCIB is amongst the global leaders in U.S. denominated products and this will now allow us to extend to offer and to sell products in dollars and pounds to our international clients. We've started a new platform Alpha for executing Forex trades and we at the start of the year took over the RBS Sempra teams for commodities in the United States. After doing &#x2013; after <mark type="inaudible" /> we launched two products &#x2013; the two projects, one in Europe for building our primary or commodities platform, but also the United States that we've noted.</p>
          <p>The second priority in 2010 was to rebalance our Corporate and Investment Banking activities, more particularly by investing more in intermediation and advisory services, and by strengthening our staff as I said before. We also strengthened our geographic presence in high potential areas, especially in Central Europe, in the Middle East and Asia. The last priority this year which would apply in coming years will consist in transforming our operating model for Corporate and Investment Banking. We delivered the first result of the Resolution program based on controlling operational risk and automating processes so as to optimize our costs. The gains in 2010, thanks to Resolution reached &#x20AC;120 million leading to significant investments in the second half of the year, a second reason for the increase of our costs. But that will be temporary. Finally in terms of legacy assets, Didier spoke of the impact in terms of the strength of our portfolio, we disposed off of &#x20AC;8.6 billion throughout 2010.</p>
          <p>On the next slide you can see the first results, let's say, of our strategy to develop our business. First of all, in our core businesses the leadership was once again confirmed and acknowledged with awards that are the one of the most prestigious for equity derivatives, structured products. We can also note that in our new growth areas in terms of M&amp;As but also for Forex activities we received new awards with an improvement in our market shares in 2010. On the equity at M&amp;A markets we doubled our market share in Europe and for Forex we increased by 20%. We can also see that in fast growing areas we have received interesting awards.</p>
          <p>In terms of revenues in 2010, net banking income generating &#x20AC;7.8 billion which can be considered as being robust and balanced. This NBI is well balanced between three main activities, first of all, financing and advisory with an NBI of &#x20AC;2.7 billion in 2010 up 3.5% on a like-for-like basis. These activities were particularly buoyant in financing and advisory and structured financing which is particularly dynamic in 2010 with NBI up by 17%. We have seen a pickup in market activities in 2010 versus 2009. On the market our performance is satisfactory on a very volatile environment with NBI of &#x20AC;5 billion for 2010 down by 33% versus '09, well balanced between equity fixed income activities with &#x20AC;2.5 billion in NBI for equities down by 28%. In this activity we can see a good demand rising for structured products in 2010. On the other hand the drop in volume and pressure and margins for other product.</p>
          <p>For fixed income, we have started to benefit from cross assets between fixed income and equity activities, with a significant improvement in our structured activities, in fixed income commodities, in particular. For flow products, even though our market share has improved in 2010, we saw significant pressures on margins this year, thereby explaining a downward trend versus the previous year, which was exceptional with respect to commodities. So NBI that's where we closed to what we call our revenue generation capacity at &#x20AC;7.8 billion on a volatile environment. In terms of costs, in 2010, we launched a significant investment program as I said before to develop our business and therefore recruiting new people in the front office, but also operationally with the Resolution program.</p>
          <p>Even though we had major investments, we maintained our cost to income ratio below 60%, thereby placing us in a very competitive position amongst the all CIB banks. You can see the image there with SG which is number one. In terms of compensation ratios in 2010, stood at 5.7%, a bonus that is stable versus the previous year despite the improvement in revenues and staffing as I said before. And lastly, well, we spoke about legacy assets before. So NBI reached &#x20AC;1.7 billion in 2010 a fine contribution therefore to the Group's net income.</p>
          <p>Improvement in Specialized Financial Services and Insurance can be shown on this chart with quarterly results that were all positive and consolidated. They reflect excellent performance in insurance, where we had a record net life insurance inflow with over &#x20AC;5.4 billion in net inflows with sustained growth as well in property insurance up by over 30% in revenues. A rebound in corporate financing with the growth of operational vehicle leasing activities, where we currently have 841 vehicles in our fleet under management, up by 6.5% versus the end of the previous year. This activity is supported by recovery of the second hand vehicle market and contributing therefore to a very good performance.</p>
          <p>A start of a recovery in consumer finance with a pick up in the second half of the year in terms of new loans, giving us year-on-year an almost stable result with a very significant improvement in the last quarter, with 24% improvement in this business, this improvement. We saw a 21% margin which is quite comfortable for the entire year. So recovery in consumer finance which is almost stable, except for Italy, where new launch generated are declining with strong car financing growth giving us all-in-all a slight improvement in France and Germany, a reduction in Italy, and a sharp improvement in Russia. Our business has picked up in a &#x2013; very dynamically.</p>
          <p>In 2011 therefore, we expect to consolidate our specialist positioning. We're maintaining our growth strategy in insurance with a high level of interactivity with our sales networks in France, Morocco, Russia and the Czech Republic. We will support this growth dynamically. We have a strong minded policy to improve in long-term vehicle leasing with this ability for our teams to innovate by broadening our offering and by working with innovative enterprises. In consumer finance we will strengthen our multi-country program with partnerships and through interactions and synergies with our retail banking network.</p>
          <p>Lastly, we will continue to refocus in consumer financing by providing servicing expertise to our partners and secondly, by developing our positioning in car financing where we have a strong position, and well-established expertise in France, Germany and Russia. We shall use this expertise to continue with this business in Italy. We plan to finalize recovery in 2011, which will still be a difficult year and in Italy, we expect a turnaround as of 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's now move on to Private Banking, Global Investment Management and Services 2010. Growth in &#x2013; so private banking, our inflow is &#x20AC;4.3 billion, plus 5.7% annually, in line with market and our asset management annual contribution to Amundi, &#x20AC;100 million, group net income &#x20AC;289 million.</p>
          <p>There has been a decline in revenues coming from cash flow. Private Banks of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale has been awarded the best bank in 2010. For services to investors, a good business momentum in 2010 with major contracts and we signed contracts with U.S. Bancorp in the US, National Bank for Abu Dhabi, and Oddo in France. We will see the first result in 2011.</p>
          <p>Assets under custody grew by 8% or &#x2013; over 9% in one year, &#x20AC;3,362 billion. In a low interest rate environment and favorable to revenues, the security business continued with its operational efficiency plan, enabling it to reduce its operating expenses by minus 10% into two years. This division was named Best Securities Provider Europe and Custodian of the Europe.</p>
          <p>Newedge, we maintained our leadership on the US market with 12.1% of market share in 2010. We reduced our expenses. Our cost/income ratio improved by more than 5 points in one year to increase this contribution to the Group net income. Asset Management saw a significant outflow in 2010 for the first three quarters of the year. What is positive is that at the last quarter with TCW, there is a positive inflow, which reflects the new moment of the activity is the performance of TCW and MetWest. They were awarded by Morningstar, ranking &#x2013; ranked 5-stars by Morningstar.</p>
          <p>So this &#x2013; the integration is successful. And Amundi made results, an annual contribution of &#x20AC;100 million for Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale, twice as much as what you had the previous year and the integration of <mark type="inaudible" /> takes place under good conditions. Net income for GIMS increased from &#x20AC;201 million to &#x20AC;289 million in 2010.</p>
          <p>Private Banking for 2011, strengthening the commercial setup with &#x2013; and we are going to have in France and abroad this startup product expertise. In the service &#x2013; Securities Service division, we continue to develop high added value services. And US will continue its development of the prime brokerage activity begun in 2010. And as I said, 2011 should be a progress year for the asset management business.</p>
          <p>To conclude, you have the complete overview of 2010, as you saw, with positive trend for all our business lines. In a few words, I would like to draw the conclusions and give you the outlook for 2011.</p>
          <p>First, central scenario is a contrasted worldwide recovery with a strong growth in emerging countries, but with the risk of inflation and a progressive recovery and modest recovery in developed countries.</p>
          <p>It's clear that the indicators are very short-term indicators. What we received from our customers are rather positive, but we remain vigilant on a series of risks because of major imbalances on the financial fronts, debt, public deficit fronts and macroeconomic one as well. So we will remain cautious for the following quarters.</p>
          <p>Secondly, in regulatory terms, 2010 &#x2013; in 2010, a number of decisions were made regarding capital within the framework of Basel III. So we adapt to those decisions. When it comes to the liquidity proposals currently under discussion, we will &#x2013; some rules do not seem to be really designed properly, so we'll continue a constructive dialog with the regulator on that point and other issues remain to be solved, especially the systemic institutions and the resolution mechanisms.</p>
          <p>We believe and we know that it's legitimate to strengthen the solidity of the financial system, but the banking system, especially in Europe, you know that there is a specific structure of financing economy, and we should, as a bank, be allowed to continue our work. So in this rapid evolving environment, more than ever, our target is this Ambition SG 2015 project. It is a relevant project. And in 2011, we're going continue to roll out this project to strengthen this universal bank model, well balanced, the customer <mark type="inaudible" /> diversified from a geographic and business point of view.</p>
          <p>So we're going to carry on with our roadmap. You have our main objectives, our main targets, the list on the slide 22 is not exhaustive, but this is important for the management team. The first target for the French network is to roll out pooling projects we have mentioned. We know that this year, there will be a change in the interest rate of <mark type="inaudible" /> and this will have a weight &#x2013; an impacts on the revenue growth. It is important to prepare for the operational efficiency future.</p>
          <p>Second target is in Russia, Bernardo mentioned it. It is essential to finalize this legal merger in Russia and roll out our universal bank model. Third target, capitalize on the first result of our investments in corporate investment banking, so we have recruited people and we will expect a revenue growth of the CIB in 2011.</p>
          <p>Fourth target, complete the turnaround of consumer net finance activity in Italy, so that in 2012, we are quite satisfied with those businesses; improve our operational efficiency throughout the group to fund our investment. 2011/2012, we'll see a lot of investments. The IT systems require investments first before being converted into savings, so we would like to protect our cost income ratio, improve the group's risk profile.</p>
          <p>If you look at 2010, the resilience of the CIB revenues is remarkable and it's completely in line with the profile we have in our mind. And we will keep on managing the legacy asset portfolio downward quietly and regularly given the quality of those assets concerned in our last assessment.</p>
          <p>And a final point, the launch of the new brand platform at the end of the first quarter, and this platform will support this ambitious transformation program. So 2011 will be a very active year, mobilizing our teams.</p>
          <p>I would like to thank all our employees for their extremely positive dynamism throughout the teams. The bank is changing. In that, the step one has been successful. We are turning to step two with the same determination and 2011 will allow us achieve the financial and strategic reserves for 2012, especially a group net income of &#x20AC;6 billion.</p>
          <p>This is it. And we are ready for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I have a series of questions. First, I would like to know your vision on the margin for retail banking in France. What can you say about the impact of the coverage policy and the special saving schemes and the volume with the strong growth of deposits versus loans and the commercial margin in the loan business for the real estate? It seems to &#x2013; this activity seems to be profitable again after the crisis.</p>
          <p>Next, liquidity, what is your vision on the development and the adjustment of ratios you expect from the regulator? What do you say to those regulators, what would you like to have? And how do you adjust to those ratios, especially for the collection of deposits? This is for the French retail business. There is a strong growth of deposits. What still remains to be recycled?</p>
          <p>And for the CIB business, you probably adjusted a number of transactions, consuming a lot of liquidity. Where do you stand there in these adjustments and what is still to be done. And the third point on the legacy assets, you said &#x20AC;8.3 billion. Could we have a breakdown of this figure? Do you think that you can do even more in 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Jean-Francois. For a more detailed presentation of the French Retail Network, <mark type="inaudible" /> for the CIB and liquidity, how do we adjust our model and then the legacy assets, and I will do a wrap-up on the structural questions. Jean-Francois.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For margin, Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric has said in his conclusion that the growth, the increase in the rates of <mark type="inaudible" /> will have an impact on our margin significantly. Plus the 2% of our growth in our markets, that's what it represents. And this increase in the interest rate from <mark type="inaudible" /> to the other saving books, this is mainly due to an inflation effect even if the short-term rates remain at the same level.</p>
          <p>So it has a significant impact, a rather negative impact, and we have to take that into account, of course, in our NBI adjustment for the future years. Good news is that we completed 2010 well in terms of volume, for deposits and loans. The business was quite sustained. And for insurance, the activity is good as well. So the commercial activity is good, but we have headwinds coming from the increase in interest rates.</p>
          <p>For loan markets, you said that the load for real estate are profitable again. Well, they were not really that profitable at the end of 2010 because of the scissor effect between the balance rise in the rates &#x2013; long-term rates, with a slower impact &#x2013; a lower impact on the rise, the increase in for customer rates. But altogether, we believe that there will be an increase between 1% and 2% of the NBI, slightly lower than the average plans, but we had 4.5% in 2010. Therefore, we are ahead.</p>
          <p>For the monetary of CBM, the unit trust, UCIPs, it's clear that we &#x2013; the remuneration for individual customers was very similar to or close to zero. So we motivated the individual customers to choose other types of investments.</p>
          <p>For companies, the monetary UCIPs are still interesting because of a very good liquidity and possibility of coming and going, and it is very flexible. So for companies, those UCIPs are good and for the &#x2013; it was not to the detriment of the monetary UCIPs.</p>
          <p>Didier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. To add to what Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois had said, the 1% or 2%, it is excluding SMC. SMC was consolidated over one quarter in 2010. So this is excluding SMC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Off-mic, I'm sorry. It's always on the like-for-like basis, even if there is a slight change in the scope here and there. For the liquidity ratio, what we can say is that, what we are discussing with the regulators and with the European representatives of the commission and the parliament are the following ones.</p>
          <p>First, the definition of what is the liquidity buffer. Even if this buffer was extended to tier two last summer, it seems to us that the definition of this buffer remains too restrictive, too concentrated on a class of assets which are volatile and risky, when the environment is not good. Whereas assets such as shares, and then we'll have to apply the appropriate haircut, we're not saying that it's 100%, but the market &#x2013; this market even during the Lehman crisis showed that it was good and most banks were able to use this leverage effect in the management of their short liquidity.</p>
          <p>And for the denominator, there are two restrictive definitions there. For instance, what is an operational relationship with a corporate? The vision is a bit Anglo-Saxon; it is not perjorative, but it's based on cash management. And you have 25% if you have an operational relationship and 75% if this relationship is not operational. So we would like to value the intensity of the relationship.</p>
          <p>The French banks have a good expertise in cross-selling and in sustainable relationships. So we would like to have this intensity of relationship to be &#x2013; we would like then to take that into account. And you &#x2013; there are some actions already implemented, &#x20AC;39 billion of deposits in 2010 shows that we have been active in 2010 and a very active policy for deposit, especially, for the French Retail Network.</p>
          <p>The definition &#x2013; the final definition of those ratios is not certain. We will have till 2013 or 2016 to comply with those ratios or observe those ratios. For the CIB business, we contemplate possible actions to take for the loan financing, as Didier said. We have the back-up lines. Those back-up lines are very costly in our ratios. Those backup lines will not be renewed probably. Then financing to an institutional &#x2013; financial institutions is a real problem. So we are thinking over this financing as well.</p>
          <p>The market activities, first, we want to have more eligible assets in that are in the &#x2013; through transactions with counterparties, we could have more eligible assets. Then we want to reduce the size of &#x2013; we would like to strengthen our capacity to collect deposits. We were not necessarily well equipped in the previous year, so we would like to strengthen our sales staff as well for the market business.</p>
          <p>All of these steps are being taken, it's too early to speak about them as yet, but we are making major strides to keep this ratio stable. From a strategic standpoint, I think there are a few ideas you must take away. Basically savings on bank's balance sheets. We continue to work on that as we did in 2010.</p>
          <p>For corporate investment banking, secondly, we will see the end of a certain number of funding, probably reducing relations from one bank to another, for example. It's just that we would like this process to be carried out orderly. We have clients, customers and activities behind that. So this will be a gradual process. And paradoxically maybe, but in Europe, we have the capital markets that must grow. The banks will have constraints in capital and liquidity that will be more &#x2013; with more constraints and you need to finance the economy at the same time.</p>
          <p>There will be companies and private individuals which will have needs for loans, savings connectors, investors, who are not necessarily in the same geographic area. And our role will be to connect both, and this is where to offer to our issuers a choice of the various markets available, the various currencies, it all becomes meaningful. Yet the euro, which is core in our business, but the ability to open up to the sterling pound, the dollar and maybe to a Chinese currency if it were to become global in ten years time.</p>
          <p>This is the type of growth or change that can enable them to access different types of investors and issuers. We've started this transformation. It can be done in two quarters. It affects the entire banking environment. We've started early. We will continue gradually, build in mind the interests of our customers and the economy. We must &#x2013; I think it would take more or less four years in line with regulatory changes. But we need to readjust step by step. In a very determined manner with progressive adjustments, we will adapt our business, ourselves to the new circumstances in our business. With respect to legacy assets, there will be a natural decline in our portfolio which will lead to a drop in that field as well.</p>
          <p>Let's come back to the last question, the breakdown of the &#x20AC;8.6 billion in disposals and amortization for 2010. Just over &#x20AC;5.6 billion in disposals and over &#x20AC;2.9 billion in amortizations impairment, always rounded upwards when you add up both. What's important to stress is that the &#x20AC;5.6 billion in disposals, you saw that it was more to be seen in NBI, which was positive for the year, show that we are able to manage the portfolio and to deleverage with no or even a positive impact on the group sales figure.</p>
          <p>As regards trends, we will continue to deleverage the portfolio in 2011, as Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric said. And in the appendix, you have an update of the external valuation gathered by <mark type="inaudible" />. A part of the portfolio is one where we will need to pass on provisions. For all the other assets, our valuation of loans and <mark type="inaudible" /> is higher. For these assets, for CNB assets, we have a liquidity and prices that have risen significantly, not based on the best rated tranches and that has continued since the start of the year. So we now have a capacity for assets in our banking book that we can dispose off with a gain. Our choice now must be between abandoning them on the market. We're talking about two to three-year assets with a small short-term gain. Well, that's the decision we have to make.</p>
          <p>As for CLOs and other major assets that we hold, the credit rating improved, but the market had not yet fully picked up the gap in 2010, but we have seen an improvement since Autumn and, for example, in the shadow P&amp;L that we have published, CLOs are now positive in our shadow P&amp;L. And there is now an appetite for this type of asset, showing what we have always said.</p>
          <p>All of these assets don't mean much in terms of size. They are small pockets, not notionally, which are quite important and we know that they are risks and our model was cautiously devised in the fourth quarter to increase our cover. And the other pockets are well sort out on the markets with a very attractive reward given the risk profile. We keep those and we dispose of them parsimoniously, but regularly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a few questions. Following on the questions raised earlier, regarding toxic assets, could you tell us how much in terms of the risk-weighted assets, regarding the disposal of those assets over the period? And more generally speaking, in your comments, you spoke of the disappearance of some 60% -- you gave a guidance of 60% of risk-weighted assets which should disappear. After 60%, how much would be with that risk-weighted asset? And how much capital will be generated when those assets disappear?</p>
          <p>Another question, you gave a guidance last year regarding the impact of these toxic assets. And as a matter of fact, the result turned out to be significantly better than your guidance. Do you have any guidance for next year? And could it be positive in that case?</p>
          <p>Another comment about liquidity, I am surprised when you speak &#x2013; well, in general, most bankers in France, and you gave an interview and that recently when you spoke about this, about the specificities of the French banking system which is very much developed in life insurance, in particular, bankers are saying that they have improved savings. At the same time, they are growing life insurance. And in assets management, that sounds fine, but we don't really see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, wait a second. We are a bit more consistent to what we say, don't we?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, because we hear a lot of banks, even you in your comments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's say, your ambitions are quite significant when it comes to have big insurance to grow in your network. And that's not you, it's a basic underlying trend for French banks that are trying to gain market shares by making the most of their network &#x2013; leveraging network. That's another thing, increasing our market share in a given market. That's even ambition for us. But there is still a trend.</p>
          <p>In other words, to co-finance the economy, I believe that that is one of our goals. And that means to need to work more on savings in our P&amp;L, which can put pressure in other areas, all things being equal. But the ability to increase our market shares by counting on our networks is still an ambition for us. You must also take into account the amount we're dealing with life insurance. You talked about 1,600 billions annual rankings &#x2013; 160 billion, of which 80 billion in banking. So all you need to do is to channel apart, a small part of that flow to bank's P&amp;L to significantly improve the medium and long-term collection. We saw that this year, look at Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale increase our loan to deposit ratio by 11% while have no record collection. Yes, we are very dynamic when it comes to life insurance.</p>
          <p>The problem that we're dealing with is much more simple. We have advisory services as a duty to our clients. Our clients would say, I need to invest money for four, five, ten years, so what do you advice? Today, when it comes to P&amp;L savings, we don't have much that's really valid because we have no tax instrument that will be comparable to the tax instruments you find with life insurance products in France.</p>
          <p>So we must convince the public authorities to improve on the situation and to enable banks and life insurance companies to work on a equal footing with that cost of vertical. But that will be enough to bring about fundamental changes on our P&amp;L, especially over the medium and long-term.</p>
          <p>Please continue with your question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was just thinking of one of your interviews, Mr. Oud&#xE9;a, where you warned the regulator by insisting on the specificity of the French banking network, which is at a disadvantage versus others in terms of the ratio calculations. Given the life insurance sector, we're talking about just 1,600 billion, but it's not totally neglibible, isn't it. And individually, we can see that there's a large portion of savings placed in life insurance products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The French save a lot, says Mr. Oud&#xE9;a, and I think they will continue to. Given issues regarding with comments and dependency, we'll see the political answers that will be found. But more and more, in our business managing or collecting savings, giving advisory services in savings, is becoming a critical challenge. We have monetary flows that are quite considerable each year. There will be more of a shift on our P&amp;L structurally as compared to before and each insurance company would just have to be as good as possible, but trying to capture as many market shares as possible.</p>
          <p>I believe that Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale is well positioned. It has three complementary networks. It plans to win over new clients. Plus they are in dynamic regions with a customer base that's well positioned. So I believe that our ability to collect savings is still significant. We have set up mechanisms to support these classes best possible. Please continue with the other question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's quite important. After that interview you gave, some customers were a bit worried about French banks' liquidity ratio. They'd say, hey, what's happening? Once again, it will weigh significantly. Well, given the specificities, I can't remember the exact figure. You spoke about a 44% liquidity ratio, something like that. Given the current definition, some investors may panic if they're not well familiar about the technical issues at hand.</p>
          <p>Regarding CIB, you spoke of strong pressures on margins due to flows for the flow products. Would you say that it's just passing or is it more structural? And would it be due to the formation of a competitive oligopoly that will be more significant than before the crisis in this field and how will SocGen position itself in this competitive oligopoly?</p>
          <p>Your strategy, even though you can't fully separate the Board activities which are linked, but SocGen, isn't it creating a model, a sort of specialized investment bank model? That's my first point.</p>
          <p>Secondly, you said that you were more active on some foreign currencies and the dollar in particular. Can you tell us what are your ambitions for your European clients who may need dollars, of course, but also to grow in the United States, I imagine, because you are a primary dealer in the US, if I understand correctly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, says. Mr. Oud&#xE9;a.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, we can easily imagine what I can &#x2013; BNP offering 5% of its overall NBI in Asia, what about SocGen and its share in Asia?</p>
          <p>Regarding international operations, I am a bit surprised because I know the legendary cautiousness of SocGen when it comes to provisioning, but maybe especially when you look at the significant slowdown of the economy due to tourism in countries like Egypt where you operate. Collective provisions that you organized at the beginning of problems in Greece, you were fast to shoot with provisioning in Greece. You didn't seem to do that after a conventional significant event. And it is shocking to see that the price of risk in Mediterranean countries is equivalent to what you find in France, about some 50 basis points, given the context that may seem a bit surprising. More generally and more strategically, I know that in the other countries outside of &#x2013; excepting the Czech Republic and Russia, you have a zero profitability if we remove Greece. You lose some &#x20AC;70 billion in terms of group net income, but most of that &#x2013; the loss is due to Greece. That means that the other countries are at zero after all. Don't you think that there is a choice to be made regarding assets because it's not very satisfactory to be scattered in countries like Slovakia with zero profits and the international retail business all-in-all today.</p>
          <p>I can see that you have about a 13% ROE. Now, the cost of risk is much higher in that activity since it's riskier. What are your goals for profitability and what level of profitability would make you satisfied in this risky field in the final analysis and when?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. First question for Didier on legacy assets, S&#xE9;verin will speak about CIB, Bernardo could tell us about the situation in this or that country. But I would just like to point out that in Central and Eastern Europe, once again, we're talking about a lasting operation. I think we are well positioned for future competitiveness regarding our competitors. We plan to gain market shares. And once again, we will not after one quarter build something. We were talking about building in retail banking over time, developing our system of networks, information systems and wining over market shares.</p>
          <p>So in our Ambition 2005 project, we plan to be amongst the top three in that region and we will continue to seize opportunities. We consider that we'll do so even in small countries, as you say, where growth can be generated. We'll be dynamic in a world &#x2013; let me remind you, in Europe, think of Germany, in particular, the demographics will decline. Germany will need people to work to keep its economy growing. And we continue &#x2013; the Central and Eastern Europe will continue to benefit from that. So we have a long-term perspective. Didier, about legacy assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me try to answer you briefly because you had many questions that were very lengthy. Regarding legacy assets and the impact on capital today, about &#x2013; well, linked to securitization that was not well scored. That was mainly at over &#x20AC;2.1 billion in Tier 1, 50% of the overall impact. And for Basel III, the chart that we presented earlier showed that for &#x2013; with Basel III, the deductions from risk-weighted assets in the 50% of Tier 2 would also become risk-weighted assets because all of this will become 100% weighted. So we can say that the capital mass would be &#x20AC;4 billion in terms of equipment and capital.</p>
          <p>We have a decline between the 30th of September to 31st of December and this translates the disposal of some poorly scored assets, and we spoke briefly about the third quarter, and we already started to this and we continue to do so in 2011 to see exactly how to restructure some RMB assets where the deduction is cautious, but significantly higher than economic deduction. And therefore, by restructuring, we can have high -- assets that have good quality on the average positively and we are working on that.</p>
          <p>So that's it for capital. And this is one of the levers amongst the 40 basis points, one of the levers of action therefore to increase the core Tier 1 group from 710 to 750 in Basel III. This is one of the levers we will be using above and beyond disposals and amortizations, impairment.</p>
          <p>With respect to guidance, we won't go as far to say that it will be a very general raise, an increase, as you seem to apply. This is something that we'll speak about much later in 2011 quarter-after-quarter than what we did in the previous quarters.</p>
          <p>While the restructuring of CDOs can have a negative impact on the accounts, a positive impact at the same time on capital. So we can carry out an arbitrage in favor of this type of restructuring in view of our equity. But since that we have positive, that means with respect to carry, we should have something that should be between plus and minus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding CIB &#x2013; S&#xE9;verin &#x2013; well, regarding margins in 2010 in all of our businesses, we saw a turnaround with some competitors that were less active than in previous periods. So some of our competitors have explained that recovery, so the margin should be restored given the decline in competition.</p>
          <p>Our position in CIB is based on our historical strength which we maintain. But in view of supporting our customer needs, we wanted to extend our portfolio. We're not looking for fixed income in dollars. We want to flesh out our activities to support our international clients. Given the quality of our specialties and the yield in the specialty, we can be very good indeed in Asia. We should have an NBI of 4% of the group's NBI, mainly SGCIB. We also noted in Ambition 2015 program that we expected 10% of SGCIB's NBI to be made in Asia. We said two things that the weight of the US in CIB revenue should remain stable at about 20%. Secondly, the weight of Asian, other emerging regions should reach about 20% as well by 2015. So we are driving our revenue in these zones.</p>
          <p>Thus just to stress the very specific strategy in China, in retail banking which we will continue with in 2011 which will be a year of transition. We'll be opening up branches. We have decided not to take out minority stakes in banks. We will be opening up branches. And in 2011, we plan to make money. And like all foreign banks, we need to comply with a loan-to-deposit ratio of 75%, which will be the number one constraint for all foreign banks which will not necessarily have access to liquidity. We'll have to comply with that ratio unless that was changed by the Chinese lawmakers, but I doubt that.</p>
          <p>So the Europe transition and we will continue to grow our retail banking networks, so as to collect deposits and, therefore, to finance, to fund our customers in view of the deposits.</p>
          <p>Bernardo, a brief overview of who is making money and who is still losing money.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You made a general comment on provisions and I will give you a straight answer. The event you are referring today, well, happened those last few weeks and not in 2010. So therefore, it's not really topical because it's not 2010. And what happened? Branches were closed. It's much too early to assess the impact and it might be completely marginal. So we'll have to wait for one quarter. So it's much too early. What was the figure? It's impossible to quantify anything. So at that stage, it is not really possible to comment on that.</p>
          <p>The cost of risk reflects the economy business, the economic and industrial activity of our subsidiary. We have a solid and well structured bank in Egypt with a very low cost of risk. It's the same in Morocco, in Algeria. It is extremely low in the Sub-Saharan countries. So the reality is that this part of business is robust, is healthy. And let me insist on that, this situation is getting more normal. And once it is completely normal, we should be fully equipped to Egypt. The 31st of December is slightly more than 3% of doubtful outstandings, but with a lot of provisions and therefore it's not really a problem we need to wait and see further in terms of economy.</p>
          <p>If we look at the overall results, there is one piece of data which matters. Russia is doing well with a rebound last quarter, 13 million income in a bank which is number five in Russia. Of course, our ambitions are much higher. 2011 is a year of merger. Our profitability is going to improve. And the cruising speed should be in 2012 and with 115 million under the stabilized conditions.</p>
          <p>In the other countries, you have to see that indeed Greece matters much and has a major impact in &#x2013; on the results. The result is negative in that region. Greece more than offset the positive results that we have elsewhere in small and well-integrated countries. Serbia is very integrated to the Czech Republic. In our mind, it's the kind of &#x2013; Slovakia, sorry, is a kind of branch of the Czech Republic, and so there is a strong bond between both. And hence our ID in regions which have different economic situations, we are aiming at an ROE of 18% or 20% in the local term. But of course, we have to take into account the volatility in those countries and in emerging countries.</p>
          <p>And the risk-weighted asset percentage has changed, of course. Okay?</p>
          <p>Another question and we'll have to stop in four minutes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions, short questions. One on the guidance, your guidance on the revenues of the French Retail Network 2% or 1 &#x2013; 1% to 2%, not 1.5% or 2%, 1% to 2%. Does it take into account the possible reduction in rates and the commissions which are almost flat in 2010? Will you continue with that trend or not? The second question, do you have an <mark type="inaudible" /> in the regulatory framework?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So guidance, from 1% to 2%, excluding the external growth of SMC, we took into account the economic scenario of &#x2013; so the &#x2013; coming out of the crisis with &#x2013; yes, we took into account the stability of commissions, given stability of commissions, especially the interchange commissions. There is a current debate on that and payment cards.</p>
          <p>So we took some actions, precautionary actions. We do not know what's going to be finally decided, but we took on board the uncertainties, the regulatory uncertainties.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Didier, with Coco, let's wait and see, wait and see how it can really exist in the French law, which is not that simple. If it becomes market practice, well, we will have to examine the situation much closer, but we still have to discuss with regulators, and so that our former super-subordinated securities may become compatible with Coco.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A final question, maybe a question on CIB. You said that for 2010, the structured products contributed to the profitability and that margins on the flow products fell. In 2011, the structured products will be one-off and margins on flows could remain under pressure. So what about a possible risk on the CIB revenues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The demand in structured products is not one-off. You have retail customers, banks, structured or corporate financial institutions buying those products. So the demand is progressing and the volumes of 2010 for the flow part were rather low. So maybe on the contrary in 2011, the volumes might be a bit higher. Our push business, i.e. investments we made, should also be productive or promising in 2011. So the revenue should increase rather in 2011 and the beginning of the year is good. Six weeks, of course, is not a year. So we remain very cautious. The environment might change in six weeks as well. So we are cautious in the risk management, but we pursue the development and franchise and the strengthening of our capacity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for being here this morning. And see you soon. We will organize a presentation in London and you can be connected to this presentation. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>