<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1516300" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-11-08</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3179</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric Oud&#xE9;a</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Chief Financial Officer">Bertrand Badr&#xE9;</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Delphine Lee</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Specialized Financial Services &amp; Insurance">Didier Hauguel</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Kinner R. Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">Guillaume Tiberghien</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Neuez</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole Cheuvreux SA">Pascal Decque</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer-Corporate &amp; Investment Banking, Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA">Didier Valet</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-International Retail Banking">Jean-Luc Parer</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Thibault A. Nardin</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Global Investment Management &amp; Services">Jacques Ripoll</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Natixis SA (Broker)">Alex Koagne</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Jean-Baptiste Bellon</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Broker)">Flora Benhakoun</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods Ltd.">Jean-Pierre L. Lambert</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="CM-CIC Securities SA">Pierre Chedeville</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Retail Banking, France">Laurent Goutard</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Anke Reingen</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Nick A. Davey</participant>
      <participant id="22" type="analyst" affiliation="Autonomous Research LLP">Stefan-Michael Stalmann</participant>
      <participant id="23" type="analyst" affiliation="Execution Noble">Andrew Lim</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (00:01-00:03) Okay. Good afternoon to all of you and thanks for attending our conference call on our results. What I suggest in terms of format, I think it was efficient last time, is that we stick to one-hour-and-a- half time, and that after a short presentation, we enter into Q&amp;A. And we would like to have two questions per analyst, so that everyone has the opportunity to ask a question. I will make the presentation with Bertrand Badr&#xE9;, our CFO, and then with my colleagues again, we will enter into the Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>What I would like to say as an introduction is that I think that there are two main &#x2013; key lessons to draw from these results. The first thing is that for me, this first quarter is an additional significant step in the group transformation. With, in particular, as you've seen, first of all, the announcement of disposals, the signing of Geniki and TCW, and of course the signing of Geniki means no more risk in Greece going forward.</p>
          <p>Secondly, a significant deleveraging of our legacy asset portfolio, which means that regarding the non-investment grade, the figure is down to &#x20AC;3.2 billion. It's, compared with the size of the group and the profit, a very small amount. Third, we have achieved the deleveraging of our SG CIB loan portfolio. It is completed. And it means more and more that we will enter into 2013 with a very robust balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Secondly, the performances of the business and at the end of the day, it might be the more important going forward and I'm very happy with the performances of the businesses and of course the board.</p>
          <p>Retail activities in France, in a sluggish growth environment, and of course, with the low interest rate environment, is doing pretty well. The commercial activity is good. We'll come back to that. Strong monitoring of costs also there and I'm happy with that compared certainly with our peers and certainly we enter into a period where NBI growth will be difficult, but I think we have a good performance.</p>
          <p>In retail outside France, I'm also positive with the current trend. We have, in particular in Russia, the first signs of improvement behind the hard work we have done in terms of restructuring, refocusing development of key priorities in terms of business, again, cost monitoring. And globally, we have, I think, resilient performances.</p>
          <p>Secondly &#x2013; thirdly, CIB perhaps is the &#x2013; really the outperformer even more is doing very, very well in the third quarter and I think it was very important to me because it was after the restructuring stage; in the beginning of the year, as you remember, the refocusing. Clearly we have a model which works, which is delivering added value to our clients. And I think, which can again deliver a very acceptable profitability to our shareholders, and I think we show that in this third quarter with a model which uses much, much less scarce resources than in the past.</p>
          <p>And the other businesses, which are working in close synergy, Specialized Financing Services and Global Investment Management and Services to investors as you've seen also maintain a good contribution despite, again, overall constraint on scarce resource and a difficult environment.</p>
          <p>All that with clearly a good progress in terms of cost and the benefits of all our efforts with cost which are going down. And as you've might seen, a cost of risk which is well under control. We will come back to that into more detail. And as I've said, these resilient performances for me are very important. Not only to confirm our capacity to quarter after quarter build the capital base, and of course, meet our short-term target. But more importantly, of course, to look beyond 2013 and ensure that we have the capacity to, on one hand, develop our businesses where growth will be there. And of course, have an acceptable, as I've said, overall return on equity for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>I would like to now leave the floor to Bertrand to enter into more detail in our different businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric. Good afternoon, everybody. I will just jump to the page explaining the difference between our reported results and our underlying results. I think most of you, if I read correctly, what you've published so far, I've understood the main items, which explain the difference. I will just come back on them.</p>
          <p>On the one hand, we have a reported result of &#x20AC;85 million. On the other hand, the underlying figure, which is consistent with what we've stated first and second quarter, is &#x20AC;856 million which compared to &#x20AC;793 million second quarter and to &#x20AC;2.8 billion so far this year, which clearly showed, as Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric just said, not only the resilience of our businesses but the strength of our businesses so far this year. And it is, of course, looking forward an element of comfort.</p>
          <p>The two main items are on the one hand and unfortunately, I must say we become familiar with that, is the impact of our structured debt and the mark-to-market of our structured debt which represent &#x20AC;400 million net income impact. So pretty strong negative impact this quarter. But it's also, I mean, if you think positive, it's also due to the fact that spreads have stopped widening and that our situation or signature is much better perceived this quarter than it was in the previous quarters. So this negative item in reality is a positive one.</p>
          <p>The second impact relates to also positive developments regarding our disposal program. We have made significant progress this quarter. First of all, beginning of August with the signature of the &#x2013; with the signing, sorry, of the disposal of TCW to Carlyle in the U.S., it was immediately after our results beginning of August.</p>
          <p>We had taken a hit, represented by an impairment placed on our goodwill with our second quarter results. At that time, we didn't know that things would accelerate. Now, we have taken the rest of the impact of this disposal, i.e., &#x20AC;92 million. And we don't expect any additional impact on this transaction going forward.</p>
          <p>Second element, which also accelerated over the summer is the signing of the disposal of Geniki in Greece to Piraeus. Here again, we are in the process now of the closing to happen before end of this year. But it's mostly due now to &#x2013; I mean, the regular process of the transaction. But for us, basically, the financial impact is taken into account in this quarter.</p>
          <p>So these are the main items. The rest you are more familiar. On the one hand, deleveraging cost for SG CIB. As we have said, as Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric has said, we are over now with this deleverage process.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, and also you are still familiar with that, we have &#x20AC;82 million of net impact on our legacy asset portfolio, which is basically in line with the guidance that we have provided regarding this item. So nothing really surprising. But here again, the main items, mark-to-market on our own debt and the impact of disposals.</p>
          <p>If I go on the page related to deleveraging, I think the &#x2013; and this is one of &#x2013; a very important milestone this quarter. We have achieved what we announced a year ago regarding the deleveraging of SG CIB. Our loan sale program is completed. We have sold &#x20AC;16 billion of portfolio or credit lines with a discount which is below the 5% that we had given as a target or as an indicator earlier this year.</p>
          <p>Second element, second milestone which we have reached and which is also very important, on the legacy asset front, you remember that we started with &#x20AC;40 billion four years ago. We were still at &#x20AC;30 billion a year ago. We are now below &#x20AC;10 billion and within this &#x20AC;10 billion we are roughly at &#x20AC;3 billion, &#x20AC;3.2 billion exactly on the non-investment grade asset.</p>
          <p>I think it's a very positive achievement. We have done the maximum we could do over the last four months. We have benefited of the better environment for this type of assets and of the search for yields of certain investors. And of course, we will continue to be proactive in that respect going forward, although it's still difficult. I mean as you know, we have explained this relatively often. Cracking the CDO is not just an academic exercise. It takes a little bit of time and it's never guaranteed, but we are working quite actively and we'll pursue our efforts.</p>
          <p>Third element is on the disposal front, I mentioned TCW and Geniki, which have cost us some money this quarter. But it's not only these two big items that we wanted to mention, is the fact that we are also pursuing the restructuring or the rationalization of our business portfolio. And we have mentioned as a memo item, if I may say, although it's important and it's not because it's a small transaction that it does not take time, certain number of transactions which happened over the last few months and which illustrate the fact that we are still committed to restructure, simplify and rationalize our portfolio of businesses.</p>
          <p>As far as capital is concerned, on the following page, we have gained an additional 40 bps of capital this quarter, which is exactly in line, if not a little bit more &#x2013; favorable in line with what we have announced. This allowed us to confirm that we still aim at being above 9% &#x2013; between 9% and 9.5% by the end of next year in Basel III calculation fully phased, with a caveat that as you know, Basel III is still not voted. It's still not stabilized and it's still &#x2013; I mean, with some question marks.</p>
          <p>But based on what we know, we confirm our objective. We have achieved a significant part as you see on the bottom of this page of the deleverage that will help us meet the Basel III target: 60 bps out of 70 bps. This quarter, the ratio is better not only because we have put &#x2013; we have retained earnings, it's also the deleverage of the legacy assets which provides two benefits. On the one hand, decrease of risk-weighted assets; on the other hand, decrease of the deduction from the capital. So both the numerator and the denominator of our ratio have been positively impacted.</p>
          <p>On top of that, risk-weighted assets have decreased both from the market perspective, market risks are down &#x20AC;2.1 billion. Credit risk-weighted assets are also down &#x20AC;2.6 billion, so it illustrates the strict control policy that we have on our scarce resources, as Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric mentioned at the beginning of this presentation.</p>
          <p>Another item, which is of importance as well for us is that the list of <mark type="ph" /> global SIFI (12:59) has been confirmed. We are expected to have an additional charge of 1%, which will be on top of the 4.5% plus 2.5%, i.e., in total 8%, so objective of 9% to 9.5% is significantly above the 8%, which is our regulatory constraint, not before several years actually.</p>
          <p>On the balance sheet following page, here again, we have benefited from two things. On the one hand, our own efforts; so we've been working actively on restoring the solidity of the balance sheet; on the other hand, we have also benefited from the environment. So, the both combined have allowed us to raise &#x20AC;20 billion of medium, long-term money so far this year; with I think something very important not only because of the money, which is a concern but also from the symbolic perspective. The fact that we've been able to raise $1.25 billion last month in the U.S., which I think a year ago, nobody would have thought about that. So I think it's important both from our signature perspective as well as from the environment perspective, it's a very important signal that the world, from the liquidity perspective, has changed a lot for us in a year.</p>
          <p>As far as short-term liquidity is concerned, we have maintained a strict cover of our short-term commitments with liquid asset buffer. We have also provided, I would say, some &#x2013; a little bit of fuel to our short-term activities, which are also &#x2013; which we are also able to preserve in terms of flexibility. So we are able to slow down these, if necessary. So it's just also a way to benefit from the environment so far this year. So here again, from a liquidity perspective, I think it's to a certain extent, the second quarter &#x2013; even better than the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Cost of risk. So far, it's stable, which I think is a good news. We, of course, remain cautious looking forward given the economic environment in the various zones where we are operating. But so far, it's stable. It's stable in France. We have only an increase of 1 bp. It's decreasing in our international retail, especially with a decrease in Russia. As we said in August, we had a one-off item which was significant in Russia and which explains the majority of the increase last quarter. We are back to kind of more normal level in Russia.</p>
          <p>However, we are still at a high level in Romania. But the rest is okay. So bottom line, international retail networks are down, so are the specialized financial services, where everything we've been doing in the last few years is now bearing fruit, with a strong progress in Italy where Fiditalia is now back to kind of more normal level as well.</p>
          <p>The increase in CIB can be considered two ways. On the one hand, in bps, there is a slight increase, which represent &#x2013; a real slight increase but which is also more important than it should be because of one specific old situation where we have a hit this quarter. On top of that, it's not in bps but in euro. We have a very significant impact, which also dates more than 20 years ago, which has materialized this quarter and which in euro terms, represent the majority of the increase of the cost of risk in CIB.</p>
          <p>So the underlying is okay with two specific situations, one in bps and one in euro, which have an impact. But bottom line, cost of risk is under control and we confirm our guidance that for the total year, we should be between, I would say, 67 bps to 75 bps, 77 bps, so in line with where we are today, where we've been so far.</p>
          <p>In terms of consolidated results, I think we said it in introduction, top line growth, underlying basis plus 8.7% versus last year; plus 4% compared to second quarter; so strong business performance. Cost under control and here again, we want to insist on that. I mean, we have shown this second quarter, this is a confirmation of the trend. Year-to-date, we are down minus 3.4% and we'll continue our efforts. It's critical in an environment where top line growth is not that certain to make sure that at the cost level, we maintain the pressure.</p>
          <p>Cost of risk stable, so bottom line, if we were not impacted by the various exceptional items I described earlier, top line &#x2013; bottom line, so it would be at &#x20AC;856 million, but reported &#x20AC;85 million.</p>
          <p>Business line by business line, French retail. The resilience that we've seen over the last quarter is confirmed, despite of course very strong headwinds that you're very familiar with now. Commercial momentum is there. Credit is still up. Deposits are up. And we also, even if it's symbolic, but we have net inflows in insurance which is a big difference with the rest of the market which is in net outflows.</p>
          <p>So from a commercial perspective, we are doing okay. From a revenue perspective the pressure is there. Margins, they are stable and they are under pressure, of course, if only because of the evolution of interest rate.</p>
          <p>On the fees and commission, they are down mostly due to the fact that our customer do not &#x2013; are not very active on the financial markets. So, financial commissions are really significantly down. But in total, I mean on the like-for-like basis, we are down 0.5% which I think compares favorably with the rest of the market.</p>
          <p>And more importantly, our costs are down 1.2%. So we have on the comparable basis a slight increase, but still I think it's a positive signal; a slight increase of the gross operating income which allow us to absorb the majority of the cost of risk. So bottom line, in the difficult environment, I think French retail is doing relatively okay.</p>
          <p>International retail, commercially speaking is good. It's good more or less everywhere, with some pressure in certain areas like Czech Republic for economic conditions in this country. The good point is the fact that Russia is confirming the early positive signals that we were expecting, both from revenue perspective as well as from the cost control perspective. So I think it's positive. Of course, we will need &#x2013; we would need to demonstrate this quarter after quarter, but at least this quarter shows that we have early signals, early positive signals.</p>
          <p>In Romania, the situation is still difficult. Here again, we have some slight early positive signals but we have to be cautious. The cost of risk remains high and we have more to do on the cost front. The rest of the world is good, if not very good, like in Sub-Saharan Africa and the rest of the Mediterranean Basin.</p>
          <p>In CIB, the performance is good, it's solid. It's driven by global markets. On the one hand, with fixed income which is outperforming by far the market this year. Again, based on our own computations, we've tried to exceed the average performance of the banks which have to be so far this year, over the nine months, we are at plus 50%, whereas the market is at plus 16%. So we are outperforming the market by far. It's true for nine months, it's true for quarter to quarter. It's driven mostly by short-term and long-term rates performance and to a certain extent as well by credit and with a strong underlying commercial momentum.</p>
          <p>In equity, we are more in line with the market. Our leadership position are maintained. Our performance is really in line with the market, again so far this year, where the market is at minus 11%, we have minus 14%, so closely correlated. And quarter-to-quarter, plus 23% versus Q2, versus plus 24% for the market. So here again, strong performance of the leader.</p>
          <p>And this is being &#x2013; this is done in a context where we have contained our risk as demonstrated by the VaR, I know VaR has some limits, but it's still an indicator which gives a signal of what we've done. So we have not increased our risk exposure dramatically, and I think it's important.</p>
          <p>On the financing and advisory, we have kept the momentum in structured finance. It's more difficult in capital markets, where it is compensated by still significant activity and significantly stable position in this year.</p>
          <p>Last but not least with the CIB, on the one hand, so strong revenue as you've seen, driven by fixed income. On the other hand, cost control and the cost/income ratio of 58%, 58.5%, which again, is quite positive especially versus the cost/income ratio presented by some of our competitors which have made some dramatic moves in the last few weeks.</p>
          <p>In specialized financial services and insurance, it's the third record quarter in a row, driven both by insurance and specialized financial services. Insurance driven by net inflows, I already mentioned, but also by personal protection and P&amp;C activities, so positive net income.</p>
          <p>I want to underline the situation of specialized financial services, our three business lines have positive net income and this is the third time in a row that we have positive net income in all business lines in a difficult environment.</p>
          <p>On the one hand, we have put a lot of pressure regarding the usage of scarce resources, so top line production is under pressure. But they've been able to keep decent margins and they've been able to keep the cost of risk under control. So bottom line, record quarter in terms of net income.</p>
          <p>Private banking, global investment management and services, the private banking is clearly improving its situation as shown by cost control and net inflows which are progressing. On securities services, as Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric said in the introduction, we are able to increase our gross operating income because we're working out on cost.</p>
          <p>At Newedge, the low activity has an impact on cost. I mean volumes have been down throughout the summer. And this is really the main explanation despite the fact that our market share is improving. And last but not least, corporate center, it's impacted by the various exceptional items I described in my introduction.</p>
          <p>And with that, I think I've said everything I needed to say about our activity. And I leave the floor to Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric for the conclusion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Bertrand. Just a few words to effectively wrap up and conclude. With this third quarter, I think we have, as I've said, made a significant step in our transformation, which will enable us to enter into 2013 in a position of strength.</p>
          <p>I consider that 2013, from an economic point of view, will remain relatively difficult year in the Eurozone with some uncertainty also in the U.S., and that we might see more in 2014 and 2015 the benefits of all the structural reforms that different governments are implementing.</p>
          <p>In such an environment, we are going to benefit from the strong balance sheet beginning of 2013; low exposure to sovereign debt of countries at risk. In relative terms, low exposure also on the private sector side in these countries. And as you've seen, a very limited today, exposure to legacy assets. And we are going to enter with businesses in good shape, retail activities and the positive momentum in international retail should be highlighted; as well as in CIB which has achieved its restructuring, and I think which is well equipped to fare the changes in the regulatory environment.</p>
          <p>So I'm very confident that with this balance sheet, with these businesses, we are going to, quarter after quarter, further build on the capital base and achieve them, our targets at the end of 2013.</p>
          <p>And then look beyond that, 2014, 2015 will be, in my mind, the crucial years for the Eurozone in particular, both on the economic side and political side. And we should be in a position to take advantage of all these disciplined efforts on the risks, on the cost, on the balance sheet, to look at the scenario in which we will be and, of course, take advantage of the strength of our businesses; as I said, to deliver to our shareholders a recurrent contribution of our businesses with an acceptable profitability.</p>
          <p>That's what we wanted to say. So now, let's turn to the Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We have the first question from Delphine Lee from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. Delphine Lee from JPMorgan. So, two questions. The first one is on Russia. Just to get maybe &#x2013; we've seen some progress on loan growth and also on revenues, but just to better understand when we'll see maybe some more improvements or the benefits of the cost restructurings or revenues on the corporate franchise picking up a little bit.</p>
          <p>And second question is on the corporate center run rate, if we look at the underlying revenues this quarter it was closer to &#x20AC;300 million negative, which is significantly higher than the previous quarter. So, just wondering if we need to adjust the run rate for the higher cost of liquidity or what's the expectations for the next few years? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Delphine, well, to answer your questions on Russia, I will leave the floor to Didier Hauguel, who is the Chairman of the Board of Rosbank; and then Bertrand will answer on the corporate center. Didier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Russia, we are managing the aftermath of a consolidation of a merger that was achieved in 2011. In 2012, we are boosting the revenue through increasing the earning base and activating all the lending factors, and we are also maximizing the synergies between the three platforms that we have in Russia: the universal bank, namely Rosbank, to specialized entities; on the mortgage, DeltaCredit Bank, and on the car finance, Rusfinance Bank; as well as our dedicated insurance companies.</p>
          <p>In the same time, we are also continuing the post-merger reduction of the cost base, and we are actively working on various projects on the network and on the head office structure. And we are clearing also all the cost of risk that was generated from the legacy portfolio pre-acquisition. So, we have the first result of that policy that appeared during this quarter. And we are confident that we will be able to continue to deliver according to that, but we will have obviously to check on these results going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Delphine, on your second question regarding the corporate center. The two main impacts on the run rate are on the one hand, the increased tax; on the other hand, the fact that the corporate center is basically carrying on his shoulder part of the insurance provided by the liquidity buffer basically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How much would that be roughly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How much would that be, the increase in the liquidity buffer, the impact on revenues in the corporate center?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you can make your own calculation based on the increased liquidity buffer times spread, et cetera. We are not talking of about hundreds of millions, but it's a significant number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And going back on the transaction, on the structural tax, we have had to account for three quarters this quarter. So I mean on the run rate, you should have something a bit lower.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>See what I mean?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there was, what, &#x20AC;50 million on...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x20AC;51 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x20AC;51 million?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>51 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So basically, you take out &#x20AC;30 million or &#x20AC;35 million on the run rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But basically coming back to your first point, the biggest part of the change with &#x2013; excluding this tax impact that Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric just mentioned, the vast majority of the change on the underlying corporate center run rate is really due to this kind of insurance carried by the group as a buffer basically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a next question from Kinner Lakhani from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. So I had a question on your deleveraging. I mean, clearly you've achieved a large part of the 70 basis points target that you set at the beginning of the year. And also, when you complete this target, you still have a fair amount of capital still tied up in the legacy portfolio. So my question is, once you get to the 70 basis points, I mean, do you intend to maybe raise the target in terms of the delevering between now and end 2013?</p>
          <p>And my second question was in terms of trying to understand the considerations that you would have in mind in terms of thinking about an early repayment of the LTRO money that you've taken at the end of last year, at the beginning of this year. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe, Kinner, I will take these two questions quickly. On the leverage &#x2013; deleverage, I don't think there's a need to change the target. We have completed the sale of loans and we are going to further diminish the portfolio legacy asset. But as Bertrand mentioned, cracking CDOs takes time. It's not something that is that easy. And again, as you said, we have basically completed the targets so I think we are really in line and probably even a little bit advanced, so we are going to carry on doing that progressively.</p>
          <p>On the LTRO, you know it's a kind of insurance policy, nothing more than to a certain extent. Today, there is ample liquidity and you've seen the increase of our deposits at the Central Bank. We will look at the situation beginning of next year. We will be very pragmatic on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a next question from Guillaume Tiberghien from Exane. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. I've got one request and two questions. The request, if it's possible, would it be in the future possible for you to separate in the core RWA in CIB between financing and capital market, so that maybe you can demonstrate you're not just an investment bank.</p>
          <p>The two questions are, the first one Geniki, could you give us the Q3 loss that you incurred, not on the sale but in the business and if possible split between revenues, cost and provisions?</p>
          <p>And the second question is with regard to your dividend, when you look at your payout, I think you look at the reported earnings after undated subordinated debt dividend or do you actually strip out some exceptionals when you do your payout assumptions? And if you do exclude some exceptional, which one will you exclude? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I can just say again and I will leave my colleagues perhaps to answer your question on Geniki. On the payout, we've provisioned 25% of the net profit taking out the impact precisely of the revaluation of the own debt and the mark-to-market of the <mark type="ph" /> CPI (34:40). So these non-economic items are taken out from the calculation and also the sub debt, of course, by nature but it's below the line, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And goodwill also, I guess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Geniki, is there someone who can give the answer or maybe we can come back to you if not immediately. Jean-Luc Parer, Jean-Luc, do you have the figure and the recurrent loss? Let me say it's &#x2013; going forward anyway, it's going to disappear. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But it's more to know the underlying contribution from other CEE ex-Greece. That's why I ask the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The point Guillaume is that we are in the middle of the closing of the transaction and not everything is supposed to be disclosed like this to the market, actually. So Jean-Luc might provide some details, but we are also in the negotiation process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just for the payouts, when you say we removed the non-economic items, that means you also removed the goodwill, I suppose?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the calculation, the impairment of goodwill, no, because we maintain also the capital gains. So if you wish, it's really more of the debt, the euro debt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And again, the mark-to-market of the CIB.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And for the split of RWA in CIB, would you consider giving them next time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We always consider the request and we come back to you, Guillaume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have the next question from Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Neuez from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Just had a quick question on the Basel III capital. So two quarters ago, you gave this 210 bps impact. Is it fair to say that if we wanted to see fully paid this quarter as some &#x2013; as other banks have started to do, we could do 10.3% minus 210 basis point, as you disclosed in the first quarter? That was just the first one.</p>
          <p>And then the second one is, with regard to the potential upcoming banking law in France or partial application or re-application of some the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (36:44) proposals, would you be able to quantify to a certain extent, at least, the proportion of your CIB revenues which are, for lack of a better word, at risk in this type of setup? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois, I'll first have Bertrand on the calculation of the Basel III impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on Basel III, we made the decision not to publish anything called Basel III for different reasons. First of all, because as you know, the CRD4 has not been voted. We still don't know when it's going to be voted and, of course, when it's going to be implemented. So the alternative will be to publish something with a lot of assumptions, assumptions that needs to be discussed and footnoted, et cetera. So this is not our policy. So we stick to what we've said earlier this year which is still exactly what we have in mind today. So, it is fair to say I will not confirm or deny what you say but I listen very carefully to what you say and I think you can draw your conclusions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And regarding your second question, I think it's really premature to comment on a law which is not yet <mark type="ph" /> fully of course designed (37:53). What I can just say is that, there is a consulting process and the government or different ministries have so far, clearly publicly confirmed that their objective is not to split the CIB and the retail bank. But the activities which are not useful for the economy, from the ones which are useful for the economy, we have a good understanding that with Basel III in particular, we need capital markets financing.</p>
          <p>And so, I think we are happy with that, given the nature of our business today, which is again, a client-driven business. We are very happy to, if we can, contribute to that evolution. It will help also, I think to further rebuild the image of the banking industry. And I think strategically, does not impediment the capacity to further develop our CIB business. But again, it's premature to comment on a law which is even not designed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a next question from Pascal Decque from Cheuvreux. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. My question, first is on your explanation about the provision in corporate finance in CIB. I'm sorry, I did not understand the bps and the euro explanation and the 20-year filed impact. Would it be more simple, eventually, to give the impact of this specific file if I understood well in terms of millions of euro in this quarter.</p>
          <p>The second question, you said deleveraging in CIB is now completed. Shall we expect new losses and/or cost in terms of restructuring in Q4? And could you give us an update of the total losses that you will see finally have on this deleveraging process, compared to what you said initially.</p>
          <p>And if I may, the last one, could you give the contribution of your Egyptian subsidiary in term of net profit to the group in this third quarter? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Didier, on the CIB side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi, Pascal. So on the &#x20AC;183 million of provisions set aside this quarter at CIB, &#x20AC;83 million is explained by the 20-years-old litigation. It's something that took place in Australia. And just to explain the whole I said 20 years later, we could have such an amount of provisioning, and it's the litigation, it's just because there was a banking syndicate that make an appeal and there was a revision of the discount rates applied to this litigation that is 20 years old. And 2% more over 20 years, this cost us &#x20AC;83 million. So that's most of what we can say on this litigation. It's public and there is some press article in Australia that explains all the banking syndicate has been &#x2013; has to pay more on this.</p>
          <p>So it isn't that the underlying cost income is &#x20AC;100 million and this is based on this that you have the 44 bps, which is a cost of risk of the quarter, because I'll remind you that in our cost of risk calculation, we do exclude litigation. So the pure commercial cost of risk is &#x20AC;100 million, equivalent to 44 bps. And there let's say, as Bertrand mentioned, there is a slight increase, which is not totally normal at this point of the cycle, with clearly certain corporate which are slowing down. You've seen that also at our &#x2013; one of our competitor yesterday. Overall, let's say, we're still below the cost of risk over the cycle that we do estimate in the region of 50 to 55 bps for CIB. So it showed that the performance of the portfolio remain sound.</p>
          <p>On your second question which is the loan sales. Yes, overall, so we sold &#x20AC;15.8 billion of loans, so the &#x20AC;16 million is a rounding figure. We've lost in H2 2011 and in the first nine months, &#x20AC;632 million for these asset sales. So as, again Bertrand mentioned, this represent 4% dollar loss on these asset sales.</p>
          <p>In Q4, let's say maybe there will be a few tens million euros remaining on term of cost because some of these disposal have not been settled yet, but that's it. And in term of restructuring costs on the cost base, there was a few million euros in Q1 and Q2, almost nothing in Q3, nothing to be expected in Q4. So the bulk of the restructuring costs of the CIB has been incurred in Q4 last year results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the last thing, the contribution of our Egyptian subsidiaries, Jean-Luc.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding Egypt, the net contribution for the group, for Q3 is close to &#x20AC;34 million. For the first nine months it was &#x20AC;80 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for the answers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The growth of the economy of the country, on the high level of activity of the banking industry in this country at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a next question from Thibault Nardin from Morgan Stanley. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello, good afternoon to everybody. Two quick question on my side, maybe the first one on Romania, where we heard some of your competitors over there that are expecting some kind of an economic recovery for next year. I would be happy to hear your view about that. And what kind of improvements we could expect on the cost of risk? And secondly, would be about an update on the TCW disposal process, given the outstanding litigation. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will give the floor to Jacques Ripoll regarding TCW. I think on Romania, may I say that Romania has suffered both economically but also politically, as you know, with this argument between the Prime Minister and the President. It seems more or less sorted out. And it does not help in a country which depends on the administration and the capacity also to even use some subsidies from Europe. The situation is still a little bit blurred on that front.</p>
          <p>Yes, we can expect some improvement, but I think we need to remain prudent and see how it goes in 2013. So more on the positive side than on the negative but I remain a bit prudent, given what happened in the last few months.</p>
          <p>Jacques on TCW?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sure. Well, as you know we have a pending dispute with a former part of TCW. This is taken care of through a classical arbitration process. And we're comfortable with the output. The question that the judge will have to rule in the very coming days is slightly different and it relates to the need or not to wait for the output of this arbitration to close the transaction. We shall see what it said, but in any case, it's more a delay than anything else and there's nothing else to report especially on the process with TCW.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a next question from Mr. Jon Peace from Nomura. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks. I have two questions, please. So, the first one was about the core corporate and investment bank. I just wondered if whether now that deleveraging is completed and before considering any impact from the French Banking Reform Bill, you considered that the current quarter's revenues were a sustainable run rate going into next year, because I see they're about 10% ahead of next year's consensus and I just wondered if you felt analysts were being too conservative?</p>
          <p>And then the second question related to your capital ratios. Back in the third quarter 2011 when you first outlined your deleveraging plan, you'd originally said about &#x20AC;30 billion to &#x20AC;40 billion of risk-weighted assets would be disposed of, and I wonder if you still stick by that plan and whether you can give us any color about additional assets, whether it's Egypt or SocGen &#x2013; or securities services, which you still anticipate on disposing by the end of 2013? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Didier on the run rate of revenue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jon, I used to be in your seat, so I think it's part of your job to assess by the run rate going forward of the CIB business. And I would say that the overall environment was, I would say, quiet in July and August but pretty strong in September. So I would say something which is average plus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bertrand, perhaps on the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the deleveraging, I think I will emphasize again what we said. So, deleveraging we have two elements. The second one will be dealt with by Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric regarding disposal of businesses. Regarding the deleverage, so the disposal of loans and the reduction of the legacy asset portfolio. I think regarding the loans, we are done. It's completed. Regarding legacy asset portfolio. I mean, we &#x2013; I mean, there is no doubt that we want to get rid of them someday and we do the maximum stuff. I mean, there is nothing more we can do and we stick to the objective we set up. We have been more active, and we have done faster this quarter. We'll see what the next quarter and the following quarters will be like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And regarding the disposal program, let me just remind you that we have in mind to have between 50 basis points and 100 basis points impact, positive impact at the end of 2013. Let me just say that with the TCW, Greece and Egypt, we would have &#x2013; do a very significant step towards this program, which would allow us to carry on &#x2013; complete that with a few assets but with something very &#x2013; without any pressure. And so we will look at that. Let's first, let me say, complete what we have already announced and as I've said, I will never announce in advance a disposal, I think it's the best way to destroy value. But we are committed to this program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a next question from Alex Koagne from Natixis. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Two questions from my side as well. Based on your knowledge, why do you think that CRD4 is not voted yet? And additional question on that is, do you think that there could be any discussion again regarding the Danish compromise?</p>
          <p>And coming back on your Roadmap 2015, you were forecasting a cost to income of 60% in the retail banking. I was just wondering if, do you think that you're going to reach this target before that 2015 based on the mutation that you see in the retail banking as of today? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding CRD4, why isn't it voted yet, I don't pretend to have specific information or &#x2013; it's a pretty complex matter with different dimensions, not just prudential and it's not that easy to reach a compromise. We talk about various structural reforms which are potentially impacting the financing of the economies in Europe. It is pretty normal that people really take the time to consider all the potential outcomes. Initially, let's say, there was a target end of year. It might be, maybe postponed a little bit. But I think the commitment is at some point, certainly then early 2014 to vote this legal framework.</p>
          <p>Regarding the 60%, it's again premature to give you some outlook. Let me say, as we've said, we are entering certainly in the next two to three years, a period of time during which it will be more difficult than in the last 10 year to grow the NBI of the French retail. We will work very hard on the cost. We have capacity to have a positive, again also impact on that. We are carrying on with our project to just, for example, merge the two IT systems. We will have benefit from that. But at this stage, again, it's a bit premature to comment on the cost/income ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We have the next question from Mr. Jean-Baptiste Bellon from Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. I have two question. One on the Russia, following Delphine's question. Can you maybe elaborate a little bit more on the growing driver of the top line? Because if we look back at the, say, past couple of quarters, we have top line a little bit pedestrian, with still quite an increase in the loan book. So is it something going down at the time you developed your corporate franchise or you developed the link with the three platforms as explained?</p>
          <p>The second question is on the fixed income result. You had a very nice increase of revenue and top line in fixed income. Can you elaborate a little bit more maybe on the different categories you published on the VaR on credit fixed income, forex and commodities? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will let Didier comment on, let's say, the level of activity and the risk appetite according to the Russian segment. Perhaps, Didier, can you explain a little bit more by segment of clients, where we are growing and where, for different reasons we have again, ahead of us perhaps, more potential?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, we don't see any competition between the two portfolios. It's not &#x2013; we don't see a competition between corporate lending and the individual loans. We're going to grow both. And we're going to grow the corporate lending in the context of important synergies between onshore platform, Rosbank and an offshore platform, SG CIB. That's one, on corporate.</p>
          <p>As far as individuals are concerned, we have basically three lending platforms, one is the platform of the universal bank where we will distribute personal loans and car loans to Rosbank clients. The other one is Rusfinance Bank, where we distribute car loans within dealerships, within car dealerships. And the sale platform is DeltaCredit Bank where we distribute mortgage loans. These two specialized platform enhance all lending capacity to individuals. Basically, you can count on the compounded growth rates in 2013 around 10% for all these lending businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the VaR.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, on the fixed income, maybe to give you some detail on various asset sub-segment and also maybe to comment after that on the VaR evolution quarter-on-quarter. So as Bertrand mentioned in the presentation, let's say, on the flow credit, let's say we had a strong quarter let's say, we're clearly benefiting from strong corporate issuances that we've seen especially in September. So there was a lot of volumes on both, let's say, investment grades and also high yields.</p>
          <p>On the flow rate, let's say we had a good performance on both short term and long term. FX was more, let's say, average in term of performance and emerging also did perform well.</p>
          <p>On the regulatories, maybe let's say you could be surprised not to see &#x2013; let's say, a big increase even if you were to look at both sum of credit fixed income and forex, but you should remember that we look and credit the VaR based on the last 12 months scenarios. And so in third quarter, especially on the credit, we've lost, let's say, the stress scenario that we've seen last August and September. So de facto, let's say, it is a daily calculation, and so this is the average of the quarter. The exit of certain scenario that were impacting Q2, but no longer the full Q3 had also an explanation, overall, on the evolution of the VaR.</p>
          <p>Again, we commented on the VaR. The VaR, we know that there is some weakness. It is partly now rebalances in term of capital requirement by the stressed VaR, which is based on a stress scenario which are, let's say, for us roughly the Lehman crisis period and this is always the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (55:44) that we apply to our daily positions. And, of course, you know that, internally, we do manage our operation of the stress test, and the stress test, let's say, were still low in July and August and there the slight increase in September.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We have the next question from Flora Benhakoun from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. Actually, I must say most of my questions have been answered already. Maybe just two quick follow-ups. The first one is on the cost of the deleveraging for the legacy asset part, because when you mentioned the cost, I think you only mentioned the losses on the loans sold. So I just wanted to know if you could provide some more color on the losses, if any, on the sale of legacy assets.</p>
          <p>And the second question is a follow-up also on a question that was raised on the business asset disposals. I think you said on the call that you are &#x2013; you remain committed to the target you are &#x2013; you gave on the previous quarters, so I think the 50 to 100 basis points. And I was wondering if you sell the Egyptian business, will that be incorporated into the 50 to 100 basis point or would that potential come on top of that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question I will take it. Definitely, I mean if we sell the Egyptian subsidiary, yes, it will be included in that. It's a way to complete this 50 to 100 basis points program. Second question, perhaps, Bertrand, the losses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on the losses related to legacy assets, it's smaller than on the loan sales. Roughly, we have decreased our legacy asset portfolio by more than 5 &#x2013; not 50 &#x2013; &#x20AC;5 billion during this last four months, for a cost which is roughly &#x20AC;50 million. So it's really small. Again, on this front, it's a mix of value and technicity or complexity of the transaction. As we've said, cracking a CDO is something which takes a lot of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We have your next question from Jean Pierre Lambert from KBW. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. Two questions. The first one is related to an interview which was given to <mark type="ph" /> DST (58:02), and where it was quoted that you envisaged 10% to 12% return on equity. I was wondering what kind of timeframe you have in mind and what kind of driver you see pushing the ROE to that level?</p>
          <p>The second question is general. It's about the Swiss competitor retrenching from some businesses. Do you think you have some fine-tuning to do to your fixed income model and do you expect some fine-tuning after the re-definition &#x2013; the final definition of CRD4? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding your first question, Jean Pierre, let me first say, I'm being of course very prudent regarding target of return on equity. There are still some uncertainties regarding regulation, et cetera. My point is to say with all the care around this question, I would tend to think that an acceptable return, taking into account on one hand much more resilience in the contribution of the banks, much less risk, delivering of good services at reasonable price to clients, would be between 10% and 12%. And let me say I've said that for something like one year. What I can just say, I have a feeling that my colleagues in the recent announcement tend to effectively go toward that kind of figures and usually it's in 2014, 2015.</p>
          <p>I mean, if you look at the economic environment, I still consider that, as I said 2013 will be a difficult year and it's not before 2014 and 2015 that you might see still some more &#x2013; slightly better environment, perhaps with also some increase, progressive increase on the interest rates. So, all that we will of course also help. So, it's around that kind of horizon.</p>
          <p>Didier, on the fixed income business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Jean-Pierre. Good afternoon. On the fixed income business, let's say, the adjustment that we've made, let's say, are sufficient and it's the position in the franchise where we want to be. Clearly, let's say, since the last 12 months and it was partly also of the managing of Basel 2.5 and the reduction of risk-weighted assets that you've seen achieved by the CIB. We've reduced certain, let's say, structured credit activities. This was clearly beneficial for the CRM and IRC calculations. And I would say the rest of our activity, let's say, in the fixed income is predominantly in Europe, predominantly; so less geared to structured credit as some of our Swiss competitors. Use are still have in the U.S. and lacking that, we have less need now to further adjust our, let's say, exposure to this type of sub market I would say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Much appreciated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We have the next question from Pierre Chedeville from CM-CIC Securities. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Some question. The first one is regarding the car business. It seems that this quarter you were quite happy with this business and it's a little bit paradoxical, if we think of the general environment regarding the European car industry.</p>
          <p>So, I have three questions on this item, what is your view regarding the perspective of this business of car loans and car fleet, et cetera. Don't you fear regarding a likely drop in the second hand prices that you may experience more or less the same scenario, I mean 2008 or 2009? I mean huge provisions. And of course, I don't want you to elaborate on a certain specific case for confidential reason, of course, but don't you think that from a general point of view, the car industry problems may lead in France or elsewhere to some bad surprises in the financing activity sooner or later, in terms of provision?</p>
          <p>Also I have a question regarding the cost of risk in France. I'm quite surprised to see that your cost of risk in France is nearly three times the one of BNP. Of course, you may say that you have an exposure on SME a little bit higher but for some of my clients, it's difficult to rationalize. So maybe you have some help to give me to answer this kind of question. And I think that you have the same auditor or the provision policy, so it's difficult for me to imagine such a gap between you and your main competitor.</p>
          <p>My last question will concern the buffer on liquidity. We can see that in France and elsewhere in Europe, banks are covering more and more of their short-term needs and we are now above 100%. You're probably the most reasonable on that issue but you can see 115% for instance for BNP, 135%, 150%, et cetera, et cetera, which of course is good for reassuring investors. You understand clearly what it means. But more than that, it weighs on the profitability of the P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>So, as I think that, at the end of the day, it will penalize the profitability and then the capacity of the banking industry to make its job properly, where do you think this zeal regarding liquidity buffer will stop? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, let me take this question first and then leave Didier on some, on the car and Laurent Goutard to comment on the cost of risk. May I just give you my personal opinion, is that what is being done today is not sustainable. We are in a world where there's too much liquidity, search for yield. And I think, easily getting a lot of money to put them in Central Bank in itself is a wonderful reassurance. But at the same time, as you said, it is not necessary the best use of liquidity and the optimization of the model.</p>
          <p>So, I think it's related to still the stress probably around the system. And that at some point, Central Bank will withdraw progressively liquidity, that once banks are again, in line with Basel III, some irrational fears will progressively disappear, and that we will come back according to the new rules on the liquidity, which will have to be implemented, to something which is a bit more rational.</p>
          <p>So, will it last 18 months, two years? I don't know. But at some point, I think effectively, we will have to change this kind of model.</p>
          <p>Perhaps, Didier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, on the car business, we have two car businesses, one that is embedded in the SG consumer finance business, that is a lending business. And the second business is the renting business, part of ALD Automotive. As far as the lending business is concerned, I think that we can say that this business is extremely resilient in terms of risk return, and that we have explained that in 2008-2009 and we have lower margin but low cost of risk across the board in the various geographies where we are leaders, namely in France, in Germany, in Russia and very well ranked in Italy.</p>
          <p>So as far as this business is concerned, we &#x2013; basically part of the turnaround strategy on the consumer finance business has been to refocus on the car business because it's resilient across the cycle and is part of the explanation of the resilience of our consumer finance practice.</p>
          <p>The second business is the car renting business. And yes, some of the used car markets are under pressure these days. But we experienced them when we have taken much lower residual value risk in the aftermath of the 2008-2009 crisis. And we are, these days very confident with the gap that we have between residual value and used car prices and we basically experienced no losses and don't forecast in the near future to experience any, except there will be an extremely significant drop, much bigger than 2008-2009 in the quarters to come.</p>
          <p>And to the third question and without entering into specifics, the financial difficulties of any car manufacturer doesn't translate into losses for the car lenders or the car renter, except in some extreme situation which would translate into the pure disappearance of the manufacturer. And basically this risk is hedged by the fact that we have on both lending and renting portfolio, strong diversification rules, so any problems of any given manufacturer would not translate into a significant impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Laurent, on the cost of risk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Laurent Goutard speaking here. Speaking about cost of risk and the comparison between BNP and Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale, I think it's a little bit difficult to compare because I think we have difference in terms of methodology and business portfolio.</p>
          <p>First of all, in terms of methodology, for the consumer loans, 50% of the cost of risk for French customers is including in our cost of risk for retail or retail banking. I think it's not the same methodology for BNP, where the full cost of risk for consumer loans is more on the SFS business lines.</p>
          <p>Second explanation, I would say, is coming from the segment of clients. We are probably more exposed on small business clients and medium-sized company, where obviously cost of risk is higher than for large corporates, but at the same time, the margin is higher as well. When I compare cost of risk for retail activities between SocGen and other French banks, I don't see the same gap between the competitors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Just a follow-up question regarding the car business. Regarding the difficulties of car makers in Europe, my question was also &#x2013; and of course, I repeat, I don't want any comment regarding any specific car maker. But don't you think that you may have to register in the coming quarter, I would say, a sectorial provision if you didn't do that already, and what is your view on the evolution of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I don't think so and I'm happy to discuss that with you further if you need any further comment, but I don't think so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We have the next question from Anke Reingen from Royal Bank of Canada. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. Good afternoon. I have two questions. The first one is if you could please update on the &#x2013; with respect to the legacy assets on the amortization schedule, because I was just wondering your 30 basis points &#x2013; sorry, &#x20AC;30 billion total reduction by year-end 2013 from the leveraging, would this already be achieved with legacy assets amortizing, so any sales would be on top? Or where would the &#x20AC;2.1 billion capture requirement at the nine-month stage be at the year-end 2013?</p>
          <p>And then secondly on the dividend and the payout ratio, you say it's 25% payout ratio. I was just wondering what your assumption currently is with respect to cash and stock dividend pre any additional sales? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure to understand fully what you mean. Is it the potential option to a payment in terms of share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes. What &#x2013; in your current Core Tier 1 ratio, of like guidance of 9% to 9.5%, do you assume for 2012 a stock dividend or a share dividend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't have in France, let me say, the legal framework to impose a payment in shares. So what we have is the capacity to offer an option. And it would be the decision of the board but it is, I would say, likely that we will offer this option at the end of 2012. But it's an option.</p>
          <p>Secondly, on the legacy assets, briefly let me say, and again I speak under the control of Bertrand, the investment rate basically they amortize quickly but the impact of capital is relatively limited. And on the non-investment grade, it's more a question of selling, dismantling, et cetera, than amortization. I can summarize but then, Bertrand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's exactly where we are. We have done 60 bps out of the 70 bps which are planned. So the last 10 bps are ahead of us and we have no doubt we'll make it. Regarding amortization, I don't think we've made it &#x2013; we put it in this presentation, but I think we published earlier this year an amortization schedule with the cost-of-risk schedule for legacy assets. We are slightly in advance with this schedule, which is a positive one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe, Anke, to add something, let's say, you were comparing &#x20AC;1 billion of risk-weighted assets compared to &#x20AC;1 billion of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:13:00), unfortunately these assets are weighting at 1,250% for some of them. So even if you amortize &#x20AC;1 billion, it could save you, let's say, a much higher multiple of risk-weighted assets. So keep that in mind, that's why the two figures cannot be compared and a big part of the optimization is linked to deduction and to multiplication, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:13:22), I mean.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't have a high weighting but on top of that, you have deduction and part of the benefit that we enjoy this quarter was due to the fact that we have less reduction related to legacy assets. So, it's not &#x2013; definitely not a straightforward calculation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so we have a next question from Nick Davey from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, everyone. Nick Davey from UBS. Two questions please. The first on market risk-weighted assets. You referenced in your presentation the decline on the quarter. I think there was some discussion at Q2 that we should expect perhaps some pick-up in market risk-weighted assets if and when VaR increases. I know you talked about the weaknesses of VaR as an outside indicator, but maybe if you could just guide us a little bit, if we should expect any pick-up in market RWA if and when more risk is put to work in the CIB.</p>
          <p>And the second question, please, on gross leverage, there seems to me a slight pick-up in focus on gross leverage ratio as Basel III leverage ratio at the moment. I noticed you're running at a peak balance sheet size. I just wondered whether, if at all, gross leverage ratios feature in your thinking on the balance sheet. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Didier, perhaps on the VaR and then, Bertrand, the leverage ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, what I would say on the market risk-weighted assets as a total, let's say, it was down by &#x20AC;2 billion. You've seen that the bulk of the decrease came from the legacy asset. There was a slight decrease coming from the core CIB. Let's say, part of that is explained by the fact that the VaR definitely was slightly down.</p>
          <p>As I said, I gave an example, I'll give an explanation, let's say part of the low level of VaR is coming from, let's say, first, let's say, we're extremely prudent in term of managing our risks during the quarter. And also we have benefited from exit of certain scenarios that were quite negatively weighting on the calculation that took place last year. Overall, I would say yes, we could have and maybe I will say exactly the same than last quarter, we could have a slight increase in market risk-weighted assets in this quarter, but nothing dramatic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the leverage ratio, as you know, we don't publish it for the reason that we don't think it's a correct appreciation of the business, of the bank today. As for the rest, it's not been voted yet. So we'll see when it's voted and to which detail and with which methodology and so on and so forth. The fact that the leverage ratio, I mean we are comfortable with what we have in mind. The balance sheet has grown because of the inflows of liquidity that we discussed earlier in this process. We are using this liquidity to a certain extent for short-term businesses within the capital markets activities, within CIB. And we are able to reduce this if it's needed. I think these are the main comments I could bring on this topic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have a next question from Stefan Stalmann from Autonomous Research. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. Two questions, please. The first one regarding your FICC business. Could you give us an indication of how many risk-weighted assets are tied up in your FICC business? And maybe also an indication of what share of your FICC revenues is actually generated with French clients, just very broadly.</p>
          <p>The second question regards to your French retail business and then it comes back to the question of cost management versus revenue prospects. I was just looking back at the last decade and your revenue at &#x2013; and then French retail has essentially grown at 5% per annum almost every year on average, and your cost has grown by 4% every year. And now you're facing pretty much a break in this trend where your revenue is not growing and maybe even shrinking a bit.</p>
          <p>And so you really have to probably tackle this cost base in quite a meaningful way to avoid this kind of built-in inflation over the last decade to continue. What exactly are you planning to do there? Is it just cutting at the margin or could that involve something more looking like a restructuring in terms of branch capacity, staff, et cetera? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will let Didier answer on the FICC and the proportion of French clients. Perhaps Laurent, you will comment on the French retail. Didier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Stefan, it was, let's say, regard the question of Guillaume, let's say, your question on the FICC proportion of risk-weighted asset is roughly the same. So we don't disclose that but I think that nevertheless, you could show &#x2013; you could look to page 32 where the split of the risk-weighted assets of the group, of CIB is done and you will see that market risk is limited, operational risk is quite big. And of course, the big part is coming from counterparty risk where also we take into account the corporate loan book of our global finance and commercial banking activities.</p>
          <p>So, you have to make your own calculation on the French part of the fixed income business, let's say, we are not a French house. We are a Eurozone or even European houses, so it's much more diversified, and the French is a part but not a big part of the overall revenues of the fixed income franchise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Laurent, on the French retail?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, for French networks, as said by Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric and Bertrand, I would say, NBI will remain under pressure in 2013 and for the coming years due to the macroeconomic environment and probably low level of interest rates. So under this condition I think it's difficult to anticipate very &#x2013; the dynamic and positive trend for NBI.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, I'm confident in our capacity to continue to overperform the market and our main competitors as we did for Q2 and probably Q3, mainly due to the good business performances mentioned by Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric and also by our capacity to do re-pricing of fees and condition as we did during this year.</p>
          <p>I'm also confident in our capacity to maintain cost under strict control. It means classic cost-cutting as we did for marketing cost, staff, and utilities, but as well for all the parts of cost optimization coming from mutualization between Cr&#xE9;dit du Nord and Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale, and the pleine convergence. And obviously, the part of cost optimization coming from convergence and mutualization will increase for the next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which is more a sustainable effort rather than something very brutal, one point you see, because again, the situation of the retail networks in France are pretty different from other situations in Europe. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a next question from Andrew Lim from Execution Noble. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon, everyone. I've got a question on liquidity. Your liquid asset buffer went up by &#x20AC;27 billion. But as a percentage of your short-term funding, it stayed the same at above 100% of the quarter. So obviously your short-term funding also went up by about the same amount. And then on that basis, I guess, this has cost you money. I was just wondering what the thinking is behind this strategy and what we should expect going forward.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, just on guidance really, on French networks cost of risk. You've given it at 50 bps before, but obviously you've come in lower than that. At the same time though, a lot of French corporates are noting a deterioration in trading conditions. What can we expect going forward just economically and the impact on the French networks for the cost of risk there? Is 50 bps a guidance for the next two quarters or is that too extreme?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps I will take these two answers, Andrew. First of all, your first question relates a little bit to Pierre's one. Again, this situation where liquidity is very abundant, yes, we collect much more money. And effectively as you say, a lot of that goes to central banks and probably not that profitable.</p>
          <p>Now, that's a fact of this current situation where central banks are providing this money. Banks like us with good ratings attract deposit. It's difficult to refuse that or &#x2013; so, I mean, at some point as I've said, I would expect a normalization. It can't go forever like this. And of course, we are prudent and we put that in the central bank because investing today is also complex. We don't want to speculate on that. In the long term, I don't think it's sustainable. And at some point, the central banks will withdraw liquidity. So, I don't see that as a structural factor. It's more probably linked to the current situation.</p>
          <p>Secondly, cost of risk in retail, again, it's premature to give a figure. We expect some increase clearly because of the SMEs. We are in line with what we said, if you remember in August, we don't think it will take place in the third quarter, it might be more in the fourth quarter with the traditional seasonality factor.</p>
          <p>If you look at &#x2013; back at our accounts, every year in the fourth quarter, there is a bit more, but we &#x2013; it depends to that of the outlook for France. We have in mind a plus 0.5% growth for France next year. The European Commission has said plus 0.4%. It is not that dramatic. It's sluggish but again it's not that dramatic and, of course, nothing to be compared with Spain and Italy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what I think we could say. I don't think we have any more question and I must say it's now 25 past 2. So I suggest we call it for the day. Thank you very much again for your attention and see you soon. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>