<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1533186" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-02-13</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3179</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric Oud&#xE9;a</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Chief Financial Officer, Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA">Bertrand Badr&#xE9;</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">Guillaume Tiberghien</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Espirito Santo Investment Bank">Andrew Lim</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International">Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Neuez</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Derek A. De Vries</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Nick A. Davey</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Anke Reingen</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Kinner R. Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Hans van Beeck</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="CM-CIC Securities SA">Pierre Chedeville</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Delphine Lee</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Kiri Vijayarajah</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Natixis SA (Broker)">Alex Koagne</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Jeremy C. Sigee</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale conference call. I now had over to Mr. Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric Oud&#xE9;a. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon to you here physically in London. And we are trying something; we are trying to innovate with people in Paris listening to this conference call, analysts in Paris, and I say also bonjour to them and then people on the line. So I hope everybody can hear and the sound is fine.</p>
          <p>We'll go to the presentation briefly, and then of course after that answer your questions from the different sources. I will just introduce this presentation and then I will leave the floor to Bertrand, who will go through the results more in detail.</p>
          <p>Just in a nutshell, if you remember, one year and half ago roughly of something like this, 2011 clearly, the major objective for 2012 was the transformation of the balance sheet following the crisis in December. And when I look back at 2012, I think we have achieved all our objectives. And this slide is summarizing this achievement; first of all in particular of course the deleveraging of SG CIB, all together &#x20AC;35 billion of assets sold since end of June 2011, both I would say legacy assets as well as the usual loans, the normal loans, and it's completed.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we have announced a disposal program for the next two years of 2012 and 2013 with an impact between 50 and 100 basis points of core Tier 1benefit. We have I think done very well by disposing of assets, effectively in practice reaching this 50 basis point hurdle, but more importantly I think on one hand enhancing the strategic profile of the group and reducing the risk; and in particular, of course, the disposal of our subsidiary in Greece; the disposal of TCW, which was completed last week; and as you know, the agreement to sell our Egyptian subsidiary, NSGB, with a public offering which is about to be launched, and a deal which will be closed end of first quarter of 2013.</p>
          <p>Third, the strengthening of the liquidity profile; Bertrand will go through the balance sheet in detail. That clearly we have done I think very well in 2012. And I must say that the beginning of 2013 more than ever we are definitely online with our target both in terms of capital between 9% and 9.5% core Tier 1. Bertrand again will go through all the figures and show the roadmap for 2013. We've increased our core Tier 1 by 155 basis points in 2012, 40 basis points in the last quarter. But also in terms of liquidity, we don't put a figure yet on the LTR. The rules have yet to be adopted with the CRV IV, but let's say our view is that we are already in line with requirements and certainly will be at year end. That's the first thing, and it was really the major focus, like I said, for this year.</p>
          <p>Secondly, something which is I think very important, which is that I think kept and further enhanced the contribution and generation of the businesses, and that's important for the profit this year and beyond. In retail, you will see that we've maintained the activity. We've had overall good commercial activity in France and in specialized financing, while at the same time we put the pressure on the resources on capital and liquidity, so there are more resources allocated to specialized financing, and the contribution is increasing.</p>
          <p>We've seen international retail in the fourth quarter and overall in the second half, all the benefits of the work we've made in Russia. In Russia, we make money. We disclose in the appendix the contribution of our Rosbank subsidiary taking into account the drifts and bits. And we disclose &#x2013; we split into pieces the different parts of Rosbank actually in our reporting. All in all, &#x20AC;100 million net profit this year; it's not enough and we will do more, but it is positive and going I think in the right direction.</p>
          <p>And third, CIB, which was of course an important challenge also; if you remember one year ago we had to start with the restructuring. We had to cut staff by something like 13%, and of course again maybe this deleveraging. When you look at the results and the beginning of this year confirm that with good volume, I think we have here at CIB which is in order and which can work and gain further market share. We've gained market in the last four or five years. My ambition is to confirm that in 2013.</p>
          <p>Third, you look into the cost/income, we've made also very good progress in terms of cost monitoring, and costs are down. This has been an effort of permanent itself, and I think we get the benefit including from the initiatives which have started three years ago. For example, on the IT side, when we put together all the infrastructure on a worldwide basis, 2012 is the year during which not only we improved the quality of the IT, but we see the benefit in terms of cost savings. And this will be, of course, a focus for attention going forward. And that means that the underlying net profit of the group basically has remained stable at &#x20AC;3.4 billion.</p>
          <p>I will conclude and tell you how we see 2013 and beyond. There is a second step of transformation to make, of course, this group is even more efficient in a very different environment. Exactly as previously announced, we are resuming also the payment of the dividend. We have rounded that at &#x20AC;0.45 per share. That means a 26% payout ratio in terms of group net income and excluding the revaluation of the owned debt, which is non-economic, and with also scrip dividend option, again, as previously announced.</p>
          <p>So now I will turn the floor to Bertrand, who will go through the results, and again we will conclude.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I think we have time to go through the once more numerous exceptional, also called non-recurring items which make this picture for us, as for many banks, a little bit difficult to decipher at first sight. I'll not spend too much time addressing to be able to go through the appendix, which makes a line-by-line analysis of these exceptionals. What is more interesting is to imagine what will be 2013 from that perspective.</p>
          <p>Regarding the first block, which relates to legacy assets and the deleveraging, I think the deleveraging is behind us. We have done 100% of what we had said in October 2011, so it's behind us. We have another &#x20AC;10 million this quarter and then it's over.</p>
          <p>Regarding legacy assets, what we say is that this quarter we are still around &#x20AC;100 million, which is close to our initial guidance. There is more perspective regarding legacy assets. We can say that this &#x20AC;100 million should decrease to &#x20AC;50 million per quarter relatively rapidly, and so it should be a non-material item going forward. And I think it's also an important milestone that we reached beside the fact that we are now below &#x20AC;10 billion in total and roughly at &#x20AC;3 billion regarding the many bad assets on the legacy portfolio, so this is the first block.</p>
          <p>The second block is also likely to evolve in the future. It's a mixed bag of both goodwill impairment and impact of disposals. Going forward, we already expect a positive impact from the disposal of Egypt, likely to close before the end of this quarter &#x2013; end of this quarter. Regarding goodwill impairment, again, we have carefully, as usual at year end, reviewed our goodwill. The only significant item and agreement, if I may say, or in full agreement with our partner Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole, we have depreciated the entirety of the goodwill of Newedge, which is now down to zero. And this was really the only item that was really part of this goodwill review, nothing else; so no need to do the paille de fer, as we say in French.</p>
          <p>Third block, this will continue, unfortunately, because we have nothing to phase out in a clean way, it's our own debt. I can't announce to you provided conditions are the same that we will have another negative impact from the first quarter, and there is nothing we can do against it.</p>
          <p>The other it's a mix of mostly two elements. On the positive side is the profit we made second quarter on the purchase of our own debt, and on the negative side the impact of the &#x20AC;300 million provision which was taken for litigation, general provision we've taken on litigation this quarter. So that's really what it is about.</p>
          <p>So if we move to this page, Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric has said more or less everything which needed to be said. Point number one, we have reached 100% of our deleveraging objective. We have significantly reduced the legacy asset portfolio. And more importantly because it has been weighted for a long period of time, we have been able take care of some disposals. We have closed the disposal of Greece in December. We just signed the closing of TCW last week. And as I said, we are likely to close NSGB after the offer by the end of this quarter.</p>
          <p>Bottom line, and we do not include a bunch of smaller disposals, which together also add up to a few bps of capital but more importantly which also participate through the restructuring, and I would say the rationalizing of our portfolio of businesses. So bottom line, starting where we were mid-2011, basically we have achieved what we say we wanted to achieve on that perspective.</p>
          <p>Basel 3; so Basel 3 is still up in the air. We still even don't know exactly when it's going to be voted. So we still expect this to be in place by the end of this year or beginning of next year, so a slight difference between December 31 and January 1. So this year is a bit in between, especially as far as insurance is concerned, and I'll come back to that in a minute.</p>
          <p>As far as Basel 2.5 is concerned, we are at 10.7%. We have been able to grow by close to 170 bps of capital this year. As a main element, of course, our retained earnings net of the dividend that we resumed paying; the deleverage is also very significant, mostly on legacy assets. There is also a decrease in risk-weighted assets; here again, no trick there. You might have noted that risk-weighted assets decreased by &#x20AC;13 billion this quarter, out of which you have roughly &#x20AC;2 billion which are related to metallurgical impacts, so very limited.</p>
          <p>The majority of the impact is related to either the deleverage or the fact that credit is lower than it used to be. We have a lower activity. If you add to that the financial impact; and more importantly for the year, I didn't spend that much time is a press on that because it bit technical, the fact that we have moved, in the legacy portfolio, some risk-weighted assets have moved to deduction. So we have less risk-weighted assets and more deduction in total. The impact is neutral to even negative, but it has a significant impact in terms of risk-weighted assets. So it is a mix of all this which makes us go to 10.7% Basel 2.5 core Tier 1 ratio this quarter.</p>
          <p>Starting from there, we have reset our roadmap to Basel 3. We have reset the roadmap. We have not reset the objective. The objective is still to be between 9% to 9.5% by the end of this year. If you make the calculation, you will see that with the all the pluses and minuses that we put together, we are at 9.5%, which gives us some room to further increase the risk weighted assets used by businesses, which can even be improved if we do some further disposals. I think Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric will comment on that later on.</p>
          <p>So what are the main impacts; of course, earnings with the dividend provision. From that perspective, the fact that there will be or there will not be, we don't know yet. It could be there is no impact, it's considered being paid in cash, if you consider end of this year; so net-net, 75 bps of net earnings after dividend.</p>
          <p>Legacy assets, the bulk of the deleveraging is behind us. We'll continue working on this, but here again, as we often say, less to do. We want to do as much as we can, but it's more and more difficult.</p>
          <p>Disposals, another close to 50 bps, 45 bps to be precise; we now have all the economics of this transaction. We have already mentioned, but now I think we give the figure regarding the impact of IAS 19, which will be taken onboard the first quarter of this year, 15 bps negative. And we have also that's where the reset has happened; nothing really surprising there, moving from 210 to 240 bps; here again I would say in full transparency, the major impacts are impacts which are related to the volatility of certain aspects of Basel 3, namely the way you handle deferred tax assets, and the calculations are pretty, pretty difficult, and also the way you handle the VaR on CVA, which is also quite difficult to stabilize actually. So we have taken 240 bps to be on the safe side. Here again, we'll of course update you if change is happening, but I think we are on the safe side with these 240 bps.</p>
          <p>The other element relates to the fact that we are basically at Basel 2.75 as far as insurance is related, is concerned. As you know, until end of last year insurance was deducted from total capital. Starting with Basel 3 next year, insurance will be treated as risk-weighted assets as a Danish compromise. But this year, we are back to the situation before, which is a mix of risk-weighted assets and deductions, which will have negative impact. It could be very significant under Basel 2.5 at the end of this quarter, roughly probably 60 to 70 bps order of magnitude. We have to finalize the details. But moving into Basel 3, then you will regain part of this. So we estimate, and this is probably the best figure you have to remember is that the net-net impact of moving from Basel 2.5 to Basel 3 is 30 bps for insurance.</p>
          <p>So there will be two impacts on capital, negative impact on capital. And then at the end of this quarter IAS 19 and insurance, and the positive one which is the capital gain we'll make on Egypt. So that's basically in terms of capital. The rest again, we think is pretty secure, and that's why we did not educate that much to use the word secured on the headline of this page.</p>
          <p>On the balance sheet, we have tried as well as and that's why probably we have some discontinuity with the funded balance sheet we have used previously. I think now we have stabilized this, two messages there. On the long-term side, the surplus of stable resources over long-term assets has grown. We were basically at minus &#x20AC;14 billion end of 2011, and now we are at plus &#x20AC;51 billion. So this is a very significant change due to increase in deposits and a decrease in the loan-to-deposit ratio, increase of capital even if its marginal, and we are not talking about billions but still it's a positive, and also the fact that we've been able to raise more money on the long-term front than we anticipated last year in the market. So we have a real restricting in debt on the funded balance sheet, which I think is a pretty good element.</p>
          <p>Regarding the short-term side, the main factor is the fact that we have moved from a coverage ratio, if I may say, of our short-term liabilities of 71% a year ago to more than 100% now, not including the &#x20AC;25 billion safety margin on top of that. Here again, it's a mix of &#x2013; it's something which is very difficult to assess, the fact that we receive money. There is liquidity, so we receive money and we transfer that money basically to the Central Bank, so you move two sides. It has a cost. We have reduced that cost. As you see, we were closer, if my memory is correct, over &#x20AC;140 billion, so we are trying to end that situation. But more importantly, the fact that we are using less short-term money within our business line, and on top that that we are in proportion more long-term resources than short-term resources also today. Here again, it's a strong rebalancing of the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Funding conditions, I will not spend too much time. Again, last year was pretty good from a funding perspective, from a price perspective, and more importantly from a diversification perspective. A year ago, our initial thought was that we wanted to raise &#x20AC;10 billion to &#x20AC;15 billion and we saw the vast majority of this money will be secured funding, but to now we have raised more than double what we expected, and only 20% was secured funding. We've been able, like other banks, to go back in the U.S. market. We've been able to go to Japan for the first time. We've been able to go twice to China. It's very symbolic; we were in total more than &#x20AC;100 million. We have been able to issue Tier 2 at the end of last year. And more importantly from a business perspective, our specialized financial services have been very active on the securitization front, which is also a way to reduce as a need of group funding for these businesses, and it's I think very important going forward.</p>
          <p>Our long-term funding program, &#x20AC;18 billion to &#x20AC;20 billion, is taking into account the fact that we have redemptions next year, &#x20AC;23 billion. It's the fact that we have started to reimburse part of the LTRO, and we will continue to manage this regularly over the next two years, the fact that the businesses will use less long-term money. So this is basically the mix of all this increase, in fact we have prefunded, with the excess of long-term resources raised in 2012 prefunded 2013. So this is really what is behind this &#x20AC;18 billion to &#x20AC;20 billion figure.</p>
          <p>In terms of cost of risk, if I have read correctly what some of you have written this morning and the reaction of people on the phone, I understand that there is an area of concern regarding French retail. It's neither as good nor as bad. What I mean with that is that we are at 50 bps for the year, which is exactly what we said a year ago. The profile is not exactly what we had in mind. It has been like this with a significant up at the end of the year. Looking forward, we think that we should be at 60 bps for the French retail, so it's not a drama. It's not a positive, but it's not a drama going forward. I think it's important.</p>
          <p>The rest again is very stable, although the stability of international retail banking is made up of at least additional cost of risk in Romania and the lower cost of risk in Russia. Going forward, we are anticipating that the cost of risk in Romania actually to start decreasing first half. This would be more material second half. This is very good what we have in mind. Whereas in Russia, we are at the low point and it's likely to increase a little bit, but without any problem looking out.</p>
          <p>CIB, nothing to mention; SFS is being driven down by good management of the cost of risk in the consumer credit business.</p>
          <p>So bottom line, we have raised the cost of risk from 57 bps to 75 bps. And again, if you look forward, we do not anticipate as the group level a devaluation going forward but for France, where we expect to move from 50 bps to 60 bps going forward. So again, it's an issue, but it's not as bad as what I've read sometimes throughout the morning.</p>
          <p>In terms of millions euros, that's where you have the impact. It's taken in Corporate Centers, the impact of the &#x20AC;300 million provision for litigation.</p>
          <p>In terms of consolidated results, in the figures there are &#x2013; if I take a step back and compare 2011 and 2012 in big figures, underlying top line is more or less the same slightly below from &#x20AC;25.5 billion &#x2013; &#x20AC;25.6 billion, so stability in terms of top line.</p>
          <p>Costs are down, and I think it's very important. Not only was as budget that we adopted a year ago down compared to 2011, but on top of that we have pushed throughout the year to reduce the costs. And further they have been mitigated by some ForEx impact. But bottom line, real costs in real euros are down &#x20AC;600 million. I think it's a very, very important achievement along with the balance sheet restructuring.</p>
          <p>In terms of risk, if you look at the figures, the risks are down. In reality underlying risk if you exclude the Greek impact in 2011, the cost of risk is up, and this is mostly due to France and to a lower extent part of international retail.</p>
          <p>So these are the main figures: stability of the top line from one year to another in a difficult environment; costs very well managed, down &#x20AC;600 million; risk slightly up, &#x20AC;200 million out of &#x20AC;4 billion, so nothing again to worry too much about at that stage. So these are the main figures; underlying good net income, as I mentioned, &#x20AC;3.4 billion, which is very comparable to last year as well.</p>
          <p>If we move to the various businesses, and I will not flip through all the pages; I will leave Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric to comment on the perspective for 2013 for each business. French network, in two elements: first of all, good commercial performance; second, stable gross operating income, made up of stable revenue; as you see, fees down going forward. We already said that we are looking at this very carefully. It's likely to be either flat or slightly down this year. We don't see upside in the French revenue this year. Costs will be under control; so stable revenue, stable costs, stable gross operating income, which in this environment is already an achievement, all this being impacted by the rising cost of risk, plus 20% over the year. These are the main items that we wanted to share with you this afternoon.</p>
          <p>International retail key elements, first of all the disposal of Greece will have a positive impact on our bottom line definitely, whereas the disposal of Egypt will have a negative impact on this side. So it's a significant change in the scope of international retail. Russia, I think 2011 and 2012 were years of restructuring and transformation. And the third quarter was starting to be promising, so is the first quarter. And so we are looking forward with some comfort on Russia. Most of the efforts are behind us now. We have to basically reap the fruit and start enjoying growing revenues.</p>
          <p>Romania, as I said, key item; not only are the revenues under pressure given the cost structure and the price structure of Romania, but going forward the key will be the cost of risk. Cost of risk has been impacted by two elements, the major one being the economic situation in Romania. The GDP of Romania is still 6% below what it was in 2008. So we have this economic impact, and it does have an impact on the cost of risk. On top of that, as you know, we have been impacted by a flood, which is now fully provisioned. The impact last quarter of this &#x20AC;28 million &#x2013; &#x20AC;25 million, in total &#x20AC;180 million over the last two years fully provisioned; we don't expect additional costs. So the vast majority of the deterioration of the cost of risk is not related to that flood although there is an element of flood, but is related to the deterioration of the economic situation in Romania.</p>
          <p>Czech Republic, not much to say; they are also being impacted by a slowing economy, but the profitability is maintained. Cost of risk is also slightly rising, whereas the rest of our network is still doing very well with very encouraging growth.</p>
          <p>CIB, a good year; especially you should take into account the fact that we have today 1,400 people less than a year ago and that our costs are down by 13% excluding bonuses. So it's a transformed, streamlined CIB that we are considering today. And despite all this, the engine has been working relatively well with an exceptional first quarter, an exceptional third quarter, and a good fourth quarter. The second quarter was more difficult, as you remember, driven by Global Markets; and within Global Markets driven by the fixed income business, where we have outperformed the market, again, based on people which have already released their figures. We compare our plus 58% to something which is probably close to 20%. So we have really outperformed, driven mostly by short-term rates but not only; short-term and long-term rates but not only.</p>
          <p>Equity, it has not been a year of equity last year. We are slightly underperforming the market as defined today, which is mostly driven by American performance, and we are less dependent on the American market than the Americans, so it has been make the comparison somewhat difficult. But still, our analysis is that the market is down probably 10%, and we are down 12% so far. So that's really where we are, whereas the market risk as measured by VaR in our stress test has been kept under control throughout the year.</p>
          <p>Financing and advisory, they have suffered from the fact that they have been also focused on deleveraging, so you cannot do both. At the same time it's also moving from the traditional paradigm to the more [original] distributor, so everything is transitioning. So going forward it should be better. So 2012, I don't think, is a representative year.</p>
          <p>Regarding the legacy assets, as I say, &#x20AC;90 million of negative impact; here again, it will decrease significantly quarter after quarter. And as I say, the guidance is probably roughly &#x20AC;50 million per quarter.</p>
          <p>Regarding the last two poles before Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric will be more specific on pillars because we are moving from five posts to three pillars; Specialized Financial Service and Insurance, not much to add; it has been great a year and those are record quarters this last quarter, driven both on the insurance front where we still have positive net inflows where as market is still negative inflows.</p>
          <p>On Specialized Financial Services, I just want to underline the fact that for the fourth consecutive quarter, consumer credit is positive. It's still modest, &#x20AC;21 million. But after three years of negative results, it's also very interesting again. What I would like to stress is a fact that we have external funding initiatives. This is major shift in the way you do these businesses. And for many, many years, these businesses were funded 100% by a group. Now they have raised &#x20AC;4.2 billion. It's only the beginning. We have already raised &#x20AC;500 million in securitization in January. So it is not only securitization. It's also raising deposits like GEFA in Germany, where we have already &#x20AC;1.5 billion starting from scratch mid last year. So this is very, very important. And again, going forward, the objective is really to maintain this momentum.</p>
          <p>In terms of the last pole, Investment Management and Securities Services, Private Banking; Private banking is proceeding, it's turning around, cost reduction is there. Inflows are starting to grow a little bit, so we going in the right direction. Securities Services, terrific competitive pressure on margins, so you have to work a lot on costs, which we are doing; so again, it's doing relatively okay in a very difficult environment.</p>
          <p>Newedge, you have read our presentation made in December. We've taken the necessary consequences of this decision. We impaired the entirety of the residual goodwill; difficult environment and we are working on the next steps with the management of Newedge.</p>
          <p>Asset Management, not much to add, I mean I think our friends have created a recovery. They will comment on their performance tomorrow.</p>
          <p>And I think with that, I will move to the last page, which is the Corporate Center, which is basically taking onboard all the consequences that I mentioned regarding the exceptionals, whether it's the owned debt, whether it's the litigation provision. Again, nothing specific, I'm pretty sure you all have ideas regarding what can be done on this provision. If we had precise ID, if we have a specific provision, so it's really an assessment of the fact that there are number of disputes litigation with various regulators or commercial litigation. We assess that there is, being on the safe side, putting aside certain minimum is also a good way to prepare for 2012.</p>
          <p>Another point, and I know there have been some questions at this point regarding the underlying figures of the Corporate Center besides the exceptional elements, we discussed that at length I remember during Q3. It's true that I would say the excess liquidity, the LTRO, et cetera, as a cost, which is in a significant part borne by the Corporate Center, here again with the reimbursement of the LTRO and with a better liquidity environment, if everything remains equal, Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric might comment on that, this cost should decrease over time.</p>
          <p>In terms of cleaning the Corporate Center, we have reallocated the systemic tax base, as you know, on risk-weighted assets.</p>
          <p>And with that, I think I've covered most of it, Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you, Bertrand, so just a few words in conclusion to speak a little bit more about 2013 and beyond, so based on what we have achieved in 2012.</p>
          <p>Aside from completing the roadmap for Basel 3 because you've seen we are very comfortable on that, I think 2013, first of all, will be a year where we will have progressively more visibility, more visibility on the regulations. We should have this chart before at some point, hopefully in the first half. The law in France which should be also voted in mid &#x2013; at the end of the first half of 2013, so we should know a little bit about I see the definite rules of the game. And secondly, as Bertrand said, on our accounts we'll have less exceptional ones as the bulk of the transformation is behind us.</p>
          <p>The focus is going to be really to the second step of the transformation. And the first thing would be on the businesses, and I would like 2013 to bring three confirmations. The first one is that the French Networks will be resilient. Yes, the economy will be flattish, plus 0.3%. But in a market where there is still some good activity coming from the demography, the commercial activity is pretty good, even in the beginning of this year, but again which is under pressure because of the rates. We've talked about this, some commissions which are again under pressure because of political decisions; so all in all, revenue which will be flat or slightly down I think.</p>
          <p>On the costs, a lot of work which is being done and this year is going to done to further adapt the network of branches. We adapt to the changes of behaviors of clients. There are productivity gains to be made. And of course, we carry on with the conversions of IT systems. This is a big project. You have not seen any costs on that because we basically reallocate expenditures to this project, which will bring further savings.</p>
          <p>And on the cost of risk, we've said it's 60 basis points. Keep in mind in the front retail, it does not come from individual clients on the real estate which represent 55% to 60% of the loans. It does not come from self-employed professionals. It comes from I would say midsized corporate. And again, it depends. Some of the ones which export are doing pretty well; the smaller ones which are more domestically focused which suffer from the current economy.</p>
          <p>All in all, keep also in mind that we have three brands, Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale, Cr&#xE9;dit du Nord, and Boursorama, which provide services to different categories of clients, with Cr&#xE9;dit du Nord which has completed also the integration of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; Marseillaise de Cr&#xE9;dit in the south of France, which has been very successful and where we have strong market share in the most dynamic regions of France, and I consider that the plus 0.3% will not be equal everywhere. Their concentration of the economic growth and demography will be in certain regions of France, and we are more in these regions around Paris, Lyon, and for example, the south of France. So in my view, we should in the long term do relatively or slightly better than others in this environment. So that's the first thing.</p>
          <p>The second confirmation is that effectively International Retail and CIB can provide growth, and I'm convinced about this, International Retail because we're in geographies which will overall grow and certainly more than in the Eurozone. And I'm convinced that in Russia in particular we can further get the benefits of all the hard work which has been done by leveraging more on synergies on the retail, and what is very important also in now on the corporate side. As you know, we have had a decrease of the lending book on the corporate side, which put more resources on the ground, and I consider that we should see the results of that. And we will look progressively to the SMEs also in Russia. So here we should have again growth. And as we've said, we are confident with the aggregation of the cost of risk.</p>
          <p>And Romania, we've said that, yes we will adjust on the cost, and on the cost of risk we should see progressive improvement. So again I'm confident that we will see a better contribution.</p>
          <p>In other geographies, there will be growth and I'm considering that here we will further open branches, get clients et cetera, so I think it will be a growth driver certainly, accounts which will be much better after the refocusing that Bertrand has described.</p>
          <p>CIB is a little bit different. It's not that much that I expected to be grow the market as such in 2013. We'll see. As I said, generally we had good volumes, but let's wait until beginning of the year. It does not mean that it's a similar case for the full year, but I think we will gain again further market share. Reorganization is in place. It's an organization which is focusing, as you have seen, on three pillars, equity and equity derivatives in particular which works well. On the fixed income, we have made very good progress in 2012; number two, for example, on the bond in euros for corporate. Same thing at the beginning of this year; there was good activity. And again, it's part of the model to originate and distribute, and this is going to be further developed in our businesses. We have again structured credit, which will be distributed to investors.</p>
          <p>Regarding then the third confirmation, aside from that, so two cylinders with growth, one residence in another. I want to put more emphasis, even more emphasis on the synergies across the universal group with the other businesses and in terms of functions and cost. And that's why we've decided for a rationalization of the organization of the group, in effect three pillars. So we've put together the retail outside France and the specialized financing businesses to further enhance the synergy, in particular consumer credit and the retail outside France business, there will be further refocusing of these activities and to align our presence with our presence in retail.</p>
          <p>Regarding the businesses like GEFA, the leasing and the fleet management, we are very positive about the development; again, despite less scale resources which are being used. There is also good development and insurance is doing well, and we going to tow again synergies across the different retail networks.</p>
          <p>And the second merger that we are going to do is between SG CIB and GIMS, Global Investment Management and Services. With the sale of TCW, basically private banking, custody, and Newedge, we think it makes sense to put that under the same umbrella and just also to save some cost aligned functions, but also to develop the synergies. There will be changes in the markets in Europe. It will take some time. It's not yet there. It might be the next five years just to align on the execution, clearing, and custody businesses and functions. I'm convinced that there are synergies both commercial and from an IT point of view. And please, if you wish, we have on one hand further synergies to develop with the retail networks, but also with the CIB business, when I think internationally in particular with ultra-high net worth individual.</p>
          <p>So we will push on that front on the revenue side. And as I've said also regarding the different functions to make them more efficient, simpler, we will be able I think to save costs. So we have been negotiating with the trade unions for three months now an agreement, and I'm hopeful to have a signature, support from them to precisely implement these different project which would take place during 2013.</p>
          <p>That's what I wanted to say. We are really enjoying, again, a second phase of the transformation. And commensurate with that, 2013 will remain a transition year from an economic point of view. We should not expect any miracle I think in Europe. The rest of the world is doing pretty well. Markets for the time being are relatively good. We will see again, if it's asked. But let me say that we have a very clear roadmap going forward to of course further improve the profits; again, that's exceptional; and deliver in 2013 a good return on equity to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>That's what I wanted to say in a nutshell, and now we are ready to answer your questions those physically and on the line. Let me just again of course thank Bertrand for his last presentation as a CFO of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale and wish him all the best as Managing Director in charge of finance for the World Bank, and of course welcome Philippe Heim, who will take over March 1 this year. Philippe was Bertrand's deputy. He has executed the program of disposal I think very well, and he is taking over March 1. You will have for those of you who are there, the time to meet with him and of course going forward. First question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. It's Guillaume Tiberghien at Exane. I've got two questions, the first one related to the cost of liquidity in the Corporate Center. I heard, Bertrand, what you said earlier, but still I'm trying to reconcile first the liquid assets. I'm much higher than they were quarter ago. And the cost of liquidity is much, much higher.</p>
          <p>Secondly, if I annualize the revenues of the Corporate Center excluding fair value loss on own debt and the CDS, I get to about &#x20AC;1.5 billion negative, and consensus for next year is only &#x20AC;750 million negative at the revenue line. So should we just put the number in between, or where should we actually put that cost of liquidity or where are the revenues of the Corporate Center?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know because Hans mentioned that question that you regard this morning. I'm a bit puzzled, so I have to go because there's no significant shift underlying from one quarter to the other. As you say, the structure of the balance sheet does not change significantly. Again I don't have this on top of my head, sorry. So we'll come back to this. It's probably a valid question. Looking forward, we are working on the Corporate Center to make it more ratable. And, Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric, go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You have again for the time being I think exceptional costs as we carry and I say a lot of short-term liquidity which goes to the balance sheet, and we have assets or money in the central banks. Going forward, I hope that we will be able to reduce both sides of balance sheet, these stay there and it's negative.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we've had an increase during two years of the cost of issuances. And fortunately, we've been able to issue at the lower priced end of this year and beginning of this year, we've issued for &#x20AC;5.5 billion at the lower cost. So again, it will need to factor that benefit progressively. Then you have also all the carry of the goodwill which stays in the Corporate Center, which will stay in the Corporate Center, and I don't expect that to change.</p>
          <p>Regarding the cost, what we have decided to do is to reallocate the levy and the systemic credit to the businesses, which represents something which will represent &#x20AC;140 million in 2013, roughly reallocated to the businesses and reallocated at fourth quarter. So again we will again come back to you and your calculation. We do not have the capacity to check your calculation. We will try to give you more view on the evolution of this Corporate Center, which I think probably remained loss making, but I think which will progressively improve in by 2015 with again this reduction of buffer and again a bit more cost allocated to the businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, 2012 was a bit exceptional because we have an impact of the LTRO refinancing et cetera which will decrease over time. So again, based on what I think today, we are closer to the low end of what you would expect than to the high end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My second question is below the net profit line, you've got a dividend on the undated subordinated debt. And I apologize if my calculation is wrong, but it seems to have actually increased in Q4 compared with previous quarters, and I didn't have that in mind. But on an annualized basis, it's still about &#x20AC;80 million more and that's still around 2% of your EPS, which is not negligible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, we'll check on the fourth quarter. We have issued a perpetual bond, by the way, in fourth quarter we need to check out. Probably it's linked to the issuances we made.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Andrew Lim at Esp&#xED;rito Santo. You talked about reducing the liquidity buffer, but I was wondering if you could disclose what your LCR is on the new Basel 3 basis? And I think presumably that's actually below 100%, so obviously that implies an increase in the buffer, does it not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We took account for in production. Point number one, we will meet the target this year. Point number two, we think that we have already met it now. We have two caveats, the first one the fact that it's still unstable in its definition. So I am very surprised that some competitors might produce a figure which is very precise because I can tell you the production of this figure is very difficult. You really need to cover all the production of deposits et cetera, et cetera, and you don't do it like this. It's a production issue.</p>
          <p>And second, this is my point is producing this ratio based on a number of assumptions including assumptions we make on the final decks which is not voted yet. We think that's why we're already there. So I put this disclaimer strong, but even with this disclaimer I think we're already there. We'll definitely be there officially sometime before the end of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And if you wish, if I can think about an evolution of the balance sheet going forward. We are going to further collect deposits. It's pretty clear. And in France, I think in this economy which is not growing, people will carry on saving money. I don't expect such a strong role for loans. So you can also improve your ratio, starting from a base which, in our view, is let's say roughly at 100%-plus, but we have all the caveats that we said on the interpretation, without increasing more the amount of money which is coming from whatever, investor money market fund, and which is there in the central banks.</p>
          <p>So it is a change in the balance sheet which can be pursued without having the same cost potentially. We think, and again trying to optimize the usage. There is a kind today of reinsurance that we carry in the liquidity which we think we might optimize going forward. And then you have the cost of liquidity itself, which might improve compared to what we had issued in the last two to three years because of the stress also in the Eurozone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just ask a quick question on the consequence as well of the French networks? You're guiding to 60 bps. Is that immediately for the first quarter and then staying at that level or is that just vague kind of figure for 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We talk about really relatively small figures, and when you talk about midsized corporates, it's not even a statistic. What I mean by this, one corporate can change an additional &#x20AC;10 million to &#x20AC;20 million depending on the size of the loan. Again, the very important thing to remember is the big crisis in banking comes from real estate and mortgage loans. In France, we have a situation where there is a shortage of flats, and the level of construction will be particularly low in 2013. And with a demography which is much better than elsewhere, we have a shortage of flats.</p>
          <p>So all together, prices have remained relatively high, which should see in our view a slight decline. Knowing that people have &#x2013; and France has also very low leverage. I have in mind that for a fee of something like just 30% of the owners have the mortgage and probably around 60% of the households, 60% &#x2013; 65%, something like this, owns their flat. So again on that front, which again represents the bulk of the loans, I don't see any issue.</p>
          <p>Then as I said on the self-employed professionals, the situation so far remains good. I think consumption has been relatively good in December, from what I hear from clients, but weaker in January, but again nothing that bad. And so it means again it's more in certain sectors, construction, things like this, which are very domestically oriented that you can have effectively losses. You don't plan that. Our guess, our assumption is that it will be 60 basis points for 2013. Whether it will be first quarter or not it is too complex.</p>
          <p>There is always seasonality in the fourth quarter, keep that in mind, but it's too complex to predict. And keep in mind also just the fact which is difficult to plug, which is that the government has decided this tax relief for corporate which will be financed in 2013. I don't know how it could play also on the financial situation of corporates. It's a bit difficult.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois from Goldman, three quick questions if I may. The first one was one on your fixed income business, which this year was exceptionally good, as you mentioned before. You were talking about in particular strengthening the short-term rates business. I was just wondering, right now that your LIBOR is turning a little bit or at least is stabilizing at low levels, is it something which is going to be harder to extract revenue from? Is this a driver or is this an indicator of the strength? Because essentially I'm just trying to try and figure out what the drivers are behind that strength compared to competitors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we've been pushing for now starting from a relatively low base in fixed income, we've been pushing for two or three years to increase, first of all, our distribution capacity, our foreign exchange business in particular in relation with our presence in emerging markets. We are very strong in euro rates historically, et cetera. So this is I think delivering it. Certainly it has delivered in 2012 with the change of management and organization of the teams, which has been good.</p>
          <p>And certainly, on the corporate side, on the DCM side, a very good performance, we are number two with the, again, bounce in euro with corporate; it's part of the model. I think we've been able to align more the financing also with that. And I'm positive that it will deliver at least beginning of the year. Again, the commercial volumes are good, so it's more I think commercial activity than anything else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Then on the French Retail part, you have talked about flat revenue, flat cost. Actually, I had in my mind maybe that for the first time we could see some outright cost decline in France. Is this out of the question, or how are we looking on that front?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, when you talk about zero-plus or zero-minus, the capacity to predict, again, on the revenues, let me say there are the headwinds I have discussed but also we might have on the other hand the benefits of the decrease of the remuneration of the [area]. What it will be in August, I don't know. I'm just saying that, when you talk about this, it can be difficult. Revenues will be anyway overall under pressure.</p>
          <p>On the cost side, as I said, we are going to make further productivity gains and we finance our IT system while reallocating expenses. In 2013, I would start more with a flat cost. On the IT side, it's always &#x2013; it's easy to say, of course, you don't invest. I don't think it's going to make sense in this environment because, again, we expect further productivity gains from that. And having one system shared by Cr&#xE9;dit du Nord and Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale and the quickest as possible makes sense. We have already one IT team. I think that postponing or delaying the investment is not necessary a good idea. So I would say managing the cost something like this more or less flat in my view makes sense.</p>
          <p>Again, be careful in first quarter. The tax levies in the fourth quarter you will have all that, but again overall flat should be your assumption at this stage. If we can do better, we will do better but I'll start more with this kind of assumption.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And lastly, have you got a sense of where you would like to steer the cost-to-income ratio at the group level over time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, it's difficult &#x2013; I don't like very much to add different businesses. On the French retail going forward, I think we still need to keep a 60% target. It will mean adjusting the network; it's not probably for the next two to three years. We will need to really extract more productivity gains. It will take some time and probably some kind of rebound both from the growth in France and perhaps also a slightly better interest rate environment.</p>
          <p>Regarding CIB, you've seen that the cost/income ratio we have achieved on the recurrent activities is below 60%. I've always said that 60% to 62%, something like this, is my view, the right target at least for our business model in order to deliver a return on equity based on 10% through Basel 3 between and 2013 and 2015, which again remains my target for this business. So I think we are there. And again, in the cost, there is also the level of investment you make. And cost is not just minus; it could be also some investment. And for me, this business makes sense if we achieve precisely and confirm this capacity to make market share gain because it's a way also to work on the growth of the world. It's a way to go beyond the Eurozone and accompany clients beyond the Eurozone to capture growth.</p>
          <p>Regarding the other businesses, international retail, certainly in Russia we need and we will make better, probably 70%, something like this. Yes, it's something like this, 65% &#x2013; 70%. This is a target for the next I would say three years, in 2015. Romania, for example, has a cost/income which is pretty good. There is a small question of cost of risk. So again, depending on the businesses it can change. And overall for the group, we will make further savings, as I said, on the functions. So again, we will give more clarity. I think we will give more clarity to the market by year end. When I say this when we will have more visibility on all the rules of the game in terms of financial figures for 2015 and this two or three-year horizon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just lastly, have you got the sense of the revenues at stake in the French banking law compared to your current French rate in CIB?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The revenues which could be at stake or targeted by the French banking law on potential separation of this and that and so on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me say there are really I think two topics under French law, the French retail itself, which is more about capping or not and for what kind of population certain commissions when there is an incident on the accounts when it's checked and not addressed, which has not been agreed. This is one thing. On the law given the fact that it will be implemented in 2015, I don't expect it impacts immediately. And as we've said and you know the law is a bit complex because there is the idea to put aside the speculative activity and with a definition of market-making which will be up to the Minister of Finance and regulator, it will take time.</p>
          <p>Given the model today, we are pretty comfortable that a very small part will be put in the subsidiary at the end of the day. In addition, we've said in 2006 maybe 20% of the capital market activity; today 3% or 5%, something like this, not more. And again, it's not certain because the regulator will go through the balance sheet and make his mind according to the guidelines of the law. So I don't expect an impact for the next basically two years on the revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Derek De Vries from Bank of America. I've got three questions, if I might, starting with I guess a pretty easy one. You announced this morning the streamlining of divisions from five to three. And I can understand your reluctance to want to quantify the cost and revenue synergies because of that given your union negotiations and whatnot. But if I were to take an estimate and if I were to quantify it at &#x20AC;300 million to &#x20AC;400 million, would you try to dissuade me of that order of magnitude? That would be my first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're very well in the lines of the environment in which we work. So I prefer to be very, very pragmatic, efficient, and deliver. But let's say we have ambitions there, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then the second question. You've given actually very clear guidance on French retail and on the revenues and the provisions, and that's predicated on 30 basis points of GDP growth next year. If I were to take a slightly more negative but I think still a plausible scenario with say negative 70 basis points, so 100 basis points worse than you were going for, what changes would that make to your revenue and your provision forecast, or is it all broadly kind of...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The revenue composition is so diversified again between the commissions people might say than if they come back to, for example, equity, more financial products, we will get commission there. Interest rate is an important component because in the margin there are loans, but deposits are very important. It's not necessary directly related to GDP. We have in mind low demand for credit. I think it will not be that significant, clearly. I don't think it will be that big.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then I guess the last question is just a detailed number question. Looking at your legacy assets, the capital consumption from the non-investment-grade assets rose from &#x20AC;1.2 billion to &#x20AC;1.7 billion while the balances were basically unchanged. Actually they slightly shrunk I guess in that base I assume. So I guess we're seeing asset quality deterioration there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a purely prudential accounting thing which will disappear next quarter, which is related to a name which I'm not supposed to mention today where we have discussion and we have anticipated from a prudential perspective that's what I mentioned regarding the increase of the deduction versus a decrease of risk-weighted assets. So it's a transition period, but I'm not totally comfortable to disclose more than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is not related to the rating of the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's related to a specific operation which is being discussed as we speak.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that could theoretically have an impact on the overall Basel 3 ratios you've given?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no because it is a transitory increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But the capital consumption you gave is a fully phased Basel 3?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We had an increase end of last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have a decrease fully next quarter. It's really &#x2013; again, I'm sorry. I cannot provide more detail on this maybe...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Everybody will understand which name I might have in mind or not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And again on the legacy assets, our analysis is that we should basically keep the money good asset; at that number, the return is very good. There is no reason given the size and we will further save of the money back. But again, depending it's not that easy so we will do that progressively. We know ROE in 2013. And we see naturally still the improvement of price still on these assets, yes. And I will turn to you I don't forget you, sorry about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good afternoon. I am Nick Davey from UBS. I've got two questions please, if I can. The first is on corporate banking and the revenue run rates. If I understood you correctly, you are quite optimistic about revenues going into 2013. I just wondered if you could expand on that a little bit. We saw quite a contraction in the gross books outstanding in CIB Q4 versus Q3. So I'm just trying to understand why this revenue number from Q4 wouldn't be the run rate for 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I said is last year was impacted mostly by the deleveraging profits and the restructuring of these businesses. Here again, we have already forgotten because as time goes by that we have discontinued or severely restricted some business lines in 2011, whether it's aircraft finance, shipping finance. We are more moving towards advisory business. So we say this has an impact. If you look at our figures in 2011 you don't see the impact because we have been good elsewhere. So that's why I called 2012 not really a run-rate type of year. That's why I think now we have stabilized the team, stabilized the business lines. We are moving more toward really a distribution model et cetera, so going forward that's why I am more optimistic. And so again, don't try to estimate next year based on a given quarter this year. It's still...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the fourth quarter, if you wish, in particular in Europe was a relatively challenging quarter where markets have stopped basically mid-November, even after such strong activity in financing. Again, I don't know what 2013 will be. Clearly in my mind there was more activity and more confidence coming back at the beginning of the year than I expected. Again, maybe it's a bit more down today. Overall, we are, as I said, confident to be able to gain further market share in a market which might remain relatively stable, but with again certain fronts which we are growing still or asked to reorganize, refocus. We are clear in our mind in the model and the organization is in place.</p>
          <p>I meet with a lot of clients myself from all over the world, and I met a lot of them end of the year because it's the opportunity to see where we stand, where all the projects are. I'm very confident in what we have achieved in 2012 and about the potential. And so we're again maintaining a straight choice policy. I'm confident in the revenue generation and the profitability of this CIB business. But our ambition is precisely to show that to you in 2013 and also show that this originator/distributor model effectively works and further develop in particular regarding the structured financing business. Kinner, I know that you are here, but...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I do have another question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, just one final question then. How should I think about the pace with which you'll repay LTRO? I'm interested to see that you have an issuance plan for this year which is below what is maturing. You talked a lot about deposit growth. And obviously, I would have assumed that LTRO you will be replacing with stable funds, be it deposits or issuance. So should I think that you'll repay LTRO at the same pace that deposits come into the bank? Is that the right way to think about it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It depends also on the capacity to issue. Again, we've been able to issue &#x20AC;5.5 billion in the first six months, including a &#x20AC;500 million securitization on &#x2013; it was car loans. We will be very pragmatic, and let's say the idea is to reimburse that progressively let's say in the next two years basically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not really, that's what we say from an ALM perspective, and we said that a year ago. We didn't want to create a wall at the end of the period. We don't want to create a bevel at the beginning of the period. So we try really to submit it at the very beginning, and then we try to do linearly in full agreement actually with the regulators.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we can do more and more quickly, we'll do it. But if you wish, it's a kind of insurance premium, there is cost, as we've said, and the cost might disappear progressively. But we can accept to have that for the time being as a kind of insurance. At least so far so good, including I must insist on the transformation of the financing of the leasing business, and this is very important.</p>
          <p>When you think that a business like GEFA, which is a wonderful leasing business in Germany, are selling to German companies, manufacturing equipment good to SMEs in Germany. It's now financed basically 60% independently, starting from more than zero. They collect deposits because Germans are very happy to finance Germany. So there is also a shift in the way these business are financed. We've seen this for more than &#x20AC;4.2 billion, whatever, independent funding in just one year. We are going to pursue that. And again, we think that we might just further our need for wholesale. Overall, I would like further diminish the wholesale funding consumption with the group in particular on the financial services.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kinner, if you allow me, I will come to this lady and then to you. Anke?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot, Anke from RBC. I have one longer and two shorter questions please. The first is on the reorganization, and I just wanted to better understand how important it is for you. So is it going to lead to a presentation of detailed targets, or is this going to be releases to early days? And is this something which you can do without a market recovery, or is it more focused on costs or revenues, and does it also focus on balance sheet leverage? That's the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The question of one hand further developing revenue synergies and cost synergies taking just into account that &#x2013; I will just give you a simple example. We have already a human resource department which has common in Asia between Priv and SGCIB, and it makes sense. So rather than having in each pillar you know the same function, in fact pillars, it's a way to multiply or generalize this kind of experiment.</p>
          <p>Secondly, again on the revenue side, as I said, I think it's a way to effectively further enhance synergies on the revenues. And that's valid for credit, as I said, on consumer credit in particular; also from a geographical point of view rather than having a business plan which is organized more on a worldwide basis. It is not related to any market recovery, and we will do it because it make also the work simpler. And the idea is to reduce also the number of &#x2013; what do you call that, hierarchical levels in the functions like compliance, et cetera. We have multiplied the layers and I think there is a way to be more efficient by reducing this.</p>
          <p>So we are going to implement. As I said, we will probably around year end I can't tell you if it's year end or just in the year 2014 when there is clarity gives you more flesh on the figures by 2015. But I want first to know exactly where we will stand with liquidity standing forward and the French part, and we will not know before midyear, so you need to be a bit more patient.</p>
          <p>And let me say we have in France a process that we need to comply with, and I must say I'm particularly keen on maintaining a strong dialogue with the trade unions so that it can work and be delivered quickly. That's what we've been doing now for three months, and so we will progressively present the different projects to the trade unions. And there is a consultation process; we have to comply with that. So we will do this in a very disciplined way. We have negotiated with them periods of time for that. So it will not be dragged along but we have to comply with these rules. Then you had two other questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just have one. Did I understand you correctly that you said the insurance hit on Basel 2.5 will be 70 basis points?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, roughly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a plus &#x2013; it's a negative impact of 70 basis points, and then with the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Plus or minus, there is total of net 30 bps is really what you want <mark type="indiscernible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kinner, you have another question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. So I just wanted to come back to this question on fixed income that we discussed. Last year was I think truly exceptional in the rate environment that we had LTRO at the beginning of the year and OMT coming in, which I think provided special dividends for the industry in terms of revenues, and it appeared that SocG&#xE9;n benefited more than others, so I'm trying to understand here to what extent. We could say that this year the rates business in particular within fixed income is likely to be down and it's going to struggle to match anything like what we had last year. There were some banks that were meeting their budget &#x2013; their full-year budgets fairly early on in the year given how strong this business was. So that's the first question.</p>
          <p>Second question is just on general regulation. I just wanted to get your thoughts on the risk rate review, where we saw some obviously the report coming out from the Basel Committee. And I must say some of your peers are maybe giving us more disclosure on leverage. Even I'd say a big German bank that was not deleveraging has started to focus much more in terms of the leverage ratio and how that could improve. And also the Fed proposal that we have in the U.S. that came out in December, whether that has any impact on your business in the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The <mark type="indiscernible" /> proposal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The derivative proposal. And the final question was just on the cross-border funding gap. It was a big issue last year, banks trying to essentially close the funding gap cross-border into the periphery. We haven't heard much about it. What's the general view on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to start with this. The cross-border funding gap for us was not such an issue because &#x2013; let me just remind you. We have a presence in France. With the sale of Greece we don't have any more retail presence in the Eurozone. Then we have, as I said on specialized financing businesses, which will rely on the parent company and which are developing independent funding for bank loans, deposits, securitization, all kinds of funding, and with the idea basically to make them more and more independent, of course, from the parent company.</p>
          <p>Our international retail is outside the Eurozone and the same thing. There are still some differences from one entity to the other. But overall the idea is to have a loan-to-deposit ratio of 100%. And let me say, when there is a decrease of loans in Russia on the corporate side and Romania which is the low activity, of course there are drawbacks on the revenues, but at the same time, it reduces the funding needed. So for us, it has not been I think such an issue. And what is important after that is we can issue regularly long-term funding to finance our CIB business, again with less loans in the balance sheet et cetera.</p>
          <p>So I consider that overall we are very close I think to right structure of the funding. As I've said, there will be reimbursements of LTRO, further deposits, et cetera. But overall, I don't expect such a big change in the system. We might hope to have a bit less money in the Central Bank at some point because again it's not profitable. But again, perhaps it will take two years of the Central Banks withdrawing liquidity.</p>
          <p>The Fed proposal, let me say beyond that, I was just reviewing all the U.S. regulation and I must say it's still a bit of a mess. When I say this for <mark type="indiscernible" /> we still have to fit our level. We don't have yet visibility on that after three or four years of being discussed. You will have all the swap dealer registration; we have registered there. There is lot of work still to be done et cetera, but we are assessment, we are in line with any firm regarding the requirements. Then there is the Fed proposals where effectively it could mean if you wish more capital, it's still unclear. And let's say I think there will be a debate with Europe on that front because it puts effectively pressure on non-U.S. banks. I am sure I will be forgetting a few other regulations, but there is whole menu which I would say will make the business anyway clearly more complex in the U.S., and I don't even add the litigation risk, structural litigation risk, which seems to increase overall with any businesses in the U.S. going forward.</p>
          <p>So I think from a strategic point of view, we will remain focused in the U.S. What we will try to achieve is selective development on our core franchises. Typically for example, we pursue the business in the energy sector. There is a reserve oil financing with a high-yield refinancing which is developing in a world where I think the energy is a big positive for the U.S. in the next seven years. We also develop a credit platform because if we want to originate and distribute on the energy sector, on the mining sector, a lot is still U.S. dollar-based and we have even assets like using if we want to engineer a system where we don't finance ourselves but we finance. And clearly having a presence in the dollar market will be useful. And then we are also present in equity derivatives, for example. So selective presence, a lot of hard work in different projects requested by the regulation, but I would say I don't see at this stage any strategic impact compared with that issue from the different regulation.</p>
          <p>Leverage ratio, it's a ratio we don't like in particular because the accounting are not the same. What we do is a present a balance sheet which is a more funded balance sheet and I think more comparable to U.S. peers. The leverage ratio will, of course, increase going forward because we have more and more capital. And overall the balance sheet will not increase, that's clear, if I put aside the valuation of the mark-to-market valuation of derivatives, which can vary from one quarter to the other depending on market perspective. But again, it will be, as far as I know, still a period two requirement, and we look at this.</p>
          <p>What I prefer to assure you that at the end of the day, we have also a clear understanding what is in the balance sheet. I'm confident there. If you look at the last five years, the evolution of the balance sheet has been tremendous with much more deposits, much more loans, much more long-term funding, and a very significant decrease of short-term financing. And again fundamentally, aside from the further refocusing on specialized financing I was mentioning, I am happy with the structure of the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>What do I miss around the rates? Again, it's difficult to comment. I would like to insist we were starting from a low point 2011 in fixed income, as you know, overall. Overall, we think, as I said, that we should have including on fixed income a relatively good year by gaining market share, leveraging on additional investments in terms of sales force, and additional synergies with our different presence. Again, let's wait because, again, six weeks does not make a full year, but our commitment is to deliver a second year in a row of good, solid I would say revenues and good contribution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Risk-weighted assets review?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The risk-weighted assets review, there is again this debate. It's very difficult at this stage to comment on that. What I hope is that there will be progress going forward with one regulator in Europe. I have absolutely no clue to check or have any visibility on what is being made on the U.S. And at the end of the day, I rely on the French regulator which, again, has spent a lot of time in reviewing the French models in the different foreign banks. What I am pretty sure is that there are no big differences between French banks. That's what I can say given what they have been doing to validate Basel 3. But the rest, who knows? That's where probably a European regulator will be useful to further check.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Paris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will turn the line to our friend in Paris. I will come back to the room and then...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Paris, you have the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening, Pierre Chedeville. I have many, many question, but I will disapply myself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Pierre.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Better. I don't want to come back off late. First question related to your organization, I'm not very clear about the melding between international retail and financing, specialized financing activities. For instance, I don't understand why FRANFINANCE are factoring or leasing in France with the link to international retail instead of your French retailer. For instance. Boursorama is going to work with FRANFINANCE by launching some credit consumer. I don't see why this will not be in the area of Mr. Sammarcelli instead of the area of Mr. Incera. It's not a question of person but it's a question of logic.</p>
          <p>My second question is related to the CIB. I listened to you carefully when you were talking to deputies at the French Parliament. And you gave an argument regarding the separation of activities. And you said, for instance, for a non-investment-grade German company or French company, you said that it is much more comfortable to make a swap, a long-term swap, or a DCM operation with JPMorgan than with a small subsidiary, a small CIB subsidiary. But actually, isn't it right now much more comfortable for a company to make a long-term swap or DCM operation even with JPMorgan than with SocG&#xE9;n, even if separation of not activities not happening in a certain sense and even the war already lost because of the concentration of fixed income activities that has actually been a consequence of that probably. And the fact is my point is the separation of activity for me is anecdotal compared to the moves in this industry. And I feel that your example is already a good example, but it's not very good for SocG&#xE9;n. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pierre, regarding consumer credit, first of all and for all the people here, I hope they know the people you refer to. First of all, for the time being, FRANFINANCE refers to <mark type="indiscernible" />, so I'm not putting something in France to something international as a French component is only international. We will define and detail the organization. And again, if there are refinements, if may say, from that point of view, we will decide about these kinds of refinements. But today I'm not changing at all the system, and the current situation is that FRANFINANCE, which is a French business, reports to Didier Hauguel, which reports to Bernardo Sanchez and not Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Sammarcelli. So we will again refine in the next two months probably the target of the organization.</p>
          <p>For English people, the people listening here or are being present, let me just explain what I said to the members of Parliament in France. I said to them, if you create a specific subsidiary where with no guarantee from parent company and where you put all the market-making &#x2013; or let's say more than just non-client driven businesses, my view is to say this subsidiary will have low rating. I don't see in the current environment how it could have a reasonable rating. The issue is from that perspective how it could on one hand be competitive, even on the market-making because the cost of liquidity or the amount of capital, whatever, would be much higher than the large universal banks, including in the U.S., which of course benefit on their rating from their universal and retail activities. And that's including the issue we are talking about a long-term swap, a seven-year, whatever, a five-year swap.</p>
          <p>Same thing is true with our company; you deal with a small subsidiary of something which is not rated not guaranteed. I was saying I have my doubts that they will have such an appetite versus universal banks. The issue is today, I can guarantee you there is no problem. We have a good rating. The concentration is not just such and there is a limit to concentration knowing that I think the big change on the interest rate swaps in particular might be more removed from OTC to listed products. If it takes place one day it seems in the U.S., we will see in Europe; it might take more time. But certainly I feel we are able to compete on our franchises clearly, if we have more or less the same rating and then we play with the same rules. If it were to be totally different, I think it would then be very detrimental. And personally, I think it seems that we have convinced the Parliament, which again will select what is non-client related, it's very speculative to put in this subsidiary which has not been guaranteed.</p>
          <p>Are there other questions in Paris on the line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Delphine?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Delphine from JPMorgan, just maybe two questions. First of all, sorry to come back to the Corporate Center, but just to understand what has been said previously by Bertrand, is it fair to say that for 2013 at least, we should expect a relatively let's say high revenue loss in the Corporate Center, mid of the range, let's say &#x20AC;700 million to &#x20AC;1.5 billion. And on the cost side in the Corporate Center, if you basically transfer the &#x20AC;138 million related to the systematic tax, the run rate seems to be close to &#x20AC;160 million. Is that what we should be taking going forward, or is it still a little bit higher than what we have in our numbers?</p>
          <p>And then secondly on the French retail provisions, if you could give maybe &#x2013; is it possible to get some color on let's say the books which are suffering a bit more, like construction, the midsize corporate, and what kind of NPLs or coverage do you have at the moment? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I start with your question we don't dictate by sector the NPL because, as I said more of the sectors which are domestic which are the ones which do not expose, so typically construction, it could be car dealers, people like this which suffer more than, again, SMEs which can export and have just a limited amount of their turnover in France or in Europe. You can have also some midsized transportation companies, things like this.</p>
          <p>Regarding the other question on the Corporate Center, again you will have, yes, a negative figure. Keep in mind that you might have still some owned debt impact on the first quarter. You will have the capital gain in Egypt, which again that we've said we'll have this additional burden of this excess liquidity, if I may say so, and of the LTRO, which will progressively disappear in the next two to three years. But I think these are the major elements we expect.</p>
          <p>On the cost, basically the cost is a relatively small figure. There are a few Corporate Center &#x2013; corporate costs which I think we have not reallocated like the finance division because you spend a huge amount of time to discuss with the businesses what is the right allocation key. We have absolutely no benefit from the group and at the end of the day the decision of the CEO to know exactly how many people he wants to have. So it's pointless to spend too much time. You have still also the cost of the share program that we put in place in 2010 and distributed to the staff from an accounting perspective. There is something like &#x20AC;50 million or I think a year, and I think it will last through 2013. We distributed 40 shares to staff in 2010 depending on conditions. This is the kind of cost I don't expect to be changed on that, as I've said, in 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One more question in Paris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Kiri?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good afternoon. I have one question which is, and I will limit myself to one question, which is about Russia. I don't know what the capital allocated to Russia is, in fact, out of the &#x20AC;5.6 billion you have in international retail banking, but I would assume it's a bit less than &#x20AC;1 billion. However, if I look at the book value of your holding in U.S. Bank, it's probably closer to &#x20AC;4 billion, and this is based on a company which is generating revenues of about &#x20AC;1 billion. So before you get to a return on these investments, or even if I take only the capital allocated, which would be close to your cost of equity, it would take quite of big margin on the revenues. And I was wondering whenever you're expecting basically revenues to go significantly up, or what kind of restructuring and what kind of timeframe you expect on this. And then alternatively, if you think that or if you don't think that such a margin is achievable, why don't you start considering just exiting this country, which seems to be a big drag on your return?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, we might debate for a long period of time on Russia. But our strategic view is to think that Russia will offer better growth than a lot of European countries. I'm just taking into account what happens in the energy sector, and I'll discuss that with an energy specialist. The U.S. will be independent in 2020. The Middle East will more and more work with China, and I personally consider that there is a common and long-term interest between Europe and Russia to work closely together on that front.</p>
          <p>Secondly, regarding again our performance, as I said today, it's &#x20AC;100 million of net profit taking into account fleet management, consumer credit, insurance, all the businesses we have on the ground at CIB. I have in mine a lower figure of &#x20AC;4 billion, but we will check. And again, I think that yes, the idea is to develop the revenues because it's more of this which is at stake. We have cut costs significantly and we will further cut costs. For example, may I say that on the realistic side, we have reorganized the network from I think 40 different regions to eight or something like this. Forgive me if I'm not absolutely accurate with the figures. We've cut the staff by more than 2,500 people. We sold businesses and there are still some empty premises in southern cities that we have not yet either re-let or sold. So yes, there will be further cost improvement, but fundamentally I would expect a revenue increase and to get what I would call a decent return on equity by something like 2015.</p>
          <p>So again, we will present figures for Russia. My conviction when I look at the business models in Europe, I'm not particularly confident in the growth in Europe in the next two to three years. I'm not that confident on the evolution of retail. We have here I think a way to improve significantly the businesses, develop synergies, and effectively deliver profitability acceptable even with capital allocated in all the environments in this country. So we will present that more in detail when momentum is positive. For me, 2013 is a year of confirmation for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a follow-up to your questions on Russia. The question is you want to develop the revenues and obviously to develop the corporate franchise and develop the loan activities. However, looking at Q4 and Q3, loans are down; and if we look at the loan-to-deposit ratio, it's still at a high 125%. Isn't it a huge constraint to develop the loan activity? In fact, it is the question to develop the deposit base, or really to develop the loan activity itself? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's really both. It's not just loans. When I talk about the development in Investment Banking business, and obviously I also control actions I cannot comment. It's also to help companies not only to issue bonds locally but also on the international markets.</p>
          <p>But regarding effectively the business, it's effectively to further develop our deposit base knowing that we started with, again, Rosbank, which have deposits but also this consumer finance business which is everything else, which has no deposits. So here again, like for our other subsidiaries, there is effectively a progressive need to rebalance and effectively collect more retail deposits, again, in a very immature market on the retail side altogether, more retail deposits going forward and maintain a good balance between loans and deposits.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello, Alex Koagne from Natixis, just one very quick question on the funded balance sheet. I saw that the excess liquidity &#x2013; the excess long-term liquidity is down Q-on-Q. I was just wondering whether this is a sign that you are very comfortable with the structure of your balance sheet right now and that you should not keep on increasing the excess liquidity, or is it just an optical, let's say picture? And I was just wondering if you are very comfortable with your short-term funding representing 20% of your balance sheet, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bertrand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The question is whether we are comfortable with today's situation or not. I think we'll continue, as Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric says, to slowly change the situation. I think where we are today compared to where we were last year, there is a great achievement. Now we will &#x2013; I don't think you really see some massive changes going forward. This being said, deposits are likely to increase. That's what they say in France and outside France, which I've discussed Russia. And this is a fundamental element of restructuring the balance sheet because more deposits you have, the less outside funding you need.</p>
          <p>And within this outside funding, you can split between long term which is kind of a given. We think that we can raise &#x20AC;20 billion at six to seven years of average duration, and then you can basically find out what kind of short-term financing you need. And whatever is in excess can go straight to the Central Bank is exactly what is happening to it. So that's really basically the math of our balance sheet today. So the main elements going forward would be really to have a rebalancing of this loan-to-deposit ratio, which will happen to a certain extent naturally and to a certain extent with some push on our side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And after that, there is a 20% short-term I think it's, again, a roughly that we have in mind knowing that we use that for market activities and, of course, also to have some money in the Central Bank. So I would not expect a dramatic change today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, it's not short-term money used for long-term financing. Clearly, this is one of the lessons learned from the crisis of 2011. We have been able at that time to adjust our market activities rapidly. And now we are driving our market activities with that in mind. So whenever there is a problem, we can really adjust the volumes of our market activities very rapidly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the 20% of today is not exactly the 20% of 18 months ago. That's what we think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric, just a really quick question about the so-called competitiveness tax credit. Do you expect any impact on your non-French business anywhere?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, this competitiveness credit is tax relief. Let me say a slight positive, but overall we will pay more taxes in 2013 than in 2012 with the other increases. And I will not go further on this thing. But I think all together between 2009 and 2013, the group will pay an additional &#x20AC;300 million of additional taxes of all sorts, social, corporate, systemic, whatever. So, yes, some benefit but it will not change the picture.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which will mostly impact, of course, our French retail network and the structure of this tax relief.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, any other questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question in Paris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No more questions in Paris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a quick follow-up, Jeremy Sigee at Barclays. I apologize if I missed this at the start. Could you give the Basel 3 RWAs? You changed the roadmap a little bit. So have you given or could you give where you think Basel 3 RWAs were at the end of 2012 and where you see them at the end of 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we provided some figures last year, which to be honest, I don't have on the top of my head today which are more or less still valid on average, so you should rely on that. Adjustments, as I said before you arrived, were mostly related to some volatility elements which are mostly related to the structure of Basel 3 and namely the tax deferred assets which is not directly an RWA question. And also the VaR on CVA, which is still a work in progress in terms of calculation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You have questions. Sorry, sorry, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A very quick question. So if you're thinking about a stable balance sheet, you'll get to a core Tier 1 around 9.5% by at the end of the year potentially. You still have a low dividend payout of 25%. So what could that mean for your capital ratios going forward and your dividend payout?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a very good question and this is something we will effectively have to address by year end. And again, I want to work a little bit more on that. I have in mind, of course, to potentially increase the payout ratio, but there would be this question of balance between the payout ratio and further invest in the businesses. What I want to check &#x2013; and again that's why I need more visibility on the rules still. Of course, the profitability of the business is once everything is more or less decided, and I think it's better to wait still and to optimize the balance going forward in 2014. We will stick I think to we will see where we will end 2013. But I stick at the end of the day for the time being at 25% for 2013. We will see for 2014 &#x2013; 2015 having a better view on again all the potential of the businesses. I have in mind a potential increase of the payout ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have one last question on the line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from John, please. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, just one very brief clarification. As you were running through slide 11 with the group cost of risk, I believe you indicated that you thought that the group level in 2013 will be quite similar to the group level in 2012; i.e., around 75 basis points, so the increase in the French Networks is compensated elsewhere. Was that the correct understanding? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, in practice as we said we would expect this increase from 50 to 60 basis points in the French retail, potentially a slight decrease in the international retail, as we said, basically and related to Romania; the rest, to be frank, more or less stable, we do not see any reason for big changes in Specialized Financing, and I must say on the corporate side, the large corporates has overall a sound situation, plenty of liquidity. So, yes, in practice that's what we have in mind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no other questions on the line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one follow-on question please. I think you might have mentioned this before. But could you confirm what the profitability of the Egyptian NSGB business was in 2012, and could we take that as a proxy for what the decrease in the profitability of the international business will be go forward 2Q and onwards?</p>
          <p>And then just following on from an earlier question on slide 40, you do have a notable decrease in the CIB. I was wondering if you could just give a bit more color on that going forward and what has actually happened there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank Yes, perhaps on Egypt, we will have first &#x20AC;100 million roughly in 2012, but let's say around &#x20AC;100 million contribution roughly in 2012. We have the Q1 quarter in 2013, and the balance between the disappearance of Geniki and the disappearance of Egypt should be slightly positive overall because you have to take out the losses of Geniki in 2012 and the contribution of Egypt, and I have in mind that it will always look positive.</p>
          <p>CIB, we have a decrease of credit. It's the benefit of the deleverage. And keep in mind, before you get Geniki out of the balance sheet, your need to close the deals in practice, so you can have provisioning of the deleveraging quarter before, what else, some interest &#x2013; some currency elements also. The dollar increased. And the legacy assets, yes, because, as we said, this shift between risk-weighted assets and the legacy assets and more deduction. So here from a capital point of view it's neutral but it's a treatment, it's a Basel III treatment, less risk-weighted assets, more deduction direct from the capital. These are the three elements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And it's also I think <mark type="indiscernible" />. Part of this is loans to financial institutions which, at year end, might have some seasonal impact last year. So it doesn't change anything regarding the [delevering] trend going back to one of the questions I think from Kinner on the corporate book. It's mostly related to year-end impact of relationship with financial institutions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Are we done for today? Okay, thank you very much for your attention. Thank you, good evening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the conference call. Thank you all for attending. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>