<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1472280" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-05-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3179</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Bertrand Badr&#xE9;</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Delphine Lee</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer-Corporate &amp; Investment Banking, Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA">Didier Valet</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Jon Peace</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Neuez</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Kinner R. Lakhani</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Natixis SA (Broker)">Alex Koagne</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods Ltd.">Jean-Pierre L. Lambert</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Maxence P. Le Gouvello du Timat</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Thibault A. Nardin</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Anke Reingen</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">Guillaume Tiberghien</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Global Investment Management &amp; Services">Jacques Ripoll</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole Cheuvreux SA">Pascal Decque</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Bank Plc (Broker)">Robin F. Down</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Kiri Vijayarajah</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Execution Noble Ltd.">Andrew T. Lim</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Kepler Capital Markets SA (Nederland)">Beno&#xEE;t P&#xE9;trarque</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good afternoon, everybody. I'm very happy to be here with the heads of the various business units of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale to comment with you, our first quarter results, and most importantly probably today our roadmap as far as Basel 3 capital is concerned.</p>
          <p>The main message is of course on page one. I will not spend too much time on this page and we will focus more on details on the following pages. First of all, it is important to stress because quite often we forget that we are based on the real business, and it's not about just refinancing, deleveraging, and capital building. It's also about business performance. And I think it's important this quarter to stress the fact that even if we are not back to the level that we had or we enjoyed a year ago, Q1 2011, we enjoy a significant rebound from last quarter. Depending on the perspective you take, ether we are still 5% short of our revenues of first quarter last year or 20% above our revenue of last quarter 2011. That's I think a very important achievement.</p>
          <p>In that context, we also have pursued efforts vis-&#xE0;-vis cost expense. You know that it's a very important target for us and for me, and we will continue our efforts in that perspective. Second element, I will comment in more details in a few minutes. Capital building, we are there both from a Basel 2.5 perspective and for Basel 3 perspective. It's of course difficult to play with two thermometer,  if I may say, but we have to play with two thermometers. It has created, if I've read your comments in detail, some difficulties to analyze effective impact of the deleveraging this quarter. And here again, I will try to provide additional flavor for you to better understand where we are in that perspective.</p>
          <p>Third, we have pursued a transformation of the group. On the one hand, transformation means deleveraging, which means a lighter balance sheet, and a better financed balance sheet. On the other hand, it's also about adjusting our business model, especially our corporate and investment bank business model. Fr&#xE9;d&#xE9;ric Oud&#xE9;a has been already provided some details regarding the new business model of SG CIB. If necessary, Didier Valet is next to me and will be more than happy to provide additional details if you need them.</p>
          <p>And of course, and it's very important in a deteriorating environment, risk is under control from two perspectives. On the one hand, and you're familiar with that, with the GIIPS countries, the peripheral countries of Europe, our exposure has declined from &#x20AC;2.9 billion to &#x20AC;2.6 billion on the banking book. Whereas our cost of risk in general is where we say it would be, so there is no early signal of a material deterioration, and it's still kind of okay, as for the various business lines, especially within the CIB.</p>
          <p>That, in a nutshell is the main messages that we wanted to share with you this morning, or this afternoon, technically.</p>
          <p>I will spend on next page, a little bit more time on capital. I know it's been an issue, heavily debated for the last two or three years. We provided first, comprehensive picture, end of 2010, as you remember, prior to the final release &#x2013; at that time, final release of the Basel Committee. There've been several final releases since then. So it's an adjustment to this preliminary analysis provided to you 18 months ago on Basel 3.</p>
          <p>In the meantime, we had to adjust to Basel 2.5. As you remember, the EBA had set up a target of 9% EBA definition Basel 2.5 for the thirtieth of June this year. We were already there by thirty-first of December, and we have increased our position in that perspective moving from 9% to 9.4%. How did you get there? It's, again, it's pretty straightforward and quite comforting. We've been there on the one hand with our return earnings, which is basically the performance of our business, roughly 20 bps of Basel 2.5 capital accumulated.</p>
          <p>Second, we also have made some progress in deleveraging of the CIB and mostly vis-&#xE0;-vis the legacy assets. You don't see that in the risk-weighted assets; it's mostly about losing on the deduction of capital. So it's not exactly an impact that you might see if you look at the risk-weighted assets of the CIB. But the impact in terms of Basel 2.5 whether it's about disposing of this asset or cracking the CDO is a positive one. It's relatively positive under Basel 2.5 definition, above 10 bps. It's even more efficient than the Basel 3, which is not material yet, but which is important for my next point regarding our roadmap to Basel 3. But we make more than 20 bps with this legacy assets active management. So on Basel 2.5, 9.4%, 40 bps achieved this quarter. It's quite promising and encouraging for the quarters to come.</p>
          <p>Regarding Basel 3, here again I know how frustrated you've been with our last quarter results by the fact that we did not provide a detailed roadmap to go to end of 2013. Here you have the detailed roadmap. First of all, we start with the figure that you have mind, the 9% that was achieved thirty-first of December, Basel 2.5 definition. And I'd like to walk with you, how do we get from 9% Basel 2.5 to above 9% Basel 2.3 at the end of next year?</p>
          <p>On the negative side, or the impact of Basel 3. So here again, it's a comprehensive vision of our best assessment of the impact of Basel 3, 210 bps. It's a mix of two things. As you know, you're familiar with Basel 3. On the one hand, Basel 3 means more deduction. On the other hand, it also means an inflation of the denominators, more risk-weighted assets.</p>
          <p>On the deduction front, it's roughly 40 bps or &#x20AC;1.4 billion of deduction, mostly related to deferred tax assets and to minority interest, and these are the two main items. Of course you have the rest, but these are the two main items, roughly 40 bps. And close to 170 bps corresponding to &#x20AC;70 billion additional risk-weighted assets. To calculate this impact, we have based our analysis on what is the so-called Danish compromise, which is important in that respect from two perspectives, minority interest and insurance treatment.</p>
          <p>What are the main elements behind the inflation of risk-weighted assets? Insurance of course roughly &#x20AC;12 billion of risk-weighted assets, but also of course it's not a surprise as the CBA, which also will have a significant impact on our CIB risk-weighted assets. And also closely related to our legacy asset securitization, which will cost more than even under the Basel 2.5. So roughly 210 bps, again our best assessment of our position today, &#x20AC;1.4 billion deduction, additional deduction, &#x20AC;70 billion of additional risk-weighted assets. How do we face that shock? That's 210 bps shock. It's like for our move on the Basel 2.5 this quarter. On the one hand, our return earnings; on the other hand, deleveraging of SG CIB.</p>
          <p>Return earnings, we have based analysis, of course, on public information, basically on new figures, guides on the consensus. The main adjustments we have made, though, is the fact that we have decreased our payout ratio from 35% to 25%. Again, this is subject to the decision made by the board and the General Assembly next year and the year after. But that's an important adjustment, basically, which makes us more in line with the market. The net earnings minus dividend provision is 150 bps, so that's roughly two-thirds of the 210 bps. The other third is provided for by deleveraging 70 bps, which is made more &#x2013; I mean, more for &#x2013; for more than 50 bps by the legacy assets efforts, and the rest being provided by the kind of deleveraging of the loan portfolio, basically.</p>
          <p>Here again, the 70 bps is not just a wishful thinking exercise. You will see on the following page, that we have already done, achieved, or secured 25 bps out of this 70 bps. And I think it's important. That's also why it's difficult to, at the top of the page, to have the Basel 2.5 roadmap, at the bottom of the page, to have the Basel 3 roadmap; it's not exactly the same impact.</p>
          <p>Regarding legacy assets, the same efforts provides for 10 bps under Basel 2.5, and more than 20 bps under Basel 3. That's also sometimes a little bit misleading. And there is also an impact on the risk-weighted assets calculation.</p>
          <p>As I say, even if it's stable and somewhat disconcerting this quarter, the effort that we've done on the legacy assets has also an impact on the &#x2013; capital impact of the securitization, and so it's more important for Basel 3 perspective. So I hope it's a little bit clearer.</p>
          <p>So with that negative impact of 210 bps compensated &#x2013; I don't want to use the word mitigated; it's been too widely used &#x2013; so compensated by our earnings and by the deleveraging, we come to 9.1% Core Tier 1 fully loaded Basel 3 figure end of 2013.</p>
          <p>On top of that, of course, we still have intentions, so don't misread this page. We still have the intention to dispose of assets. Objective as stated a few months ago is to reach 100 bps with a range of 50 bps to 100 bps; that's still what we have in mind. And this is how we will add some flexibility to our business model, namely to expand our credit activity with the French International Retail. That's how we'll manage the company. We'll create flexibility by making these disposals, and we'll use this flexibility to increase our credit business while staying within the 9% to 9.5% objective, which is ours for Basel 3.</p>
          <p>So I've been a little bit long. I hope it's clear. And of course, if you have questions, I'd be more than happy with my colleagues around the table to answer these questions.</p>
          <p>The following page on deleveraging, I will go a little bit quicker. As a reminder to what &#x2013; of what I just said, out of the 70 bps expected on Basel 3 from the deleveraging of the CIB, we have 25 bps which are already secured. And as you see graphically, most of this 25 bps are coming from the active management of legacy assets, whether it's selling &#x2013; we have sold &#x20AC;0.6 billion of non-investment grade legacy assets. Or whether it's with cracking these assets in order to sell the underlying assets too. So that's very important point, 25 bps already secured, which means that the total amount of assets sold is still important, especially from a liquidity perspective, but not as important as it was a few months ago.</p>
          <p>The objective that we have asked the team in charge of dealing with these assets is to secure capital relief. Here again, probably it's much more important to secure capital relief, to have 25 bps of capital relief secured in first of January, is more important for me than, I think the massive headline figure of disposal. Of course, if we can have both, that's better. I think &#x20AC;6 billion or &#x20AC;7 billion is still a very significant figure. But the objective, again, is capital relief, and that's what we have in mind.</p>
          <p>Next page, funding. Again, the picture is easier to discuss than it was three or six months ago. On the long-term front our refinancing program is achieved. I mean, we had in mind to be between &#x20AC;10 billion and &#x20AC;15 billion, and we are at &#x20AC;11.3 billion. It doesn't mean that we will stop our efforts, just it says very simply that what we've done is we have seized every window, every opportunity on every mark. Whether it's kind of symbolic, we have raised &#xA5;500 million in China. Whether it's more important, over &#x20AC;2 billion of senior unsecured funding. Both are important for me. So we've been able to be active on all fronts. We've also securitized car loans in Germany, for instance, and so on and so forth.</p>
          <p>So that's a very important message. We've been active at prices, which of course with 148 bps on an average, for what it means, is higher than what we were used to five years ago, but still it is not as bad as what people have said, especially when you compare this with some CDS measures, for instance.</p>
          <p>Second, our funding profile also is somewhat better this quarter, at least from two perspectives. On the one hand, the balance between long-term liabilities and long-term assets is better. On the other hand, the balance between our buffer on &#x20AC;4 billion, so &#x20AC;20 billion more than where we were three months ago, and our short-term liabilities, &#x20AC;117 million. The gap is getting shorter. I think it's an important signal as well of our strengthening of the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Next page regarding our results. Main message is that the top line has been impacted by two significant point. On the one hand, the mark-to-market and our own debt and our CDS portfolio above &#x20AC;200 million, at &#x20AC;213 million. And also the cost of deleveraging, which is also a massive impact on the performance of the financing business from the CIB, &#x20AC;226 million.</p>
          <p>So you have two ways to look at these figures. As I said in my introduction, on the one hand, you can compare these figures with first quarter last year. We are shy of 5% regarding the top line. So it's kind of back to where we were, but not still there yet. Whereas the operating expenses are under control and started down. The cost of risk is stable. We have very few exceptionals this quarter, if any. And so the bottom line is coming closer to where we were a year ago, &#x20AC;732 million compared to &#x20AC;900 million.</p>
          <p>You have another way to look at this figures is to compare them with where we were three months ago with the last quarter of last year. In that if you take &#x2013; if you make this comparison, what we see is absolutely different. The top line is up by more than 20%. Operating expenses are also down by close to 2%. The cost of risk is down by 8% if you exclude the Greece and legacy assets. Underlying cost of risk is down, not exceptional. And then, no surprise, the bottom line is a multiple by 7.</p>
          <p>So the reality is between both. It's an important rebound since last quarter. But we still are cautious because when you have survived the last four years, you know that by definition, you have to be cautious looking forward. It is being said it's a good starting point this year, and we of course enjoy these good figures.</p>
          <p>Regarding the cost of risk on the next page, at the group level we have a slight decrease from the cost of risk, but again it depends business-by-business. In France, we are of course down compared to last quarter, but we are still up, and you have some seasonality impact. We are up, slightly up from last year &#x2013; compared to last year. There is no early signal of an accelerated degradation of the situation. But we don't expect any material improvement. So it should go up slightly.</p>
          <p>International Retail, it's a mixed basket of different things. But all in all, there are no significant changes in trends. The very good news is on Specialized Financial Services, while it's been decreasing as far as the various business, especially in consumer finance, one of the lowest levels since the beginning of the crisis, with a strong decline in Italy. CIB is very low and here again, like in French Retail, we do not see any signals of deteriorations to come. Again, we are cautious and we will pay attention to everything which might happen. So for the time being, it's a positive but cautious outlook.</p>
          <p>Business by business, French Networks first. In a difficult environment, again, French growth was close to zero last quarter and still close to zero. We have pressure on income, whether it's on the fee and commission, where there've been some regulatory and legal changes which have a negative impact on our top line. On margins, as well, where the pressure, even if it is a credit margin improving for the year, we're still under some pressure. So bottom line, we have slightly up net banking income.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses are higher than the growth of the net banking income, but still not growing that fast at 1.7%. So this year is supported by commercial environment, commercial momentum, which is somewhat better. Deposits after more difficult second half of last year, up. It started at the end of last quarter of 2011. As you know, our figures are average figure so they do not exactly reflect the trends for the quarter. So basically we benefit from the efforts done in November and December, which still are working this quarter. So deposits are up.</p>
          <p>Credit, we are still doing our business. We are providing credit to the French people in the French economy. On the insurance front, I come back to that when we discuss the SFS figures. Insurance has been positive, where the net inflows of &#x2013; technically net outflows on the French market by &#x20AC;2 billion. We are positive. Slightly positive, but still a positive inflow regarding our life insurance business in France. And I think it's an important &#x2013; so overall, from a financial perspective side, but still positive, better than last quarter, supported by some commercial momentum.</p>
          <p>International Retail, you're very familiar with the business. It's a story of different worlds. We have also a significant rebound from last year in areas which have been very much impacted by geopolitical events, whether it's North Africa or Sub-Saharan Africa with Ivory Coast. So we have a very strong rebound in these areas, more than 12% in North Africa, more than 20% in Sub-Saharan Africa in terms of top line.</p>
          <p>Credits and deposits are up here again, with strong performance in these areas. While it's still more difficult in Greece, the news on that front. Although the cost of risk in Greece is to a certain extent lower than the &#x20AC;100 million that we have kind of budgeted, we are &#x20AC;76 million this quarter in terms of cost of risk. For one thing that we have no corporate trouble this quarter, or almost no corporate trouble this quarter, while the kind of underlying statistic or deterioration is still there.</p>
          <p>The situation in Russia is impacted by the transformation that we are undertaking there. On the one hand, as you know, we have merged the various entities last year to create one entity. On the other hand, we are in the process of letting go more than 2,000 people, out of which, I think 1,400 people are already gone. So this has created some turbulences at the business level, which is as a main explanation behind the fact that we are not as dynamic in Russia as in the rest of the International Retail Banking area.</p>
          <p>Here again, on International Retail, an area of concern, especially for the CFO, is the fact that we want these businesses to depend as little as possible from the group funding. Even we are now below &#x20AC;7 billion, and we intend to go down, further down the road in the coming years as an objective. All in all, we have a loan-to-deposit ratio of 99%, but there are still some variation, vis-&#xE0;-vis these average figures, and we are working on this variation mostly in Central and Eastern Europe and in Russia.</p>
          <p>Corporate and Investment Bank, it's been a very good quarter. I think most of you have already noted this in your preliminary analysis, driven by strong performance of market activities. The fixed income on the one hand, which has outperformed the market, and has more kind of tripled since last quarter, and is above &#x2013; more than 60% above last year's figure. Driven both by strong commercial performance, and the fact that market indices and market conditions have kind of normalized, although I'm quite reluctant to use this word, normalized. Again, things are sometimes difficult to analyze.</p>
          <p>So driven by fixed income in various business lines, actually, equities revenue are also up compared with last quarter, less so vis-&#xE0;-vis first quarter last year. But still in line with the market, and we still enjoy our leadership position in this market, and not much to add. More difficult was the beginning of the year for the financing advisory business, which were heavily impacted by the cost of deleverage, which is concentrated on these businesses, more than &#x20AC;200 million, which offset our performance in underwriting businesses. We have had one of our record quarter in terms of DCM. I think we see best DCM performance since Q3 2009 so over the last three years, both in euro and in dollar, actually, for European corporates. Our rankings and our volumes and our fees are very significant this quarter. And also, even if it's not as impressive, also pretty good performance in ECM.</p>
          <p>Important factor in the CIB is the control on operating expenses. Besides the adjustment program that has been announced early this year in January, the underlying trends in expenses excluding bonuses is very good. We are down 6% compared to last quarter if you exclude the restructuring charges, and even 7% versus Q1 last year. So here again very strong efforts to maintain the cost base, and not only maintain, but decrease the cost base.</p>
          <p>Regarding legacy assets, the main elements what I'd said regarding the active management of these assets. We have disposal of &#x20AC;1.5 billion this quarter. On top of that, &#x20AC;0.6 billion were amortized. Out of this, &#x20AC;500 million were non-investment grade assets. So half of the problem, if I may say, with a very positive capital impact, whether we take this in Basel 2.5 or Basel 3 figures. I've said that already.</p>
          <p>In terms of P&amp;L, whereas we had some impacts of adjustment especially regarding the treatment of our MBIA position last quarter, the P&amp;L impact is back to where you were used to it, around &#x20AC;100 million or &#x20AC;29 million with two main effects. On the one hand, MBIA, as you know, because we have &#x2013; we are now more kind of mark-to-market driven with our CDS position. And second, the negative impact, which is a positive from a capital perspective regarding the cracking of one of our significant CDO. So bottom line, not so much impact from our biggest CSA this quarter besides a positive capital relief impact, which was exactly the objective we said at the beginning of this year.</p>
          <p>Specialized Financial Services and Insurance on the next page, it's pretty straightforward. It's probably the &#x2013; not probably &#x2013; actually it's technically the second best quarter ever after the second quarter of 2008. We were there at &#x20AC;167 million. We are at &#x20AC;163 million this quarter driven both by Insurance. I mentioned the positive net inflows, which is a big difference with the rest of the market. And also driven by the good performance of the various SFS business lines. Although on the one hand, production is under constrained, which means technically the production is capped and not growing. But the top line is protected by the margins, which are still either flat or up. And the fact that the cost of risk, which is an area of attention and focus over the last few years, is down significantly. So all in all, a very good quarter for this area, both Insurance and Specialized Financial Services.</p>
          <p>Last and certainly of course not least, GIMS, Global Investment Management and Services. After last quarter, which was impacted by a series of one-offs like litigation and impairments, we are back to a more normal set of figures. Again, it's a mix of different things. Most of these businesses are facing different constraints, whether you take the low level of interest rates for security services, which has a negative impact on the top line, which is compensated by the strict management of the business for SGS. The private bank had a more difficult start in January, February, but is getting better in March and April. Whereas our relationship with asset managers, Amundi or TCW, are driven by positive inflows. I think it's an important factor. So all in all, a satisfactory contribution as we said to group net income, and very few if any one-offs impact.</p>
          <p>I will not spend too much time on page 19, which is a new page. And I hope you get to used it, and we are happy to welcome your comments. The idea there is to share with you the CEO/CFO dashboard, which means that this is a figure that we will follow quarter-after-quarter and will share with you, so that you have really the same dashboard. Of course, mine is a little bit more detailed. But still, what do we have in mind? As I said several times, main objective from a business perspective is, first of all, make sure that revenues are there. Second, liquidity; third, capital; fourth, cost.</p>
          <p>There is no specific order, liquidity, capital, cost. It could be cost, capital and liquidity, or whatever. But these are the elements that we want to follow. I want you to be sure that we have this on top of our head. And this is what we want to share with you in this key figures page. So we will focus on, of course, on financial results including returns. Although they are not as satisfactory as what we have in mind, but still they are better. Second, capital generation, I think I spent too much time already on that. The way we deal with scarce resources and, of course, performance per share.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, I will just say it again what we &#x2013; what I said in my introduction. First point, the engine is working. So we said it already, but to a certain extent this quarter is demonstrating that even after six months of absolute stress faced by the system last year, various businesses are working and SocGen engine is working. The cost of risk is key in a deteriorating environment, and the cost of risk is well under control. Again, we are cautious looking forward, but this is an area where we have some form of comfort. Regarding our exposure to peripheral countries, as you know, we are one of the least exposed to these countries, and it has decreased. Capital, I will not comment. It's a priority, we have set up the objectives. The roadmap, I hope, is very clear. Our job now is to deliver quarter after quarter, and we will follow that with a dashboard.</p>
          <p>The good news &#x2013; it's not totally news to us; it might be news to you &#x2013; is that we started well with this first quarter, 40 bps increase, and of course, we will continue to transform the bank. It was to a certain extent easier that quarter given the environment, which was better, and we have seized all the opportunities to reduce our balance sheet, to increase the quality of our refinancing, to work on the CIB model, and of course, to pursue efforts in terms of cost control.</p>
          <p>I hope I've been clear on all these fronts, and here again with my colleagues around the table, we'd be more than happy to answer any questions you still might have.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much for your patience and attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have a first question from Delphine Lee, JP Morgan. Madame, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, everyone. Three questions, if I may. First of all, if I can come back to the Basel 3 guidance that you've given; thank you for that, it's very helpful. First of all, on the risk-weighted asset side, if you could give me the, if that's possible, a little bit more color on the &#x20AC;70 billion? So out of that, you have &#x20AC;12 billion for insurance, but what about the remaining &#x20AC;58 billion? In particular, would be interested in how much securitization the bit that is actually 12.5 risk-weighted?</p>
          <p>And also, on the capital side, looks like the deductions are smaller than what used to be at the end of 2010. If you could just give some color on the minority interest and what the Danish compromise is actually bringing to this?</p>
          <p>Secondly, on CIB deleveraging, just to basically be able to track a little bit versus what you have announced, the &#x20AC;30 billion to &#x20AC;40 billion of risk-weighted assets reduction. &#x20AC;16 billion has been done last year. How much has been done so far this year? And how much the 25 basis points that you have already secured would that represent, basically?</p>
          <p>And also on the cracking of the CDOs, I think last year you mentioned you had secured &#x20AC;1.3 billion by end of 2013. Where do we stand today? And what's more to come potentially?</p>
          <p>And lastly on CIB, if you could give a little bit on the strength in fixed income, and if possible also on the comment from this morning on April activity? Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will pass the microphone to Didier, who is very happy to come back to you and will comment on April, and I'll come back to you on the other points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Around CIB, first, <mark type="ph" /> with impediments (33:25) as we said, we have benefited let's say from the strong market environment as well our peers. Thus we have a very good, very strong start to the year, especially in January and February. Let's say, this explain let's say the strength that you've seen, which led to revenues slightly below &#x20AC;1 billion. When I look at the detail, let's say, we have seen a strong performance between rate and credit on the flow side.</p>
          <p>Commodities also, and I remind you that we closed our physical commodity activity in the U.S. So now what is there is commodities located in Europe and physical commodity also in Europe, has performed reasonably well. And also we've seen due to, let's say, overall more liquid market condition, a strength in money market funds &#x2013; in money market business.</p>
          <p>So that's it for the funds in the first quarter. And entering into Q2, I would say like what our competitors said, we've seen a slowdown of the activity. But we managed this satisfactorily compared to the revenue power of the franchise. And thus, let's say, I think that it's something, which compared to our, let's say, budget expectation that you don't ask, but which is my target, let's say, is okay and better than expected.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Didier. Delphine, regarding your other question, so of course I was convinced that if I provided you with a roadmap to Basel 3, you wanted to have all the details regarding that roadmap. Basically, all the hotels and restaurants between now and end of 2013.</p>
          <p>What can I tell you? Regarding the mix between risk-weighted assets and deduction, the Danish compromise in terms of insurance has a strong impact, because prior to that, insurance was impacted more on the deduction from the risk-weight assets front. That's one of the main explanation.</p>
          <p>Regarding the risk-weighted assets, it's a mix of different things &#x2013; as I said, insurance roughly &#x20AC;12 billion. You should add to this the CVA and securitization. So CVA securitization and insurance represent more than 70%, 75% of the total. The rest is a mix of very different little things. So that's really what I can tell you.</p>
          <p>Here again, it's not as precise as you wish because there is &#x2013; it's really our assessment of the impact based on our trajectory, what we intend to do in these various areas. But here again, if you want to have this in mind, basically more than 70% &#x2013; close to actually 80% is represented by these items.</p>
          <p>Regarding the deduction, here again, the deduction is a mix of pluses and minuses because in terms of deductions, there are things that have moved from deduction to risk-weighted assets. So in terms of net pluses, DTA are the biggest element, and the second biggest element, which I mentioned, is also the minority interest. I'm not sure I want to tell you more than that because I am not sure that telling you more than that is really meaningful, to be honest. With that, again, you have basically the main elements, which explain where we are today and how do we intend to go tomorrow.</p>
          <p>Second question regarding the objectives, the &#x20AC;30 billion to &#x20AC;40 billion risk-weighted assets objective. We have not abandoned this. The fact is if we have reset, to a certain extent, the clock, and that's why we started with first of January figures. Objective, we were at 9% Basel 2.5 with the first of January figure, and we want to go above 9% Basel 3 end of 2013. And this is what we want to share with you quarter after quarter.</p>
          <p>So we will not follow per se this &#x20AC;30 billion to &#x20AC;40 billion risk-weighted assets target that we set six months ago. Again, it doesn't mean we abandoned it. Technically, we have done more than half of it, but it's not as relevant as it was when we announced it. The objective today is the roadmap to Basel 3. As we say, it's not always a question of risk-weighted assets, it's a question of deduction. Again, if I take the example of the cracking of CDOs, which was I think your third question, the cracking of CDO have several impacts. First of all, you can, at the end of the day, more easily sell the underlying assets. But on top of that, you don't have the negative impact of securitization deduction from your capital.  So it's not so much risk-weighted assets impact than Basel 3 positive impact.</p>
          <p>So it's a little bit of cooking, but again, when at the beginning of this year we made the difference within our legacy asset between the investment grade and non-investment grade, we said very clearly and we presented them in two different baskets. On the one hand, we say that the investment grades would be treated as the other assets within the loan book, and so we basically make an arbitrage between liquidity, release P&amp;L impact, potential capital impact, positive carry cost, and so on and so forth. And at the end of the day, we make a decision to sell or not to sell, and we have sold some of them, but not as much as what some people had expected.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, regarding the non-investment grade assets and at the heart of this is the CDOs, and the CDOs of RMBS. The objective there is not so much the headline figure of volumes, it's about capital relief, and that's really what we want to insist on. And this is really what we have in mind. We want to go down for these legacy assets from &#x20AC;4 billion, which was a figure at the beginning of this year, to &#x20AC;2.5 billion. And if we can do better, we'll do better. That's the objective by the end of 2013.</p>
          <p>And the good news is the fact that, already this quarter, because we've been active on the cracking front, if I may say, we have achieved already more than 20 bps under Basel 3. And for me this 20 bps are more important than those risk-weighted assets. It's really active and smart, if I can send myself and the team some flowers, smart management of our legacy assets position. I hope it's clear, Delphine?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. Just to come back on the Basel 3 on the assumptions that you've taken in your guidance. I mean, what's unconfirmed and what can actually change from here, which item? Is it the Danish proposal or are there other items where you could be slightly wrong? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very rapidly, technically speaking, the main &#x2013; the two main items, which have changed are insurance and the treatment of minority interest, which is again is going to be very technical depending on whether you can take them based on <mark type="ph" /> peel out (40:22) figures or depends whether you can take them based on the kind of general 7% threshold. So that's from the technical side.</p>
          <p>On the non-technical side, the main change between 2010 and now is the fact that we have deleveraged. Technically, we've been very active so our balance sheet does not look exactly the way it looked in 2010. Exactly the way that for Basel 2.5, we had good surprise. Of course, if I remember well, we were under Didier's control by 2010; it was the very beginning of Basel 3. We were still playing with figures, assumptions, models, and so on and so forth.</p>
          <p>We have refined our vision of that. And that's the main explanation. On the one hand, the Danish compromise brings flexibility. On the other hand, it's also the fact that we have managed this with utmost attention over the last two years and we'll continue to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Jon Peace, Nomura Securities. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. Just two or three short questions, please. Firstly, on the French Retail business. So I'm wondering with the outlook you have at the moment, when do you imagine the business might get back to positive jaws? The second question, Mr. Oud&#xE9;a, I think, made some comments this morning about the ROE outlook, and there were numbers of 10% to 12% on the screen. I just wondered if you could clarify those expectations. Is that an industry comment? Is that a SocGen-specific comment? And then just finally, if I could just clarify again, what was the impact of adopting the Danish proposal on your Basel 3 rollforward, which is very useful? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So outlook for French Retail was your first question, Jon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, please. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I was not totally sure I got it. Outlook for French Retail, from a business perspective, I mean, it's difficult to provide a clear guidance. We are comfortable that this should continue to be positive. But this being said, we are of course impacted by the general environment in Europe and in France, which still not as negative as people expected six months ago. But still, we have growth prospective, which are around 1%, even potentially more, but not more than that. So that's point number one.</p>
          <p>Point number two, after a second half of last year, which was more difficult, we are rebounding from that level. So as I said, commercial momentum is there. It does not totally translate one-for-one in financial performance, because there have been some, as I said, legal changes or regulatory changes regarding some commission <mark type="ph" /> expansions (43:08), which have a negative impact on our business, like on our competitors, actually. It's not targeted on Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale of course. And margins are getting a little bit up on the credit front, a little bit down on the deposit front.</p>
          <p>So all in all, I do not expect either a catastrophe or a miracle on the French Retail. It should be kind of flat to plus. But again, no guidance. It's too early days. Regarding cost of risk, as I said, it's in that environment; it's kind of okay.</p>
          <p>Regarding Danish proposal, again, the two main items, which are a positive one in our view, is on insurance. Minority interest is very limited. We are talking about 2 bps. So that does not make a big difference. On insurance, here again we are talking of several dozens of bps. That's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. And then the other question was just on the ROE comments that we made this morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you repeat, Jon. Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course. So I just noticed on Bloomberg from some interviews that perhaps yourself or Mr. Oud&#xE9;a had done this morning, there were comments made around ROE outlook. And I just wondered whether you could clarify those? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course. So ROE outlook, what we have in mind is that after the crisis, which is roughly 18 months to two years, given, on the one hand, the fact that we have to change our risk profile, the fact that we need more capital to do the same business as before. Reasonable ROE target for the Group should be between 10% and 12%. If we benefit, and that's really what we have in mind, we are able to reprice our book, we should be closer to 12%. And this is really what we have in mind. If we are not, I mean, we should be closer to the lower end of this range. Again there won't be any miracle. 10% to 12% given our risk profile, given the capital that we need is about right. This is on ROE; it would be of course higher from an ROTE perspective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's perfect. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Neuez, Goldman Sachs. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. I have three questions if I may. The first question would be on the outlook maybe for the provisioning in your main Retail businesses, and whether you see maybe deterioration? Or not at all, actually, because this quarter as you said was really in check?</p>
          <p>My second question on the balance sheet, I've seen a very notable improvement in your liquidity ratio as far as I calculate them. So for example, when I take the coverage of short-term funding with liquid assists, it improved dramatically from 73% to 89%, and also the coverage of the client asset with stable resources also increased a little bit, like 108, I think. I just wondered whether you had target in mind for these ratios? Whether you are more or less where you want to be? If you want to increase these buffers a little bit more? And what's the right level in a sense? We see the improvement. I just want to understand what the arrival point.</p>
          <p>And related to this, the third question is on the latest development around debates on the bail-inable debt potential. So I understand that some regulators are proposing 10% of the balance sheet, whatever that means in CapEx surplus, sub-debt plus, some sort of senior bail-inable debt. I just wondered, first, what's your understanding of the basis of the balance sheet for that? Is this funded or is this total asset? And secondly, what are your early thoughts on that? What are your early discussions with your investors showing on this point? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois. On outlook for provision on retail, so in France, I think I mentioned it here again, I would say a slight increase towards the year along with the economic situation developments. Outside France it's a mix of different trends. Here again, no significant signal in one sense or another, no abrupt movement. It's better in Romania for instance. It's again, it's a mix of different things but nothing significant in terms of changes so far.</p>
          <p>Regarding liquidity, as I said, discussing my dashboard, liquidity is top of our priority with capital and revenues. I'm not, as you know, very good friend of ratios targets and things. I know it's, it makes the life of everybody easier. Of course, I prefer to get 89% and 74%, and it's always better to be above level than below level, that's for sure. The objective is to make our business as soundly refinanced as possible; 89% is a good achievement. Of course, we would prefer to be slightly up. I will not tell you that 100% is the target; of course, I would like it. But we are much more comfortable, and to a certain extent, I'm quite satisfied with the situation that we are facing today. We will continue to work on loan to deposit. We will continue to work on the quality of our refinancing. We'll continue to raise money above the &#x20AC;10 billion to &#x20AC;15 billion long-term refinancing that we have said over this year. That's really what we have in mind.</p>
          <p>Regarding bailing, do I have early thoughts? It was apparent that over the last five years I've had early thoughts on so many issues and I've always lost. But I'm not sure I want share with you my early thoughts on that.</p>
          <p>I think the debate has started in a very weird way. I understand where it's coming from, and you all understand why people say bailing, because they just don't want to do any bailout anymore. That's pretty straightforward as a starting point. This being said, the way the debate is arranged is very difficult to follow. This 10% has gone from Brussels. But as you know, there is no very clear definition of what is the definition. Are we talking about the balance sheet, about risk-weighted assets, about senior debt, and so on and so forth?</p>
          <p>So I understand the concept. To be honest, I have some sympathy with the concept. I wish we had sales work around it, so that we do not create turbulence in the refinancing market for years, which is the risk that we are facing today. So we are participating to the various workshops or workgroups that are active around these things. One of the hot issue, as you might understand, is the fact that people are talking about deposits as being bail-inable. I can't, I mean, I'm pretty sure you can imagine how sensitive this type of proposal is. Not very constructive, to be honest.</p>
          <p>So I'm not sure I can give much more than that. Again, understand the concept, I have some sympathy. We are working on that. We would like the basis for that to be as large, as wide as possible. But then, it does not only depend on us. And I'm afraid this will weigh on the market for again several quarters. I'm happy to have your views, if you have some, Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just maybe to come back &#x2013; thank you for these early thoughts by the way. But just if I come back on the liquidity ratio, and I understand that maybe the targets are maybe not that relevant. But let's say directionally you intend to increase your liquidity buffers on the ratio that you present? Or you're probably where you want to be, or you feel comfortable like this? That's what I'm trying to understand essentially, whether there is still buildup required or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't want to go below that level. If I can go above, fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very helpful. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Kinner Lakhani from Citi. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. I had three questions. First one, just following on from the theme that we just talked about. Just wanted to focus less on the liquidity but more on the kind of the excess of the long-term funding over the long-term assets. It's a very significant, I would say, transformation that we've seen over the last 12 months, and again an improvement over the course of the first quarter. I think at the end of last year was &#x20AC;26 billion, now &#x20AC;42 billion on slide 8. So just want to try and understand that part a little bit better as to if we're going to continue in this direction of travel or if this provides a sufficient buffer?</p>
          <p>Second question was to come back on MBIA. Just wanted to understand how much capital is tied in to the MBIA-related transaction? And also your fourth &#x2013; we've had a number of banks now settle with MBIA, UBS being the latest one. And there's only a very small number of banks that are left including SocGen. So what your view is from here, given others have already settled?</p>
          <p>And thirdly, of course we're going through the integration process in Russia. Just trying to figure out from here, if we look out into 2013, what type of synergies we can look forward to? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On excess of long-term funding, of course we've moved from &#x20AC;20 billion last quarter to &#x20AC;40 billion this quarter. Again, it's not an objective per se, so it's a way also to secure the bench. I will give you exactly the same answer that I gave to Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois two minutes ago, that I don't want to go below. I'm happy to go above. I think, here again, we have some adjustment within the CIB regarding long-term and short-term. I think it's detailed, presented in detail in our presentation, but I think Didier will be more than happy to explain you the &#x2013; with balancing between financing and market activities from that perspective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, regarding the deleveraging, let's say, of the Financing business. As you've seen, so we sold &#x20AC;5 billion of loans, and we will continue to do that. So definitely we are, I'd say, at the middle of the road in terms of deleveraging. And thus we should have &#x2013; it's increasing a little bit, your calculation you made, i.e., long-term funding. And I think it will continue to start increase compared to our long-term assets.</p>
          <p>And maybe I will take the question on MBIA. Let's say we'll not comment on the capital committed to MBIA hedge that we have on different structural assets. And let's say regarding your question on whether or not, say, following UBS' decision to exit from the lawsuit, let's say we are in the lawsuit together with two other banks, Bank of America and Natixis. There is a trial which is settled in the next days so we'll not comment on this a bit either.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Didier. Regarding integration process in Russia, it's too early days to give you any vision. Again, we have already let go1,400 people. There are probably more than 1,000 on top of these people to go this year. We are also working on streamlining the organization and so on and so forth. So it's obvious that we'll come back to you later this year to provide you with more flavor and details around the situation in that country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Alex Koagne, Natixis. So please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. I have two follow-up questions, if I may. The first one is on the CIB. I'm just wondering on which business line you are comfortable to be able to generate an ROE higher than the cost of equity as of today?</p>
          <p>Second question is on your VaR. We see a slight increase this quarter. I'm just wondering how you manage the compensation effect? Do you give any specific target to your trader in term of diversification? I'm just wondering if we'll see this kind of volatility going forward? Those are my two questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will let Didier answer these two questions. Just as a quick point on the VaR, the figure has gone down since end of the quarter. But, Didier, please on ROE?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's say, first one, the ROE of the different business lines of the CIB. Let's say, we are actually working on a way to achieve a return on equity which is above the cost of equity for each of our business lines. After that the question is what type of EBITDA you would put on each business line after the stress that we've seen over the last 18 months. But clearly, we have a target to be in for each business line; it's a double-digit figure. So let's say 10-something after tax for each of our business line.</p>
          <p>You should also look at the fact that even if certainly we were helped by good market conditions this quarter, we have not seen the full benefit let's say of the cost adjustment that we intend to make for the full year. As for example, let's say regarding the reduction, head count reduction in France, nothing was taken into account in the first quarter as the plan was already launched on the second of April.</p>
          <p>So we work, let's say, on both on three level, let's say, to increase the return on equity after the CIB, consumption of capital through the deleveraging process, and through also this <mark type="ph" /> automated distributor (58:03) model, which allow us to otherwise to distribute more assets, while, let's say, getting in revenues, also fee business because we have capacity to increase the fee portion, especially in our financing activity going forward.</p>
          <p>Second level is of course the cost base where you've seen that we're able already to decrease quarter-on-quarter or year-on-year the cost base by 6% to 7% including bonuses. And the third let's say to see whether, let's say, in certain activities we'll receive some repricing capacity from the banking industry. We've seen that in certain <mark type="ph" /> key (58:43) capacity, let's say, especially for non-investment grade business and to reprice in certain cases. So that's for the CIB return on equity target.</p>
          <p>In term of the value at risk, well, you've seen that the cost of our sort of gross of compensation effect was relatively stable. So I think that most of the increase you've seen let's say was coming from compensation. It's something that you can only partly manage because it depends on the scenario that you have and the positions that you have, let's say, coming from your current activities. So I would say, certainly the &#x20AC;30 million in the fourth quarter was exceptionally low.</p>
          <p>And so we're expecting to move up, which is, let's say, structurally more in the region of what you've seen in the first half likely or in the first quarter of this year, even if when we say we can also reduce our rate relatively quickly if the market's request such adjustment. And I think that we've shown over the last 18 months that we were able to manage our risk market with let's say extremely quickly and extremely cautiously wherever the market conditions went.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Just one quick question on the costing coming to CIB. Are you still targeting a level below 50%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well, new additional taxes revenue pressure, let's say, to be below 60% seems to be something quite complicated. So let's say we will have a 6 as the first figure, and we would like let's say to get the lowest figure below after the 6 figure, which in my view does compare extremely well compared to the average of the industry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Jean-Pierre Lambert, KBW. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Good afternoon. I would like to come back to the Basel 3 risk-weighted assets, the &#x20AC;70 billion. Is it possible to have a split between legacy and the core CIB, an indication? And also, related to that, what is the expected weight of CIB, core CIB, in the total risk-weighted assets of the group under the Basel 3? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said, I don't think I provided details, but I'm pretty sure that based on what I've said, you can engineer the detail. On the one hand, we say that the legacy assets will  &#x2013; the capital costs of the legacy assets under Basel 3 will go down between &#x20AC;4 billion beginning of this year, basically, to &#x20AC;2.5 billion end of next year. So you can translate this. It's partly deduction but mostly risk-weighted assets. So I think based on that you might have a first idea.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the split under Basel 3 between the core CIB and the rest of the group, I don't think I have this on top of my head but we can come back in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Maxence Le Gouvello from Credit Suisse. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Good morning, everyone. A quick question on regarding the French Retail. Looking to the deposit, we can see that you have some outflows on the time and side deposit, and strong inflows coming from the regulated saving. Is it driven by a political &#x2013; sorry, a commercial strategy? Or what has been such definitions of such kind of mood?</p>
          <p>And also if you can elaborate a little bit more regarding ratio. Do we still really need to plug that while going to be loss-making into 2012? Or can we say that it will be first half of the year negative and then recurring in the second one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Being rational and being cautious, the fact that it's loss-making is also due to some exceptional this quarter. I don't want to overplay on this exceptional. The underlying situation is also due to revenues, as I said, which were impacted by the merger process and so on and so forth. But this exceptional by definition are not supposed to repeat themselves every quarter. And so I think, again, based on today, with a lot of cautious, and don't take this as a proper guidance. I would be more or less okay with what we just said. First half, kind of loss-making or flat, and second half, profitable.</p>
          <p>Regarding the split in deposit, I think on the one hand, on regulated savings scheme, basically we are moving with the tide, basically, which is in France something important. Regarding all the moves around the deferred, we are not especially active on that front, but we are moving with the market. No, the significant changes, which we did actually end of last year, which is still half of our strategy this year, is the fact that we have moved from putting pressure on very few large corporates to having a good offer to a large number of SMEs.</p>
          <p>And that's how we adjusted our term deposit policy second half of last quarter, and we're still enjoying, I mean, deposit benefit from that strategy. It's really the most active thing that we've done. For the rest, it's really with the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And regarding the loan side of the French Retail, still very dynamic. Can you give us a little bit of color of which kind of product are you selling?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we are not selling is PPI. As you know, the mortgages of the real estate products where the market is down 40%, as you know, and where we are down closer to 25%, 28% if my memory is okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on corporate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of consumer credit, it's also under some kind of pressure, slightly down. Whereas on the medium long-term, basically the loans provided to corporate and mostly SMEs is also slightly down. The biggest change is really in terms of production of new mortgages where we are very strongly down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Thibault Nardin, Morgan Stanley. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Good afternoon, everyone. Really, two quick question on my side. Just want to understand the increase in your liquidity buffer for this quarter by &#x20AC;20 billion. I just want to understand, how much was that due to the widening of active collateral by the Central Bank?</p>
          <p>And the second question, again very quickly. You've sold, I think, over the past six months around &#x20AC;11 billion of loans. I just want to understand what kind of revenue run rates you have lost through selling those books? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello? Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you repeat your second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yes. I was saying that you've sold &#x20AC;5 billion of loans this quarter and &#x20AC;6 billion in Q4 of last year. I just wanted to have a view about the revenue run rates that has been lost through the selling of these loans?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So on the first question I will answer, and I will let Didier answer on the second one. On the liquidity buffer, the widening of the eligible definition brings us probably around 20%, 25% of this &#x20AC;20 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Didier? Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We did not detail what we are likely to lose in terms of net interest income coming from this loan disposal. But what we said in Q3 and Q4 is that the deleveraging process of hedging CIB, so which that includes the deleveraging of the financing activities, but also has a reduction in term of short-term funding of the capital markets, net of the cost savings for us, is likely to lead to &#x20AC;500 million of reduction in term of gross opportunity incomes, so we'll stick to that. And we will adjust let's say, our strategy based on this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Anke Reingen, RBC. Madame, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon. It's Anke here. Questions in two areas. Firstly, on the capital environment, sorry to come back to this again. On the 210 basis points, I wasn't quite sure I understood your comment about the sensitivity into the decision on the Danish proposal, because I thought you just said the sensitivity to the insurance operations is couple of thousands of basis points? I assume, I got, misunderstood you there.</p>
          <p>And also the 200 basis points and how much this is dynamic for a year-end 2013 hits? And would this deduction potentially be higher now? And what's your assumption on your organic risk-weighted assets because it's basically zero?</p>
          <p>And then, on the other question, as with respect to your funded balance sheet, how has &#x2013; on the liability side, on the asset side, how many funds you have taken up in the LTRO impact of the change in the structure? So with the funds, would they be in the long-term funding or would there be short term? And then where did you sort of like reinvest most of the funds you've taken up? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on your first question, as I said, and I hope it's been clear. I said the Danish proposal, initially the Basel 3 &#x2013; the Basel committee proposal was to deduct insurance capital from corporate insurance as the initial step. Then you had that conversation about potential financial conglomerate approach, and then the Danish compromise, which basically say you take our insurance business and you take &#x2013; consider this as risk-weighted assets, which cost us &#x20AC;12 billion. And that's what we have in our assumption today, which will present roughly 20, 25 or 30 bps basically.</p>
          <p>If we were back to the other proposal, it's probably &#x2013; I don't have this on top of my mind, because I don't have to memorize the 20 scenarios that we are discussing with the people living in Brussels. As I say, should open some bps. Is it 20 bps or 30 bps? I don't know but that order of magnitude. I wouldn't like it. I can live with that. I mean, it's &#x2013; the point is that we will do some disposal and this is where we have additional flexibility, vis-&#xE0;-vis our roadmap. Here again, if we have other constraints, which are put on our shoulders, we'll adapt ourself based on today's environment, based to the best of our understanding. This is a roadmap that we are happy to share with you.</p>
          <p>Regarding organic growth of risk-weighted assets, basically as you've said this quarter and Didier commented this regarding CIB, we are down on the credit front in terms of risk-weighted assets and up on the market front. So we have some flexibility vis-&#xE0;-vis within our model. So the message that we want to share with you, and this is why we put it graphically this way, is that we still have intention to make some disposal, and part of this disposal will help us grow our organic activity, basically our organic risk-weighted assets, mostly in retail both in France and International Retail.</p>
          <p>That's really the main management message that we want to share with you. <mark type="ph" /> The dollar eating (1:11:20) trend that we are having is bringing us above 9%. We want to do a disposal which would bring us technically up if we do everything until above 10%. And then between 9% to 9.5% and 10% or whatever level we reach, then we have flexibility to grow or not to grow our business. But this is in the hands of the management and that's how we want to drive the businesses.</p>
          <p>Your second question was regarding the impact of the LTRO. Of course, LTRO is not part of our long-term refinancing program; that's absolutely obvious. The biggest impact of the LTRO is the fact that it has helped us basically come back to the market like others. This is the main benefit. I've discussed that with you as well in the first quarter. I think the main message sent by the ECB is that the ECB is there and will not let the system collapse. And I think the message has been received loud and clear. And this is why most of the markets including the senior unsecured markets, which was I mean considered dead four months ago, has reopened, and we've been able to raise more than &#x20AC;2 billion on that market. So I think this is for me the main impact.</p>
          <p>As to which amount of money we've taken from the LTRO, I will make &#x2013; I will give you the same disappointing answer that my French colleagues have already provided to you. It's not in the tradition of French banks and of the French Central Banks to discuss the details of the relationship between the Central Banks and the banks. And so I will not provide you with any additional comments on this situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And where did you reinvest? Will it be largely be in short-term assets? Or did you go into long-term, did you reinvest into long-term assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Where did you reinvest the proceeds from the LTRO you've taken up in the LTRO? Is it parked in Central Bank deposits or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We buy Italian bonds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Where did you reinvest the funds you've taken from the LTRO? Did it go into short-term assets or was it mainly Central Bank deposits?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Into the economy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Into the economy and Central Bank deposits; that's obvious. Again, as I explained to a number of people, if you enjoy &#x20AC;1 billion, it's very difficult to spend it in one day. So basically like most banks, that's one of the explanation why the &#x2013; Didier is smiling and says that he can spend &#x20AC;1 billion. I will not let him do that.</p>
          <p>No. More seriously, I mean, you need time to make the money be used within your system, especially in an environment which is not as buoyant as people expected. So it's not a surprise that the deposits within the Central Banks are there. It's also a signal that the interbank market is not working properly. It's also a signal that it's &#x2013; I mean, it's not working today and it &#x2013; I don't see why it should be working properly with the next few years, given also the constraints put together by the new Basel 3 liquidity ratio. So it's a mix of different things. The fact that you need money, you need time to reinvest the money. It's also the fact that the interbank market is not working properly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Guillaume Tiberghien, Exane BNP Paribas. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. I've got two questions and one request, if possible. So the request may be on your dashboard, you've got lots of useful information, would you care to add one line which would be Basel 3 fully loaded? That would be really handy for us.</p>
          <p>The two questions are, the first one is on fixed income. You obviously spent a lot of time explaining that you're de-risking the bank, et cetera, but when you look at the VaR, the market risk, et cetera, and the maybe too-good-to-be-true revenues coming from the fixed income, one has to wonder how much de-risking is there? And how much genuine group-client-related revenues there is in there?</p>
          <p>So I know you've given a little bit of flavor about what has done well and what hasn't done so well, but could you maybe elaborate a little bit more on that?</p>
          <p>And the second question relates to the Danish compromise. My understanding is that a qualified majority has been approved or has been found yesterday evening, and then it just needs to go through final detail. Do you get the same understanding of last night? And when can we expect finalization of the Danish compromise? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Guillaume, you are so full of nostalgia for hearing Didier, that I will let him answer on the fixed income, and I will come back to you on my dashboard and on the Danish compromise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bertrand. And good afternoon, Guillaume. Now, let's say, when you look at the figures first of the whole industry as we said, as you've seen also, our fixed income business was strong, let's say, across the whole industry, with a good start to the year. Maybe also let's say we should not forget that last year, let's say, the Eurozone or more Eurozone-exposed bank, did &#x2013; fell a bit more in terms of basis of comparison compared to some of our U.S. peers</p>
          <p>Then let's say regarding the risk appetite, I think that we should not have any misleading understanding as of what took place. If you look really at the value at risk, I'd say most of the parameters let's say were roughly the same than what they were in Q4, Q3 last year, excluding the compensation effect. So as I said is essentially let's say a part of a certain position that we earn from long-term base business. And that was let's say more just really necessarily decompensated compared to what we had in the previous quarters.</p>
          <p>Let's say, that said we are not expecting let's say this &#x20AC;1 billion to be a run rate by far, and let's say that we are let's say comfortable with let's say &#x2013; the <mark type="ph" /> &#x20AC;550 our (1:17:30) platform can deliver much better let's say than what we made last year. This is also partly through the start of the reorganization that we put into place say sometime. And also we've been &#x2013; thanks, let's say, the teams and my team since the beginning of this year. Even the organization was fully into place beginning of the second quarter, have started let's say to move some people to regroups within activities.</p>
          <p>As we've seen in Q4, let's say from a client base perspective, we have put some joint venture to better synergize the client flow that we have from both corporate and financial institution platforms. We were also able let's say to start to make some investment in our systems, especially on the French side. And all that together, certainly it helped also the investment that we made in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>So clearly don't multiply that by 4; this is not the run rate. So I think like the rest of the industry we were impacted by some parameter convergence that we've seen in the first let's say five to six weeks of the year. But I think also we were able let's say to show that the platform in fixed income of Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale has valuable assets to capture some client flows, and also is starting to benefit from certain change that we made in term of both management and systems</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on your two last questions, the Danish compromise, more or less my understanding is comparable to yours, although yesterday, to be honest with you, I was probably more focused on Paris and what happened on TV than what happened in Brussels. But I think I have the same understanding. And we are &#x2013; I mean, if we were not, we would not have put that roadmap on the paper. We are quite confident, although as long as this is not totally signed, rubber stamped, and translated into domestic legislation, it's not done.</p>
          <p>But we are getting closer, so we'll continue of course to be very cautious and spend lots of time making sure that the ability grows until the last minute.</p>
          <p>On the dashboard, Guillaume, I make a good note of your suggestion, and I promise that by the end of 2013 you will have the figures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from <mark type="ph" /> Tersh Shidzelasee CM-CIC (1:19:47). Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. Just two quick questions. First question about the restaurants and hotels and the roadmap to 2013. What is the treatment of deferred tax assets in your model? Do you phase it like Natixis for instance or do you fully loaded it in your hypothesis? And what is the amount of the deferred tax assets you're supposed to deduct from the Core Tier 1?</p>
          <p>My second question is, could you give us a little bit more information regarding TCW? What is the net income of this subsidiary now? And what are your view on this subsidiary regarding your strategic plan?</p>
          <p>And my last question will be a little bit more general. As you know, we will have a presidential election, I guess, and what is your view regarding the banking law that may be proposed to the voting of the Parliament probably in September, if Mr. Hollande wins the presidential election, as an act. Maybe you have some relationship but can give you some color regarding the socialist project regarding the banking sector in France? What kind of comment would you make at this stage and the kind of consequence for the banking industry and for Germany in particular? Regarding the fact like SocGen has a strong CIB, what is your view on that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. So on your first question, our DTA are fully loaded, and this is the main impact on the deduction. Although the deduction share, 1.4, is a net of pluses and minuses, but it's absolutely obvious that the biggest minuses &#x2013; minus, sorry &#x2013; is the DTA, which will of course evaporate over time if everything goes better, but which is fully loaded upfront. On TCW, maybe Jacques Ripoll?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. TCW, the quarter was a rather solid one from a performance standpoint with &#x2013; we have now almost 90% of the funds which are rated four or five stars, Morningstar. It has not translated already in the net income, which is a bit logical because the inflows at $2.8 billion of inflows have appeared during the quarter and is a bit pointing on the cost side, where we had a few one-offs.</p>
          <p>But globally, the trend is definitely strong inflows across the board, largely on the fixed income, but we start to see a pickup on the equity and definitely some good results also on the international side, so the trend is very good. The strategic vision we have shared with you has not changed. We think that it's a franchise which is really growing fast now in the market, where we believe that there is a huge amount of money that will get into the asset management business in the U.S. And where we have a team, which is now very solid and with robust performance, so we are very happy with this franchise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow-up question. Do you mean that we are still in a deficit for TCW in the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow-up question, it's not clear for me. You mean that TCW is in a better shape but still in the red? For the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's not in the red. It's making slight profits...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, slight profits...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as I told you with fewer one-offs on the cost side, but it's making benefits, making profits.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I realized that my microphone was not on when I replied to your DTA question. Did you get it or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the presidential election, as you know, it's &#x2013; I'm not speculating on elections. I'm not speculating in general, actually. This being said, of course we have had conversations with every candidate. Banking &#x2013; the banking industry has been part of the hot topics for this campaign. I don't know what would be the timing of the legislation, if any, probably as you say, September, or most likely October. I would say it doesn't make a big difference at the end of the day. It's very difficult to see now what might be the content of this legislation.</p>
          <p>On the one hand, probably, obviously, some higher taxation. I think this is pretty obvious. So higher tax on the income &#x2013; I mean, corporate income tax. Possibly some higher taxes on the systemic levy, potentially some discussion on the so-called financial taxation, although there's also some debate in Brussels. In the same time, I think you have to have in mind that you have the committee chaired by Mr. Likanen, asked by Mr. Badr&#xE9; to think about the future of the European banking industry, which might have an impact as well on the thinking in France.</p>
          <p>On top of that, people realize more and more that whether you consider Volcker in the U.S. or Vickers in the UK, which are the kind of two attractions, it's not working or not progressing as rapidly and as well as expected in these two countries. So in general, today it's very difficult to see now what might be the impact on our businesses. Yet again, I'm confident that we might be able to have our voice heard at the end of the day. I mean, changing the entirety of the French bank business model, it might not be the priority of any government, whoever is elected this Sunday, in the next three months. So there will be changes, obviously. Massive changes, it's not obvious.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow-up question, if I may, on this issue. Mr. Oud&#xE9;a said that regarding the Vickers proposal, it will be very difficult to implement it in France due to a fact that we have mostly a mature structure of banking system in France. As you previously see at first &#x2013; wait, I don't understand why it's such a problem with mutual banks compared to commercial banks, the Vickers project, or kind of Vickers project.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I'm right, under Vickers approach, you subsidiarize, and I don't know if the word is correct in English, the retail side. Whereas the mutual banks, the retail is at the top of the structure. So it's more complex to restructure those things. I don't say it's impossible, but it creates a lot of noise and will require a lot of energy in an environment where I think energy will be needed for other things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again of course, as you know I cannot and I will not comment on my previous situation. But you know that whether it's going to be one or the other mutual banks, we don't move with general banks like this in a country like France.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Pascal Decque, Cheuvreux. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon, everyone. I'm afraid I still have four questions. The first one is on legacy assets capital allocated. There's a strong increase in Q1 versus Q4, and we were going south since Q1 last year. And then I wanted to have an explanation on this evolution, please? It's on the slide 23 of the press release.</p>
          <p>The second question is on French Retail and the costs. I didn't get very well your answer where talking about the revenues, plus 1% maximum according to you, if I understood well. But you didn't say anything about the cost, and there's a very negative joy effect in Q1, and I wanted to have a view on your sentiment on this evolution in the full year?</p>
          <p>The third one is on the restructuring costs in CIB. You mentioned some costs last year and you said there were still cost pending in 2012. There was nothing in Q1 unless I missed something. I wanted to know how much there is still to spend here?</p>
          <p>And the last question, maybe I understood wrongly, but in your slide describing your Basel 3 targets, you are talking of a payout ratio of 25% and a takeout of scrip dividend at 60%. Is it the guidance for scrip dividend, 2012 and 2013? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, can you, Pascal, comment on your first question regarding the legacy asset RWA?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, in fact, in your press release on the slide 23, when you describe the quarterly figures of every division. On the legacy assets capital allocated, we are going from &#x20AC;2.5 billion in Q4 2011 to &#x20AC;3 billion in Q1 2012. And this number was going down since Q1 last year, and suddenly this is increasing a lot. Then I wanted to get an explanation on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Didier will answer that question, but I think if you look at page 27 of our slideshow, it's going down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This the average?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. No, but just, Pascal, you know that the capital allocated is the capital at the beginning of the quarter. And so in Q4 it was the risk-weighted assets and the capital allocation based on Basel 2, first of October 2011. So as from 2012, we have lessened the full impact of Basel 2.5 including deductions, so that's why you have a jump in the capital allocated to legacy assets.</p>
          <p>But as you know, it has no impact on the ratio calculation level, end of the quarter, but it's just that for taking good reason, we always allocate capital based on the risk-weighted assets and the deduction beginning of the quarter. So in Q4 last year, it was still on Basel 2 and the jump is coming just from Basel 2 to Basel 2.5.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And your question on French Retail, I think you were a little bit strong when you said very negative, <mark type="ph" /> Joe (1:31:24). It's not so very negative. It's negative of course. If you have a growth which is &#x2013; a top line growth which is below 1% and costs which are growing between 1% and 2%, you have a negative impact. Which on top of that, is the cost of risk is increasing a little bit. It might have an impact on the bottom line, that's obvious. I wouldn't say it's very negative.</p>
          <p>So that's basically is the main items that we will look at this year, of course. We will make efforts on the cost front. It's part of the general effort we make at the group level, and of course we'll make it also at the French Retail.</p>
          <p>Second, revenues, I mean, we are in the given environment, and we do as much as we can. But as I said, there won't be any miracle. As far as the cost of risk is concerned, for the time being it's kind of okay, and we are cautious. So that's again the situation in French Retail without any &#x2013; without being too rosy or too black.</p>
          <p>Regarding the restructuring cost in CIB, it's true that we said last year that we probably have a few dozens of millions spread over this year, nothing material this first quarter. Didier said even well. He said &#x20AC;8 million, but you know Didier is very precise with figures and for the big change with the new CFO.</p>
          <p>Regarding Basel 3 targets, yes, you're right. It's the guidance; 25% payout ratio, 60% scrip dividend. Technically, it doesn't mean that we will use this, and we have the intention to use this by 2014, actually, in our calculation. The potential benefit of a scrip dividend in 2014 is of course not taken into account, because this would happen in 2014, not in 2013. So in our roadmap, the only impact is for the dividends paid for the year 2012, paid in 2013, and where people choose to be paid in shares in 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Pascal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That's &#x2013; then only one year of scrip dividend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It doesn't preclude of the following years, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay, thank you very much. And then...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The way that we do it, it's just not part of our roadmap.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just a quick follow-up. My only question on French Retail was on operating costs, and the fact that should we expect growth which is much higher than 1% as well in Q1 for the full year or not? Or shall you try to reduce this number for the full year? That was the only question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I've said repeatedly, and I think for the rest of the management, I'd say cost control is one of our priorities this year. It's true for every area of the bank, of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Robin Down, HSBC. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Bertrand and Didier. Firstly, one request. On the &#x2013; I apologize in advance; analysts always ask for more information. But going back to Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Neuez' comments about bail-in. On slide 8, where you give us the funded balance sheet, it would be really, really helpful if you could break down the long-term funding in future between that which is collateralized and that which is unsecured. It's very difficult to find the right numbers I think within the balance sheet &#x2013; i.e., in other words, so we can find out which proportion that long-term debt is &#x2013; which seriously could be bail-inable if the provision was brought in?</p>
          <p>The second question really just relates to the nonperforming loans. I mean, we saw &#x2013; if I look at your doubtful loans numbers, they were remarkably static really last year, just creeping up ever so slightly as the year wore on. Yet when I look at the first quarter numbers, there seems to be a bit of a jump, and it's &#x2013; I mean, I'm not suggesting it's Spain sort of type levels, but it does seem to have shot up in the first quarter. And at the same time, the collateral relation to loans written down also seems to have shot up.</p>
          <p>I was just wondering if you could give us a little bit more color on what you're seeing with that jump in doubtful loans? Whether it's something that's due with a change in accounting, or it's the seasonality? Or whether there is a pool of new loans sort of becoming doubtful that perhaps might give us an early warning? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. On the long-term funding, I make a good note of what you've said. Here again, we have not really made our mind of what we want to disclose. A big chunk of information is available in our reference document, and you might be able to recalculate all this.</p>
          <p>Like most banks, of course, the relative importance of our secured funding has grown over the last few years, although it still remains, I mean, I wouldn't say below the radar, but not that important. I understand it's a growing concern, so we have to make up our mind on what we want to disclose and explain, and I make a good note on that.</p>
          <p>On our doubtful loans, again, I cannot be very specific but it's due to &#x2013; essentially, one specific situation, which is most public and not public, so I cannot on the specific situation. But it's not the signal of a large deterioration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, the next question is from Kiri Vijayarajah from Barclays Capital. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. You've given us some detail on the new issuance of medium and long-term funding during the quarter. But just so I can reconcile the moves, I wonder if you can tell us how much medium and long-term financing actually matured during the quarter? And also what would be useful is, what was the spread on the MLT that matured during the quarter, so I can compare that to the 148 bps on your issuance? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you have the split on page eight. Again, in broad terms, I think we did a little bit more than &#x20AC;2 billion in senior and secured. I think we provided the details down the road. We &#x2013; let me just check what we've done, I think we did &#x2013; sorry, I don't have this on top of my mind. &#x20AC;2.7 billion were SFH vehicle &#x20AC;2.1 billion in &#x2013; I mean, two moves the same day, 18-months and five-years senior unsecured on the tap on the last one. And then we also are doing roughly &#x20AC;400 million to &#x20AC;500 million of structured products every month, and we intend to continue more or less, around this reason. As I said, we've done also &#x20AC;700 million of car loan securitization in Germany. These are the main items.</p>
          <p>In terms of pricing, SFH through our covered bond program in January, we had 170 bps for ten-year. In terms of senior and secured, on top of my memory, it has also shown the change in the spreads for the quarter. We did it at 85 bps for 18-months and 222 bps for five-years, but we did adapt on the same one at 155 bps, so again, shows...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, can I just interrupt you there? I was actually interested in what matured during the quarter rather than the details, just to try and reconcile the moves. Because some of your disclosure, the 8.7 you issued, actually takes me to, into April, whereas the liabilities you've given there will take you to the thirty-first of March. I'm just trying to reconcile those moves, so it's actually the maturity date I was after. What matured during the quarter in terms of MLT financing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have this on top of my head, I'm sorry. I come back to you, answer will come back to you. I don't have this on top of my head, I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Not to worry. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a next question from <mark type="ph" /> Fleurhaben Hargoon (1:40:15) Deutsche Bank. Madame, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. First of all, I just wanted to come back quickly to Guillaume's question earlier, because I just want to be sure that I understand your answer correctly. On the strong performance that you had this quarter in FIC, was it actually also partly driven by some inventory gains and some reversals? Or was it really just client driven?</p>
          <p>And then very quickly on the cost of deleveraging, if I remember correctly, I think you had guided on your latest earnings call for around &#x20AC;500 million to &#x20AC;700 million losses on loan sales for the year 2012. And I just wanted to know if you keep this guidance? And also on the average discount on loan sales, I think you had guided for 5%, which is indeed in line with what you have achieved this quarter, so just wanted to know if you keep this guidance? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>These various points, I think on the deleveraging costs, Didier has been very clear, and I will reiterate this. Basically, the loss of revenues, it's not &#x2013; we didn't say, again, that this has converted it was in 2012. We are just speaking about kind of run-rate type of loss. Revenue impact, probably &#x20AC;700 million to &#x20AC;800 million, compensated by the savings from costs, so that the net gross operating income in fact should be around &#x20AC;0.5 billion, &#x20AC;500 million, and this is confirmed.</p>
          <p>This is kind of a run rate impact in a given year, not especially 2012, because it's a work in process. Discount on the disposal, here again, last year we were between 1% and 2%. This year we had budgeted 5%. We are below that figure if you take into account both the legacy and then on the loan sales. We are closer to 5% if you take the loan sales, and so we are in line with what we announced at the beginning of this year.</p>
          <p>On fixed income, Didier, if you want?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to add to right again, as I've said, first start, the start of the year was extremely strong due to market parameter convergence, so you can call that inventory, but there was really some benefit on the trading side. But also the same kind of assessments on the commercial fronts with the sales figures, let's say, that we've seen also good activity across the quarter.</p>
          <p>And so I think that this is something that in my view is a good signal of the performance that the platform can extract from these &#x2013; from our account base. And also, I hope that this will improve thanks with the organization that we are started to implement. So let's say part of the almost &#x20AC;1 billion is linked to inventories or to market parameter convergence. As I've said, don't multiple that by 4, but also let's say, we have seen a good performance from the commercial side on the fixed income side across the platform.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Back on your previous question, because I don't like to let questions unanswered voluntarily. I think the debt which has matured over the last four months is between &#x20AC;8 billion and &#x20AC;10 billion. <mark type="ph" /> Hans (1:43:21) will come back to you with a more precise figure. But if I made a calculation on a piece of paper, back of the envelope calculation for you, &#x20AC;8 billion to &#x20AC;10 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question <mark type="ph" /> Mariel Guarez (1:43:35), HSBC. Madame, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Can you please comment a bit more on the performance of the equity business? And also do you think there could be in the performance potentially some impact from the job cuts occurring in this business? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let Didier answer. Can you repeat your second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you think that there could be in the performance in the equity revenues some impact from the job cuts that are occurring in this business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we'll let Didier answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, well, the performance that we've seen in the first quarter, I'd say, were satisfactory. And what we've seen that we have seen already in commercial activities on the foreign structured products, while it is a dynamism, was maybe a little bit more subdued, was on the listed products side.</p>
          <p>Regarding as I said the impact of the job cuts, that's across the board as we've said for the business, located in Paris, most of that is starting beginning in the second quarter. So within the first quarter, it was more into market environment, let's say, overall and using that your business. Volumes were okay, but not as strong as we could have expected, and thus, let's say, we have all the secured concerning our leadership position.</p>
          <p>But maybe also you should bear in mind that maybe compared to some of our peers, Q1 last year was a little bit stronger than most of the average. So let's say to be down 25% almost compared to last year, and up 60% compared to Q4, in our view show the strengths of our franchise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Andrew Lim, Espirito Santo [Execution Noble Ltd.]. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Sorry to ask this, but could you quantify the inventory gains in your FIC trading, quite frankly? And then I've got a number of capital questions. You've given the benefit from deleveraging of your non-core businesses of 50 bps to 100 bps, and previously you've indicated 100 bps. Is that an implicit downgrade or is that just reflecting uncertainty on what kind of benefit you could achieve there?</p>
          <p>And then could you give more color on what kind of businesses you could sell there? I mean, if I look at what they could be, it doesn't seem to tally with the improvements on the Core Tier 1 ratio, if I try and figure out what kind of capital gains or capital relief you could achieve there.</p>
          <p>And then, two other questions. The 70 bps improvement from deleveraging SG CIB, to what extent is that dependent on achieving book values in line with fair values? I'm alluding here to the U.S. RMBS CDOs in the legacy asset portfolio, where there's a delta there of about 0.8 billion. If your book value does go down to the fair value, and you realize a 0.8 billion loss there, does that impact on that 70 bps improvement targets there?</p>
          <p>And then lastly, just a technical question, do you have capital deductions on the Basel 3 applicable to your legacy asset portfolio? Thank you very much</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, I'm not sure I got all your questions. I understand your questions regarding the size of the disposal, 50 bps to 100 bps versus 100 bps before. I understand your question &#x2013; I think I understand your question on the 70 bps impact and the relationship with the value of our assets, but I didn't get your second and last point, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The last one, are there capital deductions on the Basel 3 with respect to the legacy asset portfolio? And then with respect to the 50 bps to 100 bps improvement for the non-core businesses, can you give some color about what kind of businesses you'd be expected to sell there? And what kind of capital gains that you would be able to expect from those sales? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, as I said in my introduction, the fact that we have &#x2013; that our reaching 9.1% under Basel 3 fully loaded by the end of 2013 is not conditioned upon the disposal, doesn't mean that we want to stop the disposal process. The fact that we have moved from 100 bps to 50 bps to 100 bps, doesn't mean that we have changed our strategic plan. It just means that we are more considerate of the timetable, and we'll do what is doable under good conditions between now and end of 2013. And again, objective is 100 bps, but we are conscious of the time, and we don't want to do de-stressing, basically.</p>
          <p>Second, what kind of businesses, again, I might refer you to what has been said by the group in 2010 regarding businesses, which are considered core and businesses which are called synergetic. And of course, that's probably a good indication of where we want to put our efforts in terms of disposal.</p>
          <p>The 70 bps, again, you have to have in mind that even being a little bit simplistic, under Basel 3, every euro stuck in &#x2013; or every dollar stuck in legacy asset, we've got more or less $1 or &#x20AC;1 of capital. It's as simple as that. So whenever you sell one of the assets, you gain on the capital front.</p>
          <p>So in terms of Basel 3 trajectory, these legacy assets cost us &#x20AC;4 billion end of last year. And we expect it to be to &#x20AC;2.5 billion by the end of 2013. And we have done already a big part of this move this quarter, close to 25 bps I mean, 20 &#x2013; whatever, 22 bps or 23 bps in legacy assets related on the one hand to disposal, and on the other hand to cracking. And we continue to do that, and we're quite confident, and that's basically it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, could you quantify the inventory gains in FIC trading? And then that last technical question as to whether you include any kind of capital reductions on the Basel 3 for the legacy asset portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Didier will answer this. I'm not sure I got your question. Didier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure I get your question because on the inventory gain or whatever you call them, let's say, I was talking more about market parameters normally based. For the legacy asset, let's say the inventories are not in the performance of the core business, so the fixed income at almost &#x20AC;1 billion, and was not impacted by any improvement in valuation of the legacy assets.</p>
          <p>You can, what you aim for that &#x2013; to better assess, let's say, what to place on these instruments, you have full detail in the appendices. But don't mix let's say inventory gain, whatever, on the commercial assets, which are non-core, with the performance of the core bank on the fixed income side. I think this is what you were asking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question is from Beno&#xEE;t P&#xE9;trarque of Kepler Capital Markets. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Beno&#xEE;t from Kepler. Just to come back on the deleveraging of the legacy, I was quite surprised to have not seen more deleveraging in this quarter given the market was quite receptive. Could you have done more deleveraging without booking losses this quarter, or just prefer to keep deleveraging for just, for later? Just trying to understand why you have not done more, especially in January and February? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to reiterate what I said in my initial presentation, the objective of the deleveraging was not to reach headline figures, which were as massive as possible. What we did last quarter was to split our legacy assets portfolio in two buckets, one investment grade, and one non-investment-grade. Or to be even more blunt, money good and money bad assets.</p>
          <p>On the money good front, that's where you can make big figures, but it doesn't make sense most of the time, because these assets are providing very important yields, so a significant positive carry and very limited capital relief impact. So we continue to do some, depending on market conditions, depending on liquidity pressure, and so on and so forth, but it's not a priority for us. So we are not searching for volumes.</p>
          <p>The objective, and it's very straightforward for Didier and for myself, is to make sure that whatever we do provides capital relief under Basel 3. That's why it is very efficient from a Basel 3 perspective. What we've done this quarter, the &#x20AC;0.5 billion disposal of money bad assets and the cracking of CDOs provided more than 20 bps under Basel 3, which compares only to 10 bps under Basel 2.5. So our ratios are still under Basel 2.5, so that's really the name of the game.</p>
          <p>From my perspective, I think it's easier to free up the 20 bps or 25 bps of Basel 3 capital than just selling assets at a distressed price for the pleasure of seeing assets at a distressed price. So that's what we have in mind, this is our management intention over the next 18 months, and that's how we want to get to the 70 bps deleveraging target to put in our roadmap for Basel 3. Is it clear, Beno&#xEE;t?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the non-investment-grade sales of bad assets, are you &#x2013; kind of &#x2013; did you reach a kind of limit where you're now if you are selling more &#x2013; I understand it will be less and less. But if you are selling more, will that cost you also? You will have less impact on the capital?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will let Didier comment on that, but the arbitrage is really this one. On the one hand, you can have P&amp;L impact, on the other hand, a capital relief impact, and you have to make some arbitrage between this. Here again, the decision we made was to ask the team, which is on the ground dealing with these assets, to make sure they were targeting the Basel 3 capital relief impact is number one objective. And then, if they can do this with a limited general impact, and so on and so forth, but that really is a priority list that we have provided them with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think maybe to add a bit, some flavor to what Bertrand said. Let's say, what we are doing also in terms of settling of these legacy assets. As we said, it's cracking, cracking, I think we were maybe among the first to discuss about that. You've seen that currently, that's just some large CIBs are looking for such assets to crack and to get some &#x2013; to extract some more value in their P&amp;L. As you've seen, for example, for the major main street sale that took place last year, last week, sorry.</p>
          <p>So what we believe we can do is, first, we can do that by our own. It's a way for us, let's say, and it takes some time in terms of execution, but we are ahead of our schedule in terms of our roadmaps under Basel 2.5 and Basel 3, so we can continue to work on it. And we will do that, rather do, let's say. We are optimizing, let's say, the financial impact by extracting more value, cracking certain of the <mark type="ph" /> TU (1:55:45) that we can do before selling the underlying assets. And doing that, let's say, we will be able to have sizable capital belief, while let's say having a better, let's say, management, also the value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>And this is what we, let's say, we have decided to do entering to this year. So you won't see let's say massive figures, because also on the money good assets, as Bertrand said, we made a big effort last year in Q3 and Q4. Now, we feel that they are not consuming that much retail liquidity and capital, and we can get some carry from that on the so-called money bad. We have some restructuring to do and we are working on it, so we're doing some of the players in the Street for some parties. We do that on our own and we feel that it's much better for our shareholders to manage that let's say in the coming quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>If not, I think its 3 p.m. Paris time. So thank you very much for your attention and patience. I think myself, Didier, everybody around the table, and the Investor Relations team is at your disposal should you have any other questions or requesting clarification. Many thanks again, and I wish you a very happy afternoon. Thank you. Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the conference call. Thank you all for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>