<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1460488" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-03-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>78343</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Executive Director">Ivan Glasenberg</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Director">Steven F. Kalmin</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Paul Smith</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Liberum Capital Ltd.">Ash J. Lazenby</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Co-Director-Zinc, Copper &amp; Lead Commodity">Aristotelis Mistakidis</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Myles Allsop</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Rothschild Wealth Management (UK) Ltd.">Fiona E. Perrott-Humphrey</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Ben J. Davis</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Standard Bank Plc">Peter W. Davey</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep" affiliation="Director-Alumina &amp; Aluminium Commodity Department">Gary Fegel</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="corprep" affiliation="Director-Coal &amp; Coke Commodity Department">Tor Peterson</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Heath R. Jansen</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane BNP Paribas SA">Sylvain Brunet</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Grant Sporre</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Please hold the line for the conference hosts to join the conference or a customer services representative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome to our 2011 results. As you can see on the first slide, our adjusted EBIT is up 2%, up to $5.4 billion. The Industrial assets have performed very well. They are up 18%, that's both as a benefit of the increased production from the asset base and from the higher commodity prices during 2011.</p>
          <p>So Marketing is up 10%, that's excluding the Agricultural Products and we'll talk a bit about the Agricultural Products division performance later on. But if you take the Marketing business, even including the Agricultural Products division, it was a 35% return on equity. The Glencore net income is up 7%, up to $4.1 billion and we've had a strong operating cash flow of $3.5 billion. That's up 6% from 2010.</p>
          <p>Robust balance sheet, we have $7 billion of committed liquidity available to the company and therefore, we're able to utilize this funding in 2012 to continue growing our business. And I'm sure a lot of people have read about commodity companies having shortage of liquidity and potential liquidity problems because of bank funding, and this clearly disproves that fact. We have $7 billion of committed liquidity available lines to us and therefore, this can be utilized for acquisitions plus for trading activities in the future.</p>
          <p>Our growth projects are, overall, on track, on time and on budget. We do not have cost overruns on most of development projects, and they're very much going to be online for their projected expansions at the time they're all meant to be coming into operation.</p>
          <p>Looking at our marketing activities, as I said earlier, the Metals and Minerals division, generally, the profit is &#x2013; EBIT is $1.2 billion. That is 11% lower than 2010. Looking at this quarter in the division, you've got to remember on the copper zinc part of the business, there was massive restocking which took place in China in 2010. The same restocking did not take place in 2011. That's the reason volumes were slightly down and profits were lower.</p>
          <p>We also were building up the Iron Ore division and therefore, during the phase of the building up and developing the growth in that side of the business, we were not making the same type of profits, the same per alloys was down slightly. But aluminum, the structure of the market allowed us to make higher margins and profits during the year and aluminum profit was up during 2011.</p>
          <p>Looking at the Energy side of the business, as you are aware, the first half of 2011 was very strong towards the &#x2013; the profits were up 55%, with an EBIT of $697 million and the reason is that on the oil side, as I said, the first half of 2011 was very strong <mark type="audio gap" /> (3:14) and was a very good year for oil. The coal part of the business was strong even though there's reduced volatility and lower freight rates, which resulted in less arbitrage opportunities. The pickup of agency business, the increase of various volumes around the world enabled the coal division to perform very strongly.</p>
          <p>Agricultural business, as you can see, was a poor performing area of Glencore. The main reason, 2007 was an exceptional year. We made $659 million profit during 2010 and we made a <mark type="indiscernible" /> (03:59).</p>
          <p>Cotton caused a significant demand of these losses and we've explained the reasons during our mid-year results. The reason for these cotton losses, number one, is there's lesser volatility in the market of cotton during the year. The price rose from $0.85 a pound up to $2.50, came back down. And as we had fixed pricing contracts with our suppliers, we had a lot of nonperformance where the market rallied. And therefore, hedges that we had in place, we were not able to get the benefit on the physical side against those hedges. And therefore, we had to take a loss on the physical part of the business there.</p>
          <p>Also, there was a disconnection between the futures market and the physical market. And during a particular period in 2011, the physical market was not following the same price mechanism as the futures market and that had an effect on the profit.</p>
          <p>This was an unprecedented volatility in the cotton market. The cotton business was also a new business to the company. We brought in a bunch of individuals from outside of the business, which we don't normally do. We grow from within and we've rectified that first in the cotton market will now be priced on a quarterly-type basis and secondly, we've taken someone from the &#x2013; a head or someone within the Grain division to head up that department and ensure it's run on the Glencore-type model.</p>
          <p>Overall, on the industrial activities, as you can imagine, we have these large growth projects going forward and therefore, we increased production at Kazzinc where we have the Vasilkovskoye Gold production together with the zinc production; Katanga, the growth which we have in Katanga in the Congo, where we are growing that asset substantially; plus Mutanda. And as you can see, zinc is up 9%, copper here, production is up 35% and gold production, up 26%.</p>
          <p>On the Energy side, it's well known, the expansion of our coal assets in Colombia, the Prodeco project. Prodeco has increased considerably, up 45% and we produced 14.6 million tonnes in 2011. The development of the port there is going very strongly. This will be developed by the end of 2012 and eventually, that project will get up to 21 million tonnes.</p>
          <p>The good news on the oil side, the Energy side was the Aseng oil production in Block I in Equatorial Guinea came on stream earlier than expected and development there started in November 2011. We ramped up to 50,000 barrels per day. I think today it's getting closer to 60,000 barrels. And as you know, we own 25% of that investment and we will be developing the Alen field later on and that should add another 40,000 tonnes of production there.</p>
          <p>In Agricultural, we're also growing that division on the industrial side of the business. Rio Vermelho, our sugar production, we intend to grow crushing capacity from 1 million tonnes to 2.7 million tonnes over there. And we've also bought four oilseed processing facilities and production of a new developed one in Argentina will come on stream, and that will add 3.6 million tonnes of processing capacity in that area of the business.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, it's an important slide. If you look at Glencore compared to the other mining companies, our compound annual growth of these projects which are mentioned, Mopani, Equatorial Guinea, the E&amp;P portfolio, Prodeco, Kazzinc, Katanga, Mutanda, we have lesser growth occurring in the next two years. Between 2011 and 2013, you will see we have a CAGR of 30.6% during those two years and, if you take it to 2015, we've got a 20% growth. I think this is a stronger growth than any of the mining companies and that shows the development of these projects and the quick ramp up regarding of these projects and most of them will be fully developed by the end of 2013.</p>
          <p>Talking in detail about the production and the growth at these various assets. Kazzinc, as I said, the growth is occurring there very strongly on the zinc side. Not so strong on zinc, sorry, on the gold side, we went from 239 kt to 246 kt on the zinc side, and on the gold production from 326,000 that was Vasilkovskoye Gold to 390,000 tonnes. And in 2012, gold equivalents from this entire operation will grow to 800,000 ounces of gold production and we're pretty much on track over there at Kazzinc and Vasilkovskoye Gold.</p>
          <p>We've also increased the reserves over there on the zinc side and there's been significant increase on the JORC reserves, which took place during 2011.</p>
          <p>Katanga copper production went up. As you are aware, we are mining one of the highest grades of copper in the world, around about 4.5% cooper grade. We increased 57%, up to 91,000 tonnes at Katanga. During 2012, we expect to get to around about 140,000 tonnes of copper production. We've also developed the &#x2013; we've increased the ramp-up to 310,000 tonnes and we're moving fast ahead on that. So therefore, at Katanga, we expect to get to around about 310,000 tonnes development by the end of 2013. So that is moving along nicely.</p>
          <p>Mutanda, the other operation, we were well ahead of where we expected during 2011 and we increased production to 64,000 tonnes. We expect Mutanda to increase to 100,000 tonnes by &#x2013; to produce 100,000 tonnes during 2012. And the intention is Mutanda, together with Kansuki, to increase their production to between 150,000 and 200,000 tonnes and more likely towards the top end of 200,000 tonnes.</p>
          <p>If you look at our E&amp;P portfolio in Equatorial Guinea, as I've said earlier, we developed that project earlier than expected, during November 2011. We kicked up to 50,000/60,000 barrels a day. And we expect to be at 60,000 barrels a day during 2012. The other subsea development there, the Alen field, we expect that in late second half 2013 to add another 40,000 barrels a day production. So, with these two fields, where we own approximately 25%, we should have about 100,000 barrels of oil today and with current oil prices, it's not hard to see how that will generate significant profits to the Group.</p>
          <p>Prodeco, I mentioned earlier. Production increased to around about 14.6 million tonnes this year. The new port, which will allow us to load 21 million tonnes of coal through the new port, will be developed by the end of this year, early next year, 2013, and that will really give a massive expansion in that world-class operation.</p>
          <p>And with that, I hand over to Steve to go through more of the financial details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Ivan, and good morning to everyone here in the audience physically and for those that are listening via the Web as well.</p>
          <p>In terms of Glencore's financial performance, 2011 against 2010, I see today as somewhat of a non-event given these numbers will be released at the time of the announcement of the proposed merger with Xstrata on the 7th of February. So, you're all familiar with these numbers. There's absolutely no change whatsoever, both in numbers and geography and categories with what was reported back on 7th of February.</p>
          <p>The actual preliminary results path of which you will all have a copy of what was released today, is very comprehensive, even more like an annual report type disclosure. We've given all the notes, all the reconciliations. So from a financial perspective, I think it's quite a lot to work through there. What I will try to do, in the next three or four slides, is to focus on one or two areas of additional color that may be useful in understanding our respective financial results.</p>
          <p>So on Page 9, if we just look at some of the snapshots. Back up a slide, you've got it in front of you. The EBITDA, EBIT and net income numbers Ivan had alluded to those earlier on, where we did see improvements of 2%, 7% and 4% respectively, for those reasons, with notably the Industrial assets coming in slightly ahead of 2010 and the Marketing, largely due to the Agricultural underperformance against 2010, finishing slightly below 2010's level.</p>
          <p>And in coming down to the Glencore net income level, income tax was obviously a relevant factor there, a few points on that. We had an effective tax rate, which has been applied and reported in respect to 2011 of 10%, which is a similar level to 2010's level. 2011 is somewhat of a transitional year for Glencore from a corporate tax perspective. For those that follow Glencore in years gone by, under the old partnership structure, we did have, from the corporate level, a layer for the employee profit participation shareholders, which was a feature of our structure in the past, used to get tax deductions at the corporate level which used to maintain low corporate tax.</p>
          <p>Within that entity, that tax has nearly shifted up to the individual level. Now, that structure has collapsed as part of the restructuring and IPOing of Glencore back in May/June last year. We still had the benefit of six months of that, as well as the benefit of some other tax losses that were booked for the first time in 2011.</p>
          <p>So the accounting tax rate, which still came in around the 10% level, going forward, no change to the guidance that we'd given last year at the time of the IPO, which is a Marketing accounting overall effective tax rate of around 10% and the Industrial side of the business, obviously depending on the jurisdiction which we're operating there, but circa 25% to a little below 30% is where it comes in.</p>
          <p>So the future accounting tax charge is going to be the blend of the proportion that those two different income streams flow into Glencore. So the 10% is from an accounting perspective. You can certainly expect that to start trending more towards, if we assume 50/50 split, just as a mathematical split, you would have something approaching more the 20% rate from an accounting perspective.</p>
          <p>However, from a cash perspective tax, it is important to recognize that we do have and you'll see it in the financial statements that we have, we've recognized there's $1.5 billion of tax-effective tax losses that this Group now has carried forward largely due to some tax deductions that were crystallized as a result of the IPO because as much as there was tax paid at the shareholder level, the corporate side, in collapsing those future obligations, did get various tax allowances and you can see we're talking about jurisdictions in Switzerland certainly. U.S. is another one where there were some tax deductions there going forward.</p>
          <p>So $1.5 billion is the tax-effective and the gross amount is obviously much larger as well, which should provide quite a lot of near term cash benefits as the company is able to utilize some of those losses carried forward. So accounting-wise, we expect obviously an increase. Cash flow-wise, we would still expect to have a very low cash tax charge for the foreseeable future in the next few years at least.</p>
          <p>I'll talk about net debt and some of those metrics for this slide later on. 2012, Ivan will talk a little bit on the outlook towards the end as well, but I think you can see a trend in Marketing. We have alerted that that <mark type="ph" /> stow well (16:27) across each segment. And on the Industrials side again, looking forward, we are expecting big growth in coal, be it Colombia, the oil, we'll have our first full year of production going forward in coal and, of course, copper and gold, we've got quite big expansions going forward.</p>
          <p>If we look into Slide 10, really nothing much to add. It's just a geographical showing the Marketing performance, down 18%, really a function of the Agricultural year-on-year movement as well. Metals and Minerals, a largely consistent performance and good volumes and good premiums. Energy was the big increase, at least over 2010, particularly the oil market in the first half of 2011 which we spoke about last year, and some continued drag which is receding but there still is, there's some drag on the low wet freight market particularly in the oil side, which is both &#x2013; we have some long exposure there which is a drag and in what that does to providing some arbitrage opportunity as well. And the Agricultural side, I think Ivan's covered it largely in the cotton side.</p>
          <p>On the Industrial part of the business, if we look at the next slide, the year-on-year improvement was an 18% in the right direction, where again, you've seen growth across all segments, Metals and Minerals. You've seen some of the volume growth, which has flowed through to the bottom line. I'll provide some waterfall charts as well in the coming slides as well.</p>
          <p>Offset, which we are not immune to, as anyone in this industry, and against a higher operating cost base, by virtue of not so much the general inflation environment which is quite low, but more the mining-specific inflation environment as we're operating in many jurisdictions where this industry continues to be a source of great activity or great expansion, competition for labor and access to power ties, diesel fuel, everything has created some sort of upward pressure on the cost side and we'll talk about how that affected Glencore going forward.</p>
          <p>Own production, of course, much higher up in zinc, copper and gold as you can see. The Energy side is off a lower base but growing nicely, both on coal in Colombia. And a little bit of oil production, but that should really start seeing material benefits flowing through in early 2012.</p>
          <p>And also the Agricultural Products business as we've invested quite a bit of capital the last 18 months through the sugar plants and various crushing facilities that Ivan mentioned too, particularly Argentina, Hungary, Poland, Ukraine to name but a few as well, where we've got some expansions.</p>
          <p>If we look at Page 12, that waterfall chart, this is just looking at the Industrial side of the business, at the EBIT going from $2.9 million up to the $3.5 million in 2011. We're showing a price variance of $774 million positive and a volume variance of $272 million. To give you a split on the price variance, $523 million of that was Metals and $250 million was Energy, and that's very much gold and copper were the main contributors on the pricing on the Metals side.</p>
          <p>And Prodeco, we've provided you the realized pricing for them on their export sales, which averaged $95 million against $82 million for year 2011 and 2010, which should still remain fairly robust down there given we have got 27 million of those tonnes have been sold forward at an average price of $94 million as well as the coal side.</p>
          <p>As far as volume variances, $182 million of that $272 million has come from Metals and $89 million from the Energy. And again, you've seen the extra gold production, 26%, copper 35% and the extra coal production, 18%, making up the $89 million.</p>
          <p>In terms of costs, you can see the negative $471 million variance. That's excluding FX, which is a smallish number by mining industry standards of $42 million. But the $471 million, if we relate that over our cost base for the year, that represents about a 5.7% increase in cost base, which if you do the numbers, I think across other peers and other competitors is respectable but it is &#x2013; there are some things you can certainly control and many other things that are uncontrollable there in terms of power and diesel explosives and the like.</p>
          <p>The currency appreciation only had an impact of $42 million for us. That was mostly coming from Australia at our Murrin Murrin operation, with the Aussie dollar gaining strength of around 12%, 2011 over 2012. There's been some further increases there, so I guess that could be a variance that would be seen certainly across many people operating within the Australian market space as there are other higher producing currencies as well. Extra depreciation, higher associate income, particularly coming from Xsrata and Mutanda, was also a &#x2013; currently accounted for in the associate line given our 40% ownership.</p>
          <p>If we move on to Slide 13, from a balance sheet and a funding perspective, shareholders' funds, of course, up to $29.3 billion, both from profit generation as well as the IPO net proceeds. In terms of net debt, $12.9 billion, only a reduction of around $2 billion or 12%; that's something that I'm sure many in this room will have expected to come down further, given also we were in June.</p>
          <p>What we did to in the month of December and particularly seeing quite a big buildup in our working capital, and I'm speaking non-RMI working capital because mechanically when we do our calculations of net debt, we take off the &#x2013; as part of coming to that $12.9 billion, we produced RMI of $13.8 billion, which is, in fact, slightly less than the prior year's $14.3 billion.</p>
          <p>So most of that increase in current capital employed, which went up by $2.9 billion, was more in receivables than payables. $2.4 million of which was in the month of December alone and this was a particular period where I think the date of 31st of December was very relevant. Of course, it's the day of reckoning for many conference and financial institutions themselves, looking to improve positions, looking to many disclosures that they can around balance sheets. This was an opportunity for us to deploy some working capital either in adding receivables or even extending payable terms in some cases, but obviously doing it on attractive terms for Glencore.</p>
          <p>So we did see certain what we would say is temporary in Asia, build up in working capital. There were some profitable funded opportunities. We would expect that to reverse over the course of first half 2012 in a stable commodity price environment which, of course, have seen oil also go up, as I said, in the first two months which, of course, is going to have some impact as well on our working capital.</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding the increase in that sort of more temporary working capital, it does affect ratios and liquidity levels. The balance sheet and credit metrics continue to be strong for our particular rating category. FFO to net debt at 27% and the net debt to adjusted EBITDA at around the two level, as Ivan mentioned. Even with that build out in working capital, around $7 billion of committed liquidity headroom; that needs to be linked to some extent with what our refinancing obligations in the next 12, 18 months, two years, very little in fact.</p>
          <p>Anything within our short-term area in current borrowings is mostly secured asset-backed facilities that by their nature tends to be 364, even uncommitted facilities, but they're funding receivables and inventory in borrowing-based structures that tend to be very straightforward in their extensions and renewal, it's more a question of what's the right margin on an annual basis. They tend to make up the biggest part of our current borrowing. And in our funding history, we've never had problem extending a refinancing. It's more a margin discussion that happens each year.</p>
          <p>The ratings of the company, on a standalone basis just as Glencore, we've seen improvements back in the summer of last year both from S&amp;P and Moody's. Moody's via a stabilization, S&amp;P via the upgrade to the mid-BBB space.</p>
          <p>Following the announcement of the Xstrata proposed combination back in 7th of February, both agencies have flagged potential upgrade potential for the new co, of which is the Glencore sort of surviving-type company structure, S&amp;P via the watch positive and Moody's similarly via flagging upgrade potential.</p>
          <p>Risk, the VaR, as I've measured it, we do report and there's more details of it in the preliminary report and the annual report itself in a few weeks. We'll talk to that more as well as being fairly modest at the 39% level or at the very &#x2013; 0.1% fraction of our shareholders' equity.</p>
          <p>So with that, I'll hand over back to Ivan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Steve. Just giving an idea of where we see things for the balance of the year 2012 and going forward. If I look at the Marketing business and we look at the Marketing business separately, production, as you know, we're getting this massive production at most of our assets. As we get this increased production from our own assets, we are able to increase our activities on the Marketing side on our third-party tonnages. It gives us advantages to do more price arbitrage, utilizing our own tonnes, together with third-party tonnes. It also allows us to do more blending, bigger blending opportunities, switching opportunities on the concentrate side of the business between smelters and the mines. And therefore, we've always noted as we increase the production at our own assets, we increase our third-party marketing. So that allows us to increase our volumes.</p>
          <p>Also, another sign is the weakness we saw during fourth quarter 2011, has turned around during first quarter 2012. And we've already seen the recovery take place on a lot of our activities, bigger volumes are occurring during the first two months of the year. And in most of our &#x2013; all our commodities in fact, the Marketing activities have increased in the first two months and the profits are looking very strong during that period.</p>
          <p>On Industrial side of the business, as I mentioned earlier, that we do have these big ramp-up operations. At Katanga, we will be taking Katanga to 310,000 tonnes, which we envisage to be completed by the end of 2013. Mutanda, we will ramp up to 200,000 tonnes and we're going to get the full year's production from there. And then Aseng field in 2012, as I said earlier, the 60,000 barrels a day, our 25% of that and on the Alen field, towards the latter end of 2013, which will add another 40,000 tonnes.</p>
          <p>We also, as you know, acquired the Optimum Koornfontein, Umcebo operations in South Africa. That is going to give us a massive resource base in South Africa and you will see us increasing our production from those South African reserves, which will add a lot to the Energy/Coal division.</p>
          <p>So, overall, we see the underlying economic fundamentals showing signs of improvement during 2012. As I said, the strength of our own organic growth, demand across the world for these type products, the commodity market looking stronger during this year, once again, we do see the difficulties of the increasing production around the world. You do see the developing countries, the grades decreasing. You see the grades of copper in Chile decreasing. You see production amongst many of the producers decreasing, whilst we are increasing our production in these areas, such as the Congo, Colombia and Kazakhstan.</p>
          <p>As Steve mentioned earlier and I mentioned earlier, a lot of people have asked about the balance sheet. We do have this robust balance sheet. We do have $7 billion of committed line. This is very important going forward. People have heard about &#x2013; we talk about the banking lines tightening up for commodity companies, the smaller commodity companies are seeing tightening of their trade lines. We are not experiencing any of that. As you know, we have our revolver where we have 90 banks supporting us under a one and three-year revolver. That is fully funded and that allows us to take advantage of this liquidity, to have these better trading opportunity, which the smaller companies are finding difficulties to obtain.</p>
          <p>We have the proposed merger with Xstrata. And as we've always said and I've said during our previous discussions, we believe putting these two companies together adds value for the shareholders. The flow of the Xstrata commodity into the Glencore system will add value for both shareholders. We've indicated what the synergies will be on that. That will create net royalties to both shareholders. And we believe we will then have a unique model, which no one else has in the mining industry.</p>
          <p>It's diverse. It's fully integrated. It ensures we get the full value of the product along the value chain from production to the mine, to delivery, to the end customer via storage benefits, blending benefits, being able to arbitrage the price differentials.</p>
          <p>As you well know today, the world is changing. We are producing commodities in more difficult areas of the world. We are selling commodities in new areas of the world. Glencore has been active in all these areas for many years. We have offices in all these countries. We have 54 offices around the world.</p>
          <p>So we add a new dimension to Xstrata. And together, I believe we'll be a unique company with great assets, both long-term assets, producing for the long-term, Glencore bringing quick ramp-up projects to this model. Our projects ramp up very quickly as you've heard earlier today. And together with the Marketing activities, the diversification of having the marketing together with the production, it will be a unique model which will take us well forward for the future.</p>
          <p>I think that's it. We're open for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. So with that intro, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (31:24) several questions <mark type="indiscernible" /> (31:25) go to the phones. Who's got the microphone? Okay. Who's going to ask one first? It's Ash down there at the front.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks, gentlemen. Ash Lazenby from Liberum Capital. Just a couple of questions if I may. First of all, I realize it's still very much in the early stages of negotiation, but in terms of the Kansuki and Mutanda tie-up, would you have any indication as to when we might hear something there and also with the buying out of some of those minorities?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, looking really beyond 2015 in terms of your assets, I guess particularly probably within the copper within Africa, where do you see most potential across those assets in terms of expandability beyond the 2015? And obviously, as you talk about, with the quick ramp up of projects, what we might be able to see there kind of on a blue-sky potential?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Telis, do you want to handle that? We're staying on Mutanda-Kansuki and those questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. As we've mentioned previously, we are in negotiations to merge Mutanda and Kansuki and end up in a situation where we will have the majority of both of those entity. That is ongoing. And we expect to announce something fairly shortly, within a matter of months.</p>
          <p>As far as potentials and forwards, we think that Mutanda-Kasuki is something that exceeded our expectations in term of possibilities for us to ramp up. It's almost brand new, kind of like greens and brownfields with no legacy. It's very high grade, 4.5%, same as Katanga, but without any legacy.</p>
          <p>We will reach 110,000 tonnes of cathode in production by June this year and 15,000 tonnes of coal. We will go for sure to allow another 50,000 tonnes of SX/EW. This will be to the merged entity. It will take us to 150,000 and then the question is do we develop a sulphide ore body that is very shallow underground, like 200 meters, again, high-grade sulphide ore body, put a concentrate there that will produce 100,000 tonnes <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:56) copper and ship that from Mopani. Now, before we can &#x2013; we can increase the 210,000 tonnes of cathodes and add the sulphides as well. So, we are currently, basically doing the feasibility study and we're seeing what is the best course of action there.</p>
          <p>The Katanga side, that's pretty well flagged. What we've done, as Ivan mentioned before, is we have accelerated what we call the Phase IV, which is a $650 million investment on a 200,000 tonne SX/EW which will be brand new and that will take the production up to 210,000 tonnes.</p>
          <p>What we intend to do is we'll then scale down the current production in <mark type="indiscernible" /> (34:41) which we think will be running at around 140,000 tonnes of metal, takes that down to 110,000 on a <mark type="indiscernible" /> (34:51) basis because of the refurbishment that needs be done and run Katanga at 210,000 and that we think will be the maximum that we think Katanga should be.</p>
          <p>With the continued <mark type="indiscernible" /> (35:03) we're not sure of the war in the country. The question is, how do we best want to work to ramp up within the content of the infrastructure which is very power <mark type="indiscernible" /> (35:17).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly, the key to growing in the Congo, as Steven said, we've got sufficient ore, it's just a matter of how do we handle the power situation, roads, transport, et cetera. Now, if we can develop the rail lines or do something on the rail lines, taking it to &#x2013; we're thinking of taking it to Darussalam now, and if we can get that sorted out, that <mark type="indiscernible" /> (35:37) effect. So that it all depends how you develop the infrastructure in those countries.</p>
          <p>Now, your question where do we go from &#x2013; where else are we going? We've got the growth. We've highlighted the growth we have in the Congo. We've highlighted the growth in Colombia, et cetera. But remember, as much as people look at Glencore and I've heard about it when we're talking today about the Xstrata merger, you hear about the long life projects. We do have long life projects. Many of our <mark type="indiscernible" /> (36:01) projects are 40, 50-year life projects. Kazakhstan, the gold operation is a long life project.</p>
          <p>You've also got to remember, where we are in Kazakhstan, there's a lot of other gold reserves around there which can be developed and fed through our infrastructure, where there's full smelting refining capacity there. We have spare capacity. So we can develop other reserves around that area and we're always looking for other reserves. It's no secret. There are other reserves, which can be bought, owned by other parties when it doesn't make sense for them to build a full smelting refining facility there because it's not economical.</p>
          <p>For us to do it, to just develop those reserves and put it through our smelter refinery is pretty easy. So it would not be surprising to see us grow our coal production in Kazakhstan substantially by adding on other reserves there.</p>
          <p>You've also got to remember our reserves and what we've purchased, as I mentioned earlier, in South Africa, on the coal side in South Africa, we have massive resources, yeah. I think we have correspondingly we have 2.5 billion tonnes of resources together with all our projects for the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (37:10) Koornfontein, and Optimum in South Africa and that allows us to really grow our production in South Africa, I know which is very constrained, but which is where the rail lines can increase and as it does increase, we can increase our production over there.</p>
          <p>You also got to remember in South Africa, there's also shortage of coal for Eskom power stations. And with the new power stations coming on stream, Eskom is trying to tie up supply of coals substantially on a long-term basis. We are able to increase our production considerably over there.</p>
          <p>If you look at our West African oil development, as you are aware, we've got these developments in both Alen and Aseng fields. We also got the Carla and Diega developed preserves in the Alen and Aseng fields, and that should kick in production from 2015.</p>
          <p>We also have developments where we're drilling in Cameroon so we've got further potential development there. And together with the infrastructure that we have there, where the FPSO, which we can move around in that area and go to other areas as we develop the Carla and the Diega fields, you could see both increases of production in that area from 2015.</p>
          <p>Also, you people, where you're also not focusing on is you've got to remember we also own RussNeft in Russia. As you are aware, RussNeft produces around about 280,000 barrels of oil a day. That is reserves which it can grow. We are showing our shareholding in that. We are not showing a value on that shareholding in the coming &#x2013; we have the $2 billion loan to RussNeft, which is being serviced. But RussNeft does a big &#x2013; it can expand and even just maintaining at 280,000 barrels of oil and keeping that for the long term, it does have sufficient reserves where that can maintain it for the long term. That is for the expansions of the company.</p>
          <p>So on the relevant assets and other reserves, we have our bigger expansions from 2015. The good thing about these expansions, a lot of them are brownfields. What Glencore is focusing on here and we always have is return on equity. As you know, this company has always managed a return on equity over the 37 years we've been around, but if we look at the past 20 years, between 35% to 60% return on equity.</p>
          <p>So on any assets we are developing and any of these growth assets, it's purely going to be based upon a return on equity, remembering most of us working in this company have a fairly big stake in the company. So we're very much guided by return on equity. We are not building projects for the fact of building project. I'm not saying greenfields are not good projects, but greenfield projects we've seen in the past, we've experienced it ourselves at <mark type="ph" /> Manala (40:00), tend to have cost overruns of more difficult projects.</p>
          <p>We like to focus on easier projects, projects we understand, can be developed at a quicker rate with less risk, with less chance of capital overruns. And that's what we've done in the past in Glencore. So you will see these projects are pretty easy expansionary projects, which we can do pretty quickly and at a low cost.</p>
          <p>And if you look historically at the assets which we have developed within Glencore, there's a slide somewhere there in your pack, you will see we've developed projects, if you look at the copper equivalent, at a lower cost than anyone else in the industry per revenue that day and per capacity in which they bring. And that is what we're focusing on.</p>
          <p>All our assets have been developed on that process. It's in your brochure, how we developed the Congo business, how we developed our Colombian business, how we developed our regional coal business in Australia, South Africa now sitting in Xstrata today, but they were obtained by putting pieces together, getting Tier 2, Tier 3 assets together and developing Tier 1 assets.</p>
          <p>So as much as we're hearing about this merger, you saw that Glencore, a lot of people are saying we don't have this Tier 1 long year, long term 40, 50-year old assets, the majority of the real value assets which Glencore has are those Tier 1 assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question. I'm sorry, I forgot to say could you sort of introduce yourself before you ask the question, please. Myles?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Myles Allsop, UBS. First of all, could you say what feedback you've had so far of the Xstrata merger? What do you see as the key issues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think &#x2013; look, we haven't visited the Xstrata shareholders yet. Steve and myself will be going on a road show after this results presentation. We'll be focusing on &#x2013; actually, the Glencore will meet the Glencore's shareholders and they're meeting the Glencore shareholders also in Xstrata, but we will be meeting a lot of the Xstrata shareholders who are not shareholders in Glencore.</p>
          <p>So we haven't met them and so what I've reading in the press, what I've heard from Mick Davis of these road show, I think a lot those shareholders in Xstrata are not shareholders in Glencore. A lot of them we haven't, in fact, met. So a lot them are sitting and they don't understand Glencore. What we are hearing is exactly one of the questions asked today is a lot of them don't believe Glencore has these Tier 1 assets. We've clearly proved we do have Tier 1 assets. A lot of them don't believe we have these 50-year life assets. We have these 50-year life assets.</p>
          <p>What a lot of them are forgetting, we have quick ramp-up, which you've heard today. If you talk about our CAGR in the next two years, we have a 30% CAGR which is higher than any of the other mining companies. So we do have a quicker growth than them and that's what I believe Xstrata gets the advantage of these quick growth projects, which come into the merged company.</p>
          <p>A lot of those people don't understand our Marketing business. They have the so-called black box which I read about and we hear about the black box. What those people fail to understand, which I think we did a pretty good job during the IPO educating people about the Glencore model, what is the trading business, it's not a bunch of speculators trading on derivatives.</p>
          <p>It is a physical business. It is not us loading CAGRs of coal, copper, zinc, aluminum, putting it on boats, shipping it to other parts of the world, looking for the best price arbitrages, using third-party tonnes to complement our business, whereby we can substitute third-party tonnes against our own tonnes and look for the best price available and therefore take advantage of the price arbitrage that exists in different countries.</p>
          <p>We also have the ability to blend products. Blending different products and not supplying our own produced products into a customer, which is too high a quality for their customers' requirements, which is shorter than today all the other mining companies do today, they produce a product. They invest the product, they sell to their customers.</p>
          <p>The fact that that's a better product than the customer requires, there's not much they can do about it. Glencore deals with 7,200 suppliers. It's able to buy in third-party tonnes, blend down the higher quality products and take advantage by buying in a cheaper product, which can be blended in and therefore, making a margin on that business.</p>
          <p>It's also able to substitute Russian tonnes to deliver to a customer <mark type="indiscernible" /> (44:28) take its own tonnes to a higher price or a vessel which is going to a higher priced customer. It's able to play around and use its smelters for a better advantage, whereby you don't need to supply high concentrate, high quality concentrates into a smelter. They can get a price advantage by taking a higher concentrate, a higher quality concentrate and get a premium with a particular time they may require them and put a lower quality, third-party concentrate through its smelters. This is what Glencore does.</p>
          <p>Now this we have to educate and show the investors who don't understand Glencore that ain't the black box, that ain't a bunch of guys sitting behind the screen speculating on our commodity prices. It's a physical movement of tonnes around the world.</p>
          <p>What we also got to educate them and I think this is important is the flow of the Xstrata tonnes into the Glencore system we've never had before. We've had agency agreements. We've had marketing agreements. We've had advisory-type agreements. But we never had a free flow of the Xstrata tonnes into the Glencore system. We believe the free flow of the tonnes into the Glencore system allowing us to be three-point, as I mentioned, arbitraging and all the stuff we do, allows us to add more value.</p>
          <p>You know we've mentioned the synergies are around about $500 million. That's the synergies we believe we get from this type of movement of the tonnes throughout the Glencore system. Now, all the shareholders are getting the benefit of that. It goes to the Glencore shareholders, the Xstrata shareholders. As you are aware, this is a merger. It is a share-for-share deal. So all the shareholders get the benefit.</p>
          <p>So this is something we've got to try and explain what is our business model. People also have got to remember that Marketing has been run for 37 years. This is not a company that was developed overnight and the Marketing business is new and it may have a bad year or good year. Sure, it may be a year where <mark type="indiscernible" /> (46:23). It will have the problem type we had in cotton last year and you will have that from time to time.</p>
          <p>However, Glencore for 37 years in its Marketing business has both relationships with suppliers and consumers around the world, and we have always made a profit in the Marketing business. There is no year that the Marketing has taken a loss. So we've always averaged on the Marketing business alone between a 35% to 60% return on equity. And even if you look in two slides, as I mentioned at the beginning of my presentation, in 2011, the Marketing business still gave a 35% return on equity. Well, that's together with the cotton loss included.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What would you say is the normalized profitability for the Marketing business? So you say 35% is rather the lowest <mark type="indiscernible" /> (47:11)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We really can't &#x2013; I'm afraid, we can't comment on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe one, two quick questions for Steve. In terms of the working capital, how much have you accrued kind of flowing back in during kind of January and February?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean a lot of work was put out in December, anyway a lot of that has flowed back. We were also moving and Telis can talk to that, we're also moving a lot of copper generally across the world, which has a conversion cycles, sort of west to east and that will take 60 to 120 days to sort of recycle through as well. So a lot of that certainly has reversed and come back, but I would say tempered a little bit by the higher oil prices we'll likely see, which just naturally &#x2013; in there is a bit more working capital we need within the oil business if you're sustaining volumes over 125 compared to the 115 or a 118 sort of level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just on the margins of these 364 loan facilities, have you seen those margins increase as you've refinanced them, or are they pretty stable themselves?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They are relatively stable. I mean, we will be, within the next &#x2013; we were even in a pre-syndication phase of extending the 364-day facility refinancing effectively replicating the terms for another year, the sort of one plus one transaction, which we were able to extend another year on that, and it's not too out of kilter, it's quite a small-ish movement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think just one final point, just in terms of to help you understand. I mean, from here, we'll be doing four days in the U.K., two days in the U.S. next week and then Steve and I will be in Asia the following week and that is the Glencore road show. We've looked to do it for a joint road show together at some point in early April ahead of the documentation, probably the back end of April. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fiona Perrott-Humphrey from Rothschild. History has not been kind to joint CEO situations. Can you comment on how the day-to-day running of the business is going to pan out with two very strong personalities at the top?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, history hasn't been good in certain companies, but in other companies it has been good. If you look at the history of Goldman Sachs, in particular time frames, they've been very successful with joint CEOs. So it has worked in that case.</p>
          <p>Firstly, it's not joint. Mick Davis is the CEO, I'm the Deputy CEO/President. And I don't think it's an issue. You've got to remember, Mick and me have worked together for a long time. We know each other for a long time. Mick joined Xstrata in 2002. He came on board. We've had a very successful relationship since he joined Xstrata. Glencore has supported any of the activities of Xstrata, as you know, where it's contributed to our 40% equity raising at various times. We supported all the ventures that Mick has done. We've worked very close with each other during that period. Nothing has happened in Xstrata where we didn't coordinate and discuss daily what's going on there.</p>
          <p>So it's not a problem. We work together. This is no different. Mick has certain strengths. I have certain strengths. I focus and we'll be focusing more on the trading activities of the business. I focus more on the relationships. I'm traveling, as you can imagine, with our business in Russia. I have to spend a lot time in Russia, a lot of time in Africa and that's where I'll be focusing my time.</p>
          <p>Mick does focus more time on the asset production base of the business, investor relations, et cetera. And I think it's a perfect combination. You've got to remember this is a big company. It's going to be a $100 million company. It's complex. It has trading. It has the asset side of the business, which the other mining companies don't have. And I think it does require two people at the top to be running and assisting this company growth and to integrate these two companies together.</p>
          <p>And as I do have a relationship with the trading part of the business, yes, Glencore does also have assets, the combination of the two bringing the skills of Xstrata on the production side of the business, the skills of Glencore on the trading side of the business, my skills on the trading side of the business, Mick's skills on the production side of the business, I think it's a perfect combination and I think neither of us have egos that is a game that has to be played. And it will work.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question. No? No questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben Davis with UBS. Just in terms of iron ore. We've referred <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:14) you've referred to the Glencore approach about growing through this fashion would be more attractive in greenfields, blending lower cost material with higher cost material to <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:25) opportunities. Do you see the iron ore business as slightly different from that in terms of low-grade of material and higher grade in brownfield versus greenfield?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think iron ore in Glencore is working perfectly with what we do. What has happened two years ago, as you're aware, BHP changed the <mark type="ph" /> volume (52:45) of iron ore towards <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:46) a supplier to the end customer type business. It was an annual pricing-type business, so it was hard to break in. BHP adjusted the model.</p>
          <p>The rest of the mining industry followed their <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:58) is priced on a spot basis. It always has allowed traders to move into their game whereby you can buy plenty from producers. You can supply to customers because all the customers now is not supplying to consumers. They've either placed in between and that has been well proven even though it's only started for a few years. Okay, I think that they'll grow substantially, but this year we locked, I think we did 11 million tonnes of iron ore. This year we'll grow significantly. We've locked up a lot of tonnage in the third-party producers and our tonnage will increase in that area pretty well in 2012.</p>
          <p>Xstrata, as you know, have their development in Mauritania and that is a brownfield-type expansion <mark type="indiscernible" /> (53:44) and then we'll be developing those projects which fit perfectly in line with the Glencore-type model. And there's another greenfield expansion in <mark type="ph" /> Lagos (53:54) for that to be a test one to turn that project and get Xstrata going forward. But these are tonnes that can flow into the Glencore system.</p>
          <p>Now, will the company continue to look for new expansions and new projects which we can acquire with brownfields or greenfields on existing projects? Sure. Luckily, Glencore operates opportunistically. And I'm not saying we're going to go out of our way <mark type="indiscernible" /> (54:18). It's going the other way at all cost of growing iron ore. No. it happens within Glencore, it happens within the department and does the iron department bring potential possibilities.</p>
          <p>As you know, he's dealing with a lot of suppliers in Africa and he's doing pretty fine and has facilities with these suppliers in getting the off-take. Could it occur that those like had happened within Glencore that develops a relationship with a lot of these producers who we do due pretty finance projects with them. And eventually we do convert some of that debt into equity as we understand the project, we get to know it better and we feel more comfortable in the area.</p>
          <p>So, yeah, Glencore will develop opportunistically and hopefully together with Xstrata, and will have the power that Xstrata will have more experience on the iron ore development. So we can look at it. We will be looking at areas opportunistically and it may be existing production in the same branch of a greenfield over the expanse of the field.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just one follow-up if I may. You could argue there's been some missteps from major iron ore producers within West Africa. Do you see opportunities arising for Glencore out of that given your longer term established relationships in the area?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, I think that's how we developed in the Congo. Other people were in the Congo. They were developing in the Congo. They lacked funding. As you are aware, that's how we got into Nikanor-Katanga. We saw opportunity. We had prefunded some of those <mark type="indiscernible" /> (55:46). They needed further equity raises. We were there to underwrite further equity raisings, which we did with Katanga. We merged Katanga and Nikanor together, the opportunity occurred and that's how we grew.</p>
          <p>Now, in West Africa, the different regions of West Africa, sure there had been mistakes in Guinea. I think that's what you were referring to. Of course, we're going to be around looking to see what opportunities, through vacant sales available. There are various companies who are there at the moment who are looking at different ideas how to solve their problems, et cetera. Sure, we're all around that area. We are buying tonnes. We're active in that area and different type. We're buying bauxite from Guinea. We have our investments <mark type="indiscernible" /> (56:26) who's active in Guinea, so we know the area. So, of course we'll look for opportunities. For the entire West Africa area, we'll be looking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Simon, can we go to the Web, investors and analysts from the Web for questions? Just meanwhile if there's another question from the floor while we're waiting? Unusually reticent this morning. Question from the gentleman over here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Peter Davey from Standard Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Ivan, just in terms of your comment on the fourth quarter and how into this first quarter, the commodity market has improved, how much of that have your traders seen as the customer pulling through? Or how much of it might be due to the speculators, the hedge funds, sort of maybe topping up underweight positions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if you talk to the guys across the board, yeah, I think the copper guys can talk to you guys. I think across the board, even if I'm talking some of the lesser commodities, if you're talking cobalt, moly some of the ferrochrome areas, I think we're seeing a lot more physical movements. I mean, do any of you guys want to comment of what you're seeing on the physical side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I think <mark type="indiscernible" /> (57:46) strength that we're seeing is <mark type="indiscernible" /> (57:48) sitting on the futures market <mark type="indiscernible" /> (57:50) and all those that people are facing. If you look back a little bit over the last two or three years, the fourth quarter of 2010, we said that it was strong. Why? Because prices were low and people respond because prices rose in 2011, you had &#x2013; in copper, you had a record high in February, March, last year, over $10,000. There was de-stocking. And then the price came down again towards the end of last year, you see re-stocking again. And now, these materials are being shipped to the consumer areas and that's the strength that we're hearing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (58:29) what do you think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we see the same thing for this <mark type="indiscernible" /> (58:35). I think Telis described <mark type="indiscernible" /> (58:38) very strongly in the U.S. for example. Three weeks ago, close to sort of all-time highs actually. And there's not as much available as it might be by looking at the newspapers and they believe what you read about is the physical demand is <mark type="indiscernible" /> (58:56) region, not just in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tell me, are you seeing it across the board? I mean zinc then, as I mentioned about zinc, but is also seeing all physical movements on the zinc side of the business. Coal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've shown growth worldwide around about 7.5% to 8%, so the demand &#x2013; from a coal perspective, prices are a little weaker and that's more a function of the supply side than increased growth in Indonesia and I'd say a big development over the last six to 12 months is in the United States market with low domestic gas prices, which you're seeing in the United States increase significantly its exports of coal, even though they're a high cost producer, they've probably tripled in the last six or seven months, and obviously that affects the Atlantic market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's it. Okay. Sophie, can we go to the Web?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question comes from Heath Jansen from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning. Just two questions. The first one on Altyntau, you just said in the release that you're still having some issues on recovery and fine grinding. Could you just give us some more detail on that and whether there's going to be any change in terms of your guidance on production this year?</p>
          <p>And then just secondly, just back on the markets again, we're seeing some of the physical premiums particularly in copper coming down in China. So I'm just wondering perhaps you could tell us that in more comments or clarity to add on that and whether that's impacting your business at all? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you can take both, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:00:46).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay yes, I'll take the copper one first. I think if you look at the Chinese, the pattern of Chinese buying is that when prices are low, and I refer back to if you look at the fourth quarter of last year when copper hit a low of around $6,800 on the LME. At the time, the arbitrage was about $350 equivalent premium for the <mark type="ph" /> share fee (1:01:15). And what happened is that the Chinese restocked heavily in times of price weakness there. So what you have is you've got purchases made by Chinese buyers at around $6,800 that will take all the way up to $7,500 that are being shipped today at a time when the copper price is more like $8,500.</p>
          <p>And what you're seeing now is them taking profits and selling those internally. So they've got there a $1,000 profit. Now, when that happens and you see this pattern developing, I would say throughout the last 10 years is that in price weaknesses, the arbitrage, the premium into China increases, inter-price strengths, what you see is that the arbitrage tends to go the other way as the material is sold and custom cleared and gone and goes into China, and that's the position that we're seeing right now.</p>
          <p>And when people say weaknesses in premiums, what they're referring to generally, I'd say is they <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:02:05) LME arbitrage. Is that correct? Because the premium's at this stage, for example, are not weak, they're pretty high. They're as highest they've been for at least six years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then I was <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:02:22) don't know if you want to add anything, Daniel, but I think we're producing further MERs. As we said, in the MER, we'll hit the MER during 2012 and the recovery I think we're getting around and will move from 75% to 85% with a final crushing. I don't know if you want to add anything, Daniel?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean it's en route?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's en route. They are crushing material. We could get a better recovery. We're hoping to get better recovery than 85%. But even at 80%, 85%, we will meet the MER target. And it's just a process which they're going through.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take another question from the Web.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The next question comes from the line of Sylvain Brunet. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Sylvain Brunet of Exane, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Sylvain Brunet with Exane. Two questions please. The first one on the Kazzinc deal. If you could give us an update on your potential increase to the initially planned 93% stake in the company? And the second question, if you could recap on the Agricultural, Industrial part of the business, what impact in production and what would be a normalized EBIT number in 2012 and beyond? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just on the last question, we can't &#x2013; we're not prepared &#x2013; we can't say anything about the 2012 numbers. If we just focus therefore on the Kazzinc transaction, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so the &#x2013; as I said, we can't answer the second part of your question. The first part of your question with regards to 93% of Kazzinc, we expect that deal to be concluded during the second quarter this year, Steve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, what we put inside there that we could even close a little bit earlier, but I think both parties, due to their own specific requirements or preferences, are more targeting now a Q3 2012 completion for that particular but none of any changed terms or anything. It's still the $1 billion equity at the IPO price, $2.2 billion in deferred cash consideration. And that's the timing that currently suits both sides. That's what's being targeted at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the deal is not changed. The $1 billion of the equity will be at the price of the IPO price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sylvain, do you want to ask another question given I scratched out your second question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. No, maybe, if you could just give the recap on the issues in the production side, the Agricultural business in 2011 then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, the issues in what specifically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The rail access, I remember were...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh rail line, sorry, are you talking about &#x2013; which commodity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Agricultural Products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Agricultural Products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:05:15).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the industrial side you mean, or are you talking about Marketing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, sorry, Marketing side, Marketing side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, there were some issues I think around Q4, around access. I mean there's a structural shortage of railcars I think in the FSU and it was a record grain harvest. So there was an even greater &#x2013; I mean it's not an ongoing...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:05:40)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there's some issues around port access. Again, I know that those occur from time to time, it's not an ongoing thing, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. No problem. Right. Any more questions from the floor? Myles, I think you're &#x2013; oh actually, Grant, you've not asked one yet, so can Grant have it then? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. It's Grant Sporre from Deutsche Bank. Could you just give us an update on, let's say, the politics or the political situation in the Congo after the recent elections, particularly from your perspective and has anything changed in your business there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I mean, we were always &#x2013; the elections took place, President Kabila was re-elected into power on a pretty good majority. I think the parliament has now also been selected, been voted. We haven't seen any change. We hear that people were expecting a bit of violence or disruptions after the election; that has not occurred. So we really don't see much of a change. Of course, Ambassador Katumba, as you know, died in an air crash about two weeks ago. He was important in the mining sector. But it seems President Kabila has got control of the business. I'm sure they will put someone &#x2013; they do have a mining minister who understands it. So we haven't seen very much difference since the election, so we hopefully believe we should have five years of stability in the country and we can continue to grow.</p>
          <p>But as we say, the country does have its problems in the sector of power and that's important that we work close with the government, with SNEL, to increase the power, the capacity that we need at our operations. I mean it's just an upgrade of &#x2013; and Telis can talk on what we've got to do there and it's once again, the logistics, the infrastructure, the port, the railage and the trucking in it to make sure the roads are tarred and it's easier to track. So, that is I think, as a color, I don't think it's a political problem, it's purely infrastructure and it's holding up infrastructure. And do you want to add anything on the power, Telis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on the power. Power is the determining factor for any increase in production <mark type="ph" /> when the government (1:07:55) says, oh I'm going to increase this. Well, today, he has to kick somebody else out because the power is there. As far as we're concerned, we have an agreement with SNEL which is the national power company <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:08:05), where we will invest &#x2013; well, it's actually a loan, sort of pre-financed $350 million for upgrades in two hydroelectric plants and also to find down to Katanga to provide 450 megawatts which will feed Katanga to go up to 310,000 tonnes and Mutanda to go up to 200,000 tonnes. We will prefund $250 million and we get that back essentially with discounts from our electricity bills over a five-year period. And that's what we've done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. So, can I just follow up on that? In your prefinancing to SNEL, does that sort of help you in discussions with being able to join up Kansuki and Mutanda? Is it part of a bargaining chip or is it..?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I mean this is &#x2013; it's &#x2013; in the beginning, the power funds are tight, the budget is stretched. And what we can do, which at Mutanda, is one, negotiate a deal where you make sure that the money that is spent equals the power given to you and that takes a long time and it's quite comforting <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:09:20).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:09:28) just like economical for him. And this through land, his land has got the sulfur dioxide all in the way. Telis and his team are developing that project. It makes sense to put the two together.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Myles?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Myles Allsop, UBS. Could you just go into a bit more detail in terms of the trading conditions that you're seeing in the market currently? I mean I guess thinking on the energy side as well with the recent move in oil prices, does that give you more opportunities? Is that why you're sort of sounding more confident today in terms of trading opportunities?</p>
          <p>And also, just to reassure investors around the cotton loss, why this just cannot happen? I mean do you think it can never happen again. I know you're pretty confident now that there's no other part of the Marketing business that could have a potential slip up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean we talk about the cotton situation, nonperformance by customers, not performing as prices move upward. That happens. That happens all the time. However, the cotton team was a new team. I don't think they understood their business well as our people do generally understand the business in the Glencore system. We know what's falling or rising commodity prices. We know which customers will remain on contract. Actually, the ones that those call with all those top customers, and you see the letters of credit in place and as you know, we have <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:10:54) saw bad debts in the company because we only load coal as you know, we've got letters of credit or insurance systems in place to avoid that.</p>
          <p>But what does happen and it happened in 2008 and 2009, where you had some customers not perform and at that stage, it was time and they talked and talked about it basically. The coking coal side of the business where customers &#x2013; there was a part and the receivers did not perform when you had higher product contracts.</p>
          <p>Generally, you run your book correctly, as you know, particular customers or particular people in particular countries will not perform at a contract which is out of the money. They treat such contracts as options. We know that. We know who run the book and if you're always running the book that you know the price of coking coal drops. You're going to divert that cover and you've got a reserve customer where you can take it.</p>
          <p>And that's what we've always protected within the Glencore system and we've been very successful. From time to time, what you consider a very reliable customer doesn't perform and you indeed get caught as in 2008, 2009 on coking coal event.</p>
          <p>Now, cotton, these guys have a lot of fixed price contracts which when the price rallied, they should have known they weren't going to get performance. But let's take number one. So we took a hit on that and that should not occur. And as we have proved over the years, when markets do move up or down and we do get changes in markets, we have not been caught like that in other commodities.</p>
          <p>What also happen in that commodity, which could happen in other commodities, but it wasn't a strange event at the time, where the futures markets and the physical markets were not moving at the same time. So there was the squeeze being created. A war started happening in the futures market, which was not being handled in the physical market, which was an unusual situation and it was a big part of the book but it was a part where we also got hurt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's also worth noting that the forward fixed price contract part of our business is actually very small. And most contracts in which we're operating from performance risk, physical performance risk is down into a few smaller parts of the commodity you expect. And your really big flows in oil and metals and these things, yes, you've got big volume commitments but you're not pricing until much closer to the point of actual delivery.</p>
          <p>Cotton was a more &#x2013; sort of had its own pricing structure for many, many years. It's now getting reviewed, as did iron ore and coking coal coming into 2008. We started moving to quarterly had to do with some of our performance factors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:13:30) I know companies that say nothing with the mining companies. You just don't see it in those figures because it's not a trading position. But if you look during 2008, all the major producers of iron ore, sold at fixed price, went to the Chinese, to the Indians, et cetera. But when the market dropped, they didn't get performance. Very similar to what I'm talking about here.</p>
          <p>You didn't see that come up because they may have sold iron ore at $330 a tonne or whatever. They dropped to $150, so they rarely lost that opportunity profit which they had locked in. And you didn't see it in their figures but they took a far bigger loss than us and I think that's a big reason why the mining companies have now moved to the spot price basis because they're saying even if we were a long term, that we don't get performance, what's the benefit of having it. Well those will just be on a spot basis.</p>
          <p>So I think every <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:14:19) across the board, we just feel it because we've got a trading position where we have to take the physical from the producer, in that case it was iron ore, or the other case we have to deliver the physical or cotton to the customer even though our producer is not delivering to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And in terms of trading opportunities at the start of 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think trading opportunities 2012, as you heard earlier when we were explaining earlier, the physical business is stronger. There's more physical movements around the world. When you see physical movement, it means more tonnage moving. You do get higher prices, which we are seeing today.</p>
          <p>When you do get higher prices, you are getting price arbitrages around the world because there's shortage of tonnages. It is an oversupply in every country. So therefore, they all want these product arbitrages and across the board, we are taking advantage of those price arbitrages because of the increased volume of product around the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the oil side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The same goes for the oil side also.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Alex will be at the lunch here today. If you are...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you can give him <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:15:22) exactly where he's sitting on this situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, one more question? If there any interest from the floor? Otherwise, I'll think we'll wrap it up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>No, okay, fine. Just one moment, I think, apparently, I'm getting the feedback of the sound quality on the webcast is not great. If anyone has any &#x2013; if they're not clear on and want to follow up, then if you email me paul.smith@glencore.com, I'll come to you as soon as I can and apologies for the sound quality. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>