<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1303545" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-04-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>68614</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Randy Arickx, Executive Director, Investor Relations and Financial Communications</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Christopher P. Liddell, Vice Chairman and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Nicholas S. Cyprus, Vice President, Controller and Chief Accounting Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Himanshu Patel</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Rod Lache</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Brian Johnson</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">John Murphy</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Patrick Archambault</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Dee-Ann Durbin</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Philip LeBeau</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">David Welch</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Chris Isidore</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="corprep">Chuck Stevens</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to the General Motors' Analysts and Media Conference Call to discuss its Fresh-Start Accounting. During the presentation, all participants will be in a listen-only mode. Afterwards, we will conduct a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. As a reminder, this conference is being recorded Wednesday, April 7, 2010.</p>
          <p>I will now like to turn the conference over to Randy Arickx, Director, Investor Relations and Financial Communications. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, operator. Good morning, everyone. Thanks for joining us. As we will be filing later today, Forms 10-Q and 10-K for the periods ending September 30, 2009 and December 31, 2009 respectively, including the impact of fresh-start accounting.</p>
          <p>During today's call, Chris Liddell, Vice Chairman and Chief Financial Officer; and Nick Cyprus, VP, Controller and Chief Accounting Officer will provide context for the SEC filings. Like always, if you have questions after the call I would recommend that members of the media contact our Financial Communications team, and financial analysts contact our IR Department.</p>
          <p>I would like to direct your attention to the legend regarding forward-looking statements on the first page of the chart set. The content of our call today will be governed by this language. I would also like to highlight that GM is broadcasting this call live via the Internet.</p>
          <p>The presentation portion of the call will be followed by approximately 10 minutes of questions from financial analysts, followed by 10 minutes from members of the media. I would ask that you limit your questions to one per caller.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll the turn the call over to Chris Liddell.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Randy. And good morning everyone on the phone. Today clearly marks an important day for the new General Motors. We will be filing later today with the SEC our December 2009 10-K and 10-Q under fresh-start accounting.</p>
          <p>I'd like to spend my time this morning providing some context for the SEC filings and along with Nick Cyprus who is our Controller and Chief Accounting Officer providing some commentary on that content.</p>
          <p>In terms of context, we are in the process of building a foundation for this company to successfully return to public ownership. To achieve that, we need to make significant progress in several key areas. In particular, we need to design and build the world's best vehicles, improve our relationships with all of our key stakeholders, return to profitability and positive operating cash flow, achieve sustainable financial strength, while continuing to operate with integrity and reliability in every aspect of our business including financial reporting.</p>
          <p>As you know, the company has been through a tremendous amount of turmoil over recent years. But it's time to put that behind us and build for our future. In that regard, I'm incredibly encouraged by the progress that I've seen in the short time that I have been here.</p>
          <p>Today I'm going to discuss some of that progress, in particular, our efforts on fresh-start accounting and what you could expect from us as we move to regular financial reporting.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide two &#x2013; and I'll talk to the slide as we go through for those of you who can see them. During &#x2013; driving everything that we do is the vision of designing, building and selling the world's best vehicles. It's a simple easy-to-understand and compelling vision given the heritage of our company. We are aligning all of our efforts globally to achieve it.</p>
          <p>We intend to design the world's best vehicles, build them to the highest possible quality, and sell them globally in our traditional and emerging markets. You'll consistently hear me say that financial success will come with achieving this vision, and with financial success will come the underpinnings of a healthy company that can successfully return to public ownership.</p>
          <p>While it's early we've made some tangible progress towards that vision as you can see on slide three. Despite the financial challenges this company has endured, I will give real credit to previous management for continuing to invest in our product portfolio. In fact, Bob Lutz, who as you know will be retiring a few weeks after 47 years in the industry, describes our current portfolio as the best line-up, top to bottom, that General Motors has had in decades, if not ever.</p>
          <p>By the way, I'd like to pause on that comment and acknowledge Bob for the great job he has done over the past eight years here at GM overhauling both the product development organization and product line-up. I have only had the chance to work with Bob briefly but have enjoyed him enormously.</p>
          <p>Our recent launched products have been well received including the Buick LaCrosse, Chevrolet Equinox, and Camaro, which recently won the World Car Design of the Year award judged by a panel of five global design leaders, the GMC Terrain, the Cadillac SRX in North America, and in Europe the Opel/Vauxhall Insignia and Chevrolet Cruze, Chevrolet Agile and Buick LaCrosse and Regal in other international markets.</p>
          <p>New products we have coming as &#x2013; that you will see on slide three, give us the confidence we can build on that success. For example, the Chevrolet Cruze which is already selling well in 66 countries comes to the U.S. in the third quarter. We've just unveiled the Cruze Eco model at the New York Auto Show, which I know a number of you attended last week. And rated at 40 miles per gallon on the highway with a manual transmission, Cruze Eco will offer hybrid-like economy without the added cost.</p>
          <p>Joining the Buick family this quarter is the Regal mid-sized sedan which shares its heritage with the Opel Insignia, winner of the 2009 European Car of the Year award. And in the fourth quarter we'll begin selling the Chevy Volt, part of our global commitment to advanced energy saving technologies. For commuting, Volt can drive up to 40 miles per charge on pure electricity, backed by a range extender that can provide an additional 300 miles if needed.</p>
          <p>In Europe, the Opel Meriva is launching now, although we've not released a photo yet, the next generation Astra Wagon is coming at the end of 2010, and the compact seven-seater Chevrolet Orlando will also make its debut later this year.</p>
          <p>Turning to China, we are now launching the Chevrolet Sail, the first GM high-volume, small car to be developed entirely in China. The new Buick Excelle is designed especially for Chinese luxury car customers, while the Chevy Spark mini car continues its global debut in major markets, including China, during the balance of 2010.</p>
          <p>I'm often asked as a newcomer if I have had any surprises in joining GM and the honest and best answer is the quality of the cars launching in the next couple of years. Probably the most enjoyable part of my job is spending time at our design center seeing what's coming in the next two, three and four years out.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide four, a second element, a second important element of our foundation is building first-class relationships. Clearly the most critical of those relationships is with our customers and we'll achieve that by producing great vehicles. However also we need positive lasting relationships with our dealers, communities, union partners, employees and suppliers. A good example of how we are approaching this is within our purchasing organization. We are committed to doing a better job of engaging our suppliers with new ideas and solutions, and our vehicle development process and driving mutual success. We want our suppliers to be healthy. So when suppliers had cash problems last year, we developed a plan in the fourth quarter to pay them weekly instead of monthly. We also changed the process of handling savings that came from suppliers' suggestions and we now share 50/50 in those savings.</p>
          <p>Probably the most important thing we are doing in this space is working to rebuild relationships with our dealers. Our dealers need to provide an experience as outstanding as the quality of the products that we produce. Our senior leadership team has been on the road in recent weeks talking to and engaging with our dealers.</p>
          <p>Another key business goal is to become a workplace of choice. We currently employ 207,000 employees worldwide and approximately 77,000 here in the U.S., critical jobs at a time of significant unemployment in this country.</p>
          <p>Clearly one of the most important measures in establishing the foundation for going public is returning the company to profitability. As you know, we are filing our results today for the period ended December last year. While these are now somewhat dated they give you some sense of the financial hill we intend to climb. As shown on slide five for the fourth quarter we lost $4 billion at the earnings before interest and tax level; we'll call that EBIT from now on, on revenue of just over $32 billion. At the net income level we lost $3.4 billion.</p>
          <p>Our net cash provided by operating activities in the fourth quarter was negative $1.9 billion largely related to negative working capital due to changes in supplier payment terms.</p>
          <p>For the period from July 10th through December 31st, we lost $4.8 billion at the EBIT level on revenue of $57.5 billion, and at the net level we lost $4.3 billion. This loss includes the pre-tax impact of a 2.6 billion settlement loss related to the UAW retiree medical plan and a $1.3 billion foreign currency re-measurement loss.</p>
          <p>Net cash provided by operating activities for the period was positive 1.0 billion, largely related to favorable working capital but also reflecting an improving cash position.</p>
          <p>If you look at slide six, a closer look at the fourth quarter EBIT loss as shown there indicates that most of the EBIT loss was in North America. GM North America's Q4 EBIT was a loss of $3.4 billion on revenue of 18.3 billion. Results were impacted by depressed industry conditions as evidenced by the Q4 U.S. industry SAAR of 11.2 million units. Also included in the EBIT loss of $3.4 billion is the previously mentioned 2.6 billion settlement loss related to the UAW retiree medical plan, foreign currency re-measurements of about 0.4 billion and dealer wind down charges of $100 million related to the Saturn brand.</p>
          <p>GM Europe recognized an EBIT loss of $0.8 billion on revenue of 6.3 billion in the fourth quarter. Results were reflective of the continued depressed industry conditions as the fourth quarter total European industry of 19.6 million units continue to run below recent trends, despite scrappage campaigns in certain Western European countries running for all the parts of the quarter. Volumes in Central and Eastern Europe were particularly depressed.</p>
          <p>As you might know Opel and Vauxhall announced in February a five-year, 11 billion euro plan for the future that will reinvigorate 80% of the Opel/Vauxhall car lines and place a strong emphasis on alternative propulsion. This includes eight major launches in 2010 and another four in 2011. And adjusted to the current and forecasted market environment, Opel and Vauxhall will reduce its capacity by approximately 20%.</p>
          <p>General Motors International Operations, GMIO, was profitable for Q4 and reported an EBIT of 0.7 billion on revenue of 9.1 billion. GMIO benefited from strength in the international markets, in particular China, which ran at a record fourth quarter industry of 15.7 million units. And Brazil, which also set a new industry sales record for the fourth quarter within industry of 3.15 million units.</p>
          <p>Included in GMIO results, is equity income of $300 million, primarily related to the Shanghai General Motors and SAIC-GM-Wuling Automobile Company joint ventures.</p>
          <p>As I said to some media representatives at a breakfast a couple of weeks ago, despite the results that you've seen for the fourth quarter, I believe we have a chance at achieving profitability this year, at least at the operating level. This is a long way from the results that we're showing for last year but reflects the progress that we intend to make in the marketplace and on our cost structure.</p>
          <p>I'll give you a much better sense of how that progress is translating into financial results in mid-May, when we released our first quarter earnings, which are obviously much more timely. But I'm very happy with the progress we made in Q1 towards the goal of profitability.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide seven, our other financial goal is to return the company to a strong investment grade credit rating. That will likely take some years, but will provide us with a sustainable financial strength to prosper in good times and survive in tough ones. General Motors should never again be in the financial position that it found itself in last year.</p>
          <p>For quarter four our total cash and marketable securities, including government escrow, ended at $36.2 billion. This was a result of net cash used in operating activities and the repayment of United States Treasury and Export Development Canada loan payments of $1.2 billion, German bridge loan repayment of $1.3 billion, and payments related to Delphi of $2.8 billion.</p>
          <p>GM has reduced its overall debt, resulting in a year-end 2009 balance of 15.8 billion of book value and approximately 17.4 billion at face value.</p>
          <p>In addition, however, we have a number of other obligations. We have preferred stock with a book value of seven billion and a face value of nine billion that we issued to the UAW VEBA trust and the United States and Canadian governments.</p>
          <p>On a global basis, pensions were also under-funded 27.5 billion at year-end, and of this the U.S. qualified pension plans were under-funded by approximately 16 billion. Finally, our OPEB obligations have been significantly reduced to 9.6 billion at year-end 2009, as responsible for UAW retiree healthcare transferred to UAW VEBA trust.</p>
          <p>Remaining in the OPEB liability is 5.8 billion related to U.S. plans, which primarily consisted UAW Life Insurance and pre-65 retiree healthcare.</p>
          <p>Finally, over the last few months, we've dedicated an enormous amount of time and resources to ensure the integrity and reliability about public reporting. We're taking a big first step with the completion of fresh-start accounting today. This was a critical part of establishing the foundation for going public, so what I'd like to do now is hand it over to our Chief Accounting Officer, Nick Cyprus, who will speak for a few minutes on fresh-start accounting, the process and the results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chris, and good morning. I wanted to take a few &#x2013; I wanted to cover a few key areas you will see in our 10-K, which is going to be filed later today. Slide eight of our deck talks to the 363 transaction and fresh-start accounting.</p>
          <p>Fresh-start accounting was required as a result of a 363 sale. 363 is simply a section of the bankruptcy code which enables a bankrupt company to sell assets to a third-party purchaser, generally free of any liens or encumbrances. Fresh-start means just that. The company's financials are restarted; balance sheet is created; and all assets, liabilities and equities are reset to fair value. The difference between the fair value of the new company and the book value of the predecessor company are recorded as part of the reorganization gain line in the predecessor company's July 9 income statement. We, working with outside professionals, completed this valuation; adjusting more than one million records in our sub-ledgers and ledgers. This was a major undertaking for the company and our first step in preparing to take GM public.</p>
          <p>What I'd like to cover briefly now on slide nine covers the reorganization gain, how it was derived and reviews some of the key fresh-start balance sheet items. The reorganization gain is shown on the predecessor company's, old GM if you will, income statement. The gain on the reorganization of GM is $128 billion, composed of the following adjustments: 83 billion associated with the reduction of debt and other obligations, which were extinguished or exchanged for 20 billion in common stock, preferred stock and warrants; 33 billion associated with the change in the net assets between old and new GM from the application of fresh-start; an $8 billion benefit from the reduction of the OPEB liability related to the revised UAW settlement agreement; and a 4 billion benefit associated with the modification of other employee benefit plans. These fresh-start adjustments are described in detail in footnote two of the 10-K we will file later.</p>
          <p>The new GM emerges from fresh-start accounting with 142 billion in assets. The largest asset is goodwill. Normally goodwill results when the purchase price or economic value of the company exceeds the fair value of the asset. This was not the case here. In our case we did not generate economic goodwill, i.e. total liabilities plus equity did not exceed the fully valued assets. The reason the company has goodwill is solely an accounting exercise.</p>
          <p>The majority of the goodwill results from the difference between the fair value of the new GM pension obligation which includes &#x2013; which is included in the company's equity valuation and the GAAP value of the pension obligation. The fair value of the pension obligation is determined by discounting the pension cash flows at a CCC discount rate. The GAAP value prescribes a AA rate for discounting the expected benefit payments. The difference between the pension obligation between these two methods is $20 billion. In order to account for this difference, you record an incremental asset as goodwill and add the incremental liability to the fair value pension obligation. Between pension and OPEB, 24 billion of goodwill was added.</p>
          <p>There is an additional six billion added for deferred tax assets related to NOLs, which had an economic value over book due to GAAP requiring a valuation allowance reducing the deferred tax asset recorded on the books. So an entry is required to record goodwill and a deferred tax valuation allowance for six billion. The combination of these equals $30 billion.</p>
          <p>The new GM also added intangible assets of $16 billion associated with technology, brands and dealer networks. GM emerges with lower property, plant and equipment. It was reduced by about $18 billion for a new balance of $19 billion at 7/10.</p>
          <p>The new GM has equity and cost-based investments valued at 7/10 of $8 trillion. These include our investments in China with SGM and GMAC.</p>
          <p>I would like to close the session with a brief summary of the internal control improvement that we've made at GM. Item 9A disclosures in our 10-K indicate the many improvements we've made to internal controls during 2009 in spite of all the activities that were going on. We believe that these remediation activities would have been sufficient to allow us to conclude that the previously identified material weakness in the period and financial recording process no longer existed.</p>
          <p>However, as discussed in Note 2 of the 10-K, there were many activities that took place during 2009: Chapter 11 bankruptcy, 363 sale taking place mid month and of course, fresh-start accounting. Because of this activity, we introduced additional controls designed to ensure the accuracy and completeness of our fresh-start accounting. The sheer volume and complexity of all these activities did not allow management clear visibility to the operational effectiveness of the newly remediated controls within the period end financial reporting process, and in some cases management was unable to meet these &#x2013; unable to test these remediated controls.</p>
          <p>So while we believe we have remediated this material weakness because of our inability to observe and sufficiently test all these remediated controls, we concluded that a material weakness in the period end financial reporting process still existed at 12/31/09. We do expect to list this material weakness when we've had adequate time to test these controls and ensure that they are functioning properly.</p>
          <p>It is expected that this will happen prior to any initial public offering. And with that I'll turn it back to Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Nick. Turning to slide 10, we take very seriously the commitment to our current shareholders. The first thing that we need to do is pay back the U.S. Treasury an Export Development Canada loans that were extended last year. Of the original loans of $8.4 billion, we've paid back 2.8 billion plus full interest. We are committed to repaying the balance off by June of this year, significantly ahead of the original repayment schedule.</p>
          <p>After we repay the loans, we owe to our shareholders to complete a successful public offering as soon as it makes sense. I know there's a huge interest in when that actually might be and the best I can indicate is when the markets and when the company are ready. There are some variables that are outside of our controls, for example the readiness of the financial markets and the state of the global auto industry. However, just as important will be the progress we've made on the foundation that I've outlined above.</p>
          <p>Some parts like fresh-start accounting were completed. And I'd like to pause here to compliment Nick on his and his team's great work in achieving that. We were &#x2013; I met with some of his team last night and we were trying to determine exactly how many man-years, in this case we measure it in years, had gone into the process of fresh-start accounting.</p>
          <p>And this is a non-GAAP number, unaudited, but it's something in excess of 1,000 man years we believe of effort have gone in to producing a document, which you'll see later today, which currently runs at 322 pages; so a huge effort. For other things that we need to achieve in order to go public, we still have a long way to go.</p>
          <p>Having said that, I'd like to conclude by mentioning our leadership team as shown on slide 11. Since Ed Whitacre was named CEO in December 2009, he has assembled a 13 member Executive Committee made up of seasoned GM veterans as well as newcomers from outside the industry. 12 of the 13 Executive Committee members are new to the company or in new positions since July of last year. It will be this team that has the responsibility of delivering the elements we've talked about. Everyone clearly knows what they are responsible for and everyone is aligned on the vision of designing, building and selling the world's best vehicles.</p>
          <p>The combination of non-automotive and automotive expertise is providing a healthy mix of experience and perspectives, and we're united in one goal which is returning General Motors to the great company we know that it can be. As the year unfolds, I am increasingly confident that we are on the right track.</p>
          <p>With that overview, I'm going to hand it back to Randy to let it &#x2013; let him open it up for your questions. I'm happy to take any mix &#x2013; obviously happy to take any &#x2013; and I've also got Ray Young who is the CFO now of our International Operations; and Chuck Stevens who is the CFO of our North American operations here, and they could help you out on any questions on their particular area that you might be interested; and Walter Borst, who is our Treasurer as well in any capital markets questions.</p>
          <p>So plenty of people here delighted to take whatever questions you have of us over the next 20 minutes or so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Chris. Operator, we are ready to open up for Q&amp;A. I would just ask everyone to try to keep it to one question if they could. Ready to go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, we will now proceed with the analyst portion of the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question comes from the line of Himanshu Patel, JPMorgan. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I wanted to know first, is there any impact on GM healthcare liabilities from the new healthcare bill?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as we can determine &#x2013; and we are obviously waiting for the final word, as far as we can determine it will be modest. So, modest to negligible. So we don't expect to have anything in the first quarter by way of a significant charge, I know some other companies are looking at that. But at this stage we are not expecting to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's because we are out of post-65 healthcare, pretty much out of that business, with the UAW, with the OPEB settlement, the big obligations are behind us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I think you guys had mentioned before a 1.3 billion foreign exchange hit, but I think you said about 400 million of that showed up in North America. What was &#x2013; where was the balance? In which division would that have shown up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, one number was for the quarter and the other number was for the whole period, so some additional proportion would be in North America as well and the balance would have been in Europe in particular with some of the foreign exchange movements there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then lastly, is it possible to give us kind of a walk from the third quarter to the fourth quarter for North America excluding one-time charges?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A walk in the sense of...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just key drivers, how much was contributed by volume, price changes, cost savings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, what I'm prepared to do especially since you &#x2013; that sounds like the third of the one question, but that level of detail &#x2013; happy to give that, but we'll have some follow-up after the call and either myself or Chuck will be happy to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Rod Lache from Deutsche Bank. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. Just wanted to get a couple of housekeeping things. First of all, just to clarify, the 2.9 billion of one-timers that you outlined, the 400 million, 2.6 billion and 100 million for Saturn, that was all in the fourth quarter in North America. Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And can we get an EBITDA by region or at least just depreciation and amortization by region? Is that available?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can certainly do that. I'll follow-up again with that level of detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the net operating cash flow that you are disclosing here, I assume that's not GAAP &#x2013; what would that number look like before the one-timers like Delphi and restructuring?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is GAAP. That is our GAAP number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a GAAP cash from operations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct, yes. I am &#x2013; in particular, you'll see perhaps a change somewhat &#x2013; I will be &#x2013; when I give numbers out I am going to be definitely orientating our external reporting to GAAP. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So is that --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll provide reconciliations there afterwards, but that is the GAAP number that you'll see in the 10-K coming up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's cash from operations before CapEx?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct, that's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, what was CapEx then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>CapEx was 1.7 billion in the July 10 through December 31 period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, 1.7 billion in the full period. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What's the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, we are going to limit this to one per &#x2013; one question per person to give everyone a chance. And can I just ask people, it's probably a change in the theme, but if you've got really specific line item by line item questions that's really the sort of thing that we can handle after the call. I'd much rather concentrate the time that we have on this call on major themes or significant issues. If you need a specific data point, let's follow-up afterwards rather than use the valuable time on the call for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Brian Johnson with Barclays Capital. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. On that note, can you give us a sense of when you go from the fourth quarter loss to the possibility of an operating gain in 2010 especially in North America, how much are you dependent on industry volume, market share and how much is going to be on the cost side or the product pricing side? On product pricing, does Toyota moves put some of that at risk?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. If you look at the fourth quarter and you back out the large items that we talked about, you will see that the EBIT was actually relatively close to breakeven excluding those. So the starting point from a headline GAAP number is quite negative, but the underlying profitability is actually not as bad as it would seem, and when you look at the cash flows you get some sense of that as well. So we don't need to make that much improvement to get to profitability; that's the positive side of things.</p>
          <p>In terms of taking costs out, that will certainly help during the course of the year and we continue on that, particularly in some of the areas like overhead where we're continuing to look for areas of saving. Clearly, incentives are likely year-over-year to be down and that will help as well. Toyota actions are &#x2013; have some impact on that but not in total. As you saw in March, our incentives were actually below the industry average for the first time -- a lot of people around the table, the first time they've seen that in a number of years. So our incentive levels are quite low. So in my view, we don't need the industry to be significantly better in order to achieve the potential for profitability.</p>
          <p>Having said that, the way the year is shaking out is the industry is looking better and that's helping as well, in particular in markets that are outside North America, but increasingly in North America as well. When we look to markets for example in China, that continues to be very strong, and that's certainly helping us from a profitability point of view.</p>
          <p>So I don't believe we need significant industry improvement to get to profitability, but it's certainly going to be part of the answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, is there a market share line in the sand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I see market share as an output, not an input.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of John Murphy with Bank of America. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Slide 4 is interesting. You have a lot of partners and relationships on here. One that doesn't appear to be on here though is the relationship with GMAC or your financing partners. I was just wondering where that relationship stands at this point, how maybe you're accounting or thinking about the zero percent financing or sub-vented loans and leases and if that relationship is working very well or if you'd really like to have this company or that division back inside of GM?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, GMAC is certainly not meant to be left off the list on purpose. The relationship is incredibly important. And clearly their return to health is very important from our point of view. I don't &#x2013; there's arguments for having a captive finance industry &#x2013; captive finance subsidiary, there's arguments against it. Where that will come down on balance, we'll see.</p>
          <p>But from my point of view, the key thing is that we have a strong partnership. And we are continually in discussions with GMAC on how we might develop the business on a partnership basis. Seeing them return to health and seeing certainly their leasing activity continue over time is incredibly important for us. But I don't think it's necessary per se to own them for that to happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Chris -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's certainly important from a partnership point of view, very important.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just one quick follow-up question on that profitability for &#x2013; potential for profitability in 2010. I mean it looks like you guys in North America were getting close to breakeven with just a 61.5% cap-ut rate, capacity utilization rate. What kind of capacity utilization rate &#x2013; forget about the industry metrics and all that stuff &#x2013; do you think you need in North America to maintain breakeven or maybe create profitability, because that's a very low number at this point to be breaking even at?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you've seen we are adding third shifts. I think we now have them in Chuck, five plants? So our capacity utilization will progressively increase. I don't think there is a number we are putting out there that is &#x2013; we achieve breakeven at X percent, but you will see us progressively increasing our capacity utilization as we already have in particular as some of the new models come on stream. And at the moment, we are having to increase some of the capacity to make up for some of the lines where we have particularly short inventory in North America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Patrick Archambault with Goldman Sachs. Please proceed with your question. Mr. Archambault?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick, are you there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was an easy one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You must've been on mute, we can hear you now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I apologize. Yeah, my question was on fresh-start accounting, a couple items. How much is &#x2013; now that you've done all the math, how much is the sort of ongoing non-cash impact of fresh-start accounting that you're going to see at the EBIT level on a go-forward basis?</p>
          <p>Number two, how much of that was in the fourth quarter numbers that you reported on page six?</p>
          <p>And I guess question number three is, on a go-forward basis seeing that that's non-cash and will tend to sort of exaggerate your D&amp;A beyond where it has traditionally run, how are you guys &#x2013; are you going to present that &#x2013; how are you going to present that to us when you report quarters in the future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, a couple of things, number one, I caution you to do the same thing with your models that I did with the accounting. In other words, what you want to do is you want to fresh-start your models, okay, so that we don't start giving out these numbers for fresh-start. This is part of our new financial statements as we go forward.</p>
          <p>Two, if you looked at what I did, yes, we did put on a significant amount of intangibles but we also reduced a significant amount of the PP&amp;E. And so you're going to get greater amortization and it probably will be somewhat in excess of the benefit of depreciation going down, but it won't be as huge. So you could expect more amortization expense. This will be fully disclosed. And as you start going period to period, you can build your model to understand how that works. But to go into detail and start saying fresh-start is a unique event is probably not somewhere we are going to go. But you'll be able to look at the financial statements, watch the rhythm of the numbers, and pick right up on it. So I'd suggest just fresh-starting the model.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I endorse that. Rather than spending all of our time trying to reconcile every quarter from now on back to where it would have been in fresh-start accounting, we have to use this as an opportunity to restart just as we are in every aspect of what we're doing in the company. And Nick and I are going to be working on a package of information from the first quarter onwards that basically is different to the way that you will have seen it. I think it's going to be much more informative and useful from your point of view, but you'll certainly always have all of the detail produced. So if you want to reconcile it back to whatever line it is, EBITDAR in particular I think is clearly one that you can look at, then that will all be available. So this is a great chance to restart a number of things with the company, one of which is how we look at financial accounting from now on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So with that Randy, maybe we might transition to media?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Operator, if we could go to the media Q&amp;A we would appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, we will now proceed with the media portion of question and answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first media question comes from the line of Dee-Ann Durbin with The Associated Press. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I'm wondering if anybody can comment on the UAW lawsuit that was filed yesterday saying that GM owes the UAW $450 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I prefer not to comment on that. I mean obviously we are aware of it and it's &#x2013; but given it's a legal case I don't think it's appropriate for me to comment on this call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I apologize for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Phil LeBeau with CNBC. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Chris. When you take a look at your cash on hand at the end of last year and the cash flow, what's your outlook for the first quarter, how comfortable are you with the way the cash flow is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I feel very good about that, Phil, and I think I might have mentioned this at the breakfast we had a few weeks ago, I think the cash position is actually very strong. Now, we have a number of obligations that we need to meet over future years, so I'm not minimizing that particular. Clearly we need to get the pension fully funded over time and we need to repay debts starting with the government loans that I talked about in my prepared script. But starting from a base of $36 billion this year, I actually feel very good about our financial position going into this year, and nothing has changed in the first quarter to change that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of David Welch with the Bloomberg News. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chris. You said that you are pretty confident you should be able to turn a profit this year at least on an EBIT basis. Considering you guys weren't that far off from breakeven for Q4 and you've added some production in the first quarter and even recently, seems like you should be able to pull that out of the water. What could stop you from making money this year? I mean, the economy is rebounding a bit. Can you get into that a little bit further?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I am the financial guy. So, yeah, I think I said possible, you said pretty confident. Look -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. But still, I mean, I was thinking you guys should be able to hammer this one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there is a danger and this company has possibly been guilty of this in the past of over promising and under delivering. I would rather turn that around the other way; I would rather under promise and hopefully over deliver. When we put the runs on the board, we will come out and tell you about them. I don't want to sit here and predict profitability or anything like it and then disappoint. I'd love to see those runs on the board.</p>
          <p>The only thing that I can say of a positive nature is there's nothing that I've seen in the first quarter which you'll see in a month's time that changes my opinion that there is a good chance that we will be profitable this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you're just being a bit coy in other words.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I beg your pardon, sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You're being a bit coy on your profit outlook in other words.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Those are your words, not mine. Look, I'd rather stick &#x2013; I'd rather under promise and hopefully over deliver. There are lots of things that we need to continue to do in order to be profitable and it's one step along the road, but it's an important step. But in terms of the hard work that's gone on before I joined this company, to be honest, last year, in particular, in terms of taking costs out, in terms of restructuring the company, in terms of setting us up for success, I am actually really encouraged by what's being done and how I think that's unfolding this year. So I am as positive as you will hear me, Dave. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And by the way the VEBA cost, is that 2.6 or 2.4 billion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>2.6.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>From one-timer, 2.6?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>2.6, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Chris Isidore with CNNMoney. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Chris, I just want to make sure I'm clear, you're saying that you weren't that far off from breaking even in the fourth quarter on EBITDA, but I'm looking at what, three, 3.5 on a EBITDA basis or three, 3.4 on an EBITDA basis in the fourth quarter. Is there a different number when you're &#x2013; what you get from stripping other things out, kind of an included items type number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe I referred to EBIT, and I think you might have said EBITDA although it's a little unclear on the line -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...but if you look at EBIT, EBITDA obviously will look even better than this. But EBIT in the fourth quarter was negative 3.4 billion but we &#x2013; what we showed in that &#x2013; I beg your pardon, four billion but included in that was $3.4 billion of items which you might deem to be special, I'm not calling them that but I'm calling them out, for example the 2.6 that we just mentioned at the VEBA. So if you took the 3.4 away from the four you would still be negative but it would be 0.6 billion. That's the point that I was making that is, it's getting close to breakeven if you exclude some of those one-off items that happened in the fourth quarter. That was the reference I was making. Is that more clear?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, okay. So excluding &#x2013; if you exclude one-off items, it's about 600 million --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Still negative, but clearly in the context of the size of this company getting closer to breakeven than the headline GAAP numbers would suggest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay. That's what I was looking for, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we might have quick time for one more &#x2013; or are we finished, Randy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take one more if it's available, otherwise we will wrap.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>One moment please for the next question. Okay, Mr. Arickx I will turn the call back to you, please continue with your presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, operator. We appreciate everyone's time this morning. We look forward to talking to you in the middle of May with Q1 results. Thanks everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that does conclude the conference call for today. We thank you for your participation and ask that you please disconnect your lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>