<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1432648" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-10-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8961</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial &amp; Administrative Officer">Daniel Mu&#xF1;iz Quintanilla</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer of Ferrocarril Mexicano SA de CV and Ferrosur SA de CV, Grupo M&#xE9;xico, S.A.B. de C.V.">Rogelio Velez Lopez de la Cerda</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Ita&#xFA; Corretora de Valores SA">Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Manager-Financial Planning &amp; Investor Relations, Southern Copper Corp.">Raul Jacob</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Rene M. Kleyweg</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Societe Generale">Jordi Dominguez</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep" affiliation="General Director-Corporate Security">Rafael R&#xED;os Garc&#xED;a</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Actinver Casa de Bolsa SA de CV">Karla Beatriz Pe&#xF1;a</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co., Inc.">Mandeep Singh</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Santander Central Hispano Investment">Sergio Matsumoto</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Oscar Gonz&#xE1;lez Rocha</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, and welcome to Grupo M&#xE9;xico's Third Quarter Earnings Conference Call. With us this afternoon is Mr. Daniel Mu&#xF1;iz, Chief Financial Officer; and other executives of the company, who will discuss its financial performance of the company during the quarter along with a summary of the latest news.</p>
          <p>At the end of the presentation, we will answer any questions you may have. The information discussed on today's call may include forward-looking statements regarding the company's results and prospects, which are subject to risks and uncertainties. Actual results may differ materially and the company cautions not to place undue reliance on these forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Grupo M&#xE9;xico undertakes no obligation to publicly update or revise any forward-looking statements, whether as a result of new information, future events or otherwise. All results are expressed in full U.S. GAAP.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Now, I will pass the call on to Mr. Daniel Mu&#xF1;iz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Pam, thank you.</p>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you for joining us today in Grupo M&#xE9;xico's third quarter earnings conference call. Joining me today are Mr. Rogelio Velez, CEO of Grupo Ferroviario Mexicano; Jorge Pulido, our Head of Investor Relations; and other executives of the company.</p>
          <p>On today's conference call, I will briefly comment on the economic environment of this quarter and the main issues impacting the company's profitability. Then, I'll comment on our Mining Division's most relevant results, to pass on the call to Rogelio, who will explain the financial results of our Transportation Division.</p>
          <p>Getting to metal prices, the health of the financial markets, volatility and risk aversion have been the main drivers of metal markets this quarter, which were affected by different macroeconomic events that caused a significant correction in prices and are somewhat delaying recovery of metal demand.</p>
          <p>The most important macro events are the U.S. economic troubles, collapsed business confidence. Since the U.S. economy is about 25% of the total world economy, any of its macro problems creates concerns in the rest of the world. The European sovereign debt crisis, which affects the confidence of investors, the economic stability, and lower growth expectations of this region. On Chinese and other emerging economies' anti-inflation programs, which may reduce the respective growth.</p>
          <p>As a result, copper prices dropped more than US$2,000 per ton or US$0.95 per pound from late August until early October. This was in fears of major global economic collapse.</p>
          <p>On the positive side, events of recent weeks have not altered our underlying views on copper. On the contrary, we have seen a decoupling between financial markets and the physical ones, and we are very confident on copper fundamentals.</p>
          <p>During October, prices have rebounded approximately US$0.50 per pound, as scrap merchants withhold material after a 25% price drop. Strikes have continued in diverse jurisdictions, ore grades have continued to decline throughout the mining spectrum, and copper inventories dropped by 10% at main metal exchanges.</p>
          <p>We are one of the lowest-cost producers of copper, and our confidence is strong in our ability to operate under the current economic conditions, although we anticipate constrained production growth matched with increased consumption.</p>
          <p>For the first time in many years, revenues from silver were higher than those from molybdenum, when talking about our byproducts, making silver our most important byproduct for the third quarter 2011 and year-to-date, representing nearly 7% of our Mining Division's sales.</p>
          <p>Molybdenum accounted for 6% of total mining revenues. We believe that molybdenum prices are close to bottom and by mid-November could bend back.</p>
          <p>Average silver prices in the third quarter were US$38.76 per ounce, nearly 105% above the average for 2010, while average molybdenum prices in the third quarter of 2011 were US$14.44 per pound, 3% below the average for 2010.</p>
          <p>Now, turning into Grupo M&#xE9;xico's financial highlights, in the third quarter 2011, our total consolidated revenues were US$2.7 billion, an increase of 32% year-over-year. Net sales year-to-date were over US$7.9 billion, an increase of 32% year-over-year. This increase is mainly due to higher metal prices, higher copper sales volume as a result of the full production at Buenavista mine, and despite that revenue at AMC levels were affected by US$109 million due to traditional sales, which as you know, is customary in this industry. Our Transportation Division also increased revenues by 18% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Cost of sales for the third quarter was US$1.3 billion, an increase of 22% on a year-over-year basis and nearly 2% above second quarter 2011. This cost increase of US$235 million is mainly explained by higher prices in power and fuel, increasing 34% year-over-year; purchase of concentrates and maintenance costs. The company will continue its efforts of reducing costs, improving productivity, and maintaining consumption and expense discipline, with a goal of strengthening our position as one of the world's leading lower-cost producers.</p>
          <p>We are happy to report that we achieved a record-high EBITDA in the third quarter of US$1.4 billion, with an EBITDA margin of 52%. This figure represents a significant improvement of 50% year-over-year, out of which US$1 billion came from Southern Copper, with a margin of 59% of sales, an increase of 55% over the third quarter 2010.</p>
          <p>EBITDA for Asarco reached US$203 million, equivalent to a little south to 40% of sales. EBITDA for the Transportation Division reached US$116 million, equivalent to 27% of sales.</p>
          <p>EBITDA year-to-date was US$3.9 billion, an increase of 45% year-over-year, out of which US$2.9 billion came from Southern Copper, US$610 million from Asarco and US$351 million from our ITM Transportation Division.</p>
          <p>Net income in the third quarter was US$693 million, a significant increase of 74% year-over-year and almost 6% higher quarter-over-quarter. Net income accumulated in the first nine months was US$1.8 billion, an increase of 75% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Year-to-date CapEx amounted to US$738 million, 96% increase year-over-year, of which US$396 million was spent in the Mining Division and US$249 million in our Transportation Division, the balance in our Infrastructure Division.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditures in the Mining Division have been lower than expected, as a result of the temporary expansion of the Tia Maria project in Peru. Our capital budget has been approved and is mainly waiting on the resolution of the Peruvian Government. We're actively negotiating with the communities and the government to reach a mutual satisfactory agreement. In the meantime, we've been active in the pursuit of greater value for our existing mines. As you know, we have the world's largest copper reserves and what's driving our strategy is converting them into cash flow productive assets. Our confidence on copper fundamentals allows us to continue our CapEx plans.</p>
          <p>In the Transportation Division, investments are moving forward as planned. We continue to focus investments mainly in locomotives and infrastructure, with significant CapEx of US$249 million spent year-to-date; that is 273% higher than the previous year.</p>
          <p>The total consolidated debt at September 30 amounted to nearly US$3.9 billion, with a cash balance of US$2.6 billion. The company's net debt stands at US$1.2 billion.</p>
          <p>Grupo M&#xE9;xico maintains a healthy balance sheet with a low leverage, while its total debt-to-EBITDA ratio is 0.74 times, with which the company can access markets without putting its credit rating at risk. In addition, healthy cash flows and comfortable debt amortization schedule with maturities for US$400 million not occurring until 2020 afford the company financial flexibility to take advantage of opportunities in the market and to ensure our growth.</p>
          <p>With respect to dividends, on August 19, we paid a dividend of US$0.45 pesos per share outstanding, that was equivalent to US$296 million. On October 28, the Board of Directors approved a dividend payment in cash of US$0.40 pesos per share and that dividend payment in kind consisted of one share for every 389 shares outstanding, which will be paid on November 14.</p>
          <p>I will now discuss the main developments of Americas Mining Corporation, the entity that consolidates both of our subsidiaries, Southern Copper and Asarco. AMC's mine copper production in the third quarter increased 15% to 203,917 tons, compared to 177,968 tons in the third quarter 2010. This increase was again, mainly due to the restart of our Buenavista mine, which has been operating at its maximum capacity since April, producing a little bit south of 50,000 tons in the third quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>Asarco's mine copper in the third quarter 2011 decreased 8% year-over-year. However, production increased 5% quarter-over-quarter due to higher ore grade, which we expect to continue during the fourth quarter 2011.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter 2011, molybdenum production decreased by 4% to 4,787 tons compared to 5,009 tons in the third quarter 2010, but 6% above the second quarter. It was due mainly to expected improvement in ore grades at the mines in Peru and better recoveries at La Caridad mine, which we expect to continue improving as well during the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Our Mining Division has invested US$396 million over the first nine months of the year, 32% over the previous year. In order to be mindful of your time, I will not give a breakdown of Southern Copper's CapEx for the quarter; Southern Copper had its conference call just earlier today.</p>
          <p>Asarco's CapEx for the first nine months of the year were US$59 million, 209% over the previous year, and it was mainly attributable to maintenance projects at the smelter, refinery, and the replacement of mine equipment and for the expansion of operations at Mission and Ray mines.</p>
          <p>The consolidated AMC operating cash cost per pound of copper, including the benefit of byproduct credits, was US$0.778 per pound in the third quarter 2011 compared to US$0.671 per pound in the third quarter 2010. This increase is primarily due to lower returns on the byproducts, higher fuel and energy costs.</p>
          <p>However, Americas Mining's third quarter 2011 operating cash cost per pound of copper produced before byproduct credits was US$1.79 per pound. This cash cost compares to US$1.80 for the second quarter 2011.</p>
          <p>With this, I'll now pass on the call to Rogelio Velez who will discuss the main financial highlights of our Transportation Division. Rogelio, please, if you will.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Daniel, and good afternoon to everyone. Today, I will talk about the main developments during the third quarter and year-to-date of our Transport Division, represented by the holding company Infraestructura y Transportes M&#xE9;xico (ITM) and its principal subsidiaries, Grupo Ferroviario Mexicano, Ferrocarril Mexicano, Ferromex and Ferrosur.</p>
          <p>ITM's load volumes transported during the first nine months of this year, measured in net tons-kilometer, were US$39.2 billion compared to US$39.4 billion in 2010, representing a marginal decrease of only 0.5 percentage point.</p>
          <p>The 2011 volumes have totally been affected by the Agriculture segment, due to crop damages during the first half of the year, but compensated positively by an important increase of 32% in the Intermodal segment and increases as well in minerals, energy, chemicals, and the steel segments.</p>
          <p>Ferromex's load volumes as of September of this year were US$33.8 billion net tons-kilometer compared to US$34.1 billion during the same period of 2010, a reduction of 1.1%, all attributable to the Ag segment.</p>
          <p>In terms of cars transported, Ferromex moved 644,158 railcars during the nine-month period, compared to 611,308 railcars moved in the same period of 2010, an increase of over 5%. The main increases were seen in the Intermodal segment, reporting a 34% increase in net tons-kilometer and 24% in containers; the mineral and chemicals segments, with increases in net tons-kilometers of over 8% and railcars more than 19%.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter 2011, Ferromex transported a new record of 225,382 railcars, 8% over the previous year and previous record.</p>
          <p>Ferrosur's load volumes during the first nine months of this year were 5.5 billion net tons-kilometers compared to 5.3 billion in 2010, representing an increase of 2.8%. In terms of cars transported during the year, Ferrosur has moved 214,084 railcars compared to 199,102 railcars moved during the same period of 2010, an increase of 7.5%.</p>
          <p>The main gains were seen in the Metals segment with 41% in net tons-kilometers and 28% in cars; and also the Energy and Automotive segments which increased net tons-kilometers by 18% and 16%, and cars by 20% and 11% respectively.</p>
          <p>ITM net sales as of September of this year were over US$1.2 billion, representing an increase of 16% versus the same period of 2010, with main increases coming from the Intermodal traffic, which rose 45%, Energy 29%, and Minerals and Metals were 28%.</p>
          <p>Ferromex's net sales reached US$1 billion over the first nine months of this year, an increase of 15% above the US$870 million in the same period of 2010. During the third quarter 2011, net sales were US$354 million, 17% above the US$301 million recorded in the third quarter a year ago.</p>
          <p>Ferrosur's net sales as of September were US$237 million, an increase of 17% above the US$203 million in the same period of 2010. During the third quarter 2011, Ferrosur again set a new sales record with US$81 million, a 16% growth compared to the previous year and 1% above the previous record set in the second quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>ITM's operating cost for the nine-month period was US$857 million, an increase of 22% compared with the same period in 2010, mainly attributable to import increases in the cost of diesel, labor, maintenance, and terminal services. For the third quarter of 2011, cost was US$309 million, an increase of 25% year-on-year.</p>
          <p>ITM's EBITDA for the nine months in 2011 was US$351 million, 1.4% above the US$347 million of 2010. In the third quarter 2011, EBITDA was US$116 million, an increase of 2% year-on-year.</p>
          <p>Ferromex's EBITDA in the third quarter was US$92 million, just 1% shy of the US$93 million in the third quarter a year ago. Ferrosur's EBITDA in the third quarter was US$22 million, an increase of 13% above the US$19 million a year ago.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditures; the Railroad Division invested US$249 million over the first nine months of the year; US$211 million in Ferromex, including the acquisition of 44 locomotives; US$35 million in Ferrosur; and US$3 million in other subsidiaries. The total investment is 273% over the previous year. In the third quarter 2011, capital expenditures for Ferromex were US$49 million, 71% over the third quarter of 2010 and Ferrosur invested US$23 million, 304% over the third quarter a year ago. Both companies continue to focus their investments mainly in locomotives and rail infrastructure.</p>
          <p>I would now return the call to Daniel Mu&#xF1;iz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rogelio.</p>
          <p>To conclude, I would like to mention that regarding the combination of operations within Southern Copper and Asarco, a proposal that was delivered to the Board of Southern Copper on July 22, 2010. Grupo M&#xE9;xico's Board of Directors, after recent communications with Southern Copper's Committee of Independent Directors, have decided to maintain the value that Asarco represents to Americas Mining and withdraw its proposal to combine the operations of Asarco with those of Southern Copper.</p>
          <p>Asarco's assets are operating at full capacity in the U.S., probably arguably the lowest country risk. The results of the operations have been better than expected. We are actually expecting an EBITDA in excess of US$800 million for 2011. Over the past year, Asarco has carried out an <mark type="ph" /> expansive (19:14) exploration and drilling program, increasing its reserves 25%, and these reserves have the potential for further increases due to its ongoing exploration program.</p>
          <p>This gives Asarco's mines an average useful life of over 20 years &#x2013; 28 years in fact, longer than comparables. And the company has aggressive expansion plans, to increase its production 40% over the next four years, at a marginal cost of investment. Americas Mining as the holding company and Grupo M&#xE9;xico, I mean, will explore other strategic alternatives to create value through our both subsidiaries.</p>
          <p>And with this, we conclude the comments for the earnings results and we'll be happy to answer any questions you might have. Operator, we would like to open up the forum for questions, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. And your first question comes from the line of <mark type="ph" /> Santiago Berisso with BM (20:31).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Daniel, Jorge, and Rogelio Velez Lopez on these outstanding 3Q '11 results. My &#x2013; I have two questions. The first one is regarding your stock dividend. <mark type="ph" /> Your repeat trading (20:43) shares are made through our capital reduction? And my second question is relating to AMC, could you give us a light on CapEx guidance for 2012, along with Asarco's production guidance? And also, we would appreciate any comments on AMC's hedges and its strategy going forward? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, <mark type="ph" /> Santiago. (21:04) Thank you for the questions. I mean just good &#x2013; to start off on the dividend, we are distributing 20 million shares from our buyback program part of the dividend. So that is &#x2013; I mean shares that we have in the Treasury that will be distributed there in addition to the US$0.40 per outstanding share in cash.</p>
          <p>Regarding the hedging strategy, as we've pointed out, every quarter, we analyze the market, we analyze the prices, we analyze cash flow needs, et cetera and based on that, we decide on a hedge program going forward. For 2012, as you know, we've only hedged through callers at Asarco and Southern Copper and that has been only for the first quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>Just to give you an idea of the put and call levels, for AMC, if you look at it consolidated, our put is at US$3.50, and the call is at US$5.20, with hedged. If you look at it again, consolidated wise, only about 4.5% of the production. At the moment, we're not hedging and we &#x2013; I think at this point, we're going to wait until the next board and see what happens with the market to do this analysis. This past week's board, we are not deciding anything regarding hedges.</p>
          <p>And <mark type="ph" /> Santiago, (22:30) what was the last question you had? Yeah. Three, right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>AMC's CapEx guidance for 2012 and Asarco's production guidance, you would be able to give those, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean Asarco should be in line with this year, which is around 200,000 tons for next year. And in terms of CapEx, we will &#x2013; I mean as we pointed out in Southern Copper's conference call, we are tuning that particularly based on the delays and the situation with the permits and the projects. We'll be happy to report that the latest next conference call, if you don't mind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o with Ita&#xFA;.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, everybody. My question is, first, regarding the cash cost. What is your expectation regarding cash cost before byproduct for the fourth quarter? And also, can we expect higher copper and molybdenum volumes from the <mark type="ph" /> Bronx (23:34) and Cuajone mine already in next quarter as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think in terms of cash cost, I mean, as I pointed out, what we've been seeing is a lot of pressures from the &#x2013; I mean, from electricity, diesel and mainly power pressures. We expect for the fourth quarter pretty much to be in line on this, about US$1.80 roughly. I mean only that before byproducts? And I'm sorry, you broke up in your second question. Can you repeat that, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. If we can expect a higher copper and molyb volumes from the <mark type="ph" /> Bronx (24:10) and Cuajone mine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll let Raul Jacob comment on that, but what I'm happy to report is that yeah, we <mark type="ph" /> did got through as (24:19) lump in terms of the ore grades at Cuajone and that is turning around. Raul, do you want to expand there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I like to add to that &#x2013; Daniel and to the audience that we are progressing with the two projects that we have at Cuajone that are aimed to improve the production &#x2013; the copper production and molybdenum production of this mine. And the results of these two projects will be much clearer as we move on into the fourth quarter and particularly on the &#x2013; in 2012.</p>
          <p>By the second quarter of 2012, we should start seeing much, much clearly the improvement in production at Cuajone. At this point, we have one of the projects pretty much working, which is the <mark type="ph" /> payable kind of grade. (25:17) And the other one, which is the high-pressure grinding rolls should be up and running by the second half of next year. So, with both projects at full capacity, we'll be able to improve our production on Cuajone from where it is right now to a much better outcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Rene Kleyweg with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Afternoon, gentlemen. And could you touch on the thinking behind listing AMC separately in terms of how that would unlock value in terms of how you would create liquidity in that instrument, and how you would avoid a discount on AMC versus Southern Copper?</p>
          <p>And then, also if you could perhaps provide a little bit of color? I might have my numbers wrong, but the EBITDA for AMC is higher than the combined EBITDA of Southern Copper plus Asarco. Could you just give us a little bit more color on the additional sources of EBITDA generation for AMC? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Rene. Thank you. I mean, yes, I guess because of our views on strong profitability of Asarco in the future and our potential additional <mark type="ph" /> ancillary (26:42) created by the recent Delaware Chancery Court opinion, I mean, I guess the point here is, we are going to continue to explore strategic alternatives that better capitalize on the strength of our two subsidiaries. And I mean that's really where we are.</p>
          <p>I mean we are going to start analyzing ways to create value. Again, I do have a, I mean, corporate structure that has two great companies with a very world-class asset base and we are working on that. It doesn't mean that we are going to &#x2013; I mean that was kind of given as an example in our earnings release, but that's where we are. And the second question was, when you do the EBITDAs, and can you repeat that please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just the consolidated EBITDA of AMC is US$1.303 billion, the EBITDA of Asarco plus Southern Copper is US$77 million lower than that. I was just looking for a clarification on the additional EBITDA generation within AMC?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. That has to do mainly with the foreign exchange fluctuations and the deep relation of the pesos that you looked at. As you could probably remember, we even had the debt that we incurred in order to acquire, reorganize Asarco in December 2009 that was in pesos, so that's what plays out basically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's not the locking in, is it the US$60 million that you made on the swap, or is it in general FX movements on AMC's debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, it's the swap, and then if you &#x2013; and then the FX movements as well play out, but it's really the plus $60 million swap debt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And your next question comes from the line of Jordi Dominguez with Societe Generale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys, thank you for taking my questions. And a couple of questions, the GAAP purchase, if indeed it goes forward after all the antitrust issues, how would it be financed, would you use cash on hand, would you tap the markets in any way with that? And the second question for the Asarco expansions and the life of mine, could you provide a bit of indication as to what metals price forecast are you using? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Jordi. Thank you. Well, first of all, I mean, of course, we &#x2013; I mean it's uncertain of this date, whether it's going to be approved and what's going to be the legal turnout in terms of the Grupo Aeroportuario del Pacifico's standard offer that we are required to make under law.</p>
          <p>I mean, how are we going to finance that? I mean I think we will close that later when we get there. Markets have been very volatile. And I mean if we looked at it three months ago, the market would not be looking at, I mean, the way they are today. So, I mean, we will just get there. I think the point here is that we have a very strong underutilized balance sheet that could do it either. I mean it just depends on the timing, I guess, Jordi. But as you know, we have a very strong cash position; in Grupo alone, it's not more than US$150 million to-date and well, that <mark type="ph" /> just split (30:07) the Grupo levels. So let's see, let's see how this plays out. But &#x2013; and what was the last question, Jordi?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For the &#x2013; what type of metals price forecast do you use to calculate the life of mine at Asarco and for the mine expansions, what kind of metals prices do you use to make that expansion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've been doing this very conservatively, but in the long term, which maybe it's more interesting to you and the audience, we've been using US$2.50 long term, which has really consensus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And for the byproducts in silver, molybdenum, gold, et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of that, we had molybdenum at US$15. And I just want &#x2013; one good thing to point out is that reserves we account for at US$1.80, FYI.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And molybdenum on US$14 maybe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jordi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is a follow-up question from the line of Rene Kleyweg with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks again, gentlemen. Could you talk a little bit more about the AMC &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; the legal case, the Delaware issue?</p>
          <p>And should we be thinking about that in the context of the current minority participation in Southern Copper? Or should it be more related to the minority shareholders away from Grupo M&#xE9;xico at the time of the transaction back in 2005? So is it a 20% that would be paid away or is it 44% or so that would be paid away?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, thank you for the question.</p>
          <p>First of all, the case remains active, and we will appeal. Therefore, I mean, we feel that we should not comment a lot on it. I mean we &#x2013; as pointed out in our earnings release, the acquisition of Minera followed law, legal precedents, and market practice.</p>
          <p>A special committee was formed, the committee retained experts. With the assistance of all those experts and more than 60 people worked in the transaction, conducted a thorough analysis of Minera Mexico. Independent committee and its advisors negotiated the terms of the transaction for the benefit of minority shareholders of SPCC. And Goldman, you should have <mark type="ph" /> heard his opinion. (32:15) So we feel very confident that things were done according to law.</p>
          <p>And then, taking into consideration and doing just a simple mathematical calculation, what we understand &#x2013; and again, trying not to get into further analysis on legal implications of the case <mark type="ph" /> remain active, again, (32:44) we see this as a derivative action, and it will be 20% out of the US$1.263 billion that the Chancery Court <mark type="ph" /> issued (32:53) as we believe the benefit is for the current minority shareholders as the beneficiary of the decision is Southern Copper.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just in terms of one more follow-up question on the railway side. Could you just expand a little bit on the quarter-on-quarter margin pressure? Because we saw volumes remaining relatively stable but EBITDA margins coming in 300, 400 basis points quarter-on-quarter.</p>
          <p>And then just you mentioned the issues around Manzanillo and whether you could expand the potential implications there, in terms of lost volumes with the situation on Lagoon? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let me get that &#x2013; Rafael R&#xED;os to answer that for you, as he joined us today. And that is the cost pressures that we've seen from the second quarter to the third quarter in Manzanillo, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you, Rene. The reason &#x2013; the cost had been related basically to diesel, and our mileage in diesel, because of our speed in the line. Our speed has been reduced to about 20.5 kilometers per hour.</p>
          <p>We have implemented a plan in which we are going to be ordering the volume in the whole network in order to make sure that our speed improves and therefore will result in an &#x2013; in our improvement in fuel mileage.</p>
          <p>So far in October, we were able to increase velocity or speed to about 22.5, 2 kilometers already in the network. We think that once we resolve that problem by putting an order to &#x2013; in order all of our volumes, we should be able to increase in the next six months, our speed in another 4 to 6 kilometers an hour. That's mainly the main reason why our costs have increased.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that fuel efficiency or is that utilization of equipment or is that <mark type="ph" /> total capacity? (35:04)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's fuel efficiency because of the speed, okay. And because of the leased locomotives that we have had &#x2013; we have taken over this year in order to manage the increased volume. Those locomotives are not that fuel efficient as the new ones.</p>
          <p>However, we are leasing another 34 &#x2013; another 38 new locomotives in exchange for 50 locomotives that we are leasing currently that are used and not so fuel efficiently &#x2013; efficiency. And that will also help our mileage in the next three to five months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And then, just the implications on Manzanillo in terms of the challenges there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We have resumed shipments or traffic in Manzanillo as of last Friday. Once the bypass has been already approved by the SCT. And so far, we are operating normally since Saturday.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think just one comment there. I mean, it's important for the rest that are not that familiar with Manzanillo that really &#x2013; I mean, the government did promise us an agreement four years ago. And that's why we ended up here.</p>
          <p>I mean there was not a lot of work done by their end. So it's important to note that it's not &#x2013; it has nothing to do with our company, it has more to do with the way the federal government dealt with this issue, and kind of it was left behind.</p>
          <p>But I don't know if you want to add something, Rogelio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, because the SCT has not completed what they offered to us three years ago, almost four years ago, which was to rebuild a new yard in a more adequate place before starting the bypass. And second, to build a tunnel in order to avoid going right through downtown in Manzanillo. We are hoping that those two issues are going to be cleared up in the next weeks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And sorry, just to clarify, because of the tunnel required and the stockyards, et cetera, is the idea here that the agreement allows you to continue operating as is until those facilities are in place?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but as is through the gateway &#x2013; through the bypass, I'm sorry &#x2013; which, with a couple of changes that we have made, should not affect our capacity to service the ports and specifically our most important customer, which is Ternium, and they have the mines right there by the port.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Karla Pe&#xF1;a with Actinver.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, gentlemen. Good afternoon, and thank you for the call. I think all my questions have been answered. I just wanted to clarify. I think you already discussed cash costs, but I wanted to know if you have a guidance for long-term cash cost that we should take into account? If you could give me that, that would be great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Karla. Yes, what I was commenting on is that we do see &#x2013; I mean, obviously, it depends on what oil prices do, et cetera. I mean, it's very hard to predict, but we were discussing recently that US$1.80 should be around where it stabilizes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's for, a, Americas Mining, right? That was consolidated operations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. That's a good clarification, yes, Americas Mining is consolidating both Southern Copper and Asarco.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Karla.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of <mark type="ph" /> Louis Fergnadi (39:06) with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, everybody. Thank you for taking my question. Actually, I have just one question. If you could comment a little bit on the measure between Ferrosur and Ferromex? And how have been the negotiations with the partners? If you have any expected timeline, it would be great? That's my only question. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. As we reported in the Annual Report, I mean we're happy to comment that we are meeting with our partners. We think that it makes sense to move forward with that. Unfortunately still not able to give details, we haven't reach agreements. We have working teams on those matters.</p>
          <p>And I mean timelines are harder to really mention, but we should hear within the following probably semester or so. I mean definitely 2012, we are working full speed on it.</p>
          <p>So we will be reporting back to you guys once we reach an agreement and have a little more color or flavor of how this is going to turn out. But we are working on it full speed ahead. Thank you for the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o with Ita&#xFA;.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I have two follow-up questions. First one is on Asarco potential growth projects.</p>
          <p>You mentioned about increasing capacity by nearly 80,000 tons. Could you provide a little bit of details on estimated CapEx and the potential startup for this project?</p>
          <p>And the second question is actually on infrastructure on the Salamanca-Le&#xF3;n highway? How long it will take to build the highway and what's your expected EBITDA after the ramp up of this project? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Thank you, Marcos. Great questions.</p>
          <p>I mean, of course, one of the things that came out of the process of the combination of Southern Copper and Asarco, as you know, is that, we both &#x2013; Southern Copper and the independent committee and Grupo M&#xE9;xico &#x2013; retained advisors and experts to do a thorough analysis on both assets.</p>
          <p>So I guess after a little bit of a year, a lot of work we did, as I pointed out, a very extensive drilling program and validation of the reserves. So we are very confident that Asarco can increase its production all the way to 280,000 tons. That is estimated, and we should bear this in mind. It's just a plan. And it would be around 2015, when we reach 280,000 tons.</p>
          <p>And then the CapEx, I would like to just to take that with a little bit more careful as that we are working on now. But I mean the largest CapEx we'll see between now and then will be around US$400 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, on a yearly basis, one year. That's a spike if you like in our projections when you look at this program. And I think at this point that's probably where we like to leave these details of a plan as we keep on working on them and now as we &#x2013; I mean, just our board decided to not pursue the combination. So we're going to &#x2013; I mean, a lot of those plans have to do with mergers and synergies, now we are working around that and seeing how we create value from having both independent and corporate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And you have question regarding Le&#xF3;n-Salamanca Highway?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is, as you know, a three-year construction, which was awarded to us. It's about $4.7 billion US$4.7 billion (sic) [4.7 billion pesos] (42:44) investment. We have I mean &#x2013; that's pesos I'm sorry and we have one of the confuting, a little bit south of $1 billion pesos and we are working on the financing and better, a little bit of equity there too and that'd be two years in construction phase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Any expectations on potential EBITDA that the separation could generate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are looking at really IRRs around 20%, 25%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mandeep Singh with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, my questions have been answered. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Sergio Matsumoto with Santander.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Daniel, I have a question on Asarco. The EBITDA margin for the second quarter and the third quarter are much lower than they were in the previous quarters. Is there any reason why that's the case? You mentioned in the last conference call about lower grades in Mission and Ray mines and also some bottlenecks at the Hayden Smelter and Amarillo Refinery, are these issues &#x2013; are you still working through them or is there something else going on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I mean, those, as you pointed out to the right, I have a good memory. Those are the issues that impacted the profitability at Asarco, and particularly in those two mines. We also had 11 million capacity and there was a maintenance done. But, Oscar, would you like to give a little bit more details on it? Oscar is the CFO of Asarco.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, part of it is the great that you mentioned both on Mission and Ray. And Mission, last year 2010 was a high rate year, and we are more on the normal this year and going to continue there. And then Ray we are going up. As mentioned, we had a 5% increase from last quarter to this quarter and we expect to see something similar for the fourth quarter. So that's going to improve the EBITDA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the Hayden Smelter and Amarillo Refinery, that's result of it, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was just a normal outage that we have every two to three years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that took its course and now we're at production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Perfect. And I just have one more question on the Transportation Division. Do you have a new load volume guidance for 2011 and 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Load volume guidance for 2012, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's now into works, but it's going to be around 3.5% in carloads and pretty much in line in tons-kilometers, probably 1% increase in tons-kilometers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Sergio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And there are no further questions at this time and do you have any closing remarks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, just once again to thank everyone who is joining us to our third quarter conference call. And we hope that you can join us for the next earnings conference call to be scheduled around the fourth week of January 2012. Thank you very much and good-bye now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's conference call. Thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>