<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1209634" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-02-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8961</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Daniel Muniz Quintanilla, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Enrique Nava, Administration and Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="3">Carlos De Alba</participant>
      <participant id="4">Daniel Muniz Quintanilla</participant>
      <participant id="5">Enrique Nava</participant>
      <participant id="6">Rodrigo Heredia Matarazzo</participant>
      <participant id="7">Jordi Dominguez</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jorge Beristain</participant>
      <participant id="9">Victoria Santaella</participant>
      <participant id="10">Efrain Chavez</participant>
      <participant id="11">Genaro Guerrero</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, thank you for holding; and welcome to Grupo Mexico's Fourth Quarter Earnings Conference Call. With us this morning, we have Mr. Daniel Muniz, Chief Financial Officer and other executives of the Company who will discuss the financial performance of the Company for the quarter, give you a summary of the latest news of the Company and answer any questions that you might have.</p>
          <p>Information discussed on today's call may include forward-looking statements regarding the Company's results and prospects, which are subject to risk and uncertainties. Actual results may differ materially and the Company cautions not to place undue reliance on these forward-looking statements. Grupo Mexico undertakes no obligation to publicly update or revise any forward-looking statements whether as a result of new information, future events or otherwise. All results are expressed in full U.S. GAAP.</p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to remind participants that your lines will be in a listen-only mode until the question-and-answer session. Now, I will pass the call on to Mr. Daniel Muniz. Sir, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us for Grupo Mexico's fourth quarter earnings conference call. I am joined in this conference by Enrique Nava, Chief Financial Officer of Grupo Ferroviario Mexicano; Jorge Pulido, our Head of Investor Relations; and other executives of the Company.</p>
          <p>In today's conference call, we will first probably comment on copper prices. Next, we will highlight some of Grupo's financial results, specifically addressing the main issues impacting the Company's profitability. And we will comment on the Mining division most relevant results to continue with the financial results of our Transportation division. And finally give you an update on other relevant matters such as ASARCO and Cananea.</p>
          <p>The London Metals Exchange 2008 fourth quarter average copper price was $1.77 per pound, 46% lower than $3.26 per pound average for the same quarter of 2008 &#x2013; '07, I apologize. And 49% lower than the third quarter of 2008. In fact, 2008 ended with an LME copper price of $1.32 per pound.</p>
          <p>After this sharp decline in copper prices during the second half of last year, we have seen prices stabilize between the 1.45 to $1.55 per pound range. Opinions are mixed as to whether prices will continue the downward trend after some early-year seasonal affects. We remain confident, even anticipating high volatility in the short-term, that resurge in copper demand and production cuts should maintain prices from further decline.</p>
          <p>On the supply side, several copper producers have announced production cuts. Additionally, there are still several operating units worldwide that have higher cash costs than current market prices. So, we expect some additional announcements on mine closures for 2009 that could probably help rebound the market. We expect copper prices to start appreciating by the second half of this year.</p>
          <p>So, in the fourth quarter of 2008, our total consecutive revenues were 740 million, a decrease of 54% year-over-year. Accumulative revenues for the year were 5.9 billion, which represents a decrease of 16% against total revenues for 2007. This reduction is mainly attributable to lower metal prices and significant price adjustments resulting from provisionally priced sales.</p>
          <p>This provisional sales mechanism is common practice in the mining industry. By the mechanism, the end price on sales is defined months after delivery of the product. Excluding the effect of provisional sale adjustment, net sales in the fourth quarter of 2008 would have been 1.1 billion and 6.4 billion for the full 2008.</p>
          <p>Despite slowdown in the fourth quarter of 2008, which Enrique Nava will explain, our Transportation division concluded a strong year of growth with a 9.4% sales increase compared to 2007. Cost of sales for the fourth quarter was 655 million, a decrease of nearly 7% on a year-over-year basis and 23% lower than the third quarter 2008. This reduction is mainly explained by lower prices in several of our key inputs.</p>
          <p>Fuel cost decreased 14%, electricity cost went down 23%, and spare parts and maintenance materials decreased 21%. Under adverse economic circumstances, we believe our Company will continue its effort to reduce cost, improve productivity, maintain consumption and expense disciplines with the objective of strengthening our position as one of the world's leading low-cost producers in copper.</p>
          <p>For 2009, we anticipate further price reductions in several of our high consumption inputs, particularly, electricity, where we expect the downward trend will continue.</p>
          <p>EBITDA in the fourth quarter was a little south of 22 million while 2008's full year EBITDA ended at 2.9 billion compared to 3.2 billion, a 28% decrease over full year 2007.</p>
          <p>Excluding the effect of provisional sale adjustment, EBITDA in the fourth quarter '08 would have been 394 million, and 3.6 billion for the full 2008. For the first time since fourth quarter '03, the Company realized a net loss of 175 million in the fourth quarter of 2008. Full year 2008 earnings reached one billion compared to 1.6 billion from 2007. Excluding the effect of provisional sales, again, net earnings in the fourth quarter '08 would have been 68 million and 1.3 billion for 2008.</p>
          <p>Regarding stock repurchases, during 2008, Grupo Mexico repurchased a total of 155.4 million of its shares for 2.1 billion pesos. Additionally, the Company increased its ownership stake in Southern Copper from 75.1% to 79.1, mainly due to the fact that Southern Copper repurchased 29.6 million of its shares in accordance to the 500 million repurchase program authorized by its Board. All repurchases at both Grupo Mexico and Southern Copper's level totaled an expenditure of 558 million. Given Grupo Mexico and Southern Copper <mark type="inaudible" /> share price, the buybacks were geared by creating values for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>For full year 2008, capital expenditures amounted to 730 million of which 554 million were spent in the Mining division and 176 million in the Transportation division. This represents an increase of 15% over total expenditures in 2007.</p>
          <p>Given the sharp drop in metal prices and economic deceleration, Southern Copper is postponing the majority of its investment projects to reevaluate their viability and also to obtain prices from our supplier firms that reflect the current economic reality. We reduced our 2009 CapEx budget by 61%, from the previous 1.2 billion to a revised plan of 515 million. 415 out of this will be invested in the Mining division and 100 million in the Transportation division.</p>
          <p>I am happy to report that our Engineering and Construction division recently won a 507 million pesos public bid from CFE [Federal Electricity Commission] to build two deviation tunnels for the Grijalva River in Tabasco. This is the first of several large-scale infrastructure projects we will participate and we expect substantial growth opportunity in these sectors, both in Mexico and across Latin America.</p>
          <p>The total consolidated debt at the close of 2008 was a little south of 1.7 billion, with the cash balance of almost 1.9 billion, this is equivalent to approximately 156 million in net cash after discounting debt. The low debt level, healthy debt profile, low cost of operations and sales in U.S. currency give us an excellent financial and cost structure to face the current crisis. Grupo Mexico has a schedule for debt amortizations that does not represent a financial burden to the Company.</p>
          <p>Between 2009 and 2014, average debt amortizations will be 83 million per year. This cash position will support our operational needs and our capital expenditures program, leaving room to explore potential value generating opportunities as they arise. We'll talk a bit about Frontera Copper.</p>
          <p>Cash positions are held in low risk instruments with healthy financial institutions. Our investment policy focuses on the safety, availability and capital preservation of our funds.</p>
          <p>With respect to dividends, last quarter we paid a stock dividend of $1 a share &#x2013; I apologize, one share for every 35 Grupo Mexico shares outstanding, this was equivalent to 174 million.</p>
          <p>For the fourth quarter, the Company's Board of Directors approved the quarterly dividend payment of one share for every 75 shares outstanding. This will be paid on February 27, 2009. The consolidated EBITDA for 2009 is estimated to be between 1.3 and $1.5 billion, considering an average copper price of $1.75 per pound and molybdenum price of $10 per pound.</p>
          <p>I will now turn to the main highlights of Southern Copper and will try to keep it brief as Southern Copper had its conference call yesterday. Specifically I'll elaborate the effects of provisional sales, production and cash cost. In the fourth quarter 2008 Southern Copper's net sales were 450 million, cost of sales was 477 million, EBITDA resulted in negative 48.5 million.</p>
          <p>Excluding the effect of provisional sales adjustments, EBITDA in the fourth quarter 2008 would have been 327 million with an EBITDA margin of 38%. And the net loss was 125 million for the quarter, which again, excluding the effect of provision sales, net profit in fourth quarter '08 would have been 130 million.</p>
          <p>For full year, sales were 4.9 billion, EBITDA reached 2.6 billion with an EBITDA margin of 49%, and net income reached 1.4 billion.</p>
          <p>During 2008 Southern Copper benefited from its copper hedging contracts, with a gain of 137 million, partially mitigating the negative effect of price decline and provisional sales.</p>
          <p>Now, turning to provisional price sales. For the second half of the year, this provisional price sales adjustments had actually two parts, for provisionally priced sales at the end September, we had an adjustment for $161 million for copper, that is for a 120 million pounds; and 84 million for molybdenum, that is for 4.6 million pounds.</p>
          <p>The second part we need to add to these figures, the adjustments of the fourth quarter where we had a significant reduction in copper and moly prices. To put this in perspective, regarding copper, we began the quarter at $2.89 per pound and ended the fourth quarter at $1.38 per pound. With respect to moly, we began at $31.40 per pound and ended at $9.50 per pound.</p>
          <p>When we adjusted sales by these price reductions and volumes sold in the fourth quarter we had copper sales affected by 102 million and molybdenum sales by 63 million. Overall, we had adjustments to copper sales by 262 million and molybdenum by 147 million. This is how we reached the indicated price adjustments of 409 million for the fourth quarter '08.</p>
          <p>Southern Copper's fourth quarter copper production was 125,000 metric tons, 6% higher than the third quarter '08. The 6,500 ton production improvement quarter-over-quarter was mainly the result of the following: increased smelted and refined copper production from having our smelter plants at full capacity in Ilo, Peru; higher copper concentrate production at La Caridad mine, and the processing of third-party copper concentrates.</p>
          <p>The Company's fourth quarter '08 cash costs we provide for our credit was $1.50 per pound, $0.06 lower than the $1.56 per pound for the same period in 2007, and $0.52 lower than the $2.02 in the third quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Cash cost for the fourth quarter 2008 with byproducts was $1.17 per pound, but was negatively affected by $0.61 of provisional sales, excluding this affect, we estimate that the cash cost for the quarter would have been approximately $0.56 per pound.</p>
          <p>Given the Company's increasing tight cost control and expected benefits from lower input prices, we believe that Southern Copper is well prepared to manage the current downturn of the commodity cycle.</p>
          <p>Our cash cost position should improve in 2009, ensuring that the Company continues to generate attractive returns on all of our assets. I will now turn &#x2013; I will now hand the call to Mr. Enrique Nava who will discuss the main financial results of the railroad and infrastructure industries. Enrique?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Daniel. Good morning, everyone. I will now turn to the main remarks of the fourth quarter 2008 results of the transport division, represented by the subsidiary Infraestructura y Transportes Mexico, ITM; its principal subsidiaries being Grupo Ferroviario Mexicano, GFM; and Ferrocarril Mexicano, Ferromex.</p>
          <p>Load volumes transported during the fourth quarter of 2008 measured in net tons-kilometer moved 9.5 billion compared to 10 billion, a decrease of 5% year-over-year. For the full year 2008 the load volumes for 2008 was 40.2 billion compared with 40.5 in the same period of 2008. For 2009, we estimate load volumes, measured in net ton-kilometers to move 87.4 billion, 6.9 lower than 2008.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter 2008 net sales amounted to 263 million, an increase of 1.3 year-over-year despite the load volume was down 5% due to mix of better traffic and fare. For the full year 2008 amounted to 1.09 billion, an increase of 9.4 year-over-year. The cost of sales was 178 million in the fourth quarter '08, an increase of 11% year-over-year. As Daniel mentioned, diesel, which is one of the major cost components, increased 8% during the last 12 months.</p>
          <p>Second, car hire reported an increase of 84% or nearly 28 million in fourth quarter '08, as the Company increased the utilization of cars owned by third-party railroad companies. The operating income was 54.1 million in the fourth quarter '08, a decrease of 18% year-over-year with a margin of 21%. The operating income for the 12 months of 2008 was 253.6 million compared with 236.8 million in the same period of 2008, a 7% increase.</p>
          <p>EBITDA during the fourth quarter of 2008 was 72.9 million, a decrease of 18.9% and was equivalent to 27.8 of net sales. The decline was due to higher cost, the impact of climatic changes causing some accidents due to floods, and to the peso currency devaluation.</p>
          <p>EBITDA for the year 2008 totaled 352.2 million, an increase of 8.6 year-over-year and was equivalent to 32.3% margin of net sales. The net income during the fourth quarter of 2008 reached 26 million compared with 47 million, 45% lower year-over-year. The net income in 2008 amounted to 154.4 million compared with 153 million in the same period of 2008, an increase of 1% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Total capital expenditures in the fourth quarter '08 amounted nearly 61 million compared with 130 million in 2008. A reduction of 53% year-over-year, as no new locomotives were acquired in 2008. Capital expenditures for the year 2008 reached a 176 million compared with 281 million in the same period of 2008, a decrease of 37%.</p>
          <p>CapEx was mainly used for the rehabilitation of rail tracks, enlargements and new sidings, and the acquisition of railroad machinery, which have increased train velocity, improved operating safety and produced savings in diesel consumption. We expect CapEx to be approximately 100 million for the year 2009.</p>
          <p>I will now briefly discuss the results of our subsidiary, Ferrosur, which currently does not consolidate in ITM. In the fourth quarter 2008 &#x2013; 2008 Ferrosur's total revenues were 53 million, an increase of 15.9 year-over-year. This increase is mainly attributable to lower volumes transported during fourth quarter 2008 measured in net tons-kilometer or 1.6 billion compared to 1.7 billion, a decrease of 6% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>The operating income was 6.8 million in the fourth quarter '08, a decrease of 44% year-over-year. The operating income for the 12 months of 2008 was 41.4 million compared with 42.6 million in the same period of 2008, a 2.7 decrease.</p>
          <p>EBITDA during the fourth quarter 2008 decreased to 10.8 million from 17.6 million a year ago, a 39% reduction with an EBITDA margin of 20%. The decline was due to higher cost and to the peso currency devaluation impact. Net income during the fourth quarter of '08 was 7.9 million compared with 5.4 million in the fourth quarter of '07, 30% higher year-over year. The net income for the full year 2008 reached 25.4 million, an increase of 9.4 year-over-year.</p>
          <p>I will now return the call to Daniel Muniz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Enrique. We released our press release, incorporating the press release regarding the acquisition that we have entered into a support agreement with Frontera Copper Corporation. For the acquisition of Frontera's outstanding common shares pursuant to an all-cash takeover bid for consideration of $0.65 of Canadian dollar per share, that is approximately $42 million Canadian, which is approximately $34 million U.S. dollars.</p>
          <p>Frontera's Board of Directors has unanimously recommended that Frontera shareholder accept the offer. This offer is subject to a number of conditions, including the valid deposit of not less than 66% of Frontera's shares on a fully diluted basis, and also subject to certain customary conditions including receipt of necessary regulatory and antitrust approvals.</p>
          <p>Frontera Copper, has one particular mine in the Southern part of Sonora, as most of you remember, that is where our Cananea and Caridad mines are located. And this has a capacity to produce 31,000 tons of copper, that's cathode. This is an SX/EW facility.</p>
          <p>I'll be happy to answer more questions that you have. I can just comment that this is consistent with our strategy of capitalizing on opportunities to realize value for our shareholders, and we're pleased that Frontera's Board has recommended our offer.</p>
          <p>Now to conclude, I'll just give you a brief update on ASARCO Chapter 11 proceedings, in particular what we disclosed in our earnings report. The independent board and the creditors of ASARCO have not yet reached a reorganization plan for the company, after more than three years since ASARCO filed for Capture 11. Despite the time elapse, the court granted ASARCO another extension to present a new reorganization plan.</p>
          <p>The two reorganization plans filed by Grupo Mexico in the past were rejected by ASARCO's independent board, and this has caused significant economic damage to ASARCO, to its creditors and Grupo Mexico its only shareholder. Therefore, Grupo Mexico is currently analyzing and evaluating the legal actions to recover from ASARCO damages resulting from the negligence of its independent board.</p>
          <p>With respect to Cananea, as I just commented, given the combination of the drastic fall in copper prices and high extraction costs, under which we have been operating the mine in the past, the Company consider it is appropriate to save the reserves for better times when the Company has the legal and labor certainty that will ensure an efficient operation.</p>
          <p>With this we conclude our remarks for this quarter, and would be happy to answer any questions you might have. Operator, can you please open the forum for questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And your first question comes from the line of Carlos De Alba with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning gentlemen. My first question is regarding the further detail on the Transportation division, could you share with us your views on where tides are likely to go in 2009? And then also, what &#x2013; if you have an EBITDA guidance for the Transport division that'll be great?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Carlos, let me pass &#x2013; led this on to Enrique.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Surely, Carlos. We are contemplating two elements on price increases. One, that is natural on the traffics that are related to an import or export, that is, that they are established in U.S. dollars, they will remain in U.S. dollars the same, but will have a benefit in pesos of about 25%. And that is about 30% of our volume. Regarding the other traffics, they will be increased in the average, they are being increased, in the average, as of February 1 of about 6%. And we will &#x2013; this increase is in addition to whatever overcharge comes related to diesel prices.</p>
          <p>As you know, we have a program by which if there are further increases in diesel they are passed on to our customers, so that our profitability is not damaged. Regarding &#x2013; that is why, despite of having a relatively lower volume for 2008, 2009, we are contemplating not so much its impact in the revenues &#x2013; in the revenue side.</p>
          <p>The EBITDA &#x2013; answering your question &#x2013; the EBITDA number that we are contemplating for 2009 is U.S. $313.5 million for the full 2009 for the Transport division. That is a decline of 11% over the 352.2 of 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. A follow-up then on my second question on Frontera. Based on what I read on the Company's documents, they shut down their operations in mid-November, presumably because of the lower copper price &#x2013; the low copper prices. What is the strategy for you if this transaction does close and you acquire the asset? What is the strategy going forward, I mean, at what copper price level can you restart this operation? Given that is in Sonora, but in the Southern part of the state, is there any synergies to speak of in consolidating the operations of Frontera? And could you elaborate a little more, Daniel, on this transaction please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely, Carlos.  Thank you for the question. I mean, yes, the &#x2013; let me just clarify one thing, this is an SX/EW facility, and the mine was shutdown, as you just commented, but not the leaching facility. The leaching facility has been working. And, well, absolutely, I mean we do see a lot of synergies here. I mean just to give you some light, we see a lot less mining costs. We see less costs on sulfuric-acid, as most of you know, the cost of an SX/EW facility are very related to sulfuric-acid, which we &#x2013; given our product &#x2013; I mean, that we are &#x2013; Southern Copper is an integrated copper producer, and having build the smelter and refinery in Sonora have a lot of asset that we could provide to this facility, plus all the administrative savings that we could provide now.</p>
          <p>I mean this is being currently operating by a supplier, and we believe that this cost once integrated with us, our mining costs could go down.  Also we believe that once we integrate this, we could have a better recuperation of copper, if you will.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is there any specific number that you can -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At this point, Carlos, given that the offer has just been announced today, and that it's subject to closing. I mean, we've been advised to, kind of, hold on to the specific numbers. But I can tell you that they've been mining on $1.10 per pound. And we could do that, we believe, lower.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then my final question there is, for how long can the SX/EW operation continue to produce cathode, if the mine remains shutdown?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The expected life of the mine is 11 years. Plus, as you know, in order to finally extract from the leaching pads, I mean, the copper, you still carry on for another four to five years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just clarify it. I mean this company, it is a Canadian company listed in the Toronto Stock Exchange, but which has one sole asset located in Sonora, which is the Piedras Verdes mine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Rodrigo Heredia with IXE.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everybody. Good morning. I've got a couple of questions.  The first one will be how much left of the GMEXICO buyback program and to the repurchase PCU shares?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Rodrigo, thank you for the question. Well, I mean typically at the Grupo Mexico level the Board of Directors authorized the program as well as in the Southern Copper level. I mean we've expended $2.1 billion &#x2013; pesos &#x2013; I apologize &#x2013; still 236 million left for this program, however, we have our shareholder meeting in April as you know.  So, that is for the buyback of Grupo Mexico shares. I don't know if that was your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, in the report you said that the Board of &#x2013; I think it's Grupo Mexico or I don't know if it is AMC &#x2013; authorized an buyback program of $29.6 million in order to buy PCU shares. So, my question is how much of that money has been used?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me just clarify then. I mean the $500 million was the program authorized at Southern Copper's Board, I mean, i.e., that's at Southern Copper's level, that's $500 million. At Southern Copper, we've acquired 29.5 million shares of Southern Copper. Southern Copper has acquired 29.5 million of its own shares. American Mining Corporation, as you just pointed out, acquired 12.4 million shares of Southern Copper. That is at the AMC level. And Grupo Mexico has acquired the &#x2013; I'm sorry, I apologize, [Foreign Language] 155 million shares.</p>
          <p>So, I mean, Southern Copper's &#x2013; let me just clarify, American Mining Corporation has no program, because it is acquiring the assets from &#x2013; I mean, shares from Southern Copper. The rationale for that &#x2013; and I'm sure I'm now preceding a couple of questions &#x2013; it has been that we see that the Southern Copper shares have been undervalued, that is the sole reason of this, and also we've been acquiring, or Grupo Mexico has been acquiring, its own shares.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. One more, how much are you expecting, I mean in the free cash flow of Grupo Mexico for this year, if you can put it in detail with or without special CapEx?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, I can tell you that we're expecting between 1.3 and $1.5 billion in EBITDA and that's what we've disclosed to-date and that is including the 13 point, I mean 313.5 million that Enrique Nava just commented, the rest has to do will be the EBITDA of Southern Copper. I hope that answers your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. And one more please, what is the estimated CapEx for PCU in their railroad division?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the transport division is U.S. $100 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And now, as I just said during the call the CapEx for the mining division makes for 414.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, what is number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>414.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Jordi Dominguez with HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, good morning, the acquisition of Frontera, it's a rather smaller mine compared to your four operating &#x2013; three or four assets that you guys have. Are you guys going to take further looks into buying smaller assets or smaller producing assets in Mexico or you guys going to remain with the current focus of the company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jordi. As always, I mean, our provision has been to be always on the look for assets that first of all of very high quality and second compliment what we currently have. I mean, Frontera, there is a copper mine, I mean we think it's a great asset, we think it make synergy as I just explained. And I mean, we will continue to keep on looking of acquisitions as we always have something that creates value and better accretive, so I guess I mean, the answer is yes, we will continue to look at acquisitions that are accretive as we've always have. This is one that we've concluded or will, we have finalized the offer and the Board has recommended our offer and we are looking forward to closing the transaction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Jorge Beristain with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning Daniel. Sorry, could just clarify what exactly is the production output of Frontera in thousands of tons per year and how much of it is SX/EW based and how much is concentrate and what the sort of proven and probable size of the resource is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely Jorge, thank you for the questions. I mean, the production in 2008 was a little bit north of 20,000 tons of copper cathode, that is electrolytic cathode. I mean, this has no concentrate production per filed just SX/EW facility. So, this is, and the capacity of the facility is 31,000 tons per year, so, I mean, we will &#x2013; we're planning on improving the, and running the facility to capacity. We are looking at a new state of the art SX/EW facility. So, we believe that with some of the synergies and some of the mine plan changes that we have in mind, we in mind, we can accomplish full capacity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what's the size of the sort of proven and probable could we extrapolate; you said it had about an 11 year life of mine, would that be based on your 20,000 tons of production?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, approximately, there is around &#xA3;167 million and that gives you the total of 15 years approximately and that is 11 of mining and the rest in the just on the leaching process.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just on the dividend policy at Grupo Mexico, I just want to understand the logic, obviously you guys had for quite sometime maintained a fairly reasonable pass through of the dividend that you obtained from your subsidiary Southern Copper. In the third quarter, I guess, you ended up declaring a stock dividend, this was again repeated in the fourth quarter, so there is no &#x2013; the money is flowing up to GMEX, but it's now stopping and it's not in turn being returned to shareholders.</p>
          <p>So, could you just discuss what your vision is for the dividend policy for the next few quarters, would you see continuing the issuance of dividends? Also I'm not quiet clear why would you be buying back the stock if you believe it's so cheap? But then on the other hand turning it around and reissuing it in the form of dividends which actually increases your shares outstanding in a very costly way if you believe your shares are so undervalued.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes Jorge, thank you for the question. I'll be happy to clarify that. Yes, I mean, first of all I'd like to remind you, I mean everybody that this shares that we are passing on to the market, our shares that we recently acquired from Southern Copper. So, this not just issuing in shares if you will, like a typical stock dividend. I mean, these are shares that would currently hold through a trust and then recently would acquired from that very old if you will, the stock options plan that was setup when the Meta Mexico used to be Grupo Mexico and I won't get into the complex reorganization pluses that the group has gone through in the past ten years.</p>
          <p>But so these are shares that we acquired from Southern Copper. So, the other rationale have been, I mean, at these times keeping up with dividend practices it's very hard and discussed as you remember at the Board meeting quarter by quarter and this particularly dividend was in an effort not to stop the dividend. Given the, I mean, given the net loss that I have just commented on during the call. So, I mean business is going to continue going on.</p>
          <p>I mean, yeah, I think it depends on copper prices and the outlook of the economy in general, and the projects that we have in infrastructure and another project that could create value for our shareholders. At this point this is the answer. I guess this &#x2013; I mean, we'll have to wait for the next quarter and wait and see, I mean, there has been very difficult times and uncertain times, and this has been discussed at length at the Board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But, just to clarify, you ended 2009 with &#x2013; at the Grupo Mexico level 7.61 billion shares outstanding. Will those increase in the first quarter because of your policy of now paying a stock dividend or are those shares already counted in as outstanding, and therefore would not change the share count?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Those shares are already counted as outstanding, and that's why I kind of tried to explain the difference between just issuing new shares -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Or having shares that were in a trust, but outstanding. I mean those shares with fixed dividends and were counted in this 7.6 &#x2013; I mean the outstanding shares.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And sorry to belabor this point, but then -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would your shares decrease going into the first quarter because I don't know if the 7.61 represented a year-end number or an average of period number. But you guys have been buying back quite a lot of stocks, so I'm just trying to get an idea, what shares will you have outstanding in the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, absolutely. Thank you for the question. That's helps clarify. Now the 7.610 billion shares outstanding are the number outstanding to-date. So that would not increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The first quarter --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That would not increase. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Be the same or will that decrease because of the effect of -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, if we buy more shares they'll decrease absolutely, but it will not increase because of the dividend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean the stocks that we're passing on to our shareholders of dividend are already comprised in the 7,610 million shares outstanding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Thank you for clarifying that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Victoria Santaella with Santander.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, Jorge. I have a couple of questions and if you can elaborate a little bit more on the ASARCO legal claims, if you can give us an update on the status, which are the dates that we should be looking forward, and the fact that ASARCO is now losing money. What is your strategy from Grupo Mexico point of view? Does it speed up the process or basically it's more a laid back situation and see how things deteriorate there? And the second question is regarding transportation volumes in Mexico, if Mr. Nava can give us some visibility in terms of how things are looking for the first quarter? Are things getting worse, getting better in terms of volume? If you can give us some idea, I would appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you, Victoria. Well, first of all, just giving you a little bit more color on the ASARCO situation, I mean as I try to emphasize, we've done a lot of efforts in trying to file our proposed reorganization plans. The Board, Independent Board has not entertained our proposals and has really gone through the route of discussing this with the bidder that is Sterlite/Vedanta for the assets. As you know, they've filed an offer &#x2013; they had an offer for $2.6 billion for the assets. As far as I understand, they withdrew the offer. I'm not sure they have filed the new offer yet. I mean to the best of our knowledge, word on the street is that they have, but they're discussing with them whether that's an offer that they could really finalize or close on the assets. Additionally, they have until 17th of March to file a Rear Plan. And apart from that, we're kind of waiting and hoping that we have an opportunity to sit down and discuss a plan. Does that answer your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Basically, there is no date that we're looking for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Only date that I can probably tell you and it's very administrative is the 17th of March, which is a date for them to file a Real Plan. I mean, for us there is no specific date or important date that we're looking into in the near term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the fact that ASARCO is losing money, does this change anything in the process or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the fact that ASARCO is losing money just emphasizes our point that the Board has really caused damages to creditors, to ASARCO, to us, just that not taking the offers that we filed or that we offered by the summer of 2007. So, yes, you're absolutely right. I understand that the company is losing money now and that is only going to harm creditors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I mean, can you repeat the questions for Enrique? You have it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Victoria, regarding the volumes for 2009, as I commented, they show a decline of 6.9% and it is &#x2013; we have taken a new realistic, more in the conservative side looking at what is happening with the economy and in specific of the different segments that we obtained. One, there is a &#x2013; that we are considering a significant decline is in the minerals sector. In the mineral sectors, we are coming from 6.1 billion to 4.4 and that has to go along with the plans that we have received and we have commented with <mark type="inaudible" />, the steel producer and that we are monitoring those plans very closely and to see if they are an opportunity to increase those volumes.</p>
          <p>And that, I can tell you that we are looking at every segment and every significant customer, so that we can improve from what we have already placed as the budget base. For the first quarter I cannot tell you, but I can say that for January numbers look fine, look more or less in line with budget. And we'll be monitoring and obviously those declines in volumes will be &#x2013; will have an effect in declining cost, in measures that we have already taken, reduction in administrative costs, in terms of labor, we already went on with some measurements. We took some measures...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The numbers for January, are they worse than December or are they very much in line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is slightly lower than December, but very much in line with the budget that we prepared, that comprises the number that I gave you for the full year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Surely, Victoria.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And the next question comes from the line of Rodrigo Heredia with IXE.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, again. Let me check a couple of figures that you gave, that nearly &#x2013; you said that the $2 capacity Frontera is 31,000 tons per year. Am I correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is correct, that is the capacity. As one of &#x2013; Carlos De Alba commented at, the mining &#x2013; I mean they're not mining currently at the mine that has been stopped. And for 2008, they posted a little bit north of 20,000 tons of electrolytic copper catheters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the total offer for the company is something around $34 million?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At GSE value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay, yeah. So, the average cash cost of Frontera is something around $1.65 per pound. How do you planning to deal with this &#x2013; with this figure, because the PCU figure is way lower?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, you know actually what I was &#x2013; I didn't say $1.65 Rodrigo, I mean the cost of mining at Frontera currently through a third-party service provider, it has been around $1.10 and probably our synergies we believe will help us get that lower the $1.10.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I see the figure in the webpage, I don't know we've heard that, did you save that number? Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the other question will be, what is the thing with Cananea, so you are not longer willing to reopen the mine. You will &#x2013; we wait for some political decision or this is the final decision that you are not going to do anything about it in this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I mean I guess what we are trying to convey is in order to reopen the mine we need to have legal and labor as our TMP, that gives us the required characteristic to operate efficiently the mine, that was and you know we're not willing to do it ever. I mean in order to do that we need to have this &#x2013; there is legal and labor certainty that is all we mean. I mean currently, I mean we'll keep on working, our team the federal state and municipal authorities keep on working and everybody is working towards reopening the mine.</p>
          <p>At this point as Southern Copper pointed out yesterday, we have excluded Cananea production from our estimates, which is not excluded &#x2013; it-s not included in the EBITDA guidance that I just provided and that is currently the situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And the last one from me, I missed the figure of your guidance for the volume in the Railway division for the whole year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The volume I can give you, one second the volume is 37.4 billion, 37.4 billion or 6.9% lower than in 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Surely, Rodrigo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Bradford Jones with Sakil Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi good morning. Just a follow-on question on the acquisition of shares in PCU. Some stuff on that given Grupo Mexico is buying shares in PCU and PCU has got its own buyback program, is there a minimum free cash that you would look to maintain that at some point or at this point could we see the acquisitions continuing the share prospects at these levels?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for the question. I mean no there is, the answer is no. We don't have a minimum free flow target in mind. Part of the rationale of this has been the dramatic turmoil and drop in share prices and value, that the market has awarded our companies. So, that is really the rationale behind this and that we're trying to support our shareholders and our stock price, with these programs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, just following on from that, then why not just buy shares in Grupo Mexico and increase the velocity of that buyback given that Grupo Mexico chose such a big discount through Southern Copper?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Well, I mean, Grupo Mexico has been aggressively acquiring its shares as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Efrain Chavez with Artha Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you for taking the call. And then, I guess, all of my questions is answered and was asked by the previous gentleman. But I'll go on to ask you, in your opening remarks you talked about the copper outlook and your expectations for mine closures, and I'm just curious where &#x2013; I mean, any details on that and where you see kind of a supply-demand, any more details around where you see kind of the balance being for the year, and maybe &#x2013; going forward, maybe 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you. I mean, yes, I mean regarding copper outlook, we have &#x2013; Jorge do you want to answer that. We have here Genaro Guerrero also, who is the CFO of Southern Copper. Do you want to go ahead?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, well, we think that, as Daniel mentioned before that at the second part of 2009, we are going to start seeing a little bit of decrease on the supply side. We have seen that a lot of companies have been cutting their productions, because these companies &#x2013; mainly the little ones, they have some continue having a cash cost that is higher than the current market. In the demand side, well, then &#x2013; that is also have been declining and has been producing a build up of inventories. And that &#x2013; and China, another major consumer have been de-stocking there and that has been producing that the inventories, gold will be higher than that we have been seeing.</p>
          <p>And China, well another indication of demand contraction is that China is growing in terms of consumption less than the past. And &#x2013; but even that we will &#x2013; we are seeing that driving the &#x2013; in 2000 &#x2013; the second half of 2009 the copper is going to get on &#x2013; it's going to stabilize and that's the reason that we are seeing $1.75 per pound average for the whole year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And actually, I'm just going back to China, I'd like to comment that. I mean, we do believe that even though the infrastructure development programs of the China and the U.S. I mean most of the countries in the world will &#x2013; can have a lag effect, and that will take time to kick in and to really start, I mean, we do believe that they are serious and that they are going to be picking up demand in the near future.</p>
          <p>I mean given the flexibility of economies on this planet I mean we &#x2013; well, we see that that pick up in demand will eventually happen, although, as Genaro just said, we've been seeing a lot of demand disruption, if you will. And as I said during the remarks also we &#x2013; I mean I think we are still going to see a lot of volatility in the near term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure I understand that because if your expectation is that in second half you have supply coming off, but at the same time demand picking up, and if this supply has not come off during really what you saw copper price at, let's say a $1 or maybe at $1.35. If your expectation is that the average will be $1.75 for the year, why would this &#x2013; why would this production be shut now? I mean I would expect that you would expect that they would &#x2013; if weather the worst of the storm, so may be you just kind of continue to run until if you're seeing kind of a bottoming effect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean that is our view, but I am not sure that's the view that everybody shares. Particularly, there are lot of companies that aren't highly leveraged and then there are companies that &#x2013; I mean that have been cutting down and really that's the effect that they have a different view than we have. I mean, we are, as you know, one of the lowest cost producers in the industry, if not probably the one lower &#x2013; lowest. And I mean that's what we've currently being seeing. I mean we do look into the past into our gold production cost that we have been seeing a lot of &#x2013; I mean additionally I mean when the prices pickup I don't think there is going to be enough supply.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Any sort of target in terms of where you see the surplus going this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I mean, I think it's very had to predict at this moment. I mean the rationale behind our belief is really that the infrastructure development programs will take a lag effect and that will not be really look that at the market before I mean the end of the first half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean we &#x2013; as we said yesterday, we are currently seeing no problems in allocating 100% of our product to the market. This has more to do I mean with the economic worldwide circumstances.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Claudia Valina with Banco Ita&#xFA;.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, gentlemen. Good morning. I have &#x2013; well, I have a bit of a crazy question. Is there anything on the debt contracts that would prevent a de-listing of Grupo Mexico? I mean, I am still trying to figure out based on stock dividend, and I am thinking could it possibly be that perhaps the Larrea family is increasing their personal position on GMexico so that in the event of a de-listing it would be easier to carry it out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, I guess Claudia, I appreciate your question, but &#x2013; I mean no, not that we can comment on. I mean, no. Regarding the debt contracts, I mean there is no provision whatsoever that comes to mind. Regarding the stock dividends, I could say that the Larrea family have &#x2013; they will receive <mark type="inaudible" /> shares of every other shareholder regarding those dividends. Whether they are increasing their personal stake, I don't know</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And I don't know if this was happened before, is it possible to share with us the multiple paid for from data to EV/EBITDA multiples stayed with this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This one came before, I would pass on and there are no signs at the movement to de-list Grupo Mexico if that was kind of like what a question was geared at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Daniel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Jorge Beristain with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's just a follow-up. Just on the &#x2013; again the ASARCO legal issues what we were focused on in the last few questions was really the bankruptcy of Chapter 11 workout. Where do you stand with the fraudulent conveyance lawsuit and I understand that those have been minimized quite a bit, but could you kind of walk through what is &#x2013; what would happen both with the fraudulent conveyance lawsuit and in the event that Vedanta or Sterlite completely withdraw, would there be any legal recourse again against GMEXICO that the ASARCO credit issuing committee would be seeking in terms of compensation either for the Asbestos Litigation or for the fraudulent conveyance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes Jorge, thank you for the question. I mean regarding the fraudulent conveyance, well, first of all, let me just go backward, first of all Vedanta Sterlite signed an agreement to what as far as we understand the independent board is about or has sued and that's not &#x2013; we don't know the exact details. And they have a break-up fee agreed with them.  So, that's one thing that they are going over now as far as we don't know.</p>
          <p>Then moving to the fraudulent conveyance issue the position has &#x2013; it's still the same. If you recall we had a couple of conference calls only the legal team trying to clarify what was the decision rendered by the judge and still the position is that we feel very strongly and that we are happy with the outcome of that decision in the way that there was not fraudulent conveyance and that we paid the correct amount for the acquisition of the shares.</p>
          <p>So, basically we're still very, very positive and feeling that if &#x2013; just to remind others if they are not familiar the judge have not ruled if there are any damages on what he referred to not treating the creditors in the same way and what have you.  We believe that is just minimal and that the decision at the end was very positive for us.  So, Vedanta Sterlite's withdrawals, ASARCO still have the option of going into standalone plan as far as we understand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, but ASARCO under standalone plan and forgive me if I lost track of the billions of  dollars here, but roughly speaking if it's &#x2013; they themselves have done multiple settlements particularly with the EPA, so I think that they have agreed to mining reserves 1.5, $2 billion to the EPA and then there is still the issue of about $5 million of unresolved as best as law suits out there, let's say for round numbers they settle on $4 billion. And ASARCO cannot pay that, would there still be some remedy sought in continuing to sue Grupo Mexico to contribute to the repayment of those billions of dollars of potential settlements I mean is there still some umbilical cord that they would tried to trace up the GMEXICO is my question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thank you that's clear. Well, first of all, no, the answer is no, I mean beyond the umbilical cord, the only way that damages could result in Grupo Mexico you have to do with Brownsville litigation.  And regarding the Chapter-11 I totally agree and we totally agree with you.  I mean it is impossible to keep track and the judge has not ruled on all the claims that they are out there by the EPA and the rest of the creditors.</p>
          <p>I think creditors and we believe and that's why we believe that have been severely harmed by the fact that copper prices have dropped, we have now the financial turmoil, and that I mean their claims will no longer be likely to be satisfied as they were six months ago.  So that is why we mean when we say that by not defining or agreeing or turning out with the plan, the creditors have been harmed.  And, again I mean the issue of damages against Grupo Mexico has to do only with in fraudulent conveyance and we feel very strong there about given the decision that was rendered during summer this past 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well sorry to labor the point but, I also thought that beside the fraudulent conveyance of the mains trust of the ASARCO credits steering committee was also to get money from Grupo Mexico because they were essentially suing you guys and I think that's what ultimately triggered a bit of a bidding war for the ASARCO asset when Vedanta came into the picture. So I'm just trying to understand how many billions of law suit dollars are still out there from the ASARCO credit steering committee that they are seeking from Grupo Mexico excluding if you will be the fraudulent conveyance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean this is the only issue is that &#x2013; the way you have to look at that the fraudulent conveyance it's part of the Chapter 11 and when you think of millions of dollars of suits you have to do really would claims against the state for remediations and rest of the environmentals, when you look at some body looking to claim money from Grupo Mexico you have to keep on just looking and the conveyance case, because that's the way &#x2013; that's the only thing that could turn out to be damages. And at this point we believe those who would be zero or very close to zero, even the decision by the judge has already ruled. I apologize if you had the wrong impression, but what you had in mind was the interrelation between fraudulent conveyance under Chapter 11.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And at this time there are no further questions.  Do you have any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well just to thank everybody for joining us in this conference call.  I look forward to having you in our next conference call for the first quarter 2009.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And this concludes today's conference call.  You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>