<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1494374" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8961</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial &amp; Administrative Officer">Daniel Mu&#xF1;iz Quintanilla</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Director &amp; General Manager, Ferrocarril Mexicano SA de CV">Rogelio V&#xE9;lez L&#xF3;pez de la Cerda</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Carlos De Alba</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Oscar Gonz&#xE1;lez Rocha</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Casa de Bolsa Credit Suisse Mexico SA de CV">Santiago Perez Teuffer</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Ita&#xFA; Corretora de Valores SA">Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Corretora de Valores SA">Leandro Cappa</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="GBM Grupo Burs&#xE1;til Mexicano SAB de CV Casa de Bolsa">Rodrigo Garcilazo</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="GBM Grupo Bursatil Mexicano">Juan Jos&#xE9; L&#xF3;pez Q</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon and welcome to Grupo M&#xE9;xico's Second Quarter Earnings Conference Call. With us this afternoon is Mr. Daniel Mu&#xF1;iz, Chief Financial Officer and other executives of the company who will discuss its financial performance of the company during the quarter along with a summary of the latest news. At the end of the presentation, they will answer any questions you might have.</p>
          <p>The information discussed on today's call may include forward-looking statements regarding the company's results and prospects, which are subject to risks and uncertainties. Actual results may differ materially, and the company cautions not the place undue reliance on these forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Grupo M&#xE9;xico undertakes no obligation to publicly update or revise any forward-looking statements, whether as a result of new information, future events or otherwise. All results are expressed in full U.S. GAAP. At this time, I would like to remind participants that your lines will be in listen-only mode until the question-and-answer session.</p>
          <p>Now, I will pass the call on to Mr. Daniel Mu&#xF1;iz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you for joining us today in Grupo M&#xE9;xico's second quarter earnings conference call. Joining me today are Rogelio V&#xE9;lez, CEO of Grupo Ferroviario Mexicano; Jorge Pulido, Head of our Investor Relations; and other executives of the company.</p>
          <p>On today's conference call, I will briefly comment on the economic environment of this quarter and the main issues impacting the company's profitability. Then, I will comment on our Mining Division's most relevant results, to pass on the call to Rogelio who will explain the financial results of the Transportation Division.</p>
          <p>Global economic concerns took hold during the first half, leading to copper prices falling below $3.37 per pound of copper. The key takeaways during the quarter were Europe recent indicators suggest that the sovereign debt crisis <mark type="ph" /> in my instant (02:03) to other countries and is affecting all of Europe's economic growth. Additionally, the possibility of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (02:10) in the Eurozone remains. Chinese markets continue to point to a soft landing.</p>
          <p>During the second quarter 2012, growth slowed to the weakest pace since the global financial crisis. However, we maintain our positive outlook for copper. This outlook is mainly supported by China, which is taking measures to sustain economic growth above 8%, through monitory and fiscal stimulus and has expressed its commitment to support economic growth through strong investments in infrastructure. Therefore, strong levels of copper consumption are expected to continue for the coming years. CRU estimates that demand in China has grown 9% during the first six months of the year.</p>
          <p>The housing and automotive sectors in the U.S. have posted positive results, suggesting that its economy may have been stronger than the market had previously thought. Inventories have dropped globally 19% from its peak during the first half, resulting in physical tightness. This is copper inventories for you.</p>
          <p>Project delivery and ramp up timelines in the copper industry have taken longer than expected. Also, mine disruptions and lower ore grades will get further pressure from supply. All of this makes us believe that the expected deficit for 2012 was hold into 2013 supporting copper prices.</p>
          <p>Regarding the situation in Europe, I can comment that this does not affect directly Grupo M&#xE9;xico in terms of the number of pounds sold, as more than 80% of our sales are made on annual contracts. Our corporate sales to Europe have remained the same over the past 10 years and have not been affected even when the financial crisis of 2008 forced many customers to cancel orders, proof of the loyalty and confidence we've developed over the years with our customers. On this topic, I can share with you that we've not received any cancellations of orders in recent months.</p>
          <p>Now, turning to Grupo M&#xE9;xico's financial highlights, I am pleased to say that we managed to increase our total consolidated revenues for the first half of the year to $5.2 billion. This was despite the shortfall in commodity prices and the damages left by the hurricane Carlotta to our railroad.</p>
          <p>All of our mining units are operating at full capacity, which helped a substantial production increase; copper, an increase of 13%; silver 10%; gold 35%; and molybdenum 6%. In addition, this result was also possible because of the Transportation Division increase its load volumes due to higher efficiencies in its travel distance.</p>
          <p>The cost of sales for the second quarter was $1.2 billion, a reduction of 4% on a year-over-year basis and 4% lower on a quarter-over-quarter basis. Cost of sales accumulated for the first half was $2.5 billion, a decrease of nearly 2% year-over-year. This significant cost reduction is mainly explained by improved productivity and operating efficiencies with the completion of our Buenavista mine. The Transportation Division reduced cost 6% this quarter, and this is in dollar terms, mainly as a result of operating efficiencies through logistics and drag of a greater number of railcars, resulting in lower fuel consumption and lower labor cost per ton kilometer.</p>
          <p>Although cost increases are an evident industry problem, we've managed to contain these cost pressures. We will continue our efforts of further reducing costs, improve productivity, and maintain consumption and expense discipline with the goal of strengthening our position as one of the world's low-cost producers.</p>
          <p>EBITDA in the first half was $2.6 billion, an increase of 6% year-over-year, out of which $2 billion came from Southern Copper, $353 million from Asarco, and $286 million from ITM. Net income accumulated in the first half was nearly $1.3 billion, an increase of 13% year-over-year.</p>
          <p>We are happy to report that in the first half of 2012, total CapEx reached a record amount of $1 billion, of which $493 million was spent in the Infrastructure Division, $471 million in the Mining Division, and $85 million in the Transportation Division. Capital expenditures in the Mining Division have been mainly allocated to our Buenavista mine expansion, which will continue to be an important low-cost source of copper production. We continue to focus in organic growth.</p>
          <p>CapEx in the Transportation Division were mainly allocated to track infrastructure and railyards developments, like the one at Rio Escondido, which will increase capacity in the border of Piedras Negras. It's gratifying to see just how well the Transportation Division is going, which reflects higher sales, increases in average speed, and improvements in fuel consumption while reducing costs.</p>
          <p>In the Infrastructure Division, investments were mostly allocated to the purchase of two oil exploration rigs, which provide services to Pemex and two power plants in which will provide energy to the Mining Division at a competitive cost. The strategy of the company is on value creation. We have been cherry-picking projects in this division with the most attractive risk and return profiles, with commitments of achieving long-term returns to shareholder, replicating success stories like our Transportation Division. For this project, we expect a minimum internal rate of return of 18%.</p>
          <p>The total consolidated debt at June 30 amounted to $3.8 billion. With a cash balance of $2.4 billion, the company's net debt stands at $1.4 billion. The company maintains a comfortable long-term debt amortization schedule and ample financing flexibility going forward.</p>
          <p>Our cash position, both our cash generation capability will support all of our operational needs and CapEx and allow us to have ample room to explore additional value-generating opportunities as they arise. Our first priority for the use of our cash flow is to increase shareholder value by investing in high-quality growth and maintain a prudent preservation of our cash in volatile times.</p>
          <p>With respect to dividends, on May 14, we paid a dividend of MX$0.50 per share outstanding, which was equivalent to $300 million. For the second quarter 2012, the company's Board approved a quarterly dividend payment of MX$0.40 per share outstanding, which will be paid in cash on August 9, and represents a disbursement of approximately $228 million. Our dividend yield has been consistent and above industry average in the last year. Last quarter's &#x2013; last four quarters, dividend yield averaged 4.7%, which reinforces our commitment to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>I will now discuss the main developments of our Mining Division, represented by Americas Mining, which as you know comprises our subsidiaries, Sothern Copper and Asarco. I'm proud to announce that Americas Mining has performed strongly during the first half. The Mining Division significantly increased its production of copper and byproducts, minimizing the effect of lower metal prices.</p>
          <p>Americas Mining mine copper productions in the first half increased 13% to 406,000 tons compared to 359,000 tons in the first half of 2011. This increase is explained by higher production in Buenavista, Cuajone, and Ray mines, and improved ore grade at Ray, Cuajone and Caridad. Asarco's mined copper production in the first half increased 4% to 92,780 tons compared to 89,000 tons in the first half of 2011. This increase was mainly due to more production because of higher ore grades at Ray. Molybdenum production increased by 6% or 9,310 tons for the first half 2012. This was because of improved grades in Cuajone and Caridad.</p>
          <p>The 9% increase in production of silver is the result of increased production at Buenavista, Cuajone and Caridad mines. This was also due to better recovery. Our expansion projects are progressing favorably. We are on track with our development plan to increase copper production capacity from 800,000 tons to 1.4 million tons by 2015. I will not go into the detail of every single project as we had Southern Copper's conference call earlier today.</p>
          <p>We have managed to maintain costs, due to management focus in cost reduction and control, operational efficiencies, improved ore grades and higher production. Our operating cash cost per pound of copper, net of byproducts was $0.91 per pound in the second quarter 2012, compared to $0.77 per pound in the second quarter 2011. This increase is explained principally by higher direct production costs and the lower contribution from byproducts because of lower prices from our principal metals, that is silver, molybdenum and zinc. However, the operating cash cost per pound of copper, excluding byproducts, was $1.87 per pound of copper in second quarter 2012, remaining flat, or the same as the cost for the second quarter 2011.</p>
          <p>With this, I'll now pass on the call to Rogelio, who will discuss the financial highlights of our Transportation Division. Rogelio, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Daniel, and good afternoon, everyone. I will comment about the main developments during the second quarter and first half of 2012 for our Transport Division, represented by the holding company Infraestructura y Transportes Mexico, ITM, and its principal subsidiaries, Grupo Ferroviario Mexicano, Ferromex and Ferrosur.</p>
          <p>Load volumes transported during the first half of this year, measured in net tons kilometers, were 26.6 billion compared to 25.6 billion in 2011, an increase of 4%. In terms of cars transported, the total was 587,000, or 5% more, with the highest increases in the intermodal and agricultural segments, at 14%, and industrial at 12%. This last one in industrial was mainly due to increased volumes of exports of new railcars from Monclova and Ciudad Sahag&#xFA;n to meet the new capacity needs in the U.S. For 2012, we expect to move nearly 1.3 million railcars and 54.2 billion tons kilometers, representing growth of 3.5% and 3.8%, respectively, compared with 2011.</p>
          <p>Net sales for the second quarter of 2012 were $420 million, basically in line with the $422 million in the second quarter of 2011. Net sales in the first half reached $840 million, a 4% increase compared with the same period of 2011, due to a combination of increased volumes and a more favorable mix of rates and traffics.</p>
          <p>The sectors showing the best performance were agricultural with 12%, due to increased imports of grains along the border and at the ports of Manzanillo and Veracruz; intermodal 6%, driven by a growth of export containers through the port of Manzanillo and also increased volumes from Veracruz to Puebla and Mexico City. We're maintaining our 2012 revenue guidance of $1.66 billion for the year.</p>
          <p>Operating cost for the second quarter of 2012 decreased 6% and also decreased 3% in the first half of 2012 compared with the same periods a year ago. Train productivity reached record levels, which are mainly attributable to the investments in infrastructure and locomotives made last year. We have successfully managed to keep operating cost control in spite of high diesel prices, labor cost, maintenance, connecting service and the adverse effects caused by the Hurricane Carlotta.</p>
          <p>The average track speed increased from 23 kilometers an hour to 27.5 kilometers an hour as a result of the construction of new sidings that increased line capacity and the acquisition of 82 new locomotives, which in addition to being more efficient, consistent and reliable, reduced locomotive leasing costs. These actions have allowed for an 8% improvement in fuel performance so far this year. With a volume growth reported an improved operating efficiency, the operating margin reflects a significant recovery, from 20% in the first half of 2011 to 25% in the first half of 2012.</p>
          <p>EBITDA for the second quarter of 2012 was a record high of $144 million, 13% above the $128 million a year ago. EBITDA in the first half of this year amounted to $286 million, an increase of 21% year-over-year. EBITDA margin reached 34% during the first half 2012, improving from a margin of 29%. We're maintaining our 2012 EBITDA guidance of $517 million.</p>
          <p>In capital expenditures, the Transportation Division invested $85 million during the first half of 2012, concentrating investments mainly to track infrastructure and the development of our railyards like the one at Rio Escondido, which will increase the border traffic capacity with the U.S. For 2012, we're increasing our capital expenditure guidance from $253 million to $275 million. We will continue focusing mainly on maintenance, track improvements and capacity expansion to increase operating volumes, safety and speed.</p>
          <p>I will now return the call to Mr. Daniel Mu&#xF1;iz.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rogelio. <mark type="ph" /> While concluding, (16:48) I'd just like to remind that we're happy that we've been able to share these positive results, especially given the global economic uncertainty and also in spite of an important drop in metal prices.</p>
          <p>With this, we conclude our comments to the earning results. So operator, could you please open the session for questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Carlos De Alba from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. Thank you very much, gentlemen. First question, <mark type="ph" /> Rogelio (17:40), what is the EBITDA generation that you expect you can generate from the platforms that you bought, the one that is really in operation, and the other one that should arrive in the near future that will be working for Pemex? Here, yes, this is very important for us to assess the attractiveness of the sector?</p>
          <p>And my second question is regarding Asarco, the realties are that the quarter was very strong and you perform &#x2013; the company performed better in selling copper and the railroad business relative to our estimate, but Asarco was a little bit shy of our expectations, cost value be higher. So, I wonder if you can comment about why it is happening on Asarco and what is the guidance going forward in terms of cash cost. And second, if you can also talk about volumes or grades in that operation? I will appreciate that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, thank you, Carlos, we are on the line of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (18:37). Oscar, can you please comment on Asarco first and I'll comment on <mark type="indiscernible" /> (18:44).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Can you repeat the second part of the &#x2013; of your question? Please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. What is happening &#x2013; can you just mention what is happening on Asarco regarding their volumes and the cost and what is the outlook or your guidance for 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, in the first &#x2013; I guess in the first half of the quarter, our <mark type="ph" /> rate (19:08) has been better than we had forecasted and then last year in our Ray operation and that has improved our production, but our volumes have been affected due to some of them to onetime events, some of that through the expansion of our facility admission, we're replacing equipment with higher capacity and that has affected and especially in the second quarter of this year. We expect, unfortunately &#x2013; and we expected in the rest of the year to meet our budget and that to be shy of the 200,000 tons for the year, probably 190,000 tons, that's what we expect for the rest of the year. And then, cost, well, we have diesel cost, we moved in total in this period as a whole year about 2% more than last year. So our costs are a little higher on that diesel affected reagents and we had some property taxes that affected our cost also for this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, you mentioned that you moved more material this year than last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the mines, we moved a little bit more. We are moving a little bit more waste, so it was about 2% in the period over period, although ore, we processed less than our concentrates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So grades are stable and improving on rates, however, <mark type="ph" /> the strip rates is (20:57) increasing, is that in all mines or in one mine in particular?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's mostly in our Ray and Mission mine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is this because you are doing a push back of the pit or why is the throughput ratio increasing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it was planned like that and this year we had to move a little bit more ore than the prior year or a little bit more waste, excuse me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you over that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Santiago Perez from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. How are you, Daniel, Rogelio and Jorge? Thanks for your time in answering our questions and congratulations on these very good results. My question is regarding ITM. We saw a strong contribution through consolidated operational figures and also very <mark type="ph" /> evident (21:50) to free cash flow, very strong generation. Can we expect the 2Q 2012 EBITDA margin to be sustained and also going forward? And should we expect the same levels of free cash flow from this subsidiary? Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Santiago. I think that we have here Rogelio that can answer that better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course, we can explain that. We're gaining all the benefits from the heavy strong investments that we made in the last two years Last year in the new locomotives, 82 in total and the both 2010 and 2011 with a strong investment in infrastructure. That, as I said, in my presentation allowed us to increase our speed from 23 kilometers an hour to 27.5. This is a very achievable speed and that is key to our service and to our efficiency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Perfect. And just have a little question on this, how much of your equipment is rented and how much is owned by ITM on a percentage basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of the rail equipment you mean and the locomotives?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we own all locomotives except for 38 that are leased, the last 38. We have them leased, out of 633 locomotives that we owned. So, 595 roughly, 595 are owned by Ferromex and Ferrosur. And in the railcars we have about 60% of our equipment leased and the rest is owned. Basically the equipment that we owned is being owned since we obtained a concession from Nacionales de M&#xE9;xico because we have centered our investments in power and in infrastructure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Rogelio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Santiago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Marcos Assump&#xE7;&#xE3;o from Ita&#xFA; BBA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon, everybody. Congratulations for the strong results. First question is regarding infrastructure projects. If you have any newer, any projects in the pipeline that you're thinking on doing in Mexico, besides the ones that you already <mark type="ph" /> approved (24:16)? And the second question is similar to what happened with &#x2013; what will happen with Southern Copper, can we expect lower dividends also in the short-term as Grupo Mexico intensifies the CapEx spending?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Well, first of all, let me get to the projects. I mean, as I mentioned in the presentation, we keep on tracking and try to cherry-pick only what we believe are projects that have a very high IRR with a reasonable risk, well, that have some kind of synergies like our power plants with the rest of our division. So at this point, we keep on working and analyzing this. We have no further projects to report at this point. So we are focusing on the power plants, as I said, on the oil rigs that we just retained, which both have been contracted by Pemex. Somebody was asking about EBITDA. I mean, these are 130,000 tariffs per day per platform, EBITDAs are around $20 million to $30 million per year on each platform.</p>
          <p>And the other project that we're working on, that I didn't comment on in the presentation, but we've mentioned in our earnings releases, is the toll road, the Salamanca-Le&#xF3;n toll road, which we've concluded, as you know, there is MX$1 billion being provided by the Mexican government and the financing is being provided by Banobras, so our equity contribution is minimum and it's being financed on a project finance structure. Other than that, no further projects to comment at this point.</p>
          <p>The question on dividend, so I should say &#x2013; we just had Southern Copper's conference call and I was making some remarks there that we don't have a dividend policy written in stone though, but we do try to maintain a track record that is consistent. This time, the board analyzed the economic uncertainty, the drop in copper prices and other metal prices of silver, molybdenum, zinc, et cetera, and looked at our CapEx for, particularly for Minero Mexico, which is the expansion of Buenavista mine. So we decided to be prudent and to retain some cash at this point and lower our payout ratio, given the commitments that we already have for the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>As we were pointing out in Southern Copper's conference call, the budget for Southern Copper is $1.5 billion in CapEx and we've only spent a little bit more, or invested a little bit more, $400 million to-date. So I mean Grupo M&#xE9;xico wasn't &#x2013; and it was $0.40, as you know, it wasn't as a dramatic drop as Southern Copper, so I mean &#x2013; but the same rationale and same dynamics we have at the board level, which is really a thorough discussion on how dividends should be decreed at that point, and pretty much going forward what we expect for a quarter or two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Last question for Rogelio. Can we expect any significant impact in costs or volumes from the Carlotta hurricane that hit the company in the end of the second quarter beginning of third? And lastly, can we have also &#x2013; can we expect an increase in operating efficiency in ITM, like what is the limit? In terms of speed, what's the target? With all of the investments that you made, probably you continue to improve the operations, maybe can you increase it even further your average speed and then fuel consumption and operating efficiency? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Marcos. Well, the hurricane, as you know, affected us for 25 days. The hurricane hit on the 17 of June and had an effect for 14 days in the last quarter. And we were able to reopen traffic on July 11. So that will have an effect of 11 days also on this quarter. However, we should be able to recover that, mainly because we were able to finally sign a new contract with Pemex on fuel oil that will go from the refineries in the middle of the country to Pajaritos to Coatzacoalcos. That will start giving us around 250 carloads a month, and will probably increase to as much, or as many as 900, depending on how fast we and Pemex can get additional equipment. So that should be more than enough to compensate for the 11 days that we were affected by the hurricane.</p>
          <p>In terms of the operating efficiency, we think that we can even improve on the 27.5 kilometers an hour that we have achieved for the first semester. Our goal is to get it up to 29 kilometers. Not really in this time of the year, because of the rainy season and the hurricanes affect our speed and affect our incidents in the line, but we should be able to reach 29 kilometers, maybe in the first half of next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Marcos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Leandro Cappa, Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you very much for the question. So we saw some derivative gains of US$36 million in the quarter and we know at least Southern Copper have no hedge at the moment. So I'm wondering exactly what is this related to and if you had &#x2013; have any hedge for other companies in the Group? And also, I would like to know &#x2013; to hear some guidance of production for Asarco for this year and next one, and what can we expect in terms of production, okay? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Leandro, thank you very much. Well, the numbers that you saw in our financial statements regarding hedges has to do with the swap that we have for the debt to reacquire Asarco, or reorganize Asarco. In December 2009, we borrowed $1.5 billion to reacquire, or get Asarco out of Chapter 11. So that was for <mark type="ph" /> reacquiring (30:40) and out of that, we prepaid everything, but we had still outstanding $475 million which, at that point, half of the financing's dollar, 70/30 &#x2013; 60/40 per month was in pesos and dollars, it was on the time of the financial crisis and we tapped the liquidity market in Mexico through <mark type="indiscernible" /> (31:08). So that's the swap that you looked at.</p>
          <p>In terms of production Oscar Gonzalez, Asarco's CFO, was just commenting that he expects 190,000 tons of copper for Asarco this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Rodrigo Garcilazo, GBM.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon, everyone. Two questions on the Infrastructure Division. With your net debt on that division for this quarter almost <mark type="ph" /> $100 million (31:45), is this project finance, or is it at the holding level of the Infrastructure Division? That will be my first question. And the second one, there have been some rumors that you have a strong interest in a cargo airport in San Luis Potos&#xED;. Could you comment on that too, please? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Thank you, Rodrigo. Well, first, yes, the two oil rigs that we acquired were financed in a project finance structure, 70% debt, 30% equity. This was a all-project finance that I just mentioned, eight-year term and at the project level, not the whole collateral. And no, this is first news to me regarding this project that you're talking, San Luis Potos&#xED; or whatever.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Also in the highway, the Le&#xF3;n-Salamanca Highway, would you <mark type="ph" /> stake (32:42) another project finance or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I was commenting on the presentation that, yes. What we're looking at there, as you know, this project have financing, first the Mexican government is going to put $1 billion into the project as a contribution. And the rest is being financed through Banobras at very competitive rates and terms, in a project finance structure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I guess, as I was mentioning just FYI is, the way we see these projects are, I'm not betting the house on them, but looking at projects that have important rates of returns that allow us to diversify a little bit our cash flows and not put at risk the whole co, that's why we're being &#x2013; we're financing this project at a project level, that is project finance structure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Carlos De Alba, Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Daniel to clarify, was the EBITDA that you expect from the oil rigs, you came back and mentioned ...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I mean as you know these contracts, Carlos, are set. I mean the day you sign the contract with Pemex, you are &#x2013; it's for a certain amount base and for a daily rate. So we expect around $25 million to $30 million of EBITDA per oil rig, I mean based on the contract that we currently have signed, and this is for both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how long is the contract for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Three-and-a-half years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Juan L&#xF3;pez, GBM.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everybody. Thank you for the conference call. I have a question regarding Asarco, if you could give us a guidance for a more long-term perspective, even &#x2013; I don't know if you can give us for 2013 or 2014 maybe. And regarding ITM piece, if you could give us a sustainable long-term EBITDA margin that we could expect, if those margins that we see during the quarter are sustainable right now? And the last question would be, if you could provide us some guidance on the traffic you're expecting for the Salamanca-Le&#xF3;n tollway?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Thank you. We've commented in the past, Juan, and we made it public in our earnings release, that we believe that Asarco has a lot of potential, that the fact that, when we acquired Asarco, we went through a rough patch, if you will, in copper prices and then Asarco operated for five years under Chapter 11mode, now provides us an opportunity, and we've been conducting an intensive program in drilling in order to be able to really assess how much growth it has. As you know also, Asarco <mark type="ph" /> are mature (35:50) assets. But any ways, we can grow from 200,000 tons to 280,000 tons per year. I mean that is like a long-term goal and plan with the information we currently have from this drilling. Oscar, do you want to add something to that, probably based on next year, what you're seeing, et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, the two important priorities that we have is the expansion at Mission for another 9,000 tons, and we think that's going to add 10,000 tons of &#x2013; 9,000 <mark type="ph" /> short tons (36:16) of milling or <mark type="ph" /> bailey (36:29), and that's going to add, in a year, 10,000 tonnes of copper, metric tons, and then we're starting the &#x2013; restarting our plant of moly that is going to come into operation on the first quarter, at the end of the first quarter of next year, that is going to produce in a year 544 tons. And the project of the expansion of the mill in Mission is going to start in the second quarter, towards the end of the second quarter of 2013. So those are the two expansions that we're doing right now. As Daniel said, we're exploring and we think we have some possibilities of expansion in Ray, but we're still in the beginning studies of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to comment, I guess, the other two questions, where the rail &#x2013; I mean, the toll road and that's &#x2013; I mean, it will start at 10,000 cars per day to ramp up to 25,000 or plus cars per day. And regarding AMC's margin, I mean, we've been around 52%, obviously that depends on the metal prices of course. But in the terms of, I mean, in the cost area, I can say that as you know, I mean the Southern Copper, main costs have to do with electricity and diesel consumption, where obviously that has to do &#x2013; the index to oil, what happens with the oil price. And in Asarco, our largest cost is the labor basically because it's in the U.S. and it's a different cost structure. So we do see them, I mean, all things maintained equal, that we <mark type="ph" /> can maintain the (38:17) market. Thank you for the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. The fact my question was more related to ITM, the division, the Railroad Division, if we could see similar EBITDA margins over the course? Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Juan, yeah. We should be ending this year close to 33% and our five-year plan that we have been working on calls for EBITDA margins between 34% and 37%. We think we can maintain these margins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Juan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no further questions at this time. Do you have any closing remarks, sir?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, no. Thank you very much for joining us today in our second quarter earnings conference call and we hope to probably be with us for the next quarter's conference call. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's conference call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>