<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1186082" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-10-16</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8238</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Krista Bessinger, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Eric Schmidt, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Patrick Pichette, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Sergey Brin, Co-Founder and President, Technology</participant>
      <participant id="5">Imran Khan</participant>
      <participant id="6">Eric Schmidt</participant>
      <participant id="7">Hal Varian</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jonathan Rosenberg</participant>
      <participant id="9">Mark Mahaney</participant>
      <participant id="10">Patrick Pichette</participant>
      <participant id="11">Sergey Brin</participant>
      <participant id="12">Brian Pitz</participant>
      <participant id="13">Christa Quarles</participant>
      <participant id="14">Benjamin Schachter</participant>
      <participant id="15">Omid Kordestani</participant>
      <participant id="16">Douglas Anmuth</participant>
      <participant id="17">Justin Post</participant>
      <participant id="18">Ross Sandler</participant>
      <participant id="19">Jeffrey Lindsay</participant>
      <participant id="20">Youssef Squali</participant>
      <participant id="21">Krista Bessinger</participant>
      <participant id="22">Jeetil Patel</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day and welcome everyone to the Google Inc. conference call. This call is being recorded. At this time, I would like to turn the call over to Ms. Krista Bessinger. Please go ahead, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon everyone and welcome to today's third quarter 2008 earnings conference call. With us are Eric Schmidt, Chief Executive Officer; Patrick Pichette, Chief Financial Officer; Sergey Brin, Founder and President of Technology; Jonathan Rosenberg, Senior Vice President of Product Management; Omid Kordestani, Senior Vice President of Global Sales and Operations, who is joining us from London today; and Hal Varian, our Chief Economist. Eric, Patrick, and Sergey will provide us with their thoughts on the quarter; and then Jonathan, Omid, and Hal will join us for Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Please note that this call is being webcast from our Investor Relations web site. Please also refer to our Investor Relations web site for important earnings related documents including our press release issued a few minutes ago along with slides that accompany today's remarks. A replay of this will also be available on our Investor Relations website in a few hours.</p>
          <p>Now let me quickly cover the Safe Harbor. Some of the statements we make today may be considered forward-looking, including statements regarding investments in our core business, traffic acquisition costs [TAC], operational efficiency and cost, and our expected level of capital expenditures. These statements involve a number of risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially.</p>
          <p>Please note that these forward-looking statements reflect our opinions only as of the date of this presentation, and we undertake no obligation to revise or publicly release the results of any revision to these forward-looking statements in light of new information or future events. Please refer to our SEC filings, including our quarterly report on form 10-Q for the quarter ended June 30, 2008, as well as our earnings press release for a more detailed description of the risk factors that may affect our results. Copies can be obtained from the SEC or by visiting the Investor Relations section of our website.</p>
          <p>Also please note that certain financial measures we use on this call such as EPS, net income, operating margin, and operating income are expressed on a non-GAAP basis and have been adjusted to exclude charges related to stock-based compensation. We have also adjusted our net cash provided by operating activities to remove capital expenditures, which we refer to as free cash flow. Our GAAP results and GAAP to non-GAAP reconciliation can be found in our earnings press release.</p>
          <p>With that, it is my pleasure to turn the call over to Eric.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Krista, and good afternoon everybody. First, let me welcome Patrick Pichette, who is our CFO, who is off and hit the ground running. He certainly joined us at an interesting time. Before he goes into the details, which of course everyone is quite interested in, let me just talk about some of the highlights.</p>
          <p>Thanks to everybody's hard work, Google had a good quarter. Traffic and revenue were both solid and we kept tight control on costs. Year on year, for example, search query traffic is growing in almost every vertical. And we believe that these results reflect the fact that as marketing budgets are squeezed, targeted, measurable ads are becoming more valuable to advertisers. And as consumer budgets are squeezed, people use the web for comparison shopping to hunt for bargains online and in stores.</p>
          <p>Now the economic situation, I think everybody on the call and listening understands that it's pretty clear the economic situation today globally is worse than people were predicting just a month ago. Look at the difference in the papers. What started off as a financial crisis appears, at least according to the consensus around the world, to be affecting the wider economy. So when I talk to other CEOs in Europe and in America, it's clear that the economic situation is so fluid that we're all in uncharted territory. The question is how should Google respond. Our answer looking at it is we have always managed for the long term and we believe that that's even more today &#x2013; more important today than ever.</p>
          <p>Search, which of course is Google's core, is where we're putting a lot of our investment. Better search, better ads, improved latency, our user experience is getting much better. Index size is getting much larger. Greater personalization for better results globally for every user, lots and lots of language support, that sort of thing; more highly relevant ads against as many queries as possible, and using more sophisticated tools for advanced bidding and measurement and optimization, so that advertisers who understand that advertising is directly correlated with revenue can use those tools to maximize revenue based on the terms that they set and based on the budgets that they care about.</p>
          <p>So the opportunities, in addition obviously to search and ads &#x2013; in Apps, for example, a company is going to cut IT cost and increase productivity with greater collaboration, we're there for them. Our Enterprise applications really add value there. In Display by improving targeting, we deliver better and more relevant ads for users and higher ROI for advertisers, agencies, and publishers. The DoubleClick integration, now going very well, David Rosenblatt from DoubleClick is now President of our Display businesses, which is great. YouTube is now running 90% ads against 90% of all the content claimed by partners using our Content ID tool. And we're experimenting with different advertising formats now well announced in in-video ads, click-to-buy, and pre-roll.</p>
          <p>Geo and Mobile, another core component and new opportunity for us, geographically relevant in location-based advertising is valuable to users in our view, who are working developing advertising products that match ads to geographic data. We think that's a big opportunity for us.</p>
          <p>So along the way, we're going to stay very close &#x2013; keep a very close eye on costs. It makes sense given everything we read in the papers. And we have done that effectively this quarter. It is the right thing to do. What I like about it &#x2013; and Sergey can talk about this a little bit if he likes. Sergey likes to say, "Scarcity builds clarity," and I think it's a great focusing opportunity for Google as well.</p>
          <p>So we're very realistic about the macroeconomic climate, but we're optimistic about Google's future because we're confident about the enduring value and power of the web. Sergey will talk about this some more, but fundamentally people are moving to the Internet. They're moving to more targeted advertising. They're using information in a smarter way, and Google is one of the significant beneficiaries of that. We fundamentally believe that users will always want information and need to communicate and advertisers will always value relevant and very measurable advertising, which of course these are Google's core strengths.</p>
          <p>So with that Sergey, maybe you'd like to &#x2013; I'm sorry. Patrick, maybe you should talk about our financials first and then we'll go over to Sergey.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Eric, and good afternoon everyone. So as Eric said a few minutes ago, we had another solid quarter, despite a challenging economic environment. A few numbers, gross revenue was up 31% year over year to 5.5 billion, reflecting healthy growth across both Google.com and our network. So Google.com was up 34% year over year to 3.7 billion, driven by steady traffic growth; and AdSense up 15% year over year to 1.7 billion, also reflecting solid growth across both content and search.  Global aggregate paid click growth was also reasonably good. It was up 18% year over year and 4% quarter over quarter, reflecting healthy growth across all major properties.</p>
          <p>We saw also steady growth in the US, with revenues up 22% year over year to 2.7 billion and up 5% quarter over quarter. International revenue also held up reasonably well, accounting for 51% of our total revenue, or $2.8 billion. The UK showed some softness, but up 17% year over year to 776 million, but essentially flat quarter over quarter, including the impact of the currency. The rest of EMEA performed better, driven by relatively good performance in the Netherlands and Germany. Asia and Latin America were solid as well, mostly driven by relatively good performance in Brazil and China.</p>
          <p>From an advertiser spend perspective, we saw a combination of strong relative performance in many verticals including home appliances, apparels, jobs, but also and not surprisingly some tougher performances in others such as home financing, auto financing, and real estate, as everybody can imagine.</p>
          <p>Let me turn to expenses now. Traffic acquisition costs were 1.5 billion in Q3, or 27.9% of total advertising revenue. This is down from 28.4 in Q2. AdSense TAC was $1.3 billion, and Google TAC was $167 million. As we embark on new initiatives, we may see additional pressure on TAC rates going forward.</p>
          <p>Other costs of revenue, they have increased 4 million over Q2 to 678 million. The largest driver of the increase was data center related costs and those include depreciation, equipment, and operations. All other operating expenses totaled $1.63 billion, including approximately 269 million in stock-based compensation. And expenses related to payroll and facilities increased 49 million over Q2 to 859 million.</p>
          <p>On the head count front, we finished the quarter with approximately 20,000 full-time employees. That's approximately 500 net new employees added in the quarter. And over half of these new net hires are in engineering, and then followed by sales and marketing. We have implemented and continue to follow a disciplined hiring process in all areas of the organization. But as we have indicated in the past, we continue to invest in our core business, both in the US and internationally.</p>
          <p>In consequence of all this management expense, our non-GAAP operating profit which excludes stock-based compensation crossed the $2 billion threshold for the first time in Q3, driving non-GAAP operating profit margins to 36.5%.</p>
          <p>As Eric mentioned a little earlier in his comments, it makes sense in the current economic environment to maintain a clear focus on operational efficiency and cost containment; and we have done so, and we'll continue to do so, better positioning Google for healthy long-term growth.</p>
          <p>Let me move on to interest income and other, which was 21 million for the quarter. The primary driver for interest income and other are on the positive side, a very strong cash balance, $14.4 billion. The annual interest we earn on that cash is currently in the 2 to 3% range and we also had a small realized gain on investment of 11 million in Q3.</p>
          <p>These benefits are to a large extent offset by the impact of the rollout of our hedging program in Q3. So in Q3, our hedging expense and related impacts totaled approximately $80 million. Please note that we amortize the costs or the time value of our cash flow hedging programs in other income and expense on a monthly mark-to-market basis, not a straight line basis. So as a result, the amount of amortized expense we recognize in any particular quarter is impacted by how much the auction moves in or out of the money, as well as the underlying currency volatility. So in particularly volatile periods, like the ones we're experiencing now, this can result in a front end loading of expenses associated with the outstanding hedges, as was in fact the case in Q3. So clearly, currency was working against us in this quarter, but on the good news, our hedging programs are in fact working well.</p>
          <p>So a bit more on the hedging program. Our FX program should be viewed essentially as an insurance policy. Our programs are designated to protect us against future downside risk to revenue and earnings, reported in US dollars. Our largest currency exposures are the euro, the Canadian dollar, and the British pound, and are now hedged. And over the coming year, we will roll out incremental hedges to cover much of the remaining exposure.</p>
          <p>So how does the accounting for all this hedging work? It's FAS 133, which is a standard in US accounting, and we use FAS 133 to account for our cash flow hedging programs. FAS 133 is not a simple standard, by any means. So it's well worth the time to understand the basics and I encourage you to do so. We walked through some of those basics of FAS 133 in our earnings slide deck, which I encourage you to reference. It's posted, as Krista mentioned, on our Investor Relations site.</p>
          <p>So the impact on Q3, before hedging the recent strength of the US dollar relative to other currencies had a negative impact of 59 million on revenues in Q3. We were able to recognize as a benefit of approximately 34 million to revenues through the cash flow hedging this quarter. So to understand why our hedging doesn't offset 100% of the negative impact of currency on revenue, it's important to remember three key factors. First, our cash flow hedges are designed to protect against a downside risk to earnings, not revenue. And second, our Q3 hedges were made against three major currencies, the euro, the British pound, and the Canadian dollar, but not all currencies. And then finally, our pound hedges were put late in the quarter.</p>
          <p>So with that, let me return to our financial results. I'm pleased to report that operating cash flow remained strong at $2.18 billion for the quarter. CapEx for the quarter was $452 million. We have invested very heavily in our data centers and are continuing to do so. As in previous quarters, the majority of our CapEx was related to IT infrastructure, including data center construction, production of servers, and networking equipment. Because of economies of scale, however, as well as greater efficiencies in our system infrastructure and in some ways Moore's Law, we can actually do a lot more today with less, which is a positive trend for us. That said, we'll certainly continue to make significant investments in CapEx in future periods.</p>
          <p>Finally, free cash flow, a non-GAAP measure we define as free cash flow from operations less CapEx. It remains strong at $1.73 billion, up 61% year over year.</p>
          <p>So in summary, our core business continues to demonstrate strength despite a challenging economic environment. While we're focused on operational efficiency, we have and will continue to make crucial investments that are needed to drive value for our users, our advertisers, and our partners.</p>
          <p>And before I hand it off to Sergey, I'd like to take a moment to share with you some of my early thoughts on joining Google. So thanks, Eric, for the kind words at the front end of the conversation. First, let me say that I am delighted to be here and to join this company. This is obviously a great team I am joining, and everything you hear is true. These are super smart people, tremendous integrity, positively ambitious for the company, and without a doubt a great winning combination. It's a great time to join Google and it's a real pleasure for me.</p>
          <p>Yes, the financial and economic environment is going through a lot of uncertainty, but with great uncertainty also comes tremendous opportunity. I look forward for leveraging my financial and operational background to take advantage of the tremendous opportunity in front of us and lead with the team the company into the next phase of growth.</p>
          <p>With that, I'd like to thank you for the time and I will turn it over the Sergey for his thoughts on the quarter. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Patrick. I'd like to update you this quarter on many different improvements we made across the board. Let me start with our infrastructure, and I'm talking about both the hardware and software infrastructure, the powers of all of our services. First of all, this quarter we significantly increased the size of our index. And to put this in perspective now, every four hours we index the same amount of information that's equivalent to the entire US Library of Congress. I encourage you, by the way, how can you see this? I encourage you to search for information that might not have that many references about &#x2013; on the web, whether it's a neighbor or local place, something like that, just to see how much more information we've been able to put on the index.</p>
          <p>We've also worked a lot on our performance. And particularly, we have had a lot of improvements in search, especially if you use the Google Toolbar, which I encourage you to do. And YouTube, and also many of our Apps, especially Calendar. And hopefully, you will see the improvements as snappier performance when you come back and use these services now.</p>
          <p>We have also been working on our overall efficiency from an energy point of view. And I should report that our data centers now use several times less energy than typical facilities that would house and cool the same number of computers that we would have.</p>
          <p>Next moving on, search of course remains core to our business. And now for the second quarter in a row, we have launched over 100 search improvements during the quarter, so more than one per day. This has obviously improved things for our users all around the world.</p>
          <p>A very important feature, Google Suggest that we've had available in a variety of different interfaces and now is on Google.com is running in 10 countries. And this actually really helps users and speeds them up much more than you might expect. As you're typing a query, we will fill out what are the likely &#x2013; what's the likely query that you might want, spelled correctly. And it really significantly speeds the overall search process.</p>
          <p>We also have continued to take our other corpuses that aren't just web pages, things such as books and videos, and we continue to blend more and more of those into the first page of results across all of our domains. And the number of these blended results has increased significantly over the past quarter. I'd encourage you to try &#x2013; if you tried searching, for example, for Michael Phelps, you will see video of swimming and whatnot. And this also is very, very powerful, especially when you look at video because people think of video as entertainment. But in fact, video is a very compelling reference material. It's a really good way to learn something, to really understand it. And oftentimes you won't actually think to search for video. So for us to present it in the first page of results means people are going to get much higher quality information about what they are looking for than they otherwise would have.</p>
          <p>On the business front, of course, advertising remains the vast majority of our revenue, and we continued to improve our ad systems. We have updated our quality-based bidding system, which helps weed out underperforming ads and gives us the opportunity to run better ads and generate a better return on investment for advertisers.</p>
          <p>We've also made some changes to how we rate landing pages in terms of quality. And we really want to make sure that when our users click on ads, they are taken to useful sites. That way, people are encouraged to click on ads in the future. In fact, on the whole, I should mention that our ads add a significant amount of high quality material to our search. And we believe that they overall increase our overall search quality experience.</p>
          <p>We've also been working hard of course on display ads, as Eric mentioned, with David Rosenblatt now heading that entire operation. Now with DoubleClick integrated and the various properties that we have with potential display inventory, we're really moving along.</p>
          <p>We've made about two dozen improvements to our content network over this past quarter. And just last week, we launched a new category, AdSense for Games. Over 200 million people play web-based games every week, and our network already reaches almost 10% of them, just at launch. So we're very excited about that.</p>
          <p>Speaking of display inventory, I just want to talk a little bit about YouTube. They have been experimenting with a number of monetization methods. We have now the click-to-buy feature that you might have seen, where now if you watch a YouTube video &#x2013; that either could be a user-uploaded video or uploaded by, for example, a studio, and now people can just click to buy either CD or a video or other content that's relevant to that video. This is obviously a benefit to both end users as well as the publishers and presents a great monetization opportunity.</p>
          <p>I should also mention that we have launched full length videos from CBS with in-stream ads. And that means they can be pre-rolled, mid-roll, and post-roll. And these full length videos really take YouTube to another level of offering a completely different kind of video than one would typically expect on that site.</p>
          <p>We've also been investing a lot in geographic and local information. And I'm sure many or all of you have used Google Maps and Google Earth. They are a really big monetization opportunity because there are such local searches and there are many local businesses. Now we have been able to expand just the data available there, so we can provide a better end user experience by launching Map Maker to over 100 additional countries. This is our product that lets end users create and edit the maps for their own countries and regions. And by doing so, the users have already added over 50,000 kilometers of roads and 75,000 business listings. I should mention that an increasing percentage of our local search queries now deliver user-generated maps content.</p>
          <p>We've launched Street View in Japan and Australia, and we saw significant increases in usage there. And of course, Street View is now available on BlackBerries and many Java enabled phones in addition to the other phones that already have it. It can be pretty handy. When you do a search for now a business, a store, a restaurant, something like that, you can just click on Street View and see what it actually looks like and make sure that's the place you want to go. And as I mentioned before, now with the ability to do that on phones, it is very handy.</p>
          <p>Now speaking of phones, we of course had a very important announcement this past quarter, which is our new Android operating system, which is launching first on the T-Mobile G1. These phones, by the way, you can get them starting next week at your T-Mobile store. I have been using mine for a few months now as my primary phone, and it has been very, very helpful. It really integrates Google services very nicely on the phone. It has really great web browser. I'm able to search and browse through my Gmail just as if I was at my desktop. The G1 is just the first of a number of phones that will hopefully be running Android. And you should take note of all of the partners we have built in the open handset alliance. I would encourage you all to try it out and if it suits your need, then please, by all means, get an Android phone.</p>
          <p>Moving on, we've been busy at work, as Eric mentioned, on enterprise. Now we have over 1 million businesses using Google Apps. In fact, we've launched Google Video for your business as part of our Apps Premier Edition. Now, you may think of video like YouTube basically for your business as the last thing that might be needed in a business. But in fact, we've had great demand for it. And internally, we use video a lot. We have so many internal talks that we are able to record and then the people who miss it can just watch it online. And we've had just a great amount of demand by businesses for this. I think this will be a very compelling feature to our Google Apps product.</p>
          <p>In addition to businesses, Google Apps are increasingly being adopted by universities. Now over a million students use Google Apps just a couple years after the launch.  And we have had dozens of universities and colleges deploy Apps since the new year just started including Indiana University, the University of Virginia, Georgia Washington, and many others.</p>
          <p>Now lastly, I wanted to tell you something I'm really excited about and I'm sure many of you saw. It is the launch of Google Chrome, which is our new web browser. As you know, we created a lot of web services, and an increasing challenge to us is to have a robust enough platform to be able to run those web services quickly and reliably, and Chrome does both of those things. It has an incredibly fast JavaScript engine which we're really excited about; it's called V8. In addition, it has a process model that is much more robust. Now, if you have a problem with one tab in your browser, you can just kill that tab and your browser just keeps running just fine, whereas in the past in a number of browsers, if you had one tab hang, you could hang the entire browser.</p>
          <p>We are continuing to improve it and we have opened sourced it entirely, so not just Google but the whole community is improving Chrome. And we hope that it obviously continues to improve Chrome, but also it raises the bar for all browsers because we want all the web platforms out there more capable so we can more easily deploy our services.</p>
          <p>All in all, it has been a very busy quarter at Google. We have had so many announcements, launches, so many improvements, it's really hard to keep track. And I appreciate all of you following it.</p>
          <p>Thank you and talk to you next quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Sergey. You are going to stay for the Q&amp;A for a few minutes too. We've got Patrick as well. Why don't we have Hal, Jonathan, and Omid join us and maybe we could just move to questions, Krista?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We're ready to queue up for questions, operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And we will take our first question from Imran Khan from J.P. Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you very much for taking my question, a question about the economy and what trend you are seeing. I think, Eric, you talked about the economy seems like weakening over the last four weeks or so that I have been hearing the same thing. Can you give us some color like how is your business trend July &#x2013; August versus September? Did you see the business weakening significantly in the month of September or if you can give us some color what kind of trends you're seeing in October? And second question is regarding the network revenue. Excluding TAC, it seems like network revenue growth has decelerated quite a bit. I was trying to understand that better. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Imran. I'm going to ask Hal to help me here. We see fluctuations and they are more complex than they may appear. Some things go up, some things go down. Obviously it is going to change as the global financial crisis moves through. It also varies by country and by region. Hal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think I can give you a little color on some of the things that have been going on. As you know, we don't give guidance with respect to our internal numbers, but we have a nice tool out there called Search Insights, where you can take the pulse of the consumer.  And if you look in the last several weeks, there has been this almost obsession with the financial markets; huge increases in queries on money market, mutual funds, buy gold, 401-Ks, banking crisis, LIBOR, home safes. So right now, I think it's very difficult to really extrapolate from the current period where you've got this major event going on, really a once in a lifetime event. Let's all hope it's once in a lifetime. So it is very hard to tell what things are going to look like on a going-forward basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jonathan, you have a view on this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just very quickly on the second question which I didn't think Hal got to, the network deceleration, Imran, there's really two things that you want to look at. Some of it is a function of quality efforts, and the other is basically a function of deal flow on the large partners that we have that are participating. So, those are the two things that you need to look at. Landing page quality, which Sergey mentioned in his introductory remarks, relates to the quality issues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thank you, and Hal, I agree. Let's hope it is a one-time event of our lifetime.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we will go next to Mark Mahaney from Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, I wanted to ask two questions, please. The first has to do with thoughts on cost.  Eric, you talked about needing to be more cognizant of cost structure in a deteriorating economic environment in what's going to be a severe recession. Does that mean you cut back just on operating costs or would there be a point where you would actually delay materially major investment priorities like mobile? And then a quick question to Sergey. Could you just talk broadly about what in display advertising you think can be fixed, or what are the major innovations that could be brought to display advertising that we haven't seen before? When you look at that, what do you see that Google could bring to that market? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, in the question of investments, Google has shown courage when we need to. And we also intend during this period to show very responsible management of our expenses. Patrick, do you want to talk a little bit about how you're structuring this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I got off mute; yes, absolutely. In these uncertain economic environments and I think that we have seen it through the Q3 results, I think that the company is very responsible in managing its cost base to make sure that we are adapting to the environment in which we are operating. So operational efficiencies and cost containment have been in place for a couple of quarters already, and they continue to do so. So we're adapting. We're very nimble and very agile in this and will continue to be.</p>
          <p>On the second question that you've made, obviously, strategic investments are strategic investments, and those you separate them from day-to-day operations. And every time we have a great opportunity, we're going to jump on it. And, as I said in my comments, the basics of CapEx infrastructure and the fundamental infrastructure for the company, we're not going to stop. So, that's the balance we're striving.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sergey, the second part of the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Display, I think there are certainly a lot of opportunities in Display. And let's just not forget when we first got started with AdWords or the predecessors to AdWords, it took us a number of years for those things to even catch up to what then was the big dollar numbers of display advertising, and finally to show the incredible power for both advertisers and end users of search-based advertising. So I think we could see the same thing with Display where it takes actually a while to mature with the new model.</p>
          <p>One of the things that I think is very valuable for Display, even though it might be more brand focused, you still really care about targeting, and showing the right ads to the right users at the right times and try to show them things they might be interested in. And you might want to have a return not be a click necessarily but just be the branding and having &#x2013; generating awareness. But nevertheless, you really want to reach the right people.</p>
          <p>Now, another part of that is we have great measurement tools, as you know, what happens after people might see an ad and how might they act differently. We also have access now to a vast variety of inventory, ranging from obviously our AdSense network to a variety of our DoubleClick technologies can give you access to more inventory; and finally, properties such as YouTube and orkut. So we still see this as an area that is right for development and innovation. And we think that we can continue to create great tools for Display. And this includes, by the way, things like not just &#x2013; we're not just talking about banner ads on web pages. It includes AdSense for Games as I mentioned earlier. It includes feeds; it includes video like YouTube and other sites, so a big opportunity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's go to our next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Brian Pitz from Banc of America Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. You announced three changes relatively recently, in particular, replacing minimum with first page bids. It was I think late in Q3. Would you talk about the early impact these changes are having on the auction process? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, this is Jonathan. That particular quality-based bidding effort I think was launched around the first week of September. And basically, the impact that that has is that the quality score is calculated real-time on each query. So what was happening previously was key words that were inactive &#x2013; keywords were inactive and not available based on the quality dynamic. And what's happening now is there are keywords that are able to participate in every auction because we're calculating it real-time. So it's basically allowing us to get what were previously inactive keywords to compete in the auction more successfully based on the real-time calculation. That's pretty much it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are there any major impacts so far that you're seeing or is it &#x2013; how long will it take to really work its way through?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the quality announcements that we typically talk about, it's certainly one of the bigger things we did in the quarter. And typically these things tend to manifest themselves in terms of their impact reasonably expeditiously after the launch. So I think that most of the benefit of the typical quality enhancements are real very, very quickly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I just want to remind everybody that we make, very commonly make 10, 20, 30, 40, 50 quality improvements in a quarter. These are just some of the better known ones. But we're constantly tuning based on our quality testing and again globally as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go next to Christa Quarles from Thomas Weisel Partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. My question is really related to the Yahoo! deal. Eric, were you surprised I guess by the vitriol in the response from the advertisers out there? Clearly there is reality in how this thing functions versus the perception. So I would be curious, how are you approaching the government meddling in your ability to function and operate and how are you responding as it relates to Yahoo!-Google arrangement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Christa, thank you. I'll let you use the phrase meddling. I'm not going be using that phrase. When we did the deal, we understood that the deal would be both controversial, that our competitors would oppose it and they would oppose it using every tactic that they could, and also that there was a proper role for the legal review process. So we anticipated a, what turned out to be roughly four-month delay, literally to give everybody time to talk about it. And we are hopefully nearing the end of that period and we're obviously in communications with the Justice Department and the other groups that are doing it.</p>
          <p>With respect to the advertiser reaction, we've seen a balance of reactions. We've seen some large advertisers complain. We've seen other large advertisers say that this is ultimately good for our businesses. I obviously have a bias on this question. And in my view, many of the complaints are based on the fact that people don't understand how the auctions really work and the benefits that auctions provide. Auctions provide really a clearing price for accurate value. And because the prices in our auction are largely set by people who can back-solve to the cost per acquisition, the cost per click and the revenue that we get is largely tied all together. Hal in fact wrote a blog post yesterday precisely on this issue because there has been so much confusion about it. Hal, do you want to comment on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, we've been making a concerted effort to try to educate people more about how our model works. One thing we were a bit surprised in is even people who have been using AdWords didn't necessarily understand how and why it functions the way it does. So we're really trying across the board to communicate better with all the sectors that we serve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So our next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we will go next to Ben Schachter from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys, congratulations on a nice quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks, Ben.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In order for the Display strategy to work, do you think you need to offer more inventory on your own site or can it become meaningful just through better penetration of the AdSense network? And also on Google Checkout, in the past there have been a lot of discussion around the badges and how they have increased click-through rates and conversions. It seems there is less of an emphasis on that product. Does it make sense to potentially work with PayPal moving forward? And then one last housekeeping one, if you look at depreciation and cost of goods less TAC, they seem to be flat quarter over quarter, which has never happened before. So, any comments on that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So you actually have three questions then, and so Patrick you'll do the third one. Omid, can you &#x2013; and thanks, Ben, for that. Can you talk a little bit about Display and Checkout?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, but I'm calling from London so please let me know if the voice is not getting through correctly.  As Sergey mentioned earlier, we put a concerted effort across all the regions and our product teams and brought Dave Rosenblatt into the position with his vast experience from DoubleClick to help us really piece this all together and bring great focus in our execution. And simply, our objective here is that we want to marry the art of Display, which is the engagement it offers, with the science of search advertising relevancy and measurability.</p>
          <p>We have a lot of inventory, great inventory, both across our content network already and across YouTube. And our goal really is to focus both on the advertisers and publishers here; for advertisers, really scaling the advertising process from media planning, buying, selling, all the way to optimization; and for publishers helping with increasing the yield that they're experiencing.</p>
          <p>And we've had great headway already in Q3. We had NBCOlympics.com using DoubleClick serving ads to over 30 million unique users. In Europe, AutoIS used the platform very effectively to increase the number of transactions and reduce the cost per transaction by 33%. So this measurability and reach is already very effective across our network and our existing properties. It's just, as Sergey mentioned, a long term focus for us to get all the pieces together and execute and grow the business.</p>
          <p>As far as Checkout goes, I think again, we continue to evaluate what is the best way to focus and utilize the existing headway we've made. There's really nothing really new to announce here other than we are considering how best to apply the service going forward. And we're open to all kinds of options and we'll evaluate it as we see the results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Patrick, do you want to handle the last question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'd just like a clarification. Is it about D&amp;A specifically or is it outbacks excluding D&amp;A and TAC that was the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it was really looking at the depreciation and I'm looking at the cost of goods less the TAC. If you look at those excluding stock-comp, they're both flat quarter over quarter, and that has never happened.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and what we've done is in the first part of the year, we had accelerated some depreciation and amortization on a bunch of equipment that now has flowed through. That's really the core driver of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. Next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go next to Doug Anmuth from Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question, first one for Sergey. You made some comments last quarter indicating that coverage may have dipped too low. Can you talk about what you did with coverage during 3Q and a little bit on your updated view on that? And then a second one for Hal, can you just talk about how advertisers are changing their behavior and strategy in terms of keyword bidding in this environment, and what's happening with average cost per click and what's happening with ROIs as well? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sure. Hi, Doug. I can start briefly on coverage and maybe Sergey can follow-up. I think one of the things that we've probably done a better job in the last year or so is we've done a much better job of eliminating the bad ads than we have introducing functionality that makes it particularly easy to enable good ads.</p>
          <p>This isn't really a dial that we just want to turn. We have a very clear goal, which is to show as many high relevant ads against queries as possible and there are lots and lots of queries still out there that we can do better on. We have a good list of those, particularly complicated long queries or queries that have very diverse meaning. Queries with modifiers, for example, if you look on say "Wii games," we have ads. But if you type in "best Wii games," we don't. Your plumber isn't on AdWords. So the goal isn't really to explicitly try to figure out how do we get coverage up. The goal is to figure out how do we add the bidding functionality so that advertisers can serve better ads. If you're actually looking at the particular components of the RPM equation, which we don't really break out much, generally you're seeing what we've said in the past, which is that coverage is in the ballpark of the historic lows.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to the advertiser behavior side, people focus on this aggregate cost-per-click measure. And as we said before, it's misleading because it's aggregating across the entire world, and it's aggregating across AdWords and AdSense, and so relatively small changes in the mix can show up in that number. We don't really think it reflects the actual advertiser behavior in a very clear way. Our experience is advertisers are willing to take all the clicks we can give them at the current CPC. Even in tough times, we think that will continue to be true because nobody wants to turn away a customer. So we think that's actually a pretty solid number and will continue to be so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, this is Sergey. You're exactly right. That's what I noted last quarter. I should mention that we have made progress. For example the quality-based bidding launch we talked about earlier, increased our coverage significantly. And fundamentally, as Jonathan says, look at a page of our web search results. I think we're far from the ideal set of advertisements, and there are many advertiser has that I think ought to be showing up at certain situations that aren't for a variety of reasons. So I think there is certainly opportunity to give end users better, higher quality advertisers that are going to add to their overall search quality experience.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Thanks, Sergey; our next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go next to Justin Post from Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Now that have you've had a bunch of mobile phone launches. I'm wondering if you can give us an update on what you're seeing on the query volumes, and maybe an estimate on when that could be maybe 5% of your total volumes. And then on the currency, I think you said it cost you 80 million in the quarter. Is that one-time as you establish the hedges or is this an ongoing thing that could last a few more quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Eric. We've said publicly for the last few months that we're seeing an explosion in mobile search volume. A lot of it has been enabled by the fact that these new sets of devices have much more powerful browsers. So they are on 3G or EV-DO networks and they have more powerful browsers and people are busy browsing just an amazing amount of time. We don't show the exact numbers, but I can tell that you the compound growth rate is one of the fastest growing things in the company. Patrick, do you want to answer the second part?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the 80 million was in both Q2 and Q3. Because we've launched these programs and put them in place, they are much higher than what you can expect in the future in fact. We got the 18-month programs mostly in place for the three big currencies I talked about, and now we're going to be in maintenance mode, so from that perspective it will be less.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if they currencies keep &#x2013; if the US dollar keeps appreciating, will you continue to see a revenue benefit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you put hedges over the long term, yes. The answer is yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're assuming it will or will not. So, we never know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we never know whether currency is going to go up or down. Let's move to our next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to Ross Sandler from RBC Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question, just two quick questions, first on the retail category. EBay painted a pretty disastrous picture for e-commerce and the consumer in general last night, stating that there was a meaningful slowdown in activity beginning in August and deteriorating into mid-October. Clearly that company is having some specific issues. But you didn't mention retail as a category of weakness in your prepared remarks, and in judging by your numbers, especially in the US, that would suggest that you're pretty well diversified. So can you comment on the current trends in the retail category?</p>
          <p>And the second on the UK, Google changed its policy on bidding on gambling keywords this morning, and it appears that those ads go live tomorrow. So unlike prior policy changes, this one was delivered with little advance notice. Agencies got the criteria this morning, and campaigns go live right away. So any reason for the quick rollout there? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll have Omid since he's in London answer the second question. The first question, we have looked at what we think will happen in the next few quarters. And the problem is that there is so much uncertainty now in the financial markets, in the press, and in potential government action, and so forth, it's very, very hard for us to give you a sense of what's going to happen in retail or any other category between now and the Christmas season, or over the next 12 months or so forth. Hal, you've looked at the various categories. Can you give some macro comments about categories for us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When you look at the US aggregate statistics, we definitely saw weakness in US offline retail, the numbers that are reported by the government. One thing that we think at Google is that when there is a recessionary environment, people are counting their pennies, are going to be researching their purchases, looking for bargains. And this potentially has something of an upside for Google. When we referred to this last time, I called it the Wal-Mart effect; that as people shop more carefully, they're going to be researching the things they buy. So as Eric said, we don't really know what's going to happen. This is a speculative statement, but we think that this kind of effect could actually work to Google's benefit potentially.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Omid, do you want to comment on the UK?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I think to be honest with you, this is one of the benefits we have now of much tighter attention to every aspect of our international operations. We now have both Nikesh Arora head of EMEA and Tim Armstrong head of Americas attending our executive's meetings. And there frankly is a set of policies and questions that the market had put on us and we really are being much more responsive to these things through our sales organization and change these policies very quickly to address the market demands. And so I think we will definitely work with our agency partners and customers to make the transition as smooth as possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. So our next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we will go next to Jeffrey Lindsay from Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. We just wanted to in fact get a little bit more clarification on the improvement in margins. Was this due in any way to improved terms on the AdSense deals or was it primarily expense control? And if it was expense control, was that really through avoided hiring or was there actually any staff reduction? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can answer. On the expense side, across all categories of expenses, people have been very diligent over the last 90 days. And on the specifics of hiring, I mean we've continued to hire. We just hired in many areas. We're continuing to hire because we have a lot of needs, and then what we're doing is just doing it responsibly. So we will continue to hire. That's why you see the net improvement in head count, but it is truly broadly across all categories of expenses that we're focusing on, like the AdSense too. I think that covers it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'm not aware of changes that would &#x2013; on the ad or ad partnership side that would result in a margin change. Omid?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, our next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we will take our next question from Youssef Squali from Jefferies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you very much, two quick ones. First on CapEx, if I look at CapEx this quarter, so 450 million was the lowest we have seen since Q1 of 2006. Are we at a point where basically the bulk of the infrastructure is already built and now any incremental is all that much smaller? Is CapEx starting to normalize?</p>
          <p>And second, a question for Sergey; you talked earlier about the Geo and Local, with product like Maps and Earth as being monetization opportunities. So we've talked about them for a long time and they remain opportunities. I guess one of the issues there has been this direct access through the advertisers to the local merchant. Have you &#x2013; are we any &#x2013; are we closer to cracking the code on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick, do you want to give a sense of CapEx?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, with pleasure. I mean essentially, CapEx is a lumpy business in many instances. So think of data centers going up and down. I mean one quarter you have it, one quarter you don't. So we're going to continue to invest in CapEx. We're going to continue to invest heavily in CapEx, so we have no plans of slowing down. What you see here is just the nature of that lumpiness. We're obviously getting better at it. So with efficiencies, every extra unit of capacity is cheaper for us, so we're going to benefit that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Were there any costs pushed out in CapEx into Q4?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, none.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Sergey and maybe Jonathan, do you want to talk a little bit about the Geo and Local ad opportunity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, let me talk about it. Certainly Geo/Local has been a substantial source of investment on the part of our company. And you're absolutely right. I think it is a really big monetization opportunity, but it's going to have a pretty long bootstrap time because there are so many small businesses, and you have to get them all in the loop. And technology is evolving quickly with respect to things shifting to mobile phones and some of them will have GPS now; some of them don't. Some of them have cell ID, different devices and things. I do think that this is an investment that we're going to have to keep investing in for some time until we get a really big payoff.</p>
          <p>But I should mention we already have fairly substantial revenues from Geo/Local. So, it is not the case that somehow this is a &#x2013; I mean this is a good chunk of our business and I expect that when we do finally bootstrap it in lots and lots of local advertisers, and when there is some settling of the best user experiences for doing this both on mobile devices as well as on their desktops, I think you will see a substantial ramp there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Eric, did you wanted to add anything? Yes, this is Jonathan. I guess the biggest thing I would reinforce from Sergey's comments is this is an area where we're winning. Maps is the most popular mapping site in the world. We've got all sorts of data now for over 160 countries. We're also doing some very exciting things in terms of ramping our ability to get data for areas where there aren't very good maps, where we're harnessing the power of users to enter information in.</p>
          <p>And on the Local side, what we're doing really goes beyond the traditional Yellow Page types of activities. We're taking all the information that a business would want a user to see, reviews, hours of operation, photos, web results, and we're embedding all of those onto these maps which have a great deal of traffic. So if you just run a query, steak house in Chicago or something like that. When you click on the map and select a particular listing, you can now do things like click on Street View and actually see the restaurant. So we're very, very pleased with the traffic that is being driven. And one other thing I would actually suggest you try, one of the coolest Maps applications I saw, go to Swisstrains.ch to see the precision of Swiss trains in real time. And you will actually get a visceral sense of what it's going to be like for people when all of this stuff works on their browsers and works in mobile devices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And let's go ahead, and Krista, I think we are running out of time, maybe this should be our last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, this is our last question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our last question comes from Jeetil Patel from Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. Just one last question, on your AdSense indication network, can you talk about the rollout of the quality score initiative? I guess is it still a first half '09 rollout or perhaps a little longer? And I guess have you learned anything around the testing that you're doing and are you still tweaking that? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, Jeetil, you're using the word "quality score." Could you precisely define what you mean?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess the scoring index you're looking at for your syndication network, rating each partner out there. I'm just curious how that &#x2013; I guess how that initiative or program that you're looking at launching is progressing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is actually in the process of being launched. A number of partners are already working with it. And the plan is to get it done in early next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's still on time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And obviously we spent a lot of time with them to make sure that their sites are done properly, and our system responds properly to their query traffic and so forth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And I guess how often will the scoring system change, will it be real time or will it be a month at a time or quarter at a time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We tend to be very dynamic because these systems have feedback in them. So as they learn, they get better at judging what is a higher quality click. And as they learn, they get better and better and that's why it is such a nice model.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. This is Sergey. It's probably worth adding, we've had this sort of system in place for AdSense for content for a long, long time. And so now it is the extension of that into AdSense for search. And these are obviously some of our larger customers that have significant implementations and we're taking our time to roll it out in a way that's sensible for both us and them. But this is something that we've been doing for a long time within AdSense for content and now it will be applied more broadly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>So, why don't we go ahead and finish up. I want to thank you for spending time. Everybody is very busy with all the things going on around the world. Thank you for our panelists on our call-in today. And from my perspective, there is an awful lot of stuff going on in the world. There are an awful lot of actions that we hope will be taken correctly by the governments around the world, by the bankers, and by the institutions that are there to make sure our system runs well. We have a duty and a responsibility to run Google well. We take a long term view. We have the opportunity before us and we have the time and the patience to build a great future, which is what we hope will happen for everybody. So thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's conference. We thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>