<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1280377" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-01-21</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8238</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Maria Shim, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Eric Schmidt, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Patrick Pichette, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Jonathan Rosenberg, Senior Vice President, Product Management</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Nikesh Arora, President, Global Sales Operations and Business Development</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">James Mitchell</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Mark Mahaney</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Ben Schachter</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Justin Post</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Douglas Anmuth</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Imran Khan</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Brian Pitz</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Spencer Wang</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Scott Devitt</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Sandeep Aggarwal</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Jeetil Patel</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Jason Helfstein</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Gene Munster</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Mark May</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst">Youssef Squali</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst">Steve Weinstein</participant>
      <participant id="22" type="analyst">Marianne Wolk</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Please stand by, we're about to begin. Good day and welcome, everyone to the Google, Inc. Conference Call. This call is being recorded. At this time, I would like to turn the call over to Ms. Maria Shim, Senior Manager of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon everyone and welcome to today's fourth quarter and fiscal year 2009 earnings conference call. With us are Eric Schmidt, Chief Executive Officer; Patrick Pichette, Chief Financial Officer; Jonathan Rosenberg Senior Vice President, Product Management and Nikesh Arora President, Global Sales Operations and Business Development.</p>
          <p>Eric, Patrick Jonathan and Nikesh will provide us with their thoughts on the quarter and full year and then we'll take your questions. This call is being webcast from our Investor Relation's website located at investor.google.com. Please refer to our website for important information including our earnings press release issued a few minutes ago along with slides that accompany today's prepared remarks. A replay of this call will also be available on our website in a few hours.</p>
          <p>Please note that we routinely post important information on our Investor Relations website located at investor.google.com and we encourage you to make use of that resource. As a reminder today, we're holding two calls. On this call we'll discuss our strategic overview and Q&amp;A with the usual format followed by a second call, which is effectively an extended Q&amp;A session with Jonathan and Patrick giving the opportunity for participants to ask more detailed financial and product questions in an efficient and Reg FD-compliant manner.</p>
          <p>The second call will begin at 3:00 PM Pacific Time and will also be webcast from our Investor Relations website. Now, let me quickly cover the Safe Harbor. Some of the statements we make today may be considered forward-looking including statements regarding Google's future and investments in our long-term growth and innovation, expected performance of our business and our expected level of capital expenditures.</p>
          <p>These statements involve a number of risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially. Please note that these forward-looking statements reflect our opinions only as of the date of this presentation and we undertake no obligation to revise or publicly release the results of any revision to these forward-looking statements in light of new information or future events.</p>
          <p>Please refer to our SEC filings including our annual report on Form 10-K for the year ended December 31, 2008, as well as our earnings press release for a more detailed description of the risk factors that may affect our results. Copies can be obtained from the SEC or by visiting the Investor Relations section of our website.</p>
          <p>Also please note certain financial measures we use on this call such as operating profit and operating margin are expressed in a non-GAAP basis and have been adjusted to exclude charges relating to stock-based compensation. We have also adjusted our net cash provided by operating activities to remove capital expenditures, which we refer to as free cash flow. Our GAAP results and GAAP to non-GAAP reconciliation can be found in our earnings press release.</p>
          <p>With that I will now turn the call over to Eric.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, good afternoon to all, happy New Year and welcome to our Q4 earnings call. This was a very strong quarter for Google and extraordinary end to a rollercoaster year by any means &#x2013; measures: 17% year-on-year revenue growth and we performed literally I think well across the board.</p>
          <p>We learned a lot in 2009, the strength of our management team, the talent of our employees, pace-setting innovation within our product and engineering teams. If you take a look, at the investments we made for example in Chrome and Chrome OS that we announced over the summer.</p>
          <p>The resilience of our business model: when advertising dollars are scarce, measurement matters even more, so we tend to benefit more than you might have expected and that's great. And we're optimistic about the future as a result. The digital economy continues to grow very rapidly. And specifically we're moving literally eyeballs and advertising online, and we continue to benefit from that.</p>
          <p>And our decision to start ramping up our investments in Q3, which we talked about maybe six months ago was clearly the right one so we'll get the benefit of that now in 2010. So we continue to invest heavily for the long-term, investments that are designed to maintain and even to increase Google's pace of innovation. So where are we investing? Well, we're obviously going to invest first in people, engineering, the best engineering, best technical, best researchers and so forth and product sales in key markets across the country in all the ways that we've talked about before.</p>
          <p>Second of course investment is in technological innovation, which is our core value proposition if you will. We're going to follow the 70, 20, 10 which has worked so well for us, 70% in our established businesses, search with an emphasis on search quality as we continue on our quest which will never be fully realized to create the perfect search engine. We added for example real-time search in Q4 which has been very successful, more than 550 search quality enhancements in 2009, far more than one per day for obvious and it just continues to accelerate. Search advertising shifting &#x2013; the shift online as I talked about, lots of growth in our core business as a result of that shift.</p>
          <p>Display, we've talked about before is now a huge opportunity for Google. 60 quality improvements in our display ads and last year YouTube great progress with our key TV and music deals in Q4, which have been discussed already in the press. Enterprise business again very strong, terrific momentum there, as people move to the web based model with products that really work very well. In the 20% area, newer businesses, these are newer businesses that fuel our search business, for example mobile.</p>
          <p>Everybody knows about the success of Android, our search traffic increased five times in the past two years. The Droid and Nexus One show the power of the Android approach, great devices, multiple partners, great features, lots of different use cases, again, a pretty clear success at this point. And we also have our 10% long view investments and here we're interested in things like commerce and social initiatives, which Jonathan will talk some more about.</p>
          <p>A third component for 2010 will be acquisitions. We've &#x2013; the pace of deals in Q4 shows that we're at least on a path of one per month, and we should expect that to continue. Some big, more small than big probably and designed either to build upon an existing business, the most obvious being Teracent and DoubleClick but also to bring in new talent.</p>
          <p>If you look at like the Gizmo5 acquisition, again people with a unique expertise that we can use as part of our platform. So overall, very pleased with the performance in Q4, we're back in business full blast and throughout 2009 if you look at it we're investing heavily, we're excited about continuing to re-invent search, which continues to be our core mission.</p>
          <p>I think with that why don't we turn it over to Patrick and take us through the numbers. Patrick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Eric. Good afternoon, everyone. So I'll go through the financial results quickly and then turn it over to Jonathan and Nikesh for more retails on our performance. So we had a very strong finish to 2009. We're very pleased with the Q4 results and that gives us, as Eric said, the confidence to turn our focus to the growth opportunities in 2010 already making already in the back end of 2009 the necessary and significant investments to pursue those opportunities. So let's go through the numbers quickly.</p>
          <p>Our gross revenue grew 17% year-over-year to $6.7 billion. Our business was strong across the board, in search, display, apps and mobile. Nikesh will go into more details on our performance in a few minutes on these matters.</p>
          <p>Google website revenue was up 16% year-over-year to 4.4 billion. We saw strong growth on Google.com across the world boosted by very strong retail season, economic recovery in many of our major geographies as well as some favorable FX. We also saw some impressive growth in YouTube revenues. AdSense revenue was up 21% year-over-year to 2 billion driven primarily by solid performance in AdSense for Search, strength in AdSense for Content and growth in our display initiatives.</p>
          <p>Our global aggregate paid click growth remained healthy, up 13% year-over-year and 9% quarter-over-quarter. The aggregate cost per click growth was also up 5% year-over-year and 2% quarter-over-quarter. Year-over-year CPC growth was also positively impacted by some of the FX. Remember too that this is an aggregate number, which includes both Google and AdSense properties and also includes diverse geographic markets some of which have lower CPCs.</p>
          <p>Turning to our geographic performance, revenue from the U.S. was up 11% year-over-year to 3.2 billion, international revenue accounted for 53% of our total revenue or 3.5 billion with about 8 million of benefits from hedging program this quarter. The U.K. was up 13% year-over-year to 772 million and this despite a weaker pound in Q4 of 2009 compared to last year. Finally, using fixed year-over-year exchange rates our international revenues would have been roughly 196 million lower.</p>
          <p>So let me turn to expenses. Our traffic acquisition costs were 1.7 billion or 27% of total advertising revenue. Our other costs of revenue was 688 million, including our stock-based compensation of $6 million. And finally, all other operating costs total about $1.8 billion, including approximately 270 million in stock-based compensation.</p>
          <p>So on a year-over-year basis, our OpEx excluding SBC was higher by 138 million and up 172 quarter-over-quarter, the increase, both year-over-year and quarter-over-quarter primarily due to increases in marketing spend. As a result, our non-GAAP operating profit which excludes the stock-based compensation increased to $2.8 billion in Q4 resulting in a non-GAAP operating margin about 41%. 41.3% to be exact. Our head count was also slightly up at the end of the quarter, approximately 20,000 full time employees. And as Eric discussed, we plan to continue to aggressively hire through this year, particularly in engineering and sales.</p>
          <p>Let me turn for a moment to cash management. Our other income and expense was 88 million for Q4 and for more details on OI&amp;E please refer to the slides that accompany this call on our Investor Relations website. Our effective tax rate for the quarter was 23%.</p>
          <p>Now turning then to operating cash flow, it was also very strong at $2.7 billion. CapEx for the quarter was 221 million, again primarily related to our data center operations. We continue to make significant CapEx investments and these continue to be lumpy quarter to quarter, depending on a timing of when we're able to make these investments. The net of all this is a free cash flow quite strong at $2.5 billion for the quarter. So in summary, we're very pleased with the strong performance of Q4 across revenue, margins and cash flow.</p>
          <p>As we enter 2010, we're very excited about the opportunities of our core business, our display, mobile, apps and so you should expect us to continue to drive real investments in significant ways in the areas we believe have real long-term opportunities for Google and that will accelerate our pace of innovation.</p>
          <p>With that, thank you for your time.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn it to Jonathan who despite, you'll hear, quite a rough voice and a bad cold, I can assure you has all his regular, expected energy. Turning it over to Jonathan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Patrick. I'll do my best. So naturally I think that part of our success this past year was the result of a very focused product strategy. At the beginning of 2009 our strategy was basically to double down on our core, which was search, AdWords and display and of course push on monetizing YouTube.</p>
          <p>We also wanted to invest in Chrome, Chrome OS and Geo and at the same time we made some very hard decisions to focus our resources. We shut down Lively, Notebook and our Audio Ads efforts. Internally we refer to this as the, "More wood behind fewer arrows," approach and I think it worked for 2009.</p>
          <p>As we look back. AdWords launched a whole new front end and several new ad formats that I think you can see are delivering results. Android started 2009 with just one device and is now at 20 in 48 countries and I'm proudly carrying the gorgeous new Nexus One in my pocket. DoubleClick is now fully integrated and display is ramping nicely and we open sourced a whole new operating system designed for the Internet era with Chrome OS.</p>
          <p>We also saw a steady stream of small businesses, large enterprises and lots of schools move to the cloud. And YouTube is in fact, it turns out, monetizing well and we're helping lots of our partners who are working with us there make money.</p>
          <p>But most importantly, search did particularly well in 2009 and I think that may be the best example of what we feel we can do when we double down and focus. We launched 550 quality enhancements which Eric mentioned, we produced a much bigger and faster index, we expanded the capabilities of universal search and we added tools like the search options that let you work with your results to get to the best answer.</p>
          <p>We also launched music search and real-time search, which are pretty amazing. I don't know if any of you are actually in Northern California, but we had this 4.1 earthquake a couple of weeks ago and like my office shook while I was in it and two minutes later, Google search was showing me people's Tweets from all over the Bay Area talking about the quake that had just occurred and within minutes I was looking at news reports and the USGS data on the same quake. This looks easy, but we had to build dozens of new search technologies so we could process the hundreds of millions of real-time changes that occur each day to make it happen.</p>
          <p>Eric mentioned that in 2010 we're going to be investing so let me try to take a minute to talk about how we're thinking about making those investments. Of course we're going to pour a lot into search. The key there, as always, is time to result. How fast can we get the user to the best answer for her or him? Whether that's a web page, a map, a video, a Twitter update, whatever it is. We're also going to work hard on making the ads richer, more diverse and more useful. We've talked about the single perfect ad and we mean that from the perspective of both the advertiser and the user at the same time.</p>
          <p>Beyond search and search ads, I think we see a few major trends that are transforming the Internet and we think we're in a great position to compete in those areas too. The first is social. And when you say social, I think people think of social networks. But really we believe the entire web is social. So we're going to look at making all of our products more social. We think you're more likely to trust a restaurant or a movie review from a friend of yours than from a stranger. So maybe it should be rated as a higher quality result, but only for you.</p>
          <p>The Internet is also local and we see more and more a business's online presence is as important as its physical one, so we're trying to make it easier for businesses to manage that presence and to connect with people who might actually be right around the corner and want to find them.</p>
          <p>The web has also always been about commerce and now more and more people who buy stuff online are starting their &#x2013; who buy things offline are starting their shopping process and researching all of that stuff online. And we want to help those people decide what to get, and where to get it, whether it's offline or online.</p>
          <p>Personalization is also getting more important and we think mobile is a big part of that. More users both for search and other products are accessing us from mobile devices. And with all of the capabilities these phones that are coming out have, GPS, cameras, we think there is the potential to actually make this mobile web better than the PC web.</p>
          <p>Finally the shift from enterprises to online will accelerate and now we think organizations are moving to the cloud not because they save money, but because it's actually a better way to run their business. They can do things in the cloud that they simply can't do in the old desktop world. So those are the trends that are guiding our product plans in 2010 and we think it's going to be an exciting year and we'll certainly look forward to sharing our progress with you on future calls.</p>
          <p>So with that I guess I'll turn it over to Nikesh.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jonathan. This was an exciting quarter for us after a challenging year. 2009 started under a cloud of uncertainty but after about three quarters of steadily improving performance I'm now pleased to report we ended the year with a robust quarter in revenues.</p>
          <p>Let me take a quick few minutes to provide details on some examples of how advertisers can and have better leveraged their online marketing to reach their audiences. The first macro trend affecting all of our ad driven businesses was a continued rising adoption of online advertising by larger companies. In these tighter economic times we saw bigger companies like Staples, Volvo, Ubisoft, Abbott Labs, etcetera, turn an increasing proportions of their spend to what is a more measurable ROI of online advertising, they're basically shifting to where their audiences now spend their time.</p>
          <p>Looking globally we saw a significant uptick in retail advertisers' online spending, this was for a change, driven by both online e-tailers as well as traditional brick and mortar companies. Our sales team took advantage of this trend and had strong showings on Black Friday and Cyber Monday which marked the start of the largest e-commerce holiday season in history.</p>
          <p>It's interesting to note, remember, search ads are always a better value in December. CPC's go up, but CPA's go down because people end up buying more during that period. Let me give you a geographic flavor of how our revenues spread out around the world. Within the U.S. the impact of the economic recovery is beginning to show, particularly in sectors with a strong ROI focus. On the other side of the Atlantic, U.K. companies in verticals that have been traditionally large spenders in offline have also increased their online ad budgets.</p>
          <p>If you shift to emerging markets we're very happy with our performance. In most of these markets we see clear effects of underlying economic expansion again, as well as the accelerating adoption of both search and online display advertising. For example our Q4 growth in Brazil was particularly strong driven by efforts to educate the advertisers and the under-penetrated companies to help them understand the value of online advertising and what that represents in their overall marketing mix.</p>
          <p>The second big trend we're seeing is brand marketers continue to better understand the online display format and incorporate that into their campaigns. With our broad portfolio of products, we are pleased with the performance of pretty much all four parts of our display strategy, YouTube, the Google Content Network, DoubleClick and our Ad Exchange.</p>
          <p>In YouTube we have had many successful brand advertising campaigns of note. One that you might have come across was Fox's integrated media campaign for Avatar which used pretty much all four parts of our display strategy. If you haven't seen it, you can go to the web, to YouTube, query Avatar, and it will show you the interactive integrated multimedia channel which starts advertising the movie's trailer in high def.</p>
          <p>We're also very excited about an event we held with American Express and Sony for World AIDS day, where we streamed and hosted live Alicia Keys benefit concert on YouTube. In the campaign American Express, Sony, were able to reach millions of viewers in 167 countries around the world.</p>
          <p>Beyond YouTube brand advertisers continue to see the value of our million publishers in our Content Network and finally, the Ad Exchange, which we launched in Q3, continues to show good progress and is increasingly becoming an important part of the display ecosystem. We believe most of the top networks are now signed on to the exchange.</p>
          <p>Third as Jonathan mentioned, we continue to see the global trend towards cloud computing speed up, as more companies growth more and more comfortable with hosted applications, our sales teams are moving quickly to capitalize on these opportunities. We had key wins at Jaguar, National Geographic, as well as one of our most comprehensive deals with the City of Los Angeles which moved 30,000 users to Google apps.</p>
          <p>Set against these major commercial wins we have signed educational deals with Virginia Tech and Fresno State, while both small and medium size businesses continue to adopt Google Apps.</p>
          <p>Finally with the trends that Jonathan mentioned, and the penetration of smart phones and other mobile devices, our sales teams are continuing to work with advertisers who can reach and target their customers through mobile advertising like <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>One campaign of specific note was done by Razorfish, an agency partner of ours, who used a targeted mobile campaign to improve conversion rates for one of their retail clients by approximately 10%. So we continue to see promise in this area.</p>
          <p>Now I'm going to turn it over to Patrick to set up the question period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Nikesh. So everybody will remember that our last call we had set up a Dory page &#x2013; a question page online to sort out through the questions-and-answers. And through your feedback, and actually having tested that, we preferred actually to go back to our more traditional mode. So thanks for actually having tried it with us and in spirit of innovation, and I'll turn it to Connie to set up the call in questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. And we'll take our first question from James Mitchell from Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much for the question. It looked like your U.S. revenue accelerated from 4% year-on-year growth in the third quarter to 11% year-on-year in the fourth quarter, which was great. While your international revenue growth accelerated from 19% in the third quarter to 21% in the fourth quarter, and 21% is still a big number but not as sharp an acceleration. I wonder if the discrepancy was due to any of the following; first, the U.S. having easier comps than international from a year ago; second, the monetization improvements you made in the U.S. that you haven't rolled out internationally; or third, the fact that display advertising is benefiting your U.S. business more than your international business at this point? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I'll let Nikesh give you a sense of the focus that he's put in the U.S. for Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The U.S., as I mentioned earlier, we have been able to see the continued shift of large advertisers which started in Q3 and continued into Q4 and has been reasonably strong.</p>
          <p>On the international side, I'm very pleased with the growth we've seen across the world, but you have to understand there is a mix issue. There are different parts of the world, which have grown at different bases and whilst we continue to see growth in most markets, there are some of the markets where we're seeing growth, which are like Brazil as I mentioned, which are causing the growth rate to look different than the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Let's go to the next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Mark Mahaney from Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Two questions, please. The sequential growth is actually very similar to what you had in 2007. Is it pretty clear to you that overall search spending trends are kind of back to normal seasonal patterns, or are there still verticals that seem still weak to you, not retail but obviously &#x2013; but other areas?</p>
          <p>And then second the materiality of mobile, could you talk about any data points of sequential growth in searches, what percentage searches are off mobile devices in any particular markets? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So just in a very general issue we don't &#x2013; we won't comment on &#x2013; about the mobile and how it affects our total revenue. And then in general, there is clearly &#x2013; I mean, you see through the second half of 2009 a recovery in economic activity worldwide and that clearly has shown up in our results, but I'll let Nikesh give you a bit more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From a vertical perspective, as I mentioned, we have seen very strong strength in the retail vertical across the board pretty much all around the world. We've also continued to see strength in the technology vertical. As you would expect finance is not as strong as it was in 2007 and we're seeing stabilization and some amount of recovery. In addition to that, we continue to make progress with all the other verticals like CPG, health, local, et cetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's go to the next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question from Ben Schachter from Broadpoint.AmTech.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you could rank the key monetization changes you made in 4Q and how do you think they're going to impact the model going forward? And then on mobile just wondering, if you could have a broader discussion about how you think about the P&amp;L there. I mean, is this something that you want to drive revenues or is there something you just want to push the Internet experience forward on mobile? And then finally any comments on China and the situation there? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Ben, it's Jonathan. So I guess I can just start with the quality questions since that suggests specifically. Q4 tends to be a modest quarter for us quality wise. We had about a dozen launches but the dynamic that we have there is that we try to freeze the launches after Thanksgiving, so that we have stability for our advertisers around the holiday period.</p>
          <p>So from an overall impact on RPM perspective, the quality launches are actually more modest. Some of the ads changes that we made, site links, comparison ads and product extensions certainly started to take effect as did the fact that all of our advertisers are now on AdWords-3, which we think is allowing them to be much more effective in terms of their bidding efforts, but I would generally describe the quarter as relatively modest from a quality perspective.</p>
          <p>I can &#x2013; Nikesh and others can maybe give you their perspective on mobile. The main thing that I think we're starting to see there is that advertisers are getting better at figuring out what kinds of ads work on the mobile devices. The simple addition, for example, of things like including a phone number or an offer is substantially increasing the click through rates and the ROI for the subset of advertisers who are correctly optimizing their mobile campaigns. So we're certainly seeing very strong growth there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to close on mobile. There really is a two &#x2013; if you think about it, a two prong strategy on it, which is one is driving innovation in an ecosystem on one side, so when you think of all of the applications like Goggles and all of the &#x2013; we would have seen on voice recognition and navigation, that's all innovation that basically drives people to the web with these new mobile applications. Obviously, the more people spend their time on it then they trigger into search and then monetization occurs. So for that perspective I think that that's the core engine of the mobile model. On China, I suggest that Eric answers that one, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben, I think the China stuff has been covered really quite well in the press. Just to review for everybody on the call, we announced a little more than a week ago three reasonably separate facts. One that there had been a cyber attack on Google probably emanating from China, origin, details unknown, still under investigation. We believe we've made the necessary technical changes to prevent such a future attack.</p>
          <p>The second was a &#x2013; we discovered in the course of that a perhaps related, perhaps unrelated, monitoring of human rights activists which we disclosed in the spirit that people would be aware that this may be occurring. And then the third was a decision for those reasons and other reasons, a decision for Google to no longer be willing to apply the censorship rules in China.</p>
          <p>This has a bunch of consequences. One of course is that we're in conversation with the Chinese government. The second is that our business in China is today unchanged. We continue to follow their laws, we continue to offer censored results, but at a reasonably short time from now we will be making some changes there. We've made a strong statement that we wish to remain in China. We like the Chinese people, we like our Chinese employees. We like the business opportunities there and we'd like to do that on somewhat different terms than we have. But we remain quite committed to being there. So I hope that helps.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Eric. Let's go to the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Justin Post from Merrill Lynch [Bank of America].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. My questions were on competitive issues in search. It looks like U.S. did accelerate where I would expect Bing to have the biggest impact. But are you seeing any share changes internationally related to any of your competitive initiatives? And then secondly on the partner environment, are you seeing more competitive pressure on signing up partners given some of the initiatives of your competitors out there? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the competition question I think it's better for us to focus on what we do and not what our competitors are doing. I think our results sort of speak for themselves and I'll let you judge how they're doing in the market. But it's a highly competitive market. The one area where there is probably a pretty big competitive event is whatever happens in China, which at this point is obviously unknown but that would clearly make a difference. Nikesh?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We continue to work closely with our partners both on the search and the display side. And most of our partnerships are based on very clear ROI and very clear benefits to partners and to us. And we haven't seen any change from our partner experiences in Q3 into Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In fact, on the content side, right, the announcement of VIVO, the announcement of Channel 4 and Channel 5 in U.K. through YouTube, there has in fact been an increase and we're very pleased about these types of partnerships.</p>
          <p>All right. Let's go to the next question, please. Thanks, Justin for your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Doug Anmuth from Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for taking the question. Two things, first, I was wondering if you could comment on the relative out-performance of the network business versus O&amp;O, if there is any particular dynamic in there that would make network growth higher. And then secondly, can you also comment on the higher marketing costs that you saw during the quarter and in particular how much of that is attributable to Android launches and the Droid in particular? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, so in terms of O&amp;O versus network, nothing really significant to disclose in this quarter. On marketing, I think it's fair to say there's two things there. There's a high level and then I'll let Nikesh give a couple of comments. T the higher level, remember when we said at the end of Q3 that we wanted to ramp up our investment in a bunch of areas to accelerate our growth. Marketing is one that you can actually affect in the short-term quite well. And because we have such a scientific approach to track it, we decided to invest a bit more in Q4. So Nikesh could probably give you a couple of examples of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. For example, many of our marketing efforts in Q4 have been targeted towards trying to educate and bring more and more small advertisers into the web where we can clearly measure the ROI and clearly understand what the impact of those is. So that's been one big focus, and the other big focus on the consumer side has just been to support some of our more consumer launches which have happened in Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Doug. We'll go to our next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Imran Khan from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Thank you for taking my questions. Two questions. You talked about search traffic increased five times on mobile. I'm trying to understand the unit economics. What kind of revenue per search on mobile are you guys seeing compared to the PC? And secondly, couple of questions &#x2013; more related questions on the cost side. You talked about spending more on the marketing in Q4, is it more of a one-time nature? Do you expect that to go down in Q1? And also how much you had bonus accruals for Q4 due to exceeding your full year plan? And should we think the bonus accrual will go down in Q1? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me start with bonus, and then we'll go back to the other question of marketing. So on bonus, here's what everybody has to remember because last year you'll remember there was a lot of questions about that. When we start a year, we reset the plan and as we progress through the year, if we varied a plan, whether positive or negative, then we have to make additional accruals but at the beginning of the year we just don't know that. So in 2009 -- so in 2010, next quarter, you can expect that we will reset our plan and therefore we'll go back to the base number.</p>
          <p>For this year, 2009 specifically, we had actually by Q3 figured out that we had a different trajectory than the base plan and what we did is in consequences is actually did a combination of cash up to Q3 and Q4 to make sure that we were properly provisioned for the bonus at year-end. And that's why you haven't seen like at the end of Q4 last year a big blip for that reason. We've increased it but just in proportion to the second half of the year. So that's the key on bonus.</p>
          <p>On marketing, I think the issue from a financial perspective clearly we do not give any prospective view on marketing. I think the most important thing is that we're really pleased with the experiments we're running right now in the marketing domain. And again, I'll circle back to Nikesh if he wants to give more precision on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm just going to echo what Patrick said. We are going to look at the campaigns that we have in place. We're going to look at our products that we have in place. And based on the ROI of those campaigns, we are going to ratchet our spend up or down in the following quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And on mobile, maybe Jonathan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sure Imran.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we hear you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I was muted. Sorry, Imran. I'm not going to give specifics on mobile RPMs versus desktop RPMs, but I think the main thing we can say is that the new formats, the targeting tools and the reporting that we're giving to the mobile advertisers is making the huge difference. And I mentioned click-to-call, putting phone numbers in the mobile ads making a difference.</p>
          <p>Try something like auto insurance on your phone and you'll see that the Progressive ad on the phone actually shows the phone number, while on the PC it doesn't. Nikesh gave the Razorfish example in his opening remarks and we're also letting the advertisers target high-end devices, specific devices or specific carriers, and we've also launched the reporting with analytics to the mobile phones. So we're starting to see much improved monetization in generalization across mobile.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, thanks for the questions. Let's go to the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Brian Pitz from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. Over the past couple of quarters you've rolled out several new ad formats such as site links and video ads on the Google.com site, could you discuss the adoption of these formats among advertisers and any commentary on if these formats have potentially lowered paid clicks and increased CPCs on the site? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the ad formats we launched in Q4 have been very successful. The advertisers have taken them up very effectively. We've actually used our direct sales force across the U.S. as well as across major parts of Europe and worked with some of our larger advertisers to introduce site links to some other ad formats. I'll pass the CPC question back to Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, we won't comment on the very specifics of each one of them, but it's very clear that when you have product listing ads that have &#x2013; come in either new cost per action pricing models, as that includes images and pricing within them or even the comparison ads that we've now kind of started introducing. I mean, all of these obviously provide more information to the user and therefore more value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So from that perspective. I mean, it's been a real positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For people that are confused, the easiest way to see what we're talking about, is just try typing something like Sears into Google and you'll see the example of what Nikesh was referring to is ad site links. And you &#x2013; it's intuitively easy to see how they lead to higher user engagement. You'll see the electronics and tools section, the deal of the day and you can see how much of a better experience that is both for the advertiser and for the user.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Brian. Let's go to the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Spencer Wang from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good afternoon. So my question is regarding YouTube monetization. I know you guys have talked about being happy with the monetization at YouTube, I was wondering if you could just give us, perhaps some updated metrics on how much of YouTube is being monetized. I think in previous calls you said it's tripled year-over-year, so any update on that would be great? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we're not going to give any specific metrics on YouTube. What I can say is the big shift we're continuing to see at YouTube is that, it's gone from being nice to have to an essential part of the media mix of any display campaign that our advertisers are planning and that's a big shift from our perspective and we continue to see people and if you look at YouTube, it's very easy to see, you will see that our home page ads are there on there, our watch paid -- watch page ads are there on there and we've been able to expand that across the world in many markets where we have YouTube in place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Great performance &#x2013; I mean, just to close on, just when people think of kind of key insights on YouTube, right, the home page is nearly sold out in Q4 and that was a great testimony of the power of YouTube. And we're now running ads in 20 countries worldwide. So again, to give you a sense of perspective of how successful the YouTube has been. So I hope that's useful, Spencer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's go to another question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Scott Devitt from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you. There was data in the quarter that suggested that large branded retailers grew online sales at roughly 15% in the quarter and that smaller retailers experienced slower growth and given your broad visibility into ad spending and particularly the long tail and smaller advertisers, I wonder if you could just comment on ad spending trends by advertiser size? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I alluded to this earlier, our larger advertisers continue to increase at online spending and upgrading search and online display within their marketing mix. So, retail has been particularly strong during the holiday season, most of the large retailers have created very robust websites and they are able to target a very large host of key words and to some degree automated this stuff and we continue to work with some of our smaller advertisers and bring them to the fray. It's clearly a mix issue and a seasonal issue where we've seen the larger advertisers outperform the smaller ones.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your question, Scott. Let's go to the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Sandeep Aggarwal from Collins Stewart.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. Can please rank your non-core search businesses in terms of the growth potential, i.e. display, YouTube, mobile and apps and then also any color you can add on your partnerships/competitive dynamics with Google and Apple?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Eric. It depends on whether you're looking at asset growth or percentage growth. Obviously the smaller ones are going to grow large &#x2013; grow faster than the larger ones. We've said for a pretty long time that the next huge business for us is display. And we've put in place a series of acquisitions, a series of products, we've integrated them, we're seeing the benefit of that. I think one of the stories that's not really come out yet is how successful Google is at display and I think you'll see that especially in 2010.</p>
          <p>So if I were to talk about absolute numbers, that are not search, I would say that's probably your number one. But obviously the smaller ones will grow faster on a relative basis. There the most obvious one in terms of growth rate will be mobile. And a lot of that depends on the competitive dynamics of the industry, how successful the new AFMA product from us is, the AdMob acquisition as that comes through. We have a lot of evidence that people are moving to these data &#x2013; data friendly mobile devices very, very quickly. Our search traffic is quite a &#x2013; growth rate is quite a bit faster than on PCs and we expect that to continue. So for lots of reasons 2010 will be a year of significant mobile revenue growth for the whole industry and I'm sure Google will play a major part of that.</p>
          <p>With respect to Apple, it's probably better to say that Apple, I as I former board member have a special spot for Apple in my heart, but I will tell you that Apple is a very well run company and they've got a lot of very good stuff coming. We have a couple of very good partnerships with them and it's clear we also compete with them in a couple of areas and my guess is that's a pretty stable situation for a while.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Eric. Thank you for your questions. Let's go to the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Jeetil Patel from Deutsche Bank Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks. Two questions. One, just taking a step back, you've got a $23 billion business built around advertising and there's seems like it's a &#x2013; got some sensitivity to the macro environment these days. I guess broadly, I guess, as you look forward at the broader ecosystem of consumers and business partners you work with, I guess are there newer, more unique ways of kind of adding value to the broader ecosystem in terms of new revenue models or business models that are kind of maybe worthwhile exploring as you look ahead and to try to break away from the sensitivity of the ad business that seems to be tied to macro.</p>
          <p>Second on mobile your strategy seems to be a little bit perplexing in that you've got a partnership strategy with a slew of handset OEMs and then the Nexus One, I guess, is that a comparison of network and O&amp;O? Is that kind of how we should think about the evolution of that strategy or are you just trying to push the smart phone category and be obviously the interface of the brand that consumers use to access information through those devices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will let Eric answer both of those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On your question about the macro, we said last year and reiterate that we are not immune to global economic trends. I think the evidence would say that we fared better than most companies in a global economic downturn and hopefully global recovery that is clearly underway at this point. We've seen that at least for six months, maybe longer. So I'm not so worried about our reliance on ads, which is sort of the premise of your question.</p>
          <p>From our perspective, our goal as a business is to solve the advertisers' and the other businesses' problems, which is ultimately about selling product and marketing and so forth. We are in various conversations about trying to do alternative ways to distribute digital content. We are trying to come up with new ways of using GPS data to sort of advertise against position and place. We have a lot of initiatives of this category.</p>
          <p>The ones that will probably have the biggest impact are not in mass, as much as those are exciting, will probably be in the display area because in aggregate size our display business will give people an opportunity to reach people with visual stories, with images, with narratives that they couldn't do with search text. So it's probably the case that the combination of local advertising, all of the things that we're doing in the display plus some of these new and more speculative things, we're likely to drive a lot of new ways of solving the businesses problems.</p>
          <p>We also &#x2013; and we haven't talked very much about this, but we've quite a healthy enterprise business that's going to grow we think quite rapidly over the next few years as people move from the older legacy, PC-centric, traditional operating system model to the new web-based application model. And the trend there is clear. Everyone is moving there and we're going to be one of the leaders there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Eric, do you want to comment on the issue of mobile and the question that was about the perplexity of our business model?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The question &#x2013; the second part of your question of course was on Nexus One and that model. And I think there is a lot of confusion about that. It's probably easiest to understand in the following way. What the Nexus One is really about is a new way of buying a phone. And the Nexus One is simply the first of a series of examples where you can essentially purchase a phone online from one or multiple manufacturers, self provision it and have it just work. And we think that's a natural evolution of a particular model. It doesn't &#x2013; it does not exclude the other models. I think it's compatible with them in the sense that the retail model will continue to be quite successful. So far our partners have understood that message and they have been okay with it and the Nexus One itself, of course, is a magnificent product.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Eric. Let's go to the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Jason Helfstein from Oppenheimer &amp; Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks. I've two. First question, are you seeing &#x2013; do you think Bing is having an impact on the cost per click? And then number two, do you expect the tax rate to rise in 2010 with the improvement in U.S. revenues? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer the second one first and then we can come back to the first one. But the &#x2013; on the issue of taxation, obviously we don't give any kind of guidance forward. We were &#x2013; we continue to monitor very closely all of the issues related to those tax bills and the legislation. And obviously we're, like most American companies that have large international presence, we continue to believe that it would be kind of a disadvantage to have kind of some of the proposals that have been tabled. So we're going to continue to participate in the process very actively and make our voice heard, and but we cannot speculate as to the out comes of these things.</p>
          <p>In terms of Bing, Jonathan, do you want to give a comment on it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. We generally do not comment on competitors. We think our CPC's are not generally impacted by what other search engines do. Our CPCs are set by competition among advertisers and we have got a very competitive auction market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the essence of the point. Right, I mean, people choose. So why don't we go to the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Gene Munster from Piper Jaffray.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you can guys talk a little bit about the impact of Nexus One on the model, specifically to the margins going forward? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In its most simplistic form, we do not track percentage margins as part of our business model. What we're looking for is opportunities to innovate, to ship products that we think are kind of disruptive, game changing and to the benefit of users and the Nexus One is a great example of that in setting the bar as to what a great mobile handset should look like and it will &#x2013; it will have it's own margin and that's how we're focused on building the business. Let's go to the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Mark May from Needham &amp; Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks. Two please, we've been hearing from a number of AdSense partners that Google's TAC rate is trending toward Google's favor. Is the fourth quarter TAC decline a reflection of a declining trend in TAC, or is it just seasonal.</p>
          <p>And then the second question is I think investors have a good sense of the assets and such that Google brings to bear in the online display space. But it doesn't have a good sense of the size of Google's display business and the trend in market share there. So the question is just how big in fact is Google in display today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the TAC issues. We have a lot of great partnerships with so many of our AdSense partners and other partners. The fact that it's been trending down has to do simply with kind of mix issues and it's not really tied to seasonality. So we &#x2013; there is nothing of a big surprise there in our mind and we continue to have great partnerships with all of our partners on AdSense and others.</p>
          <p>In the case of display, I think that the few facts that we shared already on the last webcast on display are worth kind of mentioning is the industry itself is a $17 billion industry. So it's a big pie and if you just take the TV advertising industry which is $117 billion industry, that is all eyeballs that are shifting over time to the Internet or digital content, that's also going to make it, some of it is going to make its way progressively to display. So there's no doubt that it's a huge pie to go after. And then from our side, we clearly do not comment on the specifics of our market share or our revenue dollars but I think you should take from the tonality of Eric's comments that this is really a big focus for us because it's has a lot of runway and I'll leave it at that if you do not mind.</p>
          <p>Let's go to the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Youssef Squali from Jefferies and Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Two questions please. First on mobile, we've seen from some third party data that the iPhone may account for almost as much as 50% of overall mobile traffic. First is that similar to what you're hearing or what you've seen? And second &#x2013; and I guess related to that, Eric you said earlier or you mentioned that you see the Apple relationship as stable. Are we to &#x2013; are we inferring from that that you think the upcoming renegotiations of that deal and potential of it moving to a competitor likely to move in your favor? And on the display side, can you give us a sense of the percentage of search advertisers that are buying display from you today and what is the major push back from those that don't? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So this is Eric. We're not going to speculate on the market share of Apple mobile products. That's for Apple to discuss with you. And as far as I can tell, our business structures with Apple are quite stable. I'm not going to speculate on any deals of any kind, rumored, true, not true, you name it. We're not going to talk about it. On the display question --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the display side, there is a reasonable number of our search advertisers who also buy display. Actually it depends on their campaign objectives. If their campaign objectives are direct response oriented they favor search as well as certain parts of the display network, which would give them a higher conversion rate and higher click-through rate as it relates to the advertising. If they are more brand-focused they tend to overweight display in their campaigns and in that category clearly they have many choices, including YouTube as far as where they spend their premium brand dollars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take one or two more questions. So let's take two more questions, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll take our next question from Steve Weinstein from Pacific Crest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually most of my questions have been asked. So I'll leave time for someone else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Steve. So, one more question, maybe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll go next to Marianne Wolk from Susquehanna Financial Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Given how attractive you're making the new display products to advertisers and the big push with your sales force, have you seen any of your advertisers shift budget from search into the newer display offering? And then as a follow-up, how do we think about what's going on at the content network, where are you in transforming that from basically contextual advertising to display?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Eric. On the question of shifting. My experience with advertisers is they do not shift the ad. And the reason is that the decisions that they make are sort of stand-alone. In other words, they will simply maximize the amount of search advertising they do to maximize their revenue and then the display decision is a decision they make which is both a revenue and also strategic decision around their branding and so forth and that's growing as we can offer &#x2013; if you will, the science of Google applied to the display business. And that's our differentiator. We do it better than anybody else and that's why we continue to win all of those deals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. In close, we're just running out of time. We're going to close on this for now. I want to thank everyone for taking your time to listen to our call today. As you can tell we're very excited about moving the business forward in 2010. I want to take a moment to thank also all of the Googlers that have been listening to this call, for their hard work. 2009 was a rollercoaster year, very strong performance and really the achievement of everybody on the team. So for &#x2013; on behalf of the management team thank you to all and thank you for listening and Jonathan and I will talk to you in half an hour. Cheers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And this concludes today's conference. We thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>