<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1303413" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-04-15</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8238</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Maria Shim, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Patrick Pichette, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Susan Wojcicki, Vice President, Product Management</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Jeff Huber, Senior Vice President, Engineering</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">James Mitchell</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Nikesh Arora</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Mark Mahaney</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Ben Schachter</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Imran Khan</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Justin Post</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Douglas Anmuth</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Brian Pitz</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Spencer Wang</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Ross Sandler</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Mary Meeker</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Jeetil Patel</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Jason Helfstein</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Youssef Squali</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Mark May</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst">Jordan Rohan</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst">Marianne Wolk</participant>
      <participant id="22" type="analyst">Aaron Kessler</participant>
      <participant id="23" type="analyst">Colin Gillis</participant>
      <participant id="24" type="analyst">Scott Devitt</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day and welcome to the Google Inc. Conference Call.  Today's call is being recorded.  At this time, I would like to turn the call over to Ms. Maria Shim, Investor Relations.  Please go ahead ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Connie Good afternoon everyone and welcome to today's first quarter 2010 earnings conference call.  With us are Patrick Pichette, Chief Financial Officer; Jeff Huber, Senior Vice President of Engineering; Susan Wojcicki, Vice President of Product Management; and Nikesh Arora, President, Global Sales Operations and Business Development.  Also as you know we are now distributing our earnings release exclusively through our newly revamped Investor Relations website located at investor.google.com.  So going forward please refer to our IR website for our earnings releases as well as supplementary slides that accompany the call.  This call today is also being webcast from investor.google.com.  A replay of this call will also be available on our website in a few hours.</p>
          <p>Now let me quickly cover the Safe Harbor.  Some of the statements we make today may be considered forward-looking, including statements regarding investments in our innovation agenda, expected performance of our business and our expected level of capital expenditures.  These statements involve risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially and reflect our opinions only as of the date of this presentation.  We undertake no obligation to revise or publicly release the results of any revision to these forward-looking statements in light of new information or future events.</p>
          <p>Please refer to our SEC filings including our Annual Report on Form 10-K for the year ended December 31, 2009, as well as our earnings press release for a more detailed description of the risk factors that may affect our results. Copies can be obtained from the SEC or by visiting investor.google.com</p>
          <p>In addition, certain financial measures we use on this call, such as operating profit and operating margin are expressed on a non-GAAP basis and have been adjusted to exclude charges related to stock-based compensation.  We have also adjusted our net cash provided by operating activities to remove capital expenditures, which we refer to as free cash flow.  Our GAAP results and GAAP to non-GAAP reconciliation can be found in our earnings press release.</p>
          <p>Now, with that, I will now turn the call over to Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Maria.  Good afternoon, everyone.  It's Patrick Pichette speaking.  Thank you for joining us.  Starting the new year provides us with a great opportunity to tune and streamline our quarterly earnings communications.  So as a result, we have today for you a new format for the call.  First, the two calls we had last year will be merged into a single call going forward and a slightly longer for the Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Second, Eric will not be joining us going forward so I'll be leading the call.  In the new format, Jonathan Rosenberg and I will review the quarter with prepared remarks and then Nikesh Arora, our head of Global Sales and Operations will be joining us for Q&amp;A.  Unfortunately today Jonathan couldn't be with us but however what we have is Jeff Huber, our Senior Vice President of Engineering for ads and Susan Wojcicki, our Vice President for advertising products sitting in for Jonathan.  So, here we go.</p>
          <p>Let me start by giving you some high level thoughts about our situation at Google before I go into the details of our Q1 performance.  As we enter 2010, it's really clear that the digital economy continues to grow rapidly and at Google, our users and advertisers all continue to benefit from this profound and positive trend.</p>
          <p>Our Q1 results are simply a reflection of these trends and this really fuels our optimism as we continue to invest in innovation for the long run.  Consequently, we are continuing to invest heavily in people, products and acquisitions.</p>
          <p>So you see this already in our results for Q1.  On people, we've already stepped up hiring which is evident, obviously, with the numbers presented, and we expect to continue hiring aggressively through the year.  We have a strong pipeline of candidates, primarily focused on engineering and sales.  And we're on boarding them to fuel our growth agenda as fast as possible.</p>
          <p>On product, we continue really to push the envelope on 2 fronts.  First, we're intensely focused on user experience.</p>
          <p>Our continued success really depends on delighting users with differentiated products that really inspire.  Think of Google Goggles, for example.</p>
          <p>Second, we're continuing it improve our ads business to show the right ad in the right format to the right person at the right time, all this regardless of device.  Susan and Jeff will really cover each of &#x2013; in the coming minutes both of these actions.</p>
          <p>Finally, acquisitions, we've been very active this far &#x2013; so far this year, and we have a strong M&amp;A pipeline in place.  It's really designed to build on our existing focus areas and to bring new talent and new technology to Google feeding our entrepreneurial spirit.  It really matters to us.</p>
          <p>So in sum, we continue to be incredibly excited by the opportunities in front of us and in consequence, we should expect to see continued investment in each of these areas.</p>
          <p>On the business front, Q1 was really a strong quarter.  The healthy momentum from Q4 and the general economic recovery has simply continued resulting in a very positive start to the new year for us.  Large advertisers have come back in force versus last year reflecting really an improved economy and a few really key important trends.</p>
          <p>So for example, it's clear now that our offerings are much broader in scope and by this, I mean, they offer highly measurable but also integrated campaigns across search, display and mobile.  As a result, our conversation with advertisers, they're becoming more and more strategic because of this integration.  And you can see this in our results and our performance.  By this, I mean, we perform well across every major product area including search, display, mobile and enterprise in Q1.  Running on all cylinders.</p>
          <p>So search, Google.com was very strong.  Great performance across all geographies and all major verticals including retail, travel, local, technology and finance.  Growth in display was also really strong.  Q4 momentum continued across all regions, products and channels.  The Google Content Network was strong, driven by increased demand in consumer package goods and entertainment.</p>
          <p>The Ad Exchange is also gaining great traction as we move all the buyers and sellers into the latest version of the platform.  And finally, we saw very impressive growth on YouTube with several exciting new content deals signed.</p>
          <p>Mobile, a third axis, another great, very important area for Google is also growing very nicely.  Benefiting from both the continued growth in the smartphone volumes and Internet user and usage on these eye-hand mobile devices.</p>
          <p>Finally, enterprise recently launched a host of successful integrations including a large deployment at &#x2013; for example at KLM, just one example among many.</p>
          <p>All this great performance is reflected in our financial results and our trajectories.  So I'll now, if you'll allow me, go through our results quickly.  So financially, gross revenue grew 23% year-over-year to $6.8 billion.  Google website's revenue grew up 20% year-over-year to 4.4 billion with strength as I mentioned across all major geographies and verticals.</p>
          <p>Our AdSense revenue was up 24% year-over-year to 2 billion reflecting a gain of continued strength in the Google Content Network, an important part of our display business.  Other revenue was also up 68% year-over-year to 300 million and that includes the revenue from the sales of our Nexus One product.</p>
          <p>Global aggregate paid click growth remained healthy, up 15% year-over-year and up 5% quarter-over-quarter.  Aggregate cost per click growth was up 7% year-over-year but down 4% quarter-over-quarter.  You should note that FX had a positive impact on the year-over-year on CPC growth and also a negative impact quarter-over-quarter.  A lot of movement in FX year-over-year and quarter-over-quarter.  Remember, too that this is an aggregate number which includes both google.com, but also the AdSense properties.</p>
          <p>Turning to our geographic performance, revenue from the U.S. was up 22% year-over-year to 3.2 billion.  In our earning slides, which you'll find on our Investor Relations website, you'll see that we have broken down our revenue by U.S., UK and rest of the world to show the impact of FX and the benefits from our hedging programs.  So please refer to those slides for the exact calculations.</p>
          <p>International revenue accounted for 53% of our total revenue, or 3.6 billion, up 24% year-over-year which includes $10 million of benefit from our hedging programs and this is a big difference compared to 154 million of benefits in Q1 of last year.  Using fixed exchange rates, our international revenue would have been roughly 242 million lower year-over-year.  Finally, the UK was up 15% year-over-year to 842 million.  So very strong performance right across the board on the revenue.</p>
          <p>Let me turn to expenses for a moment.  Traffic acquisition costs were 1.7 billion or 26% of total advertising revenue.  The other cost of revenue was 741 million, including stock-based compensation of 6 million, which also expenses related to the sale of Nexus One.</p>
          <p>Finally, all operating expenses totaled 1.8 billion, including approximately 285 million of stock-based compensation.  The increase year-over-year in OpEx was primarily due to increases in payroll and advertising and promotion expense.  As a result of all this, our non-GAAP operating profit, which does exclude stock-based compensation increased to $2.8 billion in Q1 resulting in non-GAAP operating margin of 41%, up approximately 180 basis points year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Head count was up 800 approximately versus Q4 of last year, ending the quarter with approximately 20,600 full-time employees.  Finally, our effective tax rate, 22% for Q1.</p>
          <p>For a minute, let me turn to cash management.  Other income and expenses was 18 million for Q1, which include great progress in our portfolio management performance, but also largely offset by the timing and accounting impact of hedging expenses associated with the FASB 133.  For more detail on OI&amp;E, again please refer to the slides that accompany this call on our IR website.</p>
          <p>So all of this turns out into operating cash flow which was very strong at 2.6 billion.  CapEx for the quarter, $239 million.  Again, primarily related to our data center operations.  As a reminder, CapEx is lumpy from quarter to quarter depending on where we're able to make these investments.  Free cash flow finished the quarter with a strong $2.3 billion.</p>
          <p>So in summary, we're very pleased with the performance in Q1 across revenue, margins and cash flow.  As a result, we are very optimistic and therefore pushing ahead with significant investments as I outlined to you a few moments ago.</p>
          <p>Finally, let me remind you as I do every year at this time that our revenue typically exhibits some seasonality between Q1, Q2 and Q3 because of the coming summer months.</p>
          <p>With that and before we open it to questions, we'll have Susan and Jeff cover their comments and then we'll come back to Q&amp;A.  Thank you and I'll turn it to Susan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Patrick.  I'd like to take this opportunity today to talk about some of the big areas of investment in our advertising business, search, display and mobile and how they are going so far.  We see a lot of opportunity to innovate in these categories and to make the ad better more useful.  As we expand to new kinds of inventory beyond search, our goal is to enable high performance, cross-media campaigns from within AdWords.</p>
          <p>Let me start with search. Starting about a year ago, we asked ourselves why do search ads just have to be text links.  In organic search, the right result might be a video, a book, or an update from a social network.  We call this universal search.  But ads are also information, they are commercial information and in many cases, it may be more useful to the user and the advertiser if we show a video, or a picture or product in the ad.  For example, if you search on the query, "HP all-in-one printer", some of the ads now include pictures of HP printers, prices and where you can buy them.  Or if you're looking for a movie and you search on "The Losers", the ad may give you the option to watch the movie trailer right within the ad.</p>
          <p>Other ads which we call site links enable advertisers to drive traffic to specific parts of their site.  The query, "Toys 'R' Us" is a good example of this.  With links to products the retailer is promoting, such as Nerf toy specials or pre-ordering Barbies.  The idea is to make the ads more useful and therefore higher performing and so far they're doing well.  Click through rates on site links for example are up as much as 30 to 40%.</p>
          <p>We also want to give advertisers more data and insight into their campaigns and customers.  Users usually go through a progression of searches and can interact with a number of ads before actually buying the product.  For example, a user may search and click on ads first for digital camera and then on Canon before actually clicking on an ad for the PowerShot S90 and buying the camera.</p>
          <p>To help use advertisers optimize for this behavior, we launched a new reporting feature this quarter called the Search Funnel, which tells advertisers about those earlier searches and the ads the users interacted with earlier in the buying process.  By thinking about the right portfolio of keywords, advertisers can maximize their conversion.</p>
          <p>Moving on to our display business, we've seen very strong momentum.  We're investing heavily in 3 different areas, our platform, which includes the DoubleClick suite of products, our Ad Exchange, and our Content Network and YouTube.  We're bringing the performance, efficiency and measurability to the display world like we did with search which we believe can overall grow the display market and benefit everyone.</p>
          <p>On the platform side this quarter, we launched the largest Google and DoubleClick integration to date.  A new version of DoubleClick for Publishers which has been rewritten on Google technologies.  The new version gives publishers more data and better tools to manage and maximize their return in directly and indirectly sold ad space.</p>
          <p>We're also doubling down on our new Ad Exchange, the second pillar in our display strategy.  It's ramping nicely and publishers and advertisers are getting great results.  Some publishers are increasing their yields by as much as 130% when compared to ads sold directly to ad networks.</p>
          <p>One of the key features that we're very excited about on the new exchange is real-time bidding, which enables advertisers to bid on an impression-by-impression basis using their own data.  By bringing this level of efficiency to display advertising buying, everyone wins.</p>
          <p>And third, on the Content Network, we've introduced a number of new features in the past year.  It's a long list.  Interspace advertising, frequency capping, above the fold targeting, new measurement tools and many new formats among other features.  Combined, they create a compelling platform for display advertisers to reach users globally.</p>
          <p>This quarter, we added a new feature that I'd like to talk about called remarketing.  Remarketing enables advertisers to show ads to users who have visited their website or their YouTube channel.  So if you're shopping around for a vacation destination or go to one resort site and then leave, when you visit another site in our network, that resort could show you an ad with a discount coupon.  As a user, this means I can get a much more compelling ad.  As an advertiser, it's an opportunity to connect with interested users.</p>
          <p>Mobile is also doing very well. This will be an increasingly important form of advertising as users transition to smartphones with full browsers.  We want to make it easy for advertisers to extend their existing campaigns to mobile rather than having to start from scratch.  When advertisers run on desktop and mobile, we enable them to separate their campaign stats by desktop or mobile to understand their mobile performance.  Many of them are surprised by how much mobile activity they have received.  Based on this information, they can decide how to customize their mobile campaigns going forward.</p>
          <p>We also rolled out new formats and targeting options specific for mobile.  This quarter, we launched a click-to-call feature that automatically puts a phone number in the ad that's running on a smartphone.  So if you're looking for auto insurance and do that query from your Android or iPhone, the ads will include a call, a number to call.  Not surprisingly, this has increased click-through or should I say call-through?  I'm just scratching the surface of all the innovations our ad team is working on, but I have to hand it over to Jeff now.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Susan.  Across all our products, we push to push ourselves to continually innovate.  We believe in open platforms and encourage everyone else to push innovation too.  Our efforts in mobile are a great example of this at work.  Eric Schmidt mentioned in a speech at the Mobile World Conference in Barcelona in February, that we're taking a mobile first approach to most everything we do.  That means doing things that take advantage of the unique characteristics of mobile smartphones.</p>
          <p>One of those is that your smartphone knows where you are, your location.  So this quarter, we launched a feature called near me now that essentially turns your location into the search query.  If you go to Google.com from a smartphone, you'll see the near me now link right under the search box.  Click on it to see restaurants, caf&#xE9;s, shops, gas stations, ATMs and other things of interest that are closest to you.</p>
          <p>Another common use case is where you're searching for something at home and then want to find it again when you're out and about.  Our new stars and search feature helps out there.  You do a search, say for a chili recipe and when you find a great result, you click on the star next to it.  Later when you're at the grocery store to pick up the ingredients, you just repeat the search with your smartphone, which is easy to do with the suggest feature, just type the first character or two.  The query will pop up or with voice search which is increasingly ubiquitous across the platforms, and that starred result shows right up at the top.</p>
          <p>The same starred results now work on maps, too.  Do a search at home or work, like on an address or for a restaurant, click a star right next to the right result and that star shows up in your map on the smartphone making it easy to get directions or get more information about it.  These are small features in some ways, but a big innovation in how smartphones can integrate into your everyday life.</p>
          <p>Our open platforms, Android and Chrome are gaining a lot of momentum.  Android is now powering 34 devices which is up 70% quarter-over-quarter from 12 different OEMs and over 60,000 Android devices are sold and activated every day.  Our whole mantra with Android is open.  First the Android OS itself is open for partners to modify and extend on their own.  Then the Android market for apps is open for all developers which is driving a lot of growth and great apps, we're now at over 38,000 apps, up 70% quarter-over-quarter.  The net effect is to make web-ready smartphones more widely available.  It is helping drive a lot of mobile search and apps usage.</p>
          <p>Chrome is also growing really well.  Mostly driven by its technical innovations and performance and in security relative to other browsers.  A new Chrome feature we launched just a couple of weeks ago helps address language as a barrier to web use around the world.  Chrome can now automatically translate any page you're viewing into any one of 52 different languages.  So if you're an English speaker and want to read the local news in Paris, you can go to lemonde.fr and chrome will offer to translate the page for you.  Uptake has been great. We're already translating over 60 million pages per day.  If we can help knock down the language barrier through innovative features like this, the web becomes a lot more accessible and useful for everyone around the world.</p>
          <p>Our latest open ecosystem effort is the Apps Marketplace for Google apps.  Many of our enterprise customers want to move more of their operations to the cloud, including applications Google doesn't offer, like CRM, accounting, project management, work flow automation, HR, the list goes on.  The Apps Marketplace has had thousands of enterprise apps purchased and installed already, all integrated with the Google Apps experience.</p>
          <p>Finally, we're looking forward to our Google I/O developer conference coming up in May.  I/O sold out in a few days.  Developers know that in the event's short history we've used it to announce some pretty amazing things, in addition to covering a huge amount of content on how they can innovate with and leverage Google's open platforms.  When you open up the web and unleash the passion and innovation of thousands and thousands of developers, great things happen.  Thanks for your time.  Back to Patrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jeff.  And thank you, Susan.  So what we'll do now is I'll invite Nikesh also to join us and ask Maria to open up the call for questions and then Maria will direct the questions for us.  Maria?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, can we start taking questions, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />  And we'll take our first question from James Mitchell from Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thank you very much.  2 questions and I apologize because one of them is really nitpicky.  But in your cash flow statement, you have got a re-purchase of stock, minus 97 million and I thought that Google wouldn't buy back stock until the AdMob acquisition was complete?</p>
          <p>And then second question is with regard to domestic and international revenue, it's great that your domestic revenue is growing almost as fast now as your international revenue, but it's also a little bit surprising to me.  Is that primarily because you've got more new activities like Nexus One contributing domestically than internationally, or does that reflect a more V-shaped recovery domestically than internationally?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I'll take the first question and then I'll let Nikesh can answer the second one.  On the first one, it's because when we bought On2, what we wanted to do is it was a share transaction, you will remember.  And because it was a share transaction, we decided to actually rebuy back the shares thereafter to make it a cash transaction.  So it's that simple for the transaction.  For the international, Nikesh?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  Hi, James.  Thanks for your question.  I think it is a combination of the things you suggest and a bit more.  We are seeing a better recovery in the domestic market definitely if you look at the comps from last year, clearly, the numbers look much better.  We are seeing tremendous activity from our large advertisers who are coming back in droves and actually reconfirming their faith in search advertising so that's all working.  Plus many of our product innovations start in the U.S. which allows to us drive those revenues faster in the U.S.</p>
          <p>Having said that, internationally our revenues did not take as material a dip as relative to the U.S. so clearly, the comps are much stronger on the international side.  And it is a basket of many, many, many countries, so we're seeing recovery in the major markets.  Some of the markets are still not on that curve of recovery as we're seeing with some of the more mature larger markets in Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're very happy with both trajectories.  Thanks for your question, James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we take the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Mark Mahaney from Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, Mark.  Is Mark with us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we can hear you, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry about that.  What percentage of your revenue now would come from mobile, display and enterprise gross basis?  Secondly, is Nexus One as a group profitable?  And third, you can give us a little color on the CPC rates?  Given the dramatic falloff in conversion rates due to the economy in the fourth quarter of '08, first quarter of '09, it's reasonable to expect that perhaps CPCs would have risen more.  Is there something else we should think about as tempering the growth in CPCs now?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Remind me your first question, Mark?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What percentage of your revenue comes from mobile, display and enterprise combined?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  So that one, unfortunately we can't give you.  We don't divulge that kind of information.  On the Nexus and then Susan can give you the answer on CPC.  On the Nexus One, it is a profitable business for us.  We don't give more details on the economics, but we were &#x2013; we are driving the business to be a profitable business from the get-go.  So on CPC, maybe Susan can give us more comments as to what's going on there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, I'll give a couple of comments about the CPCs.  So I think there are a number of trends that we see.  I think it's important to remember, first of all that the CPC and the numbers we release are an aggregate number and so there are a couple things happening.  One of them has to do with the growth rates of the different regions and CPCs being different in the different regions.</p>
          <p>The second thing which I believe is a long-term positive for Google but may be reflected in the CPC number here is that we are releasing a lot of tools to enable advertise to try to find more what I'll call long-tail keywords.  So keywords that they might not have been bidding on beforehand and that they might not be the more competitive ones.  So as a result, the CPCs may vary.  And we believe long term that's good because we're actually selling more keywords and the auctions are becoming more competitive, but it may change the mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Can we take the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  And we'll go next to Ben Schachter from Broadpoint AmTech.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys.  A few questions.  One, do you expect to continue to be the default search provider on Apple products going forward?  And then if I looked at the quarter correctly, it looks like you hired about 800 people.  Is there anything unique about that number?  Is that roughly the right number you think you're going to be hiring on a go-forward basis?  And then finally, if there is any other particular comments that you can make around Eric not being on the call, anything else we should read into that?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  So why don't we take them in reverse order.  Eric's everywhere.  Eric is at every public &#x2013; I have seen him in Abu Dhabi and then fly across to D.C. the next day.  And he's everywhere.  So the fact that we've just decided to streamlined our process just for earnings doesn't mean that Eric is not available and he is clearly leading as spokesperson for the strategy of the company.  So it's very transparent and everywhere.  So on that point, it was simply an issue of streamlining and making more focus on financial results for this call.  You shouldn't read any more or less than that in this decision.</p>
          <p>On the 800 people, look, we have talked about ever since last summer that we're trying to ramp up our machine to hire back specifically in engineering, specifically in the support of sales where we see great opportunities and it takes a couple of quarters to ramp up the machine so that we get the levels that we want.  So we're very pleased with the hiring we've done.  The bar at Google &#x2013; let me reemphasize that has not changed.  It is incredibly high.  But we're very pleased of the on boarding that we've seen this quarter and now that this infrastructure is in place you can expect us to continue to invest heavily in this form.  And we have so many projects that we would love to have more engineers right now that we'd like to fuel our growth that it is really paramount for us to continue to focus on it.</p>
          <p>On the Apple, maybe Jeff can comment?  Mute?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we can't speculate on the specific relationship around search.  We have a &#x2013; have historically had a strong relationship with Apple across a number of different areas, and we hope to and look forward to continuing that in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator can we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />  And we'll take our next question from Imran Khan from J.P. Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi.  Thank you very much for taking my questions.  I have 2 questions.  One, question is about paid clicks growth rate.  So considering that mobile is growing significantly faster and some of the international countries are growing significantly faster, paid clicks growth rate 15%, is it fair to assume that the domestic paid clicks growth rate has decelerated significantly.  And can you give us some color how should we think about the domestic rate clicks growth rate?</p>
          <p>And second question is more of a long-term threat to Google.  If we look at the third-party data, it seems like that Facebook and other social networking sites still &#x2013; while still low, becoming a bigger part, they're growing significantly faster as a traffic source to a lot of your big customers, like eBay.  How do you think Facebook or other social networking sites is a big long-term threat to the Google business model?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, why don't I let Jeff talk about the issue of Facebook and then Susan can cover the CPC growth rates.  Susan, do you want to start or Jeff?  Okay, Jeff, start please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  I mean, with regards to other folks out there, I guess, our net view is that we don't see things as zero sum game whatsoever.  Looking at the Internet and the vibrancy and rate of growth across the Internet, other people are growing.  We're very happy with our growth so we don't see that as a significant issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Susan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  I'll comment on the paid click growth.  Overall, I think we've been very happy with the number and the growth that was seen.  And it's a result of a number of things, certainly, the advertisers coming back.  Some of the largest advertisers spending more money on Google as well as growth across the board in all regions.  But with also some of the new ad formats that I spoke about have brought more clicks as to advertisers because they're coming up with formats that are more compelling for users and offering information that's very useful for the users onboard and that's causing a lot of growth in paid clicks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  So, Imran, in closing on that one, the bottom line is we see it everywhere.  It's not one versus another.  And that's true for both of the questions that you've asked.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Can we take the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Justin Post from Bank of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  2 things.  Last year, you were able to give us some intra-quarter guidance about how the quarter started and ended.  Do you feel better about a trajectory of year-over-year growth exiting the quarter than you did entering the quarter?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, on marketing spend, I think, it's up 48% year-over-year excluding stock-based comp.  I always thought of you more as a technology-driven company.  Why so much marketing spend and what &#x2013; could you talk about maybe your ROI thinking about it, or what is it really going to get for Google?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  So on the latter one, on the marketing spend, look, it's clear that we have opportunities and I'll give you a couple of examples.  One is there's a ballot in Europe right now for Chrome and &#x2013; or there are markets in which there's a lot of appetite for on boarding customers and so we get great ROIs, and Nikesh, maybe you have additional comments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's important to understand.  Our marketing spend for the most part is ROI-based.  We look at &#x2013; we spend marketing dollars to go and acquire advertisers on our B2B side, we spend marketing dollars to promote various products.  But it's very clear for us to understand for each dollar we spend what return we get in terms of long-term value for each customer that is acquired for any of these products which create additional monetization across our properties.  So you can expect us to spend marketing dollars as and when we see &#x2013; feel it's relevant for our long-term strategy to have lots more users for our products and lots more advertisers...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In closing on that one, Justin, the &#x2013; if you think of G&amp;A in general, right, at Google, you'll find that our G&amp;A is actually at 20-some percent of revenue.  I mean, it's not moving that much and what you see is a shift between regular G&amp;A is actually going down, which is good news and you're seeing if we have an incremental dollar in a great &#x2013; as Nikesh said, good ROI base, I mean we should take the opportunity on that.</p>
          <p>As it relates to your first question, we don't give comments &#x2013; I mean we had such a crisis in the last 18 months that back then it may have made sense to give some color about quarters but clearly Q4 to Q1, we just look at the level of economic activity.  It is continuing to pick up which is a great benefit to Google</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Can we take the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Doug Anmuth from Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thanks for taking the question.  First question is on the Nexus One and in particular, can you comment on how many phones you sold during the quarter and if possible, you could change the distribution plan going forward so that they actually are in stores rather than just online?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, you can comment on China as well and perhaps give us an update there in terms of what you are seeing and any thoughts you might have on what percentage of the business &#x2013; or percentage of the revenue you might be able to hold on to in that market going forward?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I'll let Jeff answer the Nexus and then I'll cover China.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're not disclosing the number of &#x2013; specific number of Nexus One devices sold.  We are very happy with the device uptake and the kind of impact that that's had across the industry of raising the bar and people's expectations of what a great smartphone can do.  I did earlier mention that across the Android landscape that we are seeing more than 60,000 devices sold and activations daily.</p>
          <p>On stores, sorry, we can't comment anything about that right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff.  Let me comment on China.  Look, we have made &#x2013; we have explained to people that the revenue numbers for China were kind of immaterial to the financial performance of the company in the previous blogs and communications.  The bottom line, though, on China is this was a tough situation where we really believe we've made the right decision.  Google stands for really important values like openness, user choice, protection of privacy and these are &#x2013; in a company that remains true to its values that's what you do, you make a decision that is driven by those values.</p>
          <p>Having said that, what we've announced a few weeks ago, right, or a few days ago clearly has us staying in China.  I mean we have just changed our strategy and adapted our strategy but our engineering force remains in China and will continue to develop great products.  We continue to keep our sales force in place because there's still an export market and a then a lot of opportunities in China for sales.  And what we've done is moved back to Hong Kong for search where we can offer it uncensored.  So from that perspective, right, you should see a lot of positive moves on the basic Google and &#x2013; but we made the right call.  Thanks.  Let's go to the next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And we'll take our next question from Brian Pitz from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Can you give us an update on where you are in terms of renewing your distribution deal with News Corp?  And then a quick question on mobile.  Is there a plan B if AdMob doesn't go through and also can you comment on whether you see mobile services eventually being delivered essentially through the browser much like the PC rather than individual application downloads?  Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just comment on AdMob and then Susan will probably give more commentary on the monetization.  Look, the case for AdMob is that there's overwhelming evidence that the mobile advertising industry, both in terms of platforms and providers, it's nascent, it's incredibly competitive.  It didn't exist 24 months ago.  There's dozens of ad networks out there.  And even last week you may have heard that there was an announcement from Apple that they were starting their own.  I mean, it is incredibly competitive and that's why we believe that actually we're positive about making this transaction happen.  The case is on our side.</p>
          <p>Now, on the specifics of monetization, maybe Susan can give a bit more color commentary?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I was just going to comment since you asked about a plan B, I will say that Google does have a monetization product for monetizing mobile applications, AdSense for mobile applications and that is a product we are investing in and we have seen good growth with that one.  But I just want to reiterate the point that Patrick said which is that we see this as a very new and nascent market.  It's less than 2 years old and there's a lot of competition in this market so we are continuing to work with the FTC on AdMob.</p>
          <p>Your other comment was about ad applications versus web, and Google is investing and believe that HTML5 has the opportunity to enable a lot richer applications on the web, and that's something that we're investing in and we'll see over time how applications and HTML5 both develop.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me go back to the very first question you asked which I think the News Corp. question was around the MySpace deal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah just the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, we're working.  Look, Google wants every partner in the sense it's good for the ecosystem, it's good for the partners.  It gives them opportunities for monetization.  We're in the negotiations right now of a deal that is coming to be renewed.  And these deals were like in the case of that specific one was done a number of years ago with completely different industry dynamics.  So we're working with them to find a real win-win, and you just stay tuned for when we have an announcement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Spencer Wang from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Just 2 quick questions.  First on the paid click growth which was up 15% year-over-year.  That actually reaccelerated for the first time in a couple of years.  So I was wondering, Susan, if you can give us a sense of what's driving that?  Is it a combination of site links?  How much of it is mobile, et cetera?</p>
          <p>And then secondly just for Patrick, G&amp;A looks like ex stock comp was actually down year-over-year.  Is that the rough right absolute level we should be thinking about for the rest of the year?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Want to cover first Susan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, on paid click, I think it's a combination of a lot of different factors and it's really important to remember that this is also an aggregate number across all of our businesses.  And so as we saw advertisers come back and start spending again driven by a lot of our largest advertisers really increasing their spend as well as Google and the ads team bringing a lot of new types of products to market in terms of the site links product, which had not just one place to click but multiple places to click, we started seeing advertisers have higher click-throughs and so all of those higher click-throughs that I talked about do manifest themselves in terms of the aggregate paid click number.  Mobile is a component of many different types of inventory that Google is expanding to, to increase the overall paid click number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  On the G&amp;A, Spencer, the short answer is we're going to continue to be disciplined just like you see in the ramp &#x2013; the run rates in the ramp-ups that you see.  So we are very disciplined. This place continues to be frugal in many ways.</p>
          <p>On the other side, right, we are hiring.  We are hiring and it's obviously lumpy.  So the point is like we are &#x2013; every time I can find another great engineer to add to the Chrome OS platform, I'm going to hire them.  We're going to hire them.  Google needs them.  On the flip side, there's a lot of discipline around.  It's not like you do whatever you want around here.  There's discipline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Ross Sandler from RBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys.  Thanks for taking the time.  2 quick questions for Nikesh.  If you look at year-over-year growth in the UK versus ROW on an organic basis, they were about the same.  Can you talk about what areas in ROW are outperforming and which ones are underperforming?</p>
          <p>And then you had mentioned a month or two ago that there was some paid click cleanup in the fourth quarter.  Was there any of that in 1Q and can you talk about the growth rate of O&amp;O clicks versus &#x2013; or Google website clicks versus partner site clicks?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your question.  In terms of UK versus the rest of the world, I think the rest of world for us performed even better than the UK did in the last quarter.  Having said that, as I mentioned there are parts of the rest of the world which are continuing to perform really well for us.  Places like Brazil which we talked about last quarter.  Places like Russia, et cetera, continue to perform well.  There's some parts of the European economy as you're aware which are still undergoing some correction like Greece where clearly you can't expect us to be performing too well.</p>
          <p>So there are pockets of strong performance in the rest of world, they're pretty much in line with our expectation in terms of trends we're seeing which are dependent on broadband penetration, dependent on the e-commerce activity, dependent on the small businesses adoption to the Internet.  And as that &#x2013; as those curves continue to go up we continue to see correspondingly good performance in those markets and we're planning our growth strategies in those markets along those lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think for &#x2013; the keyword refinancing for Greece should be pretty popular, though.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Unfortunately, I don't think there's 30 billion euros on the Internet for them to get, Patrick, but we'd love that advertising business.  See now you made me forget your other question</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  Cleanup of the paid clicks -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  We did do a slightly outside of normal cleanup in the last quarter, but I think our activity, we're constantly making sure that we're taking care of spam and we're taking care of advertising situations where we don't believe that's appropriate business.  We do that on a regular basis.  We have done nothing extraordinary in this quarter.  Last quarter we did look at our policies in certain areas and clean it up, which is why we mentioned it the last call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Mary Meeker from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks.  So just one clarification and then a question.  So on the cost per click decline, 4% sequentially.  By our math, if you exclude forex, the decline was probably closer to 2.5% and just want to try to rank order the drivers of the sequential decline.  And our thinking is that forex was the number one driver of the decline.  The second was the geographic mix which is an ongoing issue was a second driver.  Third was related to tools that Susan spoke about to find more long-tail keywords which over time should drive CPCs higher or certainly assist CPCs.</p>
          <p>The fourth was the slower economic recovery in Europe versus the U.S. and your comment about Greece related to that.  And fifth was another Susan comment, the product innovations roll-out in the U.S. first, which over time as they roll out in the non-U.S. markets should help CPCs outside the U.S.  One you didn't really mention was mobile, which is probably a factor as well.  Is that the right laundry list of drivers of a sequential CPC decline and the right list in the right order, in your view, Patrick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The &#x2013; Mary, I think that you have, in essence, the right laundry list.  And I can tell you that the FX, anybody because it's public information on FX, you can &#x2013; it is a big contributor to that 4%.</p>
          <p>For the other last element of the equation is always the mix between Google properties versus the partner properties which also has and especially in the case of the international, the UK.  So you have all the elements of what you talked about.  Plus, you have to look at your mix between the .com properties versus the partner properties.  And &#x2013; now we don't give you the breakdown of all the elements, as you know, but you have the right basket if you include the last one I just gave you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and then a question and I'm going to give you a fun name is you've been telling us about lumpiness in CapEx for a really long time.  CapEx has been actually very constrained and the phrase is going to be lumpy but disciplined.  You've been talking about investments in people for the last couple of quarters.  You increased your head count about 4% sequentially but your operating spending per employee was flat sequentially.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the question we have is as you grow, as you should, do you think you can continue to keep OpEx per employee flat sequentially?  So we'll call it lumpy but disciplined?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, that's the intent.  The intent is you onboard Googlers, right, they take real estate, they take computers, they take computing power, but it's not for the models that we have right now in the spaces where we are I mean, it's really about software development and sales.  So that's the intent absolutely.</p>
          <p>And then on the CapEx side, I could argue it grew 8% quarter-over-quarter, right?  But you're absolutely right.  We're very disciplined about it and we're very proud of, in fact, getting so much yield out of our infrastructure, and &#x2013; but there's always, remember, I tell this because what will happen, just like we had talked about a few quarters ago that we're ramping up on hiring in the same way, when there's a great opportunistic purchase on assets, we will be there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Let's take our next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />  And we'll go next to Jeetil Patel from Deutsche.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thank you.  A couple questions.  I guess, coming off the bottom obviously from an ad market standpoint, can you guys I guess talk about are you seeing from your marketers at least in the U.S. and customers a different allocation of ad dollars between search and display ads and other initiatives such as product listings and the like as you come up from Q4 to Q1 and beyond?</p>
          <p>Second question is, I guess we continue to believe and you guys investing in the business and just curious with the incrementally 800 adds, I guess, is there one or two sets of projects that you're allocating incremental investment against whether it be mobile or YouTube or what have you just to give us a flavor of where you're headed from a product innovation and a traffic growth standpoint.  And then I have a quick follow-up</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeff can talk about where &#x2013; all the areas where we're deploying the engineering and then &#x2013; I mean obviously, Nikesh will answer the first question.  So, Jeff, you want to give a sense of where we're plowing resources?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  It's a combination of the core businesses is strong and growing so we're continuing to invest in that.  Susan went through in her section a lot of the innovations in new products that we've introduced in the core search and display ads business.  Some of the other major areas of engineering investment are some of the things that I cited, the open platforms, Android and Chrome were growing very quickly and having a big impact. We're also investing incrementally in the apps and enterprise business where we're seeing very strong growth and a lot of strong customer uptake there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nikesh?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer the head count question on the sales side first, then I can go back and talk about the marketers and the advertisers.  As Jeff mentioned, on the business side, we are continuing to add resources selectively in search as you see the market continuing to grow as well as deploying it in markets where we see higher growth as I mentioned earlier.</p>
          <p>In addition to that, we are putting a significant amount of resources in our display space as the product teams continues to enhance our display offering and give us more features and that will continue to be a focus for us throughout the year going forward.</p>
          <p>In terms of what we are seeing from marketers, I think the pullback we had seen about 6 to 9 months ago is all gone.  What has also happened in parallel is I continue to see tremendous amounts of capability building on the advertiser side.  One of the challenges you always have, you can go to an advertiser, pitch them on a tremendous search campaign, however they feel like we can lead the horse to the water but they still have trouble of making it drink because their websites aren't fully capable of conducting the e-commerce transactions to the level they would like.</p>
          <p>Having said that I have seen tremendous amounts of capability improvement the last 6 to 9 months across the majority of our mature markets, both the U.S., UK, Germany, France, et cetera, which allows to us go in with bigger more &#x2013; larger campaigns to these guys and they're beginning to understand that search is sort of diminishing inventory, if you don't buy it today, it's not going to be there tomorrow.  They have to be more willing to be flexible with their budget and be open depending on what's going on.  And they are getting more and more adverse to the ways of search.</p>
          <p>So clearly, we're seeing them get more flexible with their dollars on the search side.  They're beginning to understand the value of products like Susan mentioned, like remarketing and how to use the display networks effectively in sort of the CPC model and a CPM model depending on which one they choose.  So clearly in the more mature markets, we're seeing awareness of the digital marketspace.  We're seeing them keep the search budgets open and we're seeing tremendous amounts of engagement from their side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just in closing on that point, I think that the display market is seeing such an evolution because the simplicity of the tools that did not exist a year ago are now here, and people now have the choice of participating, participating actively, and in these campaigns now, love to have the flexibility to move from one another to find the right audience so a tremendous progress we've seen in display and we're very encouraged by what we see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess a question to Nikesh's commentary, I guess if companies are having a hard time getting the transaction in the door once they get the traffic and small business have that same issue, I guess would you ever look at a model such as a percentage of sales model to go eliminate that issue and have the transaction occur on site?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that &#x2013; I want to make sure you interpret what I said carefully.  I think, to be fair, most of the small businesses are very, very good with their allocation.  As you had seen a few quarters ago we've seen a dip in large advertisers and small advertisers because they have always been ROI-driven, they totally understand how to bring in a search lead and how to convert that search lead into dollars.  I think the challenge of the large advertiser has been is as a proportion of their total advertising revenue, they have not been able to allocate a lot of dollars towards search and now as it builds up that capability, they're able to do that more effectively.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  So this is Susan.  One additional thing I would like to add is we definitely see an opportunity to move to taking a percentage of the conversion.  In fact we call this CPA, cost per acquisition.  And one of the products that was developed in this area that we are optimistic about is the Product Add product, and the way that works is the retailer just gives us all of the information about their products, the price, the listing, description, et cetera and then Google actually does the targeting to decide where to show those ads and then we take a percentage when the product is actually purchased, when the user actually converts, and we do see that as an opportunity to really simplify the process for advertisers over time and it's something we're investing in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Can we take the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Jason Helfstein from Oppenheimer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  Thanks.  Let me ask just a bit about expenses.  So did Nexus One have a material impact on sales and marketing expenses in the quarter?</p>
          <p>And then number 2, when we look at seasonal pattern of expenses last year, they increased as a percent of revenue in the second quarter.  Should we expect a similar pattern this year?  Or, is each year different based on your initiatives?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to make it simple, on the Nexus One, we did not have material advertising for it.</p>
          <p>And then on the second one, I wouldn't provide any guidance for the coming quarters.   So I would leave it at that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Can we have our next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Youssef Squali from Jefferies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.  2 quick ones.  One for Patrick, one for Susan.  Starting with you, Patrick.  I just want to go back to the China issue and understand a little bit better what you said.  So is serving China from Hong Kong a sustainable strategy for you guys?  Doesn't that put you at a strong disadvantage versus the native player over time?</p>
          <p>And then to Susan, among the many products that you cited, product search, site links, image ads, et cetera, help us understand which one or which one or two are having the most impacts on conversion rates and CPCs?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on the case of China, I mean, obviously, we still have sales in China and the fact that we serve them in Hong Kong and from Hong Kong doesn't stop us from having all the opportunities that we want from the Chinese markets, and remember that there's a huge industrial infrastructure all around Hong Kong and Southern China, so it's really addressing a market from a different perspective and our sales force is ready to serve them from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mostly for exporters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's both actually.  Because we have &#x2013; like we really have both opportunities.  What we've really done if you think about it is we've stopped censoring, but the access to Google is still available for all Chinese people through .hk.  I'll leave it to Susan to answer the second question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  So from an impact standpoint, some of the biggest changes that we make that impact the product and all the metrics, not just CPC, but percentage of click growth, et cetera, a lot of them have to do with changes in ads quality that we make in the quarter.  And the reason is because if we can make a percentage increase off of that very large business, that can have a significant impact.</p>
          <p>And so we had a &#x2013; what we'll say a modest quarter from an ads quality.  We had more than a dozen different launches that were significant across the board and they certainly over time do play an important role in how they affect the metrics.</p>
          <p>The other thing that I'd like to point out that I think also is really an important thing to look at with our overall business is something we've introduced in AdWords called Opportunity Center and Opportunity Center is a way for advertisers to know this is how many more clicks I should be getting or could be getting.  And so what we want to do is we want to give a lot more guidance to advertisers in terms of here are more keywords, they're very easy to add to your keyword list.</p>
          <p>We just launched this quarter, for example, bid suggestions to give them an understanding of what are the tradeoffs between volumes and CPCs and where is the optimal place that they should be bidding as well as budget suggestions.  And because this is a &#x2013; because Opportunity Center is applied to the core business and to all of our advertisers, it can move the metrics over time in terms of getting more advertisers to buy keywords or increase their budgets or change their bids.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for the question Youssef.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Can we take the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Mark May from Needham &amp; Co.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  I had 2.  I wondered if you could give some color around the paid click and cost per click growth as it relates to O&amp;O and the network, do paid clicks grow faster on the O&amp;O network or on the AdSense network and same for CPCs?</p>
          <p>And the second question is there are a lot of innovative companies in the display space.  Earlier, you mentioned remarketing but generally speaking there are others out there doing remarketing.  So my question is what are the top couple of things that Google is doing that's different in the area of display particularly from a targeting standpoint that is meaningfully differentiated?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.  So on the first one, I'll punt because we don't want to &#x2013; we don't divulge the split between O&amp;O and other properties, but I'm sure Susan will talk about the display innovations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  So you brought up some questions about remarketing and what we're doing there that's unique and yes, I think I would definitely agree with you that display is a really vibrant space and there's a lot of innovation that's happening right now in the display market and I think ultimately that innovation will enable the market as a whole to grow.  But one of the things that we have that's very unique from the remarketing perspective is users or advertisers can refind users across the Content Network.  And the Content Network because we have so many publishers in our site and because we are a global network as well, it gives advertisers the opportunity to expand and find a lot more of those users across the network than they probably can with a lot of other options.</p>
          <p>The other thing that we're doing from a targeting perspective is we're trying to make it really easy for advertisers to work with existing interfaces.  So right now you can do remarketing within AdWords.  So if you are an AdWords advertiser you can do the remarketing there.  If you are a DSA advertiser, then you can also do it from that perspective as well.</p>
          <p>The other thing that is important is from a &#x2013; because you also asked about different types of targeting, we offer a number of different targeting that we think are unique and the one of them that we're best known for is the contextual targeting.  So the ability to actually figure out on a page what this page is about dynamically and then serve an ad that's matched to that one specifically.</p>
          <p>Then we also have placement targeting where we give advertisers the ability to choose where they want their ads to appear by actually selecting these are the sites and this is where I want them to appear.  So the combination of all of these things together give advertisers a large number of options, and we're thinking about how these things actually work together.  So, how do all of these different targeting mechanisms, how do you combine them in a way to provide the best options for the advertisers and users?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Youssef when you said Content Network you do include YouTube in there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we do include it within there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great can we have the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Jordan Rohan from Thomas Weisel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, actually, I have a drilldown question on site links and image ads.  The question I have is really just how do I think about the pervasiveness of these new ad formats?  Over what percentage of queries or what percentage of advertisers do you think it's relevant?  It seems like it would be a relatively narrow set of very commercial queries for very response driven advertisers?  How far penetrated are we?  How new is this?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Susan, again.  So you're right that site links is new and we are really just beginning to penetrate all the advertisers that I think would benefit from the site links feature.  We do see site links appearing mostly on navigational queries where the user is looking for the brand name or the product category, but it is a very powerful tool and we believe there are still a lot of advertisers that are not using it today that would benefit from it.</p>
          <p>The other thing I'll say about site links is it rolled out globally and when you look at the combination of all the different companies and advertisers globally that could benefit from this, we're just getting started because we've just started rolling this out in Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for the question, Jordan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we have the next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Marianne Wolk from Susquehanna.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks I had 2 quick questions.  The first is with regard to your mobile advertising, it sounds like it's an opt-out program now for most AdWord users?  Is that true?  And would you also include in app ads as an opt-out mobile choice as well?</p>
          <p>And then also is it fair to say, based on the comments you made about the Content Network that the mix shifted from the content partners &#x2013; to the content partners from the search partners by several points this quarter?  And did the Content Network also grow much faster in the UK this period than in the U.S.?</p>
          <p>And I know you rolled out video and display ads on Content Network.  Can you talk about the uptake there and any positive impact that's had on pricing?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Marianne.  The first one, could you just repeat your question.  So we're &#x2013; I'll just write them down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  On the mobile advertising side -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; it sounds like you are saying it's an opt out platform?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  The opt-out issue.  The second one was about the UK versus other geographies for take-up rates for different formats?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, for the Content Network, for the Content Network.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And whether you're getting any pricing benefit there from the introduction of display and video ads recently?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Susan, you want to take these?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  I'll take both of them.  So, on the mobile component I'll say that we do give advertisers the option to &#x2013; the default is for advertisers to be on search, content and mobile.  And the reason we do that is because we want to make it as easy as possible for advertisers to get as much reach and reach as many potential users as possible.  And we try to do the right thing for those advertisers.  So the default is for them to be opted into both.</p>
          <p>However, we do offer the ability for advertisers to run a mobile-only campaign and under that mobile only campaign we give them the option to target, for example, a specific mobile OS, and we give a lot of options within the mobile category, but I really think about that more for advertisers who are &#x2013; have the capabilities and are advanced enough to know that this is &#x2013; these are the capabilities that they want to do and customize their campaign in order to make it worthwhile for them.</p>
          <p>On the formats question, I will also say we definitely have been introducing new formats into the display network and we've been really excited about that.  In fact, we have a product called Display Ad Builder and Display Ad builder is a way &#x2013; it's a template system that enables us to have lots of different ad formats and to add them very, very easily to our network and from an advertiser standpoint, they are very, very easy, too to actually start and get running.  It's really just a click, click, click and your ad can be running &#x2013; your display ad can be running.</p>
          <p>So because the Content Network and the way that we choose which ad is actually run is an auction, if display is winning, then it's winning because it's actually a higher CPM ad.  And so by bringing display ads to the mix with text, there's more competition and there's more variety and so when it makes sense for a display ad to run, then it wins the auction and because it won the auction, then it's bidding more than the existing text ad.  And so over time that can bring positive competition to the auction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your question, Joanna (sic) [Marianne].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Can we have the next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Aaron Kessler from Kaufman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, a couple questions.  First, can you just give us a little more details on the travel and retail verticals, I know you said all the verticals were strong?  Any more color there?</p>
          <p>And then just updates on your hedging program would be helpful and your thoughts going forward with the hedges?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Maybe I can start with the hedges and then turn it to Nikesh.  Look, our hedging program is really effective.  I just want to remind everybody, for us, it's an insurance policy.  It's an insurance policy for high volatility and specifically if the U.S. dollar strengthens dramatically.  And so if you look at where the euro was a year ago, versus where it was 90 days ago, versus where it is now, I mean and then you go back to last year as we discussed that we had booked at this time last year big hedging revenues was mostly because we had such a massive appreciation of the U.S. dollar.  So for us, very effective in finding the right sweet spot to make sure that we have the right coverage.</p>
          <p>What we're caught with is the accounting rules, which some quarters like last quarter, right, had very little FAS 133 ruling pushing through the P&amp;L and this quarter has a disproportionate amount.  They don't represent our regular cost of hedging.  So it creates a bit of a fluctuation for you to model but in the end, we're very happy with what we're getting out of it.</p>
          <p>In terms of the verticals, I'll turn it to Nikesh.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you mentioned, travel and retail have been strong.  I also alluded to the capability building which for e-commerce which is primarily I was talking about the retail vertical where we're seeing good strength.  Travel is growing strong and is steady.  Retail and travel end up being some of our larger verticals in the entire landscape.</p>
          <p>Having said that, I am seeing good strength as well from CPG and entertainment because that's where a lot of the display advertisers like to focus because those verticals, even though they're smaller numbers, those verticals aren't traditionally strong search verticals but they definitely play in the display space and a lot of the display efforts have been targeted at those verticals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="22" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Can we take our next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our next question from Colin Gillis from BGC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Patrick, was there any tension between Sergey and Eric over China, could that be tied at all to why Eric is not on the call today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.  I'm sorry, I shouldn't &#x2013; thank you for the question &#x2013; thank you &#x2013; I have a feeling that I've heard every rumor.  So thank you for asking the question so candidly.  The answer is no.  There is nothing going on at all.  I mean it was really as we were doing the planning at the end of last year, through all the questions every &#x2013; if you doubt that we actually scrub every department at Google, I was scrubbed, too, and the question that was asked is what can you do differently to be better next year and one of the things on the list that we brought up in finance is hey, maybe we should look at the quarterly call and the whole process and the webcast that we launched and one them was hey, we thought of this as an innovation.  It has nothing to do with it.  Thank you for asking the question</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How about as a quick follow-up, the newer ad format, does that provide any lift at all to the CPCs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The newer ad format?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Click to play video and things along those lines?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, I think it's important to understand we &#x2013; some of the newer ad formats, they're all not sold on a CPC basis, our new ad formats are sold like traditionally in the display space.  We sell them as web pages or homepages so they're not paid on a click-by-click basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="23" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Colin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we take our last question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we'll take our final question from Scott Devitt from Morgan Stanley</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks, 2 questions, please.  The first just to follow up on Mary's laundry list question.  The comment about site revenue and network revenue mix, the site revenue network revenue were flat, both flat sequentially so I was wondering if you're suggesting that CPCs in the network are actually declining if that was a contributor to the sequential decline in CPC?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, you recently indicated 50 million Chrome users and I think Android smartphone shipments have been roughly 6 million per quarter run rate.  So your thoughts on shipping a tablet to take advantage of this momentum.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer in 2 ways.  We're really delighted by the Chrome pickup rate.  I mean it is a fast browser, it is a secure browser.  It has all the elements that we have told about it.  So this is a terrific opportunity.</p>
          <p>In terms of tablets or &#x2013; the one announcement that we made last year, you'll remember with the launch of Chrome OS is, we are working with manufacturers to have a netbook out sometime in the fall and we're continuing to work diligently on this.  We're very excited about it and we think that there's going to be a ton of innovation coming out of that.  So there is no doubt that we are pushing for it for all the reasons that you're mentioning.  Can you remind me your first question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.  The addition to the list earlier in terms of drivers of changes in CPC was the mix shift between site and network.  And as we go back and look at the sequential growth rate of Google site revenue and Google network revenue, they were both basically flat.  So I was wondering if there was any implication from that that CPC and one of those two actually changed more than the other?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know what, I don't have the answer to that, but what I will do is we'll follow up with you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="24" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Great.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Maria?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're done taking questions.  So I'm going to turn it over to Patrick for some closing thoughts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  I just want to thank everybody for joining us today.  I want to thank every Googler as well who listened to the call.  I mean we have Googlers all over the world working so diligently at creating these incredible products and all the opportunities we have.  Thanks for your time and we look forward to talking to you at the end of Q2.  I'll let the lady close the call.  I forgot her name.  I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Connie?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And this concludes today's conference.  We thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>