<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1262332" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-10-15</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8238</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Maria Shim, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Eric Schmidt, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Patrick Pichette, Senior Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Nikesh Arora, President, Global Sales Operations and Business Development</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Jonathan Rosenberg, Senior Vice President, Product Management</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Nikesh Aurora</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, and welcome everyone to the Google, Inc. Conference Call. This call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the call over to Ms. Maria Shim, Director of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone, and welcome to today's third quarter 2009 conference call. With us are Eric Schmidt, Chief Executive Officer; Patrick Pichette, Chief Financial Officer; Jonathan Rosenberg, Senior Vice President of Product Management; and Nikesh Aurora, President, Global Sales Operations and Business Development.</p>
          <p>Today, we are trying a new process on our earnings call. Eric, Patrick, Jonathan and Nikesh will each provide us with their thoughts on the quarter and then we will take Q&amp;A from Google Moderator. This is our first time using Google Moderator to respond to questions from the investment community, so let me briefly explain the process.</p>
          <p>Please submit your question via the Moderator page that we have sent out and the audience will vote on the most relevant questions. We will only be taking questions that are relevant to today's earnings results and Google's long-term strategy. I will read the question and the name of the person who submitted the question and then have Eric, Patrick, Jonathan or Nikesh answer.</p>
          <p>This call is being webcast from our Investor Relations website located at investor.google.com. Please refer to our website for important information, including our earnings press release issued a few minutes ago, along with slides that accompany today's prepared remarks. A replay of this call will also be available on our website in a few hours.</p>
          <p>Please note that we routinely post important information on our Investor Relations website located at investor.google.com and we encourage you to make use of that resource. As a reminder, we're holding two calls today. On this call, we will discuss our strategic overview and Q&amp;A with the usual format followed by a second call which is effectively an extended Q&amp;A session with Jonathan and Patrick, giving the opportunity for participants to ask more detailed financial and product questions in an efficient and Reg FD compliant manner. The second call will begin at 3:00 PM Pacific Time and will also be webcast from our Investor Relations website.</p>
          <p>Now, let me quickly cover the Safe Harbor. Some of the statements we make today may be considered forward-looking, including statements regarding investments in our long-term growth and innovation, expected performance of our business, and our expected level of capital expenditures. These statements involve a number of risks and uncertainties that could cause actual results to differ materially. Please note that these forward-looking statements reflect our opinions only as of the date of this presentation and we undertake no obligation to revise or publicly release the results of any revision to these forward-looking statements in light of new information or future events.</p>
          <p>Please refer to our SEC filings including our annual report on Form 10-K for the year ended December 31, 2008, as well as our earnings press release for a more detailed description of the risk factors that may effect our results. Copies can be obtained from the SEC or by visiting the Investor Relations section of our website.</p>
          <p>Also, please note that certain financial measures we use on this call, such as operating profit and operating margin, are expressed in a non-GAAP basis and have been adjusted to exclude charges relating to stock-based compensation. We have also adjusted our net cash provided by operating activities to remove capital expenditures, which we refer to as free cash flow. Our GAAP results and GAAP to non-GAAP reconciliation can be found in our earnings press release.</p>
          <p>With that, I will now turn the call over to Eric.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thank you very much, Maria and good afternoon to all of you, and welcome to our third quarter earnings call. Let's start by summarizing where we are. While there's obviously a lot of uncertainty about the pace of economic recovery, we believe the worst of the recession is behind us and we're seeing lots of signs of that in all of the industries that we pay attention to. So we're very optimistic now about the future. And we now have the business confidence to invest heavily in the next phase of innovation, helping to invent the future as we see it.</p>
          <p>Our performance in the quarter was a strong quarter, 7% year-over-year revenue growth. We performed well across all of the financial metrics that we monitor. So it's all good news from our perspective, at least in looking at the quarter.</p>
          <p>And we're going to continue to invest in long-term growth. We tested our management team and I want to say that I'm very, very proud of the management team getting us through what could have been a very significant business event for Google and we've proven the worth of this team, tight control over costs, combined with continued innovation in search and ads, Chrome, Android, mobile, these huge opportunities ahead of us, the resources and expertise to invest heavily in long-term growth for the benefit of users, customers, and shareholders.</p>
          <p>So how are we investing? Well we are going to invest in people. We are already stepping up our hiring and also in innovation consistent with our 70/20/10 principle, the technological precondition for growth, if you will, is this investment in innovation. In the 70%, everybody here I think on the call knows that that's our core business. We want to really get to the perfect search engine. We made about 120 search quality improvements in the third quarter with more, of course, coming this quarter and we hope every quarter and we're working to create much better ads.</p>
          <p>It's important to remember that many of our advertisers would like to find more ways to spend money with Google if our products would allow them to do that and we want to make that possible and really serve their needs and that 20% out of the 70/20/10, we're stepping up our investment in up and coming businesses.</p>
          <p>Mobile high growth business for us already 30% quarter-over-quarter growth in mobile searches in the third quarter. Android, as you know, has come a long way in a year from one device with one carrier in one country to now 12 devices in 26 countries with 32 carriers with much more coming.</p>
          <p>In the display and YouTube area, both of which of course are doing well, we have a great base. We have a million publishers choosing to use the AdSense product and of course more &#x2013; many, many advertisers and we've now added DoubleClick to the mix, integrated with Google with our Exchange and all of the things DoubleClick can now offer. So you have a great business that should scale pretty rapidly.</p>
          <p>And again, even with our enterprise business, which we've been working hard on for some time, not only is our business accelerating, but I actually personally spoke to a number of our customers, for example, Motorola, Genentech and JohnsonDiversey getting feedback very strong. They need more of this product and they need us to address product shortcomings and I think the products will do very, very well.</p>
          <p>In the 10%, promising areas where we think there's a real opportunity to innovate, Google inspired development, that's why we're basically pushing our rate of hiring, partnerships with wireless and developers, but also we're going to focus more on strategic deals and acquisitions as we have discussed publicly. And we're open for business, making strategic acquisitions, both large and small.</p>
          <p>So to put it together and I think hand it over to Patrick for his analysis of the financials, I'll tell you that we're very, very happy with Q3. The worst of the recession clearly behind us and because of what we have seen, we now have the confidence to be optimistic about our future and we're going to invest as a result, and that I think is ultimately good for the long-term of Google.</p>
          <p>Patrick?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Eric, and good afternoon, everyone. So I'll go through the results quickly and then I'll turn it over to Nikesh and Jonathan for a bit more detail on our performance.</p>
          <p>So as Eric said, at a high level, we're very pleased with our Q3 results. Gross revenue grew 7% year-over-year to $5.9 billion and our business was strong across the board. Google.com, for example, the revenue was up 8% year-over-year to 4 billion; contributing a significant portion of our year-over-year growth.</p>
          <p>The traffic growth continues to be healthy and we saw stabilization or improvement in most of our major markets. It's actually worth noting that Q3 also benefited from a number of ads quality launches. In AdSense, we saw an increase up year-over-year 7% to 1.8 billion, driven primarily by growth in our AdSense for Content and our display initiatives. Our global aggregate paid click growth remained very healthy, up 14% year-over-year and 4% quarter-over-quarter.</p>
          <p>Our aggregate cost per click growth was down 6% year-over-year, but up 5% quarter-over-quarter, with FX playing quite a factor in both the year-over-year and quarter-over-quarter comparisons. So FX had a negative impact on the year-over-year for CPC growth, but a positive one quarter-over-quarter due to the weakening of the U.S. dollar during the quarter. Remember, too, that this is an aggregate number, which includes diverse geographic markets, some of which may have lower CPCs, and also includes both Google and AdSense properties.</p>
          <p>Turning to our geographic performance, revenue from the U.S. was up 4% year-over-year to 2.8 billion. International revenue accounted for 53% of our total revenue, or 3.1 billion, with 39 million benefits of hedging programs for this quarter. The U.K. was down 1% year-over-year to 765 million, negatively impacted by FX, as well as an ongoing macroeconomic weakness, but this partially offset by revenues from our hedging program. It's worth noting that using a fixed year-over-year exchange rate our total revenue would have been roughly $300 million higher.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to expenses. Traffic acquisition costs were 1.6 billion, or 27% of total advertising revenue, our other cost of revenue was $667 million. And finally, all other operating expenses totaled 1.6 billion, including approximately 303 million for our stock-based compensation. On a year-over-year basis, our OpEx excluding SBC, and other cost of sales was lower by $14 million and up 81 million quarter-over-quarter. The increase quarter-over-quarter was primarily due to increases in payroll, equipment, and facilities-related expenses.</p>
          <p>So as a result of all this, our non-GAAP operating profit, which excludes stock-based compensation, increased to $2.4 billion in Q3, resulting in a non-GAAP operating margin of 40.2%. Headcount was slightly down, ending the quarter with approximately 20,000 full-time employees. So as Eric said, we believe the worst of the recession is behind us, and we feel confident in investing in our innovation agenda in a targeted and disciplined way, and that includes accelerating hiring across the organization, particularly in engineering and sales.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to cash management. In other income and expense, we had a net expense of $7 million for Q3. For more details on this, please refer to the slides that are accompanying this call in our investor relation website. Our effective tax rate for the quarter was 21%. And let me remind you that any changes to the mix of earnings between domestic and international subsidiaries, as well as the effect on our earnings from various hedging activities and the related hedged items obviously have an effect on our tax rate.</p>
          <p>So let's complete the portrait now; operating cash flow, very strong at $2.7 billion. CapEx for the quarter was 186 million, again, primarily related to our data center operations. And we'll continue to make significant CapEx investments, although they're lumpy. Free cash flow, very strong at 2.5 billion.</p>
          <p>So in summary, very pleased with the strong quarter in Q3 across revenue, margins and cash flow. We're managing the company to best position ourselves for long-term growth and accelerating our pace of innovation. We're disciplined, but fully investing in big long-term opportunities, whether it be in search, display, mobile, or apps.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn it over to Nikesh to cover with more color commentary. Nikesh?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Patrick. I just wanted to spend a few minutes going over our performance across our businesses and our markets. Firstly, our core business continues to drive our growth. If you look at our performance across our four global regions, in the Americas, the U.S. strength was across the board, but especially amongst our larger advertisers as they have come back into the market in the third quarter. We've had a major push in the U.S. to further streamline our sales processes and go out and meet most of our large advertising CMOs. In addition to the large advertisers, Brazil was a good performer and a true standout in Latin America with strong revenue growth.</p>
          <p>If you look at our region which covers Northern and Central Europe, we began to see stabilization across the board as economy started to emerge from the downturn. The U.K. has showed strength relative to the last quarter.</p>
          <p>If you look at the region that includes Southern and Eastern Europe, Middle East and Africa, we also saw solid performance from that region, particularly Spain has shown strong signs of revival fueled by the travel, retail and automotive verticals.</p>
          <p>Our fourth region, Asia-Pacific and Japan, we continue to build and strengthen our teams. China was a strong performer as an emerging market and Japan has seen some benefits from a reorg of the sales team, the mobile growth and a more favorable economic climate.</p>
          <p>If you look at our partnerships over the last quarter, we've had a strong level of AdSense renewals and new agreements which include British Telecom, Discovery, Tiscali and eBay, with whom we signed a global AdSense deal. This deal with eBay renews our long standing partnership with them on their non-U.S. properties, as well as their classifieds and comparison shopping sites. In addition, it also extends our partnerships for the first time to eBay.com.</p>
          <p>Now if you turn over to our Display business, as Eric mentioned earlier, we've made a lot of progress across all three parts of our display business, which has shown strong results. Firstly, in our owned and operated properties, we are pleased with our progress. On YouTube, we have added new partners and advertisers and further improved monetization. Today, we can say that 90% of the top 50 Ad Age advertisers have run campaigns with successful results on YouTube.</p>
          <p>Hewlett-Packard used YouTube homepage, wrote blogs, promoted videos, partner watch, as well as content network and search for its back-to-school campaign. It has had over 2.7 million channel views in 170 countries with over 6600 subscribers and 4000 submissions.</p>
          <p>Recently Palm used the YouTube home page and its YouTube channel, as well as the content network in a recent campaign.</p>
          <p>And McDonald's also ran a YouTube video ad on the homepage to promote its McCaf&#xE9; product.</p>
          <p>On the partnership side with YouTube, we signed some important partnerships with Time Warner and Warner Music during our third quarter. We now have deals with all four major record labels and publishers, along with many independent labels, bringing more premium content to the site. This morning, we announced that we partnered with Channel 4 in the U.K. to bring full length catch up DVD YouTube. Generally we are developing successful expertise in selling home pages and now we are in the process of releasing preload inventory which is an area we expect to further drive monetization.</p>
          <p>If you look at the second part of our display business which is our content network, we continue to show healthy growth. We continue to focus on publisher acquisition and improving the monetization of our network. Specifically we're attracting key advertisers for both direct response and branding campaigns. As Eric mentioned, we have now over 1 million publishers in our AdSense network.</p>
          <p>The third part of our display business, which is beyond our network, we are very excited to announce the new DoubleClick Ad Exchange this quarter. The Ad Exchange is a key part of how we can open the display ecosystem. Its introduction is already being received very positively by both ad networks and publishers with contractual commitments from major partners and migrations from the original DoubleClick Ad Exchange already near completed in several countries.</p>
          <p>Over half of the largest TV &#x2013; I'm sorry &#x2013; of the largest 25 ad networks in the U.S. are already using the new Ad Exchange. It also will provide substantial benefits by giving our AdWords advertisers access to more high quality inventory, enabling third parties to advertise on our AdSense publisher sites.</p>
          <p>In our enterprise business, we continue to push forward. We've had some big customer wins in the last quarter, including Rent To Kill which has 35,000 users, Midwest Echo 17,000 users, and Konica with 7000 users. We are also seeing lots of traction among small and medium size businesses, which continue to increase at a fast pace.</p>
          <p>Lastly, on a personal note, I want to say I'm very pleased with the performance of our sales team this quarter, because this quarter we have transitioned many of our senior leaders, but the team has maintained its focus on going out there on driving sales and we continue to emerge &#x2013; continue to invest in our emerging businesses and emerging markets and we hope to continue to do that in line with Patrick and Eric's comments.</p>
          <p>With that, I'm going to hand it over to Jonathan for product insights for the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thanks, Nikesh.</p>
          <p>So Eric mentioned that we're investing in long-term growth. And you'll remember, of course, that we said we would take the long-term focus in our Founders Letter and I think recently we've really been pushing a number of investments and big bets that are consistent with that long-run principal. So what I want to try to do is just quickly walk you through a few of those examples.</p>
          <p>One of the biggest 2009 investments is the new AdWords front-end and we transitioned pretty much all of our advertisers to the new user interface this quarter and it was really the biggest overhaul to AdWords which we've ever done and the advertisers now have lots of new reports, they are running much, much more efficient campaigns, and we have a new infrastructure that will make it much easier for us to roll out new features moving forward.</p>
          <p>We're also making a big investment push in developing new ad formats, and we're beta testing a new ad offering, which we call local listing ad. And with that, you basically sign up with just a simple one-page form. You don't have to deal with keywords, you don't have to deal with bids to manage. There's a simple flat monthly rate. And if you don't have a web page, the ad can link to your place page and that's a free page that we generate and you can edit, that has all sorts of information about your business. And we've launched about 50 million of these place pages. And the phone numbers on the ads go through Google voice, so you can actually track the calls you get and you know which ones were generated by your Google ad.</p>
          <p>The call actually comes in and it literally says, "This call brought to you by Google." And the trial is right now just in San Francisco and San Diego. But if you enter 'coffee, San Francisco,' you can actually see one of the ads.</p>
          <p>Last week we also launched a new maps data set and we're now using that in the U.S. and Mexico. This was a huge investment, but it's going to give us a lot more flexibility to create new types of maps. If you think about it, if you're a tourist, you probably want a different kind of a map than if you're a local. And now we're going to be able to have the base to build in features like that.</p>
          <p>I also sometimes hear that it's not always obvious how some of our big product investments tie together. If you look here at what we're doing with maps and local, you'll see that we have the ads infrastructure, geographical data, Google voice, and place pages, and those things are now all working together to create a very compelling solution for small local businesses.</p>
          <p>So everything is now really finally in place for local businesses to easily connect with customers online.</p>
          <p>And we're also investing a lot in user experience and the whole underlying infrastructure that's needed to support it. We see users today come to us with much, much harder queries than they used to, so we're adding more ways for them to work with the results and to get what they need. We launched a bunch of new features in search options. That's the little Show Options toggle switch, which you'll see it in the blue bar above your search results. And now you can opt to just look at the results from, say, the past hour or whatever time period that you want.</p>
          <p>So if you're researching an upcoming purchase, like you want to buy a camera or something, we have a fewer shopping sites feature and you can filter out many of the commercial sites, if you just want to look at more reviews. But then later, you can opt to see more shopping sites, which shows you the more commercial sites, along with their prices.</p>
          <p>Eric and Nikesh mentioned the display business. That's going very well. But we think it's still a highly inefficient industry. Something like 25% of all the publishers' ad space still goes unsold, so we've launched the new DoubleClick Ad Exchange. And this was a big investment and project and a key milestone in the culmination of the DoubleClick acquisition. Our goal there is basically to increase the size of the pie for everyone: advertisers, agencies, ad networks, and publishers.</p>
          <p>And finally, we're placing some big, big bets on making the web better. We shipped the new release of Chrome, that's more than double the speed of our first launch a year ago. And we also launched Chrome Frame, which is an Open Source plug-in for IE that dramatically speeds up JavaScript on the sites that invoke it. So speed matters, and we're going to keep investing in big projects that make the web faster. So you're probably getting restless by now, so I'll take it back to the questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>So we'll turn it over to Maria and the operator to actually go through the questions that we have online.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>So Maria, I'll leave it with you to direct the questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll take the first question from Mark May at Needham &amp; Company. "What are your goals with the recently relaunched DoubleClick ad exchange? And do you think this offering could be a material contributor to Google's overall business revenues over the next one to three years?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Jonathan. I guess I can start and maybe Nikesh can help me. We think, as I mentioned in my prepared remarks, that we're making great progress with fixing the whole fractured and very complex ad ecosystem. What we still need to do is we've got to make it much easier for the advertisers to run their display campaigns across a much broader range of websites. We've got to create demand for the publishers' ad inventory, much of which I mentioned on the call goes unsold. We've got to open up this whole ecosystem and really the goal is to grow the pie for all of the players.</p>
          <p>So as we get better tools for the publishers to improve the forecasting and extract the value of the available inventory that they have, and as we make it easier for the advertisers to plan and better target their desired audiences, we think we'll make significant progress. Maybe I'll let Nikesh talk about the customer responses and the revenue opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Jonathan, you said most of what we wanted to say. But as I mentioned, over half of the largest 25 ad networks in the U.S. are already using the new Ad Exchange, which is a good thing, in addition to which we're seeing a lot of interest from other networks in the market. So, I think this is a &#x2013; the Ad Exchange is an important element of the display ecosystem and exchanges are going to be relevant going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question, which is from Imran Khan of JPMorgan; "Can you please help us understand what drove the 6% decline in cost per click? I'm trying to better understand the impact of FX versus mix shift versus the impact of the economy."</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we don't provide all of the details, but it's very clear that the FX had an impact on these numbers. If &#x2013; there's two things that we have to take in consideration. Take a step back. Paid click continued to be quite healthy with 14% and 4% both year-over-year and quarter-over-quarter, so we're very pleased about that.</p>
          <p>On the CPC growth, if you go back year-over-year, so relative to Q3 of '08, the euro actually had an 8% difference, the Great &#x2013; the pound 15% difference, and the Canadian dollar, to take another one, also close to 8% difference. So these numbers are material. They will drive quite a bit of impact in the financials. So if you reverse engineer all these numbers, that will give you a good sense of it.</p>
          <p>Second is don't forget that we have quite a good healthy growth in international markets, which are in many cases lower CPC, but they add dollars. So we're not worried about lower CPCs when you get dollars and more performance. So this would be at the highest level. Jonathan, any additional comments on the issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think Patrick nailed the primary issue in FX. I think the secondary issue, we've talked about this on previous calls, is that more of the clicks are coming from countries with lower CPCs. So we always want to caution you about not reading aggregate CPC metrics as a direct reflection of price changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, the next question, we actually received two questions on acquisitions from Brian Pitz of UBS and Jeff Lindsay from Sanford Bernstein and it was about Eric's comments on Google looking to acquire again. Whether there were some sense of strategic holes in the business, and if we are going to be doing a large transformative acquisition or will our policy still be to make small technology-oriented acquisitions. Eric?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so for both, Brian and Jeff, thank you. The way we think about acquisitions is we have historically done an acquisition perhaps one a month or so. And those are typically small and they typically complete an offering. They are typically technology-intensive. They are not very expensive in the scheme of things. And they bring some specific technology.</p>
          <p>So in search, there's a number of companies that we've looked at, again, small people who have &#x2013; small companies that have invented some very interesting way of doing, for example, a kind of vertical search or a kind of analysis of how search should perform.</p>
          <p>In the area of advertising, we've looked at, for example, in display category, there are a number of small companies that have figured out better ways of sorting and working on display ads. There are obviously, as we build out our enterprise business, small companies that, again, have pieces of the offering. In the area of, for example, Chrome, and Chrome OS. There are parts of that platform that are most efficiently built by adding features that are already being done by small companies, obviously an Android, similarly and so forth.</p>
          <p>So there's no particular rhyme or reason or prioritization, aside from the 70-20-10 that I already talked about. It's very much a function of the specific individuals. We're certainly looking for larger businesses to buy, but in those cases there would have to be some significant strategic rationale, some accelerant that it will provide for revenue, some major, major user base that we do not currently have access to, and so they are going to be quite infrequent.</p>
          <p>So if you think about it, our two largest have been DoubleClick and YouTube, both of which look as though they are going to be incredibly successful. But the integration costs, the acquisition cost itself was quite significant. So those will be relatively rare and if I were to estimate the frequency, it's hard to say, but it's certainly not monthly; maybe every year or two, certainly not every month.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you, Eric. The next question is from James Mitchell of Goldman Sachs. "Have recent Gmail outages resulted from rapid user growth, underinvestment in server capacity, or other factors?" Jonathan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, James. So I guess it's a little unclear which &#x2013; what outage you're referring to. There was a high profile outage, I believe on September 1 to the web interface and it lasted about 100 minutes and clearly that's a very big deal to us. We understand how much users depend on Gmail and we've certainly learned a lot from it and we've taken steps to make sure that it doesn't happen again.</p>
          <p>We're also very focused on improving recovery time if an outage does occur. That information is posted on our &#x2013; on the blog and I think the blog response that we posted actually covers in detail what happened. Generally it related to underestimating the headroom from a machine perspective during some routine maintenance that we did that led to a cascading failure. But it wasn't a function of any underinvestment in server capacity or anything like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the next question is on CapEx from Christa Quarles with Thomas Weisel Partners. "CapEx is down 70% year to date. Help us understand what was going on before and what is going on now. Previously, were you overspending during the search cold war, are you underspending now?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I'll take this question, and I'll make a reference to the previous question. So Christa, thanks for your question. It's very relevant that &#x2013; let me make a overall note that you will remember in the previous quarter I had warned everybody that if you just take a ruler and go down, we would hit zero CapEx sometime in mid-September and obviously that's not happened.</p>
          <p>We're investing, and we're investing heavily. It just happens that CapEx is lumpy. Referring back to the Gmail, we have all the capacity we need for all of the infrastructure. We pre-fund, we have capacity ahead of what we think our needs are going to be. We've been very fortunate in the last few quarters.</p>
          <p>A combination of very performing assets and really good utilization, as well as in a few cases like I've talked about, Scandinavia, a few delays created these timing issues. But clearly we are focused on investment and I mean maybe Eric, you can turn it back, we talked about investment at the front end of the call and make the bridge with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would like us to be spending more in this area, because I think that the opportunity that it creates &#x2013; that capital spending creates a very significant platform for future products, future growth. Part of the reason that you have seen over last year or two a decrease in capital has been we've been able to do some very, very significant efficiency improvements that are basically software.</p>
          <p>The hardware that we had deployed was not as highly utilized, technically not as busy. So we're able to increase that and that goes right to the bottom line in terms of capital spending. And that was a big project engineering.</p>
          <p>We've also benefited from the Moore's law related efficiency improvements with the multi-core architectures and what's happening, of course, is that the chips are now going four-core, eight-core, and that of course all of a sudden means that we need fewer CPUs to get the same level of performance. And most of that is related to the data center, data operations and so forth. So it's highly dependent upon how many of that we need to deploy. And so it was more a transition from one architecture to another and efficiency improvements than a change in strategic direction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Eric. The next question is from Ross Sandler of RBC. "Are you seeing higher overall conversion rates currently versus in the first half of the year, and can you quantify the improvement?" Nikesh?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Ross, we don't comment on precise metrics and conversion rates. I think the best way to think about it, is to think about it both from a consumer perspective and an advertiser perspective.</p>
          <p>In light of the continuing economic situation and still high unemployment, consumers appear to be acting rationally. If you look at it, when the price is right, they go out and buy. So getting Cash for Clunkers or taking advantage of real estate incentives, but if necessary they will buy. When you look at back-to-school purchases, they follow the normal quarterly pattern.</p>
          <p>So I think on the consumer side, we're seeing rational behavior. On the advertiser side, as I mentioned earlier, the big advertisers are ramping up again, while smaller advertisers have been slower to jump back in. They were slower to leave. So from an overall perspective, we believe conversion rates are holding up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. So the next question is from Sandeep Aggarwal of Collins Stewart. "Can you give us an update on Android adoption versus other smart phone choices? Also, how is the work on Google Chrome OS going?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. This is Jonathan, I can start with that. Eric mentioned on the prepared remarks probably the most obvious thing is just look at the scope of growth with devices, partners, carriers; one device, one carrier, one country to 12 devices, 26 countries, 32 carriers in less than a year.</p>
          <p>The market is also very robust with over 10,000 applications available, which is something that we focus on very carefully, so basically the strategy of delivering a modern Open Source OS and enabling an ecosystem of developers and carriers seems to be paying off and the strategy is working.</p>
          <p>Chrome OS is going very well. We think we're going to deliver on the goals of basically speed, simplicity and security so that computers just work and start up in a matter of seconds. And I think we'll probably have more updates on that later in the year looking out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just add, this is Eric, and thank you for the question. Android is, adoption is literally about to explode. You have all the necessary conditions. You have the vendors. You have the distribution and so forth. And so, and this of course is a very, very critical period with all of the &#x2013; all of everything being delivered and new announcements as well.</p>
          <p>From the standpoint of Chrome OS, the internal demos that we've seen indicate that it is a materially significant achievement in platform computing. It is quite different from the current incumbents in a whole bunch of ways, speed, efficiency, and so forth.</p>
          <p>It's not quite done and we hope to get a version out later this year for people to start developing. As you know, it's an Open Source initiative. And so we appear to be roughly on time with the announcements we made a few months ago about Chrome OS, and obviously the anticipation just increases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll take the next question from Jeff Lindsay of Sanford Bernstein. "What are the plans for Google's large cash balances? Are stock buybacks being considered at any point?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick and I were talking about who should answer this question. Thank you, Jeff, for asking about this. We've been doing very well on the cash generation front throughout this whole year, which is a critical year. We've been able to be very strongly cash flow positive and we hope that that will continue for a long time. We love cash.</p>
          <p>The issue with stock buybacks is historically, they have often not achieved the objectives that they set out, so there's certainly none under consideration right now and I wouldn't expect any time soon. I wouldn't rule one out, but I would not put it on your list of things to anticipate any time soon. From our perspective, the cash gives us a lot of operating and strategic flexibility over the very long-term, and so we're very happy to have it sit in our bank account and earn a modest interest rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Justin Post of BofA &#x2013; Merrill Lynch. "What verticals, i.e., auto travels, finance, e-commerce, had most year-over-year spending improvement in Q3 versus Q2?" I'll turn it over to Nikesh.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Justin, thank you very much for your question. If you look at our verticals across the board, auto was by far the most well performing vertical in the U.S. for the third quarter. This is primarily due to the government's Cash for Clunkers program. If you look beyond the clunkers program, the U.S. auto vertical is still poised for growth because of the age of the U.S. fleet and auto dollars continue to sort of shift online. And U.K. also has recovered well on a year-on-year basis as far as auto is concerned.</p>
          <p>On travel, we've seen queries a bit later than usual, sort of illustrating consumer caution, retail we're seeing sort of a back-to-school effect that's doing well, and finance continues to be a tough vertical given the comps from last year are tough, because last year we're sort of just beginning to get into the financial crisis, we were seeing lots of queries, and all of those haven't come back as well this year as you would expect or want them to. But having said that, there are pockets in finance which are still robust like health insurance or sort of insurance overall, which is primarily positive as a vertical.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much. Next, we're going to take two questions on YouTube. The first is from Mark Mahaney of Citi. "What is the update on the past profitability?"</p>
          <p>And the second question is from Ben Schachter of Broadpoint.AmTech. "Can you quantify YouTube revenues in any way? Under what circumstances might you break out YouTube and video related revenues for us in the future?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I'll answer the front end of this question and then turn it over to Nikesh for more color commentary. But in general, as Nikesh talked about at the front end, we're really pleased about YouTube's performance. It is going very well. It is completely in line with what we discussed at the last quarter's results, which is YouTube is on its path to profitability in the not too distant future. The &#x2013; I'll let Nikesh talk about all of the great partnerships that are so critical to the success and we are having a terrific quarter on this. But just to give you one sound bite, we're monetizing more than a billion videos views every week on YouTube. So if you think of that, it just gives you a sense of perspective of the success that's going on, but I'll let Nikesh give you more detail on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you look at YouTube, we've primarily been able to sell pretty much homepage ads across the world on YouTube to the extent that 90% of our U.S. homepage video YouTube inventory was sold out in third quarter, which is a tremendous improvement from prior quarters. So we continue to drive forward on this ad format around the world.  As I mentioned also, we are beginning to unleash the preload inventory which is on YouTube of making it available for our sales forces to go out and sell.</p>
          <p>So I think there are various monetization opportunities as it relates to YouTube from the ad format side. On the inventory side, as I said, we have been able to close deals with pretty much everybody in the music label business, as I mentioned, in addition to which we also announced Channel 4 this morning. So we are creating more and more inventory so that we can create more inventory for our sales forces to go out and sell these new ad formats for. Like Patrick, we are pleased with our ability to monetize YouTube so far and we like the trend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. We'll take the next question from Jason Helfstein of Oppenheimer. "Do you think the company can continue &#x2013; can execute on its long term growth initiatives and still keep margins flat or should we assume the company sacrifices some margin growth to protect its dominant position and to create new growth areas?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Wow, this is a &#x2013; listen, I don't like the word dominant. I think we have great products and because we have great products and great technologies, we're winning in the market. I think that Eric will have, I suggest Eric also comment on it. But, look, we are looking at each product that we are shipping to be a successful product. And if there's an investment phase for some of these products, and there is just a simple investment phase. And we're not managing the business for a percent margin at all. We're managing the business for successful products that contribute over time. So Eric, maybe more color commentary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's an interesting question. Because as you know, margins are actually going the other way from the questioner's implication and we've been able to build a great business. We do not look at margins on a percentage basis at all and we also are happy to have businesses that have differential margins as long as they are successful and provide strategic value.</p>
          <p>So one way to think about it is we do not have a margin target. We have a revenue growth target and an expense target and a net cash flow target and they add up to whatever the outcome margin is. So we do not manage along those lines.</p>
          <p>From our perspective, the mission of the company is to go out there and serve and also in the context, build businesses that are growing and are profitable and we'll accept whatever their native margin structures are, and if margins improve, that's great. If they get worse, that's okay, too, as long as we're winning in the marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you. The next question is from Ross Sandler of RBC. "International revenues ex-FX and ex-hedging increased 19% year-over-year in 3Q, an acceleration from 17% in Q2, if our math is correct. Can you provide some color on which regions are driving the acceleration?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ross. Ross, as I mentioned in my prepared remarks, we are seeing strength across various markets around the world. As far as it relates to the Americas, Brazil has been a strong performer. We didn't see much of a slowdown in our Asia-Pacific and Japan regions, and therefore China has done well and other parts of Asia-Pacific. We continue to see strength in Northern Europe, France and Germany have been stable. Spain is seeing a revival. As far as Southern Europe is concerned &#x2013; sorry Spain is seeing a revival, and we see most of these markets continue to grow well for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you, Nikesh. The next question is from Doug Anmuth of Barclays Capital. "How do you define, 'investing heavily in the future?' More on infrastructure, products headcounts, how will you determine how quickly you ramp spending back up?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you for that, and Doug's question basically says, how do you judge between the various things you should invest in? And the answer is, it depends. You use, you know, your business adjustment. We know when we've got a successful product. We can tell because we measure it and if we can see it growing, we invest to accelerate it.</p>
          <p>We also tend to starve the projects which are not growing and try to figure out what error we made. So it's pretty straightforward business judgment. From our perspective, I would like us to see increasing our capital expenditures to the degree that we get competitive advantage from there. We've already indicated investment in head count, investment in head count is roughly speaking half engineering and half non-engineering, which has been historically our model.</p>
          <p>The engineering is for all the reasons that you could imagine, we are short key technical talent to achieve some of these broader initiatives. In the non-engineering, it's mostly in sales and that's frankly, you know quota bearing sales people who bring in money, money and income in the quarter. And on the product side, the products are really driven by the project strategy that we've talked about and those are largely controlled by a set of operating units where they have product heads within the company who pretty much make those decisions under the supervision of Larry and Sergey.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. The next question is from Jeetil Patel from Deutsche Bank. "The underlying margin profile of the paid search business is in the 50 plus percent range; on a contribution margin basis do your display advertising initiatives carry comparable margin? Can you speak to the margin profile of the display ad business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, it's Patrick. We just don't comment on specific product margins, so thanks for your questions, Jeetil, but typically, we just don't comment on any of those. So I'll just pass and I'll ask that we move to the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The next question is from Christa Quarles of Thomas Weisel Partners. "You recently removed TeleAtlas from your mapping product in the U.S. How mission critical is the underlying mapping data with regard to your mobile ad strategy? What other areas of your business can it help you with?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, this is Jonathan, Christa. So we launched the new maps dataset and we're now using it in the U.S. and Mexico, and we basically built this through a wide range of sources that include street view, overhead imagery, the Census Bureau, the Forest Service and what's so key here is it gives us lots more flexibility to create new types of maps.</p>
          <p>So for example, somebody walking or biking or tourists versus locals will want to use very different types of maps and it also leaves us much more open to users editing through MapMaker and other feedback mechanisms. So this is very, very significant and will allow us to launch better place pages, and just make the whole process of looking at local information much better.</p>
          <p>You know, if you think about it, behind the movie theater is a valid address in some countries, but the only way you can actually capture that on a map is with local knowledge and this is going to allow us to harvest that all over the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Jonathan. The next question is from Ben Schachter of Broadpoint.AmTech again. "International revenues, any change to order of countries that are the most meaningful contributors to revenue? Trying to get a sense of where Japan and the emerging economies rank relative to the big European countries. Are Brazil or China significant yet?" Nikesh?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, Ben. Whilst we don't give out the relative rankings or the revenues of countries outside of the U.S. and U.K. I think the best way to think about this, as we mentioned, 53% of our revenues come from outside the U.S. And if somebody earlier on the call has already done the math, that that part of our revenue continues to grow at a good pace.</p>
          <p>I did call out certain countries, so in that we have countries which grow fast, which grow very fast and I called out certain countries which are growing very fast for us. I think that should give you a sense of scale in terms of which parts of our business, which parts of the international markets are doing very well relative to the others, and over time, all these markets are relevant and significant for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. The next question is from Brian Pitz of UBS. "Would you talk about adoption of the DoubleClick Ad Exchange by ad networks and what kind of impact &#x2013; has there been any discernible impact to pricing on the content network?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think given that we launched our Ad Exchange this quarter it is important -- there's not enough data for us to be able to look at and be able to say these things with certainty. But if you think about what the Ad Exchange is already beginning to do for us, it is already beginning to take away some pricing inefficiency from the market because effectively you are able to collect inventory from various networks, which is unsold which you believe is roughly about 25% of the inventory in aggregate, ends up being unsold because it doesn't have a common exchange or common place to get traded.</p>
          <p>So that's what the Ad Exchange actually begins to enable. And that is the reason you are seeing many, many large networks wanting to participate in such an ad network because they want the inventory to be sold at the best price possible. So effectively, as we can get more and more sellers to the exchange, as we have more inventory in the exchange, you will begin to see some stability in price which also allows us to create some consistency in our ability to target the ads towards the right users. So I think overall, it's going to be positive for the overall display market. It is too early to tell precisely what the impact is based on our launch this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. The next question is from Mark Mahaney of Citi. "Can you provide any commentary on how material mobile searches have been to your overall search growth? Or when they could become material on a global basis? Also, what color can you provide on these searches in terms of monetization potential?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, it's Patrick. Just to give a sense, again, we don't give the detailed numbers. What we provided this quarter, which I think was a really revealing statistic, is on a quarter-over-quarter basis, mobile searches grew 30% on Google this last quarter. It tells you something about the mobile space, the space of the smart phones, and how they are really transformative.</p>
          <p>So, the combination of the Android platform with all the smart phones and the momentum in there, as well as the iPhone and the rest of them, I mean they are just basically transforming how people live on a mobile basis. And if you run the tape forward, I think, again, another support for the Android strategy, if you have, if we move forward, the adoption of these smart phones by having a lower cost infrastructure because it's Open Source, and you bring that, instead of taking seven years &#x2013; I'm just kind of giving an illustration, all this happens in four years, think of all the searches that will happen so much faster.</p>
          <p>So, the ecosystem is incredibly vibrant right now and clearly what's interesting about these phones is they &#x2013; there is a lot of new types of searches, because you're location-specific, you're activity specific, you're local specific, just a new set of areas there to create a new set of monetization opportunities. So it's for all these reasons that we are, so bullish about it and just really investing heavily. So that's, that's my best answer I can give you, Mark, without any of the specifics.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question, from Spencer Wang of Credit Suisse. "You indicated that you are prepared to invest heavily again. Can expense ratios remain stable in that context, or will expenses as a percent of revenues begin to increase?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me give you in the context of why we're making that -- the comment this quarter about investment. I think that the best way to characterize our situation is the following. Google really has been and continues to be an unconventional company that runs on its innovation agenda.</p>
          <p>I think it's fair to say that in the last 12 months, you'll remember 12 months ago we were sitting together and there was a massive crisis going on in the banking system, in the economy, and this was the worst recession in like generations, if not a hundred years. We decided at that time to just be prudent about navigating these uncharted territories, right.</p>
          <p>As Eric said a few minutes ago, now what's clear is the banking system is not collapsing, and the economy, even though many sectors are going to continue to hurt, the worst is behind us. It is in that context that I think it's important that now we go back to do what we really do well: innovate, invest, build the future. And that's what is really meant.</p>
          <p>And then I think as Eric mentioned a few minutes ago, we're really optimistic about, you know, making these investments and we're looking forward to it and that ties to both &#x2013; hiring and more CapEx and we'll judge them on a case by case basis. I think that that's the best way to understand what's going on really in the company. I'll turn it over to the next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. So the next question is from Jason Helfstein of Oppenheimer. "Give us some color on U.S. versus international paid click trends and CPCs in the quarter?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Jonathan. We really don't typically comment on the specifics there. We certainly saw click growth across lots of regions, and CPC growth, but the main thing you have to be looking at there is the blend. It is largely impacted by the growing regions like China, Brazil and India where the CPCs are relatively low.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The next question is also on CPCs or and paid clicks, so that's from Doug Anmuth at Barclays. "Do you think your growth going forward comes more from paid click volume or pricing increases?" Nikesh?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think this relates to the previous question which Jonathan answered. I think the best way, to again, think about this is there are still a lot of countries, a lot of parts of the world where we are still seeing more and more people come online, which creates more searches and therefore creates more paid click volume around the world. At the same time, a lot of our ads innovation, which we're doing, is going to drive some of the CPC growth in some of our more mature markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you, Nikesh. The next question is from James Mitchell of Goldman. "PPC has improved by 5% sequentially two quarters in a row with benefits from FX hedging. Does Google believe its PPC has already enjoyed most of the recovery rebound, or is PPC still sub-trend?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, we don't comment forward. James, you know, so rather &#x2013; I mean, we were really pleased with, as Nikesh said, right, in a way our revenue really reflects what's going on in the economy from the consumer side and from the advertiser side. And it's a great question as to what the coming quarters are going to look like. To give a bit of color commentary again on this, what's really interesting about Q4 this year is if you think about everything that happened last year, year-over-year comparisons are going to be really interesting.</p>
          <p>So for example, last year, there was a flood of inventory that needed to find a home, so discounting was quite dramatic and coupons were everywhere. This year, it's a different story with inventory at an all-time low and people prudent. It will just be interesting to see. So rather than to give you any kind of answers as to how we see the future, I think it's really important that people have a mental model of how they think the economy is going to rebound and everybody has their own view, but we don't comment on perspective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The next question is from Jim Friedland of Cowen. "The Google site's TAC rate was down quarter-over-quarter, 6% to 5.8% for the first time. Are you pulling out of some site traffic acquisition deals? Are you renegotiating contracts? Has the site TAC rate finally stabilized?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Patrick again. We &#x2013; every deal is done on a deal basis, and they are all profitable. We look for great partnerships. So we are not pulling out of any great deals. We just work with each of our partners. We're delighted to have so many partners. And every deal that makes sense, we actually do together. So &#x2013; and sometimes you have deals that either expired or didn't have the right mix, so you may have fluctuations like you have this quarter, but I wouldn't read too much into it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'm going to take one more question, and that's from George Askew of Stifel Nicolaus. "How rapidly do you expect head count to grow over the next two years?"</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to steal the thunder from a few comments and conversations Eric and I have had. And it's been about &#x2013; if you think about everything we've lived through together over the last year, it would have been great to continue to hire even sooner. So in that sense, we're delighted that we're able to now continue to fund for investing in our resources, head count resources.</p>
          <p>And then, you still have to kind of make sure that &#x2013; it's not about head count. It's about finding the people that fit in the Google culture, the best engineers, the best minds, and as we find them, we hire them. So it's more a function of finding these fit rather than to put quotas on a quarterly basis. And that's why this quarter we had a bit of a retreat in kind of just 100 or so Googlers, but it's not because we were trying to shrink. It's just, you have to find the right Googler. Eric, any more comments on this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I think this &#x2013; we &#x2013; in terms of recruiting, I think we do it well. And so, we will grow at whatever rate we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. So that wraps up the Q&amp;A portion. Again, we were trying something new this quarter, so we'd love to get your feedback. And now I'm going to turn the call over to Eric.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, just to finish up, I hope it's clear that we're very happy with the quarter. We believe we now have the confidence in our underlying business and the business trends to begin to get back to do the kinds of things that we do so well and that we really see as our mission, which are to make the world an information-rich place, to build some of these new businesses and really serve our customers very well.</p>
          <p>So with that, thank you all very much. Thank you, Maria, and thank you, all, for being on our call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And this concludes today's conference. We thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>