<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1242686" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>625</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Dane E. Holmes, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">David A. Viniar, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Guy Moszkowski</participant>
      <participant id="4">Glenn Schorr</participant>
      <participant id="5">Howard Chen</participant>
      <participant id="6">Meredith Whitney</participant>
      <participant id="7">Roger Freeman</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jeffery Harte</participant>
      <participant id="9">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="10">Michael Mayo</participant>
      <participant id="11">Chris Kotowski</participant>
      <participant id="12">James Mitchell</participant>
      <participant id="13">Robert Lee</participant>
      <participant id="14">Douglas Sipkin</participant>
      <participant id="15">Steve Stelmach</participant>
      <participant id="16">Richard Staite</participant>
      <participant id="17">Michael Hecht</participant>
      <participant id="18">Matthew Burnell</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My name is Gerald and I will be your conference facilitator today. I would like to welcome everyone to the Goldman Sachs second quarter 2009 earnings conference call. <mark type="audio gap" /> Also this call is being recorded today, Tuesday, July 14, 2009. Thank you. Mr. Holmes, you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. This is Dane Holmes, Director of Investor Relations at Goldman Sachs. Welcome to our second quarter earnings conference call. Today's call may include forward-looking statements. These statements represent the firm's belief regarding future events that by their nature are uncertain and outside of the firm's control. The firm's actual results and financial condition may differ possibly materially from what is indicated in these forward-looking statements. For a discussion of some of the risks and factors that could affect the firm's future results, please see the description of risk factors in our current annual report on Form 10-K for the fiscal year ended November 2008.</p>
          <p>I would also direct you to read the forward-looking disclaimers in our quarterly earnings release particularly as it relates to our investment banking transaction backlog and you should also read the information on the calculation of non-GAAP financial measures that is posted on the Investor Relations portion of our website at www.gs.com. This audiocast is copyrighted material of the Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and may not be duplicated, reproduced, or rebroadcast without our consent. Our Chief Financial Officer David Viniar will now review the firm's results. David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Dane. I would like to thank all of you for listening today. I will give an overview of our second quarter results and then take your questions. I'm pleased to report strong second quarter results for Goldman Sachs. Second quarter net revenues were $13.8 billion. Net earnings were $3.4 billion and earnings per diluted share were $4.93. Excluding $426 million in preferred dividends associated with TARP repayment, earnings per diluted share were $5.71 and our annualized return on common equity was 23.8%.</p>
          <p>Our second quarter results are a product of the breadth, resilience and adaptability of our client franchise. We continue to believe that a diverse set of global businesses staffed by dedicated professionals will be the critical driver of our long-term performance. Several of the favorable conditions that we experienced in the first quarter of 2009 extended into the second quarter.</p>
          <p>The competitive environment in the second quarter remained fragmented and levels of available risk capital remained low. Our ability to stay focused on serving our clients yielded strong results particularly within our multifaceted FICC business. Importantly while first quarter 2009 FICC results reflected strength in our rates and commodities businesses, second quarter performance was driven by higher contribution from our credit and currencies businesses. This further demonstrates the benefits of having a diversified business model.</p>
          <p>The quarterly improvement in our results was also a function of a more favorable operating environment for several of our other businesses, largely driven by higher equity market prices and activity levels. As a result, we posted strong revenues in our equity underwriting business within Investment Banking and in our equity sales and trading business within Trading and Principal Investments. Our principal investment segment also benefited from higher equity prices particularly as it relates to our ICBC investment.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, we faced headwinds in the second quarter of 2009. The operating environment for several of our businesses including M&amp;A advisory and security services remains challenging. An uncertain macroeconomic outlook coupled with low CEO confidence has resulted in lower M&amp;A activity. Given the industry wide reduction in hedge fund assets and leverage, the results within our security service business were lower than in prior years. Despite the challenging environment, we maintain market-leading positions in both of these businesses.</p>
          <p>In addition, our results include fair value losses due to downward price pressure in commercial real estate. Second quarter results were negatively impacted by approximately 700 million of fair value losses associated with commercial real estate loans within FICC, nearly 500 million of losses within RIPEA and 170 million in noncompensation expenses reflecting impairment charges related to real estate assets.</p>
          <p>Results in the second quarter also included a $426 million preferred dividend associated with the repayment of the TARP preferred stock and approximately $300 million in CVA losses associated with the tightening of our credit spreads. In light of the difficult macro environment, we continue to conservatively manage our risk capital and liquidity levels. The risk reduction efforts that we undertook in prior quarters lessened the negative impact to further declines in asset values in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>We also continue to benefit from having virtually no direct exposure to the retail consumer business. Given our cautious outlook, maintaining robust levels of risk-adjusted capital for the time being is appropriate. At the end of the quarter, we had a Tier 1 ratio under Basel I of 13.8% and a Tier 1 ratio under Basel II of 16.1%. We also maintained a record liquidity pool with our global core excess averaging $171 billion during the quarter. We have an established track record of dynamically managing our capital and liquidity based on our assessment of the operating environment and potential opportunities. Our current levels of capital and liquidity reflect both the potential for further market disruptions as well as the opportunity to capitalize on distressed opportunities.</p>
          <p>I'll now review each of our businesses. Investment Banking produced net revenues of $1.4 billion, up 75% from the first quarter. Second quarter advisory revenues were $368 million, down 30% from the first quarter. Goldman Sachs ranked first in announced M&amp;A globally as we advised on a number of important transactions that were announced during the quarter. These include BHP Billiton's A$73.1 billion joint venture with Rio Tinto, Liberty Entertainment's $14.5 billion sale to DIRECTV and Sumitomo's $5.8 billion acquisition of Nikko Cordial. We were also adviser on a number of significant closed transactions including Rohm and Haas' $18.6 billion sale to Dow Chemical, Enel's &#x20AC;9.6 billion acquisition of Endesa and Hutchison Telecom's A$3.6 billion merger with Vodafone's Australian telecom operations.</p>
          <p>Second quarter underwriting net revenues were $1.1 billion. Equity underwriting revenues were $736 million, up significantly from the first quarter. The increase in activity reflected our clients' capital needs, particularly in the financial institution sector which coincided with greater investor appetite for equity assets. The activity was further enhanced by stabilizing equity market values. Debt underwriting improved 35% to $336 million given the strength in investment grade and municipal issuance during the quarter.</p>
          <p>During the second quarter, we participated in many noteworthy underwriting transactions, including HSBC's $19.6 billion rights offering, the State of California's $6.9 billion municipal bond offerings and Arcelor Mittal's $4 billion common stock and convertible notes offering. Our investment banking backlog declined during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to Trading and Principal Investments which is comprised of FICC, equities and principal investments. Net revenues were $10.8 billion in the second quarter, reflecting particular strength across our FICC and equities client franchise. FICC net revenues were $6.8 billion in the second quarter, representing a 4% increase from the first quarter. Our FICC performance continued to be driven by historically wide margins, strong market share and a focus on more liquid, plain vanilla transactions. Credit products net revenues were up substantially due to higher levels of customer activity across both investment grade and high yield products, largely in cash and other liquid markets.</p>
          <p>Net revenues in currencies were up sequentially on higher trading volumes in volatile yet trending markets. Interest rate net revenues were strong but down from a record first quarter as client activity levels declined and spreads narrowed modestly. Commodities revenues were also solid but down sequentially on lower customer activity levels. Mortgage results improved sequentially but continued to be negatively impacted by losses within our commercial estate loan portfolio which totaled approximately $700 million.</p>
          <p>Turning to equities, net revenues for the second quarter were $3.2 billion, up 59% sequentially. Equities trading net revenues were up over 100% as equity values increased leading to more active new issue markets and higher customer volumes across both cash trading and derivatives. Net revenues from our Principal Strategies business were positive but not a significant revenue driver in the quarter. Equities commissions were up 5% sequentially to $1 billion.</p>
          <p>Turning to risk, average daily value at risk in the second quarter was $245 million, up modestly due to an increase in equity VAR offsetting a decrease in interest rate VAR.</p>
          <p>Let me now review principal investments, which produced net revenues of $811 million in the second quarter. Our investment in ICBC generated net revenues of $948 million, driven largely by a 30% increase in ICBC stock price during the quarter. Our corporate principal investing portfolio generated net gains of $343 million and real estate principal investments generated approximately $500 million in losses.</p>
          <p>In asset management and security services, we reported second quarter net revenues of $1.5 billion, up 6% from the first quarter. Asset management produced net revenues of $922 million which was down 3% from the first quarter. Assets under management grew 6% sequentially to $819 billion, largely as a result of market appreciation. Security services net revenues of $615 million were up 22% sequentially due to the seasonally stronger second quarter.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to expenses. Compensation and benefits expense in the second quarter was $6.6 billion, accrued at 49% of year to date net revenues. As I've highlighted previously, this number includes salaries, discretionary compensation, amortization of prior year equity awards and other items such as payroll taxes, severance costs and benefits. As in every other year, we must accrue compensation based on our expectation of the full year expense but incentive compensation decisions are not made until year end and thus compensation will ultimately reflect the firm's performance for the entire year.</p>
          <p>Second quarter noncompensation expenses excluding those related to consolidated investments were $1.8 billion, 11% higher than the first quarter, driven by higher brokerage, clearing and distribution expenses and other expenses which included a $50 million special assessment by the FDIC.</p>
          <p>Total staff at the end of the second quarter was approximately 29,400, down 1% from the first quarter. Our effective tax rate was approximately 31.7% for the second quarter.</p>
          <p>For the past two years, we've operated in an extremely challenging environment. Our performance in this cycle has been guided by several principles, including putting our clients' needs first, executing our stated strategy and acting as a good steward of the firm. We adhere to these philosophies to enhance and preserve our franchise and protect the interests of our shareholders. These are long standing principles and we remain committed to them.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, their value is amplified in a difficult environment. Thus, we will continue to focus on maintaining our leading global franchise, serving the world's most important corporations, financial institutions, governments and high net worth individuals. In the current environment, our clients' demand for effective advice and execution is elevated. To meet these demands, we will continue to provide a broad set of solutions on an integrated basis, seeking to serve as a trusted advisor, financier, asset manager, co-investor and market maker.</p>
          <p>This environment is not conducive to straightforward solutions. Our culture of innovation and nimbleness allows us to react quickly in this dynamic environment. Financial markets and businesses are increasingly global and our geographic reach uniquely positions us to serve our clients anywhere in the world. Being a good steward of our financial position means that we will continue to manage our capital and liquidity levels based upon a conservative assessment of the potential risks and opportunities that may lie ahead. This allows us to provide risk capital where it is scarce and stay focused externally. We believe that our commitment to these principles represents the best strategy for delivering attractive returns through the cycle.</p>
          <p>With that, I'd like to thank you again for listening today and I'm now happy to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>First question comes from Guy Moszkowski with Banc of America Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Guy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just first, one very factual question, what was your risk weighted assets at the end of the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our risk weighted assets were on a Basel I basis about $409 billion and on a Basel II basis about $382 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So based on a sort of flat to smaller average balance sheet, I guess, relative to the prior quarter and improved FICC and equity trading revenues, it would seem that your bid offer spreads on average seemed to have actually improved based on the, compared to the first quarter. Is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say they were kind of flattish. And that what really drove it were activity levels, which kind of didn't result in a whole lot of assets on our balance sheet because the velocity of assets was quite high.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And you alluded in your comments to the fact that a lot of the focus really is on very liquid and kind of plain vanilla stuff. And when I met with you and your team a few weeks ago, there was even some discussion of distress and the fact that you really weren't seeing good risk adjusted returns on a lot of the distressed deal flow that you were seeing, and so you weren't doing much there. Is that still fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hasn't changed at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So then I guess the follow up question to all of that is, if your core excess is around 170 billion and I think your Tier 1 common to RWA is something approaching 11%, and I think the government's hurdled for exiting TARP sounds like, based on some other firms, that it must have been around six, 6.5%, how do you think about deploying what looks like pretty significant excess liquid capital over time? And I guess the corollary to that would be, do the results of the first half which were obviously very encouraging, do they encourage you to raise your targeted ROE from the 20% kind of return on tangible goal that you've talked about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me answer that question first, no. Our target as you know has not changed since we went public and I don't think it's going to change for now. That's what we say over the cycle and you know there are good parts of the cycle and bad parts of the cycle and I think that's a fair target for over the cycle.</p>
          <p>As far as deploying capital, a couple of things I would say, Guy. First of all, the world is still not a great place. I mean, there are, the economies are still in difficult situations in many parts of the world. Second, we're hopeful that we will see opportunities, although we're a buyer but there have not been a lot of sellers, certainly not at prices we deem attractive so I don't know when that's going to happen or if it's going to happen. And the third thing is that there are going to be new capital regulations coming out. We don't know what they're going to be. So we have to wait and see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's all fair. Thanks very much and thanks for coming on this morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No problem. Thank you, Guy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Glenn Schorr with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, hi, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Glenn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's talk about funding needs just for a second. I look at your debt maturity schedule and it's actually in a lot better shape than most but you still have some coming due each year, ten or so for the next, who knows, eight years or whatever. How much have you prefunded in terms of the near term and obviously, I take that in the context of, as Guy just pointed out, really high capital ratios and big liquidity buffer. But what I'm getting at is people are issuing in this market, you have been able to issue in this market at tighter spreads but still not tight enough spreads.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that in a way you just answered the question. We have a lot more cash than we have debt maturities coming due. We're not forced to issue debt for quite a while if we don't want to. I think we will still want to continue to issue small amounts over time at various maturities. We'd like to keep walking our spreads in which has actually been happening. As I think the world is getting better and people are getting, again, more comfortable with us, so I wouldn't tell you we're going to be out of the market. I expect we'll be in the market periodically, more to continue to have access because we have to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. On this phenomena of the wider spreads, and I think you've spoken well enough to, it's not at its widest but it's also not going to necessarily go back to where we come from. Help us walk through how much of it is reduced competitive landscape and how much of that is temporary from the standpoint of, because some of it's coming in the more liquid products, it's not necessarily all being earned in high risk weighted asset businesses. These are businesses that are actually flow businesses that are more of, if anything, people are going to allocate more resources to going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, it's very hard to quantify. I think you've hit on what a big driver of the performance has been. And I don't, I think some part of it is sustainable and some part of it is not. Over time, firms will recover. Firms will be willing to provide more risk capital and it's going to happen over time and it will drive spreads narrower. It just will happen over time. It always does.</p>
          <p>Of course, as you know, in some of the other businesses we have, they're in some ways lower than we expect and see. I would expect that as you see more and more people willing to provide risk capital, you'll see the merger business start to pick up. So you have some things that hopefully will offset.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. One last one then. I know the answer but I got to ask it anyway. A bunch of companies take a look at the new environment with new regulation coming down the pipe and think about what's happened in the funding markets and have gone through some rigorous business line  rationalization process.</p>
          <p>I think Goldman's DNA is more of capital is fungible and it kind of goes towards, with client needs than where the investment opportunities are. But has there been any, quote, business line rationalization? Do you see any need for that? And is it, how dramatically is the answer based on where the new capital requirements shake out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We, of course, have to see what the capital requirements are. We don't really think that's going to change the way we do business. And you know, Glenn, we've been quite consistent in saying that we like our business model, that we think our business lines are good business lines. We're always looking to expand them where we think there are opportunities. We largely expand them in different locations around the world, and they ebb and flow at different times. Rather than getting out of businesses, which actually I think we think has been problematic for some. When you tend to get in and out of businesses, you tend to get out at the bottom and in at the top, and we try not to do that. We try and be pretty consistent. So no, we're pretty happy with the business mix we have right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Awesome. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Meredith Whitney with Meredith Whitney Advisors. Your next question comes from Howard Chen with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Howard</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my questions. Somewhat of a follow-up to Guy's question on capital. With respect to liquidity, global excess liquidity continues to grow as you noted. How do you think about the potential drag that's having on the returns, if at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It has a fairly big drag on our returns. You know, $172 billion of capital of excess liquidity where we're funding kind of at unsecured rates rather than secured rates and in this environment, there's a pretty big spread. So it has a pretty big drag but in the risk reward of having that drag and having enough liquidity under any and all circumstances versus not having the drag and potentially not having enough liquidity, we'll take the drag. You know we've always thought that liquidity risk management was the single most important thing for any financial firm including ours. We continue to think that, and so, I think we're at the very conservative end right now, but we'll always be at the conservative end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay. And then second, I know you mentioned the 700 million of commercial real estate writedowns in your commentary, but could you just provide with us where gross exposure levels and marks stood at the end of the quarter in the usual hot spots?</p>
          <p>I think we're really just down to commercial real estate now</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's really the only thing. And if you look across all of our commercial real estate within FICC, we had round numbers, $8 billion, about 1.6 billion of that was securities. So you really market value, about $6.4 billion of loans and that's marked really in the low 50s.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then last one from me, David. A lot of real time industry discussion right now on OTC market regulation and more recently the energy trading markets. Any evolved thoughts on your end on how all this plays out and how you are potentially weighing the positives and negatives for the firm?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, it's too early to tell. Again, all the things that have been proposed have been at very high levels right now. On OTC derivatives, we are a believer in central clearing. Wherever things can be standardized and be cleared centralized, cleared centrally, we think that's good and it's good for the market and actually it's good for us because it levels the playing field in some ways. We're always kind of at the very conservative end in our credit terms, so we think this will level the playing field, so we like that.</p>
          <p>There's always going to be a need for nonstandardized OTC derivatives to help our clients manage their risk. I mean there are a lot of corporations that need the risk management services and that don't want to provide the initial margin of trading on the exchange. So we're supportive of it where it makes sense, and as far as in commodities, again, we believe very strongly that supply and demand is what drives the markets more than anything else and whenever we're doing transactions, tend to be on the other side of corporate clients. So consumers need hedging, producers need hedging and you need financial intermediaries to help do that. But we'll see what the regulations show.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for the thoughts and congrats on the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Meredith Whitney with Meredith Whitney Advisors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. Good thing I'm not a tech analyst. I had a glitch there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't know what happened to you, Meredith.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was on mute. My question relates to, once you have established or the government has established, the regulators have establish clear capital levels that they deem appropriate, when would you update your shelf? Because that looks a little late in context of what you could repurchase. And then as a follow on, what's your appetite in terms of sequencing to repurchase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, shelf really is for issuing, not repurchasing. So I think we can, from a just purely technical matter we don't need to update the shelf to repurchase. I think we're fine there and we're always reviewing both our equity and our debt shelf so that we have sufficient powder whenever we need to issue. And so we review it constantly. We talk to our Board about it and whenever we need to update it, we just go back to the Board and subject to their agreement we would update it. But I wouldn't read much into it one way or the other.</p>
          <p>Again, as far as timing and sequencing, it's too early to say anything. As I said before, first of all, we're going to manage things conservatively because the environment is still a very tricky environment, and as you well know and I know you believe, we're way, way far away from being out of the woods in the environment. So we're going to be at the conservative end on our capital. Plus, there's going to be new capital regulations coming out, and we have to look and see what they are before we make any decisions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And then would you talk about sort of the sequencing month to month in terms of activity and then how this month is shaping up so far?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, we don't normally go through month to month. We disclose quarterly not monthly. But I would tell you there wasn't that big a difference across the second quarter. It was pretty standard across really the entire quarter and it's just much too early to tell this month. We're two weeks into it and one of the weeks was July 4th so that was naturally a very, very quiet week. So it's really hard to say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, thanks David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No problem, Meredith.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Roger Freeman with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, David</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Roger</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess on the credit trading side, can you talk to, I understand it's sort of been flow driven revenues there, but we've gone through the best six month period for high yield and high grade returns in history. And I'm wondering how much of the revenues there are inventory benefits because it's an inventory business, trading corporate credit and did you take a view on spread tightening where you didn't hedge out that exposure? And then if we're not going to have that in the back half of the year, how much of an impact would that be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Virtually none was based purely on spreads tightening and inventory markups. We don't, we tend to move around whether we're long or short on a daily basis. Most of the P&amp;L coming from our credit trading business was in a variety of ways flow business. That was really the biggest driver. It was not just markups of inventory.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So you had hedged out the credit spread tightening?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, pretty much so and in our legacy leverage loan positions, we're down to a little over $2 billion of market value and that is largely hedged as well. So there's very little of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That doesn't mean in the future some day we wouldn't take a view either bullish or bearish, but that was very little.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, okay. And then on equity trading, I guess one thing that I'm trying to reconcile is the relative strength of the trading line item versus the commissions. The trading was right up at a record, commissions were strong but not at the same level of strength. Trading deal flow, you would think would generate outside commissions, so I guess the question is how much of that was derivatives trading?</p>
          <p>And then also kind of look at the VAR, right, it was the one area where VAR really picked up a lot. So it looks like a lot more risk was taken in equities trading. So can you kind of reconcile some of those pieces?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Well first of all, it was really strong across both derivatives and cash. And I would say, and you see this sometimes, you go back in history you will see times where what I would say trading activity levels were not consistent with commission levels which were just really, what is on the exchange, and so the two are not necessarily related to each other.</p>
          <p>And one of the things we've always done and you know, is we will take risk where our clients want us to and where there are opportunities. So it's not unusual for our risk to be up in one area and down in another area where we see opportunities where our clients want us to. So there was more activity and the equity risk was up because there was more activity and interest rate risk was down because there was less activity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean is it fair to say within cash trading that facilitation was up a fair amount in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right and then I guess on commodities just to drill a little into what Howard was asking, so you've historically talked commodities being 20% of FICC. I mean is that still sort of a range that we're in right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's a very wide range around that. That's a number that we have given you at times of what it's been since we've gone public in total, but there's a really wide range quarter to quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are we in a upper or lower end of that right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One or the other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me ask this. When you think about the regulatory changes here, again, a lot of high level stuff has been discussed, but if position limits are put in place but the hedge exemptions remain, it sounds to me based on what you said before that that would not have any material impact on your business because you really are just hedging client risk as opposed to doing a lot of prop trading in energy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. That is right, but boy, the devil is in the details. So it's hard to say until you see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Question is how you define hedges, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's exactly right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Last question, on TLGP debt, there's been some discussion about you taking that out. Is there a call, are you able to call that debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I don't think any of the debt we've issued has call features so no, we have no ability just to take it out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. All right, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Jeff Harte with Sandler O'Neill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of things. Investment banking, obviously underwriting's very strong. You mentioned the backlog was down some and how good FICC specifically was this quarter. As we start looking forward, I mean, does the FICC capital raise environment still have legs to run through the back half of the year, or are there kind of other areas you could see picking that up?</p>
          <p>How are you looking at the underwriting business in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well first, one interesting thing to always think about when you think of the backlog, a lot of equity deals actually never get in the backlog. M&amp;A deals always get in the backlog because they take time. But it's not unusual in today's environment for at least with some number of equity deals for them to come up because client decides on a Tuesday they want to do an equity raise, they call us on Tuesday afternoon and we do a book build over Wednesday and do the deal on Thursday.</p>
          <p>So the backlog is a very good indication of mergers, and it's somewhat an indication of equities too, but you have to be a little careful of looking at backlog as an indicator of what's going to happen later in the year in underwritings. Look, a lot of financial institution equity was issued, but I think there are still a lot of corporations around the world that need to rebuild their balance sheet. And as you know if markets stay okay and stay receptive, I think there will be a lot of equity offerings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Kian Abouhossein with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Equity derivatives, can you talk a little bit about the business in terms of performance because if you look on a quarter on quarter basis, clearly the equity numbers were very strong. And just trying to understand if this was a very important driver also on a quarter on quarter basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes our equity derivatives business as you know is a very good business for Goldman Sachs. Both our derivatives and our cash business were very strong in the quarter although derivatives was up more quarter over quarter than cash was.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And you mentioned FX being very strong but volatility came down quite materially in the second quarter which I assume impacts margins. Can you explain the strengths in FX?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There was a lot of activity and you had pretty good trending markets which is always good for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on margins, we're hearing some of the European banks indicating some margin pressure starting to come in on fixed income. Do you see any regional differences between U.S. emerging market Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not significantly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how do you see margins in fixed income? Can you, if I compare them to two, 2.5 years ago, at what level would you say they are within the fixed income worlds on a comparable basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say they're better than they were two, 2.5 years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But not two, three times better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's hard to quantify to that level of precision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And lastly in respect to fixed income, do you believe there's a real structural change in the way fixed income will be priced, or do you think it's a lack of capital which will flow back over time into the business and reduce margins to the levels that we've seen two, 2.5 years ago?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that clearly margins are up now. I think it is unrealistic to think that some amount of capital won't flow back. I think some amount of capital will which will reduce margins to some extent but I'm not convinced that it will go all the way back to where it was.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Mike Mayo with CLSA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you quantify the change in the backlogs from the first to the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Non-U.S. versus U.S. revenues, can you talk about that linked quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, one of the things we always tell you is you got to be careful about that quarter over quarter because we have global books and global trading. Best estimate it was roughly 50/50 U.S./non-U.S. It was actually something like 51/49 U.S./non-U.S. but pretty close to 50/50.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Any non-U.S. countries that stand out in particular as doing a little bit better?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. It was a little bit more in Europe than in Asia but not dramatically more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then you've replaced lost revenues a lot and just when we look at the underwriting from the second quarter, it looks like most of the underwriting revenues came from banks. I'm just looking at the same geologic data you'd have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But as you point out 19 of the 20 biggest equity deals you did were to banks and financial firms. So my question is, if the banking industry is saying they have enough capital now and you might not believe that, but does that mean you'll be hard pressed to replace those underwriting revenues from the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you know I never talk about consistency of revenues. So don't know is one answer, but as I just said, there are a lot of companies around the world that still need to fix balance sheets. And I think that if the markets stay receptive, that there will be a lot of equity issuance going on over the rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And by receptive, do you mean simply the level of the stock markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well both the level and the willingness of buyers to buy. You know you had a lot of cash, a lot of investors wanted to take equity positions over the course of the second quarter. They need to stay, they need to continue to feel that way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And last question, we've talked about the multiplier effect. How much does trading go up for every dollar of underwriting you do. And can you say what the multiplier effect was, say, in your underwriting business? In other words, if I looked year over year on your published data, equity trading went up six times relative to the increase in equity underwriting. Now I know if there's a lot of, a lot of data's in that equity trading number. Would you say the multiplier is six to one or two to one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I actually, Mike, don't know. And I think it's not necessarily consistent, but clearly around equity underwritings you are going to see a lot of trading activity. It's not linear at all. And so I would be hard pressed to give you an exact number there. I think I would really be making it up if I gave it to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Chris Kotowski with Oppenheimer</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I noticed that corporate private equity investments were up about $500 million from last quarter to this quarter. And I was wondering is that indicative of new investing, or is it marking to market up positions that were there and does it relate to a like willingness to put dry powder to use?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was largely marking to market things that were there. There were some new investments but more of it was things this we already had.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just I guess like some of my brethren on the phone, I'm stunned to sort of see your TCE levels about 50% above where they were just 18 months ago. And I guess we're all wondering, what do you do with all this capital, and how long do you warehouse it? And I'm curious, what capital ratio do you think is the most relevant that we should be looking at and any idea kind of what you think a long-term target is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I will give you the same answer I gave everyone else when it comes to capital, which is that we're not out of the woods. The world is still a tough place. We're going to be conservative. There's new capital regulations coming. We're hoping we'll see opportunities, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On that and as far as a number, like with all things, with risk, with other things, we don't think there is a single number that people should look at. We think you should look at a variety of numbers, TCE, Tier 1 capital ratios. But we're a believer that, and Basel II being a very, a reasonably good measure of risk and a good capital ratio, everyone's going to be moving onto Basel II over the next several years so I think that will be a consistent measure over the next couple of years and I think it's a good one to look at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from James Mitchell with Buckingham Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey good morning, David. A quick question on asset management business, assets under management up, revenues down. Can you talk to the dynamic there?</p>
          <p>Is it just some beginning of period pricing in the institutional business, or is there something else going on there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's actually, the two things were one as you know, assets under management did not come in all at the beginning the quarter so it took a while for them to go up. But really what it was, it's a small difference and there were a couple of items in the first quarter that were some one time fees that were not repeated in the second quarter. If they hadn't been there, it's small, but if it hadn't been there then you would have seen what you would have expected which is up from second quarter, first quarter aligned with assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nothing else to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And then maybe on just following up on the equity VAR question. The one situation is if you look in equities, volatility was down quite a bit. I would have thought that would help dampen any increase in the VAR. Is it the trading side or is it really just the underwriting business was so strong and you have some capital and risk allocation to the big uptick in the equity underwriting book? Just trying to understand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. It was really the trading side much more than the underwriting side. And yes, volatility was down and that would help dampen it, but there was just a lot more activity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and was that more driven by cash or the derivatives business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There was a lot of activity in both sites</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and maybe lastly on just M&amp;A, obviously there's a cycle. It tends to take a while. Balance sheets need to be pared first. What's your sense of I guess the dialogue and the outlook as we go forward here? Do you think given that the markets have been stable for a little while and if that lasts, do you think we finally start to see some uptick there, or do we still got to get through a few more quarters of people repairing balance sheets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that if the markets stay stable, you will start to see a big uptick in activity, but you won't see an uptick in revenues for a number of quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh no, sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think if you really have stable markets for another few months and CEO confidence starts to get a little better, then I think you will start to see some uptick there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But you're seeing good levels of dialogue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but we have for a while and it hasn't translated into deals. So you really need that stability for it to happen</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay. One last thing on the CRE investments, do you guys disclose what your commitments are? I mean obviously, you wrote off about 500 million in the investment line, but I think total outstanding only fell around 100 million. So are you guys, is there drawdowns on commitments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There were a couple hundred million dollars of drawdowns, and I think we disclosed it in the Q.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right I'll take it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's all in the Q.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right thanks, bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Robert Lee with KBW.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Most of my questions were asked but one or two quick ones. First actually relates to the money fund business. Obviously within the scheme of Goldman it's not huge but in that industry you are a pretty big player. You can give us your thoughts on where you see capital, if you see capital requirements starting to come into that business as it's one of the proposals out there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, again, too early. I'm sorry to be not answering these questions but it's just too early to tell. I mean there's a bunch of proposals out there. They're at the very high level. That is one of the things that's on the table and we just don't know exactly where that's going to end up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and maybe in the security services business and clearly, as you point out it's been impacted a lot by a variety of issues, lower customer balances, et cetera. But as you look out, what are you kind of hearing from your clients? Are you seeing that, it seems like we're getting through the redemption cycle that industry is starting to talk about maybe even flows at some point later in the year. Are you hearing that reflected back from your clientele?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think that's absolutely right. I think we're largely, assuming performance stays okay, which it's been for the first half of this year, performance has been pretty good. It feels like we're pretty much through the redemption cycle and it actually looks like you are going to start to see money flowing into hedge funds. How that continues will be really dependent on performance, but that's certainly what it feels like right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right great. That was it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Douglas Sipkin with Pali Capital</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just two questions. One, obviously tremendous pricing improvement in the fixed income trading business. Is that carrying over into the underwriting side as well? Are you guys seeing maybe the ability to raise prices a little bit there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think underwriting prices have been largely flat and they have been for a while. They haven't really changed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, even for like rights offerings and things of that nature?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not materially different.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Secondly, in terms of FICC, what percentage of the volume increase would you attribute to maybe investors getting in front of potential regulatory changes or thinking about CDS moving more to exchanges versus sort of just people getting more involved in risk assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it was largely driven by the latter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it was really people having much more of a desire to get involved in risk assets over the course of the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just third question, can you update us on when you guys officially are changing locations, and are there any things we need to be thinking about in terms of occupancy expenses after that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will begin to move into our new building in the fourth quarter of this year, and then we'll continue to move in over the course of next year. And I think you will see an increase in occupancy expenses over the fourth quarter of this year and across next year as we're kind of in two buildings and then you'll see it decline again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Steve Stelmach with FBR Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, David</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just real quick question on competitive landscape post TARP repayment. Are you seeing those who have repaid TARP become a little bit more aggressive since the TARP repayment, or is the competitive landscape pretty much as it was for most of the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think it's really changed at all based on TARP repayment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So people are still generally risk averse, at least your competitors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Most are and some are not but most are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and just maybe I will ask the capital question one last time. But when you think about your capital levels is, how should we think about what you think the regulatory environment's going to look like versus just your general risk aversion out there?</p>
          <p>Like how should we think about that split?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, I think they both influence us right now. We don't know where the regulatory environment is going to change, but we also are very cognizant that the environment is still risky. It's not that long since we're in a really risky time and it's not like economies around the world are booming, and so there's a lot of risk out there. Both of those things are influencing us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>General mantra is just more the better at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Richard Staite with Atlantic Equities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Can you give an update on how you plan to grow the asset management and private banking businesses going forward? I think the scenario where you've mentioned the possibility of acquisitions in the past and given the strength of your balance sheet, you're obviously in a good position to do that. So do you see opportunities out there at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Look, we've always felt the same way about that business, which is if there were an acquisition that made sense financially for us to do, we would certainly consider it. When we look at the prices of most of the acquisitions, we think that they haven't made sense and that you've had to assume really heroic growth rates that we don't think are realistic.</p>
          <p>In a way sometimes when you make acquisitions, you have to pay for them twice as well because you generally have to buy them and then you have to give big guarantees to the people to keep them, and we've been able to grow that business organically. It's taken a while, but we've grown it quite successfully and almost exclusively organically and the high likelihood is that's the way we're going to continue to grow it in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Michael Hecht with JMP Securities</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning, David. How are you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to come back to the equity trading number and the sustainability there. I mean it's, 2.2 billion is obviously just a monster number. I know you said it wasn't a big portion from like Principal Strategies or prop trading and the derivatives were strong but just trying to think about any of the other drivers there. I mean I think you guys report insurance activities there and then how do we think about just the 15% positive move in the equity markets here, and do we need to see a strong equity market environment like that to drive that type of quarter in equity trading?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The biggest drivers continue to be cash and derivatives trading. So the, yes insurance is in there, GSP is in there but they're not drivers. It's really cash and derivatives trading is the biggest driver. And you know the interesting thing about the equity markets is it probably has the most correlation of any market between the direction of prices and how we do, not because we're long or short but because it is the one market where you tend to see more activity when the market's going up because people are more confident. They feel better. They do more.</p>
          <p>That's not an absolute so you could see a situation where equity markets are flattish or up a little or down a little and we do quite well. But as you know, our results are really tied more to activity levels than anything and in equity markets, people tend to do more when markets are improving and so it usually is helpful to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, no that's helpful, thanks. And then just on FICC and maybe trading broadly, I mean it sounds like you're saying that the trading spreads we're seeing are likely to continue for the near term. I mean over the longer term, we'll have to see. But I'm just wondering about how we think about normal kind of third quarter and even like second half seasonality in trading particularly when we have seen such a very strong first half result?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is no normal. I wish I could tell you today something that was normal in our business but I wouldn't know how to define it. We'll just have to see over the second half of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I just wanted to follow up on your comments on the M&amp;A cycle and what we need to see to spur more activity. I think you used to kind of speak to you kind of tracking the level of conversations that bankers are having with corporate CEOs. In other words some sense of like a pre pipeline of deals. I mean, how is that kind of tracking these days?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's pretty high. I mean there's a lot of conversation but it's been pretty high for a while and it hasn't translated into deals. Now it's a little bit higher now. I think people are feeling a little bit better but not enough better to really pull the trigger yet. And so it's going to have &#x2013; confidence will need to go up even higher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and so if we're thinking about an M&amp;A recovery, I mean it's definitely not going to be a second half of '09 story, I mean maybe 2010, maybe longer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what I think. I think you'll start to see it, you might see more activity pick up in the second half of this year but you won't see revenues until next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay got it. And then just last question for me on expense trends. I mean 2.1 billion of noncomp, kind of flat quarter over quarter I thought was pretty impressive, particularly with the tick up in the trading businesses, equities in particular. I'm mean I was just surprised we didn't see more of the variable noncomp expenses tick up. I mean any color for the outlook on noncomp expense?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In some ways, we hope it goes up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We would like to see our BC&amp;E go up because volumes explode. We would like to see more travel and more things that, because business is up a lot. But we're keeping a tight lid on expenses because we're not out of the woods by any means and I think you'll see it go up with activity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Matt Burnell with Wells Fargo Securities</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David. Thanks for taking my question. Most of my questions have been asked and answered. But, and I hate to beat a dead horse on the equity, but let me try to take this in another direction. As you look at your adjusted leverage targets over the next year or two, three years, away from looking at it quarter to quarter, how should we think about where you sit today and where those ratios conceptually might move given where we've been over the past two to three years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Look, we actually don't necessarily target balance sheet leverage, either gross leverage or adjusted leverage because we think in some ways that's not a good measure. Now we know a lot of people focus on it so we're cognizant of it. But we've had this conversation. Depending on how liquid your assets are, you can be more highly levered and less risky or less highly levered and more risky.</p>
          <p>But I will tell you that the adjusted leverage ratios are at the low end of where we've been historically and I would not expect them to continue to stay this low over time. If the world stays really risky, then we might keep them low, but if the world starts to improve a little bit, I would expect to see those leverages start to go up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And I guess one question in terms specifically to Goldman Sachs bank, has there been any material change to the deposits in that bank over the quarter, or just the broad funding mix of the bank over the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think they've been largely stable over the course of the quarter, both in deposits and the funding mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then one last question in terms of liquidity, you've given us the average core liquidity number. Can you give us the trend for the quarter end balance relative to the beginning of the quarter balance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was pretty stable over the course of the quarter. It went down a little bit right at the end of the quarter because we repaid the TARP by $10 billion. Other than that, it's been pretty stable over the course of the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Ron Mandle with GIC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Hi, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi Ron.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I had two questions. One, I was wondering if you could comment on your credit facility with CIT and what your exposure might be and if things go considerably badly for them from here? And then the second question was in regard to buying back the TARP warrants, where you stand, how we should think about how much that might cost and so on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. CIT, we are, between our collateral and our hedges, we think we are well secured and well protected. So we think we're fine there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What does that mean, well secured, well hedged? You mean, if they draw down, you have the collateral that would fully cover the amount of the draw?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on warrants, we are in discussions with the Treasury.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you think you will be buying them, or will you go to arbitration, or will they be auctioned? What do you think, where do you think that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't know. We're in discussions right now. Too early to tell.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What kind of timeframe should we be thinking of in that regard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, not sure. We're in the middle of discussions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And I would like to turn the conference back to Mr. Holmes for any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you, everyone, for joining us for our second quarter earnings call. If you have any additional questions, please feel free to give us a call in the Investor Relations department. Otherwise, please enjoy the rest of your day. Bye</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude today's teleconference. You may now all disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>