<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1261107" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-10-15</date>
    <companies>
      <company>625</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Dane E. Holmes, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">David A. Viniar, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Glenn Schor</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Guy Moszkowski</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Roger Freeman</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Howard Chen</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Mike Mayo</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Chris Kotowski</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Michael Carrier</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Meredith Whitney</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Robert Lee</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Ed Najarian</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Steve Stelmach</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Doug Sipkin</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Matthew Burnell</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Michael Hecht</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My name is Gerald , and I will be your conference facilitator today. I would like to welcome everyone to the Goldman Sachs third quarter 2009 earnings conference call. After the speakers' remarks, there will be a question-and-answer period. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Also, this call is being recorded today, Thursday, October 15, 2009. Thank you.</p>
          <p>Mr. Holmes, you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. This is Dane Holmes, director of Investor Relations at Goldman Sachs. Welcome to our third quarter earnings conference call. Today's call may include forward-looking statements. These statements represent the firm's belief regarding future events that by their nature are uncertain and outside of the firm's control. The firm's actual results and financial condition may differ possibly materially from what is indicated in those forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>For discussion of some of the risks and factors that could affect the firm's future results, please see the description of risk factors in our current annual report on Form 10-K for the fiscal year ended November 2008. I would also direct you to read the forward-looking disclaimers in our quarterly earnings release, particularly as it relates to Investment Banking transaction backlog, and you should also read the information on the calculation of non-GAAP financial measures that is posted on the Investor Relations portion of our website at www.GS.com.</p>
          <p>This audiocast is copyrighted material of the Goldman Sachs Group, Inc. and may not be duplicated, reproduced or rebroadcast without our consent.</p>
          <p>Our Chief Financial Officer, David Viniar, will now review the firm's results. David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Dane. And I'd like to thank all of you for listening today. I'll give an overview of our third quarter results and then take your questions.</p>
          <p>I'm pleased to report strong third quarter results for Goldman Sachs. Net revenues were $12.4 billion, net earnings were $3.2 billion, and earnings per diluted share were $5.25. Our annualized return on common equity was 21.4%. Our results in the third quarter reflect the continued demand for expert advice and execution for our global client base. Throughout this financial crisis, we've maintained an unwavering focus on serving our clients. We believe that staying close to our clients during periods of market turmoil reinforces the strength of our franchise. Our client relationships have been critical to our recent performance and will remain a key driver of our future performance.</p>
          <p>Our FICC business continues to be a strong performer, and many of the favorable conditions that benefited the businesses during the first half of 2009 continued in the third quarter. The competitive environment remained fragmented, and available risk capital was limited. Consequently, we continued to experience elevated market share and attractive margin dynamics within several of our market making businesses.</p>
          <p>The depth and diversity of our FICC business continued to be a key contributor to our performances here. Third quarter results, for example, include a record performance in mortgages and our second best quarterly performance in credit. Rates, currency and commodities each posted one of their two best quarterly performances in either the first or second quarter. During the third quarter, the S&amp;P, Dow Jones and FTSE posted their strongest quarterly gains in over a decade, which helped drive solid results in equities and principal investments.</p>
          <p>Many of the headwinds that we faced during the first six months of 2009 also continued in the third quarter. The Investment Banking and Securities Services operating environment remained difficult. Investment Banking revenues continued to be hampered by an uncertain macroeconomic outlook and low CL confidence. That being said, we saw higher levels of strategic dialogue and a significant increase in our backlog during the quarter. However, these revenues will only be recognized if and when these transactions close over coming quarters.</p>
          <p>Results from within our Securities Services business continued to decline principally reflecting lower seasonal dividend-related activity. Similar to Investment Banking business, we began to see some positive trends developing including the beginning of inflows to select hedge funds and a modest increase in leverage. Despite the challenging environment, we maintained market-leading positions in both of these businesses.</p>
          <p>In light of the difficult macro environment, we continue to conservatively manage our risk, capital and liquidity levels. Given our cautious outlook and the prospect for higher capital requirements in the near future, maintaining robust levels of risk-adjusted capital for the time being remains appropriate. At the end of the third quarter, we had a Tier 1 ratio under Basel I of 14.5%. We also maintained a robust liquidity pool with our global core excess averaging $167 billion during the quarter.</p>
          <p>As I've mentioned previously, we have an established track record of dynamically managing our capital liquidity based on our assessment of the operating environment and potential opportunities. Our current levels of capital liquidity reflect both the potential for further market disruptions as well as the opportunity to capitalize on distressed investments.</p>
          <p>I'll now review each of our businesses. Investment Banking produced net revenues of $899 million, down 38% from the second quarter. Third quarter advisory revenues were 325 million, down 12% from the second quarter. Goldman Sachs is ranked first in announced M&amp;A globally year to date and advised on a number of important transactions that were announced during the quarter. These include Baker Hughes' $5 billion acquisition of BJ Services, Perot Systems' $3.9 billion sale to Dell and Procter &amp; Gamble's $3.1 billion sale of its pharmaceutical business to Warner Chilcott.</p>
          <p>We were also adviser on a number of significant closed transactions, including Nuon's &#x20AC;8.5 billion sale to Vattenfall, Canada Pension Plan Investment Board's AUD7.3 billion acquisition of Macquarie Communications Group and Cardinal Health's $5.2 billion spin-off of CareFusion.</p>
          <p>Third quarter underwriting net revenues were $574 million. Equity underwriting revenues were 663 million, down significantly on a sequential basis as a number of capital raises in the financial institution sector were not repeated in the third quarter. Debt underwriting declined 37% to $211 million, due to seasonally weaker new issue markets over the summer months.</p>
          <p>During the third quarter, we participated in many noteworthy underwriting transactions, including Mizuho's $5.9 billion follow-on offering, NewPage Corporation's $1.6 billion high-yield notes offering and RTO's $720 million IPO.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to Trading and Principal Investments which is comprised of FICC, Equities and Principal Investments. Net revenues were $10 billion in the third quarter reflecting strength across each of the businesses. FICC net revenues were $6 billion in the third quarter, representing a 12% decrease from the second quarter. Our FICC performance continued to reflect strong market share although client activity levels were generally lower relative to a particularly strong first half of 2009.</p>
          <p>While bid-ask spreads have begun to compress particularly in more liquid vanilla products like rates and currencies, they remain wide by historical standards. Credit products net revenues declined from the record second quarter but remain robust as we continued to benefit from strong market share and higher asset prices grow solid customer activity levels. Net revenues and interest rates and currencies were strong but lower sequentially due to lighter trading volumes and tighter spreads.</p>
          <p>Mortgages produced record results driven by strength in the customer trading business, partially offset by approximately $120 million in write downs within our commercial real estate loan portfolio. Commodity net revenues were down from the second quarter reflecting lower volatility and decreased customer activity.</p>
          <p>Turning to Equities, net revenues for the third quarter were $2.8 billion, down 13% sequentially. Equities Trading net revenues were $1.8 billion, strong but down 14% versus the second quarter due to lower client activity levels across both cash trading and derivatives. Similar to the second quarter, net revenues from our principal strategies business were positive but not a significant revenue driver. Equities commissions were down 9% sequentially to $930 million due to seasonally lower customer activity. Turning to Risk, average daily value at risk in the third quarter was $208 million, down 15% from the second quarter.</p>
          <p>I'll now review Principal Investments, which produced net revenues of $1.3 billion in the third quarter. Our corporate principal investment portfolio generated net gains of $977 million, largely in corporate debt and public equity investments. Our investment in ICBC generated net revenues of $344 million, and our real estate principal investments generated losses of $66 million. In Asset Management and Securities Services, we reported third quarter net revenues of $1.4 billion down 6% from the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Asset Management produced net revenues $974 million, which was up 6% from the second quarter. Assets under management grew 4% sequentially to 848 billion due to market appreciation. Securities Services produced net revenues of $472 million, down 23% from a seasonally strong second quarter. The third quarter also reflected fewer hard-to-borrow opportunities in the market.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to expenses. Compensation and benefits expense in the third quarter was $5.4 billion, or 43.3% of net revenues, reflecting a decline in our year-to-date accrual to 47% of net revenues. The lower compensation accrual reflects our record year-to-date revenues in 2009 as well as better visibility on expected compensation levels as we approach the end of the year.</p>
          <p>As I have highlighted previously, this number includes salaries, discretionary compensation, amortization of prior year equity awards and other items such as payroll taxes, severance costs and benefits. As in every other year, we must accrue compensation based on our expectation of the full-year expense, but incentive compensation decisions are not made until year end, and this compensation will ultimately reflect the firm's performance for the entire year.</p>
          <p>Third quarter non-compensation expenses were $2.2 billion, 7% higher than the second quarter, largely driven by a $200 million charitable contribution to the Goldman Sachs Foundation. Total staff at the end of the third quarter was approximately 31,700, up 2% from the second quarter. Our effective tax rate was 32.2% year to date and 33.5% for the third quarter.</p>
          <p>The last 18 months have been an extremely challenging period for the global financial services industry. There are many lessons to be taken from all that has transpired. During the most turbulent of times we stayed focused on several critical objectives: support the efficient functioning of capital markets which is critical to global economies, financially prepare the firm for a more difficult operating environment, provide unwavering service to our clients and protect our franchise and thus shareholder value.</p>
          <p>To accomplish these objectives, we made prices when markets were volatile and illiquid and extended credit when credit was scarce. We incurred the economic costs associated with proactively reducing our exposure to leverage loans in real estate by nearly 60% and raising $11 billion in capital. And these were steps we took before we received TARP funds from the U.S. government. In just over a year, we nearly doubled our liquidity balances to over $170 billion.</p>
          <p>We didn't have any unique insights about how difficult things would become. We took these actions out of prudence and awareness that we didn't have all the answers. We took these actions because we knew that we had an important role to play in supporting global capital markets and economies, our clients, our more than 30,000 employees and most importantly our shareholders.</p>
          <p>By staying focused on these objectives, we've gained several secondary benefits. First and foremost, the most attractive aspects of our culture, collaboration, nimbleness and commitment to excellence, have been strengthened. These cultural attributes remain critical to our ability to navigate the current environment.</p>
          <p>Second, our global team of talented professionals remains intact and committed to our business model. This holds true whether you speak to a management committee member who has been with the firm for 25 years or a recent undergraduate hire. Since people are our greatest asset, we recognize that ultimately our success will be driven by their collective effort.</p>
          <p>Third, our franchise maintains its breadth, depth and diversity, and our relative competitive position has been materially improved during this period. And finally, the combination of robust risk-adjusted capitalization and profitable results allows the firm to take advantage of opportunities as they arise, to continue to invest in growth businesses and technology and to adapt to volatile markets. In summary, while the market outlook remains uncertain, we believe that the firm is well positioned to continue to execute on its key strategies.</p>
          <p>With that, I'd like to thank you again for listening today, and I'm now happy to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And your first question comes from Glenn Schor with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Glenn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I kind of remember back a period of time when you one February said that this is the best environment in my 25 years in business. And that's not this environment, yet the numbers you're putting up are pretty damn close to record levels, on a leverage ratio that's pretty low and capital ratios that are much bigger. I guess the question is as you keep doing all the things that you said you're doing in terms of collaborating, being nimble and servicing the heck out of your clients, what are you thinking as the rules changed? The spread environment won't change what it is, but it seems like you have leeway on the capital and the leverage front to deploy things. How does that tradeoff work over the next year or two?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So first of all, I'm much more confident saying that this is not the best environment that I've ever seen, than I was saying that was the best environment I've ever seen. As you know, the best environment for Goldman Sachs is very, very strong global economic growth, and that's not what we're in right now. But our market shares have improved, and I think we're getting a bigger share of a smaller pie right now. We're certainly hopeful that over time the pie will increase, our share will probably decrease, but we think the pie increasing will hopefully make up for the share decreasing.</p>
          <p>As far as capital and leverage, we're still in an uncertain economic environment and an uncertain regulatory environment. I would suspect that the regulatory environment will clear itself up over the next year or so, and hopefully the economic environment will get better. We'll either see more opportunities, which we'll use our capital or we'll do other things to reduce what is now overcapitalization. But that won't happen any time in the materially in the very near future. It will happen over the next 12 to 18 months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I mean I saw the liquidity pool drop a drop, but it's still really big, and I commented on capital and the leverage ratios, do your comments mean that, look, we happen to be fortunate enough to be making a lot of money right now, we'll wait for the regulation to change before we do anything significant on the capital liquidity and leverage front?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's the most likely scenario.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And then is there a function of today's trading environment, especially on the FICC side? You look at a quarter like this where revenues are still pretty awesome, and VAR is down 15% sequentially. Are you seeing just an extraordinary velocity of balance sheet, if you will, and just able to turn the inventory as quick as you've seen in a long time? Is that what's helping contribute?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Basically all of the trading is kind of plain vanilla, very liquid products. They come on and off the balance sheet very quickly. You see it from the balance sheet side, and the balance sheet side stayed the same. VAR was down, and yet results were quite good</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then final question, on Securities Services, actually, sequentially the percentage drop is not all that different from third to second quarters that we've seen in the past. However, it down 50% year on year still has us scratching our heads a little bit. I know rates are really low. I hear your comment on no one is doing the hard-to-borrow because the market goes up every day. Do you think that down 50% year to date is about right, or were there some share gains there throughout the years that maybe as competitors heal, you give a little bit back there as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I actually think 50% year over year is about right given what's gone on in the world between hedge fund assets being down last year. Last year, I think hedge fund assets in total were down probably close to 50%, total hedge fund assets over the last year. We've started to see them &#x2013; and then, as I mentioned the hard-to-borrows with people being worried about shortening anything. So you put those two things together, I'm not surprised at the year-over-year decline. But we have started, and again I don't want to overstate this. We have started to see the reversal of that trend as we went through the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, cool. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Guy Moszkowski, Banc of America/Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Guy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wanted to ask you first of all if it would be possible for you to give us a little bit more color on the movement of bid offer spreads in key categories that you have identified like credit rates, FX, et cetera, over the course of the year? If you can't quantify, which I understand why you wouldn't, can you give us sort of an indexed view of where they might have begun the year and where some of those key categories are right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Boy, I mean, it's hard to be very definitive in quantifying it, Guy. But I would tell you that probably as we went through the first quarter and probably half of the second quarter, spreads in virtually every product were as wide as we've seen them. And I would tell you that now certainly in the more liquid products like rates and currencies, we've seen those spreads decline a fair bit, still higher than what I would consider normal, a lot higher than what we saw in 2006 and 2007. But it's hard to index, but a fair amount lower than we saw in the first half of this year. Credit products and things like that, still tighter than we saw in the first half, but well wide of the normal environment. So they haven't tightened as much as some of the more liquid products, but tightened a bit but well over normal levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you have an outlook, a thought on the outlook for that? I mean should we &#x2013; given the comments you made about industry conditions still being quite fragmented and capital still being &#x2013; risk capital still being kind of scarce, would you expect that the tightening trend will continue, or do you think it stalls out here for a while?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think the tightening trend will continue. I think that if the world continues to be a better place, then the tightening trend will continue. People will get healthier. Volumes will go up. More risk capital will come into the market, and again this is a question of pie versus share of the pie. I would expect that the pie will continue to grow, and I think our what is now a very elevated share of the pie will come down. I think we'll keep some of the market share gains we got but not all of them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I can just turn to compensation for a minute. Can you give us a sense for what the impact on reported compensation for the year might be of decisions that you might make to, for example, defer some comp over a period of time or increase the percentage that would be in shares?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't know yet, Guy. These are the things that we're still working through, and we won't make final decisions on these until the end of the year. So I would be premature in giving you anything there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So for now, as we try to model the full-year comp, is the best approach really to look at prior years with revenue similar to what we're seeing this year, and just look at the full-year comp ratio for those periods?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't give you any better way to do it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Roger Freeman with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Roger.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I actually just wanted to I guess follow up on a couple of these issues. I guess first on FICC, can we just maybe just touch on these dynamics a little bit more? The &#x2013; so bid-ask spreads have come in a fair amount, as you say. You're saying they're wider than normal. I guess you probably heard Jamie Dimon's comments yesterday. He kind of used an index of one before the crisis, six and now two.</p>
          <p>I don't know if you broadly agree with that, but let's assume that it's come in a fair amount, and it sounds like over really since the second quarter, but your FICC revenues are only down 15%. One of the things we've heard is because vols come down, positioning has been a lot easier within FICC. So I'm wondering as we now come into the fourth quarter, if this credit spread rally has run out of steam, maybe there's more to go in high yield. Are we going to see that impact? I mean, how much has been sort of positioning, principal, however you want to call it in all of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very little, but first, you know me well enough to know that I can't, and I'm not going to try and tell you what's going to happen in the fourth quarter because we'll see. But most of our revenues across trading, across FICC really have been client related where our clients want to do things. There just hasn't been that much conditioning, there hasn't been that much write-ups of prior distressed assets. It has been what I'll call blocking and tackling. Every day, day after day, dealing with our clients who want to do things, making markets, making prices, helping them hedge things, whether it's rates or energy prices or currencies or things like that. That's really been the great, great majority of our revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but I guess the &#x2013; and it stands to reason though somehow that the dramatic spread compression we've seen over the course of this year has to benefit a business that is an inventory business. I mean is that not a fair assumption?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It benefits it a little on some assets, but the velocity of our assets is so fast that we don't really &#x2013; we're not really holding assets, and while it's an inventory, we have inventory, we have hedges against most of that inventory. So you have some things on balance sheet, and you have some hedges off balance sheet, but our net-net, the contraction in spreads, the biggest advantage &#x2013; the biggest help in the contraction spreads and therefore the increase in kind of risk asset prices has been two things. One, it leads to higher activity levels and two, in our principal investment area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So most of the gains on holding risk assets have been in the principal investment area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then I guess there's been some shift into the higher margin, higher wider bid-ask products like mortgages, that's helpful. But I guess just sort of one more macro on this subject. You kind of look at $6.3 billion in really adjusted revenues, I think taking out some of the charges, et cetera. A strong quarter before the credit crisis for you was really like $4 billion, maybe low fours, and you still have this delta, and like you said there's market share. As the market share maybe comes down, some of these other higher-margin products grow in total. I mean, it feels like this still moves probably down on a run rate. I know seasonally it's going to be down in the fourth quarter but hard probably for you to respond. But I mean is this still a very elevated number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're very pleased with the performance. You know I don't talk about run rate revenues, their sustainability, but people asked the same question after the second quarter going into the summer, and the third quarter performed pretty well. I can't tell you if the fourth quarter is going to be as robust. I don't know. But I'm pretty confident that our performance will be as good as it can be in whatever the environment is that unfolds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. And then just last question, just back on the comps. So, and I guess you said best advice is look at prior years. I guess just one question around that, if you look at -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I said was I couldn't give you better advice.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You can't give better advice, but let's say, '06 and '07, it seems to me that a lot of the strength there was generated from harvesting principal investment gains, private equity that you would argue maybe were generated by fewer people and you had more comp leverage off of that. And I'm just wondering is that really sort of fair? I mean this time, you've got a wider range of the organization involved in generating these revenues, and I guess I'm just wondering if that's a fair way to go?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that is a fair way to think about the firm. The revenues that we have now are being driven very much by our franchise, which takes the entire firm behind it to be successful, and I think we have to be fair to those people. But we're also cognizant of what's going on in the world and the pressures we're under. And so we're going to try and balance those things as we work through the end of the year, and we'll make our decisions as we get to year end based on the overall performance of the firm and our people.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Howard Chen with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Howard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You have been in the belief that this distressed investing cycle is going take a little bit longer to play out than the past ones. Just curious, can you touch on the firm's current appetite for putting capital to work on the distressed front and how's the bid-ask evolved for the opportunities that are out there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. That's a good question. We would have thought that there would have been many more opportunities by now. We definitely have an appetite and have had an appetite and are willing to and it's been a business that we've been in for a long time. We're willing to be a purchaser of assets if we think the returns are worth it. Now you know, in the environment where the returns are in very, very liquid products have been so high, we're only going to invest in illiquid products if the returns are even higher. But there's been very little willingness of the holders of distressed assets to sell them at what we thought were reasonable prices. Just a difference in their views of price and our views.</p>
          <p>I think those views have gotten a lot closer, and I think that we are starting to see what I would call a &#x2013; maybe it's a little more than a trickle but not much more of potential opportunities. And so I'm hopeful that we'll find some. I don't think it's going to be a gigantic number, but I'm hopeful that we'll find some opportunities over the next several quarters to use our capital to invest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. And then so just stepping back from that, David, I guess by geography and by business, where are you seeing the best opportunities to deploy resources today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I actually think it's going to be &#x2013; if I give you geographies and businesses, when I'm done, I will have gone through all of them. We're really seeing these opportunities in different ways globally, and we're seeing them really across our trading businesses. We're starting to see a pickup in the Investment Banking backlog. We're starting to see more inflows and people what I would call re-risking in the Asset Management business. So we're really starting to see opportunities across all of the businesses pick up. Now we've all seen it. Tomorrow, I could tell you something different, but that's how it feels right now, and we're seeing it across the U.S., across Europe, across Asia, across developing markets and developed markets. It's really across the board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, David. And then real estate assets have been written down pretty hard. Your write-downs on the trading portfolio and within RPIA are at their lowest levels. Curious, are you seeing people here more willing to move assets or are folks still holding on to what they've got?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that real estate assets are probably still the least liquid and most distressed of the asset classes. As you said, we've written ours down pretty heavily, and we don't have that much left. I think we're still a bit away from breaking that log jam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and just final numbers question from me. Apologize if I missed this in the prepared remarks, but what impact did tightening of spreads have on the trading revenues this quarter and just where are the marks on the commercial real estate stuff stand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You mean our spreads, you mean our -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, your own sort of &#x2013; the DDA, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it was 275 million in the quarter and something like 80% of that was in FICC and the rest was in equities. And the marks on commercial real estate, I think, we're at about 50 average across our commercial real estate portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much, David</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, you're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Mike Mayo with CLSA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Mike</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow-up to the other question. Is there any way to quantify the increase in the velocity of the assets in FICC trading?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The only way I would quantify it, Mike, the real answer is no. It's very hard to quantify. But you see our balance sheet hasn't moved. Our balance sheet was 890 last quarter, 882 this quarter, kind of the same, and it's been like that for a couple of quarters, and it's not like we're not doing anything. You see the fact that we're making as much money as we are in trading, it's because there's a lot of activity and yet the balance sheet is kind of staying the same, and it's just assets going on and off the balance sheet constantly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Whatever the decline in the margin is made up for in the velocity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can you give us any sense for how much the margin might have gone down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's really hard for me to quantify. I don't like to kind of make up numbers, and I think &#x2013; it's just very hard for me to quantify, but it's down in some of the more liquid products, it's down a fair amount, but it's still significantly higher than we've seen in previous environments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in terms of the backlog, can you give any color, mergers, equity underwriting, debt underwriting and by region?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It's up in all of them. I would say really dominated by mergers and equity underwriting more than debt underwriting, but all of them are up, and I think it's really across all of the regions. Now it will take longer for merger revenue to show up than equity underwriting revenue, and equity underwriting revenue will show up if the markets stay okay, and if they don't, then some of that will go away. But I would say more mergers and equity underwritings in fixed income but pretty much across the board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then revenues outside the U.S., what was the relative growth this quarter, and what are you doing in Asia where the markets &#x2013; ?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A) we were at a little over 50% in the U.S., I think it's around &#x2013; a little over 50 in the U.S. and the rest outside the U.S. And look, we've been very focused on growing our Asian business especially our China business for a while. We continue to be. We were one of the first ones in there, one of the few that has a license to operate there, and it's probably the biggest near-term focus for the firm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Chris Kotowski with Oppenheimer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Wonder if you could talk a little bit about the Asset Management business. I notice there were modest outflows of the money market funds, but it didn't go into any of the other alternatives. Any color there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. What I would say there, look, this is a big focus of ours, and it continues to grow well, and I think if you look at our statistics, they're very consistent with the industry statistics over the course of the quarter. But really what you saw is over the last year, I would say within the Asset Management world, for us and for others, you saw tremendous de-risking. So people basically took their assets out of equities, alternative investments, other things and put them into money markets.</p>
          <p>And what you saw in the third quarter was the beginning of re-risking. Now not all of it came into our funds, but people taking their money out of money market funds and starting to put it into more risky investments, starting with fixed income because I think the general view of the world was that the credit space was the best place to invest and I think maybe you'll start seeing some flows into some other areas over the next couple of quarters, if the world stays okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then on the Principal Investments, I noticed they're up about 1.3 billion in aggregate from the prior quarter. And is that marks or putting new money to work?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's largely marks on old stuff. We made some new investments. More on the debt side than the equity side. But the ICBC one you can see. That was the ICBC stock price going up. And in the corporate principal investments, it was really dominated by private investments in debt securities, so that was our mez fund, our senior loan fund and some other debt investments and public investments in equities where it has gone public. So it's just the equities market going up. That was mostly the earnings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then finally, any thought on the contributions to the foundation? Is that something that we should look for on semi-ongoing basis? Is there a target level at which you would like to get the foundation to or &#x2013; how should we think about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No target at this time, and we'll make a fourth quarter decision in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the Michael Carrier with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, guys. Actually one question on FICC. There's been a lot talked about on the spreads, and then you guys mentioned your velocity. If you look relative to like '06, '07 levels, we can kind of see what is happening on the spread side, but from the client activity side, based on the data that the Fed puts out or talking to different fixed income desks, it seems like client activity is still relatively low. Like up a lot since the first quarter. But should we expect as spreads come in, just client activity, the markets become more efficient and trading volumes in general will start to increase and so that will cause some the offset?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that's what should happen. And I think you said it exactly right. In the scheme of what we saw in 2005, '06, '07, client activity is still low. I mean we have pretty big share. And what will drive more client activity will be better economic growth, and when there's better economic growth, clients do more things. Any time there's a merger transaction, there's hedging transactions whether it's currencies or rates or commodities or something that comes with it. Anytime there's an underwriting, there's more stuff that comes with it.</p>
          <p>And as companies do more things, they're more active and that happens when there's more economic growth. And so that's what I said before that what we're hopeful of is that we know we're not going to keep all of the market share gains that we have. We think we'll keep some of them and not all of them. But that hopefully the market of which we're getting a share will get bigger as the world gets better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just on the capital levels, there's some adjustments put out by Basel II in terms of new requirements and based on the U.S. getting there in 2010 and implementation by 2012. It seems like for Goldman, you guys always are managing your risk like with your internal standards, and it tends to be more conservative than where the regulation is. And Basel II, I think the internal models sometimes there's more weighting there, and if the models are deemed very robust, then you can actually have some benefits in terms of the amount of risk you need to put against these assets.</p>
          <p>Based on anything that Basel II has put out, and I guess the most recent was back in July. When you guys look at it and look at where Basel II is headed, are there areas that you feel like you're already at relative to the industry based on Basel I? And then do you just feel like relative to where your current capital levels, you're fine, and I guess most importantly do the regulators and does Basel, are they talking to you guys because it seems like through all of this, especially when it comes to capital levels, you've done fairly well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, it's still too early to tell exactly where the capital regulations are going to come out. I think it's pretty clear that capital requirements will go up. For the same assets, for certainly for some of the same assets that people need to hold higher capital levels. We have dialogue with our regulators all the time about our internal models and what they mean our management of risk. I think as you said we think we manage our risk very, very conservatively and always have, but I think we're still in a wait-and-see mode. I think it's too early for us to know exactly where this is all going to fall out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just finally, I guess on the innovation side or where you see new opportunities, you guys had mentioned distressed assets and opportunities. It seems like through each downturn, whether it was tech, with principal investments, or long-term capital and fixed income, Enron, commodities, it seems like there's always an opportunity besides just distressed assets. So when you look at the current environment, there's a lot talked about like the shadow banking system and that going away. I don't think Goldman is going to become a big mortgage originator. But are there any opportunities that you see there's a void or a vacuum right now that potentially there's some significant upside for Goldman or for the industry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We actually think that the biggest opportunity for us is just to continue to grow what we have, that our businesses are good businesses. We think there's opportunities to grow them around the world, and that's really what we're focused on rather than trying to get into something new where we don't have expertise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Meredith Whitney with Meredith Whitney Advisors [Advisory].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Meredith.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a few questions. The government purchase program was supposed to end this quarter, they've extended it to next quarter. How much of that is a driver of velocity of flows, and how are you positioned when they exit, if they exit, for any type of principal risk? And what do you think that impact is he going to be in the larger market? That's my first question. I'll start off with an easy one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not a problem. Look, I think as you know and I think the Fed knows this. Exiting their support of various markets is a very tricky thing. I think that they're going to do it carefully. They're going to do it slowly and over time. I think they're signaling the market. I think they're doing a very good job of letting people know that they're going to continue for a while, but they're not going to continue forever.</p>
          <p>As far as our positioning, I don't think it really matters at all. As you know, as I've said, most of what's happened has been the velocity, not the positioning. And I think that they're going slowly extricate themselves from that as the markets get healthier and can pick up the slack.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but in terms of the flow volume, right, so you have been the greatest beneficiary of increased flow volumes. How are the flow volumes going to be influenced as they exit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I was trying to say that I think that they will try to time their exit for the market being healthy enough to pick up that flow. And so I think the flow will continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then who would you imagine would be the substitute buyers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The various market <mark type="inaudible" />. I think it will be the various financial institutions, funds, I think the whole variety of buyers, and there is a lot of cash out there to buy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just the last one. I was teasing when I said it was the easiest one but it was easy for you. The last one is of the principal revenues, almost a billion, how much of that was cash sales and how much were markups?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, I would say that it was much more markups than sales. I don't know the exact number, but it will be much more markups than sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Robert Lee with KBW.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Robert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a question on FAS 166, 167. Can you just kind of update us on a little bit on the anticipated impact next year, and specifically I'm just curious, a lot of asset managers are kind of concerned about the impact of them as it would require consolidation of a lot more investment products with performance fees. I mean, do you see that having the same impact on you? Can you maybe just give us a sense on where you see that headed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Two things. First, from our balance sheet point of view, we think it will have some, but a relatively immaterial impact. The other thing to remember that is probably the most important thing for us from a P and L point of view, whether something is on our balance sheet or not, if we have the financial commitment, if we have the financial risk, we mark to market and run it through our income statement. So it will have absolutely no effect on our income statement at all, and we think some but a pretty immaterial affect on our balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That was it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from Ed Najarian with ISI Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My questions have been answered. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Steve Stelmach with FBR Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I apologize. I just wanted you to put a finer point on the velocity question. Is it fair to infer from your answers that in a better economy you suspect that velocity will increase and that maybe the second and third quarters are not sort of the peak in your balance sheet sort of velocity? Is that a fair -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess what I would say and we're using terms interchangeably so I want to be a little careful. I would expect in a better economy the amount of activity will increase. Whether assets come on or off our balance sheet as fast, hard to say. In a better world, we might do more investing than we're doing right now. So I can't tell you the velocity would necessarily increase, but I think the amount of activity from which we would get transactions of our clients would be higher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Douglas Sipkin with Pali.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Doug.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions, one I think you've hit on already. Just the balance sheet, fairly constant the last couple of quarters. I mean that for the most part a conscious decision by you guys, or is it really just a function of the way things shake out, and what would it take for you guys to sort of increase it a little bit? I know the leverage is still very low by some of the historical standards.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it is more the latter, that it's the way things shaped out, that the opportunities we saw were largely in very, very liquid product that did not require any increase in our balance sheet. If there were opportunities to increase it a little bit right now, we would do that. I don't think we would want to increase it very dramatically right now because we are still conscious of the fact that we're not out of the woods in the economic environment yet. But I think we'd increase it a little bit, but there just haven't been those opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just hitting a little bit more on the bid-ask spread stuff. I mean it just seems like a lot of your competitors are making bigger commitments now. And I'm just wondering has all that not shown up yet and maybe will it sort of like Jan 1, 2010 with a lot of the hiring that's taking place and sort of the rejuvenated commitments to fixed income trading. I mean with respect to corporates and MBS, it sounds like we're still seeing very good profitability. I mean what's the level of concern post end of year with a lot of fresh money maybe coming back to those products from competitors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure that there's a date on which it's going to change dramatically. I think that it's going to be a gradual shift over time with more competitors entering the market. And look, remember, in order to do this and do it well, you need not just firms to get healthier but to be confident in their risk management. And we've seen in the past that that's something that takes a long time to build up and you have to get it right and you have to do it well, and otherwise you get in trouble by making commitments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, and just one quickie. I know you don't always provide, but any guidance around your hiring outlook given maybe we're seeing some stabilization in markets, and I know you sort of jumped this quarter, which is know is some seasonal elements to that, but maybe through 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Don't know yet. I think we're still kind of looking through what we want to do for 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Kian Abouhossein with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. In respect to capital at risk and capital allocation, I see your VAR coming down mainly in interest rates. Is this a trend that we should expect to see that VAR  may be scaled down or is this just a methodical impact, and how do you see capital moving between different businesses and regions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It really is going to depend on the opportunities we see. I think if you look back in our history, you will see take VAR as an example, you will see both the VAR and the absolute number go up and down, but you will see even more movement within the categories virtually every quarter. You will see differences. You'll see some up. You'll see some down. And we don't walk into a period of time and say, okay, let's take risk here or let's allocate capital here. What we do is because we know we're not smart enough to know. We know the world is going to fall differently than we think it's going to. What is important for us is that we're nimble enough to move our resources where we see the opportunity. Whether that's capital, whether that's people, balance sheet, whatever we see, we move it to where we see the opportunities, and I think you will see that continue. So you'll see it moving around.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And considering the consent of this to move more capital into a lot of the fixed income businesses, do you feel uncomfortable about that at this point, or there's no, no, uneasiness about any of the movements that you have seen by peers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we're not uncomfortable. Again, we think that the key to being able to operate in the fixed income trading businesses and especially to do things on behalf of our clients is our risk management. And as long as we continue to be as focused on that as we are and have the quality of people involved in our risk management and have the most senior people in this firm involved in it, we're comfortable with where we are</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Does this shifting to risk-weighted assets, your Basel II SEC risk-weighted assets increased by about 20 billion, 19 billion. Can you explain why?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure what number you're looking at. Because I think our risk weighted assets stayed in the third quarter stayed almost flat -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I'm looking at Basel II, risk-weighted assets, SEC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure what period you're looking at. You're looking at first quarter, second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I'm looking year on year. There was 380 billion, and they're about 400 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm just trying to understand is this pro-cyclicality or what is the driver of the change?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, so you're looking at the Basel II risk-weighted assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so part of that was just a mix issue. Part of that is in Basel II, as we transition from the SEC Basel II to the Fed Basel II, there are some changes in methodology that are pretty small and because you see, while it was 20 billion, it was 380 to 400. So on a percentage basis, it wasn't that high. But you're seeing some methodology changes that have caused an increase in risk-weighted assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and lastly, your market risk, about 170 &#x2013; your market risk-weighted assets, if I compare them to peers, you're clearly significant bigger, and today the Basel committee came with a statement, a quantitative statement that you've probably seen on trading book of risk-weighted assets to double to triple on an average. And I'm just wondering what does it mean for you as a group, and how much of your market risk-weighted assets are trading book related?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's too early to tell how all this is going to unfold, and I would tell you that I think our calculation is extremely conservative. I think when everything is put on equal footing, I think the effect on us will be the same as the effect on most of our major counterparties.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you say though in terms of trading book for this market risk, is it maybe one third or half, is that kind of both parts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think those are not numbers that we want to discuss.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Matt Burnell with Wells Fargo Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David. Most of my questions are asked and answered, but let me ask a bit of a nitty-gritty question, in terms of underwriting fees across the debt and equity platform, from some of the information we've gotten from third-party sources, it appears those fees particularly in the U.S. for debt and equity products are actually relatively higher than they were a year ago and have actually been trending upward over the last couple of quarters. Is that characterization correct, and what can you tell us about what fee trends might occur in some of those products particularly outside of the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It feels, and you might have more statistics than me, I would actually say that the fees are pretty stable. That the fees on equity products, while they have been trending down, they've probably more stabilized, same thing with fixed income products. But I don't think they're really trending up very much. I think they're pretty stable. I think you might just be seeing a different mix, more highly levered deals than not, therefore the fees would be a little bit higher. Not as many really, really big deals. You tend to charge smaller fees on a percentage basis the bigger the deal, even though the dollars are bigger, and you haven't seen as many really large transactions as you had seen in 2006-2007, so that might be why you're seeing it. It's probably a mix question more than anything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, and then one administrative question. The charitable donation expense, that runs through other expenses, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Michael Hecht with JMP.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, David. Good morning. How are you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just wanted to follow up on the strength in equities trading. I know you pointed to the strength in derivatives and it sounded like GSPS wasn't a real big driver this quarter. I mean any other color you can give us on what drove the strength there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. It was really just <mark type="inaudible" /> both shares and derivatives much more than our principal strategies business, and it was just kind of as I said, every day, blocking, tackling, dealing with our clients, doing things for them, helping them reposition, things such as that. Nothing, no big item.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. And then can you talk a little bit more about the seasonality you saw in the trading business, maybe through the quarter? Just trying to get a sense of whether the revenues were evenly distributed over the three months of the quarter or whether you saw any pickup in September?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it was much more even. I would not say we saw a big pickup in September.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it wasn't a normal summer then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it was a more normal summer than the prior two summers. I would say that. But it was pretty stable throughout the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then can you talk a little bit more about your outlook on just the regulatory environment and the impact of seeing more derivatives shift from the over-the-counter markets to exchanges and through centralized clearinghouses. I mean I guess on top of the cyclical forces and the competitive forces you talked about that may drive trading spreads and now over time, do you see that as more of a secular driver with tighter spreads over time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think my first answer is we don't know. It's too early to tell. There are some themes that are almost certainly going to happen. You mentioned some of them. We've talked about some of them. Probably going to be higher capital requirements. We think there will be more centralized clearing of derivatives than we've seen before. There will be more things on exchanges, and we actually think that is a good thing. We think it's a good thing for the world. We think if it's done correctly, it will be risk reducing, and we think that is good. And so, most of the things at least at the high level that have been talked about, we're pretty much in favor of.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fair enough. And then just last housekeeping question from me. Diluted share count is up 5%, basic shares a little bit more modestly. What's the driver there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A lot of it was just the, A, the passage of time, and B, the increase in our share price. Those two things helped drive share count because of accounting for RSUs and options on the treasury stock method.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Makes sense. Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your final question comes from Roger Freeman with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, hey, just had a couple follow-ups. What's the illiquidity discount on ICBC at this point? What do you think, it's like one to two billion, is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't disclose exactly what that discount is, but you could probably get pretty close to calculating it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, because I mean the gain on it was definitely less than the share price was you got for this quarter which suggests that discount came up. But I guess the bigger question is the lockup there expires, right, April of next year, so at some point, is that going to be a point in time P&amp;L event?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, no. The discount would be amortized in over time as we get closer to that point in time, but if you remember what happened last April, we extended the discount on some &#x2013; the lockup on a very large portion of shares so we don't know what will happen in April.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fair enough. And then just in some of the illiquid investments, opportunities, what are you seeing on the whole loan front and RESI? It sounded like there's sort of a trickle-up activity. It sounds like at least some hedge funds, I'm wondering if you're doing this as well, kind of going to banks and offering to buy portfolios that they can now absorb to sell at a loss with better than expected operating earnings. Is that something you're doing, too?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think a trickle is a good way to describe what's going on there. As I mentioned to you, the buyers and sellers, there was a very wide divergence in price expectations. I think that divergence has narrowed pretty dramatically, but I still think for the most part, buyers and sellers are still not in the same place, although, getting closer, and in some cases I think you will see some sales, but I think it's going to be a while before it's a very large amount.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, okay. And then I guess just within sort of prime brokerage, leverage for hedge funds, sounds like that's sort of creeping up a bit. It sounds like there's a fairly robust repo market again for a number of assets. I'm wondering where haircuts are on sort of a lot of key, whether it's mortgage backed or other RSAs versus where they were going into the crisis? How far will you re-trace?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all on leverage, they said we saw the beginnings of it starting to trickle up, but I don't want to overstate that. It's a little bit. And I don't think haircuts on repos have changed very much at all on most securities. I think they're pretty much the same as where they've been.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just lastly real quick I guess in the mortgage securities trading area, and the escrow, are you guys pulling it back to what Meredith was asking, do you think that with the Fed having been so aggressive in buying MBS securities here that that's actually kept some of the traditional players on the side line and that's where that incremental demand comes from?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is a chicken and egg question. Did their buying keep the traditional players on the side line, or did they buy because they were on the side line? And I think it's a little bit of both, and I think that hopefully what you'll see is that they will stop buying so much as these traditional buyers become healthier and more willing to take risks -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; come back in and that's why you will see the flows stay. And I think they're trying to time their withdrawal that way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, perfect, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I would now like to hand the conference back to Mr. Holmes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, once again, everyone for joining in the call. Obviously, if you have any other follow-up questions, feel free to reach out to me in the Investor Relations department. Have a nice day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude Goldman Sachs third quarter earnings call. You may now all disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>