<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1521801" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-01-16</date>
    <companies>
      <company>625</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Director, Investor Relations">Dane E. Holmes</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Global Co-Head, Securities Division, Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Harvey M. Schwartz</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">David A. Viniar</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (USA) LLC (Broker)">Howard H. Chen</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Securities International, Inc.">Glenn Schorr</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Michael Carrier</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities LLC">Brennan Hawken</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Autonomous Research US LP">Guy Moszkowski</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Roger A. Freeman</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Betsy L. Graseck</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Oppenheimer Securities">Chris M. Kotowski</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Matt D. O'Connor</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Buckingham Research Group, Inc.">Jim F. Mitchell</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Plc">Kian Abouhossein</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Wells Fargo Advisors LLC">Matt H. Burnell</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Agricole Securities (USA), Inc.">Mike L. Mayo</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="SunTrust Robinson Humphrey">Eric E. Wasserstrom</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="Mediobanca SpA (United Kingdom)">Christopher J. Wheeler</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My name is Dennis, and I will be your conference facilitator today. I would like to welcome everyone to the Goldman Sachs fourth quarter 2012 earnings conference call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Also, this call is being recorded today, January 16, 2013.</p>
          <p>Thank you. Mr. Holmes, you may begin your conference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. This is Dane Holmes, head of Investor Relations at Goldman Sachs. Welcome to our fourth quarter earnings conference call.</p>
          <p>Today's call may include forward-looking statements. These statements represent the firm's belief regarding future events that, by their nature, are uncertain and outside the firm's control. The firm's actual results and financial condition may differ, possibly materially, from what is indicated in those forward-looking statements. For a discussion of some of the risks and factors that could affect the firm's future results, please see the description of risk factors in our current Annual Report on Form 10-K for our fiscal year ended December 2011.</p>
          <p>I would also direct you to read the forward-looking disclaimers in our quarterly earnings release, particularly as it relates to our Investment Banking transaction backlog, capital ratios, risk-weighted assets, and global core excess. And you should also read the information on the calculation of non-GAAP financial measures that is posted on the Investor Relations portion of our website at www.GS.com.</p>
          <p>This audiocast is copyrighted material of The Goldman Sachs Group, Inc., and may not be duplicated, reproduced, or rebroadcast without our consent.</p>
          <p>Harvey Schwartz will now review the firm's results, and David Viniar and he will make a few closing remarks. Harvey?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Dane. I would like to thank all of you for joining us today. I will give an overview of our fourth quarter and full-year results, and then David and I will take your questions.</p>
          <p>Full-year net revenues for 2012 were $34.2 billion. Net earnings were $7.5 billion. Earnings per diluted share were $14.13, and our return on common equity was 10.7%. Fourth quarter net revenues were $9.82 billion. Net earnings were $2.9 billion, and earnings per diluted share were $5.60.</p>
          <p>The operating environment in 2012 was defined by a few significant trends: substantial central bank activity, improved economic data in the United States, and continued political uncertainty. For example, actions and commentary by the European Central Bank played a significant role in moderating concerns about a European linked tail event. At the end of 2011, the ECB announced that it would enhance its long-term refinancing operations to provide term liquidity. The ECB further demonstrated its commitment during 2012 by affirming its support for euro and its willingness to make outright purchases in the secondary bond market.</p>
          <p>In the United States, the Federal Reserve also took steps to support markets and economic growth, announcing further increases in monetary stimulus during the year. In 2012, the U.S. economy posted stable to improving economic data, particularly with developments in unemployment and housing. Over the course of the year, the U.S. economy added nearly 2 million jobs, and the housing price index increased by 4% over the past twelve months.</p>
          <p>Despite the systemic benefits of central bank activity and improved U.S. economic data, our clients continued to struggle with the complex set of issues facing the global economy and the political backdrop. The most obvious recent example was the debate in the United States surrounding the fiscal cliff. These factors translated into mixed activity levels for our corporate client base. For example, global debt issuance increased by 11% year over year, with high-yield issuance increasing 38%. In contrast, global equity underwriting volumes were only up 1%, and completed global merger and acquisition volumes actually decreased 18% in 2012 and remain very low as a percentage of market capitalization.</p>
          <p>We experienced lower activity levels in most of our businesses and general risk aversion by our investing clients. This was offset by improving asset prices and lower volatility, which created a more favorable market-making environment. Although equity and fixed income asset prices trended up over the course of the year, volumes generally declined given the previously mentioned factors. For example, U.S. listed equity volumes declined 18% in 2012. And as we all know, the S&amp;P 500 climbed by 13%.</p>
          <p>While macroeconomic challenges persist, our leadership teams remain focused on enhancing our returns. Drivers of our long-term success include: focusing on our clients; prudently managing our risk profile; and being disciplined about capital and expenses.</p>
          <p>I'll now review each of our businesses. Investment Banking produced fourth quarter net revenues of $1.4 billion, up 21% from the third quarter. The increase was due to higher equity underwriting revenues following a weak third quarter and continued strength in debt underwriting. For the full year, Investment Banking net revenues were $4.9 billion, up 13% from 2011, due to a robust environment for debt issuance. Within Investment Banking, fourth quarter advisory revenues were $508 million, flat with the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Goldman Sachs ranked first in worldwide announced and completed M&amp;A for 2012. We advised on a number of significant transactions that closed during the fourth quarter, including: Kraft's $36.1 billion spinoff of its North American grocery business; Walt Disney's $4.1 billion acquisition of Lucasfilm; and Dollar Thrifty's $2.3 billion sale to Hertz.</p>
          <p>We also advised on a number of important transactions that were announced during the fourth quarter: Ralcorp Holdings' $6.8 billion sale to ConAgra; the $4.5 billion sale of eAccess to SoftBank; and Gambro's $4 billion sale to Baxter International.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter underwriting net revenues were $897 million, up 37% sequentially, as issuance improved relative to the third quarter. Equity underwriting revenues of $304 million increased 61% compared to the third quarter, reflecting increased deal activity. Goldman Sachs was ranked first in worldwide equity and equity related and common stock offerings for 2012. Debt underwriting revenues increased 27% to $593 million due to our involvement in several significant transactions and a favorable new issue environment.</p>
          <p>During the fourth quarter, we participated in noteworthy underwriting transactions, including: AIG's $6.4 billion sale of its remaining stake in AIA; AvalonBay Communities' $2.2 billion follow-on offering; and Clear Channel Outdoor's $2.7 billion high-yield offering.</p>
          <p>Our Investment Banking backlog increased compared with the end of the third quarter. It was also higher than year-end 2011.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to Institutional Client Services, which is comprised of FICC and equities client execution, commissions and fees, and securities services. Net revenues were $4.3 billion in the fourth quarter, up 4% from the third quarter. Net revenues within Institutional Client Services improved, as the fourth quarter included an approximately $500 million gain from the sale of our hedge fund administration business.</p>
          <p>Full-year net revenues of $18.1 billion for Institutional Client Services were up 5% relative to 2011 and included a $714 million DVA [Debt Valuation Adjustment] loss. Excluding the impact of DVA, revenues were up 13% year over year and benefited from an improving market environment with tighter credit spreads, higher equity prices, and lower levels of volatility.</p>
          <p>FICC client execution net revenues were $2 billion in the fourth quarter, including a DVA loss of $79 million, and were down 8% sequentially as certain businesses reflected seasonally lower levels of activity.</p>
          <p>Credit revenues increased significantly, as client activity was supported by a favorable market backdrop, which included a relatively benign macro environment. Robust primary issuance and tighter credit spreads also helped.</p>
          <p>Currency revenues also increased. Commodities revenues were higher compared to weaker third quarter results, although absolute levels of client activity remained pretty low.</p>
          <p>While rates and mortgages were lower sequentially, both businesses were strong contributors to the franchise.</p>
          <p>For the full year, FICC client execution net revenues of $9.9 billion were up 10% relative to 2011. Excluding the impact of DVA, revenues were up 20% compared to 2011, as markets in 2012 were less turbulent and benefited from an improved backdrop in Europe, modest growth in the U.S., and strong central bank activity.</p>
          <p>In equities, which include equities client execution, commissions and fees, and securities services, net revenues for the fourth quarter were $2.3 billion, up 18% sequentially, and included $47 million in DVA losses. Excluding the impact of DVA, revenues were up 12% relative to the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Equities client execution revenues decreased 10% sequentially to $764 million, reflecting fewer client driven opportunities in our cash market-making business. Commissions and fees were $722 million, roughly flat with third quarter levels. Securities services net revenues of $818 million reflected the $500 million gain on sale that was previously mentioned. For the full year, equities produced net revenues of $8.2 billion, consistent with 2011.</p>
          <p>Turning to risk, average daily VaR [Value at Risk] in the fourth quarter was $76 million, down from $81 million in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Now I will review Investing &amp; Lending, which includes both direct investing and investing through funds across various asset classes as well as lending activities. Investing &amp; Lending produced net revenues of $2 billion in the fourth quarter. Our investment in ICBC [Industrial and Commercial Bank of China Limited] produced a $334 million gain in the quarter. Other equity investments generated $789 million in gains, reflecting realized and unrealized gains on private equity investments and markups related to public equity investments, as equity markets were stronger in Asia and Europe.</p>
          <p>Net revenues from debt securities and loans were $485 million, largely driven by tightening credit spreads and net interest income. Other revenues of $365 million consist primarily of operating revenues from our consolidated investment entities and are largely offset by equivalent expenses.</p>
          <p>For the full year, Investing &amp; Lending generated net revenues of $5.9 billion, driven by a $408 million gain on our investment in ICBC, $2.4 billion in gains from other equity investments, $1.9 billion of net revenues from debt securities and loans, and $1.2 billion of other investments.</p>
          <p>In Investment Management, we reported fourth quarter net revenues of $1.5 billion, up 26% from the third quarter, primarily as a result of $344 million in incentive fees generated from the firm's alternative asset products. Management and other fees were 5% higher at $1.1 billion. For the full year, Investment Management net revenues were $5.2 billion, up 4% from 2011 levels, on stronger incentive fees.</p>
          <p>During the fourth quarter, assets under supervision increased $14 billion to $965 billion, largely due to net inflows of $15 billion into other client assets, mainly as a result of advisory mandates. Total assets under management were essentially unchanged.</p>
          <p>On a full-year basis, assets under supervision increased 8%, as other client assets received $39 billion of net inflows. We ended the year with $111 billion of other client assets. Assets under management increased 3%, reflecting net market appreciation that was partially offset by outflows.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to expenses. Compensation and benefits expense, which includes salaries, bonuses, amortization of prior-year equity awards, and other items such as benefits, increased 6% to $12.9 billion for 2012, and translated into a compensation to net revenues ratio of 37.9%. It is important to note that our lower compensation ratio in 2012 is in part a byproduct of our efficiency efforts that began in early 2011.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter non-compensation expenses were $2.9 billion, 24% higher than the third quarter. Other expenses were significantly higher, reflecting net provisions for litigation and regulatory proceedings of $260 million, an increase of approximately $200 million over the third quarter. Based on the provision taken this quarter combined with previous reserves, we have fully accounted for the independent foreclosure review settlement.</p>
          <p>The fourth quarter also included a $157 million donation to Goldman Sachs Gives, our donor-advised charitable fund.</p>
          <p>Finally, depreciation and amortization increased by approximately $100 million, driven by impairments to certain investment entities and our New York Stock Exchange designated market-maker rights. For the full year, non-compensation expenses were down 4%.</p>
          <p>Total staff at year-end were approximately 32,400, down 3% from year-end 2011 and 9% from year-end 2010.</p>
          <p>Our effective tax rate was 33.3% for 2012.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we repurchased 12.7 million shares of common stock for a total cost of $1.5 billion. For the full year, we repurchased 42 million shares for a total cost of $4.6 billion.</p>
          <p>Historically, our financial success has been a function of broad and deep client relationships, our best-in-class people, a disciplined approach to allocating financial and human capital, and a culture of collaboration and partnership. The value of this partnership is highlighted in challenging market environments and drove our results in 2012.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, we believe that we are well positioned to expand on our client franchise globally. For corporate clients, we will continue to leverage our strong M&amp;A, equity, and debt underwriting positions. For investing and other institutional clients, we will continue to rely on the quality of our content and execution. We will remain very disciplined in our approach to expenses, balancing near-term benefits to our margins against longer-term revenue opportunities.</p>
          <p>As we gain greater clarity on regulatory changes, particularly capital requirements, we will respond accordingly. For example, given the Basel III capital changes that we incur as an owner of own reinsurance business, we are considering a potential sale of a majority stake in the business. We have strong risk-adjusted capitalization, which provides protection to shareholders against tail events.</p>
          <p>In addition, our capital levels also create opportunities. First, it positions the firm to help our clients navigate an uncertain economic event. It also allows us to provide capital where capacity is diminished. We are committed to effectively deploying our capital and maintaining dry powder to meet future client needs. We will also return capital to shareholders when appropriate returns aren't available.</p>
          <p>Our capital trends in 2012 reflected our measured approach, as our estimated Basel III Tier 1 capital ratio increased from approximately 8% to nearly 9%, despite returning $5.5 billion to shareholders via share buybacks and dividends.</p>
          <p>We are encouraged by the early signs of improvement in the markets and economy but remain cautious given the complexity of the risks and challenges. The quality of our advice and execution in today's challenging markets serves as a foundation for maintaining long-term client relationships and ultimately meeting the needs of all of our stakeholders.</p>
          <p>Everyone at Goldman Sachs remains steadfast in their commitment to serving our client franchise. We have a deep appreciation for our responsibility to all of our constituents: clients; shareholders; regulators; our employees; and of course, the broader financial system. We believe that there's a shared interest among our constituents to manage the firm in a way that supports economic growth and sustainability. Our firm is fully committed to fulfilling that responsibility.</p>
          <p>With that, I'd like to take a moment to thank David on behalf of the firm for his significant contributions to Goldman Sachs over his 32-year career. There is no doubt that our clients, employees, regulators and shareholders have all benefited from his unwavering commitment, sound judgment and devotion to the firm's culture and principles.</p>
          <p>As a personal note, I really want to thank you. You've been a tremendous partner, David, and not only during this transition. I truly can't thank you enough. I look forward to working with you as a member of our Board of Directors. For those of you who weren't keeping track, this is David's 55th consecutive earnings call. It is only fitting that he provide some closing comments. David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Harvey.</p>
          <p>As many of you know, I've spent my entire career at Goldman Sachs, so it's all I know. I always believed that it was a special place. That is a perception which has been validated over the last several years given my experiences during this period of stress. I witnessed the strength of our client franchise, the quality and dedication of our people, and the commitment of our shareholders.</p>
          <p>It was an honor to be asked to join the Board of Directors. I look forward to continuing to serve as a steward for shareholders in that role. It is a responsibility that I take with full confidence in the strength of the client franchise, the financial health of the company, and the caliber and devotion of our people.</p>
          <p>I would also like to thank all of our shareholders, debt investors, and research analysts for their support of the firm and me personally. I leave knowing that I am turning the role over to Harvey, who has the skills and judgment to warrant that same level of support.</p>
          <p>Thank you again for listening today, and now Harvey and I are happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question is from the line of Howard Chen with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Harvey. Good morning, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think everyone would acknowledge 2012 was a pretty tough year for the industry. But yet when all is said and done, the firm posted nearly 11% return on equity. Just given where revenues and where you decided to accrue comp, can you just discuss the significance of that 11%? Is that a threshold ROE that we should think about that you don't want to fall below in a challenging environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So what I would say about 2012, obviously, as you mentioned, certainly some elements of the marketplace were particularly challenging. What put us in a position to achieve the ROE really were the steps we took over the last two years in terms of managing expenses and being quite disciplined. But in terms of what we're able to achieve in the future, we're going to have to see what the market opportunity brings to us. But this was a year where, like all years, we took everything into account, performance, the competitive dynamic. And as I said, we benefited from the steps that we took over the past few years. But quite frankly, I don't think &#x2013; while we're pleased with the performance in the environment, it's not particularly aspirational. We'd like to do better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And then switching gears, Harvey, with respect to Investing &amp; Lending, you noted the improved realization environment and mix. As many of your investments have been in the ground for a few years now, I was hoping you could provide us some thoughts on how you think about the realization pipeline. Give us a little bit more detail on that appetite to sell today if markets were cooperative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the ability to monetize, as you know, is really driven by two factors. Obviously, it's market performance, but it's also the idiosyncratic nature of your own portfolio. In the past year, obviously, the opportunities &#x2013; you could argue that our performance exceeded that of the marketplace in terms of what you might have expected, but that was this past year, and our portfolio performed well. I think in some quarters it will perform well. In some quarters we won't perform as well relative to the marketplace, but the market will drive that. Certainly over time, with events around the world, we feel like we'll see attractive investment opportunities. But in terms of the scheduled monetization, it's difficult to predict.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then just finally for me, I realize we're now ten trading days into the new year, but just given all that happened at the end of 2012 with the fiscal cliff and so forth, I'm just curious how the year has begun.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's too early to tell with only ten business days into the quarter. You could paint a picture of concern given events in Europe and certainly events in Washington that could be disruptive. If you talk to our economists, our economists would say that we'll see pretty modest growth for the first half of the year in the developed economies, and it will exceed that in the growth economies in maybe the second half of the year, but it's difficult to anticipate that. We do feel pretty well positioned from a business point of view, whether it's in our Investment Banking franchise and certainly across the firm, to capitalize on opportunities, but it's too early to tell.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I had to give it a shot. Thanks for taking the questions and congratulations again, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Howard. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Glenn Schorr with Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks. I think risk-weighted assets were down 8% quarter on quarter, but GAAP was down only about 1%. I know those are different animals. I'm just curious what drove the RWA in the quarter, and then if you had any thoughts on as we look forward, obviously, just on what's the path going forward for RWA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I wouldn't focus so much on the quarter-over-quarter move more so really on the end of last year to the end of this year. So that's roughly 100 basis points, 8% to nearly 9%. And as we've said before, as we get visibility into the rules, we will deploy our teams with tools and we'll be able to react. So what we're really seeing over the course of the year is the effort to be more efficient with capital and, of course, the earnings performance. And so we will continue to react as we get more visibility into all the rules.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So is that a way of saying as the rules come out, I think this quarter many companies have been pushing through getting other model approval. This was a little more driven by that versus actual assets going out the door.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we're not in a position to comment on any model approvals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. How about in a different way, and I understand the sensitivity. As the rules come out, I think Goldman has historically been very good at pushing out whatever the new rules are to the trading desks on the technology, on the desktop, and it make the company more efficient in that manner. Can you just maybe comment where are we in that process, and am I correct to say that that is how we can envision higher ROEs going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The way I would think about it is performance is going drive the ROEs, and that will be about our competitive position and ability to deliver our franchise to our clients relative to others in the context of what the market provides.</p>
          <p>With respect to managing our capital, I think you should expect us to continue to be disciplined. And when we get visibility around rules, we will look to be particularly responsive. We want to be very careful not to overreact before we have a rule and we don't want to under-react after we have a rule, so we hope to do more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. And on the positive side, the competitive landscape has definitely shifted a little bit. I think there's a lot of pressure under some of the European investment banks to do some form of shrinkage, small or large. Do you view that as a big opportunity? I know that over the past year or so or two during the European crisis, you guys have commented that it might be your best near-term opportunity. Is that still in motion and how are you guys going about positioning for it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't say that it's the best near-term opportunity. I think those things are always difficult to weigh. But I think if you're thinking about longer-term strategy across multiple years, certainly capacity leading industry broadly and specifically opportunities in Europe, we think we're well positioned and very attractive to us, but we'll have to see what materializes. The reason why I focus on near term, it's difficult to be too precise about how these things unfold and certainly when.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. Last one is a quickie. If you're schooled in David Viniar answers, I know it's going be a quick answer too. But this year, revs were up 19%. Comp dollars were up 6%, and non-comp was down 4%. That's a fantastic mix for shareholders. I know we can't predict the future. So let's just make believe for a second that revenues will be flat on a go-forward basis. In a flat revenue world, do comp ratios stay and non-comp expenses keep trending lower?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think you have to go back again to how we manage the company and how we think about compensation specifically. So there are a whole host there of factors that go into that. One is going to be how our performance is, and certainly that's going to be reflected in compensation. The competitive dynamic is certainly in there. And then, of course, this is a balance issue, obviously, in terms of providing returns to shareholders. And look, this year we hope we got the balance right. As I said, we're not satisfied. We'd like to do better. But again, it will be determined by what the market opportunity provides us in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, awesome. Thank you for all that, Harvey.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from the line of Michael Carrier with Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, guys. So we've seen two quarters where core revenues felt like they came in a bit better than expected, not only for you, but for the industry. It feels like activity may be stabilizing, hopefully improving. But when we look at the liquidity reserve, it's still seems pretty high. I think in the past, you said when the environment gets better, you could see that trend down. So I guess basically, does that relationship still stand? Do you sense any improvement, or are there still enough regulatory uncertainties on the liquidity and funding side to remain ultraconservative?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what I'd say is just as a matter of principle, we're always going be conservative with our liquidity. I like to say that there are two core life bloods to the firm. One is our clients, and the other is our liquidity, and so we're going stay very focused on both.</p>
          <p>Look, there's a lot of uncertainty in the world, and I agree with you. When you look back over the past six months, certainly the world feels a bit better. Clients generally, although there was a fairly significant amount of risk aversion, got better towards the end of the year, and we'll see how this year goes. There are still a lot of things in front of the world, so I wouldn't expect any significant shift.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, then just a follow-up question on RWAs. Maybe just when you look at the rules and trying to manage the assets and the capital, what percent &#x2013; I know it's an easy question, probably tougher to answer. But what percentage of the rules do you feel like you have clarity on? Maybe like what inning are we in that process of fully getting clarity so you can manage your assets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's a hard question. I would say that &#x2013; I'm trying to be as narrow as possible. I would say that on capital, I don't know, maybe we're in the sixth inning in terms of capital rules visibility. Maybe some people could argue the seventh, but that's using a baseball analogy. I think the broader issue is the collective visibility into all rules, whether it's Volcker, the impact of Dodd-Frank, things that impact globally. And so there, I don't think we have a lot of collective visibility into the weight of that. Actually, I think it's difficult for the regulators to really assess all of that which, quite frankly, is a concern for the industry, and obviously it's a concern for the global economy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay, and then last one. You mentioned just the reinsurance business, maybe putting that up for sale. I'm just wondering. It might be too early, but any size of that business? And maybe the same thing on Investing &amp; Lending; you guys have said in the past there are areas of that business where on the lending side you'll continue to operate that business, and then there are other areas that will wind down over time. So is there any update on the assets or the revenues related to those businesses and then capital that would be released and redeployed elsewhere?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I'm not in a position to comment on the reinsurance business beyond what's in the release. What I would say with respect to Investing &amp; Lending is those are core competencies of the firm. And so for example, when we had visibility on part of the Volcker Rule, we took steps around certain businesses. But at this stage, this will be about how we adapt to rules as we get further visibility. And so I don't know necessarily that we would say that we'd deemphasize anything in Investing &amp; Lending at this stage. Now of course, over time as businesses like the reinsurance business are maybe better held in other people's hands and we can be a minority owner because of capital reasons, then we'll make those decisions, but that will be on a business-by-business basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, got it. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Brennan Hawken with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One question to follow up on that. I'm just assuming that if you guys hold a minority stake in the reinsurance business, it would probably be below the Basel III threshold to avoid a hickey?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then also, how should we think about &#x2013; I'm not sure how much color I'm going get from this, but I'll give it a shot. How should we think about a comp ratio on I&amp;L revenues? My guess is that would be at a lower rate than it would be for other businesses in the firm. But can you maybe provide some color to help us out on that front?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's really important to emphasize the point that when we think about the comp ratio, we think about it in terms of the aggregate of the firm. And then within that, we compensate across the various business units and we build it out individual by individual.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but you'll clearly take into account revenue mix when you start to think about those allocations, right, because that's basically what is the sum of the parts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I would say more simply we don't look to overpay anybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So then with that in mind then, you could easily say that given the competitive environment right now for talent on the street that the improvement in the comp ratio should be at least somewhat sustainable for the benefit of shareholders here in the near term. Is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess you could surmise that. As far as I can tell, even as capacity has been leaving the industry, there has been a huge demand for Goldman Sachs people. And so the competitive dynamic in aggregate may feel much better. But for very talented people of Goldman Sachs, they're very attractive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's fair.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brennan, it's David. You've heard me say this many times before, so I'll just say it again. We don't set a comp ratio. We don't start out and say here's the comp ratio. We compensate our people individually, and we take into account the performance of the firm, the competitive environment all the time, and we're always thinking of those things. So it's hard for us to say what it's going be going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's fair. Unfortunately, we have to set a comp ratio in our models, so I've got to give it a shot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We appreciate that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then I guess last one for me, any color on deferrals? It has been my understanding that you guys have historically had less deferred comp than peers, which clearly gives you greater flexibility. We're hearing a lot of noise around deferrals here given the calendar and where we are. Do you intend to try to keep that flexibility? What's your view on that front?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So there are no deferrals. And I think you're right to say that we have to be very tough when we do that because there's a bit of mortgaging the future. And so there have been no deferrals &#x2013; sorry, no additional deferrals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I was going to clarify that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I got my last bit of mentoring from David there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Harvey.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No problem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from the line of Guy Moszkowski with Autonomous Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning. The CFTC [Commodity Futures Trading Commission] obviously pushed back timing of the OTC reforms with respect to central clearing at least to pretty close the middle of the year. And I know this is a narrow question, but I'm just interested in how you think about it. All else equal, would you expect that revenues in FICC or broadly from OTC derivatives transactions would be higher in the first half as a result of just that change, or is that not the right way to think about it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's a good question. I think that the only case study we have is really history. And when you look back over history, history has proven a couple things. One, it has proven that rule changes and the ultimate impact on market structure, incredibly difficult to predict. I would say &#x2013; and I didn't really feel this way about a year ago. I thought that the rule delays or uncertainty around rules I didn't think was having impact in terms of client activity. I do think as we get more clarity on rule certainty, it may ultimately impact client activity to the positive.</p>
          <p>Now having said that, I wouldn't trade off that delay for bad rulemaking, and I think the CFTC and other regulators have been pretty thoughtful about taking the steps to delay rules because the single most important thing is that the market has an opportunity to adapt because we don't want to increase systemic risk while the regulators try and put new rules in place. So I think all these delays have been quite thoughtful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And from a competitive perspective, just to one of the points that you just alluded to, as the changes in the regulatory environment, for example, Basel III capital requirements, get better understood and your competitors move closer to full adoption, do you feel like the pricing dynamic for transactions that have a big slug of capital that has to be priced into them has become more rational?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not so sure it's necessarily capital rules. I think broadly speaking, it's a level playing field, and so we all have the same rule set. The way we have to differentiate ourselves is by playing to our strengths. And we have a history of our clients wanting capital, and we want to differentiate ourselves by providing capital. And so I think it's really how you execute. Everybody's going to live with the same rule set.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But do you feel like over the last couple of years, competitive pricing has really been rational with respect to what those medium to longer-term capital requirements are? And if it hasn't been as much so as you would have liked, do you feel like it has gotten closer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that &#x2013; and now we're getting into more art than science. I think that competitive response as it relates to things like capital changes, that's a very &#x2013; that's something that plays out over the intermediate to long term. In the short run, you can see irrational behavior by competitors which can't be explained by a capital war. I would say &#x2013; and I'm not sure this is related at all to capital, but I do think that the crisis itself at the margin has made people much more disciplined about their capital deployments. And so for example, I don't even know if this is an indicator that you could extrapolate into your question, but in the fourth quarter there was amazing amount of block activity. There were days where David and I were working with our teams in banking and the financing group on sometimes four or five inquiries. If you ask me on that particular day in December did pricing feel a bit more rational, yes, but I couldn't tell you if that same day occurred this January whether or not it would be as rational. But over years, the market makes people more rational.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's helpful, and then one last question, which follows up a little bit on something that was being talked about before. In Investing &amp; Lending, as you had said, when it became very, very clear that proprietary activities weren't going be precluded, you shot a bunch of that down. What other business adjustments, not necessarily shutdowns, but significant changes to parts of I&amp;L are you either doing or contemplating, for example, in the lending and distressed debt trading parts of the business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say there are obviously a number of rules that can have incremental impact there, Volcker being one of them. We'll see Volcker when it comes out and we'll respond accordingly. But also those businesses, obviously, tend to draw more capital. And so we have no immediate plans for any changes. But to the extent we need to respond again, we'll do it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much for taking the question and, David, farewell. Thanks again so much for all your help over the years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Guy. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from the line of Roger Freeman with Barclays.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe to just pick up there on Guy's question, on I&amp;L you've got I think you said a decent amount of clarity on the capital portion. There are still other pieces, including Volcker, outstanding. But in more of the traditional equity investments area, is that an area that presumably you'd continue to invest or maybe even pick up again, because I think that has been in somewhat of a lull, if the returns are there, right? You'd look at this just like any private equity investor with a return threshold based on the capital requirements, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it would be just like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then separately on comp, some of the reduced ratio sounds like they came out of the restructuring efforts over the past year and a half or so. How much of that decline in the ratio do you attribute to that versus the market environment, the competitive environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we don't think of it in that way in terms of parsing it. I understand why you'd ask the question. I think that what we would say is the following. Obviously, there were a lot of operating leverage in the business this year, and you see the translation of that in terms of the increased revenues into all the metrics. But in terms of how we think about comp, I think David discussed it earlier. It's going be performance driven, and then we take all those other factors into account, including the balance and what our shareholders make.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I guess you touched on this, but the liquidity levels remain still at the highs. The environment is more stable at this point. What do you look for to bring that down, if you have any plans to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no plans to bring it down, so I haven't looked at it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's it for now. Okay, thanks and good luck to you, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from the line of Betsy Graseck with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Betsy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, one nitpicky question. But on Investing &amp; Lending on the debt side, can you give us a sense as to realized versus unrealized?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think it's like a little more than half. There's like a...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the debt side, remember there's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, on the debt side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's interest in there as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would think that it would be more unrealized on the debt side than realized, but we can come back to you with a breakdown.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But remember, a big part of that is the interest also.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. No. I'm definitely taking the interest piece out. I'm just asking on the non-interest piece.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can follow up with you. I don't think I'm far off.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we'll double-check for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, cool. And then on the equity side, we can follow up on that too?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Could you repeat the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the equity side, the realized versus unrealized? Is that mostly unrealized? Is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's a bit more than half on that also.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. And then I know we discussed the clearing question. I just wanted to understand how you're thinking about managing the potential outcomes here because as initial margin does get charged to the buy side whether or not it goes on schedule or is a little bit delayed, how are you thinking about setting yourselves up for what could be a change of behavior on the client side when initial margin comes through?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is an important question because you could extrapolate in some respects our strategy and philosophy around reg reform pretty broadly in this context. So it's incredibly important for us to serve our clients as best we can today. And so it's hard to truly anticipate what any rule change, initial margin for example, will have on their behavior. But we know we need to be there for them today, and so we'll adapt as they adapt. And again, this is a very careful balance because our view is you need to be incredibly focused as the rules come into frame clearly. I think that's obvious. But there can be quite a penalty, I think, paid for overreacting. And so if you ask me &#x2013; if I answer the question very narrowly, we have no explicit plans to adjust around that. But when we see the rules and we work with our clients, we'll work with them as closely as possible to adapt and make sure that their needs are fulfilled.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So we have some example of this in the energy market, right, because we've already seen some rule change and had some behavior move from swaps to futures. And so I'm just wondering if that has given you any sense of experience with regard to how you might behave as the other products come online.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think it's as much, for example, swaps to futures, although it could be, and it could end up looking just like the energy market. But clients, of course, have been large users of futures for many, many years. And so they always could have used futures, so that was always a choice.</p>
          <p>I think a good example of regulatory reform impact would be the collection of rules, whether it was decimalization or Reg. ATS, et cetera, in the equity markets in 1999 I think it was, in 2000 and the early part of the decade. And I think that had a transformational effect, obviously, on the equity markets. We all know that now in retrospect, and that forced us to make significant changes in our business. We had to reduce staff significantly. Back in the day, a very small portion of what we did in the equity business was electronic. Now on any given day, the vast majority of what we do will be done electronically. And so I think it's hard to predict, but the key issue is staying very close to our clients during that period, but it's really about how we adapt. And so I'm not trying to evade your question. I'm just saying it's too early to speculate on how we'd adapt, but we just have to execute.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, so be nimble and carry some capacity to manage through it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can't imagine reducing capacity and then trying to rebuild it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That would be really hard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I hear you, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from the line of Chris Kotowski with Oppenheimer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Just always believing that people's actions speak louder than what they can say sometimes, looking at your share buybacks and going back to 2010, every single quarter the share buyback has been in the range of somewhere between $1 billion and $1.5 billion. And conversely, every single quarter since late 2010, your tangible common equity at the end of the period has been $63 billion or $64 billion. I'm curious. Which is the target and which is the plug? Is it that you've decided that at this level of profitability, $5 billion or $6 billion a year is the right amount of buyback? Or is it just that $63 billion to $64 billion is all you need to run a world-class investment bank, and anything above that you can return to shareholders?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so I wish the science was that precise. But unfortunately, unfortunately for you and for us, it's not that precise. It's much more dynamic. And the way I would frame it is we want to be very conservative about our capital. And that's the first priority. And so we will evaluate it on a quarter-by-quarter basis; and certainly now with CCAR, we work hand in hand with our regulators to make sure that we have a conservative capital plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But just as a follow-up to that, I guess in the context of JPMorgan allocating about $40 billion to its investment bank, B-of-A I think is in the same area code, and obviously all the other banks and European banks generally have less than that, what would be the argument that you need more than $63 billion &#x2013; $64 billion of tangible common to run a world-class investment bank?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As it relates to us, like I said, we want to be conservative about our capital, but we also want to be positioned because capital can make us &#x2013; can put us in a very competitive offensive position. I don't know how JPMorgan and B-of-A allocate their capital, but it's probably a better question for them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fair enough. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from the line of Matt O'Connor with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I could circle back to the OTC derivative topic here, just as we think about the FICC businesses specifically, have you talked about the mix of cash versus non-cash?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, did you say can I talk about it? I couldn't hear the exact question. I apologize.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the question is within the FICC trading businesses, have you talked about what's driven by cash versus non-cash?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we have not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because I had one large investment bank when I was talking to them about the whole potential revenue give-up from swaps, they had noted to me that probably only about 15% of FICC revenues were non-cash. And obviously within that, there would be some structured stuff that wouldn't be at risk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so we haven't talked about it. I'd give you've the following observation. Certainly post-2008 there was a real desire, I think a very rational desire and a natural shift by the whole industry, driven by the client, to really focus on simplicity away from complexity. So you lost some of the most what I'll call the most complex aspects of derivatives, the correlation businesses and things like that, and I don't see those returning. So I don't see those as lost revenue opportunities, although who knows, maybe someday far away they will. But I think that because of that, you've seen a mix shift that was to cash. That feels to me like it has been in place for a while.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just any comment on whether it's for you or you think for the fee pool overall, that 15% is non-cash?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no comment on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just separately as we think about the FICC revenue drivers, whether it's this year or beyond, I get a lot of questions that debt issuance has been so strong the last couple years. How can that be repeated? Credit spreads have tightened so much. How can that be repeated? And then obviously when you talk to people in the business, they remind you that secondary trading has been weak and it has been very low margin business, or a lot of low margin business. Could you just talk a little bit about the puts and takes and if there's any way to quantify the drag from weaker secondary trading or some of the opportunity as you move away from lower margin areas to higher margin areas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that in all these businesses, and let's just take the securities business because you're talking about, for example, cash bond trading and secondary market activity, we benefit from basically the diversity in the collection of businesses. So the credit business may be busier than the mortgage business in a particular day or in a particular month. So that's how we think about it.</p>
          <p>In terms of secondary volumes, it's not really particularly surprising to me, although maybe if you asked me this question a year ago I would have gotten the answer wrong; that just given the incredible influx of capital into the bond space that managers themselves are not rotating positions as much. It had been very directional. And so I don't know. I wouldn't be making any forecasts that secondary bond trading levels would be dramatically lower or dramatically higher the second half of this year for example.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just lastly on the reinsurance business, and I apologize if you disclosed this in the Q, but within the equities business, you talk about in a footnote there's $1 billion of reinsurance revenues for 2012. Is that all driven all by one company or the one stake that you're talking about, or would there be a couple other pieces in that as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At this stage, I really can't comment beyond what's in the footnote.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from the line of Jim Mitchell with Buckingham Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. I just would like to get maybe your thoughts longer term. I think if we look at the return profile, certainly double digit is positive. But I think a good contribution came from private equity, which under the Volcker Rule may shrink over time, and the core business being dragged down by still pretty low returns in fixed income. So when we think not just to next year or so but look further out, do you see, whether it's long-dated derivatives, things like that, are we just missing that there's a significant amount of RWA mitigation over time rather than just looking out to the next year or two but beyond that that is significant enough to get returns up? Or do we have to see some material improvement in the business mix to get the returns up in FICC?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So again, I'm going to sound redundant here. I think predicting multiple years in the future is really hard. I actually think predicting six months in the future is really difficult. And so again, what I would say is the following. We're going to focus on making sure that our institutional clients can deal with us in any business they want and we want to be best in class. And we're far from perfect, so there are certainly businesses we need to work on and we can be better and we can take advantage of our improvements relative to competitors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You should have a view though &#x2013; I'm sorry &#x2013; you should have a view though, at least internally, of what your say long-dated high-RWA type products that you expect to roll off and if there's a lot. Do you have any sense or can you give us any sense if is that a lot, a little or just that would be helpful...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have that data with me, but if you're talking about additions that are on the books with clients...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...versus roll-off, passive roll-off which we've disclosed previously. We obviously &#x2013; I think you should rest assured we study all that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Maybe just on liquidity, can you give us any thoughts on with the new LCR [Liquidity Coverage Ratio] ratio language, how you guys feel you're positioned for the LCR?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So again, we finished with a strong liquidity position with $175 billion in GCE [Gross Credit Exposure]. We have no immediate concerns regarding the LCR. We thought it was good &#x2013; actually like a lot of these rules that the regulators revised the rules in the process and the final rule seemed more thoughtful and well considered than the proposed rules, but no immediate concerns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from the line of Kian Abouhossein with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I just wanted to come back to capital, and apologies if I missed it. But have you given the Basel III risk-weighted assets for the quarter as well as the ratio? And if you have, could you please repeat it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we haven't yet. But we did talk about the fact obviously that we finished near 9%, up 100 basis points over the year in Basel III.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And you have &#x2013; in terms of you have given risk-weighted asset guidance in a recent presentation, November, of $700 billion relative to about $725 billion in the third quarter, and it sounded to me like a very small number. I know you don't include proactive mitigation in your number, but I wonder. In the $700 billion, how much growth of risk-weighted assets have you included there between that number in the third quarter and 2013 year end that you've given? Is there material growth in that number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, there's no material growth in that number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in terms of mitigation, can you give us any more details of how we should look at that, considering that you're talking about how your systems are built in order to allocate capital more efficiently? How should we think about the $700 billion versus what is really achievable, even if you talk more in terms of subjective measures?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kian, I'm not quite sure what you're trying to get at, but if you really want details of all this, we're happy to follow up with you later.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're very focused on this, and you can see we increased where we are by about 100 basis points over the course of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But if you want more details on that, we're happy to follow up with you later.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, because it looks...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the reason why we're struggling a bit with the question is because, quite frankly, you'll see this as we do it, and so it's difficult for us to forecast in a way, obviously, that you'd like us to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but you're constantly beating expectations, and your mitigation seems to be much well ahead of the curve than I think what you were clearly alluding to in the $700 billion, which doesn't include any mitigation clearly or proactive measures. And I get the impression that the number that could be achieved is significantly lower, and that's what I'm trying to get to. But we can discuss it afterwards.</p>
          <p>Just on the Investing &amp; Lending expenses, to be honest, I don't understand that line. You have expense of about $2 billion to $3 billion. I always think about this business like a private equity business, and your cost/income ratio, however, is significantly higher, and your expense line is higher. What is in these expenses? I would have thought this should be more like a 25% to 30% cost/income ratio business, but obviously I don't understand it. So can you explain to me what these expenses are? I assume there are only a few hundred people in this division.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you referring to the segment, Kian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Yes, sorry, the segment Investing &amp; Lending, where you give the expenses in the filings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know that off the top of my head, so why don't we come back and follow up with you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But I assume there are only a few hundred people... running...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> And then we'll have an answer for it (1:01:45).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean there are only a few hundred &#x2013; I assume there are only a few hundred people running in this division. I can't believe there are thousands. I would be even surprised if it's 1,000 people. So I'm just wondering why you're having $2 billion to $3 billion of expenses. Is it interest expense or is it something else? I just don't understand why there's such a big expense level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll come back to you on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, then last question, staffing. Can you talk about &#x2013; you've done a great job on reducing staffing this year. But can you talk a little bit about staffing trends that you would expect to see in your business this year and maybe business or geography if there's maybe a mix change?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, so there are no plans one way or another. I think we're discussing that will all be driven bottoms up by the businesses, as it always is, in terms of the opportunities they see and how they're investing around the world in talent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And should we &#x2013; does that mean staffing &#x2013; it sounds like it's fair to say that staffing levels today are not &#x2013; shouldn't be too dissimilar to the end of this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That will be very driven by the environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right, thank you very much <mark type="ph" /> enough for that (1:03:00).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from the line of Matt Burnell with Wells Fargo Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, just a couple of I guess quick questions for you, Harvey. First of all, in terms of the net outflows on the non-money market side of things, in the fourth quarter they were negative net $18 billion. That's down pretty visibly from the third quarter, but more in line with the fourth quarter. Is that just a seasonal trend, or is there something else going on there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you talking about in Asset Management?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, on page 12 of the release.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Money markets had inflows in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. I meant non-money market flows.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry. I'm sorry, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think there was anything in particular there. I think that just related more to client and investor activity, but there's nothing significant in there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I guess in the bigger picture, Harvey, you mentioned that the backlog was up a bit versus third quarter and up a bit year over year. I guess I'm just curious in terms of your outlook, if you care to provide it, on M&amp;A, there seems to be a lot of media attention and I think some client attention on the potential opportunities for M&amp;A given the potential slowdown in the U.S. and possibly in Europe in those economies and the cash balances. Is there any greater extent of M&amp;A volumes coming in &#x2013; announced M&amp;A volumes coming in 2013 than you've seen in 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Whether or not things are going to be announced, obviously, very difficult to predict. I think it's most &#x2013; when you talk to our investment bankers and our clients, what they'll say is that the uncertainty in the economic environment globally and certainly the political backdrop in the large economies has left CEOs in the position where they've been quite conservative, and then you see it translating into all the things you described, large cash holdings, lots of efficiencies. And so I think that will be &#x2013; in my own opinion, that will be a lagging outcome in terms of when people really feel there's confidence and certainty, then there will be more motivation to consummate transactions. It's very difficult to predict that, as you know.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from the line of Mike Mayo with CLSA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. What's the dollar amount of the backlog quarter over quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't disclose that, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. What is Goldman's ROE target?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that a question for David, or is that a question for me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We want to go with the guy who's going to be around to try to achieve it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I didn't mean to make light of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You'll get the same answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I apologize. Look, so with respect to the ROE target or the absence of an ROE target, quite frankly, over the past several years, there just hasn't been enough information in the marketplace, whether it was capital rules, clarity on Volcker, Title 7, et cetera. And so at this stage, we just don't feel we have enough information to give you a target. Now having said that, what you should expect from us and you will continue to see from us is that we remain committed to superior returns over the long term, and we want to provide absolute superior terms and relative superior terms. So that's our focus, but we have no target.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When do you think you'll have enough information on the capital rules, Volcker, and anything else that's holding you back from having a formal target?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think if you had been sitting here a year ago, you probably would have felt like maybe there's more clarity. But as I said earlier, I think the regulators have done a very, very smart thing, locally and globally, by delaying the implementation because it's so much simultaneous change. Even in Title 7 itself, which is one suite of rules, the regulators have an enormous task in front of them in terms of rolling out these rules. And so that's just one set, and so we'll have to see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The assets are down 2% quarter over quarter. What's happening there and should we extrapolate that downsizing of the balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's nothing meaningful in that. I wouldn't read anything into that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The buybacks, you certainly got some great prices during the year. But you wound up buying back 8% of your stock, but shares only declined by 5%. Is there any way to narrow that gap?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. But I think if you want to go through the mechanics of share count, I'm happy to have Dane and the team follow up with you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then compensation, this is lower than last year if you look at the entire year. How should we think about the comp ratio? I'm talking about the ratio, by the way. How should we think about the comp ratio going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as we said earlier, we're going to evaluate compensation on a year-by-year basis. And we're going to incorporate everything that you would expect us to, which is performance of the firm, most importantly, and then the competitive dynamic and all the other factors that go in. And of course, we have to get the balance right with the shareholders. So we'll evaluate it as the year progresses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then last question. David's line was, "Live to fight another day." So, Harvey, we want to hear your line. But if you look at the VaR, it's down again. But you have the election over, and it seems like sentiment has improved in certain areas. I noticed the equity VaR is up; the other areas are down. So what's Goldman's thought process on taking risk as of today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So I wouldn't read too much into the decline in VaR because virtually all that's attributed to the decline in market volatilities and not actual positions on the desk. And in terms of deploying our capital, we feel quite confident in our ability to do that. And so that VaR number is going to really be driven by client demand and activity, all else being equal. And so as we continue to see a pick-up in client activity, positions may change. Now that may translate into lower things in the number of given offsets, et cetera. But the bulk of what you're seeing in the decline is market volatilities. It's not a reduction in risk or capital deployment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a clarification of that last point. I know VaR is what we have to go on. It's the best indicator in your release, and you're saying we shouldn't really rely on that. Then what else can we rely on? Do you have a, apples-to-apples VaR number that adjusts for the decline in market volatility, or if I simply ask you the question did you guys position yourselves for more risk, absent what VaR is telling us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, first of all, I wasn't saying you can't rely on the disclosure, so I want to be really clear on that. I was actually trying to give you extra information by saying the following. There are factors that go into VaR, one being the positions that we have, and then obviously a big contributor are volatilities in the marketplace themselves. And so all I'm saying is, in this particular instance, the decline was mostly attributed to the decline in volatilities. There was no top-down directive, for example, to take less risk. Our risk-taking, as I said, will be reflective of the client <mark type="ph" /> related (1:10:45) demand for capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. That clarifies it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, sorry about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from the line of Eric Wasserstrom with SunTrust Robinson Humphrey.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Harvey, I hate to come back to the Basel I risk-weighted asset question that Glenn put out several minutes ago, but I'm afraid your answer was maybe too nuanced for me to understand. But it looks like over the past few quarters, your RWAs were in a fairly narrow range of between $430 billion and $440 billion and then have fallen quite significantly in this particular quarter. Can you just help me understand a bit better why that occurred?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the movement there is, I think what we're going to see there, and we'll double-confirm it, but I think what you're seeing there is probably the knock-on effect of our Basel III mitigation efforts having an impact on the ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You asked about Basel I, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct, correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so it's the Basel III capital efficiency efforts that are having a knock-on effect on the Basel I ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from the line of Christopher Wheeler with Mediobanca.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, gentlemen; a few questions, if I may. The first one relates really perhaps not just to you but to your peer group in the United States. Having seen Basel III in terms of capital pushed out really to next year, obviously if we look at Europe, that's not really the case. There's much closer scrutiny by the regulators, particularly so in Switzerland, of the Basel III ratios as they stand. And obviously, a lot of European banks continue to deleverage. Do you see the opportunity to actually carry out some trades which look pretty unattractive under Basel III but would look attractive under Basel I while we go through this period of transition, or will your regulator actually find that's something they would rather you didn't participate in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think that the pace of development, for example, of rulemaking, whether it's the Basel capital rules or, for example in the U.S., much farther ahead on derivatives, et cetera, I don't think that will drive &#x2013; I could be wrong by the way. I don't think that will drive material differences in how firms compete in opportunities. I think a lot more of that is going to be driven by relative competitive position in aggregate. And so if you're well positioned in a particular business, at the margin capital is an input, but it doesn't strike me that the gap is so wide. But in some cases, we are seeing competitors, for example in Europe, exit businesses. So there for sure, there will be opportunities. But I think for people that are competing and electing to stay in businesses, you work within the rule set that you have and you try to bring your competitive advantage to bear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see that. I suppose what I'm really thinking is that, for example, if, as they are, a number of European banks are trying to sell securitized assets which have very high risk weightings because they are being scrutinized slightly more closely by the market, but as I said, also by the regulators, surely in terms of the U.S. banks, there is this opportunity to say, actually in terms of reporting, we don't have to worry about that from a short-term perspective, and the ability to buy some quite attractive assets and then obviously place them then out with your clients. I'm just thinking that might be actually quite an interesting opportunity for you, or do you think it's something that might lead to some unattractive commentary in the press?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, look. We look at Basel III over the long term too. And like I said, I think it's not the pace. Now having said that, do I think some European banks and just many institutions around the globe have maybe been a little slower to sell assets than they might otherwise have wanted to be in retrospect? And I think there are opportunities there, but those are opportunities that our clients are very focused on. If we can be the firm that can bring the collective resources to bear to actually deliver those assets to our clients, then that's a good opportunity for us. But like I said, I'm not sure it's so much rules-driven as it is situation-specific.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then a second question, really it's related to what Kian asked you, and I guess it's a rhetorical question for that reason. But can you give us any clue as to what your Basel III or what portion of your Basel III risk-weighted assets for the moment are deployed in Investing &amp; Lending?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we don't disclose that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that was a pretty much expected question, but thanks for thinking about it at least.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but at least I paused.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you did indeed. And just a final question really. Obviously, one of your closest competitors shed a number of jobs in the last few days. And what was intriguing was I think something like a 6% reduction in their investment banking staff, but something like 15% in Asia, and I was just wondering. You obviously had another quarter where you were very tight on staff numbers. But is Asia the market you're still investing in, or is it one where maybe you're also thinking have we perhaps over baked the pudding at this stage and we need to also look at our staffing there, as you obviously are in the developed markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, as we look at it today, we think the growth markets broadly and Asia specifically look quite attractive, and we're comfortable with our level of investment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll caveat that. And of course if the world got much brighter or turned the other way then we'd adjust, but we feel pretty comfortable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And at this time, gentlemen, there are no further questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, I'd like to thank everybody for joining us for our fourth quarter 2012 conference call. If you have any questions, please feel free to contact us in the Investor Relations group, and otherwise have a nice day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude the Goldman Sachs fourth quarter 2012 earnings conference call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>