<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1259115" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-04-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>665</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Andrew Witty, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Julian Heslop, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Timothy Anderson</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Seamus Fernandez</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Mark Clark</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Michael Leacock</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Steve Scala</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Kerry Holford</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Andrew Baum</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">James Millett</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Gbolahan Amusa</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Justin Smith</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, and welcome to the call. I'm here with Julian. I'll make a few comments and then hand over straight away to Julian.</p>
          <p>Q1 for 2010 I think really highlights that we've had a very good start to the year at GSK, with further evidence our strategy is beginning to deliver. Sales growth continues &#x2013; Q1's sales up 13%, obviously helped by pandemic products, vaccine and Relenza, but more importantly strong underlying growth. If you exclude the pandemic-related products, up 4% for the quarter, and I think demonstrating the sustainability of our sales growth.</p>
          <p>Our established and new products both helped drive this momentum. I'll give you a couple of examples. Seretide/Advair was up 9% to 1.3 billion. Cervarix was up 60% to 77 million. Synflorix, in its second quarter, at 45 million. And Tykerb, a treatment for advanced breast cancer, up 62% to 53 million.</p>
          <p>Sales from what I call "white pill in Western markets" accounted for just 27% of sales in Q1. That excludes, by the way, the pandemic flu products. And the 27 compared to 32 this time last year, so it shows a continued delivery of momentum. Also maybe just another metric to keep in mind: If you add the consumer, vaccine, and dermatology business together, they together accounted for 40% of GSK's sales in the quarter, which is again a signal of the success we've been able to deliver in diversifying the business.</p>
          <p>The diversification is getting growth from many different sources of the organization. Emerging markets, for example, at &#xA3;866 million, up 43%. If you adjust for the pandemic, vaccine, and Relenza, that number was actually up 17 compared to what we think is a market growth rate of around 13.</p>
          <p>Our consumer business continued to have another great quarter, up 9% to &#xA3;1.2 billion. Let me go into a little bit of detail, because it really was, once again, a fabulous quarter from the consumer business. Our Nutritionals business worldwide was up 12%, our OTC business worldwide was up 11, Oral care worldwide up 5. If I look now just at the BRICs for a second, overall BRICs were up 18%, India up 20%, China up 17, Brazil up 17, Russia up 19.</p>
          <p>If I look at the product line within consumer, our smoking cessation business was up 16, driven by the global rollout of Niquitin and Nicorette Mini lozenges, which we've been developing over the last couple of years. In the Nutritionals business, our Horlicks business performed very well, up 17%, led by the UK up 21 and India up 19. Lucozade also returned to growth for the first time in a year or so, up 5%, driven by the launch and supporting advertising campaign of Lucozade Sport Lite in the UK. Sensodyne is now the world's fastest-growing toothpaste, and in America, one of the Sensodyne SKUs took the title of the best-selling toothpaste in America in Q1, the first time we've ever achieved that, and I think a real testament for the efforts of our U.S. team. And of course we continue to launch Sensodyne across the world, including in China and India.</p>
          <p>Brand innovations which have been developed and launched in the last three years represented 14% of sales during the quarter, and we also picked up a raft of awards of excellence both for our marketing quality, brand innovations in the UK, and a number of customer awards for best service, best supply, in a variety of geographies. There's no doubt that our consumer business is really playing at the top of the league. And I'm also delighted, in the quarter, we secured the future leadership for this business with the successful hiring of Emma Walmsley from L'Oreal, who starts at GSK on Tuesday of next week.</p>
          <p>Our dermatology business delivered &#xA3;265 million of sales in the quarter. The brands we acquired from Stiefel contributed 135 of that number. Overall the dermatology business grew 8% year on year on a pro forma basis. We're in the process of globalizing that dermatology business. When we bought Stiefel they were essentially selling products in 50 countries. Over the next couple of years we'll be extending that distribution reach to over 100, including very big markets where Stiefel was not present &#x2013; for example, India, China, and Japan. Already we've begun to deliver our synergies that we anticipated, 44 million to date. And we're on track to deliver all the synergies that we targeted when we made the acquisition during 2010 and 2011.</p>
          <p>We've also begun to establish a consumer platform within our consumer organization to start to bring many of the assets we believe are in the Stiefel portfolio direct to consumers, giving us another leg of growth within our consumer business.</p>
          <p>Sales growth is also, obviously, underpinned by new <mark type="inaudible" /> from our core pharmaceutical business. Just in this quarter we have three key European approvals for Revolade, thrombocytopenia; Arzerra for chronic lymphocytic leukemia; and Duodart for enlarged prostate. And we also had one positive opinion for Votrient for renal cell carcinoma.</p>
          <p>So we continue to see good progress in terms of regulatory approval around the world. We've also continued to progress molecules into Phase III, the most recent being Relovair, Phase III start for asthma. And we now have six biopharmaceutical large molecules in advanced development within the organization. We continue to expect to be able to retain around 30 major programs in Phase III on an ongoing basis.</p>
          <p>Simplification remains a priority for the company, with of course a continued focus on cost containment. We remain on track to deliver annual cumulative cost savings of 2.2 billion by 2012. 1.5 billion of that number will be delivered before the end of 2010. We also continue to focus on improving returns in the business, and we intend to keep investing into our growth businesses around the world to enhance our returns.</p>
          <p>You'll have seen that our legal charges were higher in this quarter as we make good progress towards settling a number of existing cases that we have. And I'll sure you'll see our legal charges bounce around quarter to quarter. As they have done in the past, I'd remind you that over the last several years on an annual basis, our legal charges have run around &#xA3;450 million on average, and going forward, I would expect to see some quarterly volatility as we take evolving views on a variety of cases.</p>
          <p>Our cash generation has been very well sustained, certainly helped by our focus on working capital, and of course supports our progressive dividend policy. Net cash inflow from operating activities in the quarter was &#xA3;2.1 billion, up 22%, and that allowed us to increase our Q1 dividend by 7% to 15 pence a share. Overall, therefore, I continue to believe that GSK's moving to a position of delivering sustained financial performance, and I continue to look forward to the rest of 2010 with confidence.</p>
          <p>With that I'm going to hand over to Julian to give you a little bit more detail on the numbers, and then we'll open it up to questions. Thanks. Julian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Andrew.</p>
          <p>As usual, I will comment on the results using constant exchange rates and excluding major restructuring costs.</p>
          <p>Turnover in the quarter was up 13% to 7.4 billion, with pharma sales up 14% and consumer up 9%. The business benefited from higher flu pandemic vaccine sales of 698 million, although Relenza sales were lower at 84 million. Underlying sales growth, as Andrew said, excluding these pandemic-related sales, was 4% for the quarter and continued to be adversely impacted by generic competition in the U.S. market.</p>
          <p>Within pharmaceuticals, Advair performed well and delivered sales growth in all regions: 4% in the U.S., 10% in Europe, and 25% in the rest of the world. Other strong pharma performances included Avodart, Lovaza, Tykerb, and Arixtra, with sales growth of 20%, 9%, 62%, and 25%, respectively. However, Avandia sales declined by 10%. Sales of newly launched pharmaceutical products, excluding flu pandemic vaccine, totaled 412 million and were up 65%.</p>
          <p>Our vaccines business performed well, supported not only by flu pandemic growth, but also by growth in our hepatitis franchise, up 38%; Cervarix, up 60%; and Synflorix, which delivered sales of 45 million following its launch in quarter two last year. Hepatitis sales benefited from supplier shortages in the U.S. market.</p>
          <p>In Consumer Healthcare, we saw market share gains across all categories and delivered sales growth in each of our regions. Our international business performed particularly well, with sales growth of 13%, and now represents over 40% of the total consumer business. Alli achieved sales of 63 million in the quarter, which included sales growth of 7% in the U.S., and it also included a strong performance in Europe, where the brand was launched in March last year, with sales of 34 million.</p>
          <p>Looking at the income statement, you can see that cost of sales increased to 26.2% of turnover, compared to 24.3% last year, reflecting the impact of U.S. generic competition, but also &#xA3;94 million of stock write-offs, roughly half of which related to flu pandemic vaccine inventory. The company continues to expect cost of sales as a percentage of turnover to be around 26% for the full year.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A costs excluding legal charges were 28.3% of turnover, and we remain on track to deliver our estimate of around 29% for the full year. R&amp;D costs were 9% lower in the quarter compared to last year, reflecting the timing of clinical trials, good progress on efficiency savings, and significantly lower intangible asset write-offs. We continue to expect R&amp;D costs for the year to be around 14% of turnover.</p>
          <p>Other operating income was 199 million, significantly higher than the previous year, and included royalty income of 80 million and a one-off payment relating to the transfer of U.S. Boniva rights to Roche-Genentech. No further payments from Genentech are expect this year.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share in the quarter was 30.7p before restructuring charges and grew 16% CER and 17% at actual rates of exchange. Exchange gains in the quarter compared to losses in the previous year eliminated the adverse exchange rate impact.</p>
          <p>The restructuring programming is progressing well, and after deducting restructuring charges of 301 million, we reported total EPS of 26.4p for the quarter.</p>
          <p>Net cash inflow from operating activities  was 2.1 billion, up 22% in sterling terms. And net debt at the end of the period was &#xA3;9 billion, &#xA3;400 million lower than the year end, which reflected net cash generation after dividends of some 700 million and adverse exchange adjustments on the retranslation of net debt of some 300 million, a net improvement of 400 million.</p>
          <p>Finally, in an effort to improve transparency and understanding of our increasingly diverse business, we have provided more detailed segmental P&amp;L information this quarter and in addition pro forma information summarizing the performance of our global vaccines and derms businesses.</p>
          <p>Overall, the company's on track to deliver its strategic programs and remains committed to its progressive dividend policy. We increased the quarter one dividend to 15 pence.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll hand back to Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Julian. And now I'm happy to open up the call to any questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We have a question from the line of Tim Anderson [Sanford Bernstein]. Please go ahead, Tim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. On emerging markets' operating margins, as you show, they're a little bit over half of what they are in established markets. And the biggest driver of that disparity seems to be in the cost of goods line, where the gross margin percentage is quite a bit lower than it is in established markets. My question is, where do you think operating margins in emerging markets can realistically go from here over the next three to five years, given what is likely to be a continual pricing disparity?</p>
          <p>And then second question is on Avandia. If that product ends up getting withdrawn from the market, why won't that look like another Vioxx in terms of the legal liability Glaxo would face? I think in the Vioxx case, that's cost Merck about 8 billion or so in terms of U.S. dollars. And is there anything yet in your legal reserves related to Avandia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Tim, I'm going to ask Julian to begin the response to the first question. Then I'll pick up on that and then obviously answer the second question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, you're right, emerging markets' operating margin is 36%. Difficult, Tim, to predict the future. But I would expect it to stay around that level. I mean, that's an indication but certainly not significantly changed, based on everything I know today.</p>
          <p>But let's put that 36 into perspective. First of all, a 36% operating profit margin in any business is excellent. And secondly, you've got to bear mind that if you think of our R&amp;D costs &#x2013; and our pharmaceutical R&amp;D costs are about 16% of sales &#x2013; there's probably only a third of the emerging markets business that actually sells products that that R&amp;D is focused on. And you could argue that actually we don't do any R&amp;D specifically for emerging markets. But even if you take the tougher view and say, well, I'll allocate a third of it, that's a 5% charge compared to 16 for the other sectors.</p>
          <p>I just think you need to recognize that, because remember, if you look in our segmental analysis, all the R&amp;D is located under Pharmaceuticals R&amp;D and Vaccines R&amp;D. So I think you have to bear that in mind.</p>
          <p>But bottom line, I think that's a very good operating margin. And actually if you look at the total operating margin of pharmaceuticals, it's 42, and for the whole business it's only 33. So actually emerging markets has an operating profit margin that's just slightly ahead of GSK. So I think that's a very sound basis to grow that business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Julian. And Tim, I'd maybe just add to that just a couple of comments that certainly reinforce the R&amp;D point which Julian has made, because there's no question at all that certainly at the moment &#x2013; of course this might change in the future &#x2013; but at the moment, the vast majority of our R&amp;D spend is essentially stimulated by European and U.S. market demand. And essentially the emerging markets then benefit from that, but they don't stimulate it. And therefore I think it's right to offset that in the way that Julian mentioned.</p>
          <p>The other thing I would say is that we're well aware that other companies' definition of what's in emerging markets is different from ours. So for example, none of Southeast Asia is in our emerging market category; obviously, Japan is not in there. We're <mark type="inaudible" /> emerging markets particularly, but they're not in there. And it's important when you compare margins that you look at like to like. Because if you look at our Asia Pac-Japan business, you'll see they're very high-margin businesses. And so actually knowing what's in there is important.</p>
          <p>Lastly, I would say recall that we have a huge Indian business. And the Indian business is one which is going to &#x2013; puts us in a phenomenal strategic position going forward. We're in the top three manufacturers of all types in India. But of course, we all know that India has historically been a low-priced marketplace. And therefore to some degree that's a slightly different feature of the business &#x2013; one I'm very pleased we've got &#x2013; but it's nonetheless a different feature.</p>
          <p>As far as Avandia is concerned, look, Avandia is a product where there's been so much media debate, sometimes it's very easy to miss what the debate has been at the scientific level. And the debate that's been at the scientific level has been robust, and it's been in public forum, and it's been at Advisory Board in the U.S. and a variety of regulatory debate over the last several years in Europe and elsewhere. And the pattern of those discussions have been very supportive of Avandia.</p>
          <p>And if you just think about the U.S. for a second, we had an Advisory Board in 2007. There was a very strong vote in favor of keeping the product on the market. You've seen since 2007 a whole raft of new data being generated from really gold-standard trials in terms of being randomized landmark studies. All of that data has essentially served to strengthen the positive risk-benefit profile of Avandia when used appropriately, in line with the label. And of course we have an upcoming Advisory Board in July, where there is an opportunity again for the U.S. to review all of that data that's come together over the last several years.</p>
          <p>So I think at the scientific level, this remains a very dangerous, largely unmet medical need disease, with very serious consequences of not managing the disease properly. We have a medicine here which is demonstrated to gain control of HbA1c blood sugar over a prolonged period of time based on landmark prospective studies, and we have a raft of landmark prospective studies which reassure us of our view of the profile of this medicine. And that's very much the way we see this.</p>
          <p>Now, obviously we have to see how the Advisory Board goes, and we're going to have an opportunity to make our case, as will others. But I believe that this debate is very different from the situation you describe. I think it's one which has had tremendous amount of inspection, if I can put it that way, and it's one where the data continues to reassure. And on that basis, I don't think it's appropriate to draw analogies across to other examples of the type you described.</p>
          <p>Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Seamus Fernandez [Leerink Swann]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Just a couple of quick questions. One on the impact of U.S. healthcare reform. Could you help us think about &#x2013; you talked about managing the impact of healthcare reform in 2010. Can you also give us a little bit of visibility on your views on 2011 and what percent of your overall &#x2013; or at least your U.S. pharmaceuticals business &#x2013; is exposed to Medicaid and Medicare. And if you can kind of include the ViiV Healthcare in that forecast.</p>
          <p>And then separately, as you think about operating margins longer term, just to kind of extend on Tim's question with regard to the emerging markets, the number of products that you would have potentially launching across those markets and what type of investment spend you have going on in those markets, do you actually see potential leverage in those markets as it relates to your SG&amp;A spend over time?</p>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me see if I can nail those questions for you.</p>
          <p>As far as U.S. healthcare reform is concerned, as you've seen, we don't believe it's &#x2013; has a huge impact in terms of changing our outlook for the year or how we see the year go. And we've obviously made all of the appropriate provisions in our Q1 numbers to take into account those impacts which are visible and are immediate. And you've seen the very &#x2013; I think very strong overall performance, and importantly the signals of stabilization and return of performance in the U.S. business, even after you take that into account. I think that's the first thing I would say.</p>
          <p>And obviously within that we've paid very close attention to the whole raft of impacts from healthcare reform. You know as well as I do, Seamus, this is, what, 2,000 pages of legislation. I think there are 3,000 uses of the word "should" indicating some change in policy for somebody in the United States. It's a very complex thing to work through. However, if you look at everything, ranging from the simplest calculation &#x2013; which is increase in Medicaid rebate &#x2013; all the way through to the CPI penalties, the change in average manufacturing price, all of those dimensions, we've clearly worked through and assessed what we think the impact is going to be. And we feel that it's very much manageable within our business. And clearly you've seen how we've dealt with it in Q1 as a signal of that.</p>
          <p>Now, as we move into 2011, there are a couple of things which will kick in fresh. One will be the &#x2013; if you will, the tax on the industry, the assessment on the industry. And the second will be the closure of the donut hole, or the partial closure of the donut hole, through the 50% discount from the industry. Those are going to be incremental potential costs. The extent to which they are going to impact the company's trading performance really depends on what happens to some of the volume.</p>
          <p>So whereas most of the coverage extension which is foreseen in the healthcare reform bill isn't going to obviously happen until the 2013-14 timeframe, as soon as you start to see the discounts go into the donut hole, that starts to address one of the key areas where coverage has historically been patchy, where patients have hit the donut hole and then either begun to ration or cease drug treatment because of the costs associated in that donut hole.</p>
          <p>And so the real question is to what degree is the donut hole discount cost &#x2013; which is really the incremental charge for 2011, if you put the assessment to one side &#x2013; to  what degree is that going to be offset by volume? You know, we could have 20 people in the room and probably have 30 different opinions. My view is that there's every likelihood that a lot of that is going to be offset by change in patient behavior. I think this is a very positive thing for patients. It's exactly where, if the companies had to put money on the table, this is the kind of place we should put money on the table because it helps patients get through the donut hole without interrupting treatment course. My guess is the net-net of that isn't going to be very big in terms of impact on us.</p>
          <p>And then the industry assessment is the industry assessment. That's a charge we're going to have to take, obviously, in 2011. But in the scheme of the company of GSK's size, it's not something that's going to dramatically change our future one way or the other.</p>
          <p>So from that perspective, I really don't think this is something to get overly excited about. These are obviously significant contributions to the challenge of healthcare reform from companies like GSK, but we're big companies, and our job is to deal with it and make sure that we can work our way forward without this kind of thing knocking us off-track. And I'm confident we can do that.</p>
          <p>Now, in terms of where our splits of business are, essentially we have &#x2013; around 7% of our business in the U.S. is in Medicaid; around 13% is in Medicare Part D. And we have about 2% in what's called Managed Medicaid. So this is the parts of the Medicaid business where the states have outsourced to manage care companies the management of their business.</p>
          <p>HIV &#x2013; ViiV &#x2013; is a little more exposed than the average because of &#x2013; obviously there are more HIV lives in the Medicaid marketplace.</p>
          <p>And the last question &#x2013; could you just repeat the last question, Seamus?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the second question &#x2013; first question was on healthcare reform. I'm actually forgetting my own second question. So I guess the second question would really be, if you wanted to address it, would be healthcare reform potential changes in Europe as well in the context of the current crisis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Again, it's a big question. It's a good question.</p>
          <p>So context: Over the last six, seven years, I think it's a reasonable rule of thumb to work on the assumption that on the average, we take about a 3% price cut across the whole of Europe every year. So we have a European business which is used to that kind of pressure. Typically a 3% price cut on the average for the whole of Europe might have been constituted by four or five countries doing something relatively dramatic. And every year you get a different four or five countries. The question is whether or not we're going to see something different here. Are we going to see four or five countries do something which adds up to 3% for the whole year, in which case it's kind of normal? Or are we going to see something substantially beyond that?</p>
          <p>I think it's premature to take a view on that, to be honest with you. Of course we see countries like Greece clearly beginning to wrestle with some very, very serious fiscal issues under great pressure. It's obvious that we're going to see some kind of impact in some countries. I think this is the kind of think as we go into Q2, Q3, is going to become clearer, about whether or not the European-level impact is going to be much off-trend or not. At this point in time, it's very difficult to call. I think the right thing to do is to be alert, continue to manage the business as we always have done &#x2013; which is we don't expect price increases in Europe; we expect there to be price pressure. What that speaks to is volume, value for money propositions, introducing new medicines, and making sure that we can deliver to customer expectation, both at the patient and government level, and let's see how it flows out through the rest of the year.</p>
          <p>So definitely a subject to watch. Will it be a huge issue? <mark type="inaudible" /> We're relatively less exposed than most of our peers for all sorts of reasons, not least because we've diversified the group so much in the last few years. And so, again, we'll have to wait and see what happens. But I think we're in a relatively decent shape for whatever might come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I apologize. It was &#x2013; leverage in emerging markets was the question. So from an investment phase &#x2013; are you in investment phase right now on the SG&amp;A side, and do you see that as a leverage opportunity potentially over time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, yes. We have been in a leverage phase for the last two years, really, Seamus. And so essentially every dollar we've &#x2013; so, at a group level, pretty much every dollar we've spent in the emerging markets has been at least paid for by a dollar less spend in the West. Just to be very simplistic, kind of rule-of-thumb.</p>
          <p>So we've been downsizing, restructuring in the West and investing in emerging markets. For the first time over the last three, four, five months, we've actually &#x2013; now have more sales personnel in the emerging markets than we do in America and Europe combined, just to give you just a sense of the quantum of shifts. Pretty big.</p>
          <p>What you will now start to see is you absolutely will see leverage, because as we've built up that infrastructure, as we've moved our selling capacity up, we're obviously able to now drive through a greater portfolio of products. I think we've got much greater coverage in places like China; we've got much greater coverage in places like Russia. And so no question you're going to see leverage.</p>
          <p>Now, having said that, if we see opportunity to continue to invest, whether that be organically through further distribution capability or whether that be through further  bolt-on acquisitions &#x2013; as you know, we did, I think, 11 bolt-ons last year, most of them emerging markets &#x2013; we're not going to shy away from those opportunities. This is one of those moments where we're seeing fundamental economic shifts go on in the world economy. For sure we will see volatility in the growth profile of emerging markets, but they are directionally going in one direction. And this is the moment to make sure that we're invested properly in terms of our structure, in terms of our resources, and in terms of the product portfolios &#x2013; and in terms of the way we staff and then put together creative price strategies. And, yes, we should be looking for leverage, but this is still a time to look for those opportunities and invest behind them when we see them.</p>
          <p>I'm glad we got there in the end, Seamus. Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Mark Clark [Deutsche Bank].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. It's a question for Julian prompted by the table on page 23, which talks about the vaccines, dermatologicals, and all other <mark type="inaudible" />. Just wanted to double-check. Firstly, the 94 million COGS write-off is included within that table in the vaccines total of 389. If that's the case, then the, if you like, the underlying profitability there would have been sort of substantially in excess of 800 million, and the incremental margin on the delta of sales over the last year in excess of 80%. And I just <mark type="inaudible" /> I'm reading that correctly,  because clearly this is bearing a big imprint from H1N1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, the write-off in the H1N1 is in the vaccines global numbers. But clearly, large H1N1 sales in the quarter does distort the operating margin. If you were to look at it on a normalized basis without that sort of peak, I'd  expect you'd see on an ongoing basis in operating margins for global vaccines of around about the 35% mark, somewhere in that sort of level, in a sort of normal sort of course, or normal sort of year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Michael Leacock [RBS Capital Markets]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I've got three brief questions, if I may. Firstly, on the exchanges, <mark type="inaudible" /> Julian. If I calculate correctly, that's about 100 million or so benefit in the quarter. Is that correct that that goes into the SG&amp;A line, and is there anything you can tell us that might give us a chance of being able to model that with any degree of veracity? Secondly, could you talk about your working capital changes in terms of the ongoing project there? And thirdly, I know we've only had one quarter of historic data, but I wonder if you could talk about trend in the emerging markets, where clearly the cost of goods is running up in line with the sales growth, but the SG&amp;A, certainly for the <mark type="inaudible" /> isn't running as fast. Is that a trend that we could realistically expect to continue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sadly, my answer to your first question about exchange gains, are they predictable &#x2013; I struggle to predict them myself, so I fear I can't give you any guidance to help you there. I mean, just to put it into perspective, they were 85 million in quarter one. And last year in quarter one they were 11 million. Overall in 2009, we had a hit of about 103 million, and in 2008 we had a gain of about 137. So it is volatile. Clearly, the more currencies move, the more you get it. But as to predicting it, very difficult unless the trending currency's very smooth, clearly. But otherwise very hard. So that hopefully covers that one.</p>
          <p>Sorry, your second question was &#x2013; ?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Working capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Working capital. Yeah, in terms of quarter one, not much progress in terms of the numbers. In working capital, you'll see adverse in quarter one. A few reasons for that: The flu pandemic receivables were higher; that's point number 1. Invariably when we compare quarter one to quarter four, there's always a lower level of payables; it's just historical. And so the payables days are the same, but there's an adverse hit there. But otherwise, pretty flat. In terms of days, inventory days slightly better, payables days pretty flat, and receivables days marginally adverse. In terms of the year, I'm anticipating cash generation from working capital this year, not just obviously from lower pandemic receivables, but also from all the other actions we're taking, too. You will see that come through as the year progresses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then in terms of emerging markets, I mean, I think the best guidance we can give you is that overall we're aiming for that business to be, as you've heard already, operating around the mid-30s. And I'm going to reiterate, Michael, that the SG&amp;A &#x2013; we're not going to manage that business to a ratio while there's so many hot opportunities around, if they're there. And obviously if they're not there, then that's a moment to consolidate and manage to the right margin. But there are &#x2013; I really want that organization &#x2013; it's why I run it as a separate business &#x2013; I want that organization to be really entrepreneurial in terms of chasing after the opportunity and to really establish ourselves for the long run in these countries. So I can't give you a trend on that, because I really think we ought to be ready to respond to every growth opportunity we see, whether it be organic or inorganic.</p>
          <p>Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Steve Scala [Cowen &amp; Co.]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you. A few questions on the possibility of Advair generics in the U.S. and EU at some point in the future. What is your competitive intelligence on the Sandoz Oriel acquisition and its ability to develop an AB-rated Advair in the U.S.? And maybe similarly, what is your understanding of where Vectura stands in the EU? And is there any evidence that the FDA will issue bioequivalence guidelines for combination respiratory products in 2010? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Steve. On the second part of the question, we have absolutely no insight into what FDA may or may not do. So, I've no intelligence to say that anything is going to happen ever, when, no idea.</p>
          <p>As far as the first part of your question, I'm not going to comment on other people's development programs. But I'm going to reiterate what I've said many times before, and I think all the evidence of other corporate behavior in the last few months has reinforced my view of what this situation is.</p>
          <p>One, it has nothing to do with the primary patent. So the notion that there is some great event to happen when the primary patents expire on the molecule and the combination is not the trigger. It's all about whether or not people can manufacture product which can pass muster with the various regulators, of whom the U.S. FDA is, by far, the most challenging. To achieve a substitutable approval is an even greater reach than simply an approval of a non-substitute, all of which you know. But the reality is, it's exactly as we've said, this is very, very difficult. And I think we're seeing decision making and behaviors and timings and all sorts of things like that which are completely consistent with our view of how this was going to play out.</p>
          <p>And I still &#x2013; right now, for me, nothing's changed in terms of the way we view this. We view this as a marketplace where Advair remains a very strong product, up 9% in the quarter. It's a product we remain extremely committed to in terms of resourcing for growth. And we expect to be doing that for the foreseeable future, and we're moving full pace ahead to bring our own NCE programs through. You've seen the Relovair program now up and running on all fronts, and you'll see later in the year, I expect, some very good progress in the rest of our respiratory development portfolio. So &#x2013; and I'm really going to be &#x2013; I'm not going to go into the individual products of the competitors, because they've got to deal with their own problems, and it's for them to talk to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Kerry Holford [Credit Suisse]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I just have a follow-up question on Advair, actually. We saw very strong growth, particularly in Europe in the quarter &#x2013; I think it was around 10%. Can you just detail what's driving this? Give us an idea of the components of the growth <mark type="inaudible" /> in that market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thanks, Kerry. I mean, to be honest with you, it's nothing more complex than just very good executional performance. European business has been an extremely &#x2013; obviously we've been in this business for a long time in Europe, and I think that we've had a period where we've &#x2013; continually go back, refocus on what we're doing with the product. We always have had a very high market share. I think we've retained something like 70% of the combination market throughout the period of the Advair &#x2013; or the Seretide-Symbicort competition. And I think what you're seeing is, across Europe, a very strong execution of our operation. The whole thing is driven by volume. There were no price increases in Europe. And it's been a very good period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Andrew Baum [Morgan Stanley]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking the call. Just one question, following on from the guidance from the FDA regarding LABAs. I mean, Dr. Chowdhury and the FDA have referred to wanting to see LABA volumes drop in the U.S. and working with various stakeholders to achieve that goal. To what extent do you think that is a reality? Or do you think the focus of the FDA is far more on monotherapy, i.e. not concomitant use with steroids, and in fact you won't actually see rigorous enforcement of looking for reductions in volumes of combined therapies?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Andrew. I mean, to be honest with you, although there's been a variety of communications over the last few months, as you know, the final FDA &#x2013; or the, if you will, next iteration of FDA position on this &#x2013; hasn't been communicated to us or anybody yet. So I think we have to wait and see how that initial sentiment actually translates into whatever the next position we get from FDA. And as you know, they've pushed back that date once or twice in terms of when they said they'd be ready to talk to stakeholders about it.</p>
          <p>So to be honest with you, I don't think it's right to react to the initial statements when we know that they're looking at all of this &#x2013; they haven't finalized, or they haven't finalized what their next position is on this. It may well be the same, it may be different. I don't know. So if you don't mind, I'm going to kind of plead the Fifth on this one because until we actually get greater clarity about what FDA really want, having now received stakeholder feedback &#x2013; and as you know there was quite a lot of stakeholder feedback, particularly around the outcome that took place on a completely different subject. So I think that's all I would say.</p>
          <p>I can't help but take this opportunity, though, Andrew, if you &#x2013; I do recall a TC we had a year or so ago when you asked about talent in Consumer and whether or not we were really committed to our consumer business. I just wanted to remind you we've now hired a fabulous new leader for our consumer business from the pure-play consumer world. And I just wanted to add to that that in the last 12 months, we've hired 20 vice presidents or directors of our consumer business around the world, all of whom came from FMCG companies and none of whom came from pharma companies. So I just wanted to let you know, your question was listened to, and I wanted to give you some feedback on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's excellent, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of James Millett. Please go ahead, James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the question. First question on Benlysta. Based on the full data from the <mark type="inaudible" /> trials, what's your view of getting a steroid sparing claim on the label? And secondly, on the Relovair Phase III program for asthma, have these trials been agreed with the FDA, and are they sufficient for U.S. approval? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. As far as Relovair is concerned, as you know, there's still debate going on at FDA about what the safety trials that are required for registration or perhaps as a post-registration commitment for a new product are going to be. So we've initiated these trials because we believe Relovair, even excluding the U.S., is an extremely exciting opportunity. And that's particularly reinforced when you see the phenomenal growth rates of Advair, Seretide, in the rest of the world. So we're obviously getting on with it.</p>
          <p>A very large amount of what we're doing with Relovair has of course been discussed with FDA &#x2013; whether it's the dose or all those sorts of things. And we believe that in the event that there is some clarity from FDA on the trials, there will still be &#x2013; there may be a possibly we have to slightly amend the Relovair program. We think we can do that.</p>
          <p>So, at the end of the day, by definition, this program isn't yet completely in step with what the U.S. might want, because they haven't clarified what they want. But we're getting on with as much as we possibly can do because there's no point holding up the rest of the world for it. We believe that we could probably accommodate what they might ask us for. And of course, in terms of the fundamentals of what Relovair is, that has all been discussed with the agency.</p>
          <p>As far as a steroid sparing claim is concerned, obviously, the data trends are numerically the right way. But ultimately this is down to the review. It's very hard to speculate how that's going to go. This is a first modern medicine for lupus. I think we've got a terrific data set to support registration in terms of meeting the primary endpoints, meeting the prespecified endpoints. We've got certainly the regulatory package to get this medicine approved. What the fine detail is of the various dimensions, such as steroid sparing, I think we just have to go through the process and see how that plays out. But, the bottom line is this program absolutely delivered, and we continue, with HGS, to be very excited about the opportunity and confident about our ability to get this approved.</p>
          <p>The next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from the line of Gbola Amusa. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gbola Amusa, UBS. Thanks for taking my call. A question on Japan. If I understand correctly, your vaccine sales in Japan a couple of years ago were almost zero, with Japan roughly 10% of global pharma. Could you tell us what you hope Japan can contribute to your overall vaccines franchise in the next five years, just directionally?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure. You're absolutely right; there was virtual no vaccine sale &#x2013; as you might also know, virtually no vaccine sale from any foreign company. And actually not very much vaccine sale, even from local companies. A very undeveloped vaccine business. We obviously had a terrific success in terms of being able to get a pandemic flu vaccine imported. We took the biggest share of that order. It was the first time that any flu vaccine had been imported by the Japanese government. A very significant win. Obviously it's adjuvanted &#x2013; very significant fact.</p>
          <p>We've also had Cervarix approved, and that's just beginning to get going in the U.S. And you'll also be aware that we created a joint venture with a company called <mark type="inaudible" /> to develop further seasonal flu products. So we have a very aggressive agenda to develop our vaccine business. And we see a raft of potential vaccine opportunities over the next five or six years. And a bit like the pharmaceutical business, if you went back five or six years, you would see that we had very few new products being approved in Japan. Over the last two or three years &#x2013; in fact, I think we had 13 line extensions on new products approved in 2009. We have between 30 and 40 line extensions or new products to be approved between '09 and 2013. That's all been because we've figured out how to get pharmaceuticals registered in Japan &#x2013; by changing our clinical development program, by working closing with the regulators.</p>
          <p>We're doing exactly the same with the vaccine business. The fact that we got Cervarix approved miles ahead of Gardasil, the fact that we got pandemic vaccine in, the fact that we put together this JV, tells you that we're beginning to work through how to ramp up our vaccine business. And in the medium run, you've got to believe that we can build a business there which proportionately delivers just as much from vaccines as anywhere else in the group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if I may ask a quick emerging-markets question as well. You had this 15% compound annual growth objective in December. But it was for a narrower definition of emerging markets than your peers give, and it seems specific to your pharma business. With your consumer business growing very robustly on emerging markets and in all contributing to an overall franchise that's perhaps 24% of your sales, would you be able to say at least directionally whether your objective for growth in the broader definition is close to 15% as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what we've said is on the pharmaceutical emerging markets business we want to grow ahead of the marketplace and grow market share. And we're clearly doing that, and that's certainly the goal we want to. As far as the consumer business is concerned, at the global level &#x2013; and of course the emerging market's a big contributor to that &#x2013; we want to be in a position where over the next five or six years we can double the size of that business organically. And that's pretty much the set of goals that we're setting for ourselves. No question.</p>
          <p>If you look at the consumer, Gbola, and this is something we can talk about offline with anybody on this call, the opportunities for GSK consumer brands in the emerging market is absolutely phenomenal. If you look at &#x2013; in some unexpected areas, right? So you look at the functional drinks business that we have in the shape of Lucozade and in the shape of Horlicks, just in the emerging markets, that marketplace &#x2013; the beverage &#x2013; is worth about $200 billion. Absolutely massive. The drinks business in China is a bigger opportunity than the OTC pharmaceutical business.</p>
          <p>And so what you're going to see GSK do, and it's why it's so important that we continue to have this diversified portfolio, we have so many opportunities to open up emerging market business streams, whether or not it's a pharmaceutical product, whether it's a vaccine product, whether it's a dermatological product, whether it's a drinks product, a toothpaste product, or an OTC medicine product.</p>
          <p>And as a result, I'm very optimistic &#x2013; notwithstanding the occasional ups and downs that every emerging economy is going to have &#x2013; that we have got a really strong portfolio of brands to be able to open up the market. I can tell you, I was in India three weeks ago, and at Horlicks, believe this or not, in the Indian survey of the most trusted brands in India, Horlicks ranks number 6 out of all brands, all industries, all of India, Horlicks is the sixth-most-trusted brand in India. That's the kind of strength you need if you want to build up a strong emerging markets business on consumer.</p>
          <p>So where I net out of all of this is that we're focused on really investing behind a fundamental shift in economic activity in the world. We are ready for the ups and downs that exchange rate fluctuations might come. We're not going to get knocked off-course because we've got great products which play exactly into this marketplace. Combine that with our distribution power, combine that with our willingness to price properly in these marketplaces &#x2013; that's what's driving our growth, both in the pharmaceutical and the consumer business.</p>
          <p>Got time for last couple of questions, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Eric Le Berrigaud [Raymond James]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, Eric.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe we could go to another question.</p>
          <p>Of course. The next question comes from the line of Justin Smith. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks for taking my question. It was just a quick one on Cervarix. Andrew, I think you mentioned that the fourth quarter results you were expecting a big quarter in the first quarter to Cervarix. Just wanted to check you were happy with the performance in the first quarter. And also if you could just share a few thoughts with where the key wins in Europe for Cervarix have come from the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, so I am pretty happy with Cervarix in the first quarter. Of course, it's mostly driven by Europe and rest of world performances. Most of the business &#x2013; these are wins which we got last year, and they're obviously flowing through &#x2013; they tend to be a little bit lumpy because you get very government-centered on these big vaccination campaigns, and they tend to order six months of inventory in one chunk, which is why you get some very quiet quarters and some very busy quarters.</p>
          <p>Within Europe, the real standout would be UK, Netherlands, and to some degree other parts of Scandinavia, such as Sweden. And the one area where I think we've got real opportunity to, if you will, enhance the growth rate, is obviously the U.S. We've got the approval in the U.S. We're just going through the final phases of getting the reimbursement sorted out for Cervarix under the various vaccine reimbursement programs. That's imminently going to get resolved. Once that's done, then I think the U.S. will come onstream.</p>
          <p>The great news as well, obviously, is that as more data got generated for Cervarix, the profile really firmed up, really looks very good, very competitive. We've got the amendment to the European label going through as we speak. And that will continue to strengthen, I think, our competitive position. And we've got Japan under way without any other competitor in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>So yes, I was pretty happy with it. I'm keen to see the U.S. kick in during the rest of the year, keen to see Japan kick in. But overall I think good progress with Cervarix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Thank you also to everybody else. I think we're out of time. And I very much appreciate the questions. Obviously if you have more questions as you reflect on the results, the IR team at GSK is available for you to call anytime. And in the meantime, thanks for your attention today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>