<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1454541" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-04-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>64294</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">G&#xE9;rard Mestrallet</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Isabelle Kocher</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Execution Noble Research Ltd.">Lawson Steele</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Julie T. Arav</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Non-Independent Executive Vice Chairman &amp; EVP">Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Cirelli</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Michel Debs</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane BNP Paribas SA">Benjamin Leyre</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Cygnus Asset Management SGIIC SA">Luis Amusategui</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Martin C. Young</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Vincent De Blic</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (France)">Bertrand Lecourt</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Conference Call on GDF SUEZ 2012 First Quarter Results organized by GDF SUEZ along with G&#xE9;rard Mestrallet, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of GDF SUEZ; and Isabelle Kocher, the Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer.</p>
          <p>For your information, this conference is being recorded. Thank you for holding. The conference will be chaired by Mr. G&#xE9;rard Mestrallet, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of GDF SUEZ.</p>
          <p>Mr. Mestrallet, I'll now hand over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. I'm delighted to welcome you to this call. I will share the presentation with Isabelle Kocher, and afterwards we will be ready to answer your questions with Isabelle, with Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Cirelli with us, and Anne Ravignon, Head of our Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>Before starting, I just want to stress that this call is consistent with our decision to have more interactions with the financial markets, with the investors' community. We had just finished our General Meeting and I thought it was the right time to address you on our first quarter results.</p>
          <p>Let's start with our key figures which are good and in line with our full-year targets. The revenues have reached &#x20AC;28 billion, up 10.5%, compared to the first &#x2013; 2011 first quarter. The EBITDA has increased by 5.7% and reached &#x20AC;5.8 billion. Now, to date, the net debt amounted to &#x20AC;37.1 billion, down &#x20AC;0.5 billion from the amount of end 2011. Besides, you know that we are highly committed to shareholder return, and I would like to inform you that we have just completed the share buyback program. It was a &#x20AC;500 million share buyback program announced in September 2011.</p>
          <p>Now, let's have a look to the main milestones of the first quarter. Obviously, the group has reached a major milestone with the project of the full acquisition of International Power and the agreement with the independent board members on a price, 418 pence. And this operation will definitely reinforce GDF SUEZ's specific profile. The new organization of our European activities, starting at the first of January, is also a very important step for us. We know that this has been implemented since the beginning of the year, with the objective to further integrate and optimize our energy operation in Europe, and Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Cirelli is, since the first of January, the Chief Executive of this new branch, branch Energy Europe.</p>
          <p>We have also continued our industrial development, and let me give some examples. The power plant's commissioning in the high-growth markets, Al Dur in Bahrain, has been commissioned. The Paiton power plant in Indonesia has been commissioned. And also, we have been awarded new projects, and let me mention not only the AZ Zour in Kuwait. In Gas, GDF SUEZ has been recently appointed as a strategic partner to develop a floating LNG import terminal in India. This is an additional step in the building of our Asian-Pacific platform.</p>
          <p>I would like also to mention a new success, which has been announced today. It is in Saudi Arabia. It is the extension of a big cogeneration plant we have in Saudi Arabia, Tihama project, the extension from 1,000 megawatt to 1,500 megawatt. This project is contracted with Saudi Aramco. So it's an important success.</p>
          <p>In the Services business, I will mention the acquisition of Termika, a leading energy services provider in Chile, allowing us to enter this market in energy efficiency, which is also a promising market in Latin America.</p>
          <p>In Environment, we have pursued our successful commercial development with a new contract in water and wastewater treatment in Australia. All these developments are in line with the three pillars of our strategy: first, accelerate our developments in fast-growing markets; two, optimize and integrate our operations in mature markets; and three, a strengthening of our recurring business lines, which are natural gas infrastructures, energy services, and environment services.</p>
          <p>Now, I would like to give you some feedback from our shareholder general meeting that just finished less than one year &#x2013; one hour ago, sorry. All the resolutions have been approved, among others, the proposed dividend of &#x20AC;1.50 for 2011. You know that our shareholders will have the option to choose between cash or shares for the remaining part of the dividend concerning 2011.</p>
          <p>Our two main shareholders, the French state and the GBL Company, have already committed to take a share option. They also committed for any interim 2012 dividend payment, in case of the success of the transaction. The scrip dividend option is not a change of our dividend policy. The scrip dividend paid in 2012 is clearly linked to the International Power transaction in order to preserve the financial flexibility of the group.</p>
          <p>Regarding the 2011 final dividend, the price issue of the scrip dividend is of &#x20AC;16.43, reflecting the 10% discount to the reference price. Besides, it is worth noting the reduction of the number of directors from 22 to 19, in line with improving continuously our corporate governance.</p>
          <p>Now, I hand over to Isabelle, who will give you some details on our first quarter figures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, G&#xE9;rard, and good morning, everyone.</p>
          <p>So revenues stand at &#x20AC;28.2 billion, with a plus 10.5% growth increase and plus 8.4% organic growth, supported by all the business lines. If you look first of the three major elements on turnover, first of all, the turnover of Energy International grew strongly with a double-digit growth. I will go back to this performance. Revenues for Energy Europe increased by over &#x20AC;1 billion, notably with sale prices reflecting higher supply cost in our retail gas activity and return to average weather conditions in Q1, 2012 in France, impacting positively volumes of gas distributed and sold by five to six terawatt hours. And, third point, Global Gas &amp; LNG benefited from higher commodity prices and volumes.</p>
          <p>So I'd like to &#x2013; to &#x2013; now to focus on business trends and give some indications on the performance of each business line in Q1, 2012. First of all, the Energy International business line benefited from a positive scope effect since we bought 60% of IP last February 2011 and from new assets contribution, especially in fast-growing markets.</p>
          <p>Performance in Latin America improved, principally due to higher average achieved prices in Brazil, driven by inflation escalation and the commissioning of new Brazilian hydro capacity at Estreito. Operation in Chile benefited from the contribution of two new plants, around 300 megawatt hour for both plants, which started operation in H2 2011.</p>
          <p>In North America, market conditions were characterized by low gas prices, mild winter weather; but on the other hand, profitability in the region benefited strongly from a contract settlement of the gas transportation business in Mexico and from the ability to direct more LNG towards Asia.</p>
          <p>In the U.K. market and more globally in Europe, market conditions remain weak which has led to the proposed closure of two plants, but profitability nevertheless benefited from improved wind yield in Italy. In the Middle East, profitability increased from last year with a contribution from Shuweihat 2 in the Emirates and from Al Dur in Bahrain.</p>
          <p>Overall performance in Asia was slightly ahead of 2011, benefiting from first-time contribution from Glow in Thailand. In Pakistan, we reached agreement at the end of March to sell out 18% shareholding in HUBCO and to buy additional 20% of Uch 1. Those transactions are expected to close in May 2012.</p>
          <p>In Australia, despite low electricity spot prices and lack of volatility due to cool summer &#x2013; cold summer weather, our highly contracted generation portfolio contributed to the performance of all the business areas.</p>
          <p>And globally, for the Energy International business line, Q1 EBITDA growth is in line with our expectations. For the Energy Europe business line, as expected, we observed lower load factors for our gasified power plants in Benelux and Germany. These effects have been offset by higher nuclear, coal, and renewable load factors. And as I already mentioned, the first quarter 2012 was also marked by a region to average weather conditions leading to a positive impact of &#x2013; and normalized situation for our regulated gas retail activity in France.</p>
          <p>And <mark type="indiscernible" /> (12:58) for this branch, the gas supply portfolio had a global positive contribution of Q1, in line with our expectations for the year. All in all, we observe a slight increase at EBITDA level for the Energy Europe business line. E&amp;P activities performed well with those positive volume effects and prices effects. Positive volume effects, thanks to the contribution of our Gj&#xF8;a field in Norway and commodity prices were also well oriented.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, our LNG external phase increased with a doubling of the cargos shipped to Asia, from six over Q1 2011 to 12 in Q1 2012. So Q1 performance for Global Gas &amp; LNG business line has been very strong over the first quarter. We don't expect such pace to continue over the rest of the year, especially because the pace of production is not regular over the year. We confirm finally our E&amp;P production for 2012 to be roughly 55 million of barrel oil equivalent.</p>
          <p>The Infrastructure business line benefited from normalized weather conditions and the contribution from the German storage assets acquired last &#x2013; late August 2011. On the other hand, performance has been negatively impacted by lower sales of storage capacity in France. All-in-all, EBITDA of the Infrastructure business line slightly decreased over the first quarter 2012.</p>
          <p>In a tough market environment, Energy Services demonstrated its resilience in <mark type="indiscernible" /> (14:48) environments; the waste activity in Europe was affected by a decrease in volumes treated and unfavorable climate in February.</p>
          <p>Now, let's look at the net debt. Thanks to the sustained cash flow generation over the first quarter, net debt decreased by &#x20AC;0.5 billion to &#x20AC;37.1 billion. Free cash flow was affected by a variation of the working capital requirement of &#x20AC;1.4 billion, which is euro at this time of the year, but it has been emphasized by the cold spell of February.</p>
          <p>I would also highlight the disposal of Eurawasser in Germany and Choctaw in the U.S. which are part of our &#x20AC;10 billion disposal program over 2011 to 2013.</p>
          <p>Now, I'm going to hand over to G&#xE9;rard Mestrallet, who will conclude this presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Isabelle. The accretive impact on net income group share of the IP of full integration for six months contribution allowed us to upgrade our 2012 guidance for a range of &#x20AC;3.7 billion, &#x20AC;4.2 billion versus previously &#x20AC;3.5 billion, &#x20AC;4 billion.</p>
          <p>We confirm the other 2012 financial targets which are not impacted by the transaction and indicative EBITDA of around &#x20AC;17 billion, including around a &#x20AC;600 million positive contribution of our performance program Efficio 2, a growth CapEx of around &#x20AC;11 billion, excluding the IP transaction. Finally, the financing structure of the transaction allows us to reinforce the following targets. Net debt to EBITDA around 2.5 times; an A category rating for the group; and a dividend 2012 at least equal to dividend 2011.</p>
          <p>Before answering your questions, I would like to insist on a few key messages. The solid first quarter results allow us to confirm our 2012 guidance, enhance the net recurring income group share level, post IPR minorities acquisition. Through the full acquisition of IPR, GDF SUEZ will have an increased presence in fast-growing markets, with 40% to 50% of growth CapEx in the medium term. Therefore, it's clear that for us, this operation is an industrial and strategic transaction, allowing GDF SUEZ to become the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (18:12) energy player in the emerging countries.</p>
          <p>We also aim at maintaining our strong financial structure and target, as I mentioned already, &#x20AC;3.7 billion, &#x20AC;4.2 billion net recurring result group share for the year 2012.</p>
          <p>Now, let us leave the floor to your questions. We want to ask the &#x2013; the first one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Lawson Steele from Espirito Santo. Please ask your question in English. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Good afternoon and, yeah, thank you for your time. My question really is, as I see it, there are three main company-specific areas where a potentially new socialist president could attack GDF SUEZ, and I just wanted to know whether you agree on whether these are the areas <mark type="indiscernible" /> (19:59) and b, perhaps what the comments might be. The first one will be French gas tariffs, obviously the current government has tried and failed, but I guess the question there is, could a new government succeed in attacking those tariffs?</p>
          <p>Secondly, will be on the French water contracts despite being municipal in nature, I wondered if the governments could have some sort of impact. And the third would be on French infrastructure, what are the risks there of a change in return presumably if there is a high corporate tax rates, which is one of the things being discussed that would require higher offsetting increase in tariffs to maintain the current return levels of 6.8% for distribution, 7.25% for transmission. So is that likely, so that's my question, please. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, thank you for your questions, first of all, of course, you know, we are exactly in the middle of the two rounds for the Presidential election, so we will not anticipate and comment on the future outcome with a &#x2013; which is all of certain. Simply some remarks, which do not rely on the potential election outcome, on the gas tariff, you know that the previous government had decided in last April to fill the gas tariff for the second part of the year.</p>
          <p>Finally, we decided and so did the other competitors that we have on the gas market to sue the government, to sue the State and the State Council, the Conseil d'Etat. And finally, the State Council decided that we were right and therefore, the government has decided to increase the gas tariff, starting the 1st of January, 2012.</p>
          <p>So, I don't want to anticipate what could happen in the future. But clearly, this formula by which the totality of the supply cost have to be transferred in the tariffs, this formula has been applied by the government and we are now under the &#x2013; I would say the protection of the State Council. This is the case today, we will see on the &#x2013; for the future.</p>
          <p>Secondly, for the French water contract, I would say two elements. We have no &#x2013; we do not anticipate at all a big French, a deflation in order to create a pressure on the water tariff because in France, it is &#x2013; it has always been a municipal responsibility and there is no willingness at all from any political party to withdraw this responsibility from the municipalities to transfer it to the government.</p>
          <p>By the way, it is true that there is a movement, a general movement in France, which has started much before the elections by which the municipalities want to renegotiate their public service delegation. And therefore, some of their water tariffs. That is a trend, that is a trend, which does exist. But so far, the French private companies have been able to manage this transition by protecting most of their margins, even if they have been a little bit impacted.</p>
          <p>Now, on the gas infrastructures, I would say that this regulation has been working correctly for many years. There are permanent evolutions in those gas infrastructures' tariffication system, but this is a very, very stable system, which allows us to extract from our French gas infrastructures an EBITDA of &#x20AC;3 billion. If it has been reduced slightly during the first quarter, it's not at all due to the regulation, but due to the weather and the volumes treated. So we are confident this is not gas infrastructures demand, an area of concern for us in the coming months and years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Just to clarify, you said on the French water contracts, there were two elements. One is just anticipating the law. You didn't see any change in responsibility there <mark type="indiscernible" /> (26:08). On the second one, what you said is a side issue, or was there a second one you forgot to talk about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, the second observation I wanted to make is that generally speaking in France, it is true that many or some municipalities are willing to &#x2013; have been willing in the past to renegotiate the level of the water tariff, and some have succeeded. So this is a trend that will probably continue in the future, but which has nothing to see with the presidential elections.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mrs. Julie Arav from Barclays. Madam, please ask your question in English. You have the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good evening. I have several questions. The first one &#x2013; can we have an update on the Belgium's government proposal to freeze energy tariffs for end customers until year-end? Have you finally frozen your tariff as of 1st of April? And if so what is the expected impact on your EBITDA?</p>
          <p>My second questions concern the infrastructure division. You mentioned a decline in the EBITDA in this division in Q1. Can you elaborate some more on the reasons given that you have benefited from a more favorable climate effect, also a tariff increase and scope effect in Germany? Can we have overall the impact of the lower storage sales, and also can we have an idea of the contribution in your revenue and EBITDA of the storage facility in Germany?</p>
          <p>And last question, more generally, what are your development priorities in the gas business between gas storage, pipeline, LNG, and E&amp;P, please? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the first question, Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Cirelli, the Head of the Energy Europe branch, the new one, will answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. First of all, the prices are frozen starting April 1 until the end of this year. What does it mean in term of EBITDA is difficult to predict today because it will depend on the whole of the real prices at the end of the year. Second, there was a question whether we would be allowed to increase to make the last indexation on April 1 itself. And then, we decided with the others not to do it because of the difficulty with the government. All in all, what we could say today is that what we have done in Belgium, both the freeze of the tariffs until the end of the year, on the current forward and the fact that we have not indexed the prices of April 1 will amount roughly around &#x20AC;100 million for the year all together.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the infrastructure point you mentioned &#x2013; so you're absolutely right that there are two positive effects. First of all, the climate effect, with the return to globally normal weather conditions, which is significant for infrastructure on Q1, with a roughly &#x20AC;20 million effect. We have also, second positive element, we have the impact of the acquisition of Stella with I would say a perimeter effect, positive perimeter effect over Q1, but it is more at this stage more than offsetted by two things. The first one is lower sales of capacity, storage capacities at this date, and we hope that it will be better over the rest of the year. And also a slight increase on costs. So, globally &#x2013; when I say slightly, it's very slightly lower as far as EBITDA is concerned than the last &#x2013; than Q1 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would like to answer to the &#x2013; your questions about our priorities in natural gas infrastructures. I would say that we have the willingness to expand strongly in the natural gas related activities and especially LNG-related activities. The objective is to have a position in the markets where we are present in order to get flexibility and when we have client security of supply, that is the reason for which the gas storage in Europe is so important.</p>
          <p>Gas storage activities are very useful in order to preserve the security of supply in case of a strong winter. That was the case in 2009; that was the case also in February this year. And the gas are also infrastructure tools to increase the flexibility of the natural gas system. So we have invested last year in the gas storage in Germany that Isabelle called Stella, which have a positive contribution, have had a positive contribution last year.</p>
          <p>This year, we have, for example, implemented in several part of the world our know-how in the terminaling in the LNG terminal regasification plants. You know that we have since last year a big LNG terminal in Chile. We have completed last year to the LNG terminal in Fos Cavaou in France in south of France. We also have signed last week with the Indian partners, GAIL, a contract in order to build a floating LNG facility within what we call the fast-track concept and it is exactly the same concept that we are using in our discussions with the Chinese group <mark type="ph" /> Cineyug (33:35) in order to participate with their construction of a floating LNG regasification facility on the Eastern &#x2013; North Eastern Coast of China.</p>
          <p>Now, we &#x2013; since we have in those sectors, in those activity a very strong know-how and strong positions, I will simply mention the fact that we are considering to make an offer for the potential acquisition with partners of the European, German network, a transport network of E.ON or GE, which is for sale and there is a process and we are considering to participate to the process. It is the largest gas transport network in Germany and therefore with our own network in France which is the largest European one, we might have some synergies.</p>
          <p>So, the natural gas infrastructure's is a segment of our activity, it's a full branch in which we have a strong know-how. This contributes to our &#x2013; to the stability of our earnings and we also want to expand our know-how and technology when it is possible, of course at good return and protected return.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Michel Debs from Credit Suisse. Sir, please ask your question in English. You have the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good evening. I have two questions; the first question is at the back of the presentation. The document you send this afternoon, you show us the evolution of your sales and EBITDA, what explaining the scope effects, and FX effect, can you please give us a feel for what the evolution of revenue and EBITDA would have been while normalizing for weather effects, because this is how you give your guidance, on a normalized weather.</p>
          <p>And the second question I have is relative to the Southern Europe. In the documents you explained that you had adverse evolution of business in Italy, the situation doesn't look great in Spain either, yet if my memory serves me right, in February you acquired more shares in a power plant in Spain, so what is your strategy for Southern Europe, are you investing ahead of what you think is a pickup in a few years or are you moving away? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. We will answer to your question about the evolution of sale and scope effect, can you give some elements?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I will give you the two elements in fact, weather impact and the tariff impact also. On the contrary the difference between Q1, 2012 and Q1, 2011, as far as tariffs are concerned. So first of all climate effect, you can consider that the positive climate effect, if you look at Q1, 2012 compared to Q1, 2011 is roughly &#x20AC;95 million on EBITDA. As far as tariffs are concerned, you remember that we had at the same period for last year 2011, a negative impact on tariffs of roughly &#x20AC;50 million, so if you compare year-on-year, you will have a positive impact of &#x20AC;50 million on EBITDA also.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About the Southern Europe and in Spain, you mentioned the acquisition of the shares we had not &#x2013; from AES in the Cartagena plant. In fact, we were already presented &#x2013; of course, we were not interested to expand our presence in the power generation &#x2013; thermal power generation in Spain, and in the case, it was a combined cycle. But we had a tolling agreement, which has been signed in the past by our group, several years ago with AES. It was a tolling agreement, giving us in fact the responsibility of those operations. So we have acquired the shares, and now in order to have the same responsibility, but the possibility to sell it, eventually &#x2013; that would not be done very soon because of the present situation of the market. We do not intend to expand our presence in Spain. We have two CCGT plants, and of course as you know they are not running to satisfactory rates today.</p>
          <p>The situation is different in Italy, where we have a stronger presence, not only in the generation side, but also in the downstream. We have 1 million clients, retail clients, in &#x2013; most of them in natural gas. And our intention is in Italy to benefit from when the time will come to the recovery of the market. So there is a big difference in our approach between Spain, where we have no intention at all to grow and the AES transaction is, I would say, a technical one. And on the other hand, on the other side, Italy, which is in the medium and long-term a promising market for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for those answers. If I may, one quick complementary question on the first two. Regarding the grades in Europe, you mentioned that you were considering the assets that are for sale from E.ON, the Open Europe network &#x2013; open gas network, sorry. If my memory serves me right, you are already a partner of that particular company in Megal and you also have acquired storages in Germany. Is that &#x2013; can you tell us more about the way this can play in terms of option value, and also how you can hedge yourself using those assets if that's possible? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, it is absolutely right that we have a participation of a little bit less than 50% in Megal, which is the big pipe joining the Russian side and the French side. It is the pipe by which most of the Russian gas is going to supply France, the French market. The rest &#x2013; the second part of this 50% is owned by E.ON today, and it is located in this network, but of course, this is an element of our reflection. I cannot say more, but it is clearly an element of potential synergy. This is the point number one.</p>
          <p>Point number two, you are right. If we look at the European map in the natural gas, you'll see that the German market is at the center of Europe. You have not only this big Megal pipe crossing over Germany, you have also the Nord Stream pipe going from Russia to the German coast in the north. This pipe being put under the Baltic Sea, and some of our storages that we have bought last year creates interesting potential synergies with those flows of natural gas going through Central Germany. So you are right, there is a link and synergies in those values, strategic movements, and the logic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Benjamin Leyre from Exane BNP. Sir, please ask your question in English. You have the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good afternoon. Two questions, please. First one not on French politics, but on French regulation in the Infrastructure division. I understand the regulator decided to cut the large remuneration on French distribution already. I understand the regulator will set also new tariffs for transport and LNG import terminals to be effective by early 2013. I wonder in your discussions with the regulator what kind of cut in remuneration you would expect from these two remaining activities.</p>
          <p>And the second question is I would like to hear your most recent views on the need or attempts or intention to withdraw at least momentarily some power generation activities in some countries in Europe, to mothball some plants in light of the further decline <mark type="ph" /> in the team's (44:45) spark spreads that we have at the moment. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois will answer to the question number two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, naturally we are looking at the need or the possibility to mothball some plants. What we can say as different &#x2013; first of all we have during the recent years cut the &#x2013; some megawatts, a lot of megawatts, in particular in Belgium and in the Netherlands, and we will continue to do so this year. There will be some reduction continuing there. And we are for the time looking at all the possibility to mothball some plants, but every plant is different from another. It depends on many things, in particular the ancillary services that you can get in terms of revenues. So we have screening, and when it is &#x2013; when we have the possibility to mothball, we're using it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, about the infrastructure remuneration given by the regulator, you know that the gas transport remuneration has been already published. There is some cut in the remuneration, but also an incentive to create synergies and to cut cost, and those synergies are normally kept by the operator and the discussions for the distribution, which are going on and the scheme &#x2013; some project of the scheme has been already disclosed by the regulator is exactly of the same structure with some cut in the tariff, in the remuneration, in percentage of the regulated asset base, and also an incentive to reduce the cost by letting the savings made to the operators. So it's not a bad evolution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Luis Amusategui from Cygnus. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good evening, everyone. This is Luis from Cygnus. I just &#x2013; I wonder if you could give us some idea of the change in spark spreads and achieved power prices in &#x2013; across different regions for your plants. What kind of change should we expect for this year? And also I wonder if you could quantify a bit more the comments that you just made on the regulatory changes. What do you think the estimate of that impact of this could be overall?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you repeat the second part of your question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Wondering if you could quantify a bit on the regulatory changes that you just mentioned on transmission and distribution, if you have any &#x2013; if you could give us some idea of what kind of impact could this have on your figures?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Firstly, it's difficult to give a quantified position because the final decision is not made and if the regulator is listening carefully on our conversation, he could use this conversation to make it more tough for us in the decisions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry that you have to try...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And about the spark spreads in various part of Europe, can &#x2013; Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, they are not good, but what we can say is that your question was related to 2012 and there will be no significant consequences in 2012 as almost everything has been hedged before the beginning of this year. So for the time being, the fact that the spark spread in particular with the CCS on the gas are not good has no significant consequences on our account for this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But could you give us some idea of what are the differences on the spark spread &#x2013; the current spark spread that you're seeing even if your production is hedged. Are you seeing big differences in the spark?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It depends really. For instance, we had very good spark spread in Italy at the beginning of this year than what we have used to and it has allowed us to take some more additional revenues whereas in the &#x2013; on the copper plate, there is almost the same spark spread all over across the countries. And also in south of Southern Europe like Spain, spark spreads are also very depressed. So basically on gas there is very low spark spread, almost everywhere, but in Italy it was the case at the beginning of this year and in some countries in South Europe on the core, on the contrary spark spread seems &#x2013; are staying at very good level also all across Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. That's very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Martin Young from Nomura. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon to everybody, a couple of questions. The first relates to the EBITDA guidance for the full year. If you look historically, you tend to achieve about one third of your EBITDA in the first quarter of the year. Simply extrapolating the first quarter's performance would take us to about &#x20AC;17.7 billion on that basis. Do you expect now that the guidance for 2012 at the EBITDA level of &#x20AC;17 billion is actually very conservative and if not, why not? And then secondly, thinking about what you were saying about the UK market and turning that to areas of future development, just wondered what your latest thoughts around the new nuclear option in the UK are? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We will not quantify our guidance. We gave now our guidance in terms of net recurring income group share and we've mentioned the assumptions and we mentioned that the range &#x20AC;3.54 billion, the range for our net recurring income group share while that could be translated by adding &#x20AC;200 million if &#x2013; as we think our IP operations is successful. So at this stage, we do not change any element of our full year guidance. We maintain the guidance. We'll consider that the first quarter results allow us to maintain the guidance. We do not qualify it conservative or very conservative. I remind you that when we published our full year guidance and the bridge to explain the difference between what we achieved in 2011 and what we anticipated for 2012. We had mentioned the value steps in order to go from one to the other with of course a general cautiousness about the economic environment and so far we have no reason to change the approach so we maintained so far the approach. Of course, on the occasion of the first half results, we'll make probably more global qualification of our guidance.</p>
          <p>Now about the UK market and your question was about the nuclear. I would simply mention a general I would say philosophy of our group for the nuclear. First you remember, we remind that we had constituted a consortium with Iberdrola and Scottish and Southern. Scottish has left the consortium and we are now 50-50 with Iberdrola. Our intention is to take a decision in 2015, in any case not before 2015. Today due to the situation of the markets, the energy markets in Europe, but also some uncertainly in the markets we consider that a minimum CO2 price, a minimum carbon price is a useful step, but it's not enough.</p>
          <p>And we would suggest to the British authorities to think to a system in which there could be a minimum electricity price for nuclear power generation. We do not said today that it is an absolute necessary condition, but for us &#x2013; but that's not the case for everyone. But for us, a minimum carbon price is not enough and we would not take a decision if the only guarantee which would be given by the authorities would be a minimum carbon price. It is not enough, we need something much more strong as a guarantee simply to envisage our decision.</p>
          <p>And I would simply also remark that even in the States, the totality of the nuclear projects in deregulated states so in merchant environment have been totally cancelled and the remaining nuclear projects in the United States, projects located totally in regulated states. So I think this is a lesson that should be carefully studied.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much, very clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Vincent De Blic from JPMorgan. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good evening. I have three questions, please. The first one is on Energy Europe and your organization, I think in February you told us that you could see up to &#x20AC;200 million of synergies in the midterm, I was wondering whether two-and-half months down the line you are confident in this number or if you are able to envisage a higher number? That's the first question. The second one is on gas storage in France, I would be interested in a bit more detail on the dynamics. You were mentioning some disappointing commercial campaign. Is it just a temporary issue or is it something which is a bit more structural? If you could tell us what's weighing on the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (58:33) that would be great. And the second one was on the wind in France. Iberdrola, I think, is thinking of withdrawing from the market. I was wondering what your strategy was in this country, especially also after the results from the offshore tender? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for your questions. About the branch Energy Europe, I will transfer the question to its CEO, Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Cirelli.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because it was from the number, the level. That's so that we were working on having the first &#x20AC;200 million in the pocket. So no increase of figures, but trying to deliver it as soon as possible, that's the order I received from my CEO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, the second question about the gas storage, it's true that the gas storage activity has been reduced during the recent period because the reservations of the volumes have been less important, but we consider that it is not structural, it is depending on the level of activity of the shippers and there is no anticipation of a structural reduction of the level of volumes of natural gas sold in France in the medium term on the contrary.</p>
          <p>We can also mention that during the month of February which was very, very cold, the storages &#x2013; the gas storages have demonstrated how they were very useful in order to strengthen the security of supply in spite of very high consumption, peaks of consumption and thanks to the gas storages, no French consumer has been impacted in consumption by the very cold period.</p>
          <p>Now, about the wind, of course, we have to distinguish the onshore wind and offshore wind. In onshore wind, we have decided to develop this activity, which is a stable one. You have to know that the price at which the French government buys the electricity is &#x20AC;83 per megawatt hour, it's a good price and reasonable and guarantees the profitability of this &#x2013; of the investments. By the way, we have reached the 1,000 megawatt of capacity installed in January this year and we are therefore, first, the leading operator in France, two times bigger than the second one.</p>
          <p>Now, for the offshore wind, we have constituted a construction with Areva for three sites, out of the four on which we have submitted bids. So with Areva, with Vinci, with <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:02:40) and for the last site, the number four, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:02:48) we were with Siemens for the machine and also always with Vinci and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:02:54).</p>
          <p>Finally, we lost. That's, you know, we had been winning many, many bids in the world, but to win many bids, you have to be ready to lose also many bids, so we lost this case. It's not tragedy. I want also to remind that we have decided to respect absolutely the totality of our investment criteria. So therefore, we have been bidding with the high prices of the electricity, around &#x20AC;200 per megawatt hour. You'll note that it is more than twice as much of the onshore wind. That's the issue would have won the bids. The profitability has been in line with the project we have. This is not a tragedy for us. We regret because we have been working very hard with our colleagues; with the other members of the consortium. It was a good project, and we have submitted.</p>
          <p>Now, as you know, we have decided to invest &#x20AC;11 billion per year. We have around &#x20AC;20 billion of projects every year. So we select and we eliminate many projects, so we would have been prepared to incorporate some of our wind projects within the &#x20AC;11 billion frame, but if there is no offshore wind, there will be something else, either in North America, Latin America, Middle East or Asia, but we will nevertheless invest our &#x20AC;11 billion. So, the pace of growth of GDF SUEZ will not be negatively impacted by this decision, that was what I wanted to mention and this is for us not the end of the story. Offshore wind is a technology, which is &#x2013; can be used in many countries of the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Mr. Bertrand Lecourt from Deutsche Bank. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening. Bertrand Lecourt from Deutsche Bank. First question regarding nuclear in Belgium, can you tell us what the calendar is because you said you will provide an update on your strategy in mid &#x2013; in the middle of the year? What can we expect in terms of news flow by that time, what are the negotiations? What kind of scenario could be completely excluded at the moment? And also, I've read that you could have &#x20AC;200 million costs linked to the stress test. Is that mostly on the CapEx side or operating cost and that's part of your budget?</p>
          <p>And secondly, when you look at the developments of your business, the Eastern European assets or what you call the older Europe in your new split, is not doing that well. We haven't heard much about all these assets <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:06:48) Hungary and other assets that we inherited from the Gaz de France merger or in the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:06:54). What is your strategy? Does it take &#x2013; does it make part of the international goals that you have in mind or not? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Perhaps I will start and Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois could give some elements of answer about the Eastern Europe part. And on a nuclear invention, at nuclear in our strategy, I mentioned that we would make an update of our nuclear strategy at the midyear, at the middle of this year. We assume that at the middle of the year, we will have all the &#x2013; we have on the table all the elements to establish or reassess the strategy in nuclear activity. And because we need inputs from Belgium, from France, from the definitive outcome of the stress test and also we will be helped perhaps that the decisions of the British government to know if there is room for us or not at all. And also decisions coming from other countries that we could look at the potential opportunity in nuclear such as Brazil, for example, or perhaps other countries.</p>
          <p>So normally, we think that we will have all the elements at the middle of the year, especially in Belgium, why the new government has explained that you would have to take a final decision to prepare a plan to supply Belgium in &#x2013; with power and the question is very simple, is it possible for Belgium to be correctly supplied to have a minimum security of supply for power without the three oldest nuclear plants.</p>
          <p>In the past, several reports have been written at the request of the government, especially the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:09:40) report to answer this question and all the previous answers were consistent. The answer was yes, the Belgium needs absolutely the supply of the three oldest nuclear plants to secure its supply of electricity. So I don't know if the new report will conclude differently, but we are waiting for this &#x2013; those decisions. I'll simply mention that the &#x2013; for us, we will analyze any possible decision as a clear investment project and this investment to increase the time life of the plants, one, two, or three plants. This investment has to find its profitability and be in line with our own criteria.</p>
          <p>About the stress test, you mentioned &#x20AC;200 million; first, it is CapEx, it is CapEx and though it's a low level of CapEx because this have to be applied to the seven nuclear plants. Of course, the measures concerning the security concern the totality of our nuclear fleet and therefore concern the totality of the seven nuclear plants. And as you see, it is a low level compared to a figure which has been given publicity by EDF of France. It is &#x20AC;10 billion which has been mentioned by EDF for, of course, a bigger fleet of more than 55 nuclear plants, but per plant the level of CapEx because we are speaking about CapEx, the level of CapEx is much lower because simply the &#x2013; all the requirements that have been requested by the nuclear authorities in Europe, they are the same in every country, all the equipment, the necessary equipments have been in the past already built in Belgium because they have been requested by the Belgium Nuclear Authority.</p>
          <p>And just on Europe, Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so &#x2013; thank you, G&#xE9;rard. Regarding Eastern Europe, situation is very different and diverse comparing country-to-country. There are countries in the very difficult situation where we do not see for the time being any possibility to increase our footprint or the profitability will not be present like Hungary, for instance. And there are countries where they are in better &#x2013; good &#x2013; a better shape and that our footprint is already very significant and we'd like to continue to grow, particular Poland is one of this country and Romania could also be part of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just before perhaps the last question as I understand, Isabelle Kocher would like to give a precision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, maybe two points I would like to go back to, the first one is you ask me the impact of a tariff freeze of Q1 2011. I said roughly &#x20AC;50 million. It is in fact we have the specific figures in this full-year 2011 presentation. It is &#x20AC;73 million, first point. The second point when you try to forecast 2012 EBITDA level, you are perhaps looking to take into account the fact that our Q1 2012, we got in fact an exceptional level of production as far as E&amp;P is concerned, the 16 million barrel oil equivalent. It is in fact the result of negotiation we had with the Norway authorities and the result of this discussion is more production over Q1 and less over the rest of the year. So globally, I repeat, we maintain the 55 million barrel of oil equivalent as the forecast we have for 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (1:15:09).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please put your question in French. Over to you. Put your question in French, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the International Power transaction is concerned, I would like to know whether there is a date for a hearing for the other shareholders in International Power. Do you already have a date for that hearing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do we know exactly today already the date the future General Assembly Meeting, <mark type="ph" /> adjourn (1:16:01) of International Power which it will have to vote and to decide on the scheme of arrangement. And the General Assembly Meeting will take place in mid-June and normally, the closing will take place 15 days after the general assembly meeting. But we have in the meantime the court &#x2013; a court in the U.K. will have formally to approve the decision. So for the &#x2013; it is anticipated that the court takes a decision 15 days after the AGM and so the closing will normally take place mid-July. But of course, we have not in totality in our hands the scheduled timeframe because the decision of the court, there is no uncertainty on the decision itself. But we have some uncertainty on the dates and it is normally a short delay, it is around two weeks delay, but of course, it's not our decision, it's the decision of the court.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand that it was &#x2013; this was the last question. So I would like to thank you. We thank everyone for your presence and I wish you a good evening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentleman, this concludes this conference call. Thank you for your participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>