<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1217555" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-03-05</date>
    <companies>
      <company>64294</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">G&#xE9;rard Mestrallet, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">G&#xE9;rard Lamarche, Executive Vice-President, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Cirelli, Vice-Chairman and President</participant>
      <participant id="3">G&#xE9;rard Lamarche</participant>
      <participant id="4">Emmanuel Turpin</participant>
      <participant id="5">G&#xE9;rard Mestrallet</participant>
      <participant id="6">Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Cirelli</participant>
      <participant id="7">Henri Ducr&#xE9;</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, good morning. Thank you for being with us today. With Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Cirelli and G&#xE9;rard Lamarche, we are very pleased to welcome you for the presentation of the Annual Results of GDF SUEZ. The First Annual Results since the merger of the Group.</p>
          <p>We met last November for the Investor Day, devoted to a better understanding of our new organization, and the dynamics of our business model. 2008 has of course been an important year for our Group with the implementation of the merger, between SUEZ and Gaz de France, leading to the immergence of a world leader in the energy sector. As you know 2008 has also been marked at least for the quarter, by the sharp downturn in economic conditions, leading in particular to a sharp fall in energy prices.</p>
          <p>I have five messages for you in this introduction, before handing over to G&#xE9;rard and Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois. First message, our Group has experienced a strong growth of its results in 2008, and we've exceeded all our targets for the year 2008.</p>
          <p>All business lines and geographic areas have contributed strongly to the growth in our business. Secondly, we're confident in the long-term outlook of the markets where we operate. Our industrial ambitions remain unchanged in spite of a short-term economic context that is less favorable than early in 2008.</p>
          <p>Thirdly, our Group displayed great pro-activity right from the beginning of the downturn with the launch of our new performance plan, Efficio, &#x20AC;1.8 billion by 2011 and strengthening our cash position. So we're coming before you fully transparently with the mid and long-term objectives that we view as coherent and realistic with the current market conditions.</p>
          <p>Fourthly, we are continuing to implement our industrial strategy, which is on track. Our ambitions in the gas and nuclear sectors are more than ever reaffirmed. And lastly, let me say that our strong business model is aimed at creating a sustainable value, allowing the Group to create value over the long-term. This concept of a dynamic balance, which is the heart of our business model, is aimed at meeting the challenges of the company.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to present the good results of 2008, which are sharply up across our indicators as you can see. EBITDA is up 10.7%, as compared to a target of 10.7. And in spite of the crisis that impacted the last quarter, we were on target. Organic growth excluding scope effects is plus 12.5%, current operating income is up 9.4%, and net income up 13%. This latter, of course, benefited from the capital gains from the sale of Distrigas and Fluxys, as part of the implementation of the remedies linked to the merger.</p>
          <p>Thanks to this excellent performance an ordinary dividend of &#x20AC;1.40 will be proposed by the Board, decided yesterday at the shareholders' meeting of the 4th of May 2008. That's up 11% over the dividend paid in respect of 2007. And that's consistent with our commitments and a down payment of &#x20AC;0.80 per share was paid out last November.</p>
          <p>So the balance of the ordinary dividend will be paid after the shareholders' meeting and in addition an exceptional dividend of &#x20AC;0.80 will be put to the same shareholders' meeting with the possibility offered to shareholders of opting for a cash or a share payment for this exceptional dividend.</p>
          <p>During 2008, we continued to implement our industrial development strategy. We've invested 11.8 billion net of the sessions relative to Distrigas as part of our program of 30 billion net investments for the period 2008, 2010. This includes our tangible and intangible investments of maintenance and development as well as targeted acquisitions, such as NAM in exploration production in the Netherlands, or FirstLight in hydropower generation in the US.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to the performance of the Group by business line and geographic area. The Group generated sales of &#x20AC;83 billion. That's up of the order 17%, and all business lines contributed to this sustained growth in our business in spite of scope or exchange rate effects, which were sometimes unfavorable.</p>
          <p>We benefited in particular from a price environment that was on the whole buoyant for the first nine months of the year, and also the climate was more favorable in 2008 than in 2007 in France. So this balance is also reflected in the broad geographic areas where we operate.</p>
          <p>Our domestic markets, France and Belgium that account for 53% of our business are up close on 15%. North America posts a growth level of 8%, in spite of the decline of the dollar over the year. And lastly rest of Europe and rest of the world represent, as we announced, significant growth drivers, because in these two areas we are recording growth of plus 20 and plus 24% respectively.</p>
          <p>I won't dwell on this fine performance achieved in 2008. G&#xE9;rard will return to that in a moment. Let's look to the future. In spite of the deterioration of the current economic climate, our belief is that the economic downturn that we are experiencing in no way changes the long-term trends for the energy or environment market that benefit from growth drivers. These are as follows. As you know the structural growth for world energy demand. The long-term trends of the International Energy Agency indicates that global demand should grow by plus 8 -- 1.8% per year between now and 2030, and demand for electricity is expected to double between now and 2030. We believe that energy efficiencies will accompany the growth in demand.</p>
          <p>CapEx requirements in order to replace aging infrastructure, but also to meet new needs, and by way of illustration, the need for additional power production capacity between now and 2020 is of 340 gigawatts, that's three times the French production base. It's important to note what's happening in areas of the world that are seeking to put in place support plans. We see that governments increasingly &#x2013; are increasingly including our business infrastructure in the stimulus plans that are being put in place.</p>
          <p>Energy and infrastructure are key in all these plans, be it in Europe, in the US or in China, as we've just seen. So there's a return to meeting key requirements in the field of energy and the environment, and this is very encouraging for the mid-term as well as for our presence in these stimulus packages.</p>
          <p>Another growth driver is the need to ensure security of supply in energy in a context of resources becoming scarcer, more and more removed from centers of consumption, and we saw with the Russian/Ukrainian crisis, how this is at the heart of concerns.</p>
          <p>Combating global warming, this is a requirement for all countries, and lastly developing market regulations, setting a new frame for the various players. So, it's on this long-term vision of our markets that our industrial strategy is based, and our industrial investment program amounting to &#x20AC;30 billion over three years.</p>
          <p>And before Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois speaks to that, let me just remind you of the broad lines of this plan that we presented at our Investor Day last November, 100 megawatt of installed power capacity by 2013, increasing our capacity for the transmission of gas and re-gasification capacity worldwide. So with its strong presence across the energy value chain, our Group has a diversified and balanced business mix. This business model that is simple and strong ensures our resistance in the face of the crises. We are confident as to the growth prospects of the Group over long-term and the relevance of our strategy and our positioning represents our greatest strength in the face of the downturn.</p>
          <p>Let me just perhaps recall some of the facts that have impacted our sector for several months now. Firstly, the price of oil and the price anticipations for oil have declined. The forward curves that you can see going forward have shifted downwards by about $50 a barrel. You can see this on the chart, on the right hand side, the three parallel lines with an ellipse. The orange line represents the price anticipations at the end of July 2008, at the time of the merger about six months ago. The red curve, end of October, that was around the time of the Investor Day. And the blue line, the forward curve for price is at the end of February 2009.</p>
          <p>The price of gas being directly correlated to the oil price, our global gas and LNG business line that combines the activity of an independent producer in E&amp;P, with a gas supply portfolio in LNG with stored quantities to allow for arbitrage and periods of strong demand. This is directly impacted by this trend. And financially, we estimate a decline in the contribution to this &#x2013; of this branch to EBITDA between the order of 1.5 billion between 2008, 2009.</p>
          <p>2008 was exceptional for the results of this business line. Conversely this trend strengthens our assumption of a breakeven EBITDA in 2009 for our gas sale activity at the regulated price. That is that for 2009 we expect to pass on our costs, whereas in 2008 in the results that we presented we suffered a deficit in terms of selling gas at the regulated price in France of the order of &#x20AC;700 million.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the price of electricity. The second chart illustrates the base price in Germany, very correlated to the prices in France and Belgium and Holland, as well as the forward prices since July 20, 2008.</p>
          <p>Electricity price anticipated stood up well to the middle of the fourth quarter and then declined sharply between October 2008 and February 2009. We have a prudent hedging policy and this price drop will have the limited effect on 2008, 2009. The effect is not totally nil, particularly for the hydraulic portion of our European output that is sold on the wholesale market.</p>
          <p>So in the face of this downturn and the difficulties encountered by banks and the financial markets, we responded vigorously back in the autumn of last year.</p>
          <p>As of September, we firstly decided to launch a new performance plan, Efficio, that's &#x20AC;1.8 billion by 2011 and Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois will return to that optimization program in a few moments.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we've decided to strengthen the selectivity of our investments. By way of an example, you've no doubt noted our -- that we pulled out of the Belene project in Bulgaria or that of Calaca in the Philippines.</p>
          <p>The current situation leads us to be even more demanding in terms of our profitability criteria, the profitability risk ratio, we have many projects and we can afford to be very selective and only choose the best.</p>
          <p>Third decision is our liquidity. We've decided to strengthen the Group's cash position and extend our debt maturities by the issuance of a bond for approximately &#x20AC;10 billion under good conditions to ensure the funding for our industrial investment program. I believe we can say that we were the western company that was the most responsive and the fastest on the bond markets.</p>
          <p>We also believe that given the current difficult times, we must increase still further our communication efforts in order to explain and share with you in full transparency what our vision is, as we've always done. Investor Day was a part of that approach and today we're presenting targets that we view as consistent and realistic for the short to mid-term.</p>
          <p>In 2011, the end of our Efficio program, and as we did with the merger, we're presenting targets for this three year plan. The Group is setting as a target an EBITDA between 17 and &#x20AC;18 billion range as compared to 13.9 billion in 2008.</p>
          <p>This target is supported by our industrial development program and our market view. It is secured by the streamlining of the Group through the implementation of the Efficio performance plan, 1.8 billion. Of course, we maintain our strong A credit rating target. And we confirm our dynamic and competitive shareholder remuneration policy that you're familiar with, that we decided to issue the ordinary and the exceptional dividends agreed last night by the Board. These are based on commodity forward prices and trends as G&#xE9;rard will indicate in a few moments.</p>
          <p>On the basis on the same 2009 assumptions and in spite of the downturn of 1.5 billion that I mentioned for the LNG branch, the 2009 EBTIDA will be higher than the 2008 EBITDA. These targets based on the implementation of our industrial plan.</p>
          <p>Let me just give you the three pillars that support this program, set in hand in 2008 that will be reviewed by Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois. The reinforcement across the entire energy value chain, both in power -- energy power, as well as in the upstream gas midstream.</p>
          <p>And thirdly, the deployment of our global leadership in three sectors, recall our business model, LNG, independent power production projects and energy services. Lastly, energy environment synergies that we are developing very successfully at the moment in the Middle East, in Oman and Bahrain.</p>
          <p>We have a portfolio of projects that is identified and firmly underway with secured funding for the next two years, which should feed through to the growth of our EBITDA as of 2009-2010.</p>
          <p>This is an important point that we wish to stress, because our investment effort as it's based essentially on organic growth rather than acquisitions, very few acquisitions. We constantly have CapEx that is linked to infrastructure construction projects or power plant projects that are not completed. So our investment effort doesn't always produce its effects immediately in our profitability benchmarks, and market operators don't always include those in our value.</p>
          <p>The contribution of EBITDA to our CapEx in 2008 is, if fact, lower than &#x20AC;400 million, whereas our prime investments of that year have rates of return between 8 and 17%. The future growth of our EBITDA will, of course, be rooted in today's industrial momentum. Let me illustrate this industrial strategy through two examples.</p>
          <p>And just to remind you that J&#xE9;r&#xF4;me Tolot announced a couple of days ago not only the launch of this new brand Cofely replacing the Cofathec and Elyo brands, but especially and above all the merger of the activities of the Energy Services business. It's the follow-up of the SUEZ Gaz de France merger, replicated in the various entities in France, Italy, the UK and Belgium to mention those.</p>
          <p>So Cofely is the standard bearer of our Energy Service activities. It's a major operation in its own right affecting 36,000 staff, 8 billion in revenues in 2008 and is a European leader in energy and environmental efficiency services, will be present in 15 countries and representing a big half of the Energy Services business line of GDF SUEZ. So it's a major operation, highly visible, which the Group is now establishing in 15 countries.</p>
          <p>A word on the transactions concluded with Eni in May and E.ON in December. These transactions have allowed us to increase our industrial presence in two major European countries without a cash outlay. The Eni agreement covers the sale of our majority stake in Distrigas and the acquisition of gas and electricity assets.</p>
          <p>The E.ON agreement involves the exchange of gas-fired plants and nuclear energy drawing rights between Belgium and Germany for about 1,700 megawatts. These agreements are important in two respects for GDF SUEZ.</p>
          <p>GDF SUEZ continues to expand its major positions across European markets, expansion of the Group in Germany, expansion of the Group in Italy, and moreover allows us to scrupulously adhere to the commitments made to the European Commission as part of the merger, and with the Belgium government for the Pax Electrica II, illustrating our approach in favor of free competition in Europe. In other words, we have been able to transform what seemed to be at the outset a dual constraint into a dual opportunity for expansion, consistent with our strategic vision.</p>
          <p>Second illustration that I'd like to expand on is that our nuclear ambition that represents the long-term strategy of the Group in terms of a balanced energy mix. We have four strong assets. Historic position, the Belgium plan developed on a par with France. The first high pressurized reactor was built in Belgium. We have a strong position on the domestic base; 6,000 megawatts of nuclear installed capacity in Europe, know-how and skills right along the value chain construction, a role of architect, designer, operating and maintenance with a high level of security and availability right through to decommissioning.</p>
          <p>Growth based on partnerships with the EDF, our power plant at Tihange, Tricastin, with Iberdrola to take part in the development of new power plants in the UK. Nuclear power plants with a joint venture will be a candidate for the purchase of nuclear sites in the UK. Partnership with the Atomic Energy Commission for R&amp;D, partnership with TOTAL and Areva for a nuclear power plant project in the UAE. Partnership with Areva for our stake in the Georges Besse II enrichment plant to secure our supply of enriched uranium.</p>
          <p>What is our strategy to operate the existing nuclear facilities? As long as planned by the legal framework with the priority on nuclear safety, increase the production of nuclear power in Europe and in the world on the basis of national policies.</p>
          <p>Of course, we seek to maintain in the long-term the share of nuclear power 20% in a balanced production mix, and continue to operate third generation nuclear power plants by 2020 developing on the key markets in Europe and outside.</p>
          <p>We also want to use the business driver represented by engineering, Tractebel Engineering and the energy -- engineering services, offering nuclear specialty skills to drive the Group's expansion and participate in major nuclear projects for external clients.</p>
          <p>As you know, we are not proponents of the all-nuclear solution. This must be supplemented within the portfolio of other energies, offering the necessary industrial flexibility in particular for peak power demand or to smooth the effects of the commodity price fluctuations. The key word is balance, ensuring the long-term strength and flexibility.</p>
          <p>France is a natural priority for the Group's growth in nuclear power. It is an unquestionable asset for France to have two nuclear players, France and abroad. The announcement of a second EPR in France is excellent news for the power supply in France and EDF -- GDF SUEZ is proud to be involved in the second with EDF, whose skills are recognized.</p>
          <p>We welcome the support of the French state that has acknowledged our will to build and operate France's third EPR, when that is decided by the French authorities.</p>
          <p>And let me end this introduction by reminding you that our business model is robust for creating value over the long-term. It is simple; our prime asset is a diversified energy mix balanced across regions that are subject to different cycles. With a position at the heart of Europe, GDF Suez is at the heart of Europe with a very strong commercial position and an energy mix that is fully flexible and diversified, one of the most efficient in Europe.</p>
          <p>Second strength, our world leading skill sets making us different from the others. In LNG and gas supply we are one of the major purchasers of gas worldwide. And through our gas plants, we can ensure the convergence of gas and electricity, and like no other player.</p>
          <p>Leadership in the independent power production in key areas with a recognized position, number one in the Middle East, number one in Brazil, presence in Southeast Asia and in North America.</p>
          <p>Lastly, leadership in Energy Services at a time when energy efficiency is key for the stimulus plans and packages. We're at the heart of that thanks to this leadership and this business line that is fully devoted to energy efficiency. So, three areas that offer long-term solution to today's energy challenges as well as tomorrow's, without, of course, forgetting the synergies between energy and environment, particularly useful at the present time.</p>
          <p>So GDF SUEZ offers a unique profile through its global presence, it's presence across the energy value chain, presence in the environment, a unique set of know-how, skills, industrial positions. This is a great asset to continue our expansion and continue to create value over the long-term.</p>
          <p>Over now to Gerard Lamarche.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good morning to everyone. It's my pleasure today to present to you the first annual results of GDF SUEZ, which underscore the robustness of our business model. The major highlights are as follows, a solid set of 2008 results in the context of a commodities market where the prices were particularly favorable for the first nine months of the year.</p>
          <p>Sustained cash flow generation, which has enabled us to sustain our investment program as well as providing high dividends to shareholders, while maintaining a strong balance sheet, which has been strengthened by increased liquidity over the past few months. Our 2008 targets have been exceeded and I shall conclude by talking about our medium-term objectives and our 2009 objectives that G&#xE9;rard Mestrallet referred to a few moments ago.</p>
          <p>Before presenting the 2008 results, I'd like to recall very briefly a number of key principles concerning the pro forma accounts. The income statement and the balance sheet, 2007-2008, are done on the basis of the merger starting on the 1st of January 2007. The provisional purchase price accounting, 40 billion, has been slightly restated on the -- compared to what you were told at the Investor Day and a depreciation announced of 479 million has been taken in 2008.</p>
          <p>I would recall that we have until June of 2009 to finalize the opening balance sheet. SUEZ ENVIRONNEMENT is integrated globally, but of course we only have 35% of its income -- its net income in our net income. The impact of the divestment of Distrigas, SPE and Fluxys has been put into a specific line of the income statement so as to make it clearly -- make it clearer.</p>
          <p>Okay. Let's talk about the figures. The pro forma 2008 results are very good as you can see on this slide, which show a double digit growth of the main indicators. Revenues 83 billion, up by 17.5%, EBITDA almost 900 million, up by 12.5%, current operating income 8.6 billion, plus 9.4%. Our net income is 6.5 billion is also a double-digit increase of 13%.</p>
          <p>Net capital spending &#x20AC;11.8 billion, these are in line with the envelope we announced of &#x20AC;30 billion of capital spending over three years. They include a 10.5 billion of industrial CapEx, 4.9 billion of acquisitions and 3.6 billion of divestments.</p>
          <p>Net debt 28.9 billion gives us a low debt, 46.1% gearing, and is only two years of EBITDA. The balance sheet remains very sound, therefore. The dividend proposed to the Annual General Meeting on the 4th of May is &#x20AC;1.40 per share, is an increase of 11.1%.</p>
          <p>EBITDA up by 10.7% gross and 12.5% in organic growth, and this group clearly shows that we benefited in 2008 from a very favorable commodity pricing situation, where the price of Brent in the first nine months of the year was &#x20AC;111 (sic) [$111] per barrel, and then in the last three months of the year $55 per barrel rather. So that's an average over 12 months of $97 per barrel.</p>
          <p>The consensus on the Brent today is fairly a wide range, but the average is around $50 per barrel for 2009. And this basically is what is behind the very strong growth of our businesses in Global Gas, LNG and Energy Europe &amp; International. Particularly, in the United States and Brazil, you will see the considerable increase in Global Gas &amp; LNG, and Energy Europe &amp; International.</p>
          <p>The -- however, selling gas in France has suffered from the effect that the regulated price of gas has not increased. The delay in price adjustments are now 1.6 billion, that's an increase up from 679 million. So that's a shortfall of &#x20AC;679 million in the figures you see for France.</p>
          <p>Our results are existent given our portfolio of businesses, which make it possible to share the risk profiles and returns. Energy businesses have a portfolio, which are balanced in themselves, gas and power, upstream and downstream. Between businesses, which are regulated or contractualized, and energy output, which is more directly exposed to markets. These businesses are also in different geographic locations as you can see on this slide.</p>
          <p>Let's have a look at the business lines in a little more detail. There's -- I shall be fairly brief here, there's a lot of information on these slides. And if there are any specific questions you have then we'll be happy to try and answer them.</p>
          <p>Energy France, excellent industrial performance, which has been held back by the delay in price adjustments. Revenues is up by almost 17%. That's a strong growth, 14.457 billion, whereas EBITDA is down by 40%. Let me explain this.</p>
          <p>First of all, this reflects the price of markets for energies, which are very strongly up. The volumes of gas in France, of natural gas have increased, because of better weather conditions, 294 terawatt hours. That's an increase of 1.6% compared to 2007. GDF SUEZ, however, maintains a market share of about 95% for individual consumers, and about 85% for businesses. These two sectors have been open to competition since 2007 and 2004 respectively.</p>
          <p>The increase in the supply of gas, however, has not, however, been fully passed on in these prices. And that explains the &#x20AC;246 million of EBITDA, which is down in gross terms by 3 -- 33%. And that means a delay in price adjustments of 679 million. The level of capital spending for France is 1 billion, including developments in wind energy and the further developments of CCGT in Montoir, Cycofos, and Combigolfe, the commissioning of these facilities will be between the mid 2009 and 2010.</p>
          <p>Now we hope that -- we hope we will be able to pass on the increase in our raw material prices in the rates, which should go down in April. Given our discussions with the state, it seems realistic to assume that the delay in price adjustments will remain at 1.6 billion. It won't increase, whereas that will not be the case for the first quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Let me look at Benedelux, a year which has been impacted by non recurrent events. So revenues are strongly up by 19% for the same reasons that we saw for France, increase in conserve energy prices within Belgium. And increase in transmission and distribution expenses of 55% which are passed through of course. The average selling price for industrial customers that represents 50 -- 55% of our revenue and an important part of our margins, apart from passed through elements, went up from &#x20AC;52 per megawatt hour in 2007 on average, to &#x20AC;62 per megawatt hour on average in 2008.</p>
          <p>Now, as you can see on this table, this is not reflected entirely in EBITDA, which is up by only 2.2%, 1.752 billion. This is due to the following reasons.</p>
          <p>First of all, the passed through elements, transport and distribution, price increases, increase in production costs and lower allocation of CO2 and an increase in the price of fuels, coal for instance and gas.</p>
          <p>As well as the lower availability rates of our nuclear power plants in 2008, which was 84.8% on average in 2008, given the scheduled shutdowns for 2008, compared to 90.3% in 2007. And that of course has led to a fall in power sold, minus 5.6% compared to 2007.</p>
          <p>The negative trends in current operating income is impacted by non-recurring elements. We wrote back provisions in 2007 for 165. But we also have a higher level of appreciation. CapEx of 1 billion, the commissioning of the Wilhelmshaven and Dutch and Belgian Flevo and Sigma power stations.</p>
          <p>I would also recall that 2008 does not take into account the exchange of assets with E.ON, which concerns 1.7 gigawatt hours and that of course is almost a neutral, positive on the income, slightly but that's for 2009.</p>
          <p>What about 2009 then? The increase in locked margins will continue given our gradual hedging policy over three years. Our hedging ratio is 91% for 2008 and higher to 60% for 2010.</p>
          <p>The rate of availability of our nuclear power plants should return to a normal level, close to 90%. There is one small power station which will be commissioned in 2009. The effect will be &#x20AC;37 million of contribution on EBITDA in 2009.</p>
          <p>Energy Europe, we have accelerated our industrial development which fosters sustained growth. Activities in energy and Europe (sic) [Energy Europe] are up by 19.1%, EBITDA is up by 9 -- up to 844. This is due to growth in Western Europe, plus 61 million to 126 million. Thanks to the Teesside commissioning, and a good performance of electric power in Spain.</p>
          <p>Growth in Italy, &#x20AC;257 million of EBITDA during the year, linked to the commissioning of two combined cycle stations, Vado Ligure and Leni which contribute 50 million to that 62, as well as trading margins on the local auxiliary power market.</p>
          <p>Growth is lower in Eastern Europe, plus 2.6%. The good performance in electricity partially offset by the partial pass-through of gas prices in Slovakia and Romania where that is still a system of regulated gas prices. In terms of capital spending, 1.9 billion, that covers the Virtual Power Plant that we bought from Eni 1.2 billion. And 2009 should see an increase because of the commissionings and the acquisitions we made last year.</p>
          <p>Energy International, very strong growth in buoyant markets, 2008 was an excellent year for Energy International after very good 2007 results, as you will remember. EBITDA is 1.8 billion now, that's an organic growth of almost 10%. In North America organic growth is 12%, thanks to level of prices charged in LNG USA on the NYMEX, where gas increased from $6.86 per MMBtu to over $9 for MMBtu in 2008.</p>
          <p>In South America organic growth was 15%, that's basically due to trading gains on the local power market and that's basically in Brazil that that happened. Asia, Africa and the Middle East saw a fall of 6% of EBITA, that's basically due to partial pass-through in prices in Thailand of the supply prices.</p>
          <p>We are accelerating the development of this particular business line with CapEx of 3.3 billion, 1.3 billion for the construction of major hydroelectric dams in Brazil, also developments in the Map Ta Phut facility in Thailand, which is one of the major petrochemical facilities in the world. These facilities will be commissioned in 2009.</p>
          <p>We also of course in 2008 acquired FirstLight in December, and 30% of Senoko in September 2008, which will be integrated proportionately, and remember too Ponte de Pedra in Brazil, which we acquired in May 2008 and which cost us &#x20AC;241 million.</p>
          <p>What can we expect for this business line in 2009? The effect of our capital spending in acquisitions will produce their full year effects and that should increase our results in spite of the fall of volumes of LNG in the United States, and the fact that we won't have the exceptional trading margins in 2009 that we had in 2008.</p>
          <p>Global Gas and LNG, 2008 was an absolutely exceptional year for this particular business line. It was of course highlighted by the sharp increase in hydrocarbon prices, 23% on average. The price of Brent up from 73 to $97 per barrel, and 81% increase in natural gas in the NBP up from 14.5 to &#x20AC;26.2 per megawatt hour.</p>
          <p>The Exploration and Production business was up by 723 million in terms of EBITDA. EBITDA on that business line is $1.808 billion. A third of this is due to the increase in production. Our hydrocarbon increase was up by 20%, 51 million barrels of oil equivalent. Two thirds of that is due to the increase in margins. Thanks to the increase in average sales price, plus 37% for gas and 27% for liquids.</p>
          <p>Then there's trading, supplies, LNG trading, sales to major accounts. This business was able to lock into trading gains in various parts and traded 796 terawatt hours of gas. The result was, therefore, up by &#x20AC;600 million and attained &#x20AC;1.780 billion. Thanks to unprecedented trading opportunities for LNG, 38 terawatt hours, an increase in volume sold, 17 terawatt hours. That's plus 11% of sales to key accounts and trading margins, thanks to our trading and our inventory effects.</p>
          <p>Investments are, of course, considerable in 2008 with continuing developments in E&amp;P with the Gjoa project in Norway, &#x20AC;339 million which will be commissioned in 2009 -- in 2010 rather than in 2009. The acquisitions of Nam &#x20AC;768 million in the North Sea, which will be integrated in the 1st of October 2008, and the Nogat Company, which is a pipeline company between the various gas fields in the North Sea, &#x20AC;232 million that cost us, and will be consolidated on the 30th of December.</p>
          <p>Also gas supply contracts for Eni in Italy, 4 billion cubic meters over three years -- per year over 20 years. And in Germany, an option for 2.5 billion cubic meters over 11 years. For 2009, we should see similar levels of EBITDA in 2007, given to our medium-term sensitivity to the fall in oil prices, &#x20AC;20 million per $1 of barrel cost. Short-term sensitivities with -- which add to the stock effects, and lower trading gains, contribution of NAM and Nogat in a full year &#x20AC;200 million, and we have hedged our positions in July on oil.</p>
          <p>Infrastructures. Infrastructure, characterized by very robust results because they are basically regulated businesses. Increase in revenue can be explained by better weather conditions, by the introduction on the 1st of July 2008 of a new price of access to distribution infrastructure for 2008 to 2012, by an increase in storage capacity subscribed by third parties, plus 3.9 terawatt hours, and increase in subscriptions to the transmission network in France, as well as the commissioning of the gas combined cycle facilities.</p>
          <p>The progression in EBITDA is in line with regulation, which ensures depreciation and remuneration of the rated asset base.</p>
          <p>Level of investment is 1.9 billion. We spent &#x20AC;110 million for the commissioning of the Fos Cavaou terminal, which will come on line in June of this year, 250 million in storage and &#x20AC;140 million in international infrastructure. For 2009, no surprise the results should be in line with the regulation, which is -- which will see an increase in the rated asset base of more than 3%.</p>
          <p>Energy Services, a very good order book and a good development of recovering energy efficiency businesses. Energy Services had an excellent 2008, an increase of more than 9% in its revenue, and margins of around 4.2%, that's stable. Sales were very strong throughout the year. And 2009, therefore, gives us confidence. There will be pluses and minuses, minus in industry, plus in terms of services.</p>
          <p>Sales developments in Services is up very sharply compared to 2007, some major standard bearing projects here, the contract for the London Olympics, CRE2 or the Nuon CCGT. Orders were similar to 2007 in spite of the slowdown in the fourth quarter. They are higher by 15% in Engineering.</p>
          <p>Capital spending, &#x20AC;600 million that's an increase compared to last year because of tuck-in products, the Olympic Games and the CPCU.</p>
          <p>SUEZ ENVIRONNEMENT, a good performance in line with our guidance. You had the presentation of SUEZ ENVIRONNEMENT yesterday from Jean-Louis Chaussade, so I won't dwell on the figures he gave you yesterday.</p>
          <p>Let's come back to the results of the Group. The next two slides I think show the reconciliation between EBITDA and net income. First of all, on this slide the impact on depreciation and amortization, 711 million. There was a write-back of the provision in 2007, which was not necessary anymore. And that in -- that shows the -- that is an illustration of the amortization figure.</p>
          <p>The amortization linked to purchase price accounting will be 479 in 2008. That should fall gradually for 2010, 200 million only in 2014. An income of &#x20AC;555 million on mark-to-market, a charge of 811 million for various asset impairments, basically the mark-to-market of our Gas Natural Securities and depreciation of one of our plants in the UK, and the result of divestments, basically the sale of Chehalis.</p>
          <p>Financial result of 1.6 billion cost of net is up, because of basically the rise in interest rates. The average borrowing cost is about 4.9% and the tax rate is up by &#x20AC;480 million. This is because of the disappearance of the deferred tax assets of 2007. The effective tax rate is 26.8%.</p>
          <p>So much for the results, strongly up as you can see. What about cash flow? In 2008 we had cash flow from operations of about 13 billion, partially used to finance the variation in working capital requirements of 3.1 billion. This is due to the increase in our business of course, the increase in the commodity prices, which has had an arithmetic impact upon our stocks and our receivables. And the existence of margin calls for Gas Elize 700 million. These margin calls are a cash outflow initially, but that will return to GDF SUEZ at the beginning of this year, as our contractual positions are unwound. So that's a temporary effect.</p>
          <p>Paid, taxes paid 2.5 billion. Difference between the tax liability 1.7 and the actual outflow for taxes is due to the prepayments of taxes in various countries, France, Belgium and the Netherlands. Given our tax strategy this should turn around, we shall recover 800 million at the beginning of this year of overpaid taxes in 2008, so much for cash flow.</p>
          <p>The amount of net CapEx is &#x20AC;11.8 billion. This is in line with the average annual CapEx announced for 2008 to 2010. Broken down, as you can see on this slide between 2.7 billion for maintenance CapEx, 7.8 billion for development CapEx, I have talked about this when I talked about the various business lines earlier on.</p>
          <p>Non-contributive investments, which are in our balance sheet, are 7 billion at the end of 2008, compared to 3 billion at the end of 2007. The development CapEx should however contribute &#x20AC;1.2 billion in 2009. They made little contribution during 2008.</p>
          <p>Acquisitions made in 2008 are &#x20AC;5 billion. This is basically Senoko, Nogat, the NAM pipe, Teesside, Ponte de Pedra and the public takeover bid for Agbar with no effect on debt, and FirstLight. These acquisitions should contribute in 2009 about &#x20AC;350 million as G&#xE9;rard said. They had a contribution of lower than 100 million in 2008. Divestments, basically the European remedies.</p>
          <p>Return to shareholders, we paid out in 2008 almost &#x20AC;7 billion to our shareholders. And you can see how that's broken down here, 5.1 billion in terms of dividends and 1.7 billion in share buybacks. Global return to shareholders was particularly high in 2008. This of course, was due to the merger and due to our desire to optimize our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Our share buyback program of &#x20AC;1 billion, which was announced in September, was carried out to the tune of 43% in November and has now been stopped. On the basis of what we have just said, the pro forma debt is up by 17.3 to &#x20AC;28.9 billion, two years of EBITDA. The structure of our debt is well-balanced.</p>
          <p>We were particularly proactive on the bond markets when the bond markets reopened in October. Since October of 2008 we've raised &#x20AC;10 billion on four markets, the euro, the pound sterling, the Swiss franc and the yen, with maturities between three to 20 years, very good conditions of spread. I said that the average cost of debt remained stable at around 5%.</p>
          <p>Taking account of these latest issues 75% of our net debt is at fixed rate or capped fixed -- capped variable rate. 63% is in euros and the average maturity has been extended from five to eight years. And this financial profile makes it possible to maintain our strong A rating. You can see that our liquidity, cash and cash equivalents, non-drawn credit lines, are amply sufficient to cover two or three or even four years of repayments of our bank or bond debt.</p>
          <p>Our 2008 objectives have been exceeded, these basically what we are -- what they were. EBITDA growth of higher than 10%, net industrial CapEx in line with the 30 billion over three years, slightly more in 2008, which means that we shall be making slightly less in 2009 and 2010, and the rating maintained at strong A.</p>
          <p>Guidance, our medium-term objectives are consistent with our industrial plan, which hasn't been changed and realistic in a difficult economic climate. For 2009, our objective is to grow EBITDA compared to the 2008 EBITDA. Taking account of the turnaround in commodities and oil prices, which would of course have the impact I pointed out on the Global Energies and Gas branch. So that is more than offset, however, more than offset by our Efficio program, which will concern &#x20AC;650 million on the result in 2009, compared to the 500 previously announced.</p>
          <p>A turnaround in our results in France with gas prices, which should make it possible to cover raw material and non-raw material prices and the contribution of the industrial CapEx and the acquisitions that I've referred to, 2009, which is when the crisis is likely to be over and on the basis of how quickly that goes, our ambitious objective is 17 to &#x20AC;18 billion of EBITDA. This is underlined by economic and oil scenarios, which are anticipated in 2009 forward prices, &#x20AC;50 per barrel in average in 2009, 58 in 2010 and 62 in 2011.</p>
          <p>Electricity, we are forecasting fairly stable electricity prices between 50 to &#x20AC;55 per megawatt hour. And a -- an exchange rate euro-dollar of 1.30, and we confirm our other objectives as well, which are continuing strong balance sheet and an unchanged dividend policy.</p>
          <p>The policy of return to shareholders, as I have just said is unchanged and continues to be dynamic and competitive. 2008 dividends were 80 cents per share, which has already been paid on 27th of November 2008. A final dividend of &#x20AC;0.60 to be approved, we hope by the AGM on the 4th of May, that's 1.40, and as has been announced on top of the ordinary dividend an exceptional dividend of &#x20AC;0.80 per share will be proposed to the same Annual General Meeting on the 4th of May.</p>
          <p>We will provide the option to our shareholders of taking the exceptional dividend in the form of stock with a maximum authorized discount of 10%, on the average of the opening crisis of the 20 trading days preceding the AGM on the 4th of May.</p>
          <p>Dividend will be paid on the 6th of May. The option for the exceptional dividend will also be the 6th of May. Shareholders will have two weeks to decide and therefore that offer will close on the 22nd of May. The exceptional dividend will be paid on the 4th of June. You have that timeframe in one of the appendices.</p>
          <p>That I think is all I have to say. I now give the floor to Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Cirelli.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, G&#xE9;rard. Good morning. I'd like to discuss with you, first of all, the impact on our business of the change in commodity prices, and also share with you our believe that long-term the markets in which the Group operates are buoyant markets, which has led the Group to maintain its CapEx program, as we've just indicated, because we believe that over the long-term this program will secure the Group's growth.</p>
          <p>The initial results of this program are there for 2008, and I'll go through those. But of course we are taking account of the current situation and the rather disrupted period to improve our profitability through an ambitious performance plan.</p>
          <p>Now, on commodity prices. And this is basically what drives our business, electricity and oil, a key component of our business and our revenues. What we see is during the first nine months of 2008, that already seem rather a long way away, we've been able to build on this situation and to leverage our assets both in terms of our electricity production assets. And of course I'm thinking here of the open positions that we have on hydropower in France, but also in Brazil, but far less so in the Benelux where we are more closed.</p>
          <p>But we will draw the positive consequences from that this year and also on the gas portfolio, because in 2008 we saw the excellent exploration production activities, but of course because of the price rise, the management of our LNG assets. While this situation was that of the first nine months, the market context has changed substantially since then. Marked, as you can see on the chart by a commodity price drop, quite significant. But here again, and this is the key message, we will be able to demonstrate as we have done in the past to demonstrate the resilience of the GDF SUEZ business model in a very different environment.</p>
          <p>So we're ending this singular year with double-digit growth rates for our major financial results, our aggregates. But when we look at the trend in these commodity prices, we can perhaps just put those in perspective. And in doing so we see, nevertheless, that today's price at levels, those on which G&#xE9;rard has indicated the trends that we've included in the 2010 and 2011 trends on our two prime markets where we operate, were back to 2004 prices for oil and 2005 for electricity period or year.</p>
          <p>Both Gaz de France and SUEZ have demonstrated that they've been able to take advantage of that market situation, without overstating that. So our model &#x2013; our business model that is balanced and resilient, it's a great strength. It really stems from our business model, which makes it possible to protect our margins in challenging economic times.</p>
          <p>You see that two-thirds of our EBITDA is only very little exposed to commodity price fluctuations because we have a substantial regulated business base, gas infrastructure activities that are regulated in France and Europe. And for 2008, is the visibility of the tariff period given by our regulator in France, because we now have a four year perspective. This was a point of keen interest to the market, the very annual nature of our regulation period.</p>
          <p>We have -- we have the vision ahead of us and the regulated activities stemming from water treatment and distribution managed by SUEZ ENVIRONNEMENT in short-term. That is a few months, a few years energy service activities, and the sale of energy to end users are not unduly exposed to commodity price fluctuations.</p>
          <p>As to the remaining one third of EBITDA generated by sale of energy to the markets, well of course that is by definition exposed to energy price fluctuations but we're managing our positions very dynamically in order to secure the margin levels to the maximum.</p>
          <p>To give you an example at the 31st of December last year, most of the European electric activities of the Group that in this third accounts for about 60% of the price exposed position, was hedged at over 90%. Now for 2010 the same period, 60% of 2010 indeed hedged before the end of 2008.</p>
          <p>As regards production that represents the balance of the activity that is exposed to price, there the situation is more different in that the hedged positions are greater than those for electric -- electrical activities. That's a decision that we share with the management across the industry, including the large oil companies that is linked to the structure of gas markets that are far less liquid than the electricity markets.</p>
          <p>Let me state here that for downstream gas, and the sale of gas to our customers, leaving asides sales at administered tariffs that evolve according to formula, and by definition hedged, we proceed as in electricity by hedging our margins by reversing the positions. And for 2008, almost all our sales at free price are secured. In price terms, this essentially concerns the major account activity for which you know that our margins are fully hedged, once the contracts are signed and for the full duration. And all the margins were set at the end of last year.</p>
          <p>When we look at volumes, let me remind you that this is well above the gas volume that is sold at the administrative price. Today it's 170 terawatt hours, very, very substantial. That's why the major account sales are in the orange portion. This is a key strength to withstand the current short-term difficulties that we're facing and to secure -- protect our margins for the coming months.</p>
          <p>This doesn't mean that we are very pessimistic about the future. Not at all, we need to, of course, go through this rather bleak period, but the markets where we operate are attractive and buoyant markets over the long term. These are revisions that were made by the energy agency in December -- November last year, taking account of the economic slowdown. But we see a mid and long term, our markets will be buoyant in areas where the Group is very present.</p>
          <p>The growth momentum that we have in LNG, so the fundamentals of our industry are resolutely strong and buoyant, and we need to bear that in mind because the Group is fundamentally well placed there.</p>
          <p>That explains why our industrial ambitions and our investment programs based on this robust, this strong long-term vision that I've just outlined. G&#xE9;rard has decided to maintain the targets that we set ourselves at the time of the merger in terms of investments. That's why we confirm our CapEx program of &#x20AC;30 billion for the period 2008-2010. It's the bedrock of the Group's growth for the medium and long-term as you can see I won't detail it line-by-line. The amounts that have been allocated out of the 11.8 billion net here you see them. And the growth indicated previously, basically a few points to be borne in mind.</p>
          <p>In France we're building, we're growing in electrical power either through gas plants or wind power. That's the 1 billion that investments are made both in gas and electricity; gas, Neptune in the U.S. or the terminal that we've almost completed in Chile. In electricity in the U.K., Brazil, Singapore, Italy where we obtained a very strong position with the swapped assets with Eni. So we will be an energy leader in Italy.</p>
          <p>E&amp;P, last year, we were able to take advantage of some very smart developments there in gas fields, where we're ranked second in terms of gas production in the Netherlands with NAM and of course in infrastructures we're continuing our program. And this year, we will at last see the commissioning of our first Cavaou terminal that will once again redistribute French gas supplies.</p>
          <p>This doesn't mean that we're not attentive to the current environment. We've enhanced the selectivity of our investment criteria presented at the time of the investor. I won't go back over those unless you wish me to do so. Our policy is implemented rigorously both yesterday, today and tomorrow. Wherever possible, we seek to focus on exchange of assets without exchange of cash, we initiated this type of transaction first and foremost with the merger, because it's the only merger where there was no exchange of cash.</p>
          <p>It is sufficiently significant to indicate that today and with the resolution of remedies, which was a good deal in that respect and a structuring transaction of exchange of assets of electricity production in Europe with E.ON last December. And so these initiatives satisfied and preserved our financial leeway, we will continue to favor those in the future.</p>
          <p>Now by securing and implementing our investment programs, secures our long-term growth over and above the strong uncertainties that we're currently experiencing, and will allow us to achieve our operational targets.</p>
          <p>Let me just pause for a moment on the gas and electricity market to show you what we achieved last year. I believe that this illustrates the point amply in 2007, 60 gigawatts. In 2008, you can see that we are on the trend of our 100 gigawatt for 2013 that we indicated. Our achievements in 2008 now make it possible to have 70 Gwatt in installed capacity worldwide, we're resolutely on the right track.</p>
          <p>You have to, of course, the 2008 achievements were essentially due to external growth transactions, Senoko, Singapore, FirstLight in the US, but what will we be seeing in 2009 and 2010, is the coming on stream of all the plants that we're currently building. And there are many in France, at least three, Montoir, Combigolfe and Cycofos, one at the Atlantic, two in the Mediterranean, Benelux.</p>
          <p>We have coal, gas, Flevo, Sigma, Amercor, and hydropower in Brazil of course with Jirau and the Middle Eastern gas with Ras Laffan and Marafiq which is the largest plant in the world currently under construction. So the Group is indeed well placed and has really set its expansion targets in electricity, as we indicated and in a geographic area that is global. Indeed we're convinced that our Group is going global and is one of the strengths of GDF SUEZ.</p>
          <p>In gas, we've continued our policy of diversification of gas supplies, securing it. We're the most diversified company and we seek to continue to develop our own production capabilities. These two strategies constitute as it were the trademark of GDF SUEZ. Today, we are in a better position than one and a half months ago, and that we were able to experience the Russian/Ukrainian supply crisis in January more calmly, and participating very actively in the resolution of that crisis by demonstrating European solidarity. That was very important towards the 5 million clients that we have outside France and Belgium and in countries where we have no customers.</p>
          <p>But to demonstrate our solidarity and the ability of the Group to supply Europe at a time, as you will recall it was pretty cold, because during the period consumption records were broken in France. That was a fine challenge and our teams were congratulated because we managed to do that and it shows our capacity for diversification, without having any -- there were no blackouts. We were able to supply Greece, Bosnia and Croatia without outages.</p>
          <p>Just a word on production exploration, you can see here the importance of the increase in 2008. That came at the right time. We were prepared for a sharp increase of output in 2008, up 20% for several years now, at a time when energy prices were at their best. So good performance of exploration production, which in 2008, generated EBITDA of &#x20AC;1.8 billion, quite a sizeable number and shows the excellence of this new business, well, ten years old now in the Group and thanks to the acquisition of NAM.</p>
          <p>Well, this 20% increase -- in excess of 20% that we achieved in 2008, of course, we won't replicate that in 2009. There will be growth however, but to a lesser extent. We're expecting an increase of 5% in our volumes in 2009. There's the full effect of NAM, and then developments in Egypt this year, but of course, production will remain in excess of 50 million barrels. And 2010, further growth with the arrival of Gjoa, in Norway.</p>
          <p>During this period, where we increased -- our reserves have increased going from 667 million barrels of oil equivalent to 704. And in the 704 million, well, this year we will include the reserves of Touat in Algeria. The world leadership position, recalled by G&#xE9;rard, and its inherent balance, the diversification, its risk management policy makes us well-placed and positioned to withstand the current contingencies. And in that context the Efficio performance plan will allow us to secure and boost our financials and that is an additional response to the current economic climate.</p>
          <p>Just a word on the Efficio, to say that since the Investor Day major progress has been achieved. The organization is now well-structured around Emmanuel Hedde, Director of Integration Synergies. Our performance with the 80 business line and division managers who manage those objectives that are clearly defined, and quantified targets by action and by item through a methodology that is applied at every level with the efficiencies reviewed every half year by the auditors. We have just over 400 action plans implemented with the efficiencies identified and implemented. And that is an excellent structure.</p>
          <p>So we confirm our 2011 target. 1.8 billion is the 2011 target for Efficio. That's confirmed with a separation of that operational performance about 50%, optimizing support functions 20%, cross-business targets that will be 20%. For 2009, we have taken new initiatives that have been launched. And we've decided to increase our 2009 target without changing the 2011 number, which has gone from 500 million given at the Investor Day to &#x20AC;650 million.</p>
          <p>This is an additional effort that we wish to make in order to achieve our targets and meet the current situation, and which we perceived as realistic when we began to work on this initiative, and we saw that additional scope was possible. So that is the new Efficio trajectory. To conclude the estimates of the contributions of each business line to this plan, indicated in percentage of the 2011 target.</p>
          <p>See the managerial effort that is required, and on the left the second graph that it's well documented that the actions are committed and well implemented. And for 2011 we have close on 11% of targets objectives that have been identified. And we're discussing just a small 20%, which is a good thing. So that's for two years time. So the plan is moving forward.</p>
          <p>So in conclusion, this rather -- these rather disrupted times restate my confidence in the Group and the growth prospects for the medium and long-term, because we have buoyant fundamentals and that the Group is well positioned to take advantage of those growth prospects going forward, to continue to implement our investment program to strengthen our industrial positions.</p>
          <p>We're an industrial company, to secure our growth over the long-term. In the short-term we have strong assets to face the crisis, the very balanced mix of our business model, very resilient perhaps more so then many of our peers, and we've set in hand a substantial improvement on our operational performance for the company. And it's all these items which these rather challenging times make us confident &#x2013; more than confident as to the targets announced and the fact that during this period, we are posting an EBITDA target for 2009 that is higher than last year, a year that was already exceptional.</p>
          <p>Thank you for listening, back to G&#xE9;rard for the conclusion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois. Before opening the Q&amp;A session, I would like just to say a few words by way of conclusion of this annual results presentation. I'd like to dwell little on our economic and corporate social responsibility, which is inherent in our business model.</p>
          <p>To illustrate this, you can see this slide here that I've been presenting to you for the past few years. And I think it's particularly welcome this year. It's the breakdown of amounts paid in 2008 to personnel, to CapEx and to the return to our shareholders. The first two, CapEx and personnel, 11 billion for personnel, 11.8 for CapEx. Those are, of course, the figures which are the roots of our growth and our performance. But of course, there's also the return to our shareholders of &#x20AC;5.1 billion, which ensures that we continue to have access to financial markets.</p>
          <p>So that breakdown, as I said, we've been presenting it to you for some years now, is not quite in line with what one might find in our accounts, or in national accounts, but it does show how the three types of expenditure are broken down in our company. As far as the 5 billion of dividends, there is 1.7 billion of extraordinary dividend, with the option for shareholders who wish to do so to take that dividend in stock.</p>
          <p>The corresponding resolution for the AGM was voted unanimously by the Board. So that will be unanimously recommended to the AGM. And if some -- and if -- if some of that is taken in stock it will be devoted to CapEx. In 2009, the distribution of the dividend today gives -- in 2009, including the exceptional dividend, a very competitive dividend yield because it's higher than 8%.</p>
          <p>I would also add that the Board also decided yesterday to distribute to the 200,000 employees of the Group 0.2% of the equity, and give them free performance shares to the 200,000 employees and that is, of course similar to what we've decided in the past two years, both in Gaz de France and SUEZ. It's a way of getting people identified more closely with the new Group and giving every employee, whatever nationality, whatever their job in the company a share of the growth of this company.</p>
          <p>A few key messages to conclude, a solid operational performance in 2008, a sound balance sheet that we wish of course to maintain, it's one of the soundest balance sheets in our industry, a strategic vision and an industrial program which remained unchanged. We have taken of course some very short term measures to whether the crisis, the Efficio plan, the liquidity issue.</p>
          <p>And we are looking beyond the crisis and looking and sticking to our strategic vision. The crisis has been anticipated. It was dealt with very proactively and quickly and efficiency. The direction for 2011 has been set and we're sticking to it. The objective of 17 to &#x20AC;18 billion in EBITDA, we confirm our leadership strategy for the long-term, finally.</p>
          <p>Thank you for listening ladies and gentlemen. We are now happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First question over here, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Inaudible" /> , Nomura, maybe we could talk a little bit more about the guidance for 2009. Could you just confirm that you are expecting EBITDA increases in each of Energy France, Energy Benedelux and Energy Europe? And if so what are your expectations around French gas tariffs come this April?</p>
          <p>And I hear what you're saying about the forward curve for power prices, but given that your average cost, or your average revenue per megawatt hour, in 2008 was &#x20AC;62, what are you looking at given your hedge position for 2009 in euros per megawatt hour for the European region?</p>
          <p>And then if we go back to November, you indicated in November you had a sensitivity of about 30 to &#x20AC;50 million for every &#x20AC;1 per megawatt hour. Given that you generate in excess of about 150 terawatt hours in Europe, surely the sensitivity over the longer-term should be around about &#x20AC;150 million for every &#x20AC;1 per megawatt hour. Could you make some comment on that please? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We will try to answer your questions. Let's start with the first one G&#xE9;rard, about the EBITDA 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we said that the EBITDA 2009 will be higher than 2008. It is based on the forecast and the forward -- hold on, can you put the slide please, on the guidance? It is based on the electricity price Benedelux of -- which will be around &#x20AC;52 per megawatt hours. So &#x2013; and we have mentioned to base those price 52 for 2009, 52 for 2010 and 54 for 2011. I've given you the percentage hedge of the margin -- it is more than 90% for the coming year and then it's going down progressively. And I also mentioned that the increase of the price locked for the Indesol customers. So you have everything to make your calculation on the electricity segment. By the way, there is a strong correlation between the price of electricity in Benedelux, France and Germany.</p>
          <p>As far as concern the longer impact -- longer-term, medium-term impact on the electricity segment, the 150 million that you calculated, I think that your estimation is right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Emmanuel Turpin from Morgan Stanley. Three questions please. You mentioned, first of all, a very interesting point about non-contributory investment to 2008 EBITDA, 7 billion on non-contributory investment. Could you tell us a little more about that? And you said that that there was EBITDA contribution of &#x20AC;1.2 billion. I wasn't quite sure for what year or for what period. Could you compare that &#x20AC;1.2 billion with the contribution of acquisitions in 2008? You said 350 million contribution of acquisitions in 2009? That's the first question. More detail on that please.</p>
          <p>Second question, net income 2009, could you summarize for us the nonrecurring items in 2008? Looking at your slides, there are capital gains on remedies, 1.9 billion, mark-to-market issues, 358 million negative. Yes, negative in 2008. Now if we adjust that for taxes and minority interests, I get 1.4, &#x20AC;1.5 billion of net non-recurring items. So that's about 5 billion of recurring net income in 2009. Are my calculations right?</p>
          <p>And the third question is this. You've talked about your assumptions on the oil price for 2009. Could you give us your expectations of E&amp;P output in 2009, and your expectations of LNG trading and whether there's going to be a fall in volume and if so by how much compared to 2008?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, G&#xE9;rard will answer your second question. I will answer your third question. Perhaps an issue about the last question which I didn't answer, the impact of regulated gas prices in France. Very simple answer, we said there would be a fall in gas prices on the 1st of April. There will be a diminution in gas prices on the 1st of April. I can't tell you by how much. The discussions are ongoing and our calculations are ongoing too therefore. Our assumptions is that the delay in price adjustments will not increase in 2009. So if we lost, so to speak, 700 million in 2008 we won't lose anything in 2009, in terms of delay in price adjustments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Emmanuel Turpin's first question concerning contribution of capital spending in 2008, what's their contribution to EBITDA in 2009? For the development CapEx, I said that the contribution was 1.2 billion in 2009, and for acquisitions financial CapEx contribution is 350 million in 2009. So that's 1.5 billion of contribution from CapEx in 2008.</p>
          <p>I also said, remember, that a part of the development CapEx was not productive, was non-contributory for a number of months. That capital spending is preparing our growth beyond 2009. And I mean by that 2010 and 2011, because it takes 18 months, for instance, for a power plant to be built. It needs more than 18 months for a gas &#x2013; re-gasification terminal to be built. So that of course contributes to EBITDA later on.</p>
          <p>Emmanuel's second question concerns nonrecurring items in 2008. It's a complex issue, but let me give you the main items here. 1.9 billion capital gains on divestment of assets. Yes, and we have a positive mark-to-market of 515 million. But we took an impairment on the Gas Natural securities for the same amount, 513 million. So that cancels -- those cancel each other out basically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On your third question, E&amp;P should increase its volume in 2009 by about 5% in volume. That is basically the full year effect of our acquisition of NAM in the Netherlands and developments in Egypt. So after a growth of 20% this year, 5% in 2009, but there will be a stronger growth in 2010 because of the commissioning of Gjoa in Norway, that's a major acquisition.</p>
          <p>As far as LNG is concerned, 2009 will not be a great year, not be a great year as I said compared to 2008 for a number of reasons. The First is that prices of course have fallen. Asia is no longer a very buoyant market. It's re-exporting LNG today. We recently acquired a cargo of LNG in Asia. And a long time we haven't been doing things like that. Prices are fairly depressed and Europe has now -- or is now becoming the leading LNG market in terms of pricing and attractiveness at the moment. We have also during the winter had to reduce our LNG operations to supply France and Europe in the face of the crisis in Russia.</p>
          <p>And third reason in the very short-term, there is a great deal of LNG floating around in the world. So don't expect the great performance -- exceptional performance of 2008 of LNG to be repeated in 2009. That's why we said EBITDA on B3G does not correspond to what you were saying about the impact in the dollar on E&amp;P. &#x20AC;20 million per dollar of oil price is more of a negative impact in 2009, because of the LNG operations, which will have an impact on the B3G business line, but also the B3EE because of LNG or a lower LNG revenue in the US.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please. First or second row, as you get the microphone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrice <mark type="inaudible" />. Three questions, if I may. The first concerns slide 78, to try and recalculate, unless I missed something, the cash flow from operations. 7.7 billion was the cash flow from operations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we have slide 78, please? 75, I beg your pardon 75, slide 75.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, 7.7 cash flow from operations, 2.7 maintenance, that's the rest. So could we have the rest for last year, could we have a dynamic view of those flows? First question.</p>
          <p>Second question, coming back to Martin's question about gas prices. I know that it's a very difficult issue, because it's political. But let me ask the question rather differently and let me ask Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois Cirelli this question. When we asked you the question last November, we asked you what level of margin you were expecting for 2010, 2 billion, and you said 2% would be the margin. Now, on the basis of the situation today, we don't know what the political decision will be for the 1st of April. But let's look forward to 2010, what will be your margin do you think on that 10 billion of revenue? Not 2 billion, but 10 billion, of course.</p>
          <p>And then another question, you've had a good first month and second month. Could we have a feel for the differences in terawatt hours for industry and households? Industry is down, of course, households may be up because of the cold weather.</p>
          <p>And then a final question, if you don't answer it too bad, but I'd like to ask it all the same. Could you tell us about Penly, the second EPR in France?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're calculating your answer to the first question. On the 2007 flows compared to 2008. Let me give you the floor to Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois on gas prices. Perhaps on gas consumption in the first couple of years -- couple of months of this year, I can give the floor to Henri Ducr&#xE9;, so he can give us his view about the gas consumption in France.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On gas prices, there is a basic issue here which is that history has shown that we had a lot more difficulty when prices were increasing rather than when prices were decreasing. That's our historical experience. So when prices were falling, and that made it possible to bring down gas prices, that was good for us. It was very difficult for us to pass on our costs when gas prices were rising, and it's much easier to pass on those costs when gas prices are falling. So that's the first issue.</p>
          <p>We don't know exactly by how much gas prices will fall on the 1st of April. So I can't give you any figures at this stage. What I can say however is that, I would repeat first of all what G&#xE9;rard said first of all, which is that we had 700 million in 2008 EBITDA which we didn't -- which we're not going to get in 2009, we've lost 700 million. And we are making the realistic assumption that in 2009, we will be able to pass on all our costs. So that 700 million shortfall will not be present in 2009, as we had it in 2008; shortfall in 2008, no shortfall in 2009.</p>
          <p>So the EBITDA for Energy France in 2009 will be very different to the EBITDA on Energy France 2008. There will be a slightly &#x2013; a slight downward impact because of the hydraulic production of CNR, which is -- part of that is not hedged, but it will be impacted upwards by being able to pass on all our costs. We haven't managed to pass on all of our costs, including at the end of 2008, because we wanted, this is no mystery, to pass on our costs. Politically that was unpalatable, but that will work itself out in 2009.</p>
          <p>For 2009 therefore, the first point is that the delay in price adjustments, the ability to pass on our costs in prices, will be 100%. Okay, so there will be no shortfall in 2009. That's our first objective. To stop this delay in price adjustments and the shortfall it involves. Then we want two things, the first thing is that we are paid for what happened in the past -- we are repaid for what happened in the past. And that we have a margin on new business. Now, all that is being discussed with the political authorities, they understand basically what we're driving at.</p>
          <p>When I said last year that we wouldn't come back to this, what's a good margin in terms of selling, and I said that a good margin could be 3%, but we considered that we would perhaps manage to go up gradually. We wouldn't get 3% straightaway, but that we may get it eventually. So I think what you can bear in mind, is that 1% on the year is about 100 million. Looking at the whole situation 1% equals 100 million. Okay, so keep that in mind. So we'll see eventually what the package comes out at.</p>
          <p>But our priorities are, one, we stop widening the deficit of costs and prices. That will be done. It won't -- it hadn't been done up to the 1st of April, it will be done on the 1st of April. Then we have to look at how we get paid back for the past. Obviously, we are not going to be able to make that up in one fell swoop. It's going to have to be done gradually. And we want to have a margin on our selling and all that has to be approved politically. But as I said, once again, it's far easier to discuss all these issues when the price of gas is falling rather than when the price of gas is rising.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois. Henri, perhaps a microphone in the first row please, just some information on how you are reading consumption levels at the beginning of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, beginning of the year consumption levels, two markets residential and industry. Residential, we're seeing consumption levels that are on a par with the weather, the climate. As you've seen, it's been -- there was a cold snap in the first few months and that's good news for us. But it was a lot colder than last year, which was a mild year. What you have to realize is Q1 of 2008, was very, very mild. We're this time colder than average, but not much colder. Difficult to give figures, it's early March and it would be difficult to give a trend. We're seeing an increase in consumption levels on the first few months, which is as it should be.</p>
          <p>Industrial consumption, no drop there. Industry is of course is far less weather sensitive, it's more crisis sensitive, but in our clients we're not seeing any drop. If we try and project this going forward of course our clients will be impacted by the downturn. But we're not expecting collapsing gas consumption levels of our clients going forward. So specific situation of the initial months good, that's weather driven, and industry consumption levels are bearing up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well on industry, let's be clear. There are drops, but --</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] (110:00)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not in Energy France, but the industry consumption unit, where there was a drop, very limited drop, not what we read in the papers of the paper pulp, steel, automotive industries and chemical industries. That's not going to come as a surprise, but these were not major selling sectors for GDF SUEZ. So the decline is there on the major accounts, but very limited.</p>
          <p>So, on the EPR now, just a few brief words. Let me remind you the statement made by the presidency a couple of weeks back on the second EPR. We were a candidate to build the EPR alone. We have the capacity to do that, EDF 2, B2. The decision of the political authorities is to launch a second EPR at Penly. EDF will be the majority and GDF SUEZ will be associated in the industrial development. We believe it's a good decision, because it came after comment about the support of the French State for GDF SUEZ to be the prime contractor and operator of the third EPR.</p>
          <p>So discussions have started with EDF under the aegis of the political authorities and we wish to be fully involved, associated. We believe we can bring a lot to this project through our very wide ranging skill-sets, a industrial architect of major projects as we're managing at present, not nuclear power plants, but a very large energy projects which for many are bigger than EPRs, be it in the Middle East or Brazil. So we can provide our engineering skills of associated services and also our skills in preparing the future operation of the EPR, because one of the characteristics of the skill set of our Group is to be able to manage nuclear power plants with availability rates that are amongst the highest in Europe.</p>
          <p>So, these discussions are proceeding and I've no doubt that we will find the right balance at the end of the day to give our Group, with TOTAL and other European partners, it's full place in a project to make this joint project because that is the decision of the political authorities, to make it a shared success.</p>
          <p>Oh, on the cash flow, yes, the first question, I don't know if we have the answer. We'll get it to you, on the cash flow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Merrill Lynch. Three quick ones if I may. First off M&amp;A, 10 billion on the bond markets raised. A lot of rumors doing the rounds, as to your participation or not, to potential deals going forward. Can you confirm that the organic growth is your priority and not M&amp;A?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, quite clearly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of clarifications on Gas Nat [Gas Natural]. You're going to participate and -- actually I &#x2013; the political climate run's not very good. Could you maybe specify that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>55.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I thought that was 3?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was actually part of the first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. 5 billion acquisitions a year, you've detailed 2.5. That's quite a big variance. Could we have some details on the remaining 2.5? And then tax credit. How much have you consumed in 2008, how much is left and what's your use timetable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. To answer your first question, the first triple question, well, I answered -- I spoke of the M&amp;A need for capital to secure our liquidity not to make additional investments. So we remain fully within our package of &#x20AC;30 billion, as we've in fact stole a bit of march on 2008, so we can remain within the 30 billion package, well just under 10 in the years 2009 and 2010. And the Group's growth has always been based on organic growth and will remain so.</p>
          <p>Gas Natural, we will decide what we will do once we know the conditions of the share capital increase in light of our interest. On Acea just a brief word and a reminder, the Group is very present in Italy. SUEZ has been present for a long time through our partnership with Acea Gaz de France present in Italy, with a number of activities of major importance. In our Italian operations we're in fact strengthened by what we acquired from Eni. So a discussion took place between the Acea management team and our Italian teams in order to structure the setup, as part of an expansion of the partnership with Acea to restructure -- to reorganize everything.</p>
          <p>So a proposal was made by the two teams of negotiators which meets with our approval. We approve the conditions that were put forward. The day before yesterday the negotiator of the Italian side resigned or was asked to resign and we don't have the full explanation on that. We're waiting for explanations, and we're entitled to explanations on that. At this stage, the Acea Board hasn't taken a formal stand on the deal, as yet we don't know what its view point is.</p>
          <p>Be that as it may, what I can say is that Italy for us is strategic. With or without Acea, we have a set of assets through the three packages that I detailed earlier, which make it possible for us to form the third player in Italy in the gas sector, behind Enel and Edison. That's what we'll do. If we can do with it Acea so much the better, otherwise we'll do it without Acea. So, all options are on the table. The Acea partnership was a good partnership. We're waiting to see what lies behind the event that occurred a couple of day ago. And Italy is very important for us and we plan to expand in Italy and to forge this position of the third ranked Italian player in the energy and gas sector and electricity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, on the acquisitions for 2008, over and above, what was specifically described?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So three questions on the figures, the first on 2008 cash flow versus 2007. Cash flow from operations is up 6.7% at 13.287 billion. On the tax credit, how much do we have left? Well a saving of -- to be made, a tax saving of 600 million to be spread over two years, that's 2009-2010.</p>
          <p>Then there's a question on the detail of the acquisitions. I won't list them all, because there are a great many. There are three acquisitions between 500 and 700 million, that's the bid on Agbar, that's FirstLight and Senoko non-contributive. And then we have four acquisitions, between 200 and 300 million; Nogat, Teesside, Ponte de Pedra, and a stake in France in the Tricastin enrichment plant. And then six investments between 100 and 200 million; Fox, Boone Comenor, SUEZ ENVIRONNEMENT, Nass Wind (sic) [Nass &amp; Wind] (119:33) and various other companies. And then a block of 1.2 billion, of acquisitions of less than 100 million individually.</p>
          <p>We'll give you all the details in the annexes and we're of course ready to supply you with additional information if you so require. We'll get back to you on that then, but I'll give the floor to someone else in the mean time. Yes please, over here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Vincent de Blic from Cazenove. I have four questions, quick ones. The first on your dividend policy, you say that you confirm your dividend policy. To call a spade a spade, does that mean more than 10% in growth of earnings per share in 2009?</p>
          <p>And you then gave us a contribution to EBITDA 2008 of CapEx 2008. Could you give us a contribution in 2011 of CapEx in 2008 and 2009 together?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm afraid I can't give you that. We'd like to, but I'm not sure that we can do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On WCR, which is perhaps a surprise for some of us, what improvement are you hoping for in 2009 on WCR? And about the tax rate, could you give us the guidance on 2008, because of the fall in profits is there likely to be a fall in taxation -- on the tax rate in 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Working capital, first of all. Yes, on working capital there has been an increase of 3 billion in 2008, which of course is consistent with the increase in revenue and influenced by increases in volumes and prices. As business will be slowing, there shouldn't be an increase which is so high. There are a number of issues we shall also be turning around, the 700 million margin call which will be coming back.</p>
          <p>And on the tax line, I said that we paid 800 million over the odds to various tax administrations in 2008. So that cash will be repaid to us in 2009. There is &#x20AC;1.5 billion coming back in, being repaid, plus the impact of the fall in revenues which will have an arithmetic impact on stocks and receivables.</p>
          <p>The tax rate, will the tax rate fall? Will it fall because of the fall in revenues? Yes, the -- yes, clearly there will be a mechanical effect there. There are various impacts that you have to take into account, and I believe that looking at the trend, you should expect the tax rate to gradually converge on the normative tax rate of 33%.</p>
          <p>Any other questions, please? Yes, over here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Benjamin Leyre from Exane BNP Paribas. First question, what do you think about some governments' capacity to get money from the utilities? What do you feel about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're against it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Not surprised. What about your debate with the Belgian government on this? And do you think that you're going to benefit or lose from the replacement of the professional tax in France by something else? What you are going to propose to the <mark type="inaudible" /> Commission for regulated prices, and are you going to present a proposal?</p>
          <p>And third point, could you tell us something about gas prices once again? What about the pricing formula which was validated by CRE, what will that mean in terms of a fall in prices in April? And what about return on capital, will that increase in 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as governments and their attitude are concerned, we are against of course any approach which would be taking money out of the pockets of the utilities, certainly. As far as our discussions with the Belgian government are concerned, we've said very clearly that we were against this tax of 250 million, which was levied in 2008, which we paid in 2008, which is in our financial statements. We will be appealing against that and that will be done very quickly. We'll be appealing against that and taking the case to the Belgian Constitutional Court, the Belgian government knows that.</p>
          <p>So we will be doing that for two reasons. The first is the tax is disproportionately high, 250 million, out of a series of businesses in Belgium, which have been considerably reduced by the divestment of Distrigas, the intercommunal gas, Fluxys, and so on so forth. And market shares that we've divested to E.ON or exchanged with E.ON and SPE. And then there's the anti-constitutional nature of the tax, which concerns one single tax payer. So it's anti-constitutional on those grounds. We are saying we're the only tax payer against which this tax is being levied, so we're going to fight that.</p>
          <p>On the French professional tax, it's a little early to say what the impact on that is likely to be. We're very much in favor of that tax being removed. And surely, we will benefit from that. We have not yet heard of what is likely to replace it. There have been a few rumors flying around, but nothing very precise at this stage. So we really don't know. We pay our professional tax, 270 million I think last year, 270 million. The basically broken down more or less half about 50/50 between former businesses of GDF and former businesses of SUEZ. So that's basically the figure for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What about the <mark type="inaudible" /> Commission on regulated prices, can we say anything about that? You gave evidence to the <mark type="inaudible" /> Commission can you say anything on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I really don't know what the outcome's going to be. That's the main point. I think we will wait with a great deal of interest to see what the proposals are and whether they are accepted politically. What we're saying, of course, as you can imagine, is that we want the opening of the market. We want a market in France which is open, fully open for electricity. We don't think it is fully open yet. And we shall try and convince the MPs that this doesn't, of course, mean that electricity prices are going to soar as far as consumers are concerned.</p>
          <p>What we have been saying for, say 2012, is that we would like to have a situation in which about 30% of the market is a market for alternative power producers. And that's basically what our rate, our percentage is in France. And we would like to be able to supply those power producers in a price which is compatible with market prices, so that there can be real competition. So there are various things can be done then, auction sales for instance, we are very happy with that.</p>
          <p>And another thing that I'd like to say, a major point that we've been making, is that the new regulatory framework and the pricing framework must also aim to make it possible to build power producing, power generating assets in France, including EPRs. So that's something too that that the <mark type="inaudible" /> Commission will of course have on its agenda.</p>
          <p>We've given evidence to the Commission. We've been very open-minded about our views. There are -- the technical side of things I think has been very well received, we shall have to see what happens politically.</p>
          <p>As far as the fall in gas prices are concerned. I really can't give you a figure. If I were to give you a figure today that would simply complicate matters in terms of negotiating with the government. So I can't really say what we want. What we want above all, is to revert to a mechanism in which the raw material prices are at the same level as the non-raw material prices. The non-raw material prices are just as important to us as the raw material prices. And when prices go up, we are told you just consider yourself lucky to pass on some of your commodities costs and we'll see about non-commodity costs later on.</p>
          <p>Well, no, we'd like to make sure that all our costs are properly included in the price formula, that's the law by the way. So all we have to do is to ensure that the law is properly enforced. And the fall in prices should take into account not only the fall in raw material prices which represent about 50% of the price paid by the consumer. But also changes in non-material costs -- non-raw material costs.</p>
          <p>Well, I've been told that in 30 seconds time the microphones are going to be cut off and the lights switched off. So let me simply answer on ROCE, we give no guidance on ROCE. So that's a quick answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry we have to close this meeting now. Ladies and Gentlemen, thank you very much for being with us this morning. And I wish you a very pleasant day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>