<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1155970" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>238</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Christian Garcia, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">David J. Lesar, Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Mark A. McCollum, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Tim Probert, Executive Vice President, Strategy and Corporate Development</participant>
      <participant id="5">J. David Anderson</participant>
      <participant id="6">Tim Probert</participant>
      <participant id="7">Charles Minervino</participant>
      <participant id="8">Ole Slorer</participant>
      <participant id="9">David Lesar</participant>
      <participant id="10">James Crandell</participant>
      <participant id="11">Mark McCollum</participant>
      <participant id="12">Michael Urban</participant>
      <participant id="13">Kurt Hallead</participant>
      <participant id="14">Michael Lamotte</participant>
      <participant id="15">Dan Pickering</participant>
      <participant id="16">Robin Shoemaker</participant>
      <participant id="17">Christian Garcia</participant>
      <participant id="18">Alan Laws</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Halliburton Second Quarter 2008 Earnings Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later we will conduct a question-and-answer session and instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to introduce your host for today's conference, Mr. Christian Garcia, Vice President, Investor Relations. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome to the Halliburton second quarter 2008 conference call. Today's call is being webcast and the replay will be available on Halliburton's website for seven days. A podcast download will also be available.</p>
          <p>The press release announcing the second quarter results is available on the Halliburton website. Joining me today are Dave Lesar, CEO; Mark McCollum, CFO; and Tim Probert, Executive Vice President, Strategy and Corporate Development.</p>
          <p>In today's call, Dave will provide opening remarks. Mark will discuss our overall financial performance and Tim will provide comments on our operations and business outlook. We will welcome questions after we complete our prepared remarks.</p>
          <p>Before turning the call over to Dave, I'd like to remind our audience that some of today's comments may include forward-looking statements reflecting Halliburton's views about future events and their potential impact on performance. These matters involve risks and uncertainties that could impact operations and financial results and cause our actual results to differ from our forward-looking statements. These risks are discussed in Halliburton's Form 10-K for the year ended December 31, 2007, our Form 10-Q for the quarter ended March 31, 2008 and recent current reports on Form 8-K.</p>
          <p>Please note that we will be using the term international to refer to our operations outside the U.S. and Canada and we will refer to the combination of U.S. and Canada as North America.</p>
          <p>Now, I will turn the call over to Dave Lesar. Dave?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Christian, and good morning to everyone. The company posted another excellent quarter with year-over-year revenue growth of 20%. Our international revenue grew 26%, which was in excess of our 20% goal with Latin America continuing its growth momentum with a 33% year-over-year growth. We expect robust activity in this region to continue for the remainder of the year as we execute our strategy in this market. Overall, our revenues grew 11% sequentially despite the pricing pressures in frac in the U.S. We had record revenue this quarter in every product line expect Landmark, which typically records its highest revenue in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to the results of North America and discuss our prospects for the second half of 2008 and onward. Despite the very negative impact of the spring break-up in our Canadian operations and of course pricing pressure in the frac market, North America revenue for the quarter grew a strong 7% sequentially due to higher activity in both U.S. land and the Gulf of Mexico.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., our revenues increased 12% sequentially as Halliburton continues to benefit from the increase in horizontal drilling activity toward which we have focused our U.S. service portfolio. Our well construction businesses in general and Sperry in particular have continued to show strong growth in U.S. Landmark at this quarter.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, Canada has now recovered from its seasonal drop and we expect strong activity in this market in the second half of 2008. More service intensive plays such as the Montney in northeastern British Columbia also are giving us additional opportunities to ply across product line solutions.</p>
          <p>Our focus on efficiency and high utilization helped us deliver strong second quarter margins in North America. The pressure pumping pricing environment continued to be competitive. Overall we experienced the 1 to 2% average pricing decline for fracturing consistent with our guidance. However, we saw clear signs of prices stabilizing toward the end of the quarter. In fact, the pricing decline was at the lower end of the range we expected.</p>
          <p>We however did see continuation of inflationary pressures and increases in fuel and materials that we discussed in the first quarter call and Mark will provide an update on this and how we are trying to mitigate them.</p>
          <p>For our product lines outside of fracturing, pricing has stabilized with the exception of some minor weakness in our cementing business this quarter. We do not expect continued pricing declines going forward. In fact, currently wireline logging, directional drilling, LWD and drill bits have the most pricing leverage upside in this market.</p>
          <p>Our customers have announced revisions to their capital programs for the remainder of 2008 and 2009 for the development of their conventional and unconventional resources. We expect unconventional drilling activity to increase over the second half of the year and be geared more towards service intensive emerging shale plays like the Haynesville and Marcellus, which will drive demand across all of our service offerings.</p>
          <p>The formations of these plays are not yet well understood and require a much more reservoir focused approach. And Tim will provide more color on the technologies that our customers are beginning to employ to unlock the value of these reservoirs.</p>
          <p>This increased activity along with the tightening and balancing out of capacity provides us with an improved outlook for all of our businesses, enhances our ability to increase prices modestly and cover cost inflation. Our fracturing equipment utilization remains high and we've worked to optimize fleet placement. We'll continue to align our equipment with our customers' assets where we receive better long-term margins and returns.</p>
          <p>Now, let me turn to our international business. Revenue continued its strong upward momentum with a 26% year-over-year growth. All of our international regions showed growth over 20% with Latin America alone growing above 30%. Sequentially, international revenues increased 15% as operations in Norway, Saudi Arabia, Angola, Mexico, and Brazil continued to expand. International margins for the quarter were 21%, even with our continued heavy investments in people, facilities, and equipment to support the next phase of our growth in the Eastern Hemisphere. Margins were additionally impacted this quarter by the ramp up cost for our Manifa offshore award where drilling is expected to start in Q4 or early next year and reach a total of ten rigs. We continue to expect expansion of international margins, which will be driven by value created from the introduction of new technology, reliability of execution and the fixed-cost leverage offsetting the price competition we are seeing on larger tenders.</p>
          <p>Project visibility continues to be very good giving us confidence that we will continue to see healthy growth rates throughout the second half of 2008 and into 2009, barring a significant global recession due to high commodity prices. We're making good progress in growing profitability in several underserved markets and are improving our exposure to the highest growth segments of the market.</p>
          <p>Let me turn the call over to Mark to give you more financial details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Dave, and good morning. I'll be comparing our second quarter results sequentially to the first quarter. Halliburton's revenue in the second quarter was $4.5 billion, up $458 million or 11% from the first quarter. Landmark, Baroid, Wireline and production enhancement product lines registered growth of over 10% sequentially. On a geographic basis, all regions showed double-digit increases except for North America, which grew 7% but was impacted by spring break up in Canada. And As Dave pointed out, we are expecting a resurgence of activity in Canada in the second half of 2008 at a much higher level than what we had originally anticipated.</p>
          <p>Operating income increased $102 million or 12% from the first quarter of 2008 representing incremental margins of 22%. Our second quarter results included a $25 million gain on the sale of two investments, which was recognized in North America in the Drilling and Evaluation segment. And a charge of $30 million for the settlement of the ReedHycalog patent dispute, which is included in corporate and other.</p>
          <p>Our first quarter results included $23 million for impairment charges on an oil and gas property in Bangladesh, which was included in the Middle East-Asia Drilling and Evaluation results and a $35 million gain related to the sale of an investment which was included in the North American Completion and Production results.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll highlight the results of our two operating segments. Completion and Production revenue increased $246 million or 11% from the first quarter while operating income increased $32 million or 6%. The higher sequential revenue was led by production enhancement with a growth rate of 15% driven by increased activity in U.S. land and Oman and a strong vessel utilization in Mexico and the North Sea.</p>
          <p>Looking at Completion and Production on a geographic basis, North American C&amp;P revenue increased 9% sequentially. Operating income was flat as the first quarter results included the $35 million gain previously discussed. The revenue increase was driven by higher activity across all product lines in both U.S. land and the Gulf of Mexico. This was partially offset by a decline in stimulation pricing of 1 to 2% as well as the seasonal spring break up in Canada.</p>
          <p>C&amp;P margins for North America continue to be impacted by higher costs related to materials and fuel prices. However, these increases are largely offset by increased equipment utilization. We've been successful in negotiating fuel surcharges and we should see the impact of these negotiations starting in the third quarter. We've also been talking with our customers about recovering our costs for other consumable materials and we'll provide an update on these discussions during the third quarter call.</p>
          <p>In Latin America, Completion and Production revenue increased 6% in the second quarter due to strong activity in Mexico, Brazil and Venezuela. However, the improved top line results were not enough to offset the negative impact of the union strikes in Argentina, so operating income declined 8%. We're not expecting a resolution of the strikes in the coming months and we're selectively transferring equipment to other countries in the region.</p>
          <p>Production enhancement experienced sequential revenue growth of 16% primarily driven by higher vessel utilization in Mexico. In the Europe/Africa/CIS region, Completion and Production revenue increased 26% and operating income increased 49%. The growth in revenue and operating income was driven by increased Completion Tools sales and favorable pricing adjustments in West Africa, strong activity across all product lines in Continental Europe and higher vessel utilization in the North Sea.</p>
          <p>In Middle East-Asia, Completion and Production posted sequential increases of 5% and 9% in revenue and operating income respectively. We experienced strong activity in Oman and Saudi Arabia. Our Khurais project in Saudi Arabia is ahead of schedule and we have started mobilizing for our Manifa project. In addition, strong sales of our completion tools in Indonesia and China contributed to the favorable performance.</p>
          <p>Now, in our Drilling and Evaluation division, revenue increased $212 million or 12% and operating income increased $96 million or 25% from the first quarter. We experienced strong sequential revenue growth in all product lines with Landmark, Baroid and Wireline posting double-digit increases. The sequential increase in operating income was driven by the flow through of higher revenue in the non-recurring items previously mentioned.</p>
          <p>Baroid margins increased more than 200 basis points from the first quarter and posted strong performance across all regions notably in the U.S., the North Sea and West Africa. In North America, Drilling and Evaluation revenue increased 4% and operating income increased by 11% sequentially as strong performance in our U.S. land operations from Baroid and Sperry offset the seasonally lower Canadian activity. Drilling and Evaluation's Latin America revenue increased 27% and operating income improved by 63% from the first quarter. The improvement was driven by higher activity associated with the Alliance Two integrated project in Southern Mexico.</p>
          <p>We are currently operating on four PEMEX supplied rigs and anticipate having six rigs by the end of the third quarter. Although this is a slower ramp up than we planned, the project is going exceptionally well. We are also seeing strong growth rates across all other countries in the region except for Argentina, and that's again due to the union strikes.</p>
          <p>In the Europe/Africa region, Drilling and Evaluation revenue and operating income increased 9% and 7% respectively. The increase was driven by higher drilling and multilateral activity in the North Sea, increased wireline activity in North Africa and favorable pricing adjustments in West Africa.</p>
          <p>Drilling and Evaluation revenue in the Middle East-Asia region increased 19%, while operating income improved 65%. Remember that the first quarter results were negatively impacted by the $23 million oil and gas impairment in Bangladesh. Additionally, the increase in operating income was driven by higher activity in Australia, Malaysia, and China across most product lines. In addition, increased Baroid revenues in the Middle East contributed to the strong performance.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll address some additional financial items. Nothing unusual on taxes this quarter. We continue to expect our full-year 2008 effective tax rate to be in the 30 to 32% range. During the second quarter of 2008, we updated our fair value calculation related to the indemnities provided to KBR during the separation process, relating to the FCPA investigations and the Barracuda-Caratinga bolt arbitration matter. We recorded an after-tax charge to discontinued operations of $117 million to reflect our most recent assumptions on the potential resolution of these issues.</p>
          <p>We currently have $1.2 billion of 3 1/8% convertible bonds outstanding. The conversion option has moved deeply in the money as our stock price has risen and the current market value of these bonds is ranging around 3 to $3.2 billion. So as the market value of the bonds greatly exceeds the par value and because we now have the ability to call the bonds although we have not yet elected to do so, a number of bondholders are electing to go ahead and exercise their right to convert.</p>
          <p>We're required to settle the $1.2 billion par amount in cash though we have the option to settle the approximately 1.8 to $2 billion premium in excess of par in either cash or stock. As we settle the premium in stock, we will do so with the issuance of Halliburton shares from treasury stock. Since the shares required to fully satisfy the premium on the converts are already included in our fully diluted EPS calculation, settling the premium in stock increases our basic share count but doesn't negatively impact diluted EPS. And to the extent we settle the premium in cash, our share count will go down but we will have an immediate earnings charge for the value paid.</p>
          <p>However, from an EPS standpoint, the higher ongoing interest expense for the increased borrowings should be offset by the lower shares outstanding. We expect our depreciation, depletion and amortization to average approximately $190 million per quarter for the rest of the year. And finally, we are increasing our capital expenditures guidance by $200 million to 1.9 to $2 billion for the full year. The incremental capital is to provide for equipment placements on the coming offshore rigs and to meet the growing demand of our customers in the emerging shale plays in North America. Tim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Mark, and good morning everyone. The continuing increase in shale activity and our role in developing these plays is a very important part of our North America story. As most of you know as activity shifts towards these plays, Halliburton is well-positioned to serve shale operators because of a combination of our reservoir expertise, proven technologies and broad infrastructure necessary to maximize the value of these assets.</p>
          <p>In the Woodford for example, stratigraphy and organic content are well understood, but due to their complexity compared to the Barnett, the formations are more difficult to drill and fracture. Horizontal wells in the Woodford are deeper with longer laterals, bigger frac jobs, and more stages. Cementing these long, horizontal sections has proved to be a challenge here. Wells cemented with conventional slurries have exhibited inadequate isolation of frac targets, which has led to reduced fracturing effectiveness and decreased production. Our zone shale cementing systems have significantly improved the segregation of targeted frac zones, prevented communication, and improved productivity. Well bore stability is an issue in the Lower Huron shale in the Northeast, where reducing exposure to the sensitive shales is critical.</p>
          <p>A combination of optimized Sperry bottom whole assemblies along with our electromagnetic telemetry technology has trimmed as many as five days from the typical drilling cycle there. Water production and water use are becoming significant challenges for our customers exploiting unconventional and tight reservoirs. In the San Juan and Green River basins, for example, our water management solutions eliminate the need to use potable water without compromising fluid qualities. Here our Omega frac fluid is the first linear fracturing fluid specifically designed to use a wide variety of field-produced brine water providing cost and environmental benefits to our customers and communities. And we're applying a similar approach in emerging shale plays.</p>
          <p>Now the Haynesville is in the early development stage and the environment is especially challenging with average depths over 12,500 feet, bottom hole temperatures approaching 350 degrees Fahrenheit and well head treating pressures exceeding 10,000 Psi. This requires the use of specialized drilling, pressure pumping, and fluids technology. Average drilling times are double those of the Barnett and fracturing requires almost twice the amount of hydraulic horse power at higher treating pressures. We estimate that Haynesville wells are currently about 1.5 to 1.7 times more drilling and fracturing intensive than those in the Barnett.</p>
          <p>Understanding fracture orientation and geometry is a key element of improving well performance. However, in this microseismic monitoring technology, exact frac, allows us to monitor frac propagation in real time to maximize well performance. In the Barnett we recently undertook a client study to evaluate a large number of wells using Landmark reservoir modeling tools with the exact frac service to both optimize horizontal well and the fracture placements.</p>
          <p>So we're pleased with these and other growing capabilities, an important component of a differentiated shale technology portfolio. Some of you may have seen the recent results from the Patent Board published this month in the Wall Street Journal, which provides a scorecard for industries based on indicators that track global patent activity related to innovation, technology and science strengths.</p>
          <p>For the energy and environmental industry, the latest survey showed Halliburton to be the leader for the third consecutive time. While we are pleased with our top ranking most importantly, the survey confirms the progress we have made in the last few years in enhancing the depth of our intellectual property and gives us the confidence that we are on track in delivering technology solutions for reservoirs that are becoming increasingly more challenging.</p>
          <p>We also continue to enhance our technology portfolio through acquisition. During the quarter we purchased the remaining 49% of WellDynamics, the world's leading provider of intelligent well completion technology. The acquisition provides a significant competitive advantage in delivering increased reservoir productivity and maximized ultimate recovery for our customers.</p>
          <p>We acquired Protech Centerform, the only provider of casing centralization that uses a carbon fiber and ceramic composite applied directly to casing. This complements our range of casing solutions, particularly for our customer's deep water and high-pressure, high-temperature drilling and completion challenges. We also completed the purchase of Knowledge Systems Inc., a respected provider of software and services that improve well planning and drilling by helping clients predict well bore geomechanics and pour pressure, so wells can be drilled safely and economically.</p>
          <p>So these three acquisitions strengthened our technology portfolio and give us greater resources to put into our broad distribution channels to support our next phase of growth. Dave?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tim. To summarize, we completed another excellent quarter with overall year-over-year growth rates of 20% and continued strong margins. We've seen prices stabilize across all of our product lines in North America. Our customers increased drilling plans are providing us with a more robust outlook for our services in the second half of the year. And all indications are that the shift of activity towards more service intensive plays will drive demand for our technologies that are specifically designed for more complex reservoirs.</p>
          <p>Internationally, we continue to make progress in balancing our geographic portfolio with year-over-year revenue growth of 26%. Margins were above our stated target. We have seen competition intensify but we believe we are well positioned given the breadth of our technology and the execution capabilities of our people. And I'd like to publicly thank our employees worldwide for delivering another excellent quarter. Let's go ahead and open it up for questions now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from David Anderson from UBS. Your question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Can you guys just talk a little bit about where you are with your utilization on the frac side? You base that generally on a five-day work week?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Utilization, thanks, Dave. Utilization is very high at the moment and we certainly have a preponderance of activity on a five-day week. We also have some Saturday work as well. So really a combination of the both at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I assume you expect that to continue to increase throughout the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes we do. I think particularly as you heard commentary during the course of the call, as we get into the third and fourth quarter, we certainly expect the pressure on utilization to increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And with regards to Canada right now, can you just kind of chat a little bit about in terms of the capacity situation up there and how does that compare to the U.S. and do you think you'll see any kind of equipment start to migrating north or is it just too much activity down here to see that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think as you heard us say, we really are expecting a much stronger second half in Canada, certainly much more strong than we had anticipated in the early part of the year. And as you know a fair amount of equipment did head south and elsewhere during the sort of the fall in Canadian activity. And I think it's reasonable to assume that some of that will return to Canada to meet the expectations there at the market. Certainly it's an area that we are undertaking careful consideration in terms of the disposition of our fleets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So do you think pricing should move up as well in Canada? I guess judging from your comments I guess I should infer yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think most certainly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. One last question. You'd mentioned in the Haynesville comparing to the Barnett, you said 1.5 to 1.7 times more fracture intensity, could you just expand upon that a little bit? Are you talking about, say, two comparable five-stage fracs or is this kind of like a all-in well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is really sort of more on a monthly basis really. I mean obviously drilling times in the Haynesville are longer and by the way that 1.5 to 1.7 was both sort of drilling and fracture intensity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But really sort of try to pare that down to a monthly evaluation, so you can get an assessment of what it means in terms of a monthly or quarterly revenue stream.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the Haynesville, it seems like that, sounds like the area where you are most focused on right now over the next call it, six months, fair to say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's clearly early days yet. There is a lot of work to be done. But I think we just wanted to kind of frame it as a point of reference for you in terms of what it might mean for the service industry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Tim, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Chuck Minervino of Goldman Sachs. Your question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Just a question on pressure pumping as well. Given the increased demand outlook here in activity levels, have your supply expectations changed at all for the pressure pumping market for the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We had basically told you on our last call that we expected a sort of 12 to 15% increase in capacity for 2008. And we still believe that to be a fairly good number in terms of capacity increases. Again lead times for equipment are still fairly long, probably in the range of nine months. So any decisions that were made in the last month or so really won't have any impact in terms of North America until clearly well into 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then when you stack that up with your demand outlook, are you looking for really flattish pricing for the remainder of the year or do you actually see pricing increasing in the second half of '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that clearly, it's going to be a matter of timing here. We had earlier expected to see stabilization in the second half of the year and clearly that came quite a lot earlier than we expected. That's stabilization occurred in really the, toward the end of Q2 rather than in Q3 that we had originally expected. So I think it's reasonable to assume that we'll see some modest increases during the course of Q3, but ramping up perhaps slightly more as we move into the back half, back end of the year. And clearly as you know, we're going to be in a renegotiation phase at the end of the year for 2009. And the climate for negotiation is clearly quite a bit different at the end of 2008 than it was at the end of 2007.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Ole Slorer of Morgan Stanley. Your question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Got a question first on the CapEx. You seem to get more bullish on your business in raising the CapEx, I think you said from 1.7 billion to $2 billion mentioning that this was partly because of offshore rigs and partly because of shale. Particularly on the offshore, what is it that's changed since the beginning of the year given that most of these offshore rigs under construction have been visible for quite a while, so what is it that triggered the greater enthusiasm for that space?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ole, of course we monitor all our projects on an ongoing basis and then really, this is really I would say as much as anything an adjustment to our view of the future with respect to the projects which we see, the projects which we think we should receive. And clearly North America plays a part in that picture as well. So I think you should take this generally speaking as a good sign of our confidence in the market ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ole, this is Dave, let me add to that. Also with the delay of the arrival of a lot of the offshore rigs, we diverted that equipment that we had built in anticipation of that marketplace developing into other parts of the business and to some extent we're now having to back-fill that equipment to meet those rigs as they are coming on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that makes sense. Secondly in Mexico on Teconitipac you bid that quite a different level to the company that was awarded the contract. Could you comment a little bit on that as well as your strategy on future IPM work and all project management work in Mexico? You've been awarded a small contract there, but are you targeting some of the bigger tenders coming up or what's your strategy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let sort of talk about IPM in general for us, that's obviously a very important part of our portfolio. And as we may have mentioned before, sort of on any given day we're sort of operating typically around about 30 IPM projects of one kind or another in about 10 countries around the globe. So we have a pretty important portfolio and certainly Latin America represents the most important part of that portfolio, also the US, North Africa and so forth are other important elements of the portfolio. But yes, we certainly intend to participate and support primarily of our NOC customers as they tend to turn a little bit more towards this approach to help them develop and exploit their fields.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So to finish, how you see that opportunity compared, it was going on in the offshore market? Is there any difference in margin if you allocate your tools to an onshore project versus allocating them to the offshore?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think as we may have commented to you on the prior call, actually if we take a look at our international business, in general, about half our business internationally is driven by offshore activity and both our share and margin are slightly better in offshore activities. So that sort of gives you a general guide. Of course IPM type activities are not always exclusive to onshore, they also take place in offshore activities as well such as we've completed in the North Sea. So it's really a blend I think of both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well done. Congratulations for that very good performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ole.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Jim Crandell of Lehman Brothers. Your question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi just as a follow up to Ole's question. You had said earlier or Dave said earlier that one of the negative things about margin was pricing competition on large tenders. Do you consider your IPM business in general to be a lower margin business than your ongoing international business since you cited it in your opening comments? And B, seems that everybody likes to snipe at each other's IPM contracts. There's certainly been a lot of talk about how far down you bid on Manifa to win that contract, would that fall into that category about a lower margin business than your total?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah I think there's a lot of discussion around IPM activities, and just sort of for the record, we really don't consider Manifa to be an IPM project. It's something, which we project manage ourselves. But for us, the definition of IPM really requires us to have some involvement in the management of rigs and the total operation, just to sort of put a little clarity to that. But I think within the scope of our definition in terms of IPM, as I said, we think it's a really important part of the portfolio. It's clearly a model which is in favor for a number of our large national oil company customers and it's something that we intend to respond to as a company. We also intend to manage the risk and ensure that clearly our execution is up to snuff to ensure that we deliver the margins which are consistent with the rest of our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You said though, Tim, that price competition on larger tenders would be sort of a negative offsetting factor to other factors giving profit margins. So to ask the question again, is your IPM business lower margin business overall than your rest of your international oil service business? And how many of these, can you give some percentage or rough guidance on how many of these 30 IPM projects you consider to be competitively bid and where there is the price competition that you said right off the bat in your opening comments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim, with respect to the comment regarding sort of larger contracts, I think in the international space, we can clearly say that the overall sort of size of the tranches of work which are being let by our customers, IPM or not, becoming significantly larger. And this is for a number of reasons, some of which are related to the ability to get access to services and some obviously are relating to bargaining power of our customer base. But the point is, is that the projects are tending to get larger and it requires us to ensure that we obviously execute well. But it also requires that we provide new technologies into those contracts to ensure that during the life of those contracts, we manage them from start to finish to ensure that we drive margin improvement during the life of the contract.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim, this is Mark. I also want to add on to your specific question about the margin differentials between IPM work and the rest of our international business. They are not that much different. They are very much in line and that's how we risk manage these things to make sure that we deliver for our shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Mark, thank you, that's very helpful. One final question, would you, you talked about the one-year tender as being renegotiated in a much different environment as we get toward the end of the year. Would you expect given the cost increases for labor, materials etcetera, would you expect to have real price improvement on your one-year tenders rollovers to take place later this year or in early 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim, this is Dave. Let me answer that one. I think that we're somewhat in the environment we were a couple of years ago where I think we will clearly press for price increases. But I think what you're going to see is you will get specifically allocated price increases for such thing as maybe shortage in certain commodity chemicals, fuel prices, that sort of thing as sort of a pass-through increase. And then we will negotiate for a price increase on the base services work. And I think we probably, we're, are a little bit further down the road before we'll be able to push for sort of a peer price increase like we were getting a couple of years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think it's also fair to say we are not waiting for the contract rollovers to go after the cost recovery portion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Mike Urban of Deutsche Bank. Your question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning. Wanted to dig a little bit more on today's favorite topic, IPM. Is some of the competitive pressure that you're seeing out there based on competitors who own rigs, bidding those more aggressively or is it difficult to tell or is it just kind of across-the-board competitive pressure on those large projects?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that really the main issue is having access to rigs and our position to this point has been that we do not wish to own rigs. We partner with suppliers of rigs to execute. We have a number of I think very good examples in a number of markets where we have developed strong relationships and execute collectively very well against our targets for our customers. So at this point, no I don't think it's a particular disadvantage to us at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean I would agree in terms of the efficiency that you guys offer and the quality of the service, but I mean is there a sense out there that those competitors are bidding both perhaps below market rates on the rigs in order to come in low on the project as a whole?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure why anyone would want to do that in today's current market. I guess it's possible, but I think they would be leaving some money on the table if they did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the follow-up to that pertains to the international margins as a whole. I think you have spoken to this a little bit, given that you are going to keep aggressive pricing on the large projects, would you say that pricing on kind of non-IPM work is improving on average or is it more the infrastructure leverage and the up-selling that's driving the margin improvement you expect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think &#x2013; this is Dave. I think it's a little bit of both. Certainly you have the leverage of the expanding footprint and your ability to take on more volume and provides you absolute operating income dollars. But also the theory around these bigger projects is to get in and then up-sell your new technologies because typically these are multiple year contracts in many cases with options to extend that our customers hold. So it's paramount basically to get in, get the project and then up-sell. And I think that we have done a pretty good job in doing that over the past several years and that's no secret formula out there. I mean everybody tries to do it but I think it's something that we have gotten pretty good at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Kurt Hallead of RBC. Your question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning. Just wanted to try to calibrate a couple of things. On Weatherford's call yesterday, they referenced price increases about 10 to 15% in North America. And then they mentioned something like 15% plus price increases internationally. They did reference the fact that it was varied by product line and so on. But I just want to try to gauge how that jives with how you are seeing the market right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sure it's not unreasonable to expect on certain items or products to see pricing increase in those ranges. And certainly when you take a look at the overall inflation for hydrocarbon based goods, let's say specialty chemicals for example, or for that matter machined items, etcetera, the inflation has really been quite substantial. So it's not unreasonable to assume that those may be quite reasonable rates. I think however for a broad basket of services such as is within Halliburton's portfolio, I think the guidance that we gave you a little earlier is probably closer to being more appropriate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just want to follow up also when Schlumberger talked last Friday, they gave a pretty positive outlook with respect to an acceleration in their international programs and I wanted to see if that's kind of caused you guys to get more optimistic with your growth rates for international business for 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we sort of commented a little bit earlier, we did adjust our capital outlook slightly as we sort of readjusted our portfolio with respect to portfolio projects if you like. So yeah we continue to see a very robust outlook and certainly have no reason to sort of diminish our enthusiasm for the coming year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So again, that CapEx increase was for offshore and for shale. Most of that seems like it's going to be geared for North America. But I was just trying to get a reference point on how incrementally optimistic you are about international growth rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the, I think what I said was that a lot of the stuff that we had planned for the offshore rigs has actually been diverted already into the U.S. market. So the increase in capital we are looking at actually is to serve the non-North America and offshore markets. So I think that sort of bodes well and gives an indication of our enthusiasm for what we see to be continued growth rates in the Eastern Hemisphere.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question is from Michael Lamotte of JPMorgan. Your question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning guys. I don't know if Dave or Tim if you are better to answer this question. But I'm trying to think about the North American market and really how it's changing versus maybe the '05, '06 timeframe where it was all about build the equipment and provide as much slick frac capacity as you can and as the new shale plays emerge, it's very clear that the technology penetration and uptake is a lot greater. And I'm just wondering sort of how, I guess, two-part question here, one is how you market, how is marketing to the client different today versus a few years ago with respect to North America? And two if we consider the margin opportunity in this kind of technology-oriented environment, could we actually see profitability get better than what we saw in '05, '06?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on a broad basis, let's just take a look at the sort of, I think the root of this question really revolves around is there a bifurcation of the market or not between the major players and perhaps the new entrants. And it might be helpful just to reference some data that Spears and Associates provided in terms of trending of both horsepower and revenues over time. So they indicated that from 2003 to 2007 that the horsepower of the big three in proportion to the total industry dropped from around about 75% to about 50%. And interesting though, if you look at the amount of revenues for the same time period, proportion or revenue that the big three had in relation to the entire industry dropped from about 80% to roughly 75%. So I think you can really see there is really a significant difference in the revenue per horsepower between the big three players and the smaller factoring players. And I'm convinced that this is clearly a representation of the technology which is applied and the value which is received. So I think that's point number one.</p>
          <p>And point number two for us, you've heard us say a couple of times, we're really very focused on trying to balance the portfolio in North America between all our various product lines. So no longer for us is it solely about fracturing by itself. We're really trying to put together a group of products and services and an efficiency model for our customers that really can drive value and productivity for them. And if I was to sort of call out one most significant change for us over the 2005 timeframe, I think it's the maturity which we had in that kind of approach to our markets and our customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful color, Tim. And maybe if I think about that trend of '03 to '07 with the technology penetration rate seeming to increase, would it be fair to say that that should trend to the faster rate over the next few years? In terms of revenue per horsepower?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe that our customers today are really becoming very focused on the productivity of their wells. And some of the color commentary that I was trying to provide a little earlier was I think a commentary on some of the thoughtfulness which our customers are entering into with respect to the longevity in the investment that they are making in these plays and the need to ensure that it's not about simply punching wells down. It's really about maximizing the productivity. And I think that really is really something which will be very beneficial to us and others that can offer something similar to the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think &#x2013; this is Dave, let me just add one last comment. I think not only do you have sort of a bifurcation going on around the ability and the technology of the frac but you also have much more of a linking together of other product lines on some of these shale plays. Tim mentioned earlier the need to get a very specific and different sort of cement job down before you can do the number of stages of fracing you want to do. The placement in a well using directional drilling is much more important. So we are seeing more of our customers in these types of plays come to us for sort of a multiple product line solution. And I think that will also help to differentiate the bigger service companies from those that perhaps don't have as strong a cementing or drilling or completion position than some of the newer entrants might have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great, thanks. Mark, a couple of quick clean up questions for you. Looking at cash balances, I'm trying to reconcile the dip in interest income from run rate in the last few quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's really driven by a couple of different things. One is obviously interest rates have fallen this year and so that's having an influence. The other side of it, last year we did have some auction rate securities. We got out of those in early January, no losses on our part but effectively that lowered our overall yields. And so that's really the two drivers of the overall income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then lastly on the KBR arbitrations, any timetable of when that investigation or arbitration process will be wrapping up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, there is really no timetable. Obviously we've had ongoing discussions all along with the Department of Justice, with the SEC and then the arbitration matter is continuing on and we've been fully cooperating with those investigations. The update that we did from an accounting standpoint is a normal process. We use an outside third party to help us do that and we are just -- we're obviously working to resolve them as quickly we can but we're not really the sole drivers of that timetable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from Dan Pickering of Tudor Pickering Holt &amp; Company. Your question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning guys. I wanted to circle back to this international growth opportunity. Dave, in your comments earlier, you kind of called out that the second quarter grew 26% year-over-year and kind of above your 20% expectation. I just, coming back to, I mean is this growth rates sustainable&gt;</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Dan, we set a long term goal of growing in excess of 20% a year in our non-North American operations and we don't see anything out there right now that would say that it's not sustainable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And then I guess a philosophical question as it relates to the North American market, particularly in pressure pumping. Last cycle pricing went up very quickly, margins expanded very quickly and a lot of new competitors came in. Capacity additions, Tim you addressed that in your discussion around capacity growth. Do, as you think about this market developing going forward, do we just let prices go where they will, run them up as much as we can or is it a more measured approach to sort of manage the capacity additions that might come as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of differences perhaps. So I'll maybe comment and Dave will obviously add any comments as he sees fit. But I think we are in a very different environment. We are clearly in a more inflationary environment today than we were in the sort of 2005 timeframe. So I think there clearly is an element of sort of recovery here, which has to take place, which clearly will mute pricing realization relative to the 2005 timeframe. I think that having been through a cycle of unbridled optimism in North America, I think it's our general belief that we will see perhaps a sort of more ordered process this time and worst of all certainly see some pricing leverage. I'm not sure that we are certainly planning on anything like the sort of 2005, 2006 timeframe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Dan just to add a little bit to that. I think the larger pressure pumping companies on sort of the last cycle really tried to balance revenue growth with margin growth, whereas I think some of the newer entrants were very much interested in market share and revenue growth with not as much attention being paid to sort of the return on capital and the return on investment they made on that equipment. And I think that as the market has moved more back into balance, I would hope that everybody sort of has learned that lesson and that you really do need to balance the revenue growth with the margin growth. But I think for the reasons we articulated earlier, there really has been bifurcation in the market too in terms of where, sort of what part of the street or what part of the neighborhood you can play in as a pressure pumping company. And I think that will be a bit of a limiting factor on the number of newer entrants that perhaps can come in to some of these more specialized plays</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is from Robin Shoemaker of Citigroup. Your question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Just to change the top for a minute. I wanted to ask you a question about your M&amp;A strategy, post the Expro situation. It seemed that that would have been clearly a much different kind of merger than the ones you have transacted here in the last year and I think you described it as transformational. But in light of that experience, what do you think are the prospects for Halliburton making a merger or an acquisition that would grow your international footprint, enter a new market such as Expro would have done in the current kind of competitive environment for M&amp;A?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thanks Robin for that question. I think clearly we continue to be very active in terms of our M&amp;A pursuits. You saw that we closed three acquisitions during the course of the quarter, all of which have some element of support for international markets. And so really we're focused in two main areas. Number one is the sort of shall I say technology additions, for which we can utilize our distribution network around the globe to enhance their growth. And secondly, in a certain number of areas, some geographic acquisitions where we feel we're not as well served as we would like to be, and in which case we can take our technologies and put them through that distribution network. So we continue to have an active program. We kind of committed to you that we would continue to focus on that. And that's something that we certainly expect to do. I think it's fair to say that there, it is a fairly aggressive market and we have to make our choices and we have to have a bright line beyond which we will not cross in terms of pricing and value. But nonetheless we still feel there are a number of opportunities out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Yeah, understood. You mentioned earlier, I think you described them as underserved markets. I assume that's both organic and potentially M&amp;A. What, I mean on a geographic kind of basis, what are the, in your mind the primary underserved markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've sort of publicly stated several of those underserved markets. Clearly Russia is one of those markets where we do feel we've got significant headroom opportunity. I think India is another market to which we were somewhat late to play. So those would be two examples of two significantly underserved markets for us. I should add that, though, it would only be fair to add that our growth rates in those markets is very good, however it is clearly from a smaller base than we would ideally like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, right. Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question is from Alan Laws of Merrill Lynch. Your question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I know we always ask you about fracturing capacity additions. I wonder if you could talk a little bit about the supply/demand balance, what that looks like for the cementing equipment? You talked about in your comments some weakness in the quarter. Was that a regional phenomenon or is that a broadly-based statement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No actually the cementing overall really held up much more so than the fracturing business during the course of the last couple of quarters. And our feeling is that the slight softness that we saw during the course of the second quarter was somewhat temporary. So we really don't see this being a long-term phenomenon. We are fairly sure that the capacity adds in the sector don't materially change the overall balance here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great and you also talked about multiple product lines and I wondered if you could comment a little bit on if there any choke points in providing those packaged services and maybe talk a little bit about in particular directional drilling business and how tight that presently is in North America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Directional drilling clearly is an area of tightness on a global basis actually. And so if I was to sort of point to one area in the provision of services overall, I would probably say that in North America that is one where there is some degree of tightness, though I believe that within Halliburton the work which we have undertaken to expand our manufacturing and supply chain capacity is something which allows us to meet the demand from our key customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. The one last thing I just wanted to ask is about the Rockies market, a big market for you. Can you talk about maybe the outlook for growth there given developing capacity issues on the REX pipeline? Have you thought about those things at all internally?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I mean clearly this sort of continues &#x2013; the Rockies clearly is a very important location for us in North America. Clearly one of the stars for us and we continue to be very enthusiastic about the outlook particularly driven by REX.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That concludes our call this morning. Please call us if you have any further questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for participating in today's conference. This concludes the program, you may now disconnect. Good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>