<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1497638" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-08-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>836</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Director-Investor Relations">George Toulantas</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman of the Executive Board/CEO, HEINEKEN Holding NV">Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois M. L. van Boxmeer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Member-Executive Board">Reinout Duco Hooft Graafland</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Ian M. Shackleton</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Trevor Stirling</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="ING Bank NV (Broker)">Gerard Rijk</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Jonathan P. Fell</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Securities USA, Inc.">Lauren E. Torres</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Olivier Nicola&#xEF;</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Andrea Pistacchi</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Royal Bank of Scotland Plc (Broker)">James H. Edwardes Jones</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Samar Chand</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (United Kingdom)">Philip M. Morrisey</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Matthew C. Webb</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by and welcome to the HEINEKEN Half Year Results 2012 Conference Call on August 22, 2012. Throughout today's presentation, all participants will be in a listen-only mode. After the presentation, there'll be an opportunity to ask questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I'd now like to hand the conference over to George Toulantas, Director of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, operator. Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us today to discuss HEINEKEN's half year 2012 results. I'm joined by Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois van Boxmeer, CEO and Chairman of the Executive Board, and Ren&#xE9; Hooft Graafland, CFO and Member of the Executive Board. Following prepared remarks, we will open the call for your questions.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn the call over to Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>So good morning, everybody. I will take you, together with Ren&#xE9;, through our slide presentation, and I hope that the synchronization will work well. Before discussing &#x2013; and I take you to page three of our presentation, before discussing our half year results, I would like to make a few brief comments in relation to Asia Pacific Breweries.</p>
          <p>We're pleased to have signed a formal agreement with the Board of Fraser &amp; Neave to acquire their entire stake in APB. We're also pleased that they will recommend the proposed transaction to their shareholders. This is an important milestone in the process of gaining full control of APB. The proposed transaction remains subject, of course, to approval from the shareholders of Fraser &amp; Neave. And as you will have seen, we have announced that yesterday we acquired 6.9 million shares in APB directly, and that brings the total percentage of APB shares owned by Heineken to 44.6% as we speak.</p>
          <p>The Southeast and the Pacific Island contain some of the most exciting and high growth markets for beer. It's a reason we know well since establishing the joint venture operation of APB some 80 years ago, and so we are 100% committed to the continued growth of both APB and the Tiger brand, and we will keep our regional headquarters in Singapore going forward.</p>
          <p>Given that the proposed transaction is still subject to approval from the F&amp;N shareholders, we will update the market further at that time. I would, therefore, politely request that you focus your questions today on our first half 2012 results, which I would now like to cover, and so I flip the page to slide number five.</p>
          <p>And during the first half, we delivered a solid top line growth, with an organic revenue up 4.5% and growth across all regions. This was achieved despite poor weather conditions across many of our Western European markets in the second quarter. Higher volume and pricing contributed to this revenue growth, with revenue per hectoliter up a solid 2.9%.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we continued to gain market share across several of our key markets, such as France, Mexico, the Netherlands, Russia, Nigeria, UK and the U.S. Heineken premium volume grew 6%, outperforming the overall beer market and the international premium segment again.</p>
          <p>TCM2, our cost management program, delivered savings in the first half of &#x20AC;85 million, and we have also achieved our &#x20AC;150 million cost saving target for the beer operations of FEMSA, and that is almost one year ahead of plan. Despite the benefit of higher revenue and cost savings, EBIT (beia) declined by 5.5%. This was largely due to lower profitability in Europe, higher input costs, and also higher planned investments in building global capabilities, in the first place our global business service which is in full swing of being built up.</p>
          <p>Now I take you to the next slide, slide number six, which is titled emerging markets driving volume and revenue gains, to be able to follow me. Volume and revenue performance was once again led by our higher growth regions. In Africa and the Middle East, we grew in almost all markets, led by mid single-digit growth and market share gains in Nigeria. The effect of higher inflation and social unrest in some parts of the country impacted consumer spending, leading to stable volume in the second quarter. In Egypt, we returned to growth following the unrest of last year.</p>
          <p>The Asia Pacific region, again, achieved healthy revenue and profit growth. The joint venture operations of APB, United Breweries in India and our export operations, all contributed to this strong performance.</p>
          <p>In Central and Eastern Europe, volume in Russia grew in the mid-teens, leading to further market share gains. The volume also grew across our key markets of Poland, Romania and Austria. The difficult trading conditions in Greece resulted in a low double-digit volume decline. The regional EBIT (beia) declined substantially, reflecting negative channel and country mix, higher input costs and lower profitability in Greece.</p>
          <p>In Western Europe, the challenging economic conditions and unfavorable weather impacted volume. However, effective marketing and strong marketplace execution drove market share gains in France, the Netherlands and the UK. Despite the benefit of higher pricing, input cost pressure and lower than planned volumes impacted the region's profitability, as you can see.</p>
          <p>The positive Americas region performance was led by strong top and bottom line results in Mexico and continued positive volume growth momentum in the U.S. In Brazil, whilst overall volume was stable, the Heineken brand grew by just less than 50% year-on-year following strong marketplace activation.</p>
          <p>I'll take you now to slide seven and a little bit zooming on Mexico. In Mexico, our strategy remains focused on driving long-term value growth. In the first half, it was evident with EBIT (beia) growth 2.5 times that of revenue. Volume grew in the mid single-digits, thanks in part to continued retail outlet expansion in the modern trade channel.</p>
          <p>The Heineken brand continued strong growth supported by targeted outlet expansion and effective marketing. In the second quarter we introduced a new returnable bottle for Sol, as we continue to support long-term brand equity building. And we remain encouraged by Mexico's long-term prospects. Accordingly, we will continue to invest behind our strong brand portfolio and further leverage our improved commercial capabilities to drive future growth.</p>
          <p>A word about Heineken, next slide. The Heineken brand growth accelerated to 6% in the first half. This was led by strong growth of 20% in Africa and the Middle East, 8% in Asia Pacific, and 7% in the Americas. In the U.S., Heineken brand shipments, which is the sales to the wholesalers, went up 6% compared with broadly stable depletions, that is the sales from the wholesalers to the retailers. Now if shipments would have grown in line with depletions, the Heineken brand growth in the Americas region would have been over 3%. Globally, we continue to build consistent brand equity for the Heineken brand with the success of the Open Your World campaigns.</p>
          <p>Let me now take you to the next slide, nine. We remain committed to delivering sustainable top line growth and enhancing margins through investments in global brands and innovation. Besides Heineken, of course, Desperados grew 12.5%, with growth in Poland, France, Germany, as well as in markets across Europe where the brand was recently launched. In January, our UK operation took over brand distribution rights. This will deliver increased brand focus and will also improve consistency with the brand's global positioning.</p>
          <p>Sol brand was successfully launched in Finland in March of this year, supported by a new global marketing campaign, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (09:19), which we will use in more geographies to come. Amstel Premium Pilsner, which is a new line extension of Amstel, was launched in Greece and Russia, which line extension helped deliver overall Amstel brand growth of 4.5%.</p>
          <p>Strongbow Gold was launched in Hungary earlier this year; recently announced the acquisition of Stassen, a company based in Belgium with proven cider innovation capabilities that will also provide additional cider production capacity in Europe. We will also regain the rights to distribute Strongbow in the U.S. as from January 2013. This will further complement our increasingly diverse portfolio of products in the country.</p>
          <p>In the UK, a new flavor variant, Strongbow Pear was launched as we aim to further broaden consumer appeal in the cider category. They are all laughing here at my poor pronunciation of Pear. And let me now take you to slide number 10, which is about the stage in which we are &#x2013; with our Global Business Services, we are leveraging our global capabilities beyond innovation.</p>
          <p>The recent establishment of Global Business Services organization as a key enabler of TCM2 cost savings program. The Heineken Global Shared Service center in Poland will drive efficiencies in financial transactional services. In the first half of 2012, our UK and Romanian operations were successfully transitioned to the shared service center. We are planning to transition a second wave of countries, comprising France, Ireland and Hungary, for the fourth quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>The Heineken Procurement Group based in the Netherlands will further leverage our scale across purchasing activities. As an example of this, in May we entered into a new global agreement that consolidates our media buying into one agency worldwide, and that will generate considerable savings for Heineken.</p>
          <p>I close my presentation with slide 11 and outlook for 2012. We expect to deliver a solid year of top line growth, driven by strong momentum in high growth markets. We have increased our input cost outlook from 6% to approximately 8%, which Ren&#xE9; will cover shortly as to the causes of that.</p>
          <p>We are expecting our marketing spend as a percentage of revenue to be 12.5% compared with 12.8% last year. Our gross capital expenditure of &#x20AC;1.2 billion versus &#x20AC;800 million last year reflects our higher planned investment in new capacity, mainly across Africa, commercial assets, primarily new fridges to secure product availability, and the upgrading of our returnable bottle fleet in high growth markets, including Mexico and Nigeria. This is expected to result in a cash conversion ratio of below 100% this year.</p>
          <p>In line with our plans, we expect a stronger profit performance in the second half of the year. For the full year, net profit (beia) is expected to be broadly in line with last year on an organic basis. Our results today confirm the success of our strategy to deliver solid top line growth. Combined with our ongoing efficiency initiatives, we remain well-placed to continue delivering long-term value to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>And I will now turn the call over to Ren&#xE9;, who will discuss further our first half financial performance. Ren&#xE9;?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois, and good morning, everyone. Let me take you through the key financial highlights of our first half results. We are pleased with our top line performance in a year of investments. Group beer volume was up 3.3% with growth in all regions, except Western Europe. We continued to witness strong volume momentum across Africa, Asia, and Central and Eastern Europe, and improved trends in the Americas region.</p>
          <p>Volume of the Heineken brand in the premium segment grew 6%, with the largest contribution to growth coming from the U.S., Vietnam, China, Brazil and Nigeria. Revenue rose a very solid 4.5% organically with growth in all regions. And although revenue growth was very strong, EBIT (beia) organically declined by 5.5%, and I will explain the main drivers of that in a moment.</p>
          <p>Net profit (beia) increased 1.6%, as lower organic growth was more than offset by a positive consolidation impact and favorable currency movements. Organically, net profit (beia) declined by 4%. This mainly reflects the lower EBIT (beia) results, partly offset by lower interest expense and a lower effective tax rate. Diluted EPS (beia) increased 4% to &#x20AC;1.22, reflecting higher net profit (beia) and a lower weighted average number of shares, following the completion of the ASDI share repurchase program last October.</p>
          <p>Reported revenue in the first half grew 5% to &#x20AC;8.7 billion. This includes favorable currency movements of &#x20AC;21 million, mainly related to the naira and the British pound. And a positive consolidation impact increased revenues by &#x20AC;20 million, and this includes the two acquired breweries in Ethiopia, the Galaxy Pub Estate in the UK, and the acquisition of a controlling stake in a brewery in Haiti. Organic revenue grew 4.5%, and this growth was well-balanced with total consolidated volume up 1.6% and revenue per hectoliter growth of 2.9%. Excluding a 0.5% negative country mix effect, the revenue per hectoliter would have risen 3.4%.</p>
          <p>Now let's have a look at the EBIT. EBIT declined organically by 5.5% as we cycled solid profit growth from the first half of last year. The main factors contributing to this lower EBIT (beia) result includes, first of all, lower profitability in Europe, as increased input costs, lower than planned volumes, and adverse channel and country mix was only partly offset by higher pricing. Secondly, higher planned spending on business capability building investments, particularly across the Global Business Services, commerce and supply chain functions. A &#x20AC;21 million impairment charge related to our share of an investment in our Heineken/APB joint venture in China.</p>
          <p>And finally, input costs; input costs per hectoliter rose 6.9%, and this is 90 basis points above our earlier full year outlook of 6%. And that primarily reflects the faster growth of countries with higher input costs inflation and also a shift towards higher-priced one-way packaging in a number of our key markets. We expect to recover a large part of this higher input cost inflation through higher revenue per hectoliter growth in the second half of the year compared with the first half.</p>
          <p>Then go to net profit, reported net profit grew 30% to &#x20AC;705 million, and this includes a revaluation gain of &#x20AC;20 million related to the brewery in Haiti and &#x20AC;131 million booked gain from the stake &#x2013; the sale of our stake in the brewery in the Dominican Republic. Organically, net profit (beia) declined by 4%, and this mirrors the operating performance partly offset by lower interest and taxation expense.</p>
          <p>At the start of the year, we announced our three-year Total Cost Management program, TCM2, covering the period up to 2014. TCM2 is expected to generate pre-tax savings of &#x20AC;500 million. And to refresh your memory, we have realized already pre-tax savings of &#x20AC;1.1 billion over the past six years from our earlier programs, Fit 2 Fight and TCM1.</p>
          <p>In the first half of the year, we realized &#x20AC;85 million of pre-tax savings, with around 60% of these savings coming from Europe. As communicated earlier, we expect upfront GBS investments of &#x20AC;200 million up to the end of 2014. Last year, we incurred &#x20AC;32 million, and a further &#x20AC;29 million was spent in the first half of this year, bringing the total expense to &#x20AC;61 million up to now.</p>
          <p>Looking at the marketing spend in the first half of the year, marketing and selling expense increased by 1.7% organically, representing 13.3% of revenues compared with some 13.6% in the first half of last year. We continue to improve the effectiveness of our marketing spend with consumer-facing spend up 6% organically. As a reminder, consumer-facing spend includes media advertising, sponsorships, POS materials and promotions. We expect the marketing spend ratio in the second half of the year to be below the first half, and for the full year we expect marketing and selling expense as a percentage of revenue to be at 12.5%, slightly below the 12.8% we had last year.</p>
          <p>The free operating cash flow was &#x20AC;345 million compared to the &#x20AC;779 million last year, and this is mainly due to the higher capital investments in new capacity and returnable bottles in higher growth markets. Secondly, increased working capital driven by sales growth and higher inventory levels in Africa to support business expansion. And lastly, a payout of almost &#x20AC;100 million related to prior year restructuring initiatives. For the full year, we expect the gross capital expenditure of &#x20AC;1.2 billion, and as indicated previously, we expect our cash conversion rate to be below 100% this year.</p>
          <p>In March of this year, Heineken was assigned solid credit ratings from the world's two largest rating agencies. Following this, we have successfully issued five bonds at low coupon rates, with maturities ranging between seven and 13 years. As a result, we have further improved our debt maturity profile and achieved particularly favorable financing rates. While for the full year interest rate guidance, we remain &#x2013; that remains unchanged at 5.5%, we expect that these recent bond issues will benefit our interest rates from 2013 onwards.</p>
          <p>I would like to conclude these opening remarks by saying that we are pleased with the solid top line performance in the first half of the year under challenging market conditions. For the second half of the year, we expect continued solid top line growth and an improved underlying profit performance. As a result, we expect net profit (beia) to be broadly in line with last year on an organic basis.</p>
          <p>On that note, Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois and I would be happy to take your questions. Operator, can you open the floor please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Ian Shackleton from Nomura. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, gentlemen. You're flagging better pricing in the second half of this year, and I just wonder whether you'll give us a little bit more detail about which markets. I mean, it strikes me both in Western and Eastern Europe you see margin declines in the first half, and that is presumably where you're going to be focusing. But please give us a little bit more color on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So what you will see in the second half of the year is, first of all, that you've got the full benefit of pricing we have taken in the first half of the year. Then, secondly, in a number of countries we are pushing further up with prices. An important market in that respect is Russia, but also we try to catch up in a market like Poland. So it is certainly in Central and Eastern Europe where we will have to take more pricing. In Western Europe, it is more that you get the full benefit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And really to cover that higher input cost guidance of 8% of the cost increases, what sort of price mix are you really looking at in the second half? Are you talking about over 4% for the Group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we don't give any specific figure apart from that we expect better or further improved price mix in the second half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I would just ask one supplement around Nigeria, it's flattened off in Q2 after some very strong growth last year or so. Is that a trend that we should expect to continue given the political situation there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I think it's hard to make prediction of political situation, but the fundamentals of Nigeria are still very good. The oil pricing is working for Nigeria. The high growth in the urban areas is &#x2013; and particularly in the southern part of the country, is working for Nigeria. So even if we noticed kind of a pause in the second quarter, we don't think that that is a trend going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Trevor Stirling from Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois and Ren&#xE9;. Three questions, please. The first thing, returning to the question about input cost inflation, I think I'm right, you had guided a 6% with more higher cost in the first half and lower in the second half. Now it's 8%. With the 6.9% in the first half, presumably that means closer to 9% in the second half. So maybe if you could talk &#x2013; just give us a little more color on, versus your expectations, where did the increased country volumes come that are driving that higher inflation, and where is that packaging increase coming?</p>
          <p>Second question relating to Central and Eastern Europe and, I suppose, pricing there. Your price mix in Russia, you're implying was flat in the half. Your two nearest competitors, one in the last quarter reported 6% and the other reported 14% price mix in Central and Eastern Europe in Russia and the Ukraine. I guess, is the volume growth you're getting in Russia of sufficient quality?</p>
          <p>And third question around TCM and cost savings and how the money is being spent. I noticed a very positive result on TCM savings, but also personnel expenses were up 6.6% organically, so well ahead of revenue. Is that a phasing thing? Are you getting double running costs at the moment on GBS and that personnel cost is going to reverse? Or if that's a real increase, perhaps you give us more color about how and where that money is being spent and what level of return you're expecting from those higher personnel expenses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so on the input cost and the fact that we are above to what we have guided before, that has a number of factors. It is partly because the growth in higher inflation countries. And certainly in a country like Nigeria, where we buy locally our sorghum, you have seen that after the withdrawal of the fuel subsidy, inflation has spiked in Nigeria and you see that back in your input cost.</p>
          <p>Secondly, you see in a number of markets shifts and strong shifts to one-way packaging. That has to do partly with the development of the market, in a market like Poland, where modern retail is taking from the moms and pops stores and that is all one way, so you go from returnable into one-way. But this is also the shift from the on-premise to the off-premise. You can imagine that when you sell beer in kegs, there are no packaging costs in that respect. And if you then go to the off-premise and you have the one-way packaging, that has an impact on it.</p>
          <p>So it is not so much that the barley or the malt we have contracted at the beginning of the year that that is changing, because that is not the case, but it is geographical mix. It is the change within the markets, and there is a number of just technical things, because these are all organic figures. If you look at the market with hyperinflation, like Belarus, there you get on your input cost per hectoliter in the way out is reported you get obviously a very strong spike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On Russia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the price mix in....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The price mix of Russia, Trevor, we are obviously not market leaders. So in pricing we have to be mindful of the steps others that are bigger than us are taking. We have been concentrating on gaining back share on the backdrop of our big losses when we made mistakes on how we could price in the market some two years ago. We are back to where we wanted to be.</p>
          <p>And we pursue a policy which is aimed at creating share also in value and improving our mix. Certainly the second half is going to be better than the first half in terms of pricing for us in Russia. And the second good news coming out of Russia is that our policy of focusing on the top end of the portfolio, the premium end of the portfolio, is starting to give really good results. So that is what I can say about Russia. So we're confident to be able to improve the situation over there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe may I add one thing, because you implied a bit in your question that we have not been taking price in Russia. We have taken this year five price increases in total for over 6%. I think it's 6.5%. As Jean says, we are certainly not leading in price in the market, but we are taking price.</p>
          <p>The fact that the price mix is so low is because a big part of the growth is at the lower end of the portfolio, and that has an effect. But it is not &#x2013; the conclusion should not be that we don't take price and, as Jean is saying, in the second half of the year we will try to be more prominent even in that area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And your third question about the TCM cost, yeah, the personnel cost, you have more inflationary pressure coming from the emerging world, noticeably Africa, Nigeria in particular, you have a much more upward pressure on personnel cost due to the whole inflationary environment which spiked with the whole energy situation over there or the liberalization of the &#x2013; or the stop of the subsidies on oil. So that has an effect.</p>
          <p>And the second thing is which is that the building of the GBS is essentially personnel cost, so it's people. So we build up in Krak&#xF3;w financial shared service, which are hundreds of people who will have to serve more companies than they serve actually. So there is a kind of a frontload affected personnel cost, which will then be built back down again as we're nearing completion of the project, and that is, of course, what you find back in the higher personnel costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Could I just ask one small follow-up, though? Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois, you referenced improving mix in Russia, and yet, Ren&#xE9;, you said that actually in Russia you're taking price, but you've got negative price mix because the volume growth is coming at lower price packaging.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I realized the confusion we have here. What I'd meant to say is that commercially we, of course &#x2013; we are heavyweight in the lower part of the price segment in the market. That is true towards our competitors. We have a big volume, which is an index of below 100 in the market. And we gained share there and we gained loads of volume there. This is what gives us the distribution muscle and the whole carry of our fixed cost base in Russia. But we devote a lot of marketing attention in developing our top premium brands, like Heineken, like Amstel Premium Pilsner, which we launched with very good results so far this year.</p>
          <p>So licensed brands like Guinness, all these brands which are substantially higher than the index 100 are developing even above our total sales. So that is the good part and that is contributing to the &#x2013; ultimately to the enrichment of the mix as we go. Obviously, you don't improve the situation in six months nor in one year. It is an ongoing effort to improve our mix going forward. So I hope that clarifies it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely. Thank you very much, Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Gerard Rijk from ING. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. I've three questions. First question is on the setup of the Global Procurement program. I would have expected it already could have a bit more impact on your input price. I understand the elements, but maybe you can elaborate on the phasing of the positives of the Global Procurement excluding the media contract.</p>
          <p>Second question is on Chile and Argentina. Second quarter associates Americas started to decline in volumes quite strongly. Maybe you can give some elements on the outlook for this area, for Chile and Argentina? And those were my questions. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gerry, on GBS, look, what you will see is that on the main packaging materials and raw materials, we have in the past already been contracting centrally. What GBS enabled us to do is to monitor these contracts much more closer to put in place better risk management systems around it, but that will not have a clear and direct impact on the pricing. Where you will see the pricing is things on elements like the media buying contract, but many other areas where we have so far local buying or country-by-country buying and which we now group under the umbrella of Heineken Global Procurement. So you will see ongoing benefits from that. As I've said, probably the effect will be stronger on the non-product-related buying than on the product-related buying. Then on CCU, obviously, we cannot give an outlook for that company going forward. It's a stock-listed company, so it's not up to us to comment on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe on Eastern Europe then. You have had &#x2013; last few quarters you have been aggressive in, let's say, gaining volume share. Is there a shift going on more value share in the upcoming period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One has to realize that Central Europe is a large region. We have been very much concentrating on gaining volume share in Russia. That is true. And in the previous question of Trevor Stirling, I tried to address why and what we are doing in Russia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously, what you see across Central Europe, it is that the mix is going &#x2013; is deteriorating. That is a market observation. So that is what we are fighting against in some countries. You still see the beer category growing, and we can even grow our share in some countries. But overall, due to the economic pressure, you have a pressure on prices. So whilst the market is still developing in terms of volume, you see that there is a pressure on the mix. That does not prevent us to continue to invest disproportionately on the higher end of the market. That is what we do. But, obviously, now for quite a while in Central Europe, you have a pressure on there and that's a market phenomenon.</p>
          <p>I would carve out Greece out of Central Europe, because Greece is really &#x2013; yeah, this is an economy who melted down. We &#x2013; it did start already three years ago, or two years ago. This is really a meltdown of a country, and I don't think we can claim that as a company we can stay out of that meltdown. So that has really steeply lowered volumes and profits, and nothing really that you can do about. This is really hard macro economics that you have in front of you. But otherwise than Greece, I would say, there is a little bit the tendency of CEE, the volumes up, but the price mix has a pressure down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is the margin deterioration mainly due to Greece in the first half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That has a big impact, obviously. It's that plus a little bit of the mix, but Greece has a bigger impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It was still profitable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it is, yeah &#x2013; no, no, it is, absolutely. It is and still has very good return on the invested capital. This is a company which has been &#x2013; we have it in portfolio for a long time. It's quite optimalized, so it is still a very good company. It was a superb company, if you will. It was really one of the AAAs we had in the company, but it's still a solid company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Jon Fell from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, a couple of questions. Firstly on TCM. I think when you launched TCM2 earlier in the year, there was a suggestion that the benefits of the total &#x20AC;500 million program will be somewhat backend loaded. But when I look at the first half production of &#x20AC;85 million, that's almost exactly a sixth of &#x20AC;500 million. So are you producing those benefits faster than you expected, or is it to do with the scale of the overall program and project being a bit larger than you initially thought?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, so we started well. That is the right conclusion, but we stick to &#x20AC;500 million target for the three-year time period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So it's just really the phasing that's been better than you thought?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We started &#x2013; we were running faster in the beginning. How do you call that when you get off the start -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Faster out of the blocks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Faster out of the blocks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. You as a good Olympian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly, yeah, the Olympics has got to my head, right. And then the other question was on working capital. Can you just explain a bit more about what that increase in inventories and trade support has actually been? And you mentioned in the statement that main working capital as a proportion of revenue is now up to 4.6%. I think it was 3% last year. Is that the sort of level we're going to have to get used to going forward, or is this more of a temporary thing that you can bring down again over time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you see there are two things. First of all, if you look at the cash flow statement, you see the contribution or the investments in the first half. It's, obviously, investment is bigger than we had last year in the first half. There, we were still on the track from growing. I think the working capital as a percentage was 8% or 9%, and we were going down to where it's at 3%. So you get the big benefit of optimizing your working capital. That is clearly what we not have seen now in the first half, being at the 4.8%.</p>
          <p>When you decompose the 4.8%, the increase is almost fully into inventory, and that has two reasons. On one hand, it's just the value of the inventories which grows faster than your revenue. So that element &#x2013; that inflationary element on your input costs, you see that back on your inventory as a percentage of revenue.</p>
          <p>Secondly, that we have higher inventories in a number of African markets, and that is to cater for the growth. If you look at investments in working capital, although as a percentage of revenue that stays the same, but obviously, when you grow your business, you have more receivables in it. So you put money into working capital. But as a percentage of revenue, that stayed stable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Lauren Torres from HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. My question is on your Americas business. You talked about some successes, particularly in the U.S. and Mexico, and I was hoping first you could talk about the U.S. The consumer environment is still relatively soft. Imports haven't taken pricing, so I was curious about what progress you've made there, whether it'd be from a volume standpoint or a pricing standpoint.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, on Mexico, last year was somewhat of a difficult year for you. You lost some share. I think there were some distribution issues. So can you talk about progress there? And I guess, looking forward, any comments as you likely will face a new competitor next year, and how do you think about yourself positioned in the Mexican market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So in the U.S. our business is doing well, and even the market was up for the first time in a couple of years. To be honest, it was very much also helped by good weather. There you have the opposite what we saw in Europe that in the first half and certainly the first quarter the weather has been very favorable in the U.S. So you see total market up by 1%, where our depletions were up 2.4%.</p>
          <p>So share-wise and performance-wise, we do well. It's also very good to see that the Heineken brand itself is now in positive territory, and as we always say, it's early days. You don't change things from one quarter to the other, but it is very positive to see that the new approach we are taking in the U.S. is resonating and we will bring that further. As you know, we have aligned fully to the global positioning. With the global marketing campaign, we will make the next step as it has been announced in the U.S. that we also go to the global packaging in the U.S. that will be further improvements of our position.</p>
          <p>Looking at pricing, we have always said, we cannot take price as long as Corona is not taking price. We see now that Corona is starting to move in a number of regions, and we will follow as soon as possible. At the same time, on Dos Equis, we have been taking price to cover step by step the gap we still have with Corona. Jean, are you taking Mexico?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. On Mexico, I think we look back to a quite satisfactory performance in Mexico. The market is doing fine. We took reasonable price in the market, and our key brands are doing well. So in terms of, if we have to recede a little of bit of share loss last year, we could kind of gain that back this year. So we are pretty much in the place where we want to be.</p>
          <p>As we indicated, we have also invested quite a bit of money into the reshaping of the Sol brand, which is a leading brand in the southern part of Mexico, renewing all the bottle fleet, but also the &#x2013; all the above the line campaigns. And, of course, that is a long-term investment, but we started off reasonably well with that re-launch of Sol in Southern Mexico. The Heineken brand is performing well and the Dos Equis brand in Mexico is also performing really well, in addition to the continued performance of the Tecate brand. So Mexico, we're pleased, and also, I think, the fact that we could realized all our cost synergies ahead of timing makes this a successful integration so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's great. I guess if I could just round out the discussion on the Americas and ask about Brazil. I don't think you mentioned performance there. That's another market where, I guess, the consumer is recovering at a slower rate than most expected, so curious to get your impression of that market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brazil, you have noted there is a slowdown in Brazil. It's kind of stable. I think you have &#x2013; it's a little bit like Nigeria. You have to take the long view here. You have a high population growth. You have a structural economic growth, which goes in the right direction, and you have a continued urbanization of the population. And all these factors, they multiply and they work hand in hand to have sustainable growing market for still quite a while. So I wouldn't take a few &#x2013; a quarter or a few quarters or even a year or two of a slowdown in any market of that typology as a structural factor. The lines never go up in the kind of &#x2013; permanent way up. You have some time to time some blips.</p>
          <p>The good news for us, we're not &#x2013; we do not have &#x2013; we do not hold a significant position in Brazil, as you know, so we could withhold our position in the &#x2013; in mainstream. But the good news is that the Heineken brand in the top end of the market grew close to 50%, again, year-on-year, which is a noticeable performance. So we are very pleased, and this is where also we concentrate our efforts in the Brazilian market. We want to be skewed towards the top end starting with the Heineken brand, and there we are successful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I could just finally ask then, as you talk about pricing opportunities in the second half, as a region I assume Americas does offer that opportunity to you for the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Where possible, we will try to do that also in the Americas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Olivier Nicola&#xEF; from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. It's Olivier Nicola&#xEF; at UBS. Just two questions, please. What is the reason, first of all, for the change in marketing to sales guidance, as you previously indicated that it will be flat year-on-year and now it's going to be down? Are you actually postponing investments into 2013? And in which region are actually reducing marketing as a percentage of sales? And the second question is just to go back to your performance in Nigeria in Q2. Is it related to actually some capacity constraints despite the Sona acquisition last year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To start on the marketing and sales, it's a marginal difference on much higher revenue, so I would not look too much at it. Why the guidance is slightly lower is that we become more and more effective in the way how we do our marketing. As Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois said, the consumer face &#x2013; or I said it, the consumer-facing spend is up 6%. But we make big steps forward in becoming more effective in dealing with the agencies and dealing with the media agencies to get lower production costs, because we make less, but better commercials. So that allows you to have that percentage slightly lower, but that should not indicate any different ambition and stance in how we operate in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Nigeria?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Nigeria, we have sufficient capacity. Capacity is no constraint for our growth in Nigeria.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Andrea Pistacchi from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. I had a question on Europe please. The volume declined &#x2013; deteriorated in the second quarter. I guess, apart from the UK, volumes were about down mid single-digit in most markets. Now the weather has obviously had an impact. I was wondering whether &#x2013; to what extent you have seen a deterioration in the macro, particularly in Southern Europe, impacting the business, and also if you could talk about France a bit. And then I'll have another question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we have to take a few things into account. We are recycling a pretty strong first half last year in Western Europe. Clearly, as you indicated, the weather plays an important role. If you look at consumer confidence, that is certainly not coming back under the current circumstances, and you see in a number of markets that VAT increases that the on-premise sales are under pressure. So Europe is not an easy place to operate in, but our outlook has not fundamentally changed with where we stood at the beginning of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And you &#x2013; just a quick follow-up here on Europe. In terms of the on-trade to off-trade switch there, have you seen any deterioration? I think, in the Q1 call you'd flagged that it was getting a bit worse. Is it &#x2013; are the trading conditions still similar to how they were three or six months ago essentially?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, yes. I think you have not to see variations from a quarter to another really. You cannot build on that. Those are long-term trends, and the long-term trend is that for beer, consumption tends to shift from on-trade to off-trade. That is something which is going on now for &#x2013; in some countries, it is going on now for 15 years. In some countries it's more recent.</p>
          <p>A downbeat consumer confidence is just adding a notch to that, but is not changing the trend. And the trend can be very different in Northern Europe. And you know that if you live in the UK, perhaps went to &#x2013; in more food service than they did, let's say, 15 years ago. And at the same time, with the food service came more wine serving, so the beer came down as a throughput per customer, but that went over very long period.</p>
          <p>Now on the contrary, if you go in Spain, for the last 30 years we have seen the throughput per customer for beer going up, because beer was the perfect combination with tapas, and tapas is the social &#x2013; it's what the pub is for the English, the tapas bar is for the Spanish, and so that ritual of going out after work to the tapas bar and eating a few bites. And there we have seen and we have been able to build preference for beer with that consumer habit going forward.</p>
          <p>Now the good news is that in Spain, people still go out, still go to the tapas bar, and I said it many times, they will eat a bit less of the more expensive ham and a little bit more <mark type="indiscernible" /> (55:13). But the consumption of beer is still growing. Despite a very heavy economic crisis, one have to say that the market in Spain is pretty resilient as an example of even in a country which has it really hard that our category is resisting quite well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Then my second and last question is on your guidance. So your guidance for the full year implies I'd imagine, obviously, an improvement in EBIT in the second half, improvement in EBIT growth. Am I right that the main driver here is an improvement in growth &#x2013; in EBIT growth in Western and in Eastern Europe? And if yes, what would be driving this, given the worsening input cost inflation that you're flagging, which you're saying will partially be offset by pricing? Is it that the volume outlook should be better, so you're relying on better volumes in the second half essentially?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So, obviously, this &#x2013; continuing the strong growth in the emerging part of the portfolio, but for Europe it is better and better pricing, and it is cycling a very, very weak Q3 of last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from James Edwardes Jones from RBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hello. Two questions please if I may. I notice a very small number, but in the circumstance, can you say a little bit about the &#x20AC;20 million impairment charge that you've taken in relation to APB? And secondly, on Mexico, just given your answer to the previous question, can we take it from that that the market share decline in Mexico have hopefully come to an end?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the impairment of DaFuHao, that is actually a thing we announced already in Q1, where APB was in the process of selling their stake in DaFuHao that didn't succeed. And on the basis of that, they have written down the stake with an amount which leads for us to &#x20AC;20 million impairment in our books. And, obviously, that has an impact on our EBIT, because we take that organically and not as an exceptional item.</p>
          <p>And in Mexico, as I said, we're pleased that we are back to the market shares and that we made up for the marker share losses of last year. Obviously, one has to realize, we are in a battle for consumer preference on the one hand that translates in market share, but we are also in a battle for value share and returns. So make no mistake about what our intentions are Mexico and worldwide. And certainly when you have leadership positions, one has to use them for strongholds to create shareholder value. So that is what I can say about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Samar Chand from Barclays. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. I've just got a question on the cost savings, the TCM2 delivery following from what Jon asked before. I understand what you're saying around the phasing around the years for the next three years, but I'm just trying to understand what will happen particularly in this year in 2012. And within that, in the past you said that the cost savings were phased towards the second half versus the first half. So yes, you've got off the blocks really fast in the first half, but do you still expect the second half to actually have bigger cost saving delivery than the first half?</p>
          <p>And then just secondly on the volumes, can you try and quantify the weather impact in Western Europe on the Q2 volumes? And following on from that, perhaps just some comments on how you're see trading conditions in Q3 today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the TCM, we have always said that it would be marginally skewed to the second half, and probably what we see today is that it is more equal balanced, and I would leave it there. To disentangle the weather effect on the volumes is, again, we cannot do, and that would be very artificial and &#x2013; how do you call that &#x2013; theoretical exercise we will not entertain, with all respect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then just how you're seeing Q3 today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We cannot more say than we have said in our outlook, and so we cannot now comment on the period between the end of June and now. So you have to do it with what we have put in our outlook, where we say that the profitability in the second half will be better than what we have seen &#x2013; or the profit development will be better than what we have seen in the first half, leading to this stable net profit or net profit broadly in line with last year on an organic basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Philip Morrisey from Berenberg Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Could I ask &#x2013; I realize it's early days, but can you comment please on how you see the outlook for input cost going into next year? And in particular, do you expect any moderation in this year's 8%?</p>
          <p>Secondly, I was wondering what coupon we should be assuming on the APB deal? Presumably it's going to be around 3%, given the bonds you've issued so far in 2012. But I wondered if that applies to the totality of the consideration?</p>
          <p>And finally, you've highlighted input cost, obviously, up 6.9% in the first half. And I wondered what that number was in Western, but also Central and Eastern Europe. Was it a lot different from the 6.9%? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So to start with the input cost, we don't give the differences in the different countries, so I cannot help you over that. On the financing of APB, yes, we have recently issued bonds 12, 13 years with interest rates below 3%. For the time being, we think the markets stay open and strong, so that would be good proxy going forward. And your first question was &#x2013; input cost -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>2013, yeah, realizing it's obviously early days, but any guidance on 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I bought a crystal ball already, so don't you worry. We are having that &#x2013; but you know we don't comment on that. So we simply don't comment. You can read the papers as I do, and you see the tension provoked by a weak harvest in the U.S. and the tension it puts on the market, but I wouldn't comment further than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, we'll take one more question at this time, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question comes from Matthew Webb from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Yes, two questions, please. Firstly, just back to input costs again. I just wanted to make sure I've understood it correctly. When you say you're experiencing higher cost inflation in the regions with higher volume growth, are you there referring to &#x2013; predominantly to Eastern Europe and Africa, are they are two you're referring to? And then also, is that predominantly packaging inflation or is there a bit of barley inflation in there as well?</p>
          <p>And then on the same subject, when you talk about the pressure from one-way packaging is &#x2013; sorry, the shift to more one-way packaging, is that both Western and Eastern Europe that you're referring to there? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And then the second question, just on your strategy in Russia, clearly the growth at the low end is not doing anything for your profitability. I was just wondering whether you are taking your prices up at the low end in an attempt to translate some of that volume growth into some profit contribution? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the input cost, it is essentially packaging, and that is &#x2013; as Ren&#xE9; indicated before, it's a packaging mix shift from on-trade to off-trade, from returnable bottles to cans, and that is across all geographies. The pressure on the input cost is &#x2013; essentially on the raw materials is perhaps a bit more in Central Europe and in Africa; Central Europe because of our ability perhaps to price a bit less than we have in Western Europe. And secondly in Africa, we depend a lot on raw materials, local raw materials, and then you don't have the same contractual environment that you would have in Western Europe to secure prices one year in advance and making sure there are no variations and that kind of stuff.</p>
          <p>So it's a combination of all these three factors that led us to a slightly higher, but the majority of it is essentially a mix change. One has to say also when you sell more Heineken, you will have more input cost, because it's just more expensive to make. So when we are successfully moving the mix, we also are, as a consequence of that, bearing the fact that you have a little bit of variable input cost increases. That is on your first.</p>
          <p>The second is on Russia. I don't think I have to add a lot to what I said before. It's just a clarification that one has to realize that, once more, we are not a market leader in Russia. And when you are with brands that are under index 100, where market leader typically would have that index 100 kind of pricing index, you are derivative of what he is moving, and you move always with a certain delay to his own price moves. Now, people buy brands because they see a value/price relation. Obviously, it's not because you are successful in putting interesting value brands on the market that &#x2013; and you grow quite a lot with it that you can suddenly increase your prices ahead of the price/value equation that the consumers gives to it.</p>
          <p>Once more, our strategy is supported to playing a good game in the value segment of the market in Russia that is paying for our infrastructure. We have a good infrastructure. It's used at a good level. It improved a lot. You have to imagine that with the higher sales that we have had for now 18 months, that has put us in a much better position as towards our capacity utilization. You will remember, we started with 10 breweries, we closed two down. We have eight breweries, and we operate them at a pretty nearing optimal state, and that is giving us a good base to dedicate a lot of work in the premium end of the portfolio and reinforce our position there. That we kind of do over there structurally in Russia. I hope this clarifies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> (1:07:26).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>George is saying that I have to end the call now. So we thank you for all your questions and dialing in today. Of course, our Investor Relations team is available throughout the day to answer any follow-up questions you might have. But for now, I'd like to thank you for your attention also on behalf of Ren&#xE9;. And hope to see you soon at least for those who will join us tomorrow in London, we'll see you back there.</p>
          <p>With that, I wish you a good day. Thank you very much. Bye-bye now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude the Heineken Half Year Results 2012 Conference Call. Thank you for participating and you may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, operator.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>