<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1176263" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-08-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>836</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois van Boxmeer, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Ren&#xE9; Hooft Graafland, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2">Matthew Webb</participant>
      <participant id="3">Ren&#xE9; Hooft Graafland</participant>
      <participant id="4">Andrew Holland</participant>
      <participant id="5">James Edwardes Jones</participant>
      <participant id="6">Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois van Boxmeer</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="8">Thomas Russo</participant>
      <participant id="9">Gerard Rijk</participant>
      <participant id="10">Chris Pitcher</participant>
      <participant id="11">Trevor Stirling</participant>
      <participant id="12">Karel Zoete</participant>
      <participant id="13">Paul Hofman</participant>
      <participant id="14">Nico Lambrechts</participant>
      <participant id="15">Bill Casey</participant>
      <participant id="16">Javier Gonzalez-Lastra</participant>
      <participant id="17">Christopher Wickham</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. Since it's a bit early in the day to serve you a pint of beer, so, we always serve you commercials with a cup of coffee at this time. Welcome to our Half Year Results Call.</p>
          <p>I am joined with &#x2013; as usual with Ren&#xE9; Hooft Graafland, our CFO, my colleague on the Board. We're going to have a quick look at our overall performance and I will take you through a regional &#x2013; region-by-region look at our performance. After that, Ren&#xE9; will go a bit more in detail in the numbers with you and thereafter, you will have all your questions. We will take all your questions.</p>
          <p>Now, against the backdrop of a weaker economies a bit around the world, I think we posted a good result for this first half. What is &#x2013; I am sorry, it is &#x2013; okay. Thank you, Ren&#xE9;. It doesn't go automatically. I'll have to work. Good.</p>
          <p>As I said, against the backdrop of weaker economic developments, we have posted a good performance. During this first half, we have lots of new consolidations as not only we started in May, the consolidation of Scottish &amp; Newcastle, which is the biggest part, but also additional operations in the Czech Republic, in Romania, in Serbia and in Belarus and Algeria. All this together, served us a volume increase of 15% year-on-year for the first half of 2008, of which 5.4 was an organic volume growth.</p>
          <p>The volume growth was particularly strong in Central and Eastern Europe, in Africa and the Middle East, in Asia Pacific, was flattish in the Americas region and was slightly under pressure in Western Europe.</p>
          <p>The Heineken brand grew again with a healthy 5.8%. And we have, thanks to all these, delivered an organic growth of our revenues by 6.7%. The EBIT, beia, organic growth was 7.5% and the net profit growth was 5.3%. Organic meaning that we take out the effect of the first-time consolidation and the effect of the currencies.</p>
          <p>We have been concentrating on this period essentially on pricing. As we have been facing rising input costs, a lot of efforts of our management around the world has been on restoring margins and to make sure that we pass on the price increases that we faced into the market. And I will tell you more about that region-by-region.</p>
          <p>Also the Fit2Fight program, which we initiated in 2006, continued well on track, and we added another 84 million to the savings. And we are well on track to realize the 150 million savings, which are on the program of this year to complete the total three-year program of &#x20AC;450 million of savings.</p>
          <p>And last but not least, the Scottish &amp; Newcastle integration is well on track. We have been revising, as we published last Friday, our estimates &#x2013; our guidance on the &#x2013; to be a realized synergies. We are now standing at 184 &#x2013; translated in euros, &#x20AC;184 million in four years time. And if we look at the synergies, we have already realized now on an annual basis, we are already standing at 60 million. So a third &#x2013; goes to a third of the synergies have been already put in place and just four months after the completion of the deal.</p>
          <p>Now let me take you in a world tour starting with the world picture on the Heineken brand. As ever, the Heineken brand continues to be the cornerstone, the centerpiece of our strategy for creating value for our company.</p>
          <p>As I said, 5.8% growth for the first half year, we broke through the 20% market share in the international premium segment that we have set ourselves putting more distance between ourselves and our nearest competitors being Carlsberg and Corona.</p>
          <p>We have &#x2013; we &#x2013; premium brand goes also with premium pricing, and so I want to underline that in practically all markets, the price premium of the Heineken brand is at least 35% up the reference mainstream brand as to support the premium image and also superior margins.</p>
          <p>We sustain the growth by innovations. It's a recurrent theme. We have, again, put efforts behind the roll out of our innovations, particularly in the DraughtKeg, the BeerTender, which we are going to roll out in the U.S. of A later in this year. We have been rolling out in France with quite a success in the second half of last year.</p>
          <p>So we continue to put a lot of efforts in the roll out of these innovations, draught beer, BeerTender, dated portable systems and Extra Cold beer program as they sustain part of the growth of the Heineken brand.</p>
          <p>And on the other side, high investments in high profile marketing events and campaigns, some of them national, but some of them international, just want to underline that we re-signed for the sponsorship of the UEFA Champions League for another three years or the sponsor or participation to sponsorship of the next James Bond to come, Quantum of Solace, that I will leave to our Chief Marketing Officer, Ren&#xE9; &#x2013; Chief Financial Officer, Ren&#xE9; to present as he will do that very well.</p>
          <p>When all regions &#x2013; practically all regions contributed to the growth of the Heineken brand with the exception of the Americas, where sales of Heineken were flattish mainly due to the United States of America and I will come back to that later on. But we have enjoyed good growth of the Heineken brand everywhere in all the continents.</p>
          <p>Now, let me turn to Western Europe now. Western Europe is by-and-large our biggest operation, certainly now that we have Scottish &amp; Newcastle on board. Here you have a snapshot of the performance.</p>
          <p>Look that we are now indicating the operating margins by region and not anymore the EBIT beia margins, but the operating profit margins, where we take only the operating margins of our own company since we have applied different rules and we have deconsolidated the joint venture. So we have taken them out and here you see the effect on our own business.</p>
          <p>We all know that the economic conditions in the region are not the best, not to speak about the weather in Northwestern Europe at least.</p>
          <p>If we look at our volume performance organically with taking out the Scottish &amp; Newcastle, which obviously boosted our sales as you see, 20% up. The organic growth of our own operations is 1.3% down. So, slightly down as I said earlier. We have put lots of efforts into pricing in Western Europe. So we have been doing our efforts for passing on the rising input cost prices to the market very early. And we have taken up our leadership role in doing that, because we thought it was very important.</p>
          <p>So in Western Europe, we have been doing that very early as to maintain our operating margins. And you will see that the like-for-like operating margins. So if you would exclude the Scottish &amp; Newcastle business is very much inline with what it was last year. So it also indicates that we have work to go further on Scottish &amp; Newcastle with the operating margins.</p>
          <p>Heineken brand did again well. It grew 2.5% in the region, which is a good performance. And the Fit2Fight program continued as we delivered for the sole region of Western Europe, 41 million of new savings for the first six months.</p>
          <p>Finally, I think it's worthwhile to mentioning that we received clearance of the antimonopoly authorities in Switzerland for the merger of Eichhof Getr&#xE4;nke Holding which we intend to buy and merge within Heineken Switzerland going forward and reinforcing our leadership position in that country.</p>
          <p>Let me now zoom in to Scottish &amp; Newcastle. The integration of Scottish &amp; Newcastle is on track. We have been integrating the Heineken operations in the U.K. within the Scottish &amp; Newcastle operations already. So Heineken and Amstel are now served together with the whole Scottish &amp; Newcastle portfolio here in the United Kingdom.</p>
          <p>We have been closing the head office of &#x2013; the international head office of Scottish &amp; Newcastle. Also, we have been integrating the people in &#x2013; some people in our own headquarters as well as in the U.K. operation as was deemed fit and we found talent, as I announced earlier, to reinforce our teams. All management teams have been confirmed. They are all with marching orders and they are back to business.</p>
          <p>The Heineken brand is integrated in the portfolio of Central Cervejas in Portugal and it is yet to come in Finland in the early part of January '09. So everything is going rather fastly on track. And as I indicated earlier, we have already in an annualized basis realized 60 million out of the 184 million synergies we want to do.</p>
          <p>When we then zoom in into particularly the U.K. situation, so out of S&amp;N, we take, S&amp;N U.K., obviously, we didn't enjoy. I don't think we enjoyed the best summer ever here in Great Britain. And it's not getting better if I look outside of the window even today.</p>
          <p>Of course, we have been here also applying price increases to cope with the increase of input costs. We have been able overall over the first half of the year, with it coming up and down, or coming down and up, maintaining our share in beer with Foster's performance &#x2013; brand performance which was inline with the market and gained in share for Kronenbourg 1664, reestablishing &#x2013; strengthening its position as number-two premium beer here in the United Kingdom. As you know, we have a 50-years license on the brand with S&amp;N here in U.K.</p>
          <p>And it's also, I think, worthwhile underlining that the Heineken brand in &#x2013; has been growing 39% in this market, which is encouraging for the future. Also strong growth with the cider &#x2013; the fine cider brands, Strongbow and Bulmers, they grew 11% over the first half. So there are also bright sides here in the British market.</p>
          <p>So, overall, Scottish &amp; Newcastle, strong brands, a leadership position to build on, a strong platform for the growth of the Heineken brand. Yes, difficult market conditions at this moment in time. Yes, a difficult or a not so nice summer. Yes, we had an increase in the excise duty, a hefty one, this year here in the U.K. Yes, we had a smoking ban which started to kick in last year around the same time. All kind of factors; and yes, the economic situation is not the best we have enjoyed. But we also take a longer view on the market and we have been like in many other markets in Western Europe, been able to extract share and value share out of the markets. And that will always &#x2013; that also &#x2013; sorry, be the case here in the U.K. And we will keep you posted on the evolution in the years to come.</p>
          <p>I now change corner of the world and we go to Central and Eastern Europe. There, it's a story about growing volumes; a healthy growth 12%. And I have to say that in that corner of the world, we have been later in phasing in price increases, which have put our margins as you can see under pressure on the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>Most of the price increases in Central and Eastern Europe have been taking place in quarter two. So you will have the effect of better margins pushed on the second half of the year, where we expect that the margins will be better and that will kick in again the growth of EBIT.</p>
          <p>The sales mix as we see is very much skewed towards &#x2013; is more skewed in our portfolio towards end value brands and premium brands. We need the value brands to sustain distribution. Affordable brands are still of utmost importance in these countries and based on that volume, we build our share of premium brands and they command a higher profitability most of the time in our operations.</p>
          <p>And I will zoom in Russia in a while, but noteworthy is to mention that we also extended our footprint in Serbia, in the Czech Republic and in Belarus. So all kind of new areas where we push and we're trying to build a leadership position in these markets.</p>
          <p>Now, zooming in Russia; there the story is that we gained market share. And the market has been developing over the first half year moderately as opposed to the fantastic growth of the first six months in 2007, everybody will remember that. But on that background, we have been raising our sales much more than the market. And on net, we reckon that we have been able to gain 2% market share. So, our market share position is definitely improving in Russia. And our areas of strengths are the premium segment, the regional strong hold and the value brands.</p>
          <p>Here also, we had late price increases. So they kicked in a bit later in the half year, so in quarter two. And that put some pressure on the margins. We had a double hit in Russia, as we did not have to face only the rise of the price of input costs, like everybody else, but also a sharp rise of transportation costs, mainly railway transportation costs, which went really a fair bit up. This has to do with Russia is an enormous country, and even if we have 10 breweries, you still have to travel a lot to deliver your product.</p>
          <p>So, we had kind of a double hit in the input cost and we are now working at restoring the margins. But as usual, you can expect that that goes quicker in the sense that you can apply for more price increases during the year than you would typically do in a mature or in a Western European environment. So that's a slight update for Russia with our gains of market share.</p>
          <p>In Africa, things are going really well. I think that Africa has been the star performer of the Group. You see a growth of sales of 25% and the growth of EBIT of 35%. So, it's quite impressive. We make progress in the Republic of South Africa, where Heineken has grown again 43%. So it's doing really well.</p>
          <p>Now the Amstel has continued to grow back its shares, since we took it over from SAB. You know we bring it on an import basis out of Europe. So it is not at a small cost if we do that but we are currently building a new brewery in the Gauteng area and that brewery will be operational in quarter-four of 2009 as planned and then we will take over the production of Amstel.</p>
          <p>The story of Nigeria, I zoom in here one country that is Nigeria since in &#x2013; star performance. This is the star of the star of the stars. And it's also our flagship brand beer in Nigeria and Nigeria stands for close to half of the total profits of the region. It is really a fantastic operation we have over there. Like everywhere in Africa, you have a more stable environment. You have economic growth. Things are developing in more countries into the right way.</p>
          <p>In Nigeria &#x2013; Nigeria in particular, is blessed with high oil prices and that is catering for the development of a middle class, which is spending, and that again is benefiting the development of our operations over there.</p>
          <p>We operate with two companies; one is Nigerian Breweries, which we own for 54%. It's a stock-listed company. And we operate through Consolidated Breweries, which is a private company in which we hold 51% of. Now, together these two companies hold a two-third of the market. We have been building that market share over the last 10 &#x2013; 15 years on a very consistent way. And it is now the absolute and undisputed leader of the Nigerian market. Star, Gulder and Heineken are the three major brands. The overall volume was 17% up and our EBIT beia grew organically up almost 44% on the first six years and that 44% is Nigerian Breweries, which is public information. It is a stock-listed company.</p>
          <p>That was to underline the performance of one of the largest and most important companies today in the Heineken Group. Who would have thought a few years ago that Africa would have become the third profit contributor of the Heineken Group after the two Europe's?</p>
          <p>And I now go to the Americas, another of our key geographies. There the volumes are stable, expect in a challenging environment &#x2013; the challenging environment applies essentially to the U.S. and also for us specifically because of the dollar which impacts us. The Americas is a scattered region. You have the U.S. and Canada; then you have the Caribbean and Central America, and then you have Latin America.</p>
          <p>Now, Latin America, starting with that one; our operations are essentially centered around CCU, which is a joint venture. CCU is doing a fine job; is booming in Chile and in Argentina, growing sales 8.8% on the first half year; is doing really well for its own volume, for its own mainstream brands but also for the Heineken brand.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, we have a license operation with FEMSA for Brazil, where the Heineken brand is also progressing very well over there.</p>
          <p>In Central America and the Caribbeans, we have enjoyed good results. A lot of &#x2013; a spectacular turnaround of our Panamanian operation and a good resilience of the Caribbean business overall which was affected by the &#x2013; by of course, you can imagine the U.S. dollar and &#x2013; however, a stable performance.</p>
          <p>And then we come to the performance of the USA and we have dedicated a slide for that. As I said, it is of course a challenging market conditions as everybody knows. We have seen a clear slowdown in the import beer market. It did not really went down, but the growth came to a halt, and that is after years of growth something which is noticeable. And it's difficult to say whether it will stay, whether it would go down. But it is clearly a change of trend that we have observed since this year.</p>
          <p>Against that market, our whole portfolio sustained its position with a scattered performance across our brands. On the one hand, we see that the Mexican beer brands have been progressing quite a bit and I look at the depletion side, which is the sale from the wholesaler into the markets, which is a better measure for re-performance of sales than the sales volume which is over load in or our in load of the distributors.</p>
          <p>You see that the Mexican beers progressed quite a bit with 8% and with Dos Equis, which is the most premium brand in the FEMSA portfolio, which has even progressed 18%; so, a very good performance. When we look at the Heineken brand, it's a bit mixed. It's a soft performance. It's minus three for the Heineken Lager. It's still growing for Heineken Premium Light. But let's face it, this is a soft performance. The total Heineken franchise is in line with, of course, the import market, by-and-large due to these economic circumstances and the fact that we are already a very, very big brand in the U.S.</p>
          <p>And Amstel Light continued to go down. We did not succeed so far to stop the decline of the Amstel brand. However, we have in the very recent months launched a new campaign for Amstel Light. Its early days to notice the effects of it, but as I said in the previous conference that we would put means and a better marketing campaigns to sustain the brand going forward. We have been doing so. We have now to wait and see how that will play for the brand.</p>
          <p>We've renewed our marketing campaign for Heineken Premium Light and I will show you an example at the closing of my presentation. And for the Heineken franchise &#x2013; the Heineken Lager franchise, we will launch a new campaign in spring '09 in the U.S. and for the premium import segment. The most important thing is to have that superior consumer pull. So advertising is playing a big role into that and so we always put lots of energy and money also into that part, because that is what creates the premium image and the pull for our brands. We have been reinforcing our marketing departments, big-time change agency. So everything has been done. We're back on track in the U.S. to grow in a more offensive way again in the market with our own brands.</p>
          <p>Then I'd like to go to Asia Pacific. Here, perhaps you see in most full the effect of the deconsolidation and I'd like to make a comment here that our business in Asia is sustained by three different kind of business settings or business platforms. The first one and known to you all is Asia Pacific Breweries where we co-own the controlling holding with Fraser &amp; Neave. The second part and that is new, it is of course UBL in India through our 37.5% we acquired through Scottish &amp; Newcastle.</p>
          <p>And the third part is of our own business that we operate ourselves and which is outside, it is 100%  owned by Heineken. That business has been &#x2013; overall, the whole business has been growing quite a big time. Margins have been growing, EBIT have been growing, the volumes are growing, everything is going the right way in all three of the blocks and I will give you a detail on that here.</p>
          <p>Asia Pacific Breweries has been good for 5.3 million hectoliter over the first six months, and our share of the net profit, which we include into our results, is 15.9 million. So you can make your reconciliation. We have enjoyed good volume growth and the organic profit growth has been strong. We have to reckon that APB is &#x2013; having currently gestation losses that it call for new operations. But when you look at the organic performance of APB, it has been extremely strong. APB is also facing some currency issues as we do with the U.S. dollars. They have in their own region also currency devaluations to face which put a little of bit pressure on their results in the same dollar. But overall, the organic growth of APB is really strong.</p>
          <p>United Breweries, we have been accounting for 2.6 million our share of net profits for the first half. As you know, we have a limited access to UB's accounts at this moment in time, since we are still in discussion to define what the best form of collaboration will go &#x2013; will be for the future.</p>
          <p>Three parties involved; ourselves; APB, who has operations already in India, and of course, Dr. Mallya, we are in active talks, it's going into the right direction. But we still need some times to come to good agreements between all of us, because we're definitely determined to leverage on the fantastic potential that the Indian market will provide for &#x2013; in the long term.</p>
          <p>And finally, our direct operations, which are mainly breweries in the Indonesia and New Caledonia and an array of export positions and the regional office which is in charge of the managing of the whole continent, including the relations with our joint venture. That has been posting a healthy EBIT of &#x20AC;21.5 million, growing 44% on a year-on-year basis. So our business is doing indeed excellently in Asia Pacific.</p>
          <p>That concludes my world tour of our regions. And I finish with the organic net profit growth forecast, which we have said to be at least mid-single digit. That is not a surprise for us at this morning driven by all these factors like Heineken growth; we continue to grow our volumes, the higher selling prices, the fact that the raw materials and the packaging materials have been fully hedged for this year and that we are on track with the Fit2Fight program that will leads us to make the guidance of the net &#x2013; at least single &#x2013; mid-single digit profit growth.</p>
          <p>I thank you for your attention so far. I'll show you a commercial out of the new series for Heineken Premium Light now, before handing over to Ren&#xE9;, who will guide you in more details. And here it comes.</p>
          <p>[Advertisement]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. Yes, as usual, I will take you through the key figures. And one caution, these are, of course, already based on the new joint venture accounting, so you'll have to take that in mind when you look at them. And as Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois already has said, these figures reflect the ongoing positive performance in the company, 6.7% organic revenue growth, 7.5% organic EBIT growth, are certainly not bad, and certainly, when you place them against in changing economic environment and very strong comparables last year. As you will remember, in the first half of last year, we grew our net profit organically by 35% and that is where we had to compare ourselves with.</p>
          <p>The reported EBIT and the reported net profits are strongly up. But they are heavily influenced by exceptional items. Last year, 251 million charges before tax. This year, we had 134 million charges and that relate to restructuring costs in France 59 million and cost related to the S&amp;N acquisition, 60 million restructuring and 50 million integration costs.</p>
          <p>But as usual, I will focus in my presentation to the figures before exceptional items and the amortisation of brands and customer relations, the so-called beia figures, and to arrive at organic figures obviously we exclude the effect of currencies and new consolidations.</p>
          <p>In our figures, S&amp;N is now consolidated for two months, so May and June is in. And last Friday, we have published pro forma financial information on the 2007 S&amp;N figures. We applied our own accounting policies to the businesses which we have acquired. And as you all have read, the pro forma EBIT is &#x20AC;303 million and the net adjustments if you add it all up, we made &#x2013; reduced EBIT by &#x20AC;40 million.</p>
          <p>But let me stress again, these adjustments are non-cash and therefore, don't have an impact on the cash flows of the acquired S&amp;N businesses. Just to give you two examples out of these adjustments, we will no longer report the amount we receive annually from InBev in relation to the termination of the Beck's license, which is 22 million per year, because we put them now on the opening balance sheet as deferred income, but of course, they will all continue to be paid.</p>
          <p>The same with the pensions. We have adjusted the actuarial assumptions, brought them much more in line with our relatively conservative view on these kinds of things. That gives us an additional charge in the profit and loss of &#x20AC;37 million per year.</p>
          <p>However, the arrangements we made for the pension funds &#x2013; the payments we make to the pension funds stayed obviously the same. In fact, the pension fund takes a little bit the same of view as we do on these actuarial assumptions.</p>
          <p>And also regarding the opening balance, we now fully consolidate one of the partner states companies and the logistic partnership we have. So we take as well the assets as the liabilities on our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Also financing from factoring what was previously netted, we don't do that anymore against receivables. And in addition because of the changed actuarial assumptions, provisions for the pension increases by &#x20AC;172 million. If you add these things up, these accounting changes and decisions we made increases the debt level by &#x20AC;1.90 billion.</p>
          <p>Then the second change we made and we announced last week is that we have changed our accounting treatment for the joint ventures from proportionate consolidation to the equity method. And by doing so, we align ourselves with upcoming IFRS changes Exposure Draft 9 stops the allowance of the proportionate consolidation. And in fact, it is in line with what our peers are doing.</p>
          <p>This obviously affects the consolidated volumes. It will affect revenues and EBIT figures on a 2007 basis, the effect on the EBIT is around 100 million, but obviously it has no effect on the current or future net profits or on equity and that's logic.</p>
          <p>Regions mostly affected, the Americas, where we have CCU, in Chile and Argentina, and Asia, where we have Asia Pacific Breweries, the joint venture together with Fraser &amp; Neave.</p>
          <p>Looking at the revenues, 17% growth, almost 1 billion additional revenues. Of course, the new consolidations had a substantial affect, 677 million is coming from new consolidations of which S&amp;N took 608 million, so the lions share of it.</p>
          <p>Currencies had a negative effect of 2%, &#x20AC;106 million and that remains mainly to the U.S. dollar, the Nigerian naira, the Russian ruble, partly offsets by a positive development of the Polish zloty. The organic revenue growth was strong with 6.7%, of which 5.1% relates to price/mix.</p>
          <p>And here you see the split of that organic revenue growth by the volume impact and the price/mix effect. And you see over the years that have changed substantially. We have increased prices in most of our markets to offset the strong increases of input costs, Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois elaborated on that and a big part of this 5.1% price/mix improvement is therefore driven by a higher prices.</p>
          <p>And certainly in Western Europe, we have demonstrated our price leadership and we have increased prices on average by 4%. In Central and Eastern Europe, yes, we also increased prices, but later, most of it, in the second quarter. And so you will see the full effect only in H2.</p>
          <p>The volume effect on the revenues was 1.6%. The fact that over 5% consolidated beer volume growth is translated only in 1.6% on revenues. So in euro terms, it's the result from the fact that the volume growth is realized in Central and Eastern Europe and in Africa, where the prices are obviously lower than in Western Europe or the USA.</p>
          <p>Looking at the EBIT &#x2013; grew to 925 million or 7.4% growth. First-time consolidations added &#x20AC;30 million to &#x2013; the biggest plant was S&amp;N and that was offset by the effect of the depreciation of most currencies against the Euro. And so the 7.5% organic EBIT growth is solid and the result of, on one hand, a healthy top line growth, on the other hand the continued cost reductions under the Fit2Fight program.</p>
          <p>Having a look at the Fit2Fight program, we are now in the last year and in the first half of this year, we added another 84 millions of gross savings, bringing the total up to 389 million or 86% of the total program of 450 million. And here on the slide, you see the development of the fixed &#x2013; Fit2Fight fixed cost ratio, so the fixed cost on the scope of Fit2Fight as a percentage of revenue. And again, we have decreased that ratio by 190 basis points compared with a year ago. And this is the last year of Fit2Fight. Often people ask me what will we do after the completion of the program, and clearly, we will continue to reduce cost.</p>
          <p>Cost focus is now embedded in the organization and we will be continuing to do that. However, we won't do it in a public way in a sense that we set up front for the outside world our targets. But just to give you an example that we continue to work on the costs, recently we announced a restructuring program in France, closing a brewery, reducing headcounts with 180 people. That will be executed in next year and the savings you will see after 2008.</p>
          <p>So they are not in the &#x20AC;450 million savings of the Fit2Fight. It's clearly a program, which yields results after 2008 and it is a proof that we will continue also after 2008 to reduce the cost, and further improve the Fit2Fight fixed cost ratio. And we will update you on a regular basis on that development of that ratio.</p>
          <p>Net profit was slightly lower at 540 million. The new consolidations had a slight negative impact of 30 million negative due to the financing cost. Currencies had an impact of 24 million negatively and the organic net profit growth was 5.3%.</p>
          <p>Let's now have a look at the balance sheet. Of course, big changes in the balance sheet. Total assets increased from 12.8 billion to 22.9 billion. And a big part of that is of course the consolidation of S&amp;N. In our release, last Friday, we gave the opening balance as the 1st of May. And that is now consolidated in the Group.</p>
          <p>Total equity is solid at the level of 5.8 billion and is over 25% of assets. Net debt increases to 9.3 billion and let me explain that in the next slide, before doing that, well, you know our industry and we have our seasonality, so normally in the middle of the year, you see the inventory build up for the summer. And so working capital is higher than what you would see at the end of the year, and therefore, the net debt levels.</p>
          <p>Having said that the big increase of the net debt is of course the result of the acquisitions of which S&amp;N obviously is the biggest one as you can see here in the table. But also you can see that our operating cash flow is sound &#x20AC;432 million. That is good. But you can imagine that with so much debt on our balance sheet, we will put an increased focus again on cash generation and it will be a key priority going forward. After the acquisition of BBAG, we launched our hunt for cash. We really got the organization on cash management and you can be sure that we will do a similar type of exercise. Now we have so much debt on the balance sheet. So that means further reducing working capital, screening investments, putting the hurdle rate for efficiency investments at a higher level and see if there are non-core assets in the company which you can dispose.</p>
          <p>A quick word on the debt related to Scottish &amp; Newcastle. We have refinanced a part of the bank acquisition facility already in the capital market and that shows that even in these times of the credit crunch, we are able to raise long-term debt. And we have decided to keep the existing S&amp;N U.S. placements so that we have to refinance less and that we don't confront it with breakups costs. And we will continue to refinance existing credit facilities, but we are not on a time pressure and because all of these facilities are mid to long-term.</p>
          <p>We estimate that the average interest rates for the S&amp;N related debts in the second half of the year will be 5.8% for the total Heineken Group in the second half of the year and that will be 5.6% versus what we had in the first half of the year, 5.1%.</p>
          <p>Then the last subject, the input costs and a hot topic in our industry. But not only in our industry, I think in all consumer industries that is an hot topic. You know this chart shows the organic growth of the input costs versus the growth in our consolidated beer volume. And you see that in the first half of the year, raw and packaging materials increased by over 23% of which 15% relates really to like-for-like pricing.</p>
          <p>This 15% will also be the figure for the full year and that is completely in line with what we have told you before and what we have guided you for. That 15% is a major impact, if you just translate that in euros, it is on the existing business and volumes &#x20AC;375 million, an additional input costs in 2008. Luckily, we have strong brands and we have been able to pass that on &#x2013; in the pricing in most of our markets.</p>
          <p>For 2009, we see a slowdown of the price increases. We are not out of it. But certainly in a slow down and we estimate for 2009 on raw and packaging materials on average an 8% increase. And that is taken into account current oil and aluminum prices.</p>
          <p>We have hedged around 50% of our 2009 needs wherein 2008 the 15% price increase was mainly driven by the raw materials, barley, malt. In 2009, it will be much more driven by the packaging materials because the increased energy costs play an important role in things like bottles and cans.</p>
          <p>Transport costs were up substantially 29%, partly to do was the increased oil prices, but also in this you see the effect of our exports from Europe to our operations in South Africa.</p>
          <p>To summarize, good performance, 7.5% organic EBIT growth driven by top line organic volume growth, 5.4%, and price/mix improvement over 5% and the full effect of this price increases certainly in Central and Eastern Europe where it will be felt in the second half.</p>
          <p>Heineken brand, again, good performance with 5.8%, therefore outperforming the international premium segment. Fit2Fight on time in its delivery 84 million in the first half year. Integration of S&amp;N going very fast; very good cooperation between both sides and we have a quick realization of the synergies on an annualized basis, already by now &#x20AC;60 million and the full forecast for the year, organic net profit growth at at least mid-single digits.</p>
          <p>And before we go into Q&amp;A, Jean-Fran&#xE7;ois told it already, you can see the new James Bond TVC. We have a long-lasting partnership with the makers of James Bond. I like it very much as a CFO, because we don't pay for it. It is a real partnership. We may associate ourselves with the movie and the actors, and in exchange, we promote the film in all our marketing activities around the world. We do that now again. And for the promotion, we can use &#x2013; make use of the Bond girl Olga in the TVC. You will also see Daniel Craig. And at this time, instead of just linking ourselves to Bond, we really try to associate our consumers or relate our consumers to it and we ask them to enter the world of Bond, and I will also ask you to do that now by looking at this new TVC.</p>
          <p>[Advertisement]</p>
          <p>And now you may ask Olga all questions, you would like to ask.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Matthew Webb from Cazenove. Could I ask you a question about the contribution from the Scottish &amp; Newcastle business in the first half? And on the pro forma &#x2013; based on the pro forma numbers it looks like the EBIT beia fell from 89 million to only 32 million. I was just wondering whether that was a fair like-for-like comparison or whether there was anything you take into P&amp;L there that perhaps we should treat as an exceptional. And either way, whether you can say anything about your expectations for the second half? It doesn't look as if the UK market is getting any easier? I mean, should we expect some material decline also in H2? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Clearly, it is a steep decline, if you compare it with the pro forma figures, obviously currency play a role to 2007 rate where we used was 139 while the average in 2008 is the 126, but it also reflect, I am afraid, debt trading in the first half of the year. We see a sharp difference between the four months, which was not on our guidance, and then the two months after you clearly see that at this moment of time it was a lot of uncertainties in the different organizations we were not able to relate with the teams on the ground, yes, on high level at head office, and so there was not a strong focus in the team. But at the same time, you saw that the UK market was changing dramatically because of the economic environment, but also the weather, the excise increase, and you have the second part of the smoking ban, the second six months to elapse that. So less volume, also not enough price increases, so margin under pressure. Not enough focus on the cost side, and that increase &#x2013; or resulted in a very modest to say it in a nice way, a very modest result out of the first six months.</p>
          <p>Going forward, we see that the business is picking up. The market is certainly not changing where the economy is not changing on such short-terms. But at least you have now comparables where the smoking ban is in. We see that the excise is absorbed, and so there are a number of things which are changing. And apart from that, we will work very hard with the strong portfolio of brands, and the leading position S&amp;N has in the different, well certainly in the UK, but also in markets like Portugal and Finland and Belgium to get the performance up to the level where it need to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It's Andrew Holland at Dresdner Kleinwort. Can I just follow-up on Matthew's question, and the other bit of that is that the sales were down I think around 19% in the first half. If we assume that perhaps 10% of that was currency related, and you are saying that you didn't really get involved, S&amp;N didn't really get prices up, would it be fair to say that your volumes in that first half were down by the difference, i.e., by around 9%? Or put another way, can you just tell me whether your volumes were down in the first half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And well, when you look at the UK in the first four months, clearly S&amp;N lost market share, especially in the off-trades. They didn't participate fully in all the promotional activities. And we are loosing out there in the on-premise they kept share, but the on-premise market was down around 9%. And so overall, they have been loosing. Luckily cider was very positive, I think, they grew cider in 11 or 12%, but I think overall they lost something like 5 to 6% in the first half of the year; market share regained in June &#x2013; in May and June, clearly that is a basis where we will start working from. There is a lot to work &#x2013; a lot of work to do, but the good thing is that it's a healthy brands portfolio. It's a very professional and good organization. And that is &#x2013; and we have leadership in the UK, so that is the basis to work from.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions, if I may quickly, so it's James Edwardes Jones from Execution. Why did you delay pushing through price increases in Russia? What was the reason for that, and what has been the volume effect in Russia since you did put those price increases through in Q2? And second, can you reconcile the 5.4% growth in organic beer volumes to the 1.6% growth in volume for the consolidated group as a whole?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will take the first question. The fact that we took price bit later in Central and Eastern Europe and Russia in particular has to do with the competitive situation. In Russia, we are not the leader of the market, so we are a bit dependent on what the leaders or the leader of the market is doing. We can only raise price backed by the industry leader doing so or having very strong strongholds in particular regions as well as strong brands. So, we are &#x2013; we tend to be more of a follower in Russia than the leader into price raising, that will be the main response to your question.</p>
          <p>The effect on the volume, it is difficult to quantify. As I said in my presentation, we will put going forward a lot of effort in restoring the margins. It's a fine line between market share and margin. If you put back your margin, and you raise your prices back, what for effect of volume will have. So I am not going to give you a precise number, let alone that we would know it. But certainly the fact that we did not raise the prices, perhaps helped a little bit the volume, but to what tune is very difficult to say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Secondly, the volume effect in the organic revenue growth that has, as I said, very much to do with the fact that you are growing in markets with much lower price levels. So if you grow by 11% in Russia, but you lose some volume in Western Europe, the ultimate effect on your revenues is of course much lower than the volume effect you'll have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can we now switch to some questions on the teleconference please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It's very good. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>And the first question today comes from Thomas Russo from Gardner Russo &amp; Gardner. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. I wonder whether you could bring us up-to-date with your progress in India post the settlement of the Scottish &amp; Newcastle acquisition, and whatever else you have been able to accomplish in that market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is still early to say what the solution or &#x2013; the way going forward. We are currently negotiating with Dr. Mallya about the future collaboration as partners in UB. Obviously, we have the complicating factor of having a participation in APB, which is already operating businesses in India, and that is posing perhaps a competitive problem. So this is the situation we are currently addressing between the three partners. We are in the midst of addressing that. And I think, it is premature seeing all interests at play to come up with solutions. But we make progress, and overall you have to reckon we see the Indian market as one of the last markets with an enormous potential to grow the beer category. And when I am saying the beer category, beer brands, Kingfisher is a superb brand. That's the industry leader in India. It is a superb platform also to grow the Heineken brand in the decades to come. So rest assured that we are working on that to make that happen, but that needs still some more time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question comes from Gerard Rijk from ING. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. Two questions. First question is on the marketing expense; you had an organic growth of 5% in the first half. What is the expectation for the second half taking into account the fact that last year in second half you had one big additional market expense, one-off. And also with respect to the weakness in United States, and probably some additional marketing expense there. Second question is on the cost saving, yes, Fit 2 Fight is over. You are now moving to the part of rigorous cost management. You don't want to give targets for that. In the last two years you have reduced the fixed cost ratio by around 150 basis points per year. And how are you going to monitor that internally that you really are moving down to the cost levels of your competitors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, let me take the marketing spend. And as you have seen, although in absolute terms and in percentage terms, we have increased marketing as a percentage of revenue. It was 12.4% versus 12.9 last year. Looking at this second half last year, we had 13% of revenues. This will be much more in line with what we have done in the first half. So, we won't get step up as we had last year. On Fit 2 Fight, obviously, internally we manage cost, we benchmark cost, we set our targets. When you look at the remuneration and bonus systems of country managers and regional management, cost is one of the elements where they are remunerated on. And overall in the company, yes, we manage and monitor the fixed cost ratio. But obviously we go much deeper. So that is certainly not changing. We continue doing that, but where we needed three years ago sort of a wake up call in the company, and therefore we announced a program also externally to reinstate to the company now this is what we have to do. We feel that we have the practices and the structures in place to continue doing this without giving it a big name to the outside world, which is obviously not very encouraging and positive for the people working in the company. And so the focus will not change, the monitoring internally will not change, the thing which will change is that we will update you afterwards every year half year, what we have done and where we stand instead of saying upfront this is what we are going to do the next three years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just continue with the questions in the house please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll do the difficult questions first, and then -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Chris Pitcher from Redburn. Two questions. You mentioned that you expect inflation of 8%, and also variable cost next year, do you think the pricing environment and the consumer environment is robust enough that you can not only maintain but grow gross margins in that inflationary environment; can we see the same sort of pricing as we saw this year carried through? And then secondly on Western Europe, post Scottish &amp; Newcastle, could you give us a feel of what percentage of your revenues in Western Europe are coming from wholesaling and what sort of drag on growth that is likely to be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first part of the question, if the increase of the input cost is structural, you have no other choice than to pass it on. And it is unfortunate that the consumer confidence, as we call it is weak and it might be that &#x2013; it is a result of the inflationary pressure that that inflationary pressure goes much beyond our own industry borders. So I don't think you have any room to take on you not to pass on these price increases, and I am thinking particularly about energy prices and about commodity prices like barley. So I think that is going forward, a discipline we ought to have to continue to maintain our margins because you can lose them only once. So that is the general philosophy.</p>
          <p>Now the rate at which you can apply that depends very much on your leadership position and the position of the industry in the market, but by and large this is the guiding line. And you will have markets where that will be a little bit weaker, but you will also, perhaps have also markets where you can apply it a little bit more forceful, that is in general terms what I can say to you. Ren&#xE9; is looking up for the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I look at the wholesale, as you know, our total revenues out of wholesale in Western Europe and Central and Eastern Europe is over 4 billion. The exact percentage, what it will be in Western Europe after S&amp;N, I am not sure, I would say it will be something that I am looking at around 25% probably will be in the wholesale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a bit lower than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are going through the analysis. It's not a drag on profitability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It &#x2013; well, it is a strategic element of our business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That is, I think, important to underline. Margins in wholesale are much lower. We all know that, but they participate to the building up of our position in the on-trade. That is very important because we service the on-trade, and the &#x2013; we group also the cost of service. And we provide for a whole area adding of services and beverages to the retail. And that is what is &#x2013; keeps together our market share. So it's an integral part of doing business in the on-trade, in large parts of Western Europe. Heineken is the biggest wholesaler in Western Europe. Now, I have to say, having said that, it is a sensitive business to volume. Because it's by-and-large done by fixed cost structures, and when you have big volume slowdowns in the on-trade business, you have to quickly and in a very flexible way adapt your fixed cost structure to the new &#x2013; what the new market is. That is what we have learned to do. In the beginning, it was in the hard way. I must say, but now we do that on a very planned way, where we always work with scenarios going forward that if the volume drops through how do we have to reconfigurate our logistic platforms, in what forms in the markets we operate. But I have to underline that wholesaling remains a core division of doing business in the on-trade in large parts of Europe.</p>
          <p>I think, I have to go to Trevor, who here in front who is waiting still for 10 minutes now. No, no, no, one &#x2013; the one here. Because otherwise I will &#x2013; we will have problems, and if I can &#x2013; to be in front of the room then you can follow quicker who is first, that would be helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Trevor Stirling, Sanford Bernstein. A couple of questions related to the 8% cost inflation of input cost for next year. I appreciate you can't give us it, line item by line item, but maybe two questions, could you say directionally what you have assumed in terms malt and barley prices? Broadly what percentage, I am assuming you are assuming some reduction in malt and barley prices looking at current spot rates?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So if you &#x2013; well, first of all, I won't give it line-by-line, but clearly malt and barley is going down, but obviously we didn't buy last year at the top of the market. So to say that, that is going down, that is not the right conclusion. Secondly, malting fees which are 30% of the cost of malt are going up, because that is a high energy consuming activity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it would be fair to say broadly on the malt and barley itself, the average price, your assumption has been broadly the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Broadly the same. Broadly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The second thing is then, does that 8% take into account these &#x2013; there's a softness in aluminium over the last month, and the recent fall in the oil price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The 8% is the best how we can estimate it now, knowing that we have covered 50% of our needs, knowing what the current oil price and aluminium prices are, we think it will be 8%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Switching over to the telco for two more questions. The telephone -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question comes from Karel Zoete from Rabo Securities. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Karel with Rabo Securities. Question with regard to pricing, in the USA you have not announced price increases so far this year after strong increases in '07. And as the market leader deciding that the pricing environment is quite positive, is it something you are considering for the second half of the year? And the second question more relates towards your guidance, versus a tough comparison base in the first half of the year, you have been able to grow organic net profits by about 5%, isn't your guidance a little bit cautious given an easier comparison base in the second half of the year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the first part, I leave you, Ren&#xE9;, the second part on the guidance. Look as I said earlier, we are not the industry leader in the U.S. So we are very much dependent on what the big domestic brewers are doing as what counts is the price point we have towards domestic proposition. We have to &#x2013; we are premium, but we don't have to be out of the market, that is why we follow developments and we see whether we can fit in or not. That is the general guidance. The time in which we do that is in the hands of the management team of Heineken USA, but rest assured that they are very well incentivized to look at the best opportunity which do justice and to the brands strength and to the operating results of our operation in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then on the guidance, we think, it is realistic guidance going forward. Yes, I realize that the comparables in the first half are &#x2013; were stronger, and therefore we believe for instance in an area like Central and Eastern Europe that we will improve in the second half, prices will come through, and volume-wise the comparatives are less challenging. On the other hand, you cannot just extrapolate the 35% growth in Africa, and take that for granted that it continues like that. Also on the margin side in Africa where we have normally much higher stocks than you have in other parts of the world because of the complicated supply line you see that we have increased prices in the beginning of the year whilst the input costs were not fully getting into the cost price of your product and that effect you will see in the second half. So it's a bit the other side of what you will see in Central and Eastern Europe, there we will see a better half with better margins in Africa. We are still very positive on Africa, but don't expect similar performance as in the first half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question comes from Paul Hofman from Chevreux. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi, good afternoon. This is Paul Hofman from Chevreux in Amsterdam. Two questions. Firstly about volume trends, you expect them to continue in the second half, does it simply mean that you do not expect really recovery in Western Europe and U.S. import market? And secondly, at head office level last year there was already a positive impact, certain one-offs, but still this year in half year it's higher than last year? What's now more &#x2013; less sustainable EBIT contribution from the head office level going forward? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the volume, we have set broadly in line, and that will be a mix between geographies and countries. And once more you'll see some countries where you expect slightly better volumes and others where it is a little bit less. So don't see that every region gets in its similar growth path as they have had in the first half of the year. But overall for the company, we expect to continue to grow &#x2013; to have continuous good growth as well in the total portfolio as on the Heineken brand.</p>
          <p>And head office, yes, there again you see in addition to the positive result that is the effect of, if you &#x2013; on one hand increase the Heineken brand with its royalties on the other hand increase the total business where we get know-how fees on. And on the other hand, you work hard on your cost side, then you would see that increasing. Ultimately it is a bit coming from one part of the business in the other part of the business so I think on the company as a whole it's not very interesting to say where that level exactly should be. That is also not how we manage it. It is much more &#x2013; ultimately you get an outcome what it is in the head office, but we look at it as part of the total operation, and it is in fact linked to the operation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The marketing of that is also...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the marketing is in that as well. Yeah. Absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Nico Lambrechts from Merrill Lynch. Just as a follow-up question on Scottish &amp; Newcastle, I think your pro forma for the second half last year is something like 214 million, could you give us any indication, first of all, I assume that none of the 30 million cost savings achieved to date fell in the first half that was all in July-August. And then for the second half, can you give us any indication how much down, do we &#x2013; do we see it 50% down on similar trend because obviously it's very difficult for this first half being smaller?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, first of all, correction the 30 million is not realized by the end of August. The 30 million is what you will see in the P&amp;L of 2008, based on that &#x2013; on an annualized basis by the end of August, and that was of course very much geared towards the end of August we have the 60 million annualized savings, but that reflects plus what we will do in the remainder of the year in the 30 million in the P&amp;L. And then yes, the pro forma 2007 is the 214 million. Again on that you will get the currency effect and the market developments, and I don't want to give specific guidance for individual markets. So I would like to leave out of that or to stay out of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you then say that the first half impact was that clearly a lack of effort from the Scottish &amp; Newcastle management at the time because what does &#x2013; it was part of the bid, et cetera. And that &#x2013; and the focus is back, so you shouldn't see a similar failure of execution?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The focus is back, but it would have been unfair to say that that performance was just the effect of &#x2013; that the management was not doing the right job. If you see how the development of the UK market has been in the first six months, and once more, it is &#x2013; and the second six months of the smoking ban, and the excise increase, and the bad weather, and the economy. So, the results of the first six months are much more than company, which is not completely focused. Going forward, once again we will work hard to further improve the performance of that company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then a follow-up question on the volume and price/mix. Again, you do break it down into price/mix of 5.1% and then you say that it's 1.6 volume. What I understand from your answer is that, that is actually more the regional price/mix rather than the actual volume impact, because your volumes of beer is 5.4, maybe you can say what's the trend on soft drink volumes, but &#x2013; ?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So if you add 100 hectoliters at &#x20AC;50 the hectoliter, and you lose 100 hectoliters at &#x20AC;100 the hectoliter. You have a stable volume, but a minus 50 on your revenues. So that is the effect that you see that the growth is realized in markets with lower revenue per hectoliter, and therefore you don't get a 5% volume growth translated in a 5% revenue growth. Next to that in the revenue obviously there are other things than just consolidated beer, like the wholesale business, soft drinks, et cetera. But it is to a great extent that the growth of beer is in markets with lower selling prices than a number of the markets where you even lose a little bit of volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, it's a regional price/mix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And so it's a regional mix, absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Bill Casey from Bradshaw Asset Management. I have got two questions, guys please. The first one is on Nigeria, 66% market share. And on a like-for-like basis, how has this evolved over the last couple of years and is there evidence that clear beer is taking share over the likes of Guinness? And the second question is on the U.S. and I suppose the first half of 2008, we have seen a bit of a slowdown in the great growth that was seen in import brands in the last few years, is that a sign that overall consumers are trading down at all, especially after the great Anheuser-Busch results last week or the week before last? And the last question on the U.S. is basically to do with merger of InBev and Anheuser-Busch, do you guys think that it's going to be harder to compete against brands like Stella and Beck's now going forward versus the distribution contract that they had last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now I cannot provide you the exact numbers over the last 10 years of how we progressed in Nigeria. But yes, we progressed. I think that to my knowledge the stock market has reached kind of a solid bottom, where this is also growing with the market albeit not substantially growing its share any more. So yes, we build that position over. I guess, 25 years. I think, if we go back in the '80s our market share with Nigerian breweries was barely 25%. And that is &#x2013; that has been grown all the way through to over 50%. So &#x2013; and that is thanks to investment in the same core three brands, superior beer quality, good distribution network, and weathering also through difficult conditions. It has not always been a bonanza like today in Nigeria, but every time our capability to adapt to that. So that is kind of a qualitative statement about Nigeria.</p>
          <p>In the U.S. the growth issue, yes, we have been seeing that clearly the import market, which have been growing year-on-year over the last, I would say, decade, has come suddenly this year to a halt, that's reality. The problem is whether that will &#x2013; or the question is whether that will continue or not. Look I would like to have a crystal ball and know &#x2013; see something, it is one year, it is early days to say whether that will &#x2013; that trend would continue. What I do know is that, yes, it will create a more fierceful competitive environment because if the pie is not growing, you are going fight for bigger size of the pie. That's what we have to do. And that's what Heineken USA, I think, has being demonstrating in the past that it could do, and that is what we will continue to do. But I would say, I would guess it's a bit early days to say whether really the trading down as you are referring to is something that will last forever.</p>
          <p>We see in our brand portfolio, you have brands which are going superbly up, I was referring to Dos Equis or Tecate Premium Light or Newcastle Brown Ale, which is more to be seen as kind of a craft beer, premium imported craft beer than something else and craft beers are very popular. So clearly early days to say, but it does not have to detract us to do our job on the brands we do.</p>
          <p>Your third question is about the impact of AB-InBev, you have on the one hand AB-InBev, you have on the other side, Miller and Coors, do not forget the access to the U.S. market is guaranteed by the three tier system, which means that as you have the constitution of two large blocks. And I think the major event is in effect, Miller and Coors. Because that creates two large domestic brewers, and a distributor is always more tied to one than the other, but he is not exclusive to. And we all know that AB had a tradition of making them quasi-exclusive to them. And whereas Miller-Coors was not following that philosophy, but a distributor is an independent operator. So that access to market is for us guaranteed by law, and also by the fact that nobody wants to be dependent on one sole supplier. So whether the competition will increase, yes, it will because under management, I guess, that under management of InBev, the Stella and Beck's brand will have more attention than it was previously under the distribution contract that is fair to expect. And on the other hand, you have the competition coming from brands like Peroni and Pilsner Urquell through the Miller-Coors arena. Yet we have a good portfolio with premium brands to fight with, and distributors are keen to take on the brands which have a strong throughput in the market and a great margin.</p>
          <p>Make no mistake, you don't build a brand overnight. You can feel up a pipeline in stocks, but building a brand and a consumer franchise that takes years and years, if not decades. And this is a fine line, it is a &#x2013; it's a collaboration between a distributor and the manufacturer, but manufacturer or the brand owner has to do its part of the job, and it takes time and you need patience for that. And we have a head &#x2013; we have a kind of a head start towards that competition, and we intend to maintain that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Javier Gonzalez-Lastra from Goldman Sachs. Two questions, if I may. First one, you had mentioned that you are going to increase your focus on cash generation. I just wondered whether you could elaborate a bit on any initiatives you are looking at there, and also following from some headlines that come out this morning from your press conference, if you are looking to indeed dispose off some core assets, whether you can give some color there. And second question with regards to coming back again to pricing. I just wondered whether you could share with us where &#x2013; which markets you found the biggest difficulty to put through price increases, and whether you foresee any major resistances into next year if you have to indeed increase prices in the similar &#x2013; at the similar rate, particularly with retailers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first on the cash. Yeah, there will be a specific program in the company addressing the different elements of working capital, and see how we can further reduce that and improve that. We will have specific programs addressing categories of investments, saying how can you &#x2013; very simple things, and we invest quite a lot of money in returnable packaging. So how can you optimize the cycle time of these kinds of things, so that you can lower your investments for efficiency in investments. We will scrutinize them stronger and get higher hurdle rates on it, really say is that going to make the difference, yes or no. These kind of things which will be deeply embedded in the company, and of course, also money towards centrally will be launched and driven through actually, we are in the full process in doing that and have gathered &#x2013; already given for this year short-term targets to regions of operating companies.</p>
          <p>Regarding the non-core assets, I think, there is a bit of misunderstanding. We are a very focused company, so we don't have big divisions, which you want to sell off. That is not what I meant, but in every company, when you look, you see that there are things on the balance sheet or somewhere in the operation which you can dispose, and that is &#x2013; can be a piece of land which was of a former warehouse, which were merged into a bigger one, and it's still not sold. So it is these kind of things where you screen the company, and say what can we get rid of, and how can we get more cash in instead of saying we will divest the region or a big operating company that is not what we have in mind. And there is no need for it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the price increases, well we sell Heineken in 170 markets, and we operate in broad leadership position in another 65 other markets. So I am not going to give you the whole list where it is more difficult or easy. The proxy to it is very simple, and when a market is growing big time, it's easier to pass on price increases than when the market is kind of slowing down or stable, and the second element of reading of how easy or difficult it is to raise prices is to look at the competitive situation. If you have two players it's tangentially more easy than when you have four or five. And the last one is the strength of the brand leader, the mental leader, a brand can set a tone in the market even if it is not the biggest, it can set a tone of setting leadership and do price increases. So these are different keys to &#x2013; and how you have to read it, as an example, I gave the United States where seeing the price differential we have with domestic and the economic environment we are definitely not in the position where we can lead the way as we perhaps were able to do in the past. So you have a number of things you can read and then you can make for your own the evaluation how difficult or how easy it is, but it's a marching order for every operation to make sure that we at least maintain our margins that's for sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chris, you are out already with your both questions, so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Chris Wickham from MainFirst. Just two things. One, I think we touched on earlier into the year, and at this stage last year the prospect of narrow price differentials and the withdrawal of private label contracts by other brewers being helpful. I mean, are you disappointed at this stage by how helpful those kind of developments might have been for pricing, market share, and implicitly even volume. And secondly, you talk about brands which take decades to build, you clearly have a number of those kinds of brands outside the Heineken and Amstel brands in terms of local brands. I am just wondering if there is anything that you are doing differently now from the way you've been doing it before in common for all those brands, i.e., any sort of central initiatives that you might have for those brands, which are other than the Heineken brand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's &#x2013; it's a very good question in the sense that we derive a superior profitability at operating international premium brands, and for profitability the key word is premium pricing. But taking a brand across its borders takes you decades and lots of money. So what we have in our approach, we have a limited number of brands that we handle internationally. But we also do care and nurture what we call the blockbuster brands, which are the mental leaders in that country. A brand like Fosters or John Smiths here in this country is important to us as much as Moretti is in Italy, or Star or Gulder in Nigeria or Primus in Central Africa. So these brands, they typically have a price positioning which would be above the average of the beer market price. And they command a superior profitability and in our approach, we dedicate a lot of attention to that. You don't drive them centrally. You will drive them locally, because most of these brands carry a lot of values, which are very much culturally bound to where they are born. From time to time, you can export that i.e. Guinness, but not all the time. But you have to nurture that. What you do in the large group like ours is to exchange best practices amongst marketeers and commercial people, how you do that in markets. It is not by manuals that you do that, but by a greater analysis of what you invest, where you distribute, what are the levels of investments you put behind the brand. And comparing notes between operations, which are to be compared. That's what we organize big time in our group to also nurture that part of the business. We tend to always speak about the Heineken brand because that's the unifying brand of the whole group, but also these local brands deserve and have a lot of attention in our group going forward.</p>
          <p>Second part and that's related to that it's the private label business, we have taken a long time already to view that it is not the part of business we want to participate, we are into brands. We are organizing the supply capacity, which is needed to service the brands we bring to the market. But we are not going to produce commodity beer. I think that the last operations we &#x2013; operation we still have in the group was the Brasserie, Saint-Omer in France, which we have announced &#x2013; being announcing. We have now disposed off. That was the last piece of private-label business we had in the Heineken group. As I said they are more hit, you will correctly notice that they were more hit by the input price rises than ours. But they have totally different standards of operations. You see that they are mostly not owned by international groups like ours, who are always looking at the branded side of things. We have seen those falling off already in that industry, but as the lifetime of these assets are so long you can survive for very long time if you have amortized everything and you inherited the brewery from your grandfather, I can tell you can still produce beer with an awfully lot lower margin but you can survive for a long time in this industry. So you can't expect that these kind of players are disappearing massively from the market, but they drop out from time-to-time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, on the telephone also -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, are there still questions on the telephone. No?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From the room?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A follow-up question from Nico's question. You talked about that the cost savings, the pressures in the UK maybe ameliorating in the second half. And you talked about the interest rate, putting all that together is it safe to assume that the Scottish &amp; Newcastle will be marginally accretive in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we said in Friday's outlook, that we are not certain that it is earnings accretive in 2009, and that is what we have said. And so in that respect to think although you have a limited part of the year in your accounts, I don't think that you should say that it is earnings accretive in 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Not so accretive in 2008, but in the second half given the timing of profitability, cash flows, and the cost savings coming, will the second half impact from Scottish &amp; Newcastle be accretive do you think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't give you an answer on that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just one other question on cash flow, you have guided to 1.2 billion of CapEx this year. Is it too early to give us a guidance for next year, the level of capital spend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You mentioned that you've regained market share -in South Africa with Amstel brand, could you quantify that? I think, you were at 7% when you terminated the license, if I remember correctly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We went back to &#x2013; at the rate running something around &#x2013; that is tangentially if &#x2013; I am not giving you the exact number, but half the running rate that we have before. What SAB was operating is return &#x2013; returnable packaging, which we do not, it's only one way. So we started from scratch and building up to what would be half the volume that we &#x2013; when we left the license situation. That is what we grow towards, and that on a base of import and glass, and one-way glass, and we are building up to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And are you reaching all the outlets that was reached by SAB or is your distribution a lot limited therefore you can't regain with the current infrastructure for your other brewery?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nico, you are a connoisseur of the market, and I &#x2013; the answer is no, we can not reach the parts SAB can reach at this moment in time with non-returnable glass for sure. Also we don't have the kind of the size and the structure to really reach out in a capillary way into ocean beams in South Africa for sure. But we have a good penetration rate. But it's not to the point SAB reached.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And looking in a positive way, therefore if you have got half the volume already, do you reach half the outlets or do you even reach less outlets, demonstrating the strength of brand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I cannot respond to that precise question there, so &#x2013; in the numbers, but going to half the volume we have, there is only one way is I guess already a very good performance. And bear in mind, we operate in the premium end of the market in South Africa. That's what we are dedicated. We cannot compete with the bread and butter Castle brands and that kind of pricing in the South African brands that is not what we are seeking for. We are looking for the premium market, and that on a backdrop where the consumers in South Africa are really looking out for more premium proposals. And you see that differentiation evolving in the South African market, and that's where we go after.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, we deserve a beer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's call it a day. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>