<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1294107" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-02-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7863</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Oliver Luckenbach, Vice President-Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Kasper B. Rorsted, Chief Executive Officer and Head &#x2013; Human Resources</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Lothar Steinebach, Executive Vice President-Finance, Information Technology &amp; Legal</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Matthias Eifert</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Hans van Bylen</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Arne Rautenberg</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Harold Thompson</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Friedrich Stara</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Mark Christensen</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep">Jan-Dirk Auris</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Marco Gulpers</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">J&#xF6;rg Philipp Frey</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to our Full Year 2010 Analyst and Investor Meeting.</p>
          <p>Before we start, I would like to remind you that there will be a live webcast of the whole meeting, including the Q&amp;A session on our Investor Relations website. May I further remind you that copies of speeches and presentations which contain the usual formal disclaimer to forward looking statements within the meaning of the relevant U.S. legislation can be accessed via our website at henkel.com/ir. The presentations and discussions are conducted subject to the disclaimer. We will not read the disclaimer, but propose we take it as read into the records for the purpose of this conference.</p>
          <p>I would like to handover now to Kasper Rorsted.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Oliver. Welcome also, here, to D&#xFC;sseldorf. Today's agenda is the following. I will speak to you through the micro picture of 2010. Lothar will take you through the details of '10 and the fourth quarter. I will then subsequently take you through the outlook for '11, and we'll close off with a Q&amp;A session.</p>
          <p>So market environment highlights, I will also speak about some of the changes we've undertaken within the company, Lothar will take you through three and four, and I will close on five.</p>
          <p>But before I go into 2010, let me just frame the entire setting because I believe it's important when we do the comparison, we do them on the right basis. We come from an economy that grew 1.4% in 2008, came into recession of latter part of 2008, had a negative GDP growth of 2.1 in '09, and now back to 4.0 in '10. So if you do with the clear mathematics, we're pretty much back to the level of 2008 from an overall size standpoint.</p>
          <p>The world trade group are 12.5%. The industrial growth was very strong but, of course, based on very weak comparables. And I think what probably was retrospectively a bit surprising was the somewhat modest growth in private consumption that we have also experienced in our markets, where in most of our relevant markets they buy them in flat or negative. I'll get back to that later in our presentation.</p>
          <p>But I think that looking back to somewhat modest growth in private consumption has been retrospectively a surprise, and we are, particularly in the latter part of 2010, seeing a very strong increase in the raw materials. That was projected for the year, however, it was much more seasoned in the second half versus the first half, and we're also seeing that in the beginning of 2011. So overall, a very strong year following the recession in '09, but on a macro bit level we are pretty much back to 2008 levels plus a bit.</p>
          <p>What was the market impact on Henkel? If you look upon the industrial side and take some of the bigger industrial sectors into the focus with whom we conduct business with, transportation being one, growth of 18% compared to '09, machinery up 16% and electronics up 14%. So strong double-digit growth rates on the manufacturing side. As I said, modest growth in private consumption in retail, so while the overall economy has strong growth, we actually saw two directions that were quite different. Strong growth in industry market segments and very modest on the overall consumer markets. However, it is fair to say that the overall recovery in 2010, of course, also was beneficial to the numbers that we are presenting today.</p>
          <p>From the achievement side, we are coming from a year where all the business groups have outgrown the relevant markets, meaning that we have gained market shares. The emerging markets continued to play an ever bigger role within the Henkel Corporation, with double-digit growth rates now accounting for 41% on our total business.</p>
          <p>Our adjusted EBIT have now, for the first time, for fiscal year surpassed the 12% barrier, or level if you want to put in that way. We've had five consecutive quarters above 12%, third quarter of 2010 surpassed 13% for the first time. So, we're taking a very important step in moving the company up one notch towards the 2012 at 14% coming from a 12% run rate in 2009.</p>
          <p>National Starch has been successfully integrated. The acquisition that was initiated beginning of March in 2008, one year earlier than planned. And this will also be the final part of reporting regarding National Starch, that means forward looking in the next coming quarters and also years, we will not do any separate accounting or reporting on synergies for National Starch. It has been finalized.</p>
          <p>We continue to have cost in our focus, and that will also be the case moving forward, and we took networking capital a further notch down from 7.0% to 6.9%. So overall, pretty much across the board a very, very solid year for Henkel.</p>
          <p>However, there were also challenges in the year that went by. I briefly touched upon it in my opening statement, but the raw materials, I would say, did have different seasonality than originally expected. When we guided you at this meeting a year ago, we said mid-single-digits with a pretty even distribution on the pricing. What did, in fact, occur was mid- through higher-single-digit but with a much higher increase coming in the second half than the first half. So the overall number wasn't that wrong, it was more &#x2013; was sequentially deployed throughout the year, so very strong roll until price increases.</p>
          <p>We did also see a supply shortage in certain raw materials, particularly impacting our Adhesive business. And the overall impact was to the tune of &#x20AC;50 million, so we all pretty much lost &#x20AC;50 million of revenue. What we also did see, though, was an impact on the GP1 line because we at times had to ship raw materials from location A to location B, simply because of lack of ability. So supply shortage in 2010 particularly impacting our Adhesive business, and we expect that also to be the case going into '11.</p>
          <p>The competition in our fast-moving consumer goods market intensified. It started with a price initiated approximately 18 months ago in Asia, in India to be more specific, and we've seen very, very strong price and promo activity in this year and the last 12 months, pretty much across the board. That has not changed throughout the year. It has somewhat stabilized in the fourth quarter, and we did start to see price increases in the market in the latter part of the fourth quarter in our Detergents business in Eastern Europe.</p>
          <p>And we have, as we also reported in the same audience as this in August following our second quarter numbers, we have not been happy with our performance in our North American business. We've undertaken a number of steps, which we also explained to you, not only when it comes to management, but also structural changes in the latter part of 2010, and we are certain that we will be able to turn the business around to a satisfactory level in 2011. We have seen the first signs of improvements with stabilizing/growing market share in the last periods, being months 11 and 12 in North America. So we are starting to see the first signs. I do, however, want to use the same wording as I did in August: the problem didn't materialize overnight and won't be fixed overnight. However, we are confident that with the actions we're taking we will be fixing the situation in 2011.</p>
          <p>Overall, we were capable to deal with the challenges in a market that was also difficult in 2010. It was not only tailwind, we did have a lot of headwind, particularly coming into the second half and through the second half, and I believe that when you look upon the overall numbers that we were able to deal with those challenges appropriately.</p>
          <p>Let me now on a macro level take you through three different business groups. On our Laundry &amp; Home Care business, we did see positive organic sales growth, and reason why I'm saying it in this way is that it was a market that has been highly characterized by enormous price and promo activity. So we've seen strong growth on the volume side, and we were also able to turn it into organic sales growth, but the promotion activities have been exceptionally strong in 2010.</p>
          <p>We continued our double-digit growth rates in the MENA region, Middle East, North Africa. We did achieve market share gains in a highly competitive market environment despite the competitive nature, and which was very good to see we did.</p>
          <p>At the end of the year, we got record high adjusted EBIT and EBIT margin for the full year. We have an innovation rate of approximately 40%, similar to previous year; 81% of our sales are generated by our top 10 brands; and we continue to strengthen the big brands in our portfolio, a strategy that we've initiated a number of years ago that we'll continue to push moving forward. So overall, despite very difficult market environment, first year about 13% and a good year for our Laundry &amp; Home Care business.</p>
          <p>For Cosmetics and Toiletries, in a stable to declining market we continue to see strong organic sales growth of almost five points, very much driven by high volume. The emerging markets continued double-digit growth rates, despite also defining to the stagnating market. We had, again, very strong gains and market shares across the board, and recorded record high EBIT and adjusted EBIT margin again above 13%.</p>
          <p>Innovation rate above 40% and 89% of our sales with 10 brands, Schwarzkopf now accounts for &#x20AC;1.8 billion. So what you are seeing is that we are really getting the payoff of building power brands within our portfolio. So consistent, strong, good performance from our Cosmetics and Toiletries business in the year 2010.</p>
          <p>Coming to Adhesive business. 2009 was a particular challenging year, particularly in the first half, changing through the second half. That's why it was very good to see that the acceleration in the second half of 2009 was continued in 2010, and we did see very, very strong top line growth across the board.</p>
          <p>The emerging markets was the main growth driver with double-digit growth, but across the board all regions grew last year. We did, also in this area, see market share gains, and again, in this year our record high adjusted EBIT and adjusted EBIT margin numbers for the full year and innovation rate at approximately 24%, up from 21% a year ago, and 52% of our sales for the top 10 brands. So very strong quarter, no, year for our Adhesive business. It has to be this way because it was the best year in the history of our company. And, of course, when everybody contributes, then by default, you will have record year for all business groups, but across the board a very satisfactory year for our Adhesive business also.</p>
          <p>From a number of standpoints, we surpassed the &#x20AC;15 billion mark for the first time; &#x20AC;15.092 billion, reported an 11-point growth organic 7.0%. Lothar will take you through the bridge between the 11 and 0 and on 7, and adjusted EBIT growth of almost &#x20AC;0.5 billion from 13.64% to 18.62%, and adjusted EBIT margin from 10% to 12.3%, 232 basis points, and earnings per share from &#x20AC;1.91 to &#x20AC;2.82. So 47.6% growth in this area. We continued our progress, as I alluded to before. Our networking capital taking it down from 7.8% to 6.9%, 90 basis points, and our current proposal when it comes to dividend is an increase of 35% from &#x20AC;0.53 to &#x20AC;0.72, which will be finally decided at our AGM in April.</p>
          <p>I believe we have taken, as a company, a major step towards 2012. At the same time, it is, as I've said on previous occasions, a bit like in football we're at half-time and we're leading two-nil, but the game has not been won. We have equally much progress to be reached in the second half, meaning your 11th and 12th to get to where we need to get to, but it was a major step in the right direction for Henkel as a corporation to achieve our targets in 2012.</p>
          <p>In 2007, we decided upon in early 2008 to set a set of sustainability targets for our business for 2012. It has been in our sustainability report in the last three years, you can see that in the reports. What I did want to do today was just give you a brief update on, and let you know that we are ahead of plan, and we've actually reached the target we set ourselves for 2012, when it comes to sustainability.</p>
          <p>These targets were set before our financial targets in 2008. And I do think it shows one thing that is very important: that sustainability performance and financial performance go hand-in-hand. We have a made a tremendous step forward in our financial performance, and in parallel we've also made a tremendous step forward in our performance in sustainability. What we will be doing is that we will be defining our new set of targets for sustainability moving forward. They will be defined this year and probably communicated next year beyond 2012. You can read details of our current performance in the sustainability report, which you have on your table along with the annual report. So you'll get the next set of sustainability targets probably before you get the next set of financial targets.</p>
          <p>With this, I'd like to move, just to give you a headline, on where we are on some of the transformational activities that we've undertaken within the company. Some are related only to 2010, and some are related to the last three years as a period.</p>
          <p>What we've done is we are taking the company through a transformational process that will not stop, period. That's a process that will continue in order to ensure that we will remain competitive in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>We've very often spoken about some of the structural changes that we have undertaken in the last few years. We have spent less time speaking about some of the cultural changes, and let me highlight a couple of those on both sides that we find are of particular importance.</p>
          <p>Last year we launched a new, what we call cultural framework, that we worked upon for the last 18 months. So it was a substantial amount of work that went into this. What it consisted of was a revised vision that articulates the aspiration that we have as a company; a revised set of values that define the behavior of every individual within our organization; a revised set of performance criteria upon which people are being evaluated when they are on the job, but also behavioral competences that we hire people upon; and a comp system that is actually linked to the evaluation criteria and the value. So, a comprehensive framework that was launched mid-year of last year and has been rolled out.</p>
          <p>And what does it consist? It starts with the Henkel logo that we haven't changed, but we have changed our claim, excellence is our passion. And we also changed our vision of global leader and brands and technologies, and both are aimed at articulating what we're trying to drive the company towards, or we strive to drive the company towards, which is being the best at what we do. So, we're definitely trying to put the ambition level at a different level, than in the past. That's why we are saying excellence is our passion, and also, we do want to be a global leader in brands and technologies.</p>
          <p>I'm not here to try to tell you what we are today, but this is the aspiration level we're setting ourselves. That is not we're trying to play in the middle of the pack, we're aiming to be a leader in brands and technologies.</p>
          <p>We've defined five values: customer, people, financial, sustainability and family. And in financials it does say we drive excellence sustainable financial performance. So, what we are doing is that we're having a very, very focused effort on driving a particular culture within our organization across the board for Henkel, and creating clarity of whom we are and where we want to go.</p>
          <p>And we've done this with significant effort. I cannot say every single employee, but I believe it would be fair to say that 99% of all employees across the board, across the globe, have gone through an intensive workshop with their respective management on our vision and values framework to have a common understanding of where are we, where do we want to go, where are we strong, and what do we need to do, in 5,000 workshops across the globe taking place, starting in October, finalizing in December. And the feedback has been extremely clear. As I said, our aim is to drive a very clear culture within our organization that articulates what we stand for, and it does start with our vision to be a global leader in brands and technologies.</p>
          <p>We have also changed our comp system. I have been asked by many of you over the last three years, is your compensation system appropriate? And the answer I gave you the first two years was, it's appropriate to the extent that it doesn't prevent us from doing what we want to do but is not giving us the final push, but it not prevents us from doing the right thing.</p>
          <p>In 2009, we underwent a very long effort of going through changes in our comp system. We have articulated what it is all about in 2010 to our entire management relation, all 9000 people, because one thing is to change the comp system, almost as important, or is as important, is that people actually understand what the comp system is all about because you can do a lot of goodness with a comp system. But a good comp system that nobody knows is not a very good comp system. So we wanted to make certain, that everybody had a very clear understanding of what the new compensation system means, and that is now being put into place and it has been rolled out from Jan 1st of 2011. What it does do, it creates a clear link between performance and Henkel performance, and also drives the spread further, so that means that the strong performance gets more of it and the less strong get less out of it.</p>
          <p>We've also initiated a special incentive program along our financial targets, or linked up with financial targets, for 2012, which is relevant for the top 3,000 leaders across the globe. Very basically said, it is giving them a double-up of their comp in 2012, assuming we hit the target and we are assuming we will hit the target.</p>
          <p>That has been communicated across the board and has created a great level of excitement in the organization. What we are striving to do is ensure that the ownership of the success of Henkel is on as many shoulders as possible, and I believe that is aligning interest of the shareholders with interest of the people in the organization. That has been rolled out. It was communicated last summer to the top leaders of our company, and finally communicated to our top 3,000 leaders by the end of the year. As I said, very basic, they double their variable pay in 2012 when we hit the target.</p>
          <p>When it comes to structural changes, we have further strengthened our global brands. In our Detergents business, our top three brands account for 50% of business. Top 10, 80% for Cosmetics business 70% and 90%. Schwarzkopf has now grown to &#x20AC;1.8 billion brand.</p>
          <p>So the criticism that we have probably rightly received some years ago that we don't have any strong brands, I hope that we are changing your perception of that. We have done a significant work on strengthening our global brands. And as you can see, we are making progress on this also.</p>
          <p>In our Adhesives businesses, top three is a quarter and the top ten is 50%. And right now we are undergoing a significant effort in our Adhesives business to further streamline and simplify the brand structure with our Adhesives business. So strong progress in our overall brand work within our organization.</p>
          <p>When it comes to our emerging markets, they have been and are and will continue to be the growth driver for our company. They generate 41% of our sales up from 31%, some 10 points five years ago, and continue to be the growth driver and in many areas, also, the profit driver of our organization. So very strong performance from our emerging regions. Our target is to get to approximately 45% by 2012. And we believe that we are well underway to reach that target.</p>
          <p>So not only is it a growth driver, it is also where by now the biggest majority of our infrastructure is. We have 53% of our employees in our emerging markets versus 47% in the mature. And if you look upon the transformation, you saw in the previous chart that we gained 10 points of relative revenue over five years. When it comes to people, we have changed five points of relative distribution over five year.</p>
          <p>So what you're seeing is we have, up to 2006, major transformation when it comes to blue collar. What you're seeing right now is that is more and more at the level where it needs to be. We are now transforming white collar because a lot of our key customer segments are now headquartered in Asia: automotive, electronics and machinery. So we're moving more and more of high qualified, white collar work also into those regions.</p>
          <p>When it comes to supply chain, we have done substantial simplification in our supplier portfolio, reduced it by approximately 25% from 8% to 10%. That has been feasible through our global purchasing system that we have. And our aim is to further reduce it over time. It is &#x2013; we need to drive out complexity on one side, and on the other side increase cooperation with our top suppliers.</p>
          <p>We have an absolutely outstanding relationship with companies like BASF, Evonik, OSiS, companies from different countries and different locations. And our relationship with our suppliers are, for obvious reasons, not only cost based, its innovation based and also delivery based. So the better and the deeper relationship we can build with fewer suppliers, the greater value will our suppliers deliver to us.</p>
          <p>We have made progress on reducing our formulations and packaging, but not to the tune where we're happy. We've reduced with approximately 10% in the last two years and we need to reduce it further. The reason being very basic, it drives complexity and cost up the more variance you have. So while we made progress, we have not made enough progress in this area. So we believe that also moving forward, we have significant cost opportunities in this area to the tune of at least &#x20AC;100 million on an annualized basis.</p>
          <p>Shared Services, a further transformation within the organization. You've heard about our centers in Bratislava and Manila on previous basis. We have now opened a third center in Mexico to serve Latin America for various reasons. Currently we have 700 people based in these centers. Our target is to have at least 1,000 people by the end of this year. And these 1,000 people serve functions only, meaning HR, finance and purchasing. What we will also be initiating is a great level of focus on how can we transfer transactional services from the business groups into these centers.</p>
          <p>So we are making progress. We believe that there is substantial opportunity moving forward in this area also, but we need to do it in the right direction. As I said a couple years ago, we had very few. Today, we have two large centers. We just opened the third one in Mexico, and driving the total population just in the functional area to approximately 1,000 by the end of this calendar year.</p>
          <p>We continue to adjust our structures to the market. Global excellence was finalized a year ahead of plan. National Starch integration was finalized a year ahead of plan. We've taken our IT supplier portfolio and consolidated from more than a 1,000 different suppliers to four: Accenture, IBM, Unisys, and IBM, thank you, for the datacenters. We've done substantial progress on our manufacturing footprint. We've spoken about that on many occasions with you. And, as I just alluded to or explained to you, was Shared Services which we have expanded and are expanding.</p>
          <p>This is not a static slide. This is a dynamic slide. What I mean by that is that we'll continue to work on our structures moving forward. But I wanted to give you an overview on some of the work that we have done. And also, at the same time, give you an indication that we continue to work on our structures moving forward.</p>
          <p>2010 was a global team effort. We had good numbers in a year that was, in many areas, difficult. We have more than 110 nationalities within our corporation. 29% of our leaders are female and we have structured succession planning going on. As you can see today on the stage, we have &#x2013; Jan-Dirk Auris is on my left. After six years in Asia coming back and taking over the Adhesive business, Geitner Thomas. And we have Bruno Piacenza, also a long-term Henkel employee. Both look young but they have a lot of age or, at least, seasonality behind them, taking over for Friedrich's on our Detergents business.</p>
          <p>So what we're doing is that we're undertaking a generation change in our Henkel management team moving forward, also in a year that has been a very successful year. We see the diversity as being one of many success factors within our organization. But it is clear that we need to have a diverse team to run a global organization.</p>
          <p>Before I hand over to Lothar, you know the slide and the triangle, we have record high EBIT margin despite tough competition. We have a strong performance across all sectors and regions. And we continue to focus on our three strategic priorities: full business potential, customers and strengthen our global team and particularly the culture element that played a big part in 2010 and we'll continue to do that moving forward.</p>
          <p>So we continue to make progress on our strategic priorities. You'll continue to see this slide until December 31st  2011, because it is important that we keep the targets we had set ourselves two and half years ago right ahead of us, even though that we might have bumps in the road. We had them in the past. We'll also have this, this year with the market conditions. But we have our target very much in front of us, and we're very committed to reach those targets. 2010 was another important step towards hitting our targets in 2012.</p>
          <p>With this I'd like to hand over to Lothar who will take you through the fourth quarter and the full fiscal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Kasper. I will start, as usual, with Q4 and then give some perspectives on the full year, reminding all of us that Q4 is usually a weaker quarter compared to the others because, in particular, of our Industrial business where our Industrial customers tend to close down their facilities earlier towards the end of the year than, obviously, in other quarters. So, therefore, Q4 as we had communicated earlier will be a weaker quarter than the previous ones. Although, from our perspective, it's not a weak quarter.</p>
          <p>Sales growth by business sector: Laundry &amp; Home Care, Cosmetics/Toiletries, Adhesive Technologies. First of all, a quick look at Laundry &amp; Home Care with 0.5% organic sales growth composed of -3% in pricing and 3.5% positive in volume. So with our strong volume, we've overcompensated the negative pricing impact, resulting in positive organic sales growth which is an improvement over Q3.</p>
          <p>We've continued to gain market share in a very difficult environment. During the year, we have communicated about price aggressiveness in the competitive environment, and that has basically carried through most of the year. We've been strong in heavy-duty laundry. We've been strong in fabric finisher and auto dish. Those are the categories we have been seeing a strong performance.</p>
          <p>We've also had, in terms of regions, a strong performance in Middle East/Africa. Eastern Europe has been much slower than what we had experienced over the previous years. Although, it's been positive as a result of our efforts to regain market share and improve our situation.</p>
          <p>We have communicated on various occasions that we've not been happy with our performance in North America, and that's been true in Q4 as well. We're underway to fix it, but we're not through with it yet.</p>
          <p>Cosmetics/Toiletries, 4.1% organic sales growth, strong continuation of our volume growth during the year ending in the Q4 with 4.1% organic sales growth, composed of a -2.5% pricing and 6.6% very strong volume growth in a difficult market environment.</p>
          <p>Despite intense competitive pressure we have outperformed, again, our markets. We have achieved record market shares in a number of categories and we have experienced double-digit organic sales growth in the emerging markets. Double-digit is true of all pieces of the emerging markets. We've been strong in Eastern Europe. We've been strong in Asia-Pacific, Latin America and Middle East/Africa.</p>
          <p>Western Europe has been okay, so, basically, slightly positive. And here again with North America, we've not been happy. Although, on a different level than in Laundry &amp; Home Care. Here again, we're on the path to fix it. We're not through with it yet.</p>
          <p>Adhesive Technologies, 9.7% with a strong finish of a strong year 2010. 0.9% positive pricing. So we're back to positive pricing in Adhesive Technologies and we've communicated that we're on the way to increase our prices. At 8.9% still a very strong performance in terms of volume growth. Here again, all regions have been contributing. We've been positive with good growth in the mature countries and markets. And a strong growth, double-digit growth, in the emerging markets, in particular Asia-Pacific, Eastern Europe and Middle East/Africa.</p>
          <p>Sales growth by regions, we've been growing in all regions except North America where we've experience flat organic sales growth. And, obviously, HPC has been negative and Adhesive Technologies has been positive in North America. We've seen especially strong organic sales growth in Middle East/Africa and in Asia-Pacific, translating into yet another year of double-digit organic sales growth in the emerging markets. Our sales share in the emerging markets has been increased from 38% to 41% of total sales. It's been driven in major part by our strong performance in Adhesive Technologies and in Cosmetics/Toiletries.</p>
          <p>Adjusted operating earnings, EBIT by business sector, let me start with total company in Q4 with -40 basis points in terms of margin in Q4. However, as one item that has not been adjusted that's an additional &#x20AC;30 million which were booked for the special incentive, which Kasper Rorsted has described earlier.</p>
          <p>A special incentive has been set out for about 3,000 people of top management if we reach our targets in 2012. Now our strong results during the year have permitted us to book already a major part of total expense that would be attributable to this special incentive.</p>
          <p>Laundry &amp; Home Care with -220 basis points over the same period of prior-year Q4. We've seen the first impact of the rising input costs. We've used cost optimization initiatives in order to mitigate the impact from the rising input costs.</p>
          <p>Q4 2009 has been a strong comparison and, therefore, comparison in Q4 2010 has been more difficult. Q4 2009 was characterized by lower promotional pressure, promotional pressure has set in, in 2010, and lower input costs. Here again, we've communicated during the year that rising input costs would hit in the third or fourth quarter and continue into 2011. So that's obviously an area where we've put a big watch on.</p>
          <p>Cosmetics/Toiletries plus 40 basis points with record-high margin we've ever experienced. We've continued on our strong profitable growth path. We've seen strong organic sales growth and we've seen, again, another increase in our profitability.</p>
          <p>Finally, Adhesive Technologies. Here again we've seen rising input costs which we have &#x2013; we've been able to offset by very strong performance in terms of capacity utilization, stronger operating leverage. So rising input costs have been offset by our continued improvements in our cost structure, on pricing increases and better operating leverage.</p>
          <p>Income statement adjusted sales to gross profit. Obviously, in Q4 our gross profit has been 110 basis points below the same period of 2009, even though we had better volume leverage in particular in our Adhesive Technologies, and even though we've utilized cost savings initiatives to mitigate the impact from higher input costs and lower selling prices. In particular in Laundry &amp; Home Care, we've seen pressure on gross margin.</p>
          <p>Reported to adjusted EBIT in Q4, -16% from one-time gains which we have experienced. And one-time losses only 5%, that is write-offs for smaller items that we had to write-off in terms of intangibles.</p>
          <p>We've continued with our strong initiatives on restructuring. Therefore, pretty high amount of restructuring charges of &#x20AC;80 million in Q4 resulting in an adjusted EBIT of &#x20AC;448 million, change of 8% over the same period of last year.</p>
          <p>That permits me to give a perspective on the full-year sales growth by business sector. Laundry &amp; Home Care with organic sales growth over the total year 1.5% composed of a strong emphasis on volume growth. I'm sure you've observed, during the year, strong statements from our competitors in terms of emphasizing volume over profitability.</p>
          <p>We've maintained our margin, increased our margin, as you've seen earlier, for the full year. At the same time, we have increased our volume. Thus permitting us to grow profitably and, obviously, supported by market share gains. It's been a tremendous achievement under very difficult circumstances in 2010.</p>
          <p>Total Henkel 12.3%, the operating margin for the full year. Here again, the full amount of &#x20AC;51 million which we have provisioned for the special incentive for Henkel reaching the targets 2012, has not been adjusted. It's obviously an operating item and therefore cannot be adjusted. Although, it won't recur every quarter, as you might imagine. So we basically built the provision that we need in order to be able to payout the special incentive to the tune of two-thirds already.</p>
          <p>Sales, gross margin over the year has been positive 90 basis points stronger than the previous period. Again, the volume leverage has helped us a great deal. In particular, stronger capacity utilization in our Adhesive division and strong and focused input cost management, overcompensating rising input costs.</p>
          <p>Income statement to adjusted EBIT, between gross profit and adjusted EBIT we have a number of items where we have changes. Marketing, selling and distribution lower by 10 basis points, admin expenses lower by 50 basis points. We've continued with our highly marketing investments, basically on the same level in terms of ratio to sales as we've had it in the same period of last year, or the year before, with selling and distribution costs down. So we have sustained our marketing investment as a percentage of sales, and selling and distribution costs have been down. That's the reason for the 10 basis points lower marketing, selling and distribution expenses.</p>
          <p>We've continued our drive to use Shared Services in all our SG&amp;A processes, with a result of -50 basis points for the full year. Extended usage of Shared Services has been and will be a strong contributor to our cost structure improvement. We'll continue with this drive for this year and next year, and we'll continue to reap the benefits of the investments that we have undertaken in creating the Shared Service centers already.</p>
          <p>As Rorsted has shown, the three Shared Service centers in Bratislava, Manila and Mexico City, Interlomas, which we have established. We have gained the lot of experience over the years in running Shared Service centers, but also transferring processes. That's not a trivial fact. It is difficult to standardize processes in the SG&amp;A sector which is a requirement of being able to transfer processes into Shared Service and then get the benefit of the lower usage of labor, and obviously the benefits of scale.</p>
          <p>We'll continue with this drive in the other areas. We've done that already in finance. We've continued in purchasing and HR and we'll continue with that in all other sectors where parts of the processes can be separated out from the countries transferred into Shared Service.</p>
          <p>Reported to adjusted EBIT for the full year, one-time gains, one-time losses and restructuring charges. First of all, one-time gains for the full year, obviously only a small portion has been recorded in Q4. So for the full year it is 59, resulting from the release of certain provisions which we could not maintain and a divestment gain from a licensing agreement which we had recorded in Q1.</p>
          <p>One-time losses, smaller amount totaled &#x20AC;14 million for the full year; impairment of some assets which we had written down in the course of the year. And a strong restructuring effort in getting our structures adapted to a higher profitability, but also to a different manufacturing setup.</p>
          <p>We've communicated during the year and the year before that as a result of the crisis there'll be changes in the manufacturing footprint for our customers and therefore for us. And we've continued with our drive to reduce the number of manufacturing facilities that we operate, in particular a pretty high number that we had in the Adhesive sector and continue to invest where our customers and our markets grow.</p>
          <p>As strongly is the case in Asia-Pacific, we're right now in the process of building the largest Adhesive factory that we have in the world in China. So we continue to adapt our manufacturing footprint to the footprint of our customers, and at the same time reduce total number of facilities in order to increase our efficiency.</p>
          <p>We have invested a large amount in 2010 already, 110 of which a smaller portion is still attributable to the National Starch integration which we have completed, and the larger part to the other parts of the Adhesive division, but also of the other divisions.</p>
          <p>Shared Services has been &#x2013; we have invested about &#x20AC;25 million in restructuring efforts in order to transfer processes into Shared Services, and obviously that's an important area for us to go forward.</p>
          <p>Cash flow statement. Interesting again, even though we've had a strong increase in our sales volume, we've not utilized more cash in order to finance our net working capital. As you can see, we have had a positive contribution from cash net working capital of &#x20AC;87 million, even though with a much higher sales volume, one would have expected a strong consumption of cash in order to be able to manage net working capital. Now we have decreased again the ratio of net working capital to sales, I will show that in a moment, which has permitted us to, even in the face of highest growth in our sales volume, generate cash.</p>
          <p>Cash flow from operating activities, or free cash flow. Even though cash flow from operating activities was slightly below the same period of last year, free cash flow is higher, so we basically have been at a level of &#x20AC;1.5 billion, which is far exceeds what we had targeted for 2008 as you might remember, the &#x20AC;1 billion free cash flow, we're far ahead of our own targets that we had identified earlier.</p>
          <p>That's net working capital, which I mentioned earlier. Our strong performance is obviously composed of different performance in our business division. We've shown that during &#x2013; on a previous occasion by business division in order to provide transparency, permitting us, ourselves and yourselves to compare us to our peers.</p>
          <p>As you can see at end of 2010, our net working capital in our Laundry &amp; Home Care division was negative. It was 3.3 in our Cosmetics/Toiletries and 14% in Adhesives. Now comparing ourselves all the time to our peers and I can tell you, this is best-in-class.</p>
          <p>Our strong cash generation has permitted us to not only reduce our net debt, but also improve our financial situation dramatically. We have reduced over the two-year period since 2008 our net debt by more than &#x20AC;1.4 billion. Strong free cash flow generation has permitted us to reduce our net debt. High discipline in spending on capital investments and on acquisitions or no acquisitions, again has permitted us to generate free cash flow; retire debt. And it has permitted us to fund our pension funds to improve our financial situation there again.</p>
          <p>Use of free cash flow. And that same chart has been with us for a long period of time and it won't change anytime soon. Our dividend policy is around 25% of net earnings, adjusted for exceptional items. And that's why we provide the transparency and clarity on what we adjust and what we don't adjust. So around 25% of net earnings and that, therefore, is our proposal for the AGM.</p>
          <p>We continue to target a reduction in debt such that our KPIs reach the targets that are required in order for the rating agencies to upgrade us to a A flat or A2, depending on the agency.</p>
          <p>We obviously have generated through two strong years in terms of cash generation, already a big reduction in net earnings and a strong improvement in our KPIs that are relevant for the financial flexibility that we have in order to augment our organic sales growth by external growth.</p>
          <p>However, our commitment remains that our KPIs shall remain within a parameters such that our rating will be upgraded, and that therefore also answers the questions as to whether there are any immediate plans for share buybacks. There are no such plans. Our strong commitment to A flat or A2 ratings remain; our strong commitments to grow our company with our own resources remain; does not exclude interesting targets but it excludes a weakening of our financial position.</p>
          <p>With that I hand over back to Kasper for the finale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Lothar. Now to the outlook for 2011. Before I come to point let me just reflect a bit what we said two and half years ago. We set the targets of organic sales growth for the following 4 years '88 to '12 of a average of 3% to 5%, and adjusted EBIT margin target of 14% and adjusted EPS growth of above 10% per annum.</p>
          <p>In 2009, we have negative organic sales growth of -3.5%, adjusted EBIT margin of 10% and adjusted EPS growth of 12.8%. With the numbers that we are disclosing today, so 7% top-line growth, 12.3% adjusted margin and adjusted EPS growth of 47.6, we are now at 1.8% versus the 3 to 5 corridor for the first 2 years and we are at adjusted EPS growth of 13.5%. So we are in the corridor for EPS. We are on track when it comes to margin. We are slightly behind when it comes to organic sales growth to be in the corridor of 3 to 5, and we believe that we have a good chance of making that up over the next two years to get back into the corridor. So at this stage, based on what we know today, we're still very confident that we'll achieve our financial targets that we're defining here for 2012.</p>
          <p>How do we see the year coming? I showed on the left hand on the slide, before, but I now added the 2011 assumption, and the assumption is that we'll see a global GDP growth of 3.2%, global trade going up by 6.6%, and industry growing at 6.1%, and private consumption down from 2.8% to 2.7%, so a somewhat similar picture to what we've seen in 2010. So the industrial side of the market, leading the overall growth, with as I said here a growth of 6%, and the consumption being fairly modest at around 2.7%.</p>
          <p>We continue to see very strong increases in raw material cost. And what I've done here is I've just taken out, because in 2008 everybody thought that the world was going crazy, with the crude oil price at $145, I believe it was $111 this morning. But I've taken three other raw materials out, so when we say that the crude oil is still below 2008 level, three crucial materials or raw materials that we are using are currently above the 2008 level. And of course these are challenges that we need to overcome. We learned a lot in 2008 of how to overcome it; we need to make certain that we push price increases through the market as quickly as possible and further drive efficiency gains within the organization.</p>
          <p>But our assumption going into 2011 is that input costs will be greater in the first half than in the second half. So the reverse trend from last year, where we saw first half being fairly modest and input cost; second half very strong. We continue to see an increase from second half '10 into first half of '11. That means that we'll have a more bumpy ride, bumpy ride meaning that we'll have more chances in the first half when it comes to input costs than in the second half.</p>
          <p>Also, I wanted to just mentioned, where are we in the Middle East, because it's on the news all the time. Middle East is one of our strategic growth regions. We did, and you can see that in our annual report, approximately &#x20AC;900 million of revenue in the region in 2010. We have 21 manufacturing sites. We have approximately 55,000 employees. We are not represented in Libya. We have sales in Egypt and Tunisia at a run rate of approximately &#x20AC;21 million per month. And we've had losses or &#x2013; we've lost revenue in to the tune of less than &#x20AC;10 million in the last two months. We are fully up and running again now. We have 10 days of standstill in our manufacturing in those two countries; we're up and fully running.</p>
          <p>The region is dilutive in terms of margin. You can see that also in our annual report. Your guess, about what's going to happen in the region is as good as my guess. We'll continue to monitor it, take the appropriate actions that we need to take, but I just wanted to put this slide up. We don't believe from a business standpoint that this will have significant impact on us moving forward. Which impact it will have on raw materials is depending on how long the unrest in the region will last, it's a different matter. And that's where your guess is as good as mine. And I'm not going to try to guess on that today; neither is any of my colleagues. But at this stage the impact on the unrest in the region so far has been minimal for Henkel.</p>
          <p>What's the outlook? We expect Laundry &amp; Home Care and Cosmetics/Toiletries markets to be flexible to a slight decline. We expect that the Adhesive market will grow between 3% and 5% and we're setting a growth target for the company within the corridor of 3% to 5%; so meaning that we will grow or aim to grow stronger than the respective markets that we conduct business in, i.e. grow market share.</p>
          <p>We are striving towards adjusted EBIT margin of approximately 13%, another step in the right direction for our 2012 targets, and adjusted EPS growth of plus 10%. So while we believe that '11 will be challenging due to two main factors, great volatility in raw materials and continued great competitive pressure in fast-moving consumer goods, we do believe that '11 will be another step forward towards hitting our targets in '12 with another increase in our EBIT margin.</p>
          <p>We also believe we're well prepared. We have strong brands which we've articulated; we have good innovation into the marketplace that will allow us to drive higher profitability. We'll continue to strive to expand our position in the emerging markets, that in many market is accretive to business and not dilutive to business. We are in the process of implementing price increases across the board, not only in industrial business, but also fast-moving consumer goods. That is going to be crucial for the progress that we'll make in 2011.</p>
          <p>We'll continue to have a very hot eye on cost, and as Lothar spoke about, we'll continue to adapt to the market. I think there is one very important message in this slide, on the slide that Lothar showed you, and that was the acceleration of transformation within the company i.e. the restructuring line in '09 and '10 grew over '09, so we actually did not decrease <mark type="inaudible" />, global excellence or National Starch, we actually increased the acceleration of a transformational company in '10, irrespective of the previous programs.</p>
          <p>You will continue to see a very strong focus on transferring &#x2013; transforming the company to adapt to the market structures that we compete within. So we believe we're well prepared and 2011 will be a very important step towards the end game in 2012.</p>
          <p>With this, I'd like to thank you for your attention so far and handover to Oliver who will take us through with your help, the Q&amp;A session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me quickly add some guidance on items that you usually get from us, guidance on financial results. It's -160, restructuring charges minimum 120; tax rate around 26; minorities around &#x20AC;30 million; CapEx around &#x20AC;400 million; net working capital high single-digits; direct materials again high single-digits; and EBIT corporate around -90 to -100.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, Kasper and Lothar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are now coming to the Q&amp;A. Before we start, please may I ask you to state your name and company and limit the questions to two at a time. Who wants to be first? Eifert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hello; it's Matthias Eifert from MainFirst. Two questions, okay. The first question in Adhesives I would be interested to get a bit more details about the utilization rate and share of sales from emerging markets and maybe a few words on pricing trends. If we can get an increase over the next few quarters, second on the Right Guard brand, it's interesting to see that you launch it now in Europe. How far are we here in terms of the rollout? Was it just a first few tests or, and can we expect a bigger gradual increase over the next few quarters? And how is the brand actually perceived in Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me quickly get into Adhesives, utilization rate in Q4 has been about 50, 51, which is an improvement over the same period of prior year. Pricing, we have implemented pricing already in Q4. We'll continue to do so in the next two quarters because the impact of input price rises usually arise in our numbers only with a delay of around six months, maybe a little bit more or less. And that is the result of obviously the value chain, obviously requires a period of time within which rising oil prices have an impact on raw materials and eventually it's also in a situation where input prices rise. There's an impact from the inventory revaluation. So therefore there's a period of time between six or seven months until we have obviously the biggest impact in our P&amp;L. So therefore, we continue to increase prices in order to fight price increases on the input side that are currently happening.</p>
          <p>What we see in the next two quarters is obviously from the period of time six months ago, and obviously we've been increasing prices already. In terms of utilization rate &#x2013; share of emerging markets, we've communicated share of emerging markets 45% in Adhesives. That's the highest rate that we have in the group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me comment on your Right Guard question. First of all, good news also from the U.S, as Kasper commented shortly. A strong comeback during the year and we closed the year in the U.S. with the highest shares with Right Guard. We reached into required dividend, so quite happy on that one. We also required dividend because we believed the segment and so the reality of men's cosmetic is quite booming. And we're quite very happy with the launch. In fact, when we launched in Germany we were not alone to launch a men's brand. And out of the numerous launches, we, by far, are outperforming which means we are the best launch within all the universe of competition launching in this men's segment. We were quite happy and, of course, we're working to further expand. I think you will understand that I will not disclose our plan on further activities on this one. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next one, Arne Rautenberg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Arne Rautenberg from DZ Bank. You mentioned the extra compensation. You booked already two-thirds. At which stage we should expect that you book the others, the last &#x20AC;25 million? And, for example, in 2012 if you reach 13.5% EBIT margin do you use it or do you give it out pro rata or is it in extraordinary gain of &#x20AC;75 million? And maybe on the raw material price increases, could you give us some more feeling how high do you expect the increases from several suppliers that's high-single digit increase to, say, this is for  you as well and that direction was lower?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to the compact we have booked approximately two-thirds and have one-third to go. So, of course, it depends on the progress. So you'll see a big part being booked next year. If we hit 13.5% we'll answer that question at that stage. I think that all of us hope that we'll use the money, meaning we'll hit the target.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of raw material prices, I think it is pretty difficult at this point in time to have a good view. Compare it to 2008 where we had a pretty fast and strong increase in the oil price rising to &#x20AC;145 or &#x20AC;148 in the middle of the year and then dropping like a stone. During that period of time, every month we had new estimates of the impact on the raw material prices, which then in the second half turned out to be totally wrong. So in a very volatile situation, we're getting new estimates every month and they may be right or wrong. They're not worth a lot. That's a difficulty.</p>
          <p>So, for the time being, our expectation for the full year remains at high-single-digits for the total company. And if that needs to change because the oil price exceeds any expectations and remains there for a longer period of time, we obviously are going to communicate again. Right now I don't believe that the oil price will remain at the level it has reached today, actually, for a long period of time. But I'm no better in guessing than everybody else. So, therefore, for the full year I think we're confident it's going to go back to more normal levels. Short-term there's a high volatility in the market. There's a lot of speculation out there. And, therefore, it's very difficult for us to be smarter than the market. So long story short, I think our estimates stay, will be the best estimates that we have and we'll have to adapt if the situation worsens.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Harold?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon. Harold Thompson, Deutsche Bank. Two questions. If I might take the household division, I mean one of the key reasons the growth is more subdued is because the industry is extremely promotional and it's kind of slightly outside of your control. So how can you move the debate on? So let's assume a key player is not willing to move away. How do you just move on from that and try and grow and think different to get away from the vicious circle? And the second one, in the Cosmetics division you make it look too easy in many ways. But you still have some big gaps in your portfolio, especially on a geographical basis. What do you think your division can do looking forward to filling those gaps? Is it going to be organic, M&amp;A, a bit of both? And how quickly can you deliver that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So let me start with Laundry &amp; Home Care. As you know, Harold, our strategy over the last couple of years has always been to focus on profitable growth. And, once again, we are very proud that 2010 proved to be another year where we were able to gain shares and EBIT margin. As far as the outlook is concerned it will be tough, but I do have the strong belief that given the current focus of raw material I do hope that our competitors, and they have more or less the same environment, will come up with the same conclusions. And count the measures against raw material there are only two options, costs down and prices up. So I do believe, once again, the entire industry will undergo strong cost measures. We are the frontrunners, I do believe. And secondly, I also do believe there is no way out of price increase. And we have already started our implementation in the first two months of this year, not all over the world, but especially in countries and regions where we have the lead, where we are really strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Harold, let me answer your question on the Cosmetics. First of all, your remark it looks too easy, be sure that &#x2013; although, of course, we're quite proud of the results &#x2013; it's hard work. We have a lot of passionate people. But anyway, your remark is also based on our scale. I mean of course if we compare ourselves to some of our competitors we are subscale. On the other hand, we've been proving that within this scale now we have 20 quarters in which we develop growth both top and bottom line.</p>
          <p>Emerging markets, of course, is one of our focus points. And as Kasper pointed out, another year of double-digit which means &#x2013; and it's even spectacular double-digits &#x2013; we more than doubled our absolute turnover in four years in emerging markets. And perhaps a little bit to your surprise, if you look at the components of our emerging markets we are, of course, extremely strong &#x2013; not of course, we are extremely strong in Eastern Europe. But we've been winning shares quite significantly. And now we're a real strong leader if you take the markets in which we are in Eastern Europe.</p>
          <p>And then the other three regions be it Middle East/Africa, be it Asia-Pacific, Latin America, if you take the emerging market part of it, especially Asia-Pacific, the three are more or less the same size for us. What you also do see is that, if you look at market share, is last year I counted 33 countries in which we have an all-time high market share, total business for us, 33. Out of the 33, 20 countries were emerging markets, where we had the best shares ever in the business in which we are. And this, of course, makes us also for us, as part of our strategy, say, we are doing what is possible within our scope to develop our basic organically in emerging markets.</p>
          <p>The other part of your question, as you know, we will not answer and we cannot answer. But we have a clear focus that we want to expand organically in emerging markets. And we also are convinced that the innovation power, which we meanwhile I think demonstrated, also proves to work in emerging markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What's crucial with both areas is that we need to have a fine tuned engine. And we have more opportunity in that area. Because the better we can run this company, the more aggressive we can price in the marketplace and drive higher our margins first and the more expansion we can drive in, whether that's organic- or acquisition-wise. That's why it's so important that we continue to focus on the 3% to 5% top line, get the margin up, get the cash, networking capital down, it gives us more options. And we don't believe, any of us, that we're at the end of that line yet. That doesn't mean everything's sequential. What it does mean is that we have more room for improvement. You saw that in the line that Lothar spoke about, the restructuring line, which we accelerated last year. We will continue with that acceleration this year. So there's still more to be gotten in the engine room that will allow us to act better in the marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark Christensen, Morgan Stanley. Just on that point, about focusing more on the Home Care. We read that you're having local review in your position in India. We know you're perhaps not large in China and Latin America as well. And that's three of the four BRIC markets, where perhaps the Home Care is not as big as what you might be as some of your competitors. Does that reflect a strategy to focus more on where you're strong in Home Care? And perhaps that emerging expansion is more Cosmetics and Adhesives? Or is that not the case, I guess?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we have said on a number of occasions, and I'll repeat that, Mark, is that on Adhesives we need to be global because our customers are global. What we virtually &#x2013; is extremely important in our Cosmetics and Toiletries and also Detergents business, we need to be strong where we are. And you can say, relatively speaking, it doesn't matter how attractive a market is if you can't win that market. So for us, with the size that we have, we need to pick our battles and that's what we're doing. And then be certain that we have enough in the emerging markets that we can grow the top line. But at the same time, we need also to make certain that at the end of the day, we need to be able to see a profit. Doesn't have to be tomorrow, but we have to be able see it at the end of the day.</p>
          <p>And we're the size &#x2013; we're not a P&amp;G. We're not a Unilever. But we need to pick our battles and be strong and defend where we're strong and through that position grow our profitability. That's what you've seen in Eastern Europe from our businesses. That's what you're seeing in Middle East. So pick it one by one instead of trying to believe that we need to be in every BRIC market in the world, all four. If we only can be strong in two then we should only be in two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Harold and then Marco.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Just two further questions. This is more on the Adhesives division. Can &#x2013; you said you were trying to leverage your National Starch acquisition to get some revenue synergies. Can you give us some examples of what has been achieved and how much that can progress going forward? And the second one is, sorry to come back on the raw material example, but could you just help us understand how contracts in Adhesives are written? And I'm sure they're very different across different products. But how do they behave? And how do they differ today versus, let's say, in 2007 and 2008? So how has the organization learned from past experience and has changed the way to operate i.e. in the current environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I guess you were suggesting already the answer. In terms of contract let me start with that. In the past, annual contracts were quite common in a more volatile environment, more quarterly contracts are the standard. And that goes back to our suppliers and then, obviously, translate also to our customers. In terms of National Starch, I guess we promised &#x20AC;250 million in synergies. We are slightly above on a run rate. And we always said that two-third is defensive and one-third is offensive. And we are actually happy to report that this was accomplished. One example, I &#x2013; which is my favorite, I like to use this because it explains very nicely the synergy, is Japan. So National Starch had a very strong organization in Japan. But they had not the technology, for instance, in flexible packaging. Henkel was and is the market leader for flexible packaging but had no organization in Japan. So bringing those two things together, actually, turned out to be a very nice success story. In our business it does not happen next month, but over that period of time we were able to gain market shares.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Marco, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Marco Gulpers, ING. Two questions, if I may. The first is on the first half 2011 comparables. You highlighted a little bit on the margin progress. What about the sales growth? Do you see any, let's say, tough comparables therefore also phasing first half, second half? And the second question would be much more on emerging markets. Some of your peers, and also World Bank data, suggests there is a little bit of a slowdown in emerging markets. Are you seeing that as well in either Industrial side or on the more consumer side? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the overall guidance, top line and margin we guide for the year. We don't guide for the quarter. But what I was alluding to is I believe that the input cost is going to be a bigger challenge in the first half than the second half. So on the top line, we don't guide and neither do we do on the bottom line. You are seeing a world &#x2013; forecast for China. I think that they're forecasting the Chinese economy going down by one point from 10.5 to 9.5. I don't think there is going to be big change. We actually did see some areas pick up in our emerging markets at the end of the last year. The question is going to be what's going to happen with Middle East? You know that as well as I.</p>
          <p>Eastern Europe seems to have stabilized and is starting to, at least in our businesses, fast moving consumer goods, starting to go back to growth. There is a slight slowdown in Ukraine. Russia is stable. So our emerging markets are, at this stage, not showing signs of slowdown on the macro level. There might be one or the other country, but on a macro level there's not the big slow down. So that is not our assumption. Our assumption is that the main growth driver within the Henkel group for 2011 will continue to be the emerging markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One more. Marco?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Maybe a small follow-up question. Is on your assumption, sorry to come back the input cost guidance, of the high-single-digit, is that based on the Slide 64 that you're basically highlighting, the $105 on the oil, the propylene of &#x20AC;1.515? Is that the base of your guidance for the high-single-digit pressure of cost control? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have more than the four elements mentioned on that slide. We have a very systematic model that we look upon a basket that is been updated regularly. We speak with expert that make their forecast and that's how we do our guidance. The only thing I wanted to show with that slide was that there was &#x2013; or is/was a notion in the marketplace that we're still below 2008. In many areas we're actually above 2008. That was the only thing I wanted to show with that slide. So we have a standard structured way of how we look upon pricing. The pricing model, or pricing forecast model, for input cost has not changed irrespective of the volatility in the marketplace. We use the same model all the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Herr Frey?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Philipp Frey of MM Warburg. Given your success, basically, in the last years, I guess, it's pretty fast &#x2013; or I mean in 2012 that you're again running into the problem of having significant funds available for acquisitions. And, well, if you just could update a bit on your views, on your preferences, which divisions do you think are most attractive for potential takeovers? And &#x2013; yes, just the overall picture. And, secondly, on restructuring if you could shed some light on the use of the restructuring charges for 2011, how many factories are going to be closed? What's the level of expenses for Shared Services and these things? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the funds for acquisitions in '11 or '12, depending on what you look at. I think we're basically going back to what we've communicated earlier, and that is we'll support or augment organic sales growth in all our divisions by selective acquisitions. And I always remind us and everybody else that acquisitions is not something which you can always plan because you need targets and they need to be &#x2013; there needs to be a willing seller, otherwise there's no acquisition possible.</p>
          <p>And you know obviously that in the HPC sector, that's a more difficult proposition than it is in Adhesives, because the markets are much more fragmented in Adhesives and therefore, the situation is different to start with. And to come up with a prediction as to what's going to happen this year or next year is impossible.</p>
          <p>What I've tried to point out in terms of acquisition targets or areas is obviously in Adhesives, it is more interesting to fill specific gaps in terms of technologies, because that's a broad portfolio of applications and customer groups where there is almost unlimited opportunities into the future, if we wanted to build through external growth. Now it's not always that the targets that we like become available, again, but the diversity of targets, potential target is much larger there.</p>
          <p>In terms of HPC, I mentioned earlier that's more difficult, that's a much more concentrated environment and the prices tend to be high to unreasonable high. So therefore, that's a more difficult area to touch. Again, we do not make any pre-selection. We do not exclude any acquisition target in any particular area if it meets our strategic requirements. And strategic requirements are obviously that it fits our business, that it fills the gap, either geographically or in terms of portfolio.</p>
          <p>So therefore, it's true that our financial flexibility will increase quite considerably over the next two years and that therefore the ability to augment our organic sales growth through acquisitions will resume and we'll obviously communicate as needed to the extent that we make decisions. Restructuring charge, basically, looking at all areas, in particular and I think I mentioned that in shared services, in the SG&amp;A sector.</p>
          <p>The SG&amp;A sector is one area where we think we can address pretty significant savings opportunities and I always give the example of what we have done in finance, that is to say, we have standardized our processes in finance in order to be able to separate out pieces of processes that we can then transfer in to a shared service center. It's pretty complicated work and therefore, pretty difficult, pretty exhaustive, I should say, in terms of getting the resources in order to focus on that particular work. But it's an area where we believe there is a lot of opportunities for the group.</p>
          <p>We have realized basically a lot of opportunity in finance already. We reduced our cost of finance in relation to sales by almost half, that is &#x2013; was approaching 2%, it's now approaching 1% and that's obviously one piece of SG&amp;A. And I think there are lots more opportunities out in the field of SG&amp;A where particular processes can be separated, can be standardized and then transferred on to shared service.</p>
          <p>That's an area where in terms of the sales and administrative sector, we haven't really started seriously and that's therefore the area that we are going to look at and not only look at, but also work at in the course of this year or next year. We are pretty through &#x2013;  we are very much through in finance and purchasing and HR, but there is a lot more opportunities and we've kind of benchmarks ourselves in terms of SG&amp;A costs to our peers. Obviously, you know we're basically industrial and in HPC and I think from a top down benchmarking, there is pretty significant opportunity there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Harold?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, just because you kind of inferred it in your slide, you said that the input cost situation will be worse in H1 and hopefully better in H2. Does that therefore mean that your margin performance this year will also be skewed that way, H2-weighted? And the second question is on the net working capital, again, linked to input costs. Although through the course of the year, I think you've got for high single digit for net working capital, should we expect a bit of outflow in the first half as the raw materials effect return and then ease off again in H2, so just to help us, I guess?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you look upon the seasonality of the company, normally, first quarter is good, second, better, third, best and fourth, worst. I pretty much expect a similar development in this area. My point is more that I think it is going to be a more rocky ride because of the very high volatility. But if you looked upon the change in raw materials from mid-November until now, you've had a much higher volatility in that area than you normally have. That's why we're saying that.</p>
          <p>So we're very committed and believe that we'll hit the 13 points that we're are guiding on. I am just saying I believe where the current lag of transparency, you will have a more or less transparent ride this year than previous years. We still believe overall that the top line will be very similar to what I said, one, two, three and four, so good, better, best, worst, that's what we traditionally have had. And there is a fairly high correlation between top line and the bottom line within our company. On the net working capital you want to add to that, Lothar?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We usually have pattern according to which Q1 and Q2 net working capital tends to be higher and Q3, Q4, it's going down. That will be the same this year, there's no question about it. We have improved and that's I guess, really, the story that we're trying to get across. We have improved every year, even though the pattern has been the same. So again, we'll not stay at seven for the first two quarters, but we'll end up at seven or something like that towards the end of the year, it will go up and then go down.</p>
          <p>We've achieved a very significantly better level in terms of being able to manage our net working capital than ever before. We've far exceeded our own expectations and targets in the past, you may remember that's a long time ago that we had a target of 12%, well, right now, it's seven, and that's not just a coincidence. That's the results of the efforts of a big team and therefore, it's there to stay, although there is going to be a pattern, as you suggested.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Who wants the next question? Alex?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Just on pricing, if you could elaborate a little bit about how much pricing you've already taken in the first two months of the year. If you were to sort of stop where you are now, what should we expect to be the year-on-year effect from what you've done at the end of last year and the start of this year? And also on that sort of 3% to 5% organic top line you are talking about for 2011, what proportion of that do you expect to come from price and what from volume? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the latter, you will see a more, we expect to see a more balanced picture, but of course more back ended. We have started to take pricing of Adhesives in the first quarter, you saw the first pricing &#x2013; first impulsive pricing in the third, coming into the fourth. We are right now taking pricing for our fast-moving consumer goods and we expect that will take effect in the second and third quarter.</p>
          <p>There is a higher delay in fast-moving consumer goods than in industrial. That's not new, that's always been the case. So that's where it is today, so a more balanced picture. Last year, we had for the year, negative pricing and positive volume for all business groups. If you go to the second half, you had positive pricing, positive volume for Adhesive, negative-negative for our consumer businesses.</p>
          <p>Just one word of advice on the model, so to speak, the way we actually run the model, because that's where there is some misleading indicators in the model. When we introduce new products, they fall into volume only and not pricing. So that means if you take and introduce a new product, irrespective of division, by default, it falls into volume even though it would have a positive price.</p>
          <p>So the more we accelerate our innovation rate and replacement rate, that actually is accounted for only on the volume side. So when we report, it is a indication, but it's actually not inaccuracy. And if you take introduction that we've had in the last two years, which has been Sayyas. Sayyas, which has been a very, very significant revenue driver within our Cosmetics business, has been solely recorded in the volume side.</p>
          <p>That's how the model works, you can then say the model is not 100% accurate. There is no 100% accurate model. So we are in the process of taking pricing across the board in our fast-moving consumer goods. We are accelerating it in Adhesives. In Adhesives if you look back in the 2008 and 2009 timeframe, we took pricing 10 to 11 times within a year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Who wants to get the last question? Marco?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Why not? On Hair Care and there are a couple of your competitors, especially in Europe, that are relaxing their stance towards Hair Care a little bit, a German one. But others are actually also stepping up to the plate a bit further, like your Cincinnati peer. What are you seeing now in the market in Hair Care in Europe balancing this out, so-to-speak? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the Hair Care market has been quite a strong battlefield since the last years and on top, what has not being helping is that the market itself in Europe and if you take even total Europe, it's not growing. If you take Western Europe, the Hair Care market itself in retail has been significantly down.</p>
          <p>What we have been doing and this is that we, I think, step by step have been taking the lead in innovation and if I look at my market share development, the most impressive part of it is the Hair business. If I see now that five years in a row, we are really significantly winning share. We meanwhile have positions also category-wise where we improved category positions, beat in hair colorations, beat in hair styling or beat in Hair Care. Of course, what we do see is that competition is getting more and more fierce and top of quite aggressive pricing promotions, we also see frontal attacks to what we innovate.</p>
          <p>I think the only and we are convinced the only right answer for this is even try to be even better and what we have, for example, if I now see the our Q1, Q2 innovation pipeline, which has been communicated also to the trade, is that I have a good feeling that again, we have the lead in a lot of things and my organization, myself, we feel extremely challenged and we take the challenge to try to every year, be best in class concerning innovation, because in this business, this is only answer to be winning shares, on top of all the other things. But we are not be sustainable winning shares but just by doing promotion. That's why, of course, this is part of how to do business, but the real difference is made by the innovation part. And that's why we try really to be and to stay best in class.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for your question. I would now like to hand over to Kasper for the closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Oliver, and thank you, everybody, for coming here today and also listening in over the web. We are looking back satisfied with the 2010 results and we are not satisfied with where we are. We believe that we have had a good year behind us, but at the same time, we are very committed to continue to improve the performance of our company. So we are satisfied with the results. We are not satisfied with where we are. We are very committed to move the company forward and align the performance with the vision we have as a company, a global leader in branded technologies.</p>
          <p>We believe there are plenty of opportunities within our company to improve the performance organically or inorganically. What we need to do is, we need to make certain that we focus on what's in our hand and that means continue to adapt our structures to the market we operate within, switch into categories that drives higher levels of growth and higher level of markets and the same goes for countries.</p>
          <p>We need to make certain that we streamlined our structure further than they are streamlined today. Lothar spoke a bit about it. We have made substantial progress in Shared Services. We believe by further increasing the standardization within our company, we can streamline our SG&amp;A structure and thereby, allow more funds to flow either into R&amp;D, line 17, what we call, which is promotional activities and advertising and of course, the bottom line.</p>
          <p>So we believe there are plenty of opportunities also moving forward and we are confident that 2011 will be a good year. I do want to say what I said also a couple of times, we believe it will be a year with higher volatility in the input costs in 2010, so I want to caution you when you take a quarter at a time, now I simplify it.</p>
          <p>In 2010 third quarter, we hit 32% margin. We didn't jump up and say, we are where we need to be. In 2010 fourth quarter, we hit a lower margin that we expected. We don't believe that's cause for concern either, but what I'm saying that you might have a year in 2011 where quarter by quarter pending on input cost, because they are so in-transparent, it will be more difficult to judge.</p>
          <p>But I'm not changing and neither is the management the guidance we are giving for the year which is 3% to 5% top line, 13% margin. That is what we're aiming at, and we are confident that we'll get there. And we're are also very confident as a management team that we'll take the company to the end of the task for 2012, which is why we have booked a part of the bonus in 2010. That is not be able to release it in 2012. That is to be able to pay it in 2012 to the team that made the number.</p>
          <p>With this, thank you very much. I look forward to see all of you May 4th to discuss the first quarter numbers with you on the phone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>