<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1476524" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-11-16</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7863</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Renata Casaro</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman-Executive Board &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Kasper B. Rorsted</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive VP-Purchasing">Carsten Knobel</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Harold P. Thompson</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Warburg Research GmbH">J&#xF6;rg P. Frey</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Iain E. Simpson</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Canaccord Genuity Securities Ltd.">Alicia A. Forry</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="McGraw-Hill Financial Research Europe Ltd.">Carl Short</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="MainFirst Bank AG (UK)">Matthias Eifert</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Asset Management (UK) Ltd.">Robin Asquith</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to Henkel's Investor and Analyst Conference in London St. Pancras. Kasper Rorsted and Carsten Knobel will give you an overview on the Q3 results, and then we take you through the Henkel year strategy.</p>
          <p>Before I hand over to Kasper Rorsted, I would like to make some general remarks. Please note that the conference is live broadcast via Internet. Before, I will kindly ask you to switch off your phones or put them on mute.</p>
          <p>And last but not least, I would like to draw your attention to some emergency instructions. Please be aware that this room has five emergency exits marking green on this plan.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention, and I now will hand over to Kasper Rorsted.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Renata. Good morning and welcome, everybody, here to London again to our third quarter press conference but, of course, also speaking about what probably will interest you most, what is the outlook for Henkel for the first &#x2013; no, for the next four years. But first, we'll go very briefly to the third quarter.</p>
          <p>The disclaimer I will not go through but I will take it as read for the entire conference, so I'd put it here. I strongly take it as read, and I will &#x2013; now, we'll take it into the records.</p>
          <p>So, I will briefly be speaking about the key developments. Carsten will take us through the third quarter in more detail. And then, we'll do a summary and outlook and a Q&amp;A. And following the Q&amp;A, we'll switch into the outlook for the next four years.</p>
          <p>So overall, the quarter came in slightly below our expectations on the top line. We saw continued solid growth on our fast-moving consumer goods side. On the Adhesive side, it was slightly below but I want to be very clear in the following statement.</p>
          <p>As I've said continuously over the last three years, we're actively managing our portfolio. And in order not to sacrifice a quality business and a high-margin business, we will refrain from the temptation of taking low margin business in to boost the top line. You can see that showing on the margin. So, it was a very deliberate part, we're managing our portfolio, Adhesives, very actively towards higher-margin businesses driven by our technology differentiation.</p>
          <p>We saw further increase in our gross margin. Our adjusted EBIT margin is at all-time high. We saw a strong Asia Pacific and we saw China in double-digit growth, with our free cash flow significantly improved. On the weakness side, I spoke the somewhat-disappointing top line. We continue to see weakness in Southern Europe, especially impacting our Adhesive business. That is an ongoing and a not surprising trend in the market.</p>
          <p>And we saw sales growth in Latin America further slowing, with a strong Mexico and a weaker Brazil.</p>
          <p>How did it translate in to numbers? We came in at &#x20AC;4.294 billion, up organically 2.5%, reported at 6.6%. The adjusted EBIT (sic) [gross] (02:57) margin went up at 150 basis points, from 45.7% to 47.2%. The adjusted EBIT, up 16.7% year-over-year, at &#x20AC;631 million. And our adjusted EBIT margin at 14.7%, an all-time high, up 130 basis points year-over-year.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share, up at 16.5% to $0.99 per share. Net working capital, great improvement, you can remember last year in this quarter I articulated my dissatisfaction with the 8% and you promptly also wrote in your papers. We're now down 140 basis points at 6.6%; and a significant increase in our free cash flow.</p>
          <p>So, we believe we showed very high earnings cost despite the reduced growth dynamics.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll ask Carsten to take you further through the details of our third quarter. Carsten?</p>
          <p>[0CMZJ5-E Carsten Knobel]</p>
          <p>Thank you very much, Kasper. Good morning also from my side. I will guide you now through the financials of Q3.</p>
          <p>First of all, looking at Henkel, the reported sales growth came in with 6.6%. We had FX adjustments by 4.4% related to all of our businesses, and that leads us to the final thing, to an organic net sales growth for Henkel of 2.5% for Q3. This growth is composed of a price component of 2.6% and the flat volume of minus 0.1%. To the organic growth, all businesses supported this development.</p>
          <p>And let me now go through the individual divisions and starting, with Laundry &amp; Home Care. Laundry &amp; Home Care came in with a solid organic net sales growth of 4.6%, and this is composed of a price increase of 3.4% and a volume increase of 1.2%. All the regions were contributing to this strong performance, especially the emerging markets showed a high-single digit growth development. And in particular, Latin America and also Eastern Europe came in very strong. To comment on some important markets, Russia and Turkey even came in with a double-digit development.</p>
          <p>Regarding our segments, laundry saw the strong growth whilst home care showed a solid performance in Q3.</p>
          <p>Let me move now to the Beauty Care business. The Beauty Care business increased the organic net sales growth by 3.3%. And combined with that was a very balanced growth of price and volume, price being up 1.5% and volume 1.8%.</p>
          <p>Our emerging markets showed another impressive development, and this was developed especially by Middle East, Africa and Asia Pacific. In our mature markets, North America showed a strong development whereas, Western Europe showed a solid growth but also impacted by the weaknesses of the Southern European markets.</p>
          <p>Regarding the segments, retail, with the solid growth, whereas the hair salon business was slightly below the previous year quarter.</p>
          <p>Coming now to our Adhesive Technologies business, we saw a positive growth of 1.0%, but definitely below the quarters of Q1 and Q2, what we experienced. And the composition was a pricing piece of 2.7% and a volume effect of minus 1.7%. But as I have already mentioned it in quarter two, we have continuously undergone the portfolio optimization which leads to selective business exits in high-volume, low-margin businesses and the effect, which are already announced in Q2, is around 100 basis points which is 100% dedicated to the volume development.</p>
          <p>Having a look on the regions, the regional growth was supported by a solid development especially of our emerging markets. Here, Eastern Europe came in very strong. Concerning our mature markets, also here North America showed again a solid performance whereas our Western European business was impacted by the slowdown of the Southern European market, and by that, have been slightly negative.</p>
          <p>Reporting on the segments, electronics, transport/metal as well as general industry came in with a solid growth, whereas our consumer business in consumer adhesives was slightly below the quarter.</p>
          <p>Let me now go to our regional performance of Henkel in total when it comes to top line. We saw an all-time high in the development of our emerging markets, and by that reaching 44% of our sales. Major positive development in that respect have been our Middle East/Africa business as well as Eastern Europe.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, Asia saw a very strong development. And in particular, our products in China were very positively asked, and by that we showed a double-digit growth also in China.</p>
          <p>However, in Latin America, we have seen a mixed development, Kasper already alluded to that. We have a double digit positive development of sales in Mexico whereas our Brazilian business as already mentioned in Q2 based on two factors a slowdown in the markets, but also internal development showed a weak development.</p>
          <p>In our mature markets, Western Europe in total slightly below the previous year figures impacted by the Southern European development whereas North America showed a solid development for Henkel.</p>
          <p>Coming now to the adjusted EBIT by business sector and starting with Laundry &amp; Home Care. We have seen an increase of 50 basis points, now to a margin of 14.5%, and this is the same margin which you all have seen in Q1 and Q2 so a very continuous positive development. Beauty Care business, again, an increase in the adjusted EBIT margin by 40 basis points, now to a level of 14.7%. And our Adhesive Technologies business, a significant improvement of 160 basis points to a level of 16.0%, an all-time high in adjusted EBIT margin for this business sector.</p>
          <p>And taking into account the 1% top line growth and combining that with the bottom line development you see that we are able even if this top line growth is not strong being able to continuously improve our ongoing margin improvement. For Henkel, this means an increase of 130 basis points, now to a level of 14.7%. And this is now the second time in a row that we are above 14%.</p>
          <p>The adjusted EBIT in absolute terms, &#x20AC;631 million for the quarter three, being up by 16.7%. We had restructuring charges of &#x20AC;45 million in the quarter three.</p>
          <p>And due to the fact that we are continuously updating, adapting our structures through the market, I would like to give you an update on our guidance for the restructuring for the total year. We will have &#x20AC;125 million for the total year of 2012, compared to the guidance, as you know, of &#x20AC;100 million.</p>
          <p>Looking now onto our income statement adjusted here sales to gross profit, another increase of 150 basis points, now to a level of 47.2% for the company. And this significant increase in gross margin was achieved despite the fact that we had a negative impact of an increase of 150 basis points by cost of goods.</p>
          <p>The implementation of countermeasures and the disciplined execution of that brought us into this situation to over achieve in driving our margin also on that business.</p>
          <p>All in all, we see a deceleration concerning our input cost inflation, as already told to you in quarter two. And here the guidance, as stated in Q2, is an increase on a low-single digit for our material prices for the year 2012.</p>
          <p>And another look to the income statement here to marketing, selling and distribution expenses, they have been up by 20 basis points in the quarter three. And this is mainly due to the fact that we increased our marketing investments to continuously support our top brands and our innovations in order to secure our top line.</p>
          <p>Looking on the administrative expenses, we are down again by 10 basis points here due to the fact on our project to drive further move our shared service activities.</p>
          <p>Kasper already highlighted this networking capital development but I would like to emphasis again on that. Networking capital, with 6.6% of sales, came in with the lowest number ever for a Q3, and by that being 140 basis points below the previous year quarters of 8.0%.</p>
          <p>And all three business divisions are supporting this development: Laundry &amp; Home Care, by minus 2.5%; Beauty Care 3.0%; and also in Adhesives, we have seen a significant improvement of more than 180 basis points to 13.3%.</p>
          <p>Our ability to drive cash orientation helps us also in another activity in our net debt development. We reduced the net debt by &#x20AC;958 million to a level now of &#x20AC;612 million at the end of quarter three.</p>
          <p>And finally, our cash flow generation. We have seen an increase of more than 50% of our free cash flow, now to a level of &#x20AC;778 million in the quarter three. And this was mainly driven by our cash flow from operating activities.</p>
          <p>And by that, I would like to hand over again back to Kasper. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Carsten. Let me try to summarize the way we see the quarter. Despite what we call a challenging market environment, we had in all line items the best quarter in the history of our company; the highest top line, the highest EBIT, the highest EBIT margin, and also the lowest net working capital.</p>
          <p>So overall, we're very satisfied with the way the quarter evolved despite the challenging market environment.</p>
          <p>We are fully committed to hit our 14% adjusted EBIT margin for the year, and we're also fully convinced that we'll hit it. All our KPIs are on-track to reach our fiscal year guidance. We are seeing solid organic growth. And as I said before, we've restricted from the temptation of driving top line through for quality of business.</p>
          <p>Our adjusted EBIT margin is at an all-time high, the emerging markets are strong, and the mature markets &#x2013; and mature markets in this context is predominantly Europe &#x2013; are flat to declining, North America continues to grow.</p>
          <p>Our net working capital further reduced. And as Carsten said, we significantly increased or improved our free cash flow throughout the quarter.</p>
          <p>So overall, a good quarter for Henkel on our way to hit our full year FY 2012 guidance and targets.</p>
          <p>What do we guide for the year? We guide an organic sales growth of 3% to 5 %; an adjusted EBIT margin of 14%, and let me reiterate here our target has been for the past four years hit 14% for 2012 and it is to hit 14% for 2012, remained unchanged; adjusted EPS growth we upped it following the second quarter, will remain, so we assume that we'll have an adjusted EPS growth of 15% for the year.</p>
          <p>When I look upon the upcoming events, here is next year's calendar. You know the quarterly dates. We have our Investor Day in June, and that will this year be targeted at our Adhesive Technologies division, and that will take place in D&#xFC;sseldorf in 2013.</p>
          <p>For this, I'd like to thank you for listening in and then come to the Q&amp;A. And we'll do, just for guidance here, we'll do a 10-minute Q&amp;A because we want to make sure that we have enough time for the strategy. Shouldn't all your questions not be answered during the Q&amp;A, our team will be fully available following this session to ask any other questions you might have.</p>
          <p>Let's please move to the Q&amp;A. Who is the first?</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="audio gap" /> (16:57-19:04)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So again, I welcome you again. Its four years ago since we met last meet here in London. And the mood back then it was a bit different. It was following Lehmann the world was going down overall and the credibility with our capability to deliver was also reduced. I hope that we've improved our credibility within you &#x2013; within your this community over the last four years with respect to delivery.</p>
          <p>We are very excited about speaking about the new strategy for the next four years so let me just briefly reflect on some of the things we've changed in the company without going into a great level of depth because it is underlying for what we are going to do in the future.</p>
          <p>The way we'll do it is I speak briefly about what's happening from 2008 to 2012 then I'll take you in through the details of our strategy, costs we'll then take you through the numbers by taking the strategy and translate them into what we are measured against and held the accountable for then we will do a summary and then hopefully we'll have a bit more question on the strategy that we did on the quarter.</p>
          <p>Four years ago, we set <mark type="indiscernible" /> direction with three strategic priorities achieving our full business potential focusing on our customers and strengthen our global team and along with that, we really wanted to build what we described as a winning culture. We also set a number, what was by many people, including you, characterize as very ambitious targets. Organic sales growth throughout that period of time of 3% to 5%, reaching adjusted EBIT margin in the end of this year of 14% and an EPS growth CAGR over the period of time of 10%, so the three strategic priorities and three main KPIs.</p>
          <p>We believe we've come a long way and the reason has been among other things a very disciplined focus on our strategic priorities throughout the four years that were also characterized by a lot of volatility. And when I look back, I would say the most fundamental change in our company has probably been within the culture. I'm not by any means saying that we are where we want to be, but the change of the culture has been very fundamental and has been a key driver to delivering the numbers that we're having today.</p>
          <p>As I said before, I'm not by any means saying we are where we want to be, but we have changed it, we are spending a lot of time driving the focus into building a very highly competitive culture in our organization, that was part of our focus from 2008 to 2012 and will continue to be the focus moving forward.</p>
          <p>So despite the environment and looking back sometimes things were more rosy or less rosy, but it was a very volatile environment. We had the financial crisis where Lehman starting out about four years ago. We've had material prices going up and down and high volatility is not always to our advantage.</p>
          <p>We have had and continue to have political turmoil, not only within Europe, but right now what you're seeing the falling of the Arab Spring. And we've had the Europe crisis that seems to be ongoing and not letting go. So when we look upon the volatility and looked upon the assumptions we said in 2008 and we actually came out, it was two very different matters.</p>
          <p>We've also been very conscious during the four years not to look for excuses throughout our assumptions. At times, the assumptions have been very different to what actually came out. We've not used that an excuse. And it's our utmost intention also to stay predictable in the future. And when we said assumptions, it is assumptions. But however, we will try, despite differences, to the assumptions to continue to deliver what we are promising the investor community.</p>
          <p>So where are we? After the first three years we have had organic sales growth of 3.1%, in the first nine months of this year 3.7%. So it's fair to assume they'll be smack in the middle of a 3% to 5%. Our adjusted EBIT margin is at <mark type="ph" /> 1 to 9 (21:52) running at 14.3%. You saw 14.7% in the third quarter. I cannot believe that we'll not hit out targets. The world has to go under. So if we don't hit it, it's not going to be the only company that will miss it. We are very convinced and committed to hitting the 14% for this year. And let me reiterate, it is the 14% we are working for. That's what we are working on for four years. So your assumption for the fourth quarter is we're aiming for landing around the 14%.</p>
          <p>EPS growth in the first three years 12.8%, in the first nine months of this year, 19.4%, which is why we changed our guidance in the second quarter to be at <mark type="ph" /> 15 instead of 10 (22:32), so the three KPIs on track. Hopefully we've shown you that we are sales critical also. One of the tasks we also set ourselves for our position in emerging regions were to reach the position of 45% in total business in the emerging regions by the end of 2012. We are right now trailing at 43%. For the quarter isolated, it was 44%. I think we will slightly miss the 45. Unfortunately, I'm convinced we'll slightly miss the 45%. There are many good excuses don't count. We had 45%. We'll not hit 45%. Three main hits we did not make the fourth one.</p>
          <p>This is a slide that I do want to spend just a bit of time on because it is very fundamental where we are, taking the company, and where we're taking the company. We have built our infrastructure out in the emerging countries, meaning that today we have 45% of all our employees in the emerging countries. So we are moving our infrastructure to where the future growth is going to come from.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we have through very restricting cost measures strengthen our competitive position in the mature markets. A couple of years ago, we hardly had any people in shared services. Today, we see shared services as being a competitive advantage for Henkel, not only in terms of cost, but also in terms of speed. We optimized our manufacturing footprint. We've closed 60 plants net but the gross number is much bigger, i.e., we have taken closed plants in the Western part of the world and moved them into the emerging countries, and by a net reduce them by 60. That was over a period of time, closing two plants planned every two weeks.</p>
          <p>We have substantial strength in our top brands, and the second time, we retired approximately 600 brands over the last four years. We'll continue on this journey. We spend a lot of time on driving talent management organization in developing talents. If you look upon our management team today in the last 18 months, four of the six managers in our top management team are coming from within. I think it's creditability to how much time we're spending on talent management.</p>
          <p>In 2010, we launched our new vision and values. This is the last time I'll call them new, but they articulate to culture we're trying to drive into our company. And that is important for us to build a very competitive culture. We launched our new sustainability strategy a year ago because the target we have set ourselves for sustainability for 2012 we hit in 2010. That's why we launched a new strategy. That means today, I will not be speaking about our sustainability strategy. We did that early on this year.</p>
          <p>But today and that's why most of you here will be speaking about what are the targets and our strategy beyond 2012, but I wanted to show this chart because a lot of the activities with the company also into 2016. So let me now speak about where we're going to take the company over the next four years. In doing this work over the last 18 months, let me just briefly describe the process and give you an insight how we work this.</p>
          <p>We listen to a number of poor questions that has an impact in our business. First one which mega trends will save our markets in the years to come? To be very clear, how is the market going to evolve over time? And secondly, position our brands and portfolio against these mega trends. So how well is our portfolio positioned against these trends? With the end of the strategic opportunity, where are we on the curve? And thirdly, what actions are necessary to take &#x2013; to capitalize on these strengths and make them the strength and asset for us and not a liability for us? And with that in mind, we subsequently defined the three most relevant global mega trends for Henkel.</p>
          <p>And the first one is the continued consolidation of supply, manufacturers, buyers, and of course also, our competitors. And the indication is size matters, absolutely, size matters. The second mega trend is the shift of market growth to the emerging market. And the indication of that is that the increasing importance of the emerging markets will continue. So size of the emerging markets also matters.</p>
          <p>And the third is what is &#x2013; what we all have experienced over the last four years and also what is our expectation to the future and that is all about volatility and change in speed that we continue to expect gradually changing markets and faster transfer of information.</p>
          <p>We believe the consequence of that is that operational excellence in process and structures is fundamental to capitalize on volatility. Those that we can react fast in volatile market have upsides. Those that cannot have downsides. And then, we've taken the trend implication and translated them into what we call performance dimension. And that then defines well how we're looking upon the business.</p>
          <p>So the performance dimensions moving forward is all around total sales, emerging market sales and consistent EPS growth, so consistently improving our business over the period of time. We're also looking and looked upon which market are we active in. and we are of the conviction that we are active in markets of significant size, they're highly attractive in terms of profitability and growth. Also on the long term and we've shown that we believe that we had a strong potential to expand our current business in the current markets. The reason why we believe that it is that we've consistently been able to win over the last four years in terms of market share and profitability. And with this in mind, when we look upon our business in organic terms, we are very clear that we believe that we have by no means at the end of the road really believe there's substantial organic upside in our three businesses, in our Laundry &amp; Home Care business, in our Beauty Care business and in our Adhesive business.</p>
          <p>So strategically for us, we are convinced that there is much more to be gotten. I've also said that repeatedly during a number of calls that we don't believe by any means that we are at the end of the journey with our organic set up. When we then look upon our strategy we've taken and derived our strategy from the vision we defined two years ago. Our vision is we want to become a global leader in brands and technologies. And we're taking that vision and transfer it again to our strategy.</p>
          <p>But let me first translate the vision into what it actually means in very concrete terms. To be a global leader means having a leading position, having a global footprint, having leading processes, having strong and diverse teams, and of course, leading financial performance. You cannot do the three or four first things without having &#x2013; being articulate in the numbers. So global leader we have defined in those dimensions. And in brands and technologies, it means being number one towards for customers and consumers being an innovation leader having powerful brands and a balanced portfolio that is how we translate our vision into action. Let me now define, what our strategy is. Our strategy is that we will outperform our competition as a globalized company with simplified of operations and highly inspired team. That is the new strategy for Henkel.</p>
          <p>So what we're going to do now is, we'll take and translate the four strategic priorities: outperform, globalize, simplified and inspire, and give you generic direction where we're going to take the company, but also be very, very specific in items where we'd already taken the decisions.</p>
          <p>But before I do that, let me now translate the strategic intent into numbers. What does that mean? We want to be a &#x20AC;20 billion organization by year 2016. In the past four years, we added &#x20AC;2.5 billion to the top line. In the next four years we want to add &#x20AC;3.5 billion to the top line. The first one is, referring to our mega trends, we want to be a &#x20AC; 20 billion organization by year 2016. In the same way of thinking in our presence in the emerging markets, we want to drive our position and size to the emerging markets to a &#x20AC;10 billion size.</p>
          <p>In the last two years, we had a &#x20AC;2 billion on the top line to our position in the emerging markets. In the next three, four years, we want to add &#x20AC;3 billion, meaning over an eight-year period of time, we double our position in the emerging markets, becoming a 50-50 company when it comes to revenue. I already spoken to you about that we already today have 55% of our infrastructure based in the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>And the third one is, because it's not only about growth, it's also about driving profitability through the system. We want to deliver an EPS CAGR over that period of time of 10%. In the past years, we've been close to 15% and now let me make the translation from the 15% to the 10%. The delta between the 10% and the 15% is almost exclusively down through the major acquisition of National Starch with it. Since we cannot plan major acquisitions, we cannot build that into the planning. So what we're looking upon is we are looking upon a consistent profitability improvement over the next four years, very similar to the previous four years. Should we go out and do a major acquisition, and I'll call it a National Starch size, we will of course adjust our earnings target and extra targets as long as we go. But since this is not a plan-able item, we cannot build that into the plan. I'm just being very clear here as we're continuing the current run rate we have. The delta was very much down to National Starch. Should National Starch 2 occur, we will of course also go out and readjust that back in to our targets.</p>
          <p>So our targets in essence are 20-10-10 and these are targets that should be easy to remember. We know them already, &#x20AC;20 billion sales as a company, &#x20AC;10 billion in the emerging markets and an EPS CAGR over the next four years of 10%.</p>
          <p>Now let me go back and articulate how we're going to take this strategy into our four strategic priorities and execute in order to ensure that we'll hit those targets. And I'll start with our portfolio.</p>
          <p>We've taken our portfolio and divided into three categories: core, growth and value. With our core categories, we'll continue investments in our top positions. In our growth, we want to invest in order to grow category of new segments above market. And in the third category, value, we want to leverage the profit portfolio and bring that back into core or growth, and at the same time, separate ourselves from businesses to the tune of &#x20AC;0.5 billion over the next four years. So it should be clear in the 20-10-10 the &#x20AC;0.5 billion we pulled out of that. So our expectation that is and we will separate ourselves of a &#x20AC;0.5 billion businesses &#x2013; &#x20AC;0.5 billion business over the next four years. We'll continue our active portfolio management.</p>
          <p>So what it means is on the brand side, we'll have a focused and balanced brand portfolio. We'll continue a very, very strong growth of our top brands and I'll show that specifically. And I've told you before, we've taken 600 brands out in the last four years, we'll continue that journey and we'll take a three number or probably a 100 plus brands more out in the four years.</p>
          <p>On innovation we are very focused on having a consistent innovation process and bringing innovation close to the market. And on the customer side, we have built a customer relation management to top the tops and we're driving consumer proximity. Now let me be very specific what we're doing.</p>
          <p>We're taking our top 10 brands that we moved as a percent of revenue from 38% in 2008 to 46% in 2012 and we're consolidating that at around 60% in 2016, so substantial consolidation among top brands and that would allow us to over proportionately invest though in the brand building in these brands.</p>
          <p>We will further through portfolio alignment and manage towards umbrella brands, but substantial ongoing consolidation around our top brands. On innovation, we have dramatically improved the quality of our innovation in the past. We are completely convinced that a primary driver for revenue growth and market improvement is coming through successful innovation.</p>
          <p>So innovation is right at the core what we're doing and then on to further strengthen our innovation set-up, what we're planning to do is to open seven new R&amp;D centers all in the emerging markets. So in the near coming future, we'll have new centers in Toluca, Mexico; S&#xE3;o Paulo, Brazil; Moscow; Dubai; Johannesburg; Pune, India; and Seoul. And it shows the immense focus we have on customer proximity and innovation to ensure that we get the progress on the top line and also on the bottom line.</p>
          <p>When we look upon customer focus within our Laundry &amp; Home Care division, we have conducted a global, what we call, shopper marketing study that very clearly defined how shoppers are behaving. And we are bringing that knowledge into retail and we already done it now and that helps us drive over proportional growth by helping the retails arranging the shelf base better. So we not only from a product stand point are bringing innovation but also how you actually position brands and our portfolio in the shelves.</p>
          <p>On our Beauty Care, as an example, we have just opened global Beauty Care center in D&#xFC;sseldorf where we are showing current portfolio. We're showing what's coming. We're showing everything what you can do about digital. And we're able to take all the new innovation and get them virtually into shelves and showing our retailers how it looks. We already brought a number of global retailers to a new global setup in D&#xFC;sseldorf.</p>
          <p>And in Adhesive division, we'll continue to what we call our design partnership model. That means whether it's automotive, aerospace or electronics, we design unique solutions for our customers in one locations of the world and execute that in a different location. Let me give you an example of I experienced three weeks ago when I was out in California meeting with our electronics division. All of you are working with tabs whether it's iPads or Nexus. What you feel is when you put it on the lap is that's actually the heat is too big.</p>
          <p>We've now developed a shelter the basically you put inside and that it absorbs and also distribute the heat that was developed in California. Right now, we're working with all the manufacturers in Asia to get that deployed. That is what we mean about partnership design. We go in and design specific solutions in one location and deploy them globally. This solution I just mentioned is of course also IP protected.</p>
          <p>When it comes to globalize, let me speak about our regional strategy. We've defined our regions in two categories. We want to leverage our position in a mature categories. And in the emerging markets, we have two directions. Where we are present, we want to go deep and accelerate growth and we'll be looking ways to roll in for selective entries in what we call white <mark type="ph" /> service (38:28) markets, so more specific on the mature markets.</p>
          <p>We'll outperform our markets by driving high investments into the fewer number of brands on one side and drive down cost. So cost will continue to be right in the center of what we do in order to ensure that we can over push and drive the investments in, that when 2016 lead to through the result that we'll have more top positions with higher top line contribution that we can reallocate us and the company or to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the emerging markets, by 2016 of the top 20 markets where Henkel, 12 were coming from the emerging markets. All four BRIC countries are included in those. So by 2016, we'll have substantially improved our position in the emerging markets not only in terms of having single markets becoming bigger but overall getting a wider position and that of course will help us also when we deal with the volatile environment. So substantial improvements in our overall position in the emerging markets, 12 of our top 20 countries in the globe by 2016 will be coming from the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>In order to accompany our organic growth in our core categories and also in our regions we will of course also taking acquisitions into account. Carsten will be speaking about this later in detail. But let me be very clear on this. We have a very strong balance sheet today in contrast to 2008. Our plan is to actually deploy our balance sheet back into our business.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, we're not going to spend money because they're burning in the pocket. We will do it in a wise way, but our plan is to have active use of our balance sheet in terms of acquisition. And Carsten, as I said, will speak to you more in detail about the process we serve and how we'll go about this for this is part of our strategy.</p>
          <p>Now let me move to simplify. It's about cost, process and IT focus. When it comes to cost, we believe that we need to continue to drive down our admin cost in our company. We need to continue to optimize our location footprint and further reduce net working capital. On the processes it's all about sourcing and shared services. An enabler to do this effectively is to create the best of the IT plan platform possible and I'll speak about that because that is a very fundamental assumption should we able to do this.</p>
          <p>Our manufacturing footprint, I spoke to you before about the net 60 plants we reduced it in the last four years. We see another 20 coming in net in the next four years, whether its 2018 or 2025, we don't know. But this is the ballpark. We're very focused in ensuring that we have an absolute localization footprint as it relates to manufacturing. That will further also drive decrease in our manufacturing costs.</p>
          <p>When it comes to leading sourcing there are three elements we're focusing on. Its value creation. Meaning getting more innovation. And we're doing this very, very specifically. Early on this week, the top management of Henkel met with the top management of Novozymes which are the leading enzyme manufacturer. So we are very focused on our top core, top suppliers to ensure that we don't only get quality products, we get key innovation from our supplier into the pipe.</p>
          <p>Secondly with the increased globalization of our company, we are moving our global purchasing organization to be much more globally spread. So moving a lot of sourcing into the emerging regions. And thirdly, as good about quality and innovation and precision, but we want the right pricing. So what we're doing is we're putting a lot of emphasis on the e-auctioning and we believe we can move approximately a &#x20AC;1 billion euro spend into e-auctioning which will drive pricing down and at the same time we are reducing the number of excess suppliers we have with 40%.</p>
          <p>So further consolidating spend with few with the clear assumption to get better pricing. Shared services has been a dear child of mine at least as long as I've been here and we made a lot of focus. We see by 2016 that at least 3,000 people within our organization will be in shared services. That will make us a leader in this area. We see this as a competitive advantage for us and we extremely focus in moving as much as we can into shared services. It started with a back-end of transaction. We're now moving very much to the front-end to just spend some part of work. And how does that look in the operational part?</p>
          <p>That means that from the four centers we have today in Mexico, Manila and Bratislava at our Henkel centers, the outsource center we have today in Bangalore with Accenture. We're adding two new centers, one in the Arab speaking part of the world because Middle East is a very attractive and growing market for us and we need to make certain that we not only capture the Arab speaking capability ,but we continue to stand around process and systems in all regions.</p>
          <p>So we're opening one in the Arab speaking kind of the worlds and we're opening one in Greater China to serve the Greater China and potentially Northeast Asia. These are the decisions we've taken and we're executing those. That will allow us to expand up to 3,000 people. And when it comes to IT let me just spend a second of this because it is and it will be a strategic advantage for us.</p>
          <p>We're coming today from an IT platform where we have consolidated most of our systems. We're running our systems with 2,200 business processes. And every business process of course create complexity, lower our speed and increase cost. We are convinced by implementing one new global platform, we can get the number of business process down to 800. The reason why we're convinced we can do that it is that we have already piloted that in Switzerland today. And we have implemented what we call the horizon platform in six countries in Asia. And right now, we're running at 500 business processes.</p>
          <p>It's a substantial simplification of how we run our business and a dramatic increase in the speed and of course decrease in cost. So we're completely standardizing our global platforms, it comes when it comes to SAP, when it comes to supply chain, when it comes to shared services, and when it comes to promotional spend. So, over the next four years we'll invest in additional &#x20AC;140 million on top of what we're doing today in a global active platform that would dramatically include increase the speed upon which we can execute and make volatility an upside and opportunity for us, instead of being a risk.</p>
          <p>Now let me move to probably the most important part how do we ensure that we have the right team on board then it can execute the challenging plan we put up. And it's about leadership, getting the right leaders on board, developing to the tests that Henkel so that's after Henkel conduct and set clear expectations. What is good yesterday is not good tomorrow. The 12% that we hit in the 2008 and 2010 that we are supposed to hit in 2008 was greater than 2010 but is flat in 2012. And that's how we think about it. The numbers we have today will not be satisfactory in the future. So it's very important that the leadership team we have, we developed and we've set very clear and built clear expectations.</p>
          <p>On talent and performance, meaning building the pipe, that if we get enough raw material into our system and develop them to help us build the competence in our organization. And when it comes to diversity, building teams reflect the global platform that we have.</p>
          <p>When it comes to leadership development, we've over the last couple of years built a very close relationship with Harvard Business School, but we're taking our top 100 people over, training, educating and preparing them for the future. It is not a static process, so be caution you have 100 in 2012 does not mean you in top 100 in 2013. It depends on how you perform. So we're putting a lot of performance pressure into our system to ensure that our top performers continue to evolve all the time in their own technique. We're using Harvard Business School as one of the development platforms to ensure that we'll continue to develop our leaders.</p>
          <p>Secondly, when we look upon diversity, we're looking upon that in more dimensions. Nationality and culture is an immensely important part when you look upon that 12 of our top 20 countries are coming from the emerging countries. That means there cannot be a white European male dominated company in our management structure. We need to ensure that we have the right capability to be competitive in the countries and regions where we conduct business in.</p>
          <p>The same goes around gender. We're completely against the quota. We have 30% female managers in this company. We increased that level by one to two points per year not because they're female but because they're the appropriate and the best managers that we can promote in our company. And then frankly, we don't care whether you're young or old, we just wanted the best and best goes in youth and also in aged and we are very focused enough making certain that we push people out because of any different dimensions. We have great people that are young and we have great people that are getting older. I have to say that because I am the oldest in the management team.</p>
          <p>And let me now come to a very important part of how we change the company good performance or strong performance need over proportional rewards. In 2011 we changed our short-term system &#x2013; our short-term intensive system. The way we managed our annual business and this is important is around three dimensions. It was and will continue also for the next four years to be so. So our short-term performance annually we managed around OSG organic sales growth, EBIT margin that someone you were asking me this morning, where is the EBIT margin that's where the EBIT margin is, and net working capital.</p>
          <p>Our long-term incentive, we have revised from a three to a four-year program and is completely aligned to one KPI and that is EPS. And we are making it very attractive. So what we're doing is, like we did in the past, we are saying, if you labor you get, if you don't, you don't. We've built it in-house so <mark type="ph" /> STI (49:10) we believe we have great model and that model is aligned to the left part of the chart here which is our cost distribution. So we want to overly reward the good ones by overly rewarding or under rewarding the not so good ones. That is unchanged measuring an OSG, EBIT and net working capital, our long-term incentive is completely aligned to the times we put ourselves out here today, 10% EPS.</p>
          <p>That means what I've done now is I've taken our four strategic priorities: outperform, globalize, simplify and inspire. I've given you the general direction where we're taking the company. I tried to give you very specific examples of what we're delivering below outperform, globalize, simplify and inspire. But I want to repeat a sentence I've said three, four &#x2013; two, three, and four years ago. Do we know all the things we're going to do over the next four years? Of course not because that would mean that we would be end of our thinking. We believe we have a good plan, but of course, we'll do our utmost to become better every day. And every time we get a new idea, we'll implement that new idea but in this framework and I'm convinced we will continue to get good new ideas within this framework and then we just need to select which one are worth pursuing. And when you have something that's worth pursuing, we need to do it correctly.</p>
          <p>I have spoken about the strategy. I'll now ask Carsten to take you through what are the financial targets for the next four years. Carsten?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thank you very much, Kasper. Let me start with the financial targets of 2016. 20-10-10 is our new ambition. We will strive for &#x20AC;20 billion in sales for the total company. We will aim to achieve &#x20AC;10 billion sales in the emerging markets. And regarding the adjusted earnings per share, we are planning to reach 10% on the CAGR until 2016. All in all, a well balanced combination of top and bottom line focus. In determining the quantification of our targets we based our calculations on the set of external and internal assumptions. The most important ones I would like to highlight. The average GDP growth on the worldwide basis, we have been assumed with a 3.3% per annum over the years until 2016. We also assume for Western Europe a growth of 1.8% per annum.</p>
          <p>As you see, we assume with that that the euro crisis will not get worse and that we will not see a breakup of the economy. Additionally to that, regarding the U.S. dollar-euro exchange, we have set a number of $1.30. And for the material price development, we foresee a mid single-digit growth per annum for these material prices.</p>
          <p>Internally we will ongoingly adapt our structures through the markets. Among others, this requires also restructuring. And as we are used to it from our side, we will guide you regarding restructuring on an annual basis and we will do that on 6th of March 2013 for the year. We will also as an assumption have included the ongoing portfolio management of our business, which is including small and midsized acquisitions and divestments and by that we have also included that in our financial targets. Kasper alluded to that.</p>
          <p>We have identified in a magnitude of &#x20AC;500 million businesses which are either strategically or financially not relevant anymore for &#x2013; going for the future. But now let's have a look on the individual targets and I will start with the sales number of &#x20AC;20 billion sales for the horizon. This number implies a mid-single digit growth as a CAGR from 2013 to 2016 and by that we have two levers behind where we would like to grow our businesses. It's outperforming competition and by that also increasing market shares and it's globalizing our businesses. Outperforming means among portfolio management particular in strong investments in our categories, and there are three drivers behind which are our top brands, our innovations but also our customers. And when we talk about globalizing our business, it' focusing on regions and countries with high potential and this is relevant for the emerging markets for sure but also for the mature markets. All in all we would like to reach the step-change in scale by reaching the &#x20AC;20 billion until 2016.</p>
          <p>Second target &#x20AC;10 billion in sales in the emerging markets, this implies an high single-digit CAGR until the period of 2016 and also here two levers which we would like to focus on which is going deep in existing countries in the emerging markets where we already have proven to be strong. So these are countries like Mexico, Russia or China but also selectively entering countrywide spots. In the case when there is a strategic fit to our business and to our company while either there is a highly effective markets or when there is an offer of a high ability to win for us.</p>
          <p>Let me come now to the third financial target which is related in achieving excellence in value creation. As you see, it's a balanced value creation and I pointed it already out before through top and bottom line growth. Earnings per share captures operational excellence and we believe that this is the right KPI also to create value for our shareholders. And by doing so, as you said it's a combination of top and bottom line. To the top I already commented on, so let me now go to the bottom line.</p>
          <p>We will drive further profitability of our business by focusing on even further standardization and reducing of complexity along the entire value chain and thereby also simplifying even more our businesses. Moreover, we will also maintain our strong cash-flow orientation, I will come to that later when I will also give you our key performance indicator on that and we will also continue our financial discipline to maintain our A flat/A2 rating.</p>
          <p>After I've gone now through the financial targets in a little bit more in detail, let me now emphasize more on creation of excellence in value. There are three drivers which we think are important for the future. It's about organic performance, it's about acquisitions, it's also about cash return options. Growing our business is an integral part of our strategy and by that I would like to focus now on the organic performance going forward. Organic performance at the end of the day means delivering cash and to deliver cash we see three pillars to do so. Investing significantly in our businesses, enhancing profitability and also further reducing net working capital.</p>
          <p>Let me first allude to investing in our business. We have foreseen for the next four years to spend around &#x20AC;2 billion in capital expenditures in our businesses which is an upside compared to more than 40% compared to the period of 2008 through 2012. With that we will further drive automation and also productivity and we also combined that with stronger investments in IT. Why IT? Because we think that IT is a key enabler for us to support our growth. And by that we have decided to also invest more than 25% more than compared to the last year's which has an amount of around &#x20AC;140 million which we will spend into systems into processes in order to drive our business to the next level.</p>
          <p>Secondly we also have to reflect our ongoing necessity to drive to our emerging markets and to over proportionally grow in that by structurally shifting our investments also to the emerging markets. And thirdly, for sure we will strengthen our brands, our top brands and our innovations by further driving marketing investments into these brands and innovations.</p>
          <p>Let me now come to the second pillar of cash generation which is we will enhance profitability as a key driver going forward and four points to be mentioned here. First as we have seen it in the quarters of this year, we will drive our gross margin by pricing power, but also by our successful innovations. We will further optimize our production landscape, Kasper alluded to that, we are currently having forecast of around 175 locations until the end of the year and we are planning to reach 155 at the end of 2016 being a net reduction of 20 locations.</p>
          <p>Thirdly, we will also expand our shared services. We have successfully over the last years driven that project but we're still thinking that there is enough potential also for the future. By that, we have defined in ambition that we would like to reach more 3,000 people working in shared services in the landscapes Kasper already showed to you. So our captured and the outsourced service centers we will further bring our businesses into that by contributing to shared services but we will also close our geographical gap which is related to the Arabic speaking countries but also to Greater China.</p>
          <p>And the last point, continuing focus on leaner structures. We will continue to optimize our cost base, be more cost-efficient and by that supporting the top line but also supporting the bottom line in order to drive the value for the shareholders. The third pillar, cash is key for us in the future, reducing of networking capital, we have shown to you over the last years that we have done here significant efforts. We reduced it, here are the Q3 figures or end of Q3 figures, with 6.6% of net sales. With that, we are already best in class in all our industries when we look at our businesses. Nevertheless, we have set an ambition going forward and we would like to reach at the end of 2016 a level of around 5% for the company supported by all three business divisions.</p>
          <p>Let me summarize and I think this picture expresses in a good way how our holistic view of value creation is set up. We will invest significantly more in our capital expenditures over the next years, I mentioned the $2 billion. We will drive profitability by gross margin improvements but also leaner cost structures. We will drive cash by further reducing our net working capital and we will also maintain our high competitive tax rate and by that further improving our free cash flow. And the improvement of free cash flow offers to us various strategic options. And one of the option is to invest this cash into acquisitions. And this is what I would like to explain to you now.</p>
          <p>We would like to accelerate the growth via acquisitions and therefore acquisitions will be an integral part of our strategy going forward. There are two kinds of acquisitions, they're are the small and midsized acquisitions which are already alluded to in the assumptions and they're are an integral part of our portfolio management. And as I said, they have been also integrated in our financial target. To give you some examples what is a midsized or a small acquisition, if we look back recently, the acquisition of SITECH in our Adhesive technology business is a good example what we call a small or mid size acquisition. In terms of divestments, you remember we divested seven non-core brands in our Beauty Care business in North America, also this we would include in our continuous way of optimizing our portfolio and call it in that respect a divestment.</p>
          <p>Major acquisitions are apart from that the ones which will occur when opportunity arises. The major acquisitions are the ones which will create a game changing picture and they call for sure of the necessity to adopt our targets, which we will do if we would acquire a major acquisition in that respect. Independent of major mid size we have set up a process for all our acquisitions. As I said before it's an integral part of our overall strategy. We have done an intensive screening of possible options and we have done a clear prioritization of categories and regions which leads to a detailed action plan and which also determines resource allocation on that. But we will not do acquisitions for the sake of acquisitions. The acquisition has to boost growth.</p>
          <p>And for our Adhesives business, that means we will support with that the technology leadership and we will use here our global scale. We have global businesses and by acquiring this leadership, technology leadership positions, we will roll out them and by that significantly use the potential which is related to that.</p>
          <p>For our Laundry &amp; Home Care and our Beauty Care business, it's more that we will strengthen our regions and our categories. And the game here is a country category positioning which we will also further drive by this. Behind that we established a very restrictive evaluation and selection process where we have a centralized decision and an execution process and by that we will ensure that the planned action will execute will be successful. In addition to that there is always the possibility to return cash to our shareholders by either doing a share buyback or by also increasing our dividend payout.</p>
          <p>I have shown you the three options which will and can create excellence in value creation and our clear priority going forward is to invest into the growth of our businesses and investing in our &#x2013; in the growth of our businesses means two points which is organic performance and which is acquisitions. These are both integral part of our planning and we think that this, at this point of time, this is the right way to create sustainable value for our shareholders. Should we not have the opportunity to adequately invest into our businesses, we will for sure consider other options like the cash return options, but so far no plan on that because we are clearly persuaded that we have a basket which is full in terms of organic and possible acquisition opportunities.</p>
          <p>In summary, we are committed that we will create excellent in value over the next years despite a very volatile and difficult environment, like the euro crisis, like the first signs of slowing down in the emerging markets, like competitive pressure or FX volatility. Nevertheless, we are on the clear opinion that our performance drivers, which we have set up organic focus, operational excellence and acquisitions and investments, will drive us further and create substantial value for the shareholders, and with that achieving our next level of targets.</p>
          <p>So with that, 20-10-10 the numbers that count for the future, and by that I would like to give back to Kasper.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Carsten, and let me now just very briefly summarize. What is our strategy? The strategy of Henkel is we'll outperform our competition as a globalized company with simplified operations and a highly inspired team. What we've done is we're taking you through the four strategic priorities and shown you a number of the plans that underline our execution model to get to the 20-10-10. We have a very clear plan on how we're going to get there, and as I said, of course the plan will evolve over years. But we're one of the few companies that go out and guide our four year period of time because we believe long-term planning is very good for the company because that way, you can make the appropriate investments to get where you want to get. When we think about how we execute, we think about it as always trying to do better. We're very committed to transfer more plans to very concrete actions, so we just don't have it on PowerPoint, we actually make it happen. And I can tell you we are extremely passionate about achieving our targets.</p>
          <p>Everybody in the company knew the times we made this work and by Christmas everybody will know these targets. We have a comprehensive global road show that will start next week where the management board will go to 22 countries in 26 locations, and within three weeks 90% of all employees in Henkel knows about the new targets. We believe that in order to reach targets, you need to get everybody on board and you do that by comprehensive communication and getting people on board in understanding what it means and what action they need to take.</p>
          <p>We have a management team that is young and passionate about achieving this. From 2008, when I did the last announcement of targets, the only one that I left without from target is Hans and I. So we have a new young management team on board and achieving one target is interesting but achieving target twice is much better. We're deeply committed to hitting our targets in 2016. I'm also certain that we'll have bumps in the road over the four-year period of time like we had 2012 to 2012, but I can tell you, we are deeply committed about reaching the targets. When we look upon our strategic framework, we want to execute our vision to become a global leader in brands and technologies. We are very clear in our culture around performance that we are focusing on customized people, financial, sustainability and family, our strategic priorities all around are performed globalized simplified and inspire and we have three hard targets 20-10-10 that we operationalize in annual plans. And the annual plans are around organic sales growth, EBIT target, margin and net working capital.</p>
          <p>With this, I like to thank you for listening. And I look forward to an interesting Q&amp;A round.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we will now start the Q&amp;A session, please raise your hand if you want to ask a question and please just ask a maximum of two questions at a time. Thank you.</p>
          <p>Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:10:07) Asset Management. I just wondered are you saying that going forward what we should expect is more investment in gross margin, but then the EPS improvement will mainly come from the improvement in cash flow rather &#x2013; whereas in the previous period what -there was a focus on getting the operating margin up and that was really what was driving growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To clarify, what we're saying is, we need to increase our efficiency by building more effective plants and infrastructures. But at the same time, to 20-10-10 can only get there if you do the math of having a balance between the top line and the bottom line. So if you do the mathematics, then depending on whether you hit &#x20AC;20 billion or &#x20AC;19 billion or &#x20AC;22 billion, the corresponding margin will come out, 15.7%, 15.8% or 16.2%, depending on what you have in financial items.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes good morning, Harold Thompson, Deutsche Bank. Just maybe one, sort of two questions. It looks like acquisitions is quite a major plank of the next four years on top of organic growth. But when you look at your two big businesses, Adhesives and HPC, in Adhesives, if I understand correctly, you are already a major player in all of the key segments you would want to be in and in many ways what's left to buy is more technology type deal. So, it's hard to see how a big deal could happen there. Whilst if you look at HPC, the absolute term there are some big deals out there but be surprised <mark type="ph" /> if ever (01:11:51) you who could get them, so in many ways only small deals look likely. So if you are going to do a major deal, I don't really see how you can do one. And the second question, Kasper, is you mentioned that in the last four years, you did about 15% EPS growth, but without National Starch it would have been about 10%. Did I understand you correctly in saying that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just start on the first one. The 20-10-10 as <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:12:22) said is predominantly organically there's a separation from small assets and there's an acquisition of small assets. So that's how we come into the 20-10-10. What we are saying is that we have today a balance sheet that will actually put in to get assets. What is available is going to be guesswork. And I think that it will be &#x2013; had we looked back and said, is National Starch going to be available? Everybody would have said, you can't buy ICI, which was appropriate. We couldn't buy ICI. So I think that putting the adjustment on that too early would be wrong. What we are saying is the 20-10-10 is predominantly organically should some large assets be available, we will be looking from those assets. Making the judgment, I think the day will tell.</p>
          <p>What I did say is that if you do the dual mathematics as we call it and do the comparison between the 15% and 10%, we did about &#x2013; a bit about 10% operationally in 2008 to 2012, so approximately 400 basis points came from National and that's when you then do the apples-to-apples comparison. You are very similar in operational improvement from 2012 to 2016 as from 2008 to 2012. Since as you said before, we can't plan major acquisitions, then we can put it into the EPS assumption. But as Carsten said, should a National occur with whichever probability, of course we'll go back and readjust that back into our EPS scheme.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry just specific geographies, what about HPC versus Adhesives where do you see that moving to in 2016?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are two ways of looking upon it. There's the organic and the inorganic. The organic one would assume under normal circumstances that you have a higher growth rate in Adhesives than you do in fast moving consumer goods. That's simply the nature of the business. So on that context &#x2013; and we will &#x2013; you'll probably see &#x2013; as we've seen in the past, that's also the trajectory but of course when it comes down to acquisition you can't plan it. The acquisition is done by the strategic pillars that Carsten alluded to, but of course there's also availability so it's great that we want our company X but if it's not for sale. So organically it will lead to a higher share of the Adhesives business. But inorganically, it depends on what's on the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, two questions please. Firstly you've talked about stepping up your marketing investments to drive innovation. Can you maybe talk a little bit where you see that spend going directionally as a percentage of sales, but also inside the spend how you think about A versus B and traditional versus things like digital? And my second question is on the production platform, you've talked about going from 170 to 155 factories. Can you maybe remind us what the time footprint is like and whether these 20 are mainly energy sets opportunity or more widespread?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If regarding the footprint, we do not have at this point of time exactly plans what also Kasper already said which exactly planned is within the 20. This is an ongoing activity as we did it also over the last years. We have set this ambition in order to drive and this will include all businesses and this will include also all regions in terms of emerging markets and mature markets because we are on the one side shifting partly our businesses to the emerging markets by over proportional growth and this will have for sure also the consequence that the production setup will accordingly move and others are regarding efficiency gains. So at this point of time, we will continuously see that over the time. But we have set the ambition in order to drive also here efficiency gains over the period of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just on that, you'll see within the next couple of weeks the first of the 20 being executed. Plans, when we speak to how we allocate our margin spend, you know that we're not very keen in doing that. But I'll give a bit in that direction. Of course by consolidating our brand structure and getting our 10 brands from 46 to 60 just by default, you get a much more consolidated spend on that. That's why the brand consolidation is very vital for us. We're seeing high growth rates in digital but digital still remain a single digit overall spend in the global market not only for Henkel but overall, that will continue to increase but I think many of you have probably also followed the debate if you unload our Facebook how do you actually measure digital spend within the digital community. We are very committed to increase our digital spend and we expect that also to dramatically improve but we don't think that market has completely matured yet. But over time in 2016, one would assume that dramatically higher spend then on the digital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Philipp Frey of Wardburg Research. Just quickly on your capacity expend or your CapEx plans actually could you give us an idea on how much of capacity will change over this period and how much of your investments are rationalization CapEx? And on the long-term incentives plans does this plan actually penalize this dividend payment or are your targets basically adjusted for that one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On dividend payment, our employees don't have the vote so to speak. So I don't think that's relevant that concession that will not prevent us from making any decisions to be very clear on that, so there is actually no implication. If we believe we would have a negative implication for our leaders, of course we will be sensible enough to adjust that because the only thing we're interested in we are trying to align external shareholder interest, i.e., EPS with internal management and if there were to be contradictory, of course, we wouldn't do that. I will speak on the utilization and Kasper will speak a bit more about the plans. As I alluded to you in the third quarter, we are very actively managing our Adhesive business upwards in lower quantities because that's where the competitive advantage lies.</p>
          <p>So you can assume that the growth rate in quantity will slow down "over time". So we'll not have the same growth rate in Adhesive quantity as you it will in quality, i.e., revenue because that is the strategy we are driving right now. We want to drive highly differentiated technology driven product into the market that allows us to capture high margins and thereby on the top and the bottom line thereby increasing our pricing power so. On the volume side, you should expect much less, lesser growth rate in adhesives.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Concerning your question regarding the capital expenditures, there are three major parts where we invest, which is in innovation, which is in rationalization and which is also in maintenance. There is a clear priority to shift &#x2013; not to shift, to have the major investments in innovation and in rationalization. And when it comes to rationalization by the nature of the markets, there will be a significant part more in the mature markets than in the emerging markets, but more details at that point I can't give you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Iain Simpson from Barclays. Just a couple of questions if I may for you, Kasper. Firstly, you talked about the importance of being of competitive size. I mean, if we just take the &#x20AC;20 billion and assume that roughly half of it is HPC, at &#x20AC;10 billion HPC business is still quite small by the standards of your global peers. So &#x2013; I mean is the solution to that the continued tight focus on sort of key geographies or is it just execution that should be innovation? Have you &#x2013; do you see yourself surmounting that challenge?</p>
          <p>And secondly, when you talk about the sort of assumptions that you make in terms of macro backdrop depending on what happened, some would argue that perhaps 1.8% economic growth our of Western Europe over the next few years looks slightly aggressive. Clearly, with the 2012 targets, we can now see in hindsight, there was a significant amount of Flex built in there as the macro picture quite widely missed your assumptions and you're still delivering that 2012 target. To save us asking the question a couple of years from now, could you perhaps give us a sense as to what Flex is built into those 2016 targets with regards to the macro assumptions? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To start with the macro assumptions, I don't think that we've built Flex in but what we do is and that's really the key word is that we're adapting the structures to the changing market conditions. If you remember back in 2008, we announced Global Excellence with a reduction of 3,000 people and along with National Starch we said that we would take some people out. We've taken between 10,000 and 12,000 people out in the last four years, so the Flex was we went in and dramatically reengineered our cost structure. That was the Flex in a model. And that is what we'll continue to do so I am not saying that we're building Flex or buffer into our plan what we are saying is we'll adjust our cost structures accordingly upward and downwardly, upward of course if the opportunity arises, we will proactively invest. Reversely if the market goes down, we will proactively take action. That was the short center I made before.</p>
          <p>The first of the 20 plants you'll see being announced in the next two weeks based on some of the macro changes in the market that we're addressing. So we don't build Flex into the plan, but what we do do is we're not dogmatic about the structure. If we believe we need to change the structure we will change the structure. When it comes to actual size, it is correct that you then compare to some of our competitors. We have significant size disadvantages. That's why we've been very focused on building on what we call country category positions. We will continue to do so also. That does not mean that it will prevent us from expanding. We have from a no position, in China as an example in 2008, build a very strong, very focused cosmetic division in China today by 2012. But we've got to do it in a different way. We don't have the size of one or two of our competitors, so you've got to hedge your bets and that's what we're doing by very clear, country, category, strategy where we hedge our bets and we're not trying to be everything to everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more questions, please raise your hands. Yes, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. It's Alicia Forry with Canaccord Genuity. I was just wondering if we could talk about the EPS growth target that you've put out. Should we expect that that is likely to be an even delivery over the next four years or is there a phasing impact that we should be aware of? And secondly, related to that, are there incentives built in that support a smoothing of that EPS growth or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't hear the last part of it &#x2013; that was?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Are there incentive built in that support the smoothing of EPS growth over the four years? And in addition to that, with the long-term incentive KPI being EPS growth, is that &#x2013; does that then imply that employees will benefit if you decide to do a buyback instead of a dividend increase or are those employee targets unaffected by a reduced share count?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So let me start with the first one. Whether it's going to be smooth or whether it's going to be rocky ride, pretty much depends on what the external world is. Of course, we would rather have a smooth ride than a rocky ride, but looking back, we didn't have a smooth ride in 2008 to 2012. So it's a bit assumption depending on what the market is. That's why we're saying CAGR. So  if we were deliver 7% one year, we need to deliver 14% the other year. If we can over-deliver, of course we're always trying to do that, but right now the world is the way it is. We will guide on annual basis as we always do. We'll prefer to have a smooth ride. But that's wishful thinking. It is not really up to us to determine how the global economy looks like.</p>
          <p>There is no smoothing built into the plan, so that means the more you deliver, the more money you get. So if you sent back, you're actually not really rewarded by it. So the more &#x2013; the quickly deliver into the plan, the more money it is because that's into the <mark type="ph" /> STI (01:25:35). On the third one, right now we're not in a position in share buyback because we're not doing share buyback. And if that were to come we'll go out speak about it right now in that part of the plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Carl Short from S&amp;P Capital IQ. You talked about losing a net 20 factories over the next four years, and what sort of restructuring should we expect to see on a normal ongoing annualized basis and will there be any sort of unusual one-off write-downs associated with that restructuring?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No as we said, we've an ongoing adaptation of our structures to the market and by that we have not foreseen any programs at this point of time. And as I've said we'll guide as always regarding restructuring on a yearly basis, which is 6th of March of 2013 which we'll do so but as I said no programs foreseen and therefore normal business as we have done it also in the last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just as we try and model this should we assume that the restructuring would be sort of even --  roughly even over the next four years and it might be a similar sort of level to what we're seeing this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good assumption. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes please, over there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Yeah. Matthias Eifert from MainFirst. I have a question about white spots in emerging markets you mentioned before. Can you go a bit more into detail, how you are exactly trying to fill it as for example in HPC, you've got out of some of the emerging markets over last several years. Are you trying to reenter these markets again organically or you're more looking at acquisitions to enter these white spots and can you maybe name your top three white spots you're seeing at the moment which you would like to have covered by 2016?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On naming the top three white spot the answer is no, when it comes to entering into white spots from our Adhesive business, we are globally pretty much globally positioned our adhesive business. White spot adhesive would mean that a last customer of ours would be in whichever country where we're not in and they would then subsequently pull us into the country because we have a very global position. On the fast moving consumer goods it is as we had before a fast move and always a country category decision and we will ongoing basis evaluate opportunities to go in to markets where we believe that "we have ability to win" that's how we look upon it. So we are doing it very diligently and where we believe the market is attractive and the end is important now that we have ability to win.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Robin Asquith with JPMorgan, three questions. First, you've got an EPS target how much capital discipline is there behind that? Obviously you can throw a lot of capital to get EPS growth but us there a capital discipline behind that? Secondly, you've got three divisions, do you think that three divisions can equally add value to 2016. And finally just a question on Adhesives you got this pruning exercise of exiting low margin areas, how longer is that process got to go, does is go over next year or is it complete by this yearend et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On EPS it's very basic, the main specific measure is 50-50 on EPS and growth share so there is fairly high cost discipline because that's our cost scheme so we only driving increased investments if you believe you can find it again on EPS side because it's not of course strategically they need to be aligned but it would have punitive impacts on it. On the three divisions maybe I was not clear enough that we said we believe there is substantial opportunity improvement opportunity in all three divisions. So we do not believe that any of the three divisions will by any means have a standstill over the next four years. And then when it comes to Adhesives you want to give a second answer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you repeat the question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's regarding the weak volume growth in Adhesives because you're exiting low margin areas how long does that process continue for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah as we've said for over the next four years we've defined businesses in the magnitude of 500 million where we think they are not attractive financially or strategically this is not only related to Adhesives this is related to the total company. But for sure we have still regarding the high volume low margin business it's only a starting point which we started in 2012 and this will still an ongoing part also within this period of 2013 to 2016. How long this exactly will last I cannot tell you at this point of time, it's always depending how fast we will in a certain way execute or in a certain way how a certain businesses will be developing also over the time. Because we have clear milestone plans in order to develop certain businesses and if they don't match that then we will execute accordingly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe just strategically, it's not only offensive strategy it's also defensive. So we might maintain a position defensively simply to prevent a competitor to move up the scale, so you might say in the short-term you know why it is punitive so to speak, but if it prevent somebody to get in and you can hurt somebody in that space we will of course also do so. So with the size that we have, it's most certain that we actually use the size aggressively in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>Maybe last question. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You said on one of the slides you're seeing an EM growth slowdown or at least that's part of the context in which this is happening. Could you expand a little bit more about where you think you are seeing that in terms of categories, geographies, is it in the consumer businesses or in the retail?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the general statement because compared to the last years, we have seen in this year in certain areas a slowdown in certain markets like in Asia compared to the previous periods and this is only to be mentioned that it is difficult to predict as an assumption and by that difficult to relate that to our targets of 20/10/10. And nevertheless, what I said is that we are committed despite these effects to reach our targets which we have defined.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>So thank you very much. And now I would like to hand over to Kasper for his closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, thank you for coming here today and taking part in our showing you with you what the new strategy is about, how we're going to take the company forward over the next four years. We believe we have made the company a much more competitive company in the last four years. Having long-term targets has been a tremendous asset for us in driving discipline into the organization. And we are very committed to hit the targets also for the next four years, we have the upside that I believe very strongly the organization is much better today, our portfolio is more robust and also that we have a better focus on our cost situation. We'll continue to adapt, discuss and set our structures to the market to ensure that we hit the target we set ourselves and the target we set ourselves the 20-10-10 is of course the consequence of a number of internals out of it.</p>
          <p>In closing, the way we run our company is, OSG, margin and net working capital on an annualized basis, but you got to have the long-term view and that's why we have the four year plan. We hope you'll be part of the four-year plan. We'll see many of you over the next four years and having interesting discussions. Should you have any questions additional to our strategy on the third quarter, investor relations team is available here for the rest of the day and Carsten and I will see many of you over the future also, so don't hesitate to contact. We hope you stay in, if not we'll see you later.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10">
        <plist>
          <p>So thank you for the those who joined the conference also from the webcast and for those who are here, you can follow the IR team upstairs to the exchange room where also breakfast will be served.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>