<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1346382" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-08-10</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7863</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Head-Human Resources">Kasper B. Rorsted</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="EVP-Finance, Information Technology &amp; Legal">Lothar Steinebach</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Rosie A. Edwards</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Celine Pannuti CFA</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="MainFirst Bank AG (London Branch)">Matthias Eifert</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Susanne Seibel</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Harold P. Thompson</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Erik P. Sjogren</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Eva Quiroga</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Alex P. Smith</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Royal Bank of Scotland Plc (Broker)">Iain E. Simpson</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome to the Henkel Conference Call. With us today are Kasper Rorsted, CEO; Lothar Steinebach, CFO and the Investor Relations team. For the duration of the call, you will be on listen-only. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Today's conference call is being recorded and the webcast is available at www.henkel.com/ir.</p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the call over to Mr. Kasper Rorsted. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, good morning and welcome to our Q2 conference call. First, I'd like to focus on the market environment and the highlights of the second quarter 2011. Then Lothar Steinebach, our CFO, will provide you with the Q2 financials in greater details and after that, I'll comment on the outlook for 2011. And finally, we'll take your questions.</p>
          <p>I'll like to begin by reminding everybody that the presentation, which contains the usual formal disclaimer to forward-looking statements within the meaning of relevant U.S. legislation can be accessed via our website at henkel.com\ir. The presentation and discussions are conducted subject to the disclaimer. We will not read the disclaimer, but propose we take it as read into the record for the purpose of this conference call.</p>
          <p>Now, let me get started. Overall, the market environment for 2011 and second quarter remained good but with a slightly lower growth than what we've seen previously. Europe with a very mix growth picture: Germany continues to be strong; Southern Europe continues to be weak. We see U.S. economy with a moderate growth and we see the emerging markets overall being strong and also contributing significantly to our business, which I'll come back to at a later stage. We continue to see a notable expense in of our industrial sector while the private consumptions remain on a moderate level and raw material prices continues to increase.</p>
          <p>In this context, the numbers for the second quarter for Henkel can be characterized as following. On the strength, we continue to have strong organic sales growth. We saw double-digit growth rates in our emerging markets with pretty much strong growth rates across the board. We continue to see market share gain in all our relevant markets and we saw price increases in all our business sectors. Lothar will go into the details of this, but this is very fundamental for the evolution of our business, not only the second quarter but also in the quarters to come. And we did see a credit rating upgrade.</p>
          <p>On the downside, we continued to see a declining gross margin. The ongoing intense competition HPC continued and raw material prices continued, which you did see in the GP1 margin. While we saw improvement in our North American business in HPC with a strong organic growth, we're still happy with the business, particularly on the bottom line. So what we said on previous quarters, we expect a full turn around to be seen in the fourth quarter. Until then, we are seeing consistent improvement but overall, we're still not happy with our business in our North American HPC business, particularly as relate to the bottom line.</p>
          <p>Going to the business groups, let me start with Laundry and Homecare. We saw a positive evolution on the top line. All regions including North America continued with strong sales growth in Eastern Europe and Middle East. We saw strong market share gains across the board and we did, as I alluded to in the beginning, see a negative impact on our GP1 market from our raw materials. Adjusted EBIT margin improved significantly and we continued to drive successful innovation into the marketplace. So overall, I'll characterize the second quarter for Laundry and Homecare division as positive performance in a highly competitive environment.</p>
          <p>Moving onto Cosmetics and Toiletries, again strong organic sales growth. Emerging markets contributed with double-digit growth across the board and North America also in our Cosmetics business continued with positive growth. We saw strong global market share improvements across the board. We saw the gross margin also in this area impacted by the raw material prices, not to the same extent as our Detergents division, but it was impacted. Adjusted EBIT margin at a very high level and also a strong innovation throughout the quarter. I'll characterize the performance as strong in a highly competitive market environment.</p>
          <p>Going on to our Adhesives division. Very strong sales growth across the board, all regions growing but American market continues as the main driver but we did see also some growth in our mature markets. We did also, as in our two other divisions, see market share gains and the gross margin was strongly impacted by raw materials. The adjusted EBIT margin continued to evolve at a very high level and we also did see very strong successful innovation in this area also. So I'll characterize this business group's performance in the quarter as strong profitable growth has continued.</p>
          <p>Let me get to the numbers. Overall we saw an organic growth rate of 6.3% reported 1.6, the predominant delta was currency. The gross margin went down by a 130 basis points from 47.4 to 46.1 and Lothar will take you through the bridge. The adjusted EBIT increased 8% and the adjusted EBIT margin increased 80 basis points, taking it to 13 points for the quarter.</p>
          <p>Earnings per share adjusted grew 8.2% to &#x20AC;0.79 per share. Net working capital, we continued our improvement with a decline of 30 basis points taken from 8.7% in the second quarter of 2010 to the second quarter of 2011 8.4%. So it was a solid performance overall in what I would characterize as a very challenging environment.</p>
          <p>Lothar will now take you through the details. I will take you through the outlook and then we'll get to the Q&amp;A side. Lothar, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Also welcome from my side. As usual, we start our walk-through on numbers with sales growth by business sector. As you can see from the charts, we've seen a very strong impact from currencies &#x2013; negative impact from currencies, which obviously in major part was the U.S. dollar, but also Chinese currency, Turkish currency and the Russian.</p>
          <p>Negative currency impact on the Henkel Group in total was minus 4.4%; on Laundry and Home Care minus 4.3%, Cosmetics/Toiletries minus 3.2%, and on Adhesives Technologies minus 5.0%, resulting in organic sales growth of 3.7% for our Laundry and Home Care, 5.4% Cosmetics/Toiletries and 8.9% Adhesives Technologies.</p>
          <p>Let me start with Laundry and Home Care with organic sales growth of 3.7%, which is a return to positive pricing for the first time since Q3 2009. As you can see in the price volume split we had 0.8%, pricing impact 2.9%; still good growth in terms of volume.</p>
          <p>We've gained market share in a very difficult environment. As you might imagine, in some of the countries we've seen lackluster consumer spending and we've seen that in all markets as well. Particular strength in our business is obviously our Laundry part which is more than two-thirds of the total, which has experienced strong growth in Q2.</p>
          <p>In terms of countries, we've been particularly strong in Germany. We've seen good growth in Eastern Europe, although not the spectacular growth rates that we have experienced in the past. Still good growth in Middle East, North Africa, despite the negative impact from the political turmoil that has been persisting during Q2 as well in Tunisia and to some extent Algeria and Egypt. We've returned to good growth, positive growth, in North America continued with our positive development in Latin America and Asia-Pacific.</p>
          <p>Cosmetics/Toiletries, another strong quarter organic sales growth of 5.4% with double-digit growth rates in emerging markets and in North America with strong growth, also double-digits. We returned to positive pricing for the first time since Q1 2010 with 0.3% pricing and 5.1% in terms of volume growth.</p>
          <p>Our strongest strategic business unit is our hair care unit with particularly strong growth continuing the launch of our innovations and the roll out of our innovations. In addition to the well-known Syoss with added strong growth through Gliss Got To Be and Perfect Mousse brand.</p>
          <p>We've seen strong growth in Eastern Europe; again, not as strong as we've seen in the past but still good growth and double-digits in Middle East Africa, North America, Latin America and Asia-Pacific. So that all results in a very strong continuation of our profitable growth past in our Cosmetics and Toiletries division.</p>
          <p>Adhesives Technologies, 8.9% with Middle East Africa, Eastern Europe and Asia-Pacific with the strongest growth and a very healthy split of 4.6% pricing and 4.3% volume growth. So we've carried out our intentions to implement price increases quite successfully and the impact on volume has been limited. So therefore, we've seen the strong continuation of our evolution in Q2 and all that despite the negative impact from Japan that we've seen continuing through Q2 and to some extent MENA.</p>
          <p>We've seen the strongest growth in our general industry business unit but also consumer adhesives, automotive transportation and our industrial adhesives, packaging adhesives. Divisions have experienced strong growth higher than average.</p>
          <p>Positive impact from pricing is obvious and that all resulted in the strong, again a very strong organic sales growth in Q2. We have estimated the negative impact from MENA and Japan for the total year at &#x2013; or the total company at about 75 million in terms of sales and 27 million in terms of EBIT.</p>
          <p>Regional view, we've seen again all regions growing. Organic sales growth in all regions was positive including Western Europe and North America, and we've seen very strong performance in Asia Pacific and in Eastern Europe, all with double-digit or close to double-digit growth rates. Our emerging markets performance continues to be strong in particular with double-digit growth rates for the total company. Sales shares in emerging markets in Q2 increased from 41% in the previous quarter to 42%. All that was driven in major part by Adhesives Technologies and Cosmetics/Toiletries.</p>
          <p>Adjusted EBIT by business sector; here again, the underlying growth in our operating earnings, Laundry and Home Care 50 basis points, Cosmetics/Toiletries 120 basis points, and Adhesives Technologies 70 basis points, resulting in 13.0% for the total company or 80 basis points on an adjusted basis.</p>
          <p>First, Laundry and Home Care, we've been able to offset the impact from rising input costs by cost optimization initiatives and positive pricing. I have alluded to positive pricing already in the sales line and we've seen, obviously, an impact of positive pricing in our bottom line as well.</p>
          <p>The adjustments in major part refer to the extraordinary gain that we have realized from the disposition of our Indian business and the negativeness from the continuation of our restructuring that we have undertaken. In Q2, the impact, the positive impact from extraordinary one-offs was bigger than the restructuring, so therefore reported figures are higher than adjusted figures.</p>
          <p>Cosmetics/Toiletries, we've continued with our strong introduction of margin accretive innovations. We've communicated on various occasions that as one requirement of introducing innovation we looked at margin accretion. That is to say any product that we substitute with a new product is required to have higher gross margin then the one that we're substituting and obviously that bears fruit not only in terms of growth but also in terms of margin progression.</p>
          <p>Our cost controls, which we have continued, has mitigated impact from the higher raw material prices which in Q2 has been quite pronounced also in our Cosmetics and Toiletries division. Historically we've seen a stronger impact in Laundry and Homecare and Adhesive Technologies but Q2 has seen a strong increase as well in Cosmetics and Toiletries. And yet, with all the measures against it, we've been able to compensate and progress with our margin.</p>
          <p>Adhesive Technologies, we've seen here again rising input costs which we've been able to offset by onset prices and further efficiency gains. Obviously there is a lot of individual activities which have been undertaken and which have helped us to equalize the impact from the raw material prices but not completely as you will see on the next chart.</p>
          <p>On the chart the gross profit, we've seen decline in gross margin by 130 basis points and that obviously is all entirely due to the strong impact from commodity inflation. We've seen a much stronger impact from commodity inflation which has impacted gross margin by 500 to 550 basis points and we've been able to offset that strong impact to three-quarters, 75%, by our own increases and the impact of the savings initiatives that we have undertaken and that we will continue to undertake during the rest of the year and for the time to come.</p>
          <p>Income statements for adjusted EBIT, marketing, selling and distribution, research and development expenses, admin expenses all down. Let me start with marketing, selling and distribution expenses because that is obviously a very important line in our branded products business.</p>
          <p>We have increased our promotional spending in order to offset the reduction of the marketing budget. So overall, taking the two together, we've basically maintained our level of impact on the markets. We've seen our selling and distribution costs down due to the savings that we have realized out of our restructuring activities.</p>
          <p>We have continued to maintain the absolute level of investment in R&amp;D that we had in the year before, thus reducing just slightly the ratio but the ratio of spending to sales has been kept at 2.6 stable.</p>
          <p>Admin expenses have been down by 10 basis points. They would have been down by 30 basis points except for the special incentive that we have accrued again in Q2 and that we will continue to accrue during the rest of this year for achieving our targets 2012. Without these accruals, we would have been down by 30 basis points and that is the result of extended usage of shared services.</p>
          <p>We've communicated on various occasions again that we continue with our drive to improve our structure, optimize our structure, optimize our processes. We're in the process of extending our shared service activities beyond HR and Purchasing, which we have included in the most recent path, now into the transactional activities in our business divisions. That will continue to drive reduction in our admin expenses as a percentage of sales.</p>
          <p>Quick look at the adjustments that we have undertaken. Higher level of one-time gains, 57 compared to the restructuring charges that we have taken in Q2. One-time gains of 57 include 48 million from the divestment of our Home and Personal Care business in India, the retail business. We have retained professional Hair Care business in India, but we've sold the retail business and we've communicated about it. So that has resulted in a gain of 48 million.</p>
          <p>The restructuring charges that we have taken of 34 million are attributable to Laundry and Home Care with 9 million, Cosmetics/Toiletries 5 million, Adhesive Technologies with 19 million.</p>
          <p>Cash flow statement, operating profit, operating earnings are up, obviously also income taxes paid are up to some extent. We have as a correction item higher net gains on disposal of non-current assets and we have a stronger cash outflow from the change in net working capital minus 136. That is the increase by the higher volume growth that we have experienced in Q2. In other words, we needed to finance our additional net working capital in absolute terms as a result of the strong sales increase.</p>
          <p>Free cash flow, which is slightly below the same period of last year, obviously impacted by the higher usage of cash for net working capital. And despite the higher usage of cash for net working capital, we have been able to continue our drive to keep our net working capital under control. We have experienced a slightly lower level of 8.4% to sales than what we had in the same period of last year, 8.7%, and that was driven and contributed by all divisions, with particular strong performance by our Laundry and Home Care division which is almost at zero and a strong, stable situation in our Cosmetics division with 4.1%.</p>
          <p>Controlling our cash out has resulted in a pretty strong cash profile, but reduced our net debt over the period two years, over the last two years from almost 4 billion now to 2.2 billion. And obviously Q2 was a little bit higher than Q1 as usual, because we pay the dividends in Q2. In other words, we further reduced on a comparable basis our net debt but the one time payment of dividends occurs in Q2. So in other words, we're continuing with our strong growth &#x2013; drive towards cash generation, reducing our debt and getting flexibility that permits us to act in the markets.</p>
          <p>Dividend distribution in Q2 as usual and that gets me to the outlook. I hand over again to Kasper for the outlook.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Lothar. What we are seeing is we are seeing a slight slowdown in the overall global economy, but overall it's trailing at approximately a 3% growth rate at this stage. And we continue to see further increase in raw material costs so overall, slight slowdown in the global economy, continued increase in the raw material basket that is relevant for Henkel.</p>
          <p>On the outlook and our guidance, we are now guiding our organic sales growth of 5%. We started the year between 3% and 5%. Following the first quarter earnings, we upped the guidance at the upper end of the range and now we are saying 5%.</p>
          <p>We are seeing our relevant markets for our Laundry and Home Care and Cosmetics, the divisions being flat and we see the market for Adhesive division, the relevant market, growing between 3% and 4%.</p>
          <p>Our adjusted EBIT margin guidance remain around the 13% range. Our adjusted EBIT EPS growth is plus 10%. We are fully committed to our 2011 outlook and I'd like to reiterate our commitment to our 2012 targets.</p>
          <p>What we see, we'll characterize a journey for 2011. We'll continue to find the right balance between profitable growth and increased market shares. I believe we've been able to do that in the first six months, building up our market share positions in those relevant markets for Henkel and at the same time substantially increasing our profitability. We will continue to focus on our position in the emerging markets and expand that as it is accretive in a number of our businesses meaning that we'll continue to drive market improvement in our business.</p>
          <p>While we've seen a good sales quarter in our North American business, one quarter is too early to say that we've turned this situation around. That's why, as I've said on previous calls, we are committed to having turn the situation around by the fourth quarter. We were happy with the top line in our North American business in the second quarter and not happy with the bottom line, so there is still work to do.</p>
          <p>We've taken measures, as we have indicated on previous calls, to offset raw material prices by price increases from our consumer and industrial products, and you've seen the first steps in the second quarter. I do, however, want to say and I'll reiterate that we are still not happy with the evolution of our GP1 margin. We've seen, as I've said, sales prices increase; we continue to apply very strict cost controls and, as Lothar has alluded to, I'd like to emphasize that we are changing or speeding up the transformation of our company.</p>
          <p>The adaption of shared services not only to the central functions but also to the business groups continues. We have fully committed to having transferred 1,000 jobs into shared services by the end of this year and seeing an equal number coming up next year. So the transformation of the company and the speed at which we transform the company is picking up. We are by no means slowing down subsequent to the finalization of global excellence in the integration <mark type="indiscernible" /> (25:22). On the contrary, we believe that we have still much more that we can do within the company.</p>
          <p>'11 is an important step to achieve our target in '12. It was, when I characterized it, a solid performance in a challenging environment. We did see strong organic growth with market improvements. But as I said before, while we've taken a number of measures and been capable of offsetting approximately 75% of the negative impact on the GP1, we were not fully capable of offsetting the GP1 decline and we're not happy with the current evolution on our gross margin.</p>
          <p>We saw a strong performance in our Cosmetics and Adhesive divisions and we have seen an improved performance in Laundry &amp; Home Care division in the second quarter. Very high level of promotional spend and the quarter was also characterized by an increased raw material price. Overall, a solid quarter; we'll continue our focus on cost and profitable growth and we'll drive the transformation within our company as we can.</p>
          <p>With this, we are coming to the Q&amp;As. And I'd like to thank you for listening so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mr. Rorsted. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question will come from Rosie Edwards from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. I was wondering if you could just give a little bit of extra color on your outlook for the Adhesive market growth. I believe it's been downgraded slightly; at Q1 you were saying three to five, it's now more like three to four and whether that is a symptom of the kind of slowing global GDP or there's some specific markets in there driving that?</p>
          <p>And secondly, just an update on Syoss, just in terms of kind of where &#x2013; which new markets you were launched into in the second quarter and where is yet to go? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just start with the growth assumption. We have not seen any slowdown in our growth assumptions at this stage. We start out by guiding the growth for the company in the range of 3 to 5, and now we're guiding 5. We've not guided before on the specific business sectors; that's what we're doing right now. And that's where we're seeing our consumer businesses acting as flat, the relevant markets for us and our industrial businesses growing at 3 to 4.</p>
          <p>We are seeing an overall slowdown in the global economy slightly, I believe from 3.2 to 3 at this stage. But we're not seeing any significant slowdown in our Adhesives growth. And that's why you can also see we're actually upped it, our guidance for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry; I mean, so the market growth, I believe actually, one, you were saying the market growth for Adhesives would be 3 to 5 and now it's 3 to 4?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Let me be clear again. We said that we expected a growth of 3 to 5. We didn't guide, if I remember correctly, a market growth in the first quarter. We did not &#x2013; what we are guiding now is we are guiding specific on market growth for our relevant markets for the first time and that's why we're guiding 3 to 4 and that we are guiding with an overall revenue growth for the company at 5. And that goes back to what we said before that we are growing faster than our overall markets. Because one is flat, the other one is growing 3 to 4 and we're growing the company at 5.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Syoss at this stage, we continue to see very strong double-digit growth for Syoss. At this stage, we are in 37 countries so we've only seen marginal country experiencing. What we are seeing, we are expanding the overall portfolio so we introduced Syoss for men. We have introduced mix-in colors. So we have seen no slowdown in the overall growth for Syoss. We have only, I believe, added two new countries to it but we're expanding the overall portfolio for Syoss.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next questions will come from Celine Pannuti from J.P. Morgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. On your input cost inflation you reiterated your low teens inflation guidance. At Q1 stage you said that Q2 and Q3 will be the maximum of input cost inflation. I wanted to know if this still holds and if we should be looking at about 500 to 550 basis points hedge in Q3 as you did in Q1 &#x2013; in Q2, sorry.</p>
          <p>And my second question is about your savings. Could you quantify the different savings you seem to be talking about? Obviously you have spoken about the admin saving which would have helped your admin by about 40 basis points on the shared services. But my question is rather on the selling expenses. If you could explicitly say what those savings are coming from and try to quantify them. I don't think that you had mentioned them in Q1 so this seems to be new.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to input cost inflation, we have indeed guided that Q3 and &#x2013; Q2 and Q3 will be having the highest impact. That's still our view. Depending to some extent on the exact sequencing, we see Q3 even slightly higher than Q2 as an impact. With respect to gross margin guidance, we would not want to give any gross margin guidance because that's not only depending on the evolution of the input cost inflation, but also the impact of our pricing and the impact of our cost savings measures. So therefore, the answer is basically yes.</p>
          <p>With respect to the admin savings, we have obviously described in detail the specific actions that we have undertaken and that we will continue to undertake. We expect a strong continuing impact from the savings. We will not quantify that because that, again, is somewhat difficult. What we have said and will continue to say is that the investment that we undertake in doing the restructuring results in a return of 50% of the investment. In other words, within two years we experience 50% of the investments at savings on an ongoing basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because in H1, Q1 you were talking about 50 million roughly savings from the shared services action and 100 million of ongoing purchasing saving. So my understanding is that your admin line was helped by the savings on the shared services line. But my question is more related to your general and selling expenses where we see 190 basis point gain. I wanted to understand how much of that is driven saving and what are the specific actions there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I did not quite understand. What do you refer to? What savings gain?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You know in the SG&amp;A line is down 190 basis points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How much of that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, I see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...is helped by saving and what exactly are those actions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yeah. Let me just &#x2013; just a second. About 60 basis points of it is from the lower investments in marketing and the rest is from savings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you said 60 basis point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And can you specifically say what those savings are like give example..?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we do not wish to be too specific because obviously that's something which is extremely interesting for our competitors. So I think we're trying to be candid in terms of the results of what we do but we're not trying to be too specific on how we do it and what we do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And should we expect the savings to recur in the current &#x2013; in the foregoing &#x2013; in the going quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the savings are sustainable savings. In other words, they'll be still there when we go into the next quarters. Whether as comparison to the previous year quarters, you'll see the same amount that's a different question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question will come from Matthias Eifert from MainFirst. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi, good morning. Matthias Eifert from MainFirst. I have a question on your incentive program for 2012. You mentioned the difference here you've seen on the admin line. Can you tell us how much you've booked already out of the 85 million in total you plan to give out so that we can calculate how much more to expect for rest of the year and if I understand you correctly there won't be then anything booked next year.</p>
          <p>Second question would be can you tell us quickly how would your performance in electronics was? And Adhesives division, we didn't hear anything about that; would be interested to hear. And thirdly, very good performance in Laundry; is that already the impact of the new head of the Laundry business or what can we expect here going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will take question two and three and Lothar will take the bonus question. The electronics industry has been impacted by Japan in the second quarter so the overall growth in the electronics industry was not to our expectation. And we believe that the electronics industry will continue to be impacted by not only global demand but also the Japanese scenario. So electronics industry was slight growth, 1.6 over last year, but not on a satisfactory level.</p>
          <p>When it comes to the changes in our Laundry and Homecare business, the new head who started March 1st has initiated a number changes in the structure and the strategy and is about to execute on those. I think it would too early to say that you are seeing the full impact of those. I think you're starting to see very early impact. What you're asking is seeing price increases. The fundamental changes which we will go into detail with &#x2013; next time we have an Investor Conference with a focus on Laundry and Home Care you will see, but this is still early days. He's been at the rudder for four months so while it's good to see the changes, the bigger changes are ahead of us not behind us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to your first question, how much have booked. We have booked another almost 20 million in Q2. We're almost through with it. We expect for the rest of the year another 20 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And now we will move to Susanne Seibel from Barclays. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I have a question regarding your advertising and promotional spend. Could you explain to us not just in basis points but also in terms of absolute numbers, have you spent less in absolute numbers on advertising? How much more have you actually spent on promotions and how do you plan that is going to develop going into the second half? That obviously then would also have an implication on your gross margin development and maybe you could shed a little bit more light on the phasing of the two elements within A&amp;P and your plans for that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Susanne. Of course overall, we always adjust for the terminal spending on advertising but also promotional spend based on the market conditions. And the market conditions vary and you saw in 2008, 2009 you're going down; you saw a strong increase in '10 and parts of '11. And what you're seeing now, and it's being emphasized, you're seeing a slowdown. You've seen that from our major competitors also. So on the advertising spend we are seeing a slowdown in the overall market and we are following that adjustment to the market.</p>
          <p>At the same time, and we have said that on a number of calls here, we've seen continued increase in promotional spend. So that's not something new also so in order to really assess the situation appropriate from our side, you have to see the two in combination and not isolated. And that's also how we manage it. So what we have said is that we have seen a fairly flat total spend or investment, if you will, in these two categories combined. We have seen an increase in our promotional spend and a decrease in our overall advertising spend.</p>
          <p>We don't give total figures out for this so we don't specify, but what I am saying is the total spend has remained pretty consistent or flat over the last year. So we're not decreasing our investment in the market, I want to be very clear on this; we're using the appropriate categories for driving spend. So if you were to go to some of our categories &#x2013; subcategories, you would have seen a strong increase in internet spending. You do see a decrease in TV spending and you've seen a strong promotional level.</p>
          <p>So my guidance to you, Susanne, without giving you fixed numbers, is we'll continue to invest by market at the appropriate level. Right now we are seeing a market that is switching more to promotional, which we are also doing, and we are seeing a market that is slight decreasing on the advertising spend and I think that's very much in line with what you've seen from the Unilever record and P&amp;G lately.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. Can I ask a follow-up question please? On adhesives and in particular on the demand situation coming from emerging markets; the numbers we've seen so far continued in a very healthy way. The trend is going into the second half now. Do you see slower demand coming from emerging markets, in particular from Asia? And what would your outlook actually be for the momentum coming from this area?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have seen so far an exceptionally strong growth coming from Asia emerging this year and I see no slowdown. We've seen in many categories very high double-digit growth rates depending on category and there is no, at this stage, indication. What we have seen, we've seen fluctuation in demand from Latin America and Middle East. You can see that in the numbers also.</p>
          <p>But right now there is very little indication that shouldn't be &#x2013; have any slowdown in Asia at this stage. So we're feeling quite confident with the evolution in Asia. We've taken the overall share of emerging markets to 42%, up one point. And as you know, we're driving towards a target of 45% for 2012, and we believe that at that time it is appropriate that we're now seeing no slowdown. Lothar, do you have anything to add?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've seen indeed strong continuation of the economic evolution in Asia Pacific, obviously in particular in China. We've seen a strong continuation in the transportation industry. And at this point in time, although overall we see a slowdown in industry and therefore a slowdown in our growth rates in adhesives, we don't see anything like a turn of events or so. So we'll continue to see good growth albeit on a slowly &#x2013; slightly lower level than what we have seen in Q1 and Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Now we will move to Harold Thompson from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, everyone. I've just got two questions. The first one is again a regional one; you seem to suggest that your HPC division has done extremely well in Eastern Europe. That's really an exception to the rule. Most of your big global competitors are doing very badly in Eastern Europe. So can you maybe a) explain what you think the markets are doing there for HPC categories; and b), why you're doing I guess so well in that context?</p>
          <p>And then the second question is on, I guess, your margin hopes of 13% around this year, 14% next year. If you were not going to achieve that number what do you think would be the biggest reason for its lack of achievement? Would it be slowing growth or further increase in promotional spending, ongoing high inputs or inability to sustain the price increases which you have pushed through? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Harold. I'll take the first question; Lothar will take the second. We've indeed continued to see a strong and very solid growth in the emerging regions, and I think without trying to make it too simple. Part of reason is that we've had a very consistent investment in the emerging regions for many, many years and built a very strong sales and marketing organization and not pulled our investments down.</p>
          <p>So I believe we've found the right balance of standardization, bringing innovation in from the west but standardized &#x2013; no, customized to the east. While we're seeing fluctuation and we are seeing a slowdown in some of the "mature Eastern European countries," the EU countries, we continue to see a very strong growth in different categories the further you go east. We did see a slight slowdown in our Russian cosmetics business. We have seen a very, very strong demand in our Russian detergents business.</p>
          <p>So while it's been a bit more volatile, we're back to double-digit growth. If you look back, we were continuing double-digit growth for a number of years. We had, I believe, one or two quarters last year where it went to single-digit. But across the board right now, we're actually quite comfortable and we continue to proactively invest into the market. It is markets where on the detergent side it's more or less a duopoly between us and P&amp;G. And on the cosmetics side you do have a more fragmented picture but still a more consolidated picture then Western Europe with hardly any private labels.</p>
          <p>So our expectations have continued to be optimistic as related to Eastern Europe. It will have an impact &#x2013; Eastern Europe will be impacted by the overall Western European position but we &#x2013; our expectation is to see substantial higher growth rates in the Easter European part of our region compared to Western Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I just ask, what do you, therefore, think the market is actually doing? I mean you're doing as you say double-digit growth, clearly doing very, very well. But what do you think the markets, that is your cosmetics and your Eastern Europe household divisions are doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We believe some of them are flat to slight growing. The markets are not particularly attractive at this stage. They've not hat declined but they're slightly growing but they are not double-digit growth by any means. So we believe that &#x2013; our assumption, at least for what we're seeing in the market area we're getting, with the uncertainty you have for market data for Eastern Europe, we're significantly growing market share in those regions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just before Lothar goes in, we have no intention of not hitting the 14.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As usual, I'm getting the more difficult question. So I think that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Life's not meant to be easy, Lothar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess, as we all know, life is inherently dangerous and business is difficult and therefore, I'm not pretending to say that we're there already. And therefore, I think the biggest risk would be that we do not continue to persist in pursuing our targets, get distracted by questions from the markets or whatever into thinking about something else than reaching our target. Right now I don't see that danger at all because, as you know, this management is fiercely determined to deliver on the promise and this company is fiercely determined to deliver on its promise.</p>
          <p>So failing a double dip or the second part of the double dip, I would assume that we're going to get there and just realistic enough to say it's going to be a tough game, it's going to be a tough struggle in order to make it this year and next year, because conditions are worsening and we need to react to it. Our major position is that we've been able to show, to demonstrate, that we can cope with difficult situations as we have done in 2008 and '09. And therefore, it's driving major parts, knowing our people, our conviction that we're going to deliver on our promise.</p>
          <p>Now even if the situation would worsen and you've seen Middle East, Africa, you've seen Japan. And if you look at our numbers, if we wouldn't go into the detail it would be almost unnoticeable. So from that perspective &#x2013; and that's not coincidental. If you compare that to some of our peers who have communicated about similar situations, I think we've been extremely capable of dealing even with difficult circumstances. And that's our major proposition of what we're going to continue to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And now we will move to Erik Sjogren from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. This is Erik Sjogren from Morgan Stanley. I just had a question on your pricing. You say low teens raw material cost inflation. Do you aim to by the end of the year fully &#x2013; be fully recovering this through pricing or is &#x2013; will part of it be made up with cost savings and so on?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, I was wondering about the U.S. Laundry market, one of your competitors has pointed towards Henkel as being kind of a leader in the promotional environment here. Is this the case? Do you see this continuing to be very tough environment here? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with commodity inflation, just to clarify what I have said is that we've compensated 75% of the impact by the combination of price increases and savings. So it's not just price increases. It includes the savings that we have undertaken.</p>
          <p>Are we going to be able to compensate 100% by the end of the year? I think we're targeting to get close to it, but there is no assurance that we're going to get 100%. But we'll be pretty close. Again, it's going to be the combination of price increases and savings activities that we are undertaking and that we will continue to drive aggressively. Second.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, in the North American detergent market, overall we see the market being down in mid single-digits and we have double-digit growth rates. So we have a strong position &#x2013; we gained a strong position on the top line and I believe that the primary reason for that is that the value proposition around our Purex brand in the U.S. is now much stronger again compared to the last two years.</p>
          <p>So one is much clearer message to the consumer what we deliver, better innovation into the marketplace, and of course also a good value for money proposition. But I believe it has been more due to the fact that we have been clear on what is the value proposition that the consumer gets when he or she buys Purex. We have not fundamentally changed our aggressiveness, but we've been clear on the brand proposition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And now we have questions from Eva Quiroga from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, it's Eva here. I have two questions, please. You have given us the Home and Personal Care growth rates that you assume for the full year both at zero. And I was wondering if you can maybe explain a little bit where you see this growth rates in the first half on a global basis? And then secondly, can you maybe talk a little bit about your salon business, which you have made very positive comments about and that's not something we've heard from your competitors?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to growth rates in Home and Personal Care in the first half, we've had &#x2013; obviously you have seen more than 5% for Personal Care and slightly negative overall for Home Care. That together is somewhere between, I guess 2% and 3% for the total.</p>
          <p>Looking to the second half, we expect &#x2013; well, pretty much continuation of our profitable growth path in both divisions. And therefore with the stronger negative impact on margin in Laundry and Home Care and I think we'll continue with our strong performance in our Cosmetics/Toiletries division.</p>
          <p>With respect to exact growth rates, that would be taking our ability to predict too far. We don't see a strong, I guess, downturn in terms of what we see in the markets. We've seen flat markets in the first half, we see flat markets overall in the second half, and therefore our growth rates have been basically from a continuation of our &#x2013; of gaining market shares. And that's something that we're still targeting.</p>
          <p>Now the simple question is how successful are we going to be in the second half and that's something where we're trying to be more cautious. It's always better, I guess, to report success than to anticipate success and gaining market share, as you might easily imagine, is a very difficult undertaking. So from that perspective, I think we do not see a big change in the markets. We see our strength continuing and we'll obviously then report as to where we end up in the next two quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Eva, with regard to the professional salon business, what we've seen is following a number of years of negative market development and gross margin, we're now starting to see a flattening out of those margins so they're starting to be stable slightly positive. What we are seeing, we're seeing flat to slight growth in Western Europe. We're seeing very strong growth in our Eastern European business for our salon business. We're seeing very strong growth in Middle East.</p>
          <p>As you know, we just acquired a business in North America, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:38) business by the end of last year, which is not a big business but we are seeing it evolving well and we are seeing very strong growth in our Asian and in Latin American businesses. So while the market has been negative in the last couple of years, we see that market slightly, what do you call it, stabilizing; slightly growing, and we are outside the Western markets growing very, very strongly. So the primary growth driver for our professional business is coming from the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>We continue to be fairly optimistic on this. I believe we have a very strong management team in place and a good pipeline of innovation coming in. And the interesting question of course was two and half years ago with the introduction of Syoss, whether you would see any cannibalization, which of course was a concern of the hairdressers. We've not seen any cannibalization. We see solid growth in our professional business growing high single-digits and we're seeing very strong double-digit growth in our Syoss business. So you can see contrary to any kind of concern previously, there is no cannibalization, at least not between our businesses in this area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>[Operator Instruction] We have further questions from Alex Smith from Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just had a follow-up question on the question previously on pricing in HPC and Laundry and Cosmetics. In terms of the outlook for the second half, do you actually need to take more pricing beyond the prices you've already negotiated to get &#x2013; to meet your numbers effectively? Or do you think the pricing you've taken at the moment is enough? And then how confident are you that the prices that you've taken will be held? I guess I look at that in the context of some of your competitors who've spoken of the potential risk or need, given the consumer environment, to perhaps roll back on some of the pricing in the second half of this year. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To quickly address the question of pricing, that obviously depends to some extent on the markets. The Western markets tend to be markets where pricing agreements are negotiated in spring and then they're supposed to be valid for the rest of the year and then they're renegotiated in fall. The other situation, and in particular in emerging markets where we have a stronger presence of distributors, and therefore pricing is obviously more flexible and more volatile in that sense.</p>
          <p>So apart from the difficulty of generalizing very different situations, I think the practical aspect of it is that while pricing has been implemented already, the real question is whether some of the pricing will be or will have to be taken back in response to competitive activity through promotions. Increased spending in promotions is basically &#x2013; or discounts is basically then resulting in lower net prices than otherwise would be achievable. And that's something which is obviously something which is going to happen to some extent.</p>
          <p>HPC are seriously competitive markets and therefore that's a situation where we need to continue to drive growth and sales and market share through the whole marketing mix and pricing &#x2013; and some flexibility in pricing is one of it. So from that perspective, while our expectation, to some extent our hope, is that we will maintain most of what we have implemented, that's by no means assured.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just guide you on the volume evolution. What we've seen, last time we took significant pricing in our detergent division which was the first half of 2009. We took pricing in the &#x2013; coming into effect in the first quarter. We had, if I remember correctly, zero growth in the first quarter, 6% growth in the second quarter and we went out and said you should look upon the average as a 3% growth in those quarters. We would expect a similar sensitivity in some of our businesses with the pricing to come so we would expect a volume slowdown or seeing to potentially slow down the volume as a reaction to price and that will then normalize over the following quarters.</p>
          <p>That is not something that we are overly worried about, because that is a pattern that we have seen. So there will be a "volume impact" on the pricing, but that's a price for pricing we believe. If we can find, as I said, in the closing of my presentation the right balance between profitable growth and market share gains, then we will do the appropriate thing. But we've got to do both. This is not if we want market share or margin; it is, we need both.</p>
          <p>With this we are coming to the last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our last question will come from Iain Simpson from RBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. Thanks very much; just a couple of questions, if I may. I was just wondering if you could talk a little bit about the drivers of your sort of upgrade to your growth forecast given that you've also downgraded your expectations for GDP growth. I mean is it just that you're taking share faster than you thought you would be three months ago?</p>
          <p>And secondly, just on the sort of A&amp;P point, yeah, that's clearly ticked down little bit. Did the mix impact of Adhesives have a sort of material impact on that or is it more or less a fairly clean number? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Overall, our intentions, specific intention is always to grow quicker than the relevant markets to gain market share. And we did get a very strong growth start during the first and the second quarter, where we have substantially grown above the market as you can see. We expect our relevant markets to be somewhat flat in our consumer area and we'll grow 3 &#x2013; respectively 5% and we grow approximately 2.5 points above the market growth for our Adhesives business.</p>
          <p>So assumption, we came in, we wanted to grow quick in the market, we grew significantly quicker which you can see in our market share evolution. We expect that to somewhat slow down for the remainder of the year partly because of some of the pricing we are taking. But we still expect to grow above the year or so despite, as you are saying, a negative evolution or despite negative evolution in the overall GDP, we believe that the market share gains that we're taking we'll be able to maintain and thus grow above market.</p>
          <p>So at this stage, we're quite confident we can maintain a somewhat similar growth rate; a slow down, which we're also indicating, the growth rate; we're growing at 6 at this stage and we're growing at 5 and that slow down should be attributed to some of the pricing impacts that we'll be getting. So it's market share gains which is really down to good execution and strong innovation pipeline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me add to your question on A&amp;P spend, obviously in our portfolio, Adhesives representing half of the company and having almost no spend or A&amp;P spend, there's always a mix impact. So the absolute amount of money that we shifted from advertising to promotion is rather small, but that translates then into a bigger basis points decrease. So you're right, there's a mix impact also. We've not quantified it; we'll think about whether that information may make sense and then we'll give it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So, ladies and gentlemen, thank you very much for participating in our Q2 conference call. Despite the challenging environment, we had a solid second quarter of 2011. At the same time, we maintain our rigorous approach to cost management and our continuous adaption of our structures to changing market environments. We remain fully committed to achieving our financial targets 2012.</p>
          <p>I wish you all the best and I look forward to speaking to you soon at the next investor conference call on November 9, 2011. Thank you very much and good-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>