<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1219690" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-03-26</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9513</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Nils Vinge, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2">Robert Miller</participant>
      <participant id="3">Nils Vinge</participant>
      <participant id="4">Jyrki Tervonen</participant>
      <participant id="5">Luca Solca</participant>
      <participant id="6">Nicklas Fh&#xE4;rm</participant>
      <participant id="7">Richard Chamberlain</participant>
      <participant id="8">Tony Shiret</participant>
      <participant id="9">Peter Farren</participant>
      <participant id="10">Nicolai Tangen</participant>
      <participant id="11">Stephen O'Rourke</participant>
      <participant id="12">Fraser Ramzan</participant>
      <participant id="13">Andrew Hughes</participant>
      <participant id="14">Anna-Karin Envall</participant>
      <participant id="15">Melvin Hecht</participant>
      <participant id="16">Peter Testa</participant>
      <participant id="17">Ben Spruntulis</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, and good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to the H&amp;M Three Months Report Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode until we conduct a question-and-answer session and instructions will follow at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And just to remind you, this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand over to your Chairperson Nils Vinge, Head of IR at H&amp;M. Please begin your meeting, sir, and I'll be standing by.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Welcome to this telephone conference on the occasion of H&amp;M's first quarter results. The presentation slides are found on our website, hm.com. Our CFO, Jyrki Tervonen and our Head of Communications, Kristina Stenvinkel, are with me today. And we will answer your questions after the presentation.</p>
          <p>Please turn to the slide first quarter 2009. As you are all aware, the market has been challenging in the first quarter. Weaker consumption has affected sales, but at the same time H&amp;M has gained market shares. The things we have been able to implement ourselves have been successful and in the light of the current market situation, we have achieved a good result.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter, net sales increased 18% to 23.3 billion. The increase in local currencies was 4%, while comparable unit sales decreased 5%. In February, the last month of the quarter, net sales in local currencies increased 1% versus a net sales increase of 24% in February last year. Comparable unit sales were down 8%. Calendar effects, up around 4 to 5 percentage points, affected sales negatively.</p>
          <p>Gross profit increased 12% to 13.2 billion, corresponding to a gross margin of 56.6%. The gross margin was negatively affected by currency effect. The operating profit was 3.7 billion corresponding to an operating margin of 14.4%.</p>
          <p>Profit after financial items was 3.6 billion, compared to 4.1 billion last year. The decrease in profit is related to currency effects.</p>
          <p>The net profit was almost 2.6 billion, corresponding to earnings per share of 3.11 Swedish krona for the quarter. Q1, we opened 13 stores and closed three. At the end of the quarter there were 1,748 stores in total.</p>
          <p>In the current market, our ability to quickly adapt our buying and our costs has really been proving itself.  In light of this, we are pleased with the results. Price reductions remain on the same level as in Q1 last year. We ended the quarter with a satisfactory level of stock-in-trade, with a high proportion of new license and a good mix. The gross margin was negatively affected by exchange rate effects. There are two major components.</p>
          <p>As in Q4, hedging of internal flow of goods to the subsidiaries has resulted in lower translation effect to the gross profit. The internal flow of goods is hedged on four to six months forward contracts, on an ongoing basis. In Q1, these hedges affected the gross margin by around 2.2 percentage points.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, the strengthening of our purchase currencies, mainly the U.S. dollar, had a negative impact on the gross margin of around 2 percentage points. The single most important part, or less than half of this, arises from 10% of the purchases that is not hedged. Another part was caused by the time difference between the time of order placement and the actual hedging. We place orders intraday, but hedge at end-of-day basis.</p>
          <p>Excluding the just mentioned currency effects, the margin in Q1 would have been 60.8%. Selling and administrative expenses increased 23%. In local currencies, the increase was 10%. Costs have been adjusted to the current market situation and we have decreased cost in comparable stores.</p>
          <p>We continue to invest in new concepts and new markets. During the quarter, we prepared the first store openings in Russia, and we successfully launched H&amp;M Home, textile fashion for the home. H&amp;M Home has been well received by customers and media. Online and catalogue sales as a whole have developed nicely, and are a good complement to our stores.</p>
          <p>Looking at sales per market, we have continued to gain market shares in a challenging business climate. We've done well in our largest market, Germany, in a difficult retail environment. Online and catalogue sales have developed very well, and H&amp;M has continued to take market shares.</p>
          <p>France is our second largest market. It is one of the countries in which we opened most stores. A few weeks ago, we opened the first COS stores in Paris. Sales in the Nordic countries have continued to be slow. The U.K. market remains challenging, and we've seen some retailers go out of business. We continue to upgrade stores and to expand, developing several new stores, and we have also taken over three store contracts from a competitor.</p>
          <p>Sales growth in Spain and Italy has slowed down significantly, although from a high-level, while Portugal continues to do well. The U.S. retailing market has been challenging, with weak sales. And actually it has affected H&amp;M as well. We'll continue to expand in the U.S. and we're prepared to seize opportunities that arise.</p>
          <p>This year, the majority of the openings take place in the second half of the year. The first contract in Florida has been signed. Sales in China have continued to develop well in the quarter. We are about to take the next step in China. In May, we will open our first two stores in Beijing. In Japan, the Tokyo stores continue to attract Japanese customers. Sales exceeded 200 million kroner in Q1.</p>
          <p>This autumn we will open at least 3 new stores in Tokyo, and next year, the first store in Corsica. Both our franchisee and we, are pleased with the development in the Middle East. Six additional stores were opened in the fourth quarter, of which two stores in Saudi Arabia. Another six stores are scheduled to open in the region in Q2. Among these, is another store in Dubai and one of the largest shopping malls in the world, Mall of Dubai.</p>
          <p>A few words on some key figures. The stock-in-trade was 9.1 billion, an increase of 15%, of which half is due to exchange rates. Stock-in-trade in comparable stores was lower than last year. We're satisfied with the level, and the stock is well composed, with a high proportion of new items. The stock-in-trade in relation to sales remains on historically attractive levels at 9.8%.</p>
          <p>Cash flow from current operations was 1.2 billion, compared to last year's 2.4 billion, mainly due to higher preliminary tax payments. Investments increased to 1.2 billion, reflecting the ongoing expansion and continued development of our offers. Our finances are solid. Liquid funds and short-term investments were 23.6 billion, up from 22.4 billion a year ago. The return on equity was 39.4%.</p>
          <p>In 2009, H&amp;M continues to expand by opening new stores, entering new markets and through new exciting offerings to our customers. As usual, most of the store openings occurred in the second and the fourth quarter. In Q2, we're planning a net addition of 67 stores. The major highlight in March was the opening of the first two H&amp;M stores in Moscow. The reception was really great with customers lining up, and sales so far had exceeded our expectations. In the autumn, we will open another store in Moscow and next spring the first store in St Petersburg, and we're looking for additional store locations.</p>
          <p>Together with our franchise partners, we will open the first H&amp;M store in Lebanon this year and next year in Jordan, and in 2010 the first H&amp;M store will open in Israel. Next year, we'll enter South Korea, where we will open the first H&amp;M store at prime business location in Seoul. The population of 49 million, of which 23 million in the Seoul Greater Area, the potential for H&amp;M in Seoul is similar to that in Tokyo. It is the next step in our Asian expansion.</p>
          <p>To conclude, H&amp;M stands strong, with a solid financial position. We're prepared to seize opportunities as they arise, and to invest in future growth. The aim is to increase sales, with the continued high profitability. This year, international expansion will mainly take place in the U.S., France, Italy, Spain, U.K. and Germany. In total, we plan to increase the store count by 225 stores in 2009, including 15 Monki and Weekday stores and 8 COS stores. Our successful expansion of online and catalogue sales continue; now also including H&amp;M Home, fashion for the home.</p>
          <p>Our business concept, fashion and quality at the best price, takes us to new large markets. In 2007, we entered China; in 2008, Japan; 2009, Russia; in 2010, South Korea. We have a challenging but exciting journey ahead of us. Thank you for your attention.</p>
          <p>We're now happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Robert Miller from Redburn Partners. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I was just going to ask about the gross margin trends. You &#x2013; I'm slightly surprised you've seen as much as a 200 basis point hit from the underlying currency move so early in this period when the currencies have been swinging. Can you tell us what you think the trend line is going to be for that number through the next few quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. 10% un-hedged and also time difference, it's really more or less impossible to predict it because it's connected to the U.S. dollar development during the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But presumably, during the second quarter you benefited from some hedging at the higher levels through this first quarter, and as I understand it, from previous conversations, the hedging parts...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...unwinds as we move through Q2 and into Q3? Is that, so the impact in theory, gets worse, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No &#x2013; that's correct. Of course, we estimate that it will, in the long-term, even out because as you said we are hedging on higher levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. But that &#x2013; but relatively, as we move through Q2 and into Q3, the currency hedging was at lower levels. So it should be a more negative impact in Q2 and Q3?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. On those prospects we are hedging.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay. And some &#x2013; still on the gross margin, with regards to the &#x2013; sort of balancing item, you've said that the hedging of your internal flows accounted for 220 bps and the currency accounted for 200, both negative, and you've said that markdown is flat. So the rest of the equation is sort of 120 basis points positive, which presumably is markup. Can you talk a bit about that and what you're doing on pricing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not the markup, Robert, it's as we previously explained, we did hedge because we bought those garments last summer when compared to last year, the previous year, the dollar was still weaker. So there is also a positive effect, of course, in the figures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So that 200 basis points on currency is just the negative?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's the negative impact compared to last year, exactly. And as Nils said, in those 90% of the hedging, there still is a positive effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just a totally different question. Can you just tell us a bit about the trend in the U.S.? Because I know it's a weak market, but your like-for-like trend appears to have dropped very dramatically. How do you think you are performing relative to your peer group companies in the States?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is very difficult to comment. I think there is a big spread. Some do much worse and some do better. But we still view the U.S. as a very interesting potential and we continue our expansion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome. No more questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Luca Solca from Bernstein in London. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good afternoon. Luca Solca from Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I just wanted to get a sense, considering the number of stores and the different mix that you're going to have in the store concepts that you will be opening this year, what would be the growth rate of retail space that we would have to look at? I would imagine that Monki would introduce a smaller store and therefore that would have to be reflected in the total space growth in the current fiscal year? And the second question, if I may...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Luca, I take one question at a time, it's easier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, go ahead, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, our long-term growth target is to add 10 to 50 number of stores. And it's very difficult for us to quantify it more in detail. We have given you the estimate for this year, which is 225 net. But even in this figure there is a lot of uncertainty, especially this year due to the financial situation because we know that a lot of projects, lot of malls will be postponed, but there will also be some opportunities that will arise, for, competitors closing down, whatever. So it is very, very difficult to even give you a total figure, then to break it down per concept and per square meter is even more difficult. So sorry, that's the best we can give you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you think that a planning assumption or a forecast assumption of 10 to 12% of growth in space would be off the mark?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's within the range, 10 to 15%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the gross margin once again, if I may ask a further question for clarification, as far as I understand, you probably have two different effects going on at the same time. One is the effect of the Swedish krona being weaker and so the potential of reporting significantly improved gross margin on the back that you translate your revenues and other currency's revenues in krona. And that is probably impaired by the fact that you have hedges in place but they should come off, and that should be a positive effect, supposing the krona stays where it is. And correct me if I am wrong in this assumption.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not exactly correct in your assumption, that is theoretically the discussion of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And the other element, which is instead possibly playing against you is the re-rating of the dollar for which the hedges would be providing you support in the gross margin in the first half, but then the second half would look the reverse, if I am correct again in the assumption. Could you give us a bit of color around the various moving parts that you see as playing out in these currency effects?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, the question was really long, could you try to compromise it? We didn't really get the point of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, what do you see the balance of the two main different forex impact on the gross margin being, as the hedges against the krona come off and the hedges against the dollar also come off?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think it's really more or less impossible to predict the future of the cost, it's so dependent on the exchange rates for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Supposing that you have stable currency movements at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Of course. When taking the internal hedging, of course if we are theoretically thinking that we are being hedging Swedish crowns against euro in December, around 10.80 or 10.85. And doing it with a &#x2013; four to six months ahead. So, of course if the Swedish crown is still around 11 crowns after four to six months, the effect will be evened out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Another question, if I may, on the operating expenditure. What underlying levels of inflation do you see in your operating expenses going into the fiscal year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The underlying inflation, of course it's come down dramatically compared to last year, but it's very difficult to say, but what we do say is that in the quarter, our costs were down in comparable stores.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Nicklas Fh&#xE4;rm from SEB Enskilda. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I also, I'm afraid, have to go back to the issue with the U.S dollar impact in this particular quarter. And I would like to put it this way. If you have hedged about 90% of your actual purchasing, with an average time lag of about six months, or two quarters, those 90% should have benefited of around 11% or so decline in the baskets of sales trends versus the U.S. dollar. That in another words, what I would like to propose is that 90% of your sourcing in this quarter should have had a positive impact from the weaker U.S. dollar, some quarters back in time.</p>
          <p>Now you're saying this was not just offset, but well more than offset, by the 10%, which was un-hedged. Can I just ask you, what in your opinion did &#x2013; what was the highest level of the U.S. dollar that you had to do purchasing during the quarter? How much weaker, versus a basket of currencies or versus the krona or something like that, did you have &#x2013; were you forced to do purchasing at, in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. We don't have those extra currency, but coming back to these U.S. dollar effects, what we are seeing is, is that we are placing orders and approximately 10% of those orders we are not hedging. And if we put them, and the payment takes place approximately four months later, of course, the effect will be quite dramatical and material with this high volatility that is occurring during the past time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course. But it must have been extremely, extremely unfavorable exchange rate for a 10% un-hedged effect to offset the 90% that you actually did hedge?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you're absolutely right, but we also said that wasn't &#x2013; it wasn't just that, there were other effects as well, as I mentioned the timing issues, for example, just by mentioning one other effect there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, Nils, I didn't catch that. What was that? What was the other effect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Timing issue, between the time that we place the order until the actual hedging takes place. Since, for administrative reasons, we don't hedge every order all the time. Normally, we hedge on a weekly basis. And just a couple of days didn't delay such a turbulent movement as we saw in the last quarter's financial effects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I also ask you on the issue of the internal hedging here? Have you tried to calculate, now, I mean you obviously say that if you take out the internal hedging effect on the gross margin, your gross margin would have been about two percentage points or so higher, more or less equal. Have you tried to do the same exercise, taking out the full translation effect throughout the entire P&amp;L, what would be, gross margin be then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The translation effect doesn't affect the gross margin there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But how &#x2013; what would have gross profits &#x2013; what would gross profits have been, if you wouldn't have any translation effects at all, no hedging effects, no translation effects?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Most of the translation effect was hedged, was done away due to the hedging.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Rich Chamberlain from JPMorgan in London. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Good afternoon, everyone. I just wondered, first of all, if you could give any detail on any planned savings you're proposing to make in terms of operating costs in response to the weaker consumer environment going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. The selling and administrative costs increased by 10% in local currencies, and as already mentioned on comparable store, they decreased. And in H&amp;M we have a cost saving &#x2013; cost program ongoing every day, and that's, for sure is shown in the decreased level in the comparable stores.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I just wondered whether you might be tempted to say, be more aggressive on rental charges in Germany or for instance flex your, sort of, staff hours in-store a bit more because like-for-like sales are running so much, sort of, below trend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course. As already mentioned in the quarter four, that of course this environment and the recession give us a lot of opportunities and of course we are acting according to those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So you are already doing that, I guess if that's part of the normal course of business, okay. I just had one another question, please, on pricing. I wondered if you could tell me whether you think you're raising prices, particularly opening price points, more than the market average in your major markets, so, particularly Germany and the Nordic region?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have one thing that is so important for us, that is fashion and quality at the best price. That is what is steering our pricing strategy, and we have not done any general increases in prices. And of course, we are looking what is happening on the market, but as an answer to you, is that we are always looking at the customer offer, that's the most important for us in the long run.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. It would appear that on certain lines, on opening price points, you appear to have raised prices, but you're saying that you are not doing that despite the dollar having made such a move against the krona, you're not trying to pass on some of that currency cost pressure to customers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On comparable garments, prices are more or less the same, but it's more due to assortment mix; for instance, going from last year a lot of jersey to less jersey, more woven, for instance. It's more due to a different mix in the assortments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay. All right. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Tony Shiret from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead with your question, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Just couple of small questions. First question, when you look at the, sort of, differential between your, sort of, local Swedish cross selling prices and the mixed effect of prices outside Sweden, are you pricing at a premium or at discount to Swedish prices? One of your competitors has traditionally disclosed that sort of information. And I mean, you obviously priced in terms of, in the context of competitiveness in local markets, I was wondered where international pricing versus Swedish pricing was overall?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we try to have them, maintain about the same level in all markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So no premium outside Sweden then, is that what you are saying?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can defer, of course due to different VAT percentages and so on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And I'm not sure if you'll be prepared to answer this, obviously given the high degree of confusion on the gross margin, I'd say complete confusion...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What do you mean?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, overall, taking everything into account, and achieving current exchange rates, what would be a reasonable assumption, would you say for the gross margin across the whole of this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's really hard to give any estimates on that and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You've got a budget, so you've got these numbers. So, it is not that difficult, you've got them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we don't actually because...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You don't have a budgeted gross margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a very quick time to market, product time to market. And as you know, the prices are always based from, on the market and the competitors and the customers. So it's impossible for us to give you the gross margin for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I find it really difficult to believe that you don't, a company your size, have a budget for the gross margin for this year. If you don't want to give it to us, that's different. But you must have a budget. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Peter Farren from Bryan and Garnier. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I had a couple of questions. First of all, I do want to come back just to clarify one thing on the currency impact, that the 60.8% excluding currencies, so that's 120 bps positive impact excluding VAT. Is &#x2013; did you say that was due to also a positive dollar hedging impact? Was there something else in there as well because you also spoke of a positive mix? That's the first question, is to clarify that. And the second question -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We said one question at a time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sorry, sorry. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you're right, there is a positive effect on the part that we hedged. We wanted to explain the two major parts that really, the difference from last year...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the plus 120 bps is mainly due to that, and there is no other particular strong impact from any other items?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And thanks for that. And the second question is, I was wondering if you are -are you seeing any different trend within your stores in terms of product mix, your quite relatively recently introduced fashion collections for example, how these are doing versus the lower priced items?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean we constantly work with the collections and there isn't anything that's stands out, but it's true that we have a bit more garments higher up in the fashion triangle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And these &#x2013; are these doing well or do you see consumers looking for cheaper price points in general?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we are doing well and I think customers are looking for things that they want to buy. And so, it's important to always have the combination of fashion and quality at the best price and value for money even more important than before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So consumers are willing to pay a little bit more for that fashion element, you're not seeing a serious retrenchment there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, could you say it again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That you are &#x2013; you confirm that consumers are still willing to spend a little extra for more fashion content.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, it's always a balance, but value for money is very, very important.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's fine. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Nicolai Tangen from AKO Capital. Please go ahead. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, I have no questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Stephen O'Rourke from Deutsche Bank in Stockholm. Please go ahead. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Hi, guys. Three quick questions, please. Firstly, I'll state them one by one, but they are quick. What's the rationale behind sort of not hedging 100%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The logic is that we are working with a flexible moving order stock and that means that we are postponing orders, adding orders. And if we don't have that flexibility, the risk is that we are doing over-hedging. And that is the reason and that is the hedging model that we have used for over 20 years to give us the flexibility.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But over-hedging, now you're under-hedging, but yes, we can talk about more of that. Second question, just to understand, the un-hedged part, is that sort of versus the SEK versus the dollar or is it a mix of dollar and euros versus the Swedish krona?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mainly the U.S. dollar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And of course it's a mix, mainly the U.S. dollar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mainly the U.S. dollar, fine. Third question, could you tell us what the sort of U.S. dollar impact was in the fourth quarter then on the un-hedged part, so I get some data points here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, we don't have that figure at this point. But let's take an example, last year for Q1, it was a positive effect around 30 basis points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Fraser Ramzan from Nomura in London. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Good afternoon. I'm afraid I'm going to ask about gross margin and currency as well. Looking back at your full-year presentation, you did say that in the first quarter due to the hedge policy of the internal flow of goods, the company would not be able to benefit from the strengthening primarily of the euro. So you did tell us that there was &#x2013; you left us a clue that this might happen. Could you give us a clue for the second quarter in the way that you did for the first quarter, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's the clue for the second. And of course, it's dependent where the euro versus Swedish crown will go during the quarter. But theoretical thinking, of course, is to go back four to six months in time and see what kind of levels we have done and transparencies to the corresponding time in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So to be very clear, do you expect a further negative impact in the second quarter from this hedging policy on the internal flow of goods?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And of the same magnitude?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said it's really difficult to predict. But, of course, theoretically if the Swedish crown will be on this level as it is now, a little bit less than 11 crowns, so it will, of course, start to diminish.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But that, perhaps at the back-end of the quarter. And then to your losses on your un-hedged purchases versus the dollar that you mentioned, you made a comment that, of course, we might transact during the week but not hedge until the end of the week, and that can affect us or something like that. Was that the significant component of this, or was it just the overall average position through the period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The most single factor was this 10% un-hedged. And then of course the second factor was this timing difference between order placement and the actual hedging, and of course there are several underlying other factors as well, but those two are the major ones.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the order placement point was about half of the lost 200 basis points, or just under, maybe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I said the 10% un-hedged was slightly less than half of it...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>... and another factor is this timing difference between order placement and the actual hedging.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But as I said there are also a lot of other factors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In a normal quarter, this doesn't give you much of effect, but we've seen abnormal situations, and this is what we get.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay. And then the question I was going to ask about this order placement difference point is, is there anything you can do going forward to mitigate that so have you in any way changed your internal procedures as a result of that loss?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course, we are looking into it. But this is the model we have been using for over 20 years and these circumstances with a high volatility in the exchange rate, of course has caused these material effects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question comes from Andrew Hughes from UBS in London. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. It's Andrew Hughes from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. Now, I've got another question on the gross margin and the hedging, which is why you have the double hedge. If you hedge the krona/dollar and the krona/euro, why don't you just put us out of our misery and just hedge the dollar/euro?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's due to our new transfer pricing systems from 2007. There are slightly time difference in those. So therefore we have this model.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you not set that buying group up, could you not set it up to buy in euros as opposed to buying in krona?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you please repeat the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'm assuming that this internal buying organization buys in krona, could it not just as easily buy in...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we are buying in U.S. dollar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you not use euros, though to buy product in dollars as opposed to using krona?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we are paying and hedging the U.S. &#x2013; Swedish crowns, but of course we are also hedging the other part Swedish crowns and euro.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would it not be easy just to have the one hedge because two-third of your revenue is in the eurozone? Then we'd cut across the two different hedging issues and just concentrate on the one currency movement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but as I said there is a time difference that makes it really technically complicated to do it like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Worse that it is now? Perhaps I'll move onto one other question then; is on the regional sales performance between Q4 and Q1, where we've seen some markets like France, for example seems awful and the U.S. not particularly good enough and others like U.K., Spain and Sweden quite a lot better. Is there any pattern as to why markets have moved as they have?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's always very difficult to comment each specific market and depending on comparable figures from last &#x2013; the previous year and competition and ultimately there's a time of course when we do open the store in the quarter. It is difficult to &#x2013; but I think we have given you a flavor for the general market and of course most markets have been very challenging this quarter. But we did say that in Scandinavian, just like in the Q4, the Scandinavian markets have been very challenging, and the Spanish market and the U.S. and the U.K. and again many of these markets have had exceptionally good sales in the previous years. Whereas other markets like Germany and Portugal et cetera where the retail has been slow, the fall is not that great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Anna-Karin Envall from ABG in Stockholm. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't we talk some gross margin? I just wanted to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, why not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't you just clarify as you did at the Swedish press conference today about this 200 basis point dollar related as it was, I mean, that the time issue you had from putting orders down to the payment, which could be everything from it was up to four months, it could be shorter than that if I understood correctly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so that is to do &#x2013; you have bad luck and the currency moved in the wrong direction. If we then look going forward and you have the situation you have with currencies right now and starting to move downwards, or the krona strengthening. Could that be the case if currencies remain at this level that we then would have a positive impact from this in Q2?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then also, you previously stated there on the more hedged situation the 90% of the total you hedged that you're not that concerned for the full year as you have some issues coming from &#x2013; deflation coming from Asia transportation coming down and so on. And also the fact that you &#x2013; when you hedge, you put the price directly on the garments you're supposed to sell and then you already know the margin that you would get when you sell it if it's three months later or six months later. So you make a decision up front when you actually put the order how much you should charge and how high the margins should be. Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So then you have a quite good picture how the gross margin from the hedged purchasing should be throughout this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the indications I think we have received from you before is that you don't expect any dramatic changes in the gross margin versus last year for this year. Is that an assumption we still can have?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, we're not very willing to give you any forecast, and that might be your interpretation. But what I have said &#x2013; what we have said is that you are right there are some things that are offsetting the strengthening of the dollar such as transportation costs, such as the raw material input costs, such as supply and demand situation to suppliers et cetera. But we also said that we don't think that this will fully offset the strong appreciation of the U.S. dollar. But at the end of the day, the most important factor again is how the collections are received, et cetera. And as you see now, there're other issues as well that could come into affect in the gross margins. And that's why it's very, very difficult for us to give you any forecasts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But the conclusion is that we should &#x2013; that you still don't expect any drama in the gross margin for this year, for this whole year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>How do you mean any drama?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say a drama is more than 200 basis points down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But as we said with both the internal euro hedge and also the U.S. dollar effect, so, we can't predict where we're going in those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Melvin Hecht from Legg Mason. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you've mention that you've grown your market share in virtually all of your markets. How precisely do you know this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if you look at the category level, we have increased our sales with 4% in local currencies, and I don't know of any markets that &#x2013; where the market has increased in this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you don't have surveys, you don't have people who report to you on all their stores and how -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are a lot of surveys out there like ExteriorShop in Germany, our single largest market, for example. But the problem with every of these surveys of course it's never 100% scientific because is it really apples-and-apples, what do you include in the figures, et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course. Okay. And secondly, obviously we're in the midst, you mentioned it yourselves of a consumer retrenchment slow down. How long do you anticipate it's going to take in your most important regions? Have you seen any signs of recovery in any of your regions or markets or do you feel that this is going to be just a matter that continues until they're there, do you have any insight into that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it will continue to advance. I think that's the true answer. But I don't know how long this is going to last, it's as difficult for us to say as for you guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have any insight as to how different regions are performing in terms of the consumer ability to spend and willingness to spend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course, we have insights. We have very clear knowledge of each of our markets down to store, down to SKU level. But the general impression this time, this quarter, is that this is a global financial or downturn that affects most of our markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Robert Miller from Redburn Partners. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was &#x2013; hopefully an easy one on currency. How much of your liquid funds is in krona and what average interest rate are you achieving on your liquid funds at the movement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The average interest rate, it's a little less than 3%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is the vast majority of your liquid funds repatriated into krona?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it is. We are looking up exact figures within a second here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A little bit more than half of it -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Peter Testa from One Investments. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you very much. I was wondering if you could help us understand something on trading in some of your bigger markets, please. You carry on opening the majority of your space in your larger market and it's clearly helping you gain share. I was wondering if you might be able to give a sense for whether in a difficult environment you can divorce some of the underlying same-store trading from cannibalization and give us some sort of sense between when we look at the same-store sales, I think down about 5% whether you can attribute any of this to cannibalization versus just more difficult environments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, of course, by definition, if you open a lot of stores, as we do, there will always be a sense of a part of a cannibalization. But nevertheless this has always been the fact and we continue to expand and we will not slow down the expansion. And I think the environment as it is right now gives us a lot of opportunities for continued expansion and profitable expansion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand that. But you have data in terms of you have opened stores near another stores, you could see their performance, you have some of the stores have been free of space comparison. I'm just trying to understand whether you could give a sense as to how much of this minus five might be a cannibalization factor in some of your key markets? And whether therefore if you look at stores that aren't being space opened by H&amp;M, whether you're seeing different trends there, just to help us understand the quantification of this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me put it this way; it's not a material part of the like-for-like decrease.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then a second question is if you look at the like-for-like decrease, obviously it's a difficult retail environment, what do you think you should do or do differently to try to compete or combat this issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think there is one patent formula to do it. I think we have to continue with our successful business concept, which is continuing improvements and working with the collections and prices and quality just as always.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Michael Houghton from Sloane Robinson. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. I was wondering if you could comment a little bit on March trading which obviously is very absent from the release, and you've talked about the fact that March is not yet over. But you face a much easier base in both March and in April. And I was wondering if you can give us any guidance as to whether we can expect that you could actually start to report some positive like for like numbers? Or will we still be seeing likes for likes on the negative trend, but presumably better than the minus five you've done Q1 to-date? And if you could comment on that, that would be great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, we can't give you any guidance on March, there is still so much left, there's 20% of the month left. And so it's very difficult to give you any sense of that, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would it be fair to say then that it could still be a negative number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, sorry. I won't be able to guide there because as I said there is still one week left and it's the last week of the month and it's very important in terms of so many factors like weather and spring, et cetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Stellen Hallstrom from Nordea in Stockholm. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I just have one question here regarding these offsetting effects to the dollar appreciation that we're talking about here. Regarding lower purchasing prices in Asia, and lower transportation costs, have you seen anything of this already in the first quarter and if so, to what extent?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course, we are always looking. For instance in the transport, we can see it slightly, but of course we are negotiating them continuously. And when it comes to in prices, of course we are looking at different factors as already mentioned in raw material prices, the negotiation position in Asia, for instance, China with a different situation amongst the suppliers, et cetera. But to quantify that, we will not do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But has it had any impact already in the first quarter, or is it something more for the later half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, the impact will come during the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Ben Spruntulis from Citigroup in London. Please go ahead. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one question on cost, if I may. You mentioned in the statement you've adjusted your cost base in the first quarter to the current market situation. Can you give us a bit more color on the initiatives that took place in order to take out costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We had a constant very high cost control in our business and in the stores. Every day they work with hours and other costs, et cetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course, in the countries of cost, major factories, the time planning in the stores to adopt that to a new level. But of course, we have ongoing, we're looking into all kinds of things, for instance traveling, transport, all kinds of expenses. And that's the normal thing we're doing every day, every year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And therefore should we think about a similar level of cost growth as we look into the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Considering that in local currencies, the growth was around 10%. So that is in line with our plan and also corresponding to our expansion of 10 to 15%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question comes from Anna-Karin Envall from ABG in Stockholm. Please go ahead, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I come with a nicer one this time. I just had a question, if you look at Germany, it looks like it's including the online figures if we try to calculate the like-for-like trend here. Can you say something about is the like-for-like trend in the German stores deviating much from the group level you presented for the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not really.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Not really. So the contribution you then have in excess to that is the contribution from online you can say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are very happy with the online.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We appear to have no further questions at this time. I will hand the conference back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for participating in this teleconference. And we welcome you back for our six-month report results in June.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation. That concludes today's conference and you may now disconnect your lines. Good-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>