<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1530030" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-01-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9513</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Nils Vinge</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">Simon Bowler</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Jyrki Tervonen</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA (Broker)">Anne M. Critchlow</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="TextilWirtschaft">J&#xF6;rg Nowicki</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Banco Santander SA (London Branch)">Rebecca A. McClellan</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Fraser Ramzan</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Simon W. Irwin</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Richard B. Chamberlain</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="SEB Enskilda (Sweden)">Nicklas Fh&#xE4;rm</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Bryan, Garnier &amp; Co Ltd. (France)">Peter Farren</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Andrew W. Hughes</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Stifel, Nicolaus &amp; Co., Inc.">Richard E. Jaffe</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital Securities Ltd.">Chris Chaviaras</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">Omar Saad</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="AKO Capital LLP">Erik T. Karlsson</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for standing by and welcome to the H&amp;M Full-Year Report 2012 Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> I must advice you this conference is being recorded today, Wednesday 30th of January, 2013 at 2:00 p.m. CET.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand the conference over to your speaker today, Mr. Nils Vinge, Head of Investor Relations. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Welcome to this telephone conference on the occasion of H&amp;M's fourth quarter and full-year results for 2012. Presentation slides are found on our website hm.com. With me is our CFO, Jyrki Tervonen, and we'll be happy to answer your questions after the presentation.</p>
          <p>H&amp;M continue to stand strong in the challenging market, which in many countries was even more demanding in 2012 than in 2011. Looking at the fourth quarter, the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:12) was characterized by macroeconomic uncertainty, particularly in Europe, and most markets displayed weak statistics for fashion apparel.</p>
          <p>Still, H&amp;M increased sales including VAT by 9% in local currencies in the fourth quarter. In comparable units, sales were unchanged. We view the performance as satisfactory given the tough macroeconomic climate, and the effect it's had on consumption in many countries.</p>
          <p>The market conditions lead to many price campaigns and high markdown activity in fashion retail. Net sales in the fourth quarter grew by 5% to SEK 32.5 billion. The Swedish krona continued to strengthen against most other currencies and again currency translation had a negative effect on sales and results. Gross profit increased to SEK 20 billion from SEK 19.2 billion, corresponding to a gross margin of 61.6%, approximately the same level as in the fourth quarter 2011.</p>
          <p>The overall effect from external factors, cotton prices, cost inflation and the U.S. dollar was neutral on purchases to the fourth quarter compared to the corresponding period a year before. Markdowns in relation to sales were at the same level as the year earlier.</p>
          <p>At H&amp;M, we have a long-term approach and we invest for the future in several areas, in online and IT, in extending the total offering of the group with, for example, entirely new fashion brand, &amp; Other Stories, and in broadening H&amp;M's product range. These large, long-term investments that are intended to secure future expansion and further strengthen H&amp;M's position long-term, have to a large extent, not started to generate any revenue yet. Although this has meant cost increases, cost control in the group remains good.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A was SEK 13.5 billion in the quarter, up 8% in SEK and 11% in local currencies. The increase is explained mainly by the expansion and by our large long-term investments.</p>
          <p>In comparable stores, costs as a share of sales were up somewhat in the quarter, mainly because sales didn't increase as much as planned. Profitability was still good with an operating margin of 20.1%. Despite the large long-term investments and despite negative currency translation effect of SEK 240 million, net profit for the quarter was more or less unchanged from year before. Net profit amounted to SEK 5.3 billion corresponding to earnings per share of SEK 3.19.</p>
          <p>And now please turn to the slide, Full Year 2012. H&amp;M is present in 48 countries with varying consumer climates. In this environment, H&amp;M continued to gain market share thanks to our strong customer offering: fashion and quality at the best price.</p>
          <p>Sales including VAT increased 11% in local currencies and were up 1% in comparable units. We think this is a solid performance, which proves that customers like our collections, appreciate our strong offering. Net sales increased 10%, SEK 121 million.</p>
          <p>Looking at sales in some of our markets, please turn to the slide, Sales Per Market. Among the countries with the best sales development is U.S., Canada, China and Russia. The U.S. is the second biggest market of the group. Last year, H&amp;M opened nearly 40 stores in the U.S. and increased sales by 24% in local currency.</p>
          <p>In China growth is even stronger. China is the fastest growing market for H&amp;M. We opened 52 stores in 2012 and by the end of the year, the number of stores was 134. Sales increased by more than 40% in local currency.</p>
          <p>Japan is also developing well, which is gratifying to see, with a sales increase of 53% for the year. We continue to expand. Asia, by now, represent more than 7% of total sales of the group and with the same growth rate, it will soon make 10% of the group revenue. Sales were also good, very good in all of the five new markets that H&amp;M came to in 2012: Bulgaria, Latvia, Malaysia, Thailand and Mexico.</p>
          <p>In Southern Europe, consumption has been affected by economic uncertainty, which has been visible also in H&amp;M's numbers, in for example, Greece, Spain, Portugal and Italy. H&amp;M has, however, continued to perform well relative to the market in these countries, where we continue to see room for expansion. Also franchise developed well. There are now a total of 88 H&amp;M franchise stores in the Middle East and now also in Thailand.</p>
          <p>Going back to the results for the full year, please return to the slide, Full Year 2012. Gross profit increased to SEK 71.9 billion, corresponding to a gross margin of 59.5% compared to 60.1% the year before. H&amp;M's gross margin <mark type="ph" /> grew as a result (07:46) of many different factors, both external and internal. But most of all affected by the decisions we make based on the strategy to always have the best customer offering in each market. The overall effect from the external factors that we mentioned earlier was negative for sourcing costs for the full year. Looking at markdowns in relation to sales, they were at the same level as in the previous year.</p>
          <p>Now over to operational costs. SG&amp;A increased by 11% in local currencies and 12% in Swedish krona to approximately SEK 50 billion. The main reasons are the strong expansion, we increased the number of stores by more than 12% last year and the long-term investments. In comparable store, costs as a share of sales were changed due to good cost control. Operating margin was 18% compared to 18.5% the year before.</p>
          <p>Net financial income for the year was SEK 531 million compared to SEK 563 million the year before. After tax rate of 24.3%, net profit amounted to SEK 16.9 billion, that is an increase of 7% for the year, more than SEK 1 billion, despite the long-term investments, despite negative currency translation effects of SEK 290 million. Earnings per share increased to SEK 10.19 from SEK 9.56.</p>
          <p>And now looking at some other key figures. Please turn to the slide, Key Data. Stock-in-trade was SEK 15.2 billion, an increase of 10% in Swedish krona and 11% in local currencies compared to the same time last year. The increase is mainly explained by the expansion and also by the fact that sales didn't rise as much as planned in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>The inventory level as of 30th of November 2012 was somewhat higher than planned, which means that markdowns in relation to sales for the first quarter of 2013 are expected, as of today, to end up at around the same level as in Q1 last year.</p>
          <p>The composition of the stock-in-trade was good. As you can see on the curve on the next slide, stock-in-trade in relation to sales was 12.6%, which is the same level as the year before and still good, <mark type="ph" /> seen over time (10:41).</p>
          <p>Back to the slide, Key Data, cash flow from current operations was SEK 18.9 billion, an increase of SEK 1.5 billion. Investments in terms of CapEx rose to SEK 6.8 billion, mainly for new stores and partly also because of the increased long-term investments to secure future expansion and further strengthen H&amp;M's position long-term.</p>
          <p>Our finances remain strong. Liquid funds and short-term investments amounted to SEK 17.1 billion. The board of directors will propose to the Annual General Meeting a dividend of SEK 9.50 per share, corresponding to 93% of net profits for the year.</p>
          <p>Return on equity was 38.4% compared to 35.8% last year. H&amp;M created 10,000 jobs within the group in 2012 and today we are more than 104,000 employees. That equals an average number of full-time employees of 72,276.</p>
          <p>Now some words about our expansion, please turn to the slide, Expansion 2012. We ramped up expansion further in 2012 and instead of an originally planned 275 new stores net, we added a net of 304 stores, which 147 in the fourth quarter. The group had a total 2,776 stores at the end of the financial year. And of these, 2,628 were H&amp;M, 64 COS, 59 Monki, 21 Weekday and 4 Cheap Monday. Of the total, 88 are franchise stores.</p>
          <p>H&amp;M's strong brand attracts customers all over the world. Today we have the strong global presence and the current number of stores is already above 2,800 in 48 markets. We're growing in all our markets. China was the largest expansion market last year, followed by the U.S. In the U.S., we have opened some fantastic new stores, for example, in Miami at Lincoln Road in Miami Beach and in Aventura Mall.</p>
          <p>Expansion on Manhattan continues, H&amp;M will open a new flagship store on Fifth Avenue this year. It will be the biggest store in the group. A new store will also open at Times Square, where H&amp;M will become a real landmark and also add to the New York City skyline. We had several other large expansion markets in 2012, such as Russia, Italy, Poland, France, Spain and the UK. We also added five new markets, Bulgaria, Latvia, Malaysia, Thailand and Mexico. Customer response has been amazing everywhere. The tremendous demand for H&amp;M in connection with the openings, both in existing markets and in new places underlines the great potential for future expansion.</p>
          <p>Our other brands expand too. COS, in particular, continues to do very well, exceeding our own high expectations. COS opened 19 stores and came to six new markets in 2012. And at the end of the year, COS had 64 stores, 15 markets and a shop online in 18 European markets.</p>
          <p>If we take a look at the current year, please turn to the slide, Expansion 2013. For 2013, the rapid expansion continues. H&amp;M grows within the target of 10% to 15% new stores per year and plans to open around 325 new stores net. That's more or less one new store opening per day. And just like last year, expansion will be the strongest in China and the U.S. There also great opportunities for continued expansion in markets such as Russia, Germany, UK, Italy, Poland and France. And also for 2013, five new markets are planned, Chile, Estonia, Lithuania, Serbia and via franchise, Indonesia.</p>
          <p>The store in Santiago de Chile will open in March. We're looking forward very much to offer H&amp;M's fashion to customers in South America and the Southern Hemisphere. H&amp;M is also growing with shop online, where we see significant opportunities ahead.</p>
          <p>For fashion retail online, market growth is particularly strong for shopping via smartphones and tablets. Two weeks ago, we launched a completely mobile-adapted shop online in our eight existing online markets to cater to this rapid development. We are also intensifying work on the future rollout of H&amp;M shop online to other markets in the group. And now we are preparing for the launch of H&amp;M shop online in the U.S. this summer. We are looking forward very much to offering our customers this opportunity in the world's largest online market.</p>
          <p>The group also continues expanding with store openings of all the other brands, COS, Monki, Weekday and Cheap Monday. We're also looking very much forward to offering our customers a completely new fashion brand &amp; Other Stories.</p>
          <p>Please turn to the next slide. &amp; Other Stories will launch its first collection this spring in 10 European markets. This new fashion brand will offer women a wide range of shoes, bags, accessories, cosmetics and clothes, allowing women to create their own personal style or story. The collections are diverse, with everything from masculine tailoring to feminine chic and are designed to provide endless styling choices.</p>
          <p>&amp; Other Stories collections are being created in studios in Paris and Stockholm and designed with striking attention to detail and quality. Prices will be affordable and in a wide span. The collections have received very positive response in fashion press throughout Europe.</p>
          <p>First stores will open in Barcelona, Berlin, Copenhagen, London, Milan, Paris and Stockholm. To begin with, eight stores in total, of which two in Berlin. The 10 countries where shop online will be available at stories.com are, expect for the ones just mentioned, we also &#x2013; will open in Belgium and the Netherlands and Finland.</p>
          <p>Before we start the Q&amp;A session, a few comments to summarize. Please turn to the next slide.</p>
          <p>Just to illustrate H&amp;M's rapid international growth. Before the end of this year, we will have more than 3,000 stores worldwide. It means that H&amp;M has opened 1,000 stores in less than four years. And to give you some perspective, it took 57 years to expand with the first 1,000 stores. H&amp;M has a strong global presence today and continues to stand strong in a challenging, clothing retail market.</p>
          <p>The fact that we increased sales by 11% in local currencies and 1% in comparable units, whilst continuing to gain market share in a very demanding market, proves once again that customers like our collections and appreciate our strong offerings. We increased profit by SEK 1 billion or 7%, despite the large long-term investments and despite negative currency translations effects. Meantime, we have great respect for the current macroeconomic climate in many countries and the effect it may have on consumption in our markets.</p>
          <p>And looking at current trading, sales in local currencies increased by 8% in December and sales in January are expected to increase by 5% in local currencies compared to the same month last year. From mid-January onwards, sales were negatively affected by very cold weather in many of H&amp;Ms markets in Europe.</p>
          <p>But we believe strongly in our offering and are convinced that H&amp;M will continue to maintain its strong position. Even now in times of economic worries in many place, we keep on growing. Only last year, we created more than 10,000 jobs within H&amp;M. We invest in online and IT. We launched an entirely new fashion brand, &amp; Other Stories, and we broadened our product range. In other words, we see significant opportunities for continued growth for the H&amp;M Group for many, many years.</p>
          <p>And we are now happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from Simon Bowler. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. I was just &#x2013; first of all, I was hoping just to clarify some commentary I saw, coming out of your earlier call around the gross margin. Just to check, were you saying on that call that the net impact of currency and input costs, are you expecting to be neutral across the first half of the year ahead?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. If we isolate the look at those mainly three things, cotton prices, U.S. dollar effect and cost inflation, altogether, we see that they are or more or less having a neutral effect on our purchase prices for the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fantastic, that was very clear. And then just a couple of quick things was, one just, the increase that we saw in OpEx coming through from the fourth quarter and could you give us any sense of how much that might have been attributable to your online expansion, I guess in particular within the U.S.? And how we should think about that cost line going forward next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, as we, already in connection with the third quarter report, stated that we will intense our efforts and investments in rolling out online in new markets, existing markets, and also the mobile adoption to have a fully-adapted mobile site, so that's the reason for the increase in the OpEx in Q4, but still we have a really good cost control. Looking at the full year, we actually, I think as a share of sales, decreased the share by 10 basis points. So, but as you said, the long-term investments are affecting the SG&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And they will continue going forward as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was the question right?</p>
          <p>[07JGFS-E Jyrki Tervonen] Yeah. Okay. Fantastic. Of a kind of similar quantum that we saw across the fourth quarter, should we think about, or is there kind of another step-up in online costs that you're expecting to see come through ?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, as we also said in previous conference calls, we will have a higher level on the long-term investments during 2013, but exactly how they will be distributed in the different quarters, but they will be on a higher level than 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But of course, cost of sales will depend on the top line development <mark type="indiscernible" /> (23:04)...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On top line...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> Which is difficult to say (23:05), and it's not just the pure online investment, this is as Jyrki said, all the long-term related investments, including the new offering, the broadening, et cetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'm sure. Okay. And then just one final one. Just, on the balance sheet, there's new cash you call, capitalized expenditures, that's coming about SEK 631 million. Can you just give some color on what that is, is that in any way linked to online?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's one part of it, it's online, it's our long-term investments in online, IT, et cetera. And the IAS accounting rules say that we have to capitalize those costs when we are in a development phase. So it's IT systems, et cetera, that has to be capitalized.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And in previous years, I presume there would have been similar costs going through for IT expenditure, was that previously being expensed through the P&amp;L or was it being held elsewhere within your fixed assets or...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we didn't have any such capitalized expenses, because we were more in a research phase when looking at our &#x2013; and then those costs has to be expensed in the income statement. But when we are moving to development phase, then the IAS rules states that then you have to capitalize those costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fantastic, very clear. Thanks very much, gents.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from <mark type="indiscernible" /> (24:44). Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon, gentlemen. A question on your ForEx and the impact of the U.S. dollar to euro currencies. Could you maybe help us understanding your hedging dynamics and if currencies were staying at current levels through the whole year, what kind of an impact should we be looking at for 2013? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we start with the transaction impact, depending when we buy, place orders today and most of that is done in U.S. dollars because around <mark type="ph" /> 80% (25:25) of the sourcing is done in Asia, where we still pay most of the garment in U.S. dollar. And of course, if the dollar is more expensive compared to the euro that is a negative in the short-term, and vice versa. And right now, I think that the currency is about the same level as last year, perhaps slightly less expensive. So if they stay like this, that's pretty much neutral going forward, but since we hedge continuously, theoretically, you can say that what we buy today, you will see in the figures, let's say, four, five, six months from now in the P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>And then you have the translation effect, which is of course, when we translate all the results from the subsidiaries into SEK and if the SEK has appreciated as it has now, that will be a negative effect from this compared to last year because we get less top line and less profit when we translate to SEK. And right now, the SEK is stronger compared to most currencies, compared to euro.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the transaction impact, could you isolate or help us isolate the impact last year on your gross margin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>While it varies from quarter-to-quarter, but we said that the combined effect, currency transaction effect and cotton prices, et cetera, were negative for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Anne Critchlow. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Anne Critchlow from SocGen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Are the current investments you're making going to allow you to roll out online after you've rolled out in the U.S. more quickly than you might have done otherwise?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's the idea, yes, but we are very cautious to give you a date, but that's of course, the intention to roll it out as quick as possible, but still with high quality.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could we expect a country after the U.S. within a year after that perhaps?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, if we've learned something, we're very humble with dates, but of course, it's in our own interest to launch it as quick as possible, but I promise you, we will come back to you as soon as we have something new to tell you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. Then just very quickly, CapEx guidance for the current year? Sorry, if I missed that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's somewhere between SEK 7 billion and SEK 7.5 billion for 2013, but you have to remember that this is just an estimation. We have to remember that we haven't signed a lot of contracts that we are planning, so it can differ, up and down during the year, but we will come back to that later during the year if we see some significant changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from J&#xF6;rg Nowicki. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, perfect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Loud and clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My first question is actually a question I've been asking you for years, but I'm not giving up, because you never gave me an answer. Can you give me a figure on how much turnover H&amp;M is doing online through its <mark type="ph" /> mail-order business (28:52)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you said &#x2013; asked the question and it's a good question, and my answer unfortunately would be the same. However, I can give you some more flavor perhaps, and it is of course that online is becoming more and more important for the industry, and of course, for H&amp;M, that's why we invest even more in online and we just launched the mobile-adapted site two weeks ago which has been very well-received and we are looking forward again to the U.S. launch this summer. And as we said before, we are investing a lot to be able to roll out online sales in all our markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is growth rate <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:32)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Unfortunately...for competitive reasons, we don't break out the different parts. And also, I think it's very important we talk about the multi-channel strategy and it's all linked, the online and the retail numbers. I mean, a lot of customers they go online and they buy something and then they maybe go to the store and return it, they buy something in the store. So what is online and what is retail, it doesn't really matter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Overall, the growth rate online is the same as the general growth in the market in online <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:05)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you say again, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is your growth in online business the same as or in line with the growth rate of online business in general?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I didn't get it. The growth rates in the industry for online?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>H&amp;M, by doing its online business, is it about the same growth rate as it is for the market in general, for fashion retailing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we don't break out the different parts, but I mean, as in general, of course, online sales are growing faster since they started from a lower &#x2013; from almost nothing 10 years ago. And of course, I expect that online sales will become even more important for the industry and for H&amp;M going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question. International retailers like Mango and even Bestseller, they work on their prices, they're offering now lower prices. And then, of course, there is the incredible success of Primark. Is H&amp;M working on lower prices, how do you maintain the prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will always look with our customer offering, it's not all about price, it's a combination of price, quality and fashion. And also we are focusing a lot on the sustainability part as well. So we will keep to our business idea to have the best combination of this and that we will speak to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When exactly is &amp; Other Stories opening, can you tell us? And then you were mentioning two stores in Germany, I only knew about one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there will be two in Berlin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One in Kurf&#xFC;rstendamm 234 and one in Neue Sch&#xF6;nhauser Strasse 15, sorry for my German.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's okay. And they will open simultaneously, like all the stores will open <mark type="indiscernible" /> (31:47)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, but they will open during the spring. We don't have an exact date yet, sorry. We'll come back to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Rebecca McClellan. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, good afternoon. I've got a couple of questions, please. Firstly, can you confirm, in the fourth quarter, you talk about comparable store OpEx to sales ratio deteriorating, partly because of sales, but the suggestion is, is that the comp store OpEx is inflating on a year-over-year basis. Could you give us the sort of like-for-like OpEx inflation, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't want to quantify, but of course, there is always an OpEx inflation when it comes to indexations for rents and also salaries, but they vary from country-to country and of course, over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's the reason why we are planning for increasing like-for-like sales every year, because as Nils said, there is an underlying inflation, but we have been managing to keep a good cost control and react on the sales figures, but in the long run, of course, it's important that we have a positive like-for-like.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, but is your operating breakeven about 1% or 2% like-for-like then, more or less?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't want to give such a figure, because it's too stiff, it's not flexible enough. We always work with the improvements in efficiency, et cetera, so that figure can vary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've proven historically where we have &#x2013; I think it was two years ago, we had minus 5% like-for-like through the year and we managed to balance that very well by being more efficient in the stores. So, I don't want to give such a fixed number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then my next question, please. When you talk about broadening the product range, could you just sort of give me an example of what you mean by that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course. It could be adding a new concept like we did a couple of years ago with H&amp;M Home or Shoes, but it can also be to broaden an existing concept or format that we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So it's just &#x2013; okay. And then finally, can you confirm that &#x2013; could you confirm if the group level is <mark type="ph" /> 100 (34:12) what is the China sales density in comparison to that <mark type="ph" /> 100 (34:15)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's lower.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>By a noticeable amount or just marginally?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's up to you to estimate, I give you the &#x2013; it is lower because the recent market is still premature, but it's developing quickly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Fraser Ramzan. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I actually wanted to come back to these investments through the gross margin and in OpEx on new concepts and online. You said that the investments will continue going forward and you also said, they will have a higher level in 2013. Can you confirm that the investments you made this year were not sort of one-off, start-up costs in nature but instead ongoing costs you have to bear in the business, such as people. And can you sort of indicate whether or not in quantum, in SEK, 2013 is planned to be a bigger incremental number or the same number or less, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, coming back when &#x2013; if it's start-up costs or costs that will continue, it's, of course, a mix. Some of them are start-up costs, some of them will continue during 2013. And we don't want to give you any forecast how much it will be during 2013. But as we said, it will be on a high level still. We have investments, long-term investments that we will continue during 2013 and our assessment is that they will be on a higher level than in 2012. But we have to remember we have been investing a lot during 2011, 2012 but, of course, we will see future revenues as well. Up to date we haven't seen much of the revenues because...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you see online, but these are long-term investments which are necessary, and will build up a strong H&amp;M for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so to be clear, the SEK amount both in gross margin and operating costs will be a larger total in 2013 than 2012? Whether or not it's a lower percent of sales is a different question, but it will be a larger absolute amount?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, by definition, if we are expanding the SEK, in Swedish krona, <mark type="ph" /> which will mean (36:49) that will increase from year-to-year when we are continuing our expansion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but you're not necessarily saying, it will rise as a percent of sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's depending on how the top line is developing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator instructions" />. Your next question comes from Simon Irwin. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, gentlemen. Could I just come back, I'm afraid, on your gross margin guidance one last time. And simply because you're talking about relatively flat input costs. Now obviously we &#x2013; given what you were saying about your hedging policy on the dollar, first half, we can then be reasonably confident that they adverse dollar movement will be high single-digit negative. Therefore, which <mark type="indiscernible" /> (37:50) buying terms then are a similar magnitude positive? I'm just intrigued by which part of these dollars costs are coming down still.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to be clear, we haven't given any guidance when it comes to gross margins. What we said is looking at those, maybe three or four main external things, cotton prices, cost inflation, U.S. dollar, we see that those all together have a neutral effect on the purchases that we have done for the Q4 and also for Q1. But how the gross margin will develop, that's totally up to the decisions that we will take when it comes to our customer offering. So this was not the guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>These three, four isolated main input factors that we were commenting on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Point taken. And just &#x2013; I think it's been a couple of year since you initially signaled that you were prepared to invest in price in order to drive top line, obviously, kind of selectively market-by-market, et cetera. And kind of two years in, do you think that that investment has paid off and do you expect to continue to do so given that you're like-for-likes are kind of broadly tracking flat at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're absolutely happy with the decision and we will continue. I mean we're always &#x2013; we're very long-term as you know. But of course, and we always strive to work with improvements, starting with the customer offering, whether how much we invest, meaning taking the markdown down, that's another question. But at the same time, we work with efficiency gains, et cetera, et cetera.</p>
          <p>And yes, the consumer environment is very demanding and very difficult at the moment and I think last year, the 11% increase in top line has improved. Again, we're on the right track and it's going the right direction. The customers appreciate what we do. But for this year, we still think it's going to be very demanding, but we have a great belief in our offering and what we do and actually see potential not just for this year, but for many years going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and just one final question in terms of stores, given that your store expansion now includes four smaller formats going forward, how should we think about your average store size? Is that going to start declining as these smaller formats make up a larger number, percent of the whole, or are they still going to be too small to influence the overall kind of average square, kind of impact from new space?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that could vary &#x2013; if you look at &#x2013; talk about 2012, the average store size is actually somewhat larger. So, the smaller formats hasn't had any greater impact yet, but who knows about the future. And then another thing is, that even though they might be smaller in square meters, they're not necessarily smaller in top line, if you have a strong sales density.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Fine. And just the final point, in terms of depreciation, presumably that capitalized depreciation number goes into the pot for the current year and you're also talking about an acceleration in CapEx in the year ahead, so should we be thinking about that depreciation line starting to move ahead fairly rapidly over the next couple of years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, of course, the capitalized, the intangible assets that we have in the balance sheet SEK 600 million of course, when we are starting to depreciate, of course, it will, but I &#x2013; it will not be a dramatical thing. So &#x2013; but of course, when we are starting to take and use those intangibles, so of course, the depreciation will be there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Tremendous. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Richard Chamberlain. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks. Good afternoon, everybody. Just &#x2013; so just a follow up on Simon's question. On depreciation, why did depreciation go up so much in the second half, please? Was that to do with those large long-term investments you were talking about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, partly, but the main reason is as you probably have seen in the previous years as well, during the first, second and third quarter, we are doing calculated depreciations and then when we are ending up the year in Q4 then we are calculating it more exactly, and all the effects will land in the fourth quarter. So that's the reason, but looking at the yearly level, it's increased by 13% something, but that's the way we are doing it and all the corrections when it comes to depreciation are done in Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. Okay, thanks. And just another quick accounting one, why was the cash tax paid figure this year so much higher than the P&amp;L charge for last year, well in this year, actually, but the amount of cash tax is quite a bit higher, is there a reason for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. If you look at the effective tax rate for instance, we have some tax receivables in the balance sheet and that's due to &#x2013; that we have made accrual funds this year due to the lower tax rate. If the Swedish tax rate has gone down from 26.3% to 22% and in Sweden you have the possibility every year to set one quarter of the Swedish profits to accrual fund to postpone, it's kind of an untaxed reserve. So therefore, this year the paid tax has been higher.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see. So what's your effective tax rate outside Sweden at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It differs very much. From Ireland I think they have 12.5% to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But on a blended basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's somewhere between the total average as you see in the income statement. The blended average is more or less what you see here in the profit and loss.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Around half of the profit are taxed in Sweden.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Got it. Okay, thanks. And just one on, again on the gross margin. I was just reading the statement, it looks like you're expecting a lower level of markdown in the first quarter and I wondered why that was. Is that just because of the base of comparison or should we assume that you are planning a lower level of markdown for the full year and will be running the business accordingly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, what we stated in the report, in the Q4 report, our best estimate for the first quarter is that we will, as a part &#x2013; as a relation to sales, that the reductions will be on the same level as in Q1 last year. But of course, that's our best estimation. If you remember last year, we said in connection with the year-end report that we had a little bit too high stock with winter garments and that ended up in Q1 with a 90 basis points more reductions compared to Q1 2010.</p>
          <p>So, what we say now is that our best estimate at this point is that the &#x2013; it will be a neutral effect on the gross margin compared to last year's first quarter. But as always, we still have one month to go and looking at the market, still a lot of reduced garments on the market and of course, if the market is starting to aggressively making campaigns and having killer prices, most probably we will also follow that. And also the turnover, it's really tough and it's dependent also if we don't get the good sales development during February, then, it will not, most probably be flat compared to last year, then, it will increase. So, but it's still too early to say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay, but just to be clear, you were planning a lower level of markdown in Q1, were you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We are planning our best assessment, our planning is to &#x2013; that we will end up on the same level as the previous year as a share of sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'm with you. Okay. All right. Yeah, thanks. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, no, it's a neutral effect on the gross margin <mark type="indiscernible" /> (47:03).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But what I said just, that's &#x2013; that can be different after February.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I know, sure. Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Nicklas Fh&#xE4;rm. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. I also have a question on accounting in the quarter. I was looking at the accounts payable in terms of days sales, I just noticed that they're now down about 10% on a full year basis to around 12 days versus 14 days last year, my question is &#x2013; sorry in 2011, and my question is then is, are you giving suppliers better cash flow terms and in exchange for that perhaps being rewarded with lower purchasing price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't go exactly but there has been no dramatical changes, so. Of course, we always &#x2013; it's part of the negotiations with the suppliers, but nothing dramatical change compared to last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, perfect. Thanks. And just the final question, which I think have been touched on before, but anyway. Are you saying basically, just for the record, that given your store, given your expansion mix in terms of store concepts that we should except a similar space conversion rate in this year as in 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Same answer as before, we don't see any, no dramatic changes in space conversion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Peter Farren. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All answered for me, thanks. Although, I &#x2013; just quick maybe follow up on the OpEx. I was wondering if you could tell us if assuming 11% currency-neutral growth in 2013 is reasonable? I mean, I've heard everything you had to say, basically a yes or no answer I'm looking for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you probably know by now we never give any forecast regarding these kind of figures, more than saying that we always have a very tight cost control and very cost-conscious in the Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks and then regarding tax rates for 2013, is 24% a reasonable assumption?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We want to be cautious when it comes to the tax rate when showing the tax rate, calculating it for Q1, Q2 and Q3. And then we will make the final calculation in connection with the year-end closing. As for 2012, we use 26% during Q1, Q2, Q3 and ended up with 24.3%. So, we want to be cautious and we'll use 24% as a tax rate during Q1, Q2, Q3. And most probably, as it looks now, we will end up in a lower tax rate than for the whole financial year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Andrew Hughes. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's Andrew Hughes from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Just going back to cash flow, where the last two years we've seen quite significant cash outflows. Should we see that as you still being relaxed because you've got SEK 17 billion left or a little bit more concerned on the basis that you might be looking at other metrics or the scale of that outflow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's correct what you say, but still we have a strong financial positions within H&amp;M and have the opportunity to take the opportunities which comes up and also it shows that we are continuing with our high expansion rates. We have the long-term investments, et cetera. So we are confident that we have the opportunities to continue being best and expand in a really good, rapid pace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So if conditions did remain difficult, you'd be happy to run with another cash outflow, at least in the current financial year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't go &#x2013; of course, looking into the future, it's really difficult to speculate about that, but I think that the main point is that we have a good financial position and continue our long-term investments, that shows our strength in really tough macro environment during 2011 and 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay. And just one follow up. I think you mentioned a couple of times that markets are more promotional, are there any particular countries where that's been the case. Is it Southern Europe or is other markets where you've had to follow with more promotional activity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, we're running the business <mark type="ph" /> times (52:05) 48 different markets. It's very difficult for us to specify in each market. In some countries it's been worse and in some others maybe not as tough. So, I don't want to go into detail for each market, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Any comment on the top six markets, then? Okay, we don't need &#x2013; we don't need a comment on all 40.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd rather &#x2013; what we give is the consolidated or the aggregated view that we have for the Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But the picture is that the activity is on a high level when it comes to markdowns on more or less all the markets. And I think the reason is that it's the same global players in most of the countries and everybody faced a tough macro environment. But of course, going into detail, there might be some markets where it's a little bit tougher. And of course, Southern Europe, the macro environment is, of course, much tougher than in maybe Northern Europe, but most retailers probably also have adapted the inventory levels to tougher conditions in those markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Richard Jaffe. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. And just a follow-on regarding the U.S. Internet business and its upcoming launch. Will the online offerings duplicate what we find in stores? Will it actually be a broader assortment than we find in stores? Give us a sense of the strategy for online in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. The current online store we have in eight countries have around 50-ish, 50% plus of the total assortment and I don't think the U.S. will differ dramatically from that. But this is something that's continuously developing and who knows about the future and it's still some months to go before we launch in the U.S. But at the moment it's not 100%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is the capacity in the U.S. sufficient to allow for some flexibility from that 50% level? I know you spent some time building out the infrastructure here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What kind of capacity? Are we talking about SKUs, no. What kind of....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, SKUs in your distribution portfolio to have a broader array of offerings. I'm sure the electronic platform is scalable to accommodate more. I'm wondering if the decision were to ramp up the offerings, if that is a possibility, fairly seamlessly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's definitely possible to do it, but there are lots of different things in the equation and that's the reason why we don't have 100% yet. But as I said the development is going in that direction. We have &#x2013; couple of years ago, it was just maybe 25% of the total collection. Now, we are more than 50%. So it's increasing year-by-year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very good. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Chris Chaviaras. Please ask you question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, guys. I had one question actually, again regarding your kind of longer-term thoughts on the investments. So, I was about to ask when the investments in the IT and the online capabilities will annualize, but then you said that you are going to continue with those. So I was wondering, are there any big projects that we should be aware in the next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are &#x2013; <mark type="indiscernible" /> (55:57), there are lots of different projects and some of them will be launched and we just, as I said, we launched, two weeks ago, we launched the mobile-adapted online site. And actually today, we launched online sales in our 18 countries for Weekday. So there will be deliveries throughout the year. And when it comes to new projects, who knows? But there is nothing that we have communicated as of today, but I hope that there will be new projects going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But then, <mark type="audio gap" /> (56:32) seems that, given that you had built this one-off investment, these will annualize and then the level of investment will fall just because the big projects are out of the way until for now, isn't that a fair assumption, no?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, but as we said, for 2013, we see that these long term investments, of course, some of them will be annualized but some of them will continue but looking aggregated, the long term investments in 2013 will be on a high level, and an even higher level than 2012.</p>
          <p>Of course, in the long run, who knows in 2014 or 2015, but as Nils said, we most probably will have always long-term investments. But of course, now we have really much bigger, the online is one big that we have, looking into IT systems, IT platform, et cetera. But still for 2013, the long-term investment level will be on a high level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for that. My other one is on the profitability of the online model. I know you don't split it out, but are you happy with the profit that these generate? Are you totally indifferent of whether the incremental sale comes from the online platform or comes from your store?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are very happy. It's very profitable and we said it's in line with retail operation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from <mark type="indiscernible" /> (58:15). Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I'd like to follow up on first COS, Collection of Style, what is driving their success and how do their metrics differ from H&amp;M? And just secondly, the expansion of the store network that you've been having globally, what benefit do you see from it in terms of economies of scale? Does it help in terms of store opening costs, advertising and real estate? And just lastly on design collaborations, they've been an element of your success and what are the plans for 2013? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. See if I remember, first one was COS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we said, we are happy with COS and the development and then we also made an exception to the rule and we commented that the profitability is also very high, it's in line with H&amp;M already. The reason for the success, again, I don't think there is just one, but the customers they love it, and I think the combination of fashion, quality and price in higher price segments are very successful. And there is a great demand for COS in &#x2013; actually globally today, I would say, so we're very happy about that.</p>
          <p>Your second question was &#x2013; could you repeat again, please? Expansion related?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. What benefit to the store does the expansion of store network provide in terms of economies of scale, store opening cost, advertising, real estate, as you open more, do you get more leverage on occupancy cost? Are occupancy costs lower as you're more important to developers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course, we get economies of scale and we are &#x2013; if you start with the brand, H&amp;M, we are today a global brand and very highly rated. We top &#x2013; ranked by the top 20 brands in the world, which of course, gives us a lot of advantages when, not just that customers ask for our products, but also the landlords they want us as anchors, we're an important tenants. Of course, that gives us a strong negotiation position.</p>
          <p>And then when it comes to other synergies, of course, we have processes for opening stores for refurbishing, et cetera, et cetera. Everybody, every company wants to expand, but it's easier said than done. And we do it every day. We open literally one store per day this year, and on top of that, we refurbish even more. So we get a lot of the economies of scale by expanding the way we do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just design collaborations, what are you expecting for 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are very happy with the design collaborations we've done, and the last one was Margiela, very appreciated again by customers. And we always try to come up with new things. The next design or the next collection we are very proud to present is the Conscious collection that we will launch in March and it's made by our own designers and we expect it to be a very big success again. And of course, the Conscious collection is made by sustainable material and you can read more about it on the website.</p>
          <p>When it comes to external design and collaborations, I mean, we never talk about them really, so much in advance because we want them to be a future. So we will see. We want them to be a surprise, sorry, so we will see in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Your next question comes from Omar Saad. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thanks for all the information, it's very helpful, guys. I wanted to ask a quick question on inventory. It seemed like it popped up a little bit in the fourth quarter relative to the sales growth, relative to kind of the change you historically see, the seasonal change from third quarter to fourth. Do you have any thoughts on that, big picture?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, you shouldn't see it sequentially, you should see it year-by-year &#x2013; year-on-year, and it's the same level as last year compared to sales. But already, as Jyrki said, last year was higher than expected due to the, just  really warm autumn in 2011. And unfortunately, we had a &#x2013; we didn't increase sales as much as planned this autumn 2012. Again, so the level is somewhat higher than planned and thus the reduction we talk about, that they will probably be &#x2013; remain about the same level as last year, which were higher than the year before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. Thanks. And then, just quickly back on the online opportunity, as you think about really building out that business globally, does it change the way you think about your store openings and kind of long term, how many stores you can have in the marketplace? Do you think of it holistically, total sales to the consumer, through both channels? And could you see eventually if online becomes ultimately very successful as kind of a slower physical store growth rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I know that there is a lot of talk about this in the industry and I'm sure in the long term that will probably, could happen. But for us, no we're not there yet. We see a big opportunity to continue the physical store, bricks-and-mortar rollout and we see that the channels really complement each other in a very good way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Last &#x2013; and really quick lastly, any thoughts on the dividend this year, didn't see it bump up last year, but historically you've been very kind of consistent dividend growers. Any thoughts that you're hoping to raise it again this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The dividend, it's a question for the board of directors and finally for the Annual General Meeting. So, the board of directors they have made an assessment based on our dividend policy and that is that the company should have financial strength and continued freedom of action. So, I think this is monitored in the dividend proposal for the Annual General Meeting to be held in April.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Erik Karlsson. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Thanks for taking my question. First of all, thanks very much for launching an iPad-friendly app now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I already bought a shirt and it works very well, very nice app. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So an online sale increase today. Thanks for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You bet. Just a quick question, how do you feel your price competitiveness is at the moment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's good. I mean &#x2013; and we see that in customer service that we do regularly, and but of course, it can always be better, that's why we always work with improvements. But we are happier today than we were in the past because we have &#x2013; we are working with continuous improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>[Operator Instruction] Your next question comes from Rebecca McClellan. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there again. Just to confirm that the SEK 7 billion to SEK 7.5 billion CapEx that you sort of guided towards for 2013 compares to SEK 6.8 billion in 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's not the SEK 6 billion, it's the SEK 6.8 billion, yeah?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Simon Bowler. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, gents. Sorry, just a quick follow-up from myself. Just you've mentioned the revenue uplift to come through from long-term investments and obviously, we've got some visibility now on when we should get some revenue uplift from the new brand, when we should get some revenue uplift coming through from online in the U.S. in particular. And it sounds like these other long-term investments that you're making within, the amount you're putting in, I was just wondering what the timeframe is around seeing any uplift or your hopes around seeing any revenue uplift come through from any other investments that you're making?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We hope to come back to you during the year about the other, but so far we have nothing more to, but we are working with different things and probably not anything this &#x2013; that you will see anything this year, but hopefully next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Very clear. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Fraser Ramzan. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Thanks for taking my question again. Sorry, just to bore on about these SEK investments in the gross margin and cost. When you say you expect the total amount of increase this year, are we talking 10% or 100%? Because if it's 10%, then obviously, it's not going to go up as a percent of sales unless your like-for-like is negative, but if it's a 100%, then it's really important and we need to know about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, we prefer not to quantify the amount, but &#x2013; sorry for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> How long is this stream? (01:07:25)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And is it very different in quantum between the SG&amp;A line and the gross margin investments in terms of the absolute amounts of increase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's &#x2013; as we are working with the functional profit and loss, some of the long-term investments will be on the cost of goods sold and the other parts will be distributed between sales and administration cost, so. But exactly &#x2013; we wouldn't like to go into exactly how much is coming in and affecting the gross margin and how much. And it differs from quarter-to-quarter, so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. So &#x2013; sorry, this 10% point, I mean, you were opening 10% or thereabouts small space. It's quite important that we understand that it's not 100% because obviously that would have a very serious impact on your margin. At the moment, you're just saying you're going to spend more money.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, agree?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, but as I said, it will be our normal expansion and that will continue during the year. And hopefully also, the online investments will give some revenues when we launch U.S., et cetera, so. But exactly how much that will effect this year of sales or the increase in &#x2013; but I think, we are comfortable that we have a really good cost control and these investments that we are doing, they are necessary and really wise to do. So I wouldn't put any dramatics in this, but the guidance is that they will continue during 2013, but no dramatic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, I mean, if you thought it was going to significantly affect your margin in any way, you would of course flag that too because it would be material, yeah?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, of course, if we see something during the year, we will of course comment on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But not right now, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do give you the information and we will continue and the investments will increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Nicklas Fh&#xE4;rm. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys, again. Just one final thing. Would you &#x2013; for me, would you care to give us some idea of how &#x2013; of approximately how store expansion will look this year, the 325 net openings on a quarterly basis, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's pretty much the same pattern as 2012, I would guess, that's my best guess. But there will always be differences <mark type="ph" /> in the pattern (01:10:18). If you look at the numbers right now, I think we already have more stores this year in the beginning of Q1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe a little bit more considering that we will open up &amp; Other Stories during the spring, et cetera, but nothing dramatically compared to last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no further questions registered at this time, sir. Please continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just one correction before I close. I think I mentioned the wrong figure for SG&amp;A for the full year in SEK, they increase by 10% and not 12%, I think I said that. Sorry for that.</p>
          <p>And then closing remarks, thank you all very much for participating in this conference call, very long one. And we'll come back for the first quarter results on the 21st of March. Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That does conclude our conference for today. Thank you for participating. You may all disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>