<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1175168" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-09-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9513</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Nils Vinge, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2">Richard Chamberlain</participant>
      <participant id="3">Leif Persson</participant>
      <participant id="4">Nils Vinge</participant>
      <participant id="5">Richard Edwards</participant>
      <participant id="6">Robert Miller</participant>
      <participant id="7">Tony Shiret</participant>
      <participant id="8">Anne Critchlow</participant>
      <participant id="9">Lisa Berwin</participant>
      <participant id="10">Andrew Hughes</participant>
      <participant id="11">John Guy</participant>
      <participant id="12">Geoff Lowery</participant>
      <participant id="13">Michael Kaye</participant>
      <participant id="14">Anna-Karin Envall</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Hennes &amp; Mauritz nine month report.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. I would now like to hand over to your host for today, Mr. Leif Persson, CFO and Mr. Nils Vinge, Investor Relations. Please go ahead, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Welcome to this telephone conference on the occasion of H&amp;M's third quarter results. The slides used during the presentation are found on our website, hm.com. With me is our CFO, Leif Persson, and we will answer your questions after the presentation. Please turn to the slide, Nine Months 2008.</p>
          <p>Sales excluding VAT increased 12% to SEK 62.2 billion. The increase in local currencies was 11% while comparable unit sales were flat.</p>
          <p>The gross profit was 38.1 billion, corresponding to a gross margin of 61.2% compared to last year's 60.6%. The operating profit was 13.3 billion and the operating margin was 21.4%. The profit after financial items increased 9% to 14.1 billion and the net profit rose 14% to 10.2 billion.</p>
          <p>During the first nine months of the year, we opened 85 stores and closed nine.</p>
          <p>In May seven Weekday-stores and 13 Monki-stores were added to the store count as the acquisition of Fabric Scandinavien was finalized. In total, there were more than 1600 stores at the end of the period.</p>
          <p>Looking at the third quarter, sales excluding VAT increased 12% to 20.9 billion. In local currencies the increase was 10% and in comparable units sales decreased 1%. August sales increased 8% in local currencies and decreased 3% in comparable units. Given the market situation in Q3 the profitability was satisfying with a gross margin of 60.8% compared to 61.2% in the same period last year. The operating profit was almost 4.4 billion and the operating margin was 20.9% compared to last year's record level of 20.6%. Profit after financial items increased 4% to 4.6 billion and the net profit was 3.3 billion.</p>
          <p>The quarter was affected by generally weaker retail sales and increased price competition in most markets. Despite this we continued to gain market shares. The decrease of the gross margin was mainly due to higher price reduction but price inflation in our production countries and higher transportation costs contributed as well. These effects were partly offset by lower buying costs due to a weaker dollar.</p>
          <p>Our efficient and flexible buying model which allows us to act promptly and adjust accordingly to the market situation together with more active price reductions has paid off. Our stock-in-trade was 5% lower compared to the same time last year. The size and the quality of the stock are very good with a higher proportion of new autumn garments than a year ago.</p>
          <p>The operating margin was lower than last year's, mainly because of a slightly lower sales development but also due to preparations for the strong expansion in Q4. This in combination with a strengthening of the organization for long-term expansion also affected the margin. Costs come before sales.</p>
          <p>We continued to work with all initiatives taken last year. The efforts we put in are long-term, regardless of today's business cycle and continue to build for the future. The target is as before, to increase the number of stores by 10 to 15% with maintained high profitability.</p>
          <p>During the quarter an H&amp;M store was opened in Egypt, in Cairo, and the reception has been as good as in our other franchise countries. Our footwear range sold well and the development of COS, H&amp;M Home and the recently acquired Fabric Scandinavien continued. Expansion of Internet and catalog sales runs very well. We firmly believe in all our initiatives and that they will contribute to make H&amp;M even stronger.</p>
          <p>Looking at sales per market, Germany, our largest market, continues to grow. Activity throughout the rest of the year remains high with many new and refurbished stores. Internet and catalog sales are important complementary sales channels that keep growing. The UK has declined in relative size due to the weakening of the British pound, but sales have performed well in Q3, increasing 17% in local currency.</p>
          <p>We continue to build our presence in Southern Europe. Spain, Italy and France are markets where we're growing. France, with over 100 stores has become our second largest market. Several interesting contracts have been signed in Q4. In Paris for instance a store on Boulevard Haussmann and last week we got green light to open an H&amp;M store on Champs-Elys&#xE9;es.</p>
          <p>In Sweden, as in the other Nordic countries, we have continued to gain market shares despite slow retail markets. In North America, we've seen good sales with increases in comparable stores. We continue to broaden our presence on the West Coast and we have opened stores in Seattle, Washington.</p>
          <p>We're proud of H&amp;M's successful establishment in China's fast growing regions, Hong Kong and Shanghai. And we've extended our reach to the Jiangsu area near Shanghai, where we've opened our first stores. We are also pleased with the progress of the franchise stores in the Middle East.</p>
          <p>Looking at some key figures. The stock-in-trade decreased 5% to 7.9 billion. The decrease is partly an effect of more active price reductions in Q3. But we are starting to see a payoff from the investments in the logistics organization which has led to more efficient allocation of goods. Stock-in-trade in relation to sales was 9.3%, a historically low level which we are very pleased with.</p>
          <p>Cash from current operations was almost 12 billion or 2 billion higher than last year. We continue to invest, so far in 2008, we've invested almost 3.1 billion. Our financial position remains very strong which enables us to take advantage of opportunities that arise. Liquid funds and short-term investments were almost 17.8 billion and the return on equity was 50.7% compared to 48.8 last year. The activity level this autumn is high. We opened far more than one new store each day. To put this in perspective, the increase in stores in Q4 alone will exceed the number of stores we opened during the entire year of 2003 and that is only five years ago.</p>
          <p>We expect a challenging autumn but it also creates opportunities and we have the resources to take possibilities we see. Historically we have not been that much affected by the business cycle and we have gained market shares. As we've seen September so far sales in local currencies up to and including the 28th of September have increased 9%.</p>
          <p>The happening of the autumn is no doubt H&amp;M's entry into Japan. Our expectations were highly set and they have by far been surpassed. The opening in the fashionable shopping district, Ginza in Tokyo is H&amp;M's most successful opening ever. Customers kept queuing up several days after the opening. The media attention was enormous.</p>
          <p>We are proud to include Japan on the H&amp;M map. So far we have signed contracts for four stores.  The next opening takes place on November 8 in another of Tokyo's best shopping districts, Harajuku. In conjunction with this opening, we will launch the designer collaboration with the world famous Japanese designer Rei Kawakubo, a founder of Comme des Gar&#xE7;ons. So far our launch in Tokyo has had a fantastic start and we are looking forward to the next steps.</p>
          <p>We're looking forward to an exciting autumn, an autumn where we prepare for the first step into Russia next spring. Already in September we opened the first franchise stores in Bahrain and Saudi Arabia and in November we opened the first store in Oman. The planned net addition of stores in Q4 is 114, mainly in Germany, Spain, the US, France, the UK and Italy. In China the expansion continues in Hong Kong, in Shanghai and in the Jiangsu region. The location is as always exciting.</p>
          <p>To conclude, our aim is to increase sales with maintained profitability. Our business concept, fashion and quality at the best price lies behind our international expansion, it's valid in new markets and to new offerings. A number of stores is planned to increase to by 190 stores this year. On top of this we should add the 20 stores through the acquisition of Fabric Scandinavien.</p>
          <p>In Q4 we are opening stores in four new countries and we are preparing for Russia in 2009. And we continue to develop our customer offerings with the new collections, new concepts and new products. We are looking forward to an intense autumn.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention. We are now happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question comes from the line of Richard Chamberlain. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, good afternoon everyone. My company name is JP Morgan. I've just got a couple of questions to start with on the gross margin, please. I was a bit surprised at the gross margin so weak given that the like-for-like was a bit better than in Q2 and I just wondered if you can run through or give a bit more detail on the additional price reductions you talked about. Was that particularly in one region or was that particularly during the summer sale or concentrated in one particular product category? If you could just give us as much detail as you can on what &#x2013; on where those additional price reductions were?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Price reduction has been more or less on the same level in all countries and the month where the most reduction occurred was in July. There was of course reduction in June and August. When it comes to different categories &#x2013; there are of course categories which stands out but I'm not, I don't really think that we should disclose how they were in the different categories.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just following on from that, on the &#x2013; I've just got another question really on the Nordic region, obviously that market has got tougher and I just wondered if you think you are gaining market share on a like-for-like basis and whether there's a significant sort of difference in gross margin there that might be putting downwards pressure on the overall gross margin if that's &#x2013; since that region does seem to have gotten tougher?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you're right, it's tougher but you should also bear in mind that it has in other years been very, very strong so the comps are very demanding. Regarding gross margin there is no &#x2013; let's put it, there is no real difference between the different markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but &#x2013; okay. But on a &#x2013; in terms of market share, do you think you are gaining that on a like-for-like basis or really because you have got over 20 more stores there than you had this time last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our opinion is that we take market shares, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You should also bear in mind that the 20 new stores, they are relatively small compared to ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay, so the space impact is less, yeah, okay. Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Ben Swintooless. Please go ahead with your question, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. Yeah, it's Ben Swintooless from Citigroup. Just a couple of questions, firstly within your third quarter revenues. Can you just give us a sense of the contribution from the Internet and catalog within those? And secondly, just breaking down the gross margin, a sense of the quantum of dollar benefit within your third quarter gross margin and therefore residualizing what the impact of markdowns, source inflation and transportation is within the third quarter gross?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the, first of all we actually never disclose the cost of the selling which accounts from the mail order and I don't think we're prepared to do that just yet, but maybe will otherwise in the future. And when it comes to the gross margin and the U.S. dollar effect on that one we have first explained that a couple of times, but we are &#x2013; there is a dollar effect, that is 100% sure, but I don't think that we really should go in and try to explain it, I think we rather confused some of the estimates with that before, if you don't mind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay if I ask a slightly different way, what level of cost inflation on the sourcing side should we be thinking about in the year ahead?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'd really like to know that as well. It's very hard to, it's very hard to quantify and if you set a goal for that one, you will probably fulfill it as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a price inflation of course, is an effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Richard Edwards. Please go ahead with your question, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Richard Edwards from Citigroup. Yeah, two quick questions, one just going back to the gross margin, if you could give some idea of the extent to which markdown affected the gross margin in the last quarter? And then the second question was on cost inflation, looking at the two major cost lines in your P&amp;L, selling expenses were up 14.5% or something like that and admin up around 32%. Give me some idea what's driving those two trends and what we should expect for them going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, regarding the reductions, we've had an impact of about 1% point in Q3 from the reduction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When it comes to the cost of SG&amp;A, you are right we're between 14 or 15% increase. And we have a number &#x2013; as for the number of stores, which we're going to open this fourth quarter, it does much more in that. So I think we have some 25% in new stores and obviously a lot of the cost outs already incurred in the third quarter plus also of course that there are a number of new initiatives, which we have taken where we have the cost and we're still waiting for the big impact on the revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So should we assume on the selling expense line that the trend in the third quarter continues or actually fades from here in the sense that you've taken a lot of pre-opening costs through in the third quarter already?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A lot of the stores open in November and therefore have no revenue in or very little revenue in Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but just looking &#x2013; ignoring the sort of the revenue component, just looking at the cost growth trend. It's been volatile just going through this year. It was up 20% in the first quarter, 13 in the second, 14.5 in the third. If you're trying to call a trend going forward what should we assume for the fourth quarter and beyond?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't really give prognosis in that respect. But for me the volatility seems much more to be in the first quarter then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, just repeat that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We never give any prognosis, but the two last quarters have been relatively stable, 13, 14 or 15%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's great, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Robert Miller. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. The company name is Redburn Partners. Just picking up on the cost question, you have in the past talked about a cost of sales range of 37 to 38%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that something that you believe is achievable in the next financial year or has the benchmark changed for the business given these additional areas of investment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We said that historically the level has been for the last I think six or seven years been between 37 and 38%. And we also stated rather clearly I think that for one or two or three quarters that could deviate as well. And I think we also pointed out quite clearly that we are taking a lot of new initiatives. But as these initiatives pays off which they should do, then hopefully we should return to that level, that's our goal anyway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right okay. Could you tell me why the receivables number was up so much in the third quarter, is it all to do with the mail order business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It has a lot to do with the mail order, yeah. A big part of it is mail order and then there is also there some effects from the IFRS keeping the books and there is also some effects from VAT. There are also some VAT effects from the way that we keep the stock today, we're keeping it in a global buying company and that also had some effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and finally can I ask about dividends because the, like it or not, I think investors now think of your very high rate of return of net income as a normal dividend rather than a normal plus a bonus. Can you, with that in mind, can you remind me what the metrics are that you think about when you're judging your excess capital?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are some key figures, which we need to keep on the, and as you know the policy states 50% plus of this cash and that is how much we can guide you today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But what are the metrics?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't really like to go into that in detail, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, we're in the dark?</p>
          <p>[Laughter].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And can I just finally ask with regards to the stock position, what does that tell us about your budgeting for sales in Q4 and the Christmas period, are you very cautions about the demand particularly in Europe for the calendar Q4 period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think that we are cautious although the stock we have today does seem to reflect the point of the end of August, so we are constantly buying now, and so we are seeing goods flowing into the company. But what you said is of course that going into the season we will have that of course, a much fresher looking freight than we had last year. That's what this figure implies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Tony Shiret. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Tony Shiret from Credit Suisse. Regarding the gross margin markdown of 100 basis points, I just wondered, could you tell us what your average selling price was going into the season? And could you sort of give us some idea about whether you think this sort of margin attrition is going to be a sort of feature going forward? Was it sort of a fact that you over-ordered or do you feel you have to invest more in price going forward to achieve a reasonable level of sales and market share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As &#x2013; it's rather a tough question. I don't think that we really disclose our average selling price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You have actually in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, what was it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But the average selling price is on the same level as last year. It's actually two points down from the year before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, 2% lower than, okay and that was the full price once before you marked down, was it? Full price sales?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was both, that was both. That was before the markdowns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And so, you basically ended up with too much stock and you marked it down or did you feel your pricing was wrong and you repriced intra-season?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have been, as everybody else reacting in the market if the competitors are marking down we have to expect the same thing, otherwise we will lose the selling and be left with too much garments in the end. So it's a market where you have to look, and you look at all the competitors and you react accordingly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, to finish that part of the question, do you expect in the future that you're going to have to invest that sort of level of margin to drive an acceptable level of sales growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Depending on what the competition is doing, but I have foreseen that a lot of the competition will be a bit more cautious going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. So, that means yes, does it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't necessarily say yes to that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, moving on. Just on the Internet and home shopping business, looking at the Netherlands sales performance over the last two quarters if you strictly store growth out of it, it looks pretty flat. Is it the case that the online home shopping business in the Netherlands has stopped growing after the initial period and can you describe why that is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, our knowledge, it hasn't &#x2013; it certainly hasn't stopped growing. Our experience &#x2013; our view is that the online catalogue is developing very well. And of course the question is, is there cannibalization, which is of course impossible to measure. For &#x2013; there might be of course, but we think the most important thing is that the overall sales developed faster than the costs and that is very satisfying in Holland.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so you're in profit in the Netherlands on online?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what sort of similar levels of profitability to the stores or significant...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we've stated last year in Q2, the margins in online catalogue are in the same region as in the retail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Julie Shauzia. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Julie Shauzia from JP Morgan. You managed very well in Q2 a difficult and volatile business delivering increasing gross margin and you ended the quarter at that time saying your inventories were of good quality, so you were not hinting for this markdown impact in Q3. So if it all came from August &#x2013; well first, can you confirm it all came from August? And then if that's the case, can we see similar development as we've seen in Q2 where you end up the period with actually a good result, you just take your hit early, but make up for it later on? I mean, can you explain what's different in August versus what you've done in Q2?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, when we get into the quarter we make adjustments of how our book in trade looks compared to last year. But you &#x2013; so we never know what's going to happen when we exit or come into the quarter and we have to react as I said before to what the market's doing. And we did that and I think, looking at the circumstances I think that the result is on a very good level. You could also say that the markdown has been, is of course in every month, but the majority of it was in July, not August. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, but so, if it was mostly the summer sales then you should have known when you reported, you know, your Q2 results and at that time you were quite confident that your inventories were of good quality, I mean you sat and you did not hint for this markdown impact?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have two comments to that. Number one, we don't give any prognosis and number two, I think we reported on the 21st or something like that in June. So we didn't know what was going to happen in July and August. I don't see how we could. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Anne Critchlow. Please state your question, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello it's Anne from SG. Hi, you mentioned some discounting in August, and within that, was there a significant amount of autumn/winter products, as in new products?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, nothing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And how do you rate the success of the autumn winter ranges so far, say compared with last year? Because you have had many good seasons recently.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Looking at the garments and the garments how they are selling. If we were to look in the beginning of August, of course it was not very good. But that was due to of course the weather, and last year was extremely calm, this year was extremely warm. I think in the last two weeks of September, of course the winter garments, also now winter garments was performing very nicely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Lisa Berwin. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Lisa from Retail Week. I just wanted to ask you about some of the new formats that you have been doing, particularly the divided format that you tried in Camden and London. And I was just wondering how that was going and if you were wanting to roll that out further?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually I think we said that the divide is not a new format. Divide is quite a old format.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean new to London as standalone concept.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The divide is part of the H&amp;M family. I think it will offset in terms of &#x2013; I don't know I presume 98 in terms of the divided shares selling in normally. We have actually tried out a newer concept in some places. It will always be a part of the H&amp;M family.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But my question was as a standalone concept, is it working well where you opened and would you roll this out further?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, this is something, which we have to look a bit more. At the moment it's not really a topic for us to roll this out in a big way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And how about COS, how is that doing for you in the UK?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are comfortable with the development, and we will actually open the second store in London this autumn. But you know it takes time to develop an entirely new concept.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And where it open, the second store?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It will be in the new shopping mall called...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In Westfield, London.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And are there any more openings in the UK this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding COS or H&amp;M?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just your whole portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, there will be a number of new stores in the UK in cities like Bristol, Leicester and also in Dublin in Ireland et cetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so how many, sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am sorry, I don't have the number, but we see a lot of opportunities going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and can I also ask, have you been &#x2013; in the last couple of weeks, have you seen any particular nervousness or drop in foot fall because of the sort of more worldwide banking crisis? Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yeah there's been <mark type="inaudible" />. In some parts of the UK there has been some reaction to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What sort of reaction?</p>
          <p>[Laughter].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know what would happen, going out like we used to see before. We don't like to comment on one single month or one single week or one single country. And we see it much more <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean do you see it on a wider basis as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if you look at Q3 in UK we actually saw a positive like-for-like despite the conditions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Andrew Hughes. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon gentlemen. It's Andrew Hughes calling from UBS in London. Just going back to the currency issue, if we assume that the dollar doesn't move from here, which quarter will show up the first impact of the strength of the dollar allowing for your forward cover? Is it going to be Q1 or Q2 next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I think we stated &#x2013; I think it was stated last time that when we hedge the orders we have something like 14, 16 weeks from the orders to actual delivery. That is the time gap.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so we could actually see some impact in Q4 as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just going back to the inventory issue as well, do you think that you've got too little stock at the moment with that 5% decline? Do you think you'll miss some sales as a result?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we don't think so. We actually are quite sure that we have a very good level of stock allowing us to take in a lot of new garments in the season. And we are quite confident that we'll be able to respond to the market situation there. I think we have a very good situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Eric Hustead. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My question has been answered. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Then our next question comes from the line of Masa Isogai. Please go ahead with your question, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes sir, Masa Isogai from ABPS, New York City, U.S.A. So first, congratulations on the great success of opening your first store in Japan, Ginza.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And my &#x2013; I have two questions. First, how many stores do you plan in Japan in approximately three years or five years time span. Number two question what are the special characteristic features of Japanese market compared with other countries? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, first question the number of stores.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our strategy always when we enter a new market is to start with a couple of stores and learn the market and the behavior. So, right now we have opened one store and we have contracts for three more stores to come. And then what's going to happen in two or three years, it's too early to say, because as I said, we have a deep respect for Japanese culture, and we need to learn the behavior before going forward. That was your first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the special characteristic feature compared with other countries?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that is exactly what we need to learn now from the first store. So it's too early to say at this moment. But we know that the Japanese customers are very fashion conscious...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as you say the reception so far has been overwhelming.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We have another question from the line of Richard Edwards. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, just a follow-up question on input price inflation and what you might instinctively choose to do with that, should it emerge in a bigger way next year? I think in the past you've always alluded to the idea that you'd seek to pass that on to the consumer, I guess with the caveat that your competition is doing something similar. Given the nature of the environment we are in and arguably going into next year, is that still your instinct or do you read this as a more difficult environment whereby you'd have to take the pain in the growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so, I think we always have to react to what the competition is there and so there is &#x2013; and if that &#x2013; if there is continuously price inflation in the Far East. We have to look at what is the competition doing. We have to try to be better at negotiating ourselves and we have to do a number of things. So it's extremely hard to say what will actually happen in half a year or a year from now. I would say it's impossible because some of these sectors we can influence ourselves and some we can't. So it's very hard to say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what's your experience in the past been of putting prices up? I mean in &#x2013; given we've had deflation in general in the clothing market across Europe for a number of years now, is &#x2013; do you read putting prices up as a credible idea in the current environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, when you put it like that, it doesn't sound very logical to put it up given the current volume. We don't know what the competition is going to do. We don't know and you have a lot of other factors. You have quality, etcetera.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean are there any reasonable examples of periods in the past where you and I guess the competition have put prices up successfully? What sort of macro conditions did those happen in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know how much I like to speculate on this at the moment because for us it's not &#x2013; doesn't bring us anywhere. We have to watch what's happening on the market and to sit today and comments or put something upfront...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am very, very sorry about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No problem. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of John Guy. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon gents. It's John Guy from MF Global in London. Just really following on from that question, with regards to the levels of underlying cost inflation you expect there for the end of this year, will that roughly track similar to last year of around 3% or you are expected to see any material change from last year's?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't quite &#x2013; yes, could you repeat the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure. Really just with regards to the underlying cost inflation. Last year that was running at around 3 to 4%. Are you therefore factoring in a similar level of cost inflation for the end of this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we take &#x2013; you are referring to the cost inflation and when it comes to the garments. Am I correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I could guess something but we have to watch all the time what's happening and that is negotiating every single order and if it &#x2013; and we have to see what comes out of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, just to be sure, you're saying that you may see cost inflation, garment cost inflation of between 3 and 4% but that's subject to negotiation on specific lines. And then if I'm looking at your...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would definitely not represent that on this one. Definitely not, because we have to look what varies on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So if I'm looking at the level cost inflation within say, your selling expenses or your admin expenses, can you just give us some sort of guidance as to what you expect to run through this year compared to last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But that would be equal to giving it for prices, and we do not really do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Geoff Lowery. Please go ahead with you question, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, it's Geoff Lowery from Dresdner Kleinwort. A question on the German market, if I may. Obviously we can see your headline sales growth, and I'm quite interested to understand your perspectives on the competitive environment particularly in the light of what Esprit have been saying about some distress amongst independents and what we can see about the department stores generally struggling to get supply. Has there been a gross margin issue for you in Germany as others clear in particular, or is it more Europe wide phenomena?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Germany as a market hasn't really been that worriful for a number of years. And possibly it's even worse today than it has been before though we have seen a lot of sales coming and going in Germany from where we have been there, but we do have a formal with, it's very suitable for all sorts of customers. And so we bring value for money and that's what this offer us in Germany and we're thankful too that we were able to sell in this environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I may a second one as well. In terms of your lease or rental cost evolution into next year, presumably both the space pipeline and distress amongst others means that rent inflation is coming down for you into 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Where it will land in 2009, we don't have &#x2013; I don't actually know but of course that's the rent. The rent levels are very much further of the demand and as players are leaving the market then the demand is probably going down. If players are coming the demand is going up. So we have -- simply have to look as what's happening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Michael Kaye. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, it's Michael Kaye from Bellman Walter. I wanted to ask a question about transportation cost going forward and on the basis of where things are today in terms of dry bulk shipping costs and the oil price, what's your outlook for transportation costs over the next few months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I probably know as little as you, but as you say of course it's a function of oil prices but also of supply and demand. So as you look past couple of weeks it has actually come down a little bit but it's impossible to say going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have another question from the line of Robert Miller. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, I just wanted to clarify your response to the answer about currency. Did you imply that you've not actually been more aggressive with your dollar purchases and that effectively you're covered, it sounds like, up to the end of January, but you've not bought further out than that. Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No sorry. That is average. The 14, 16 weeks, that's an average.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is much shorter and much longer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So &#x2013; but put in another way, you've not &#x2013; given the trends in the currency, you've not been more aggressive with your dollar hedging than in normal times.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have another question from the line of Richard Chamberlain. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot, just had a couple of follow-ups actually. I just wondered in terms of the geography of your sourcing, whether you're starting to move away from China now? Presumably that's where a lot of the cost pressure is, and more towards places like Cambodia for the knitwear and so on and Bangladesh. And then just second I just wondered if you can just tell me how many Weekday and Monki-stores you're planning to open in Q4 and also next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No so that's a big shift. So when it comes to where we are producing the garments of course and we are present on all these markets in the Far East and can shift if necessary. But there has been no big shift so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No big shift so far, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And looking at Fabric, of course we're looking at expansion as one very important thing, but it's, and we see a great potential, but it's too early to give any concrete plans yet. But there has been one Monki store opened in the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our next question comes from line of Anna-Karin Envall. Please go to your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Anna-Karin Envall calling from ABG Sundal Collier. Can you please clarify the gross margin issue for us one more time, because it seems like, if we actually do the calculation on the hedging even if you take 14 to 16 weeks, it seems like you should have had a positive dollar impact of close to 150 basis points in the third quarter. And then you're also stating that you have a marginal impact from cost inflation. How large is marginal impact and what is the rest, is it the strengthening of the Chinese currency on top of the cost inflation if you referring to transportation or what is it? What do I miss here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you &#x2013; I think maybe we missed a lot of things, because we could also add things like quality, we could add, we could add a lot of things. Also we don't, I think we tried to say that, we don't really like, agreeing to the dollar effect, because we will only be cautious because there are so many different ingredient there. We've pointed out from our point of view the biggest impact and that is the reductions. I am sorry, yeah. That's the way it is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But it seems like 100 basis points in extra markdowns compared to last year, it seems like we're missing some basis points there if you look at the historical trend here over the past quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If we include that let say that report...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We lost you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me gentlemen, she has actually disconnected from the call, so there are no further questions. So I'll hand it back to you for any closing remarks. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for participating in this conference call and we welcome you back for our full year results in January. Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect your lines. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>