<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1301846" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-04-08</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9513</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Nils Vinge, Head of Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst">Karen Howland</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Jyrki Tervonen</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Richard Edwards</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Richard Chamberlain</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Fraser Ramzan</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Fred Bjelland</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Luca Solca</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Tony Shiret</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Peter Farren</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Simon Irwin</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Henrik Fr&#xF6;jd</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Peter Brockwell</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Anna-Karin Envall</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the H&amp;M Three-Month Results Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode until we conduct a question-and-answer session and instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Just to remind you, this conference call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand over to Nils Vinge, Head of Investor Relations. Please begin your meeting and I will be standing by.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Welcome to this telephone conference on the occasion of H&amp;M's first quarter results. The presentation slides are found on our website, hm.com. Our CFO, Jyrki Tervonen is with me today and he will be happy to answer your questions after the presentation.</p>
          <p>Before moving on to the first quarter, I'd like to give a brief comment on the sales development in March, the first month of our second quarter. Our spring collections have been well received. We are especially proud of our Garden Collection, which is made using organic and recycled materials. Sales in March were strong. Sales including VAT increased 21% in local currencies and comparable unit sales increased 9%.</p>
          <p>The positive sales development in March should however also be seen in the light of a positive calendar effect of approximately 2 percentage units, and the fact that Easter occurred one week earlier than last year. The Easter effect will be reversed in April, which also was the strongest month last year with a like-for-like increase of 8%.</p>
          <p>Now, over to the first quarter, please turn to the slide, first quarter 2010. Sales excluding VAT reached 24.8 billion in the quarter, an increase of 7% in Swedish kronor and 13% in local currencies. Sales in comparable units increased 2%. We regard sales in the quarter are satisfactory in view of the continued weak economy.</p>
          <p>Gross profit increased 17% to 15.4 billion, corresponding to a gross margin of 61.9% compared to 56.6% last year. Currency hedging of the market on internal sales to the subsidiaries had a positive effect in the quarter on the gross margin of 80 basis points. In the first quarter last year, the gross margin was negatively affected by currency effects of 420 basis points in total, including hedging of the internal flow of goods and the un-hedged part of the purchases.</p>
          <p>Increased markdowns had a negative impact on the gross margin of about 160 basis points compared to last year. We'd also like to remind you that to us, the gross margin level as such is not a target. Our aim is always to deliver fashion and quality at the best price. The gross margin is affected by up to 25 to 30 different factors, some of them positive, others negative that varies over time. For competitive reasons, we wish not to go further into detail by how the different factors are impacting our gross margin.</p>
          <p>H&amp;M maintained a good cost control also in the first quarter. Selling and administrative expenses were 10.4 billion, up 6% in Swedish kronor and 12% in local currencies compared to the first quarter last year. The increase is related to the expansion.</p>
          <p>Operating profit for the quarter rose 48% to nearly 5 billion that corresponds to an operating margin of 20%. Profit after financial items reached about 5 billion, a rise of 42% from the year before. And net profit increased to just about 3.7 billion corresponding to earnings per share of SEK 4.52.</p>
          <p>We continue to grow and we see plenty of room for expansion ahead, for H&amp;M as well as for COS, Monki, Weekday, and H&amp;M Home. In the first quarter, we opened 10 new stores and we closed six. At the end of February, we had 1,992 stores, of which 37 franchises. H&amp;M is now present in 37 markets.</p>
          <p>In the second quarter, we plan to open 6 to 7 stores net. Most of the openings will take place in the UK, China, Norway, Denmark, and Germany. Scandinavia and Germany were among the best selling markets in the first quarter. In Germany, sales grew 11% in local currency compared to last year. In Poland, where we have 65 stores, sales were also good in the quarter. Further east in Russia, sales have developed well since our successful start in Moscow a year ago. We now have stores in Moscow and St. Petersburg and plan to open more stores in those cities in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Meanwhile in Southern Europe and Ireland, the situation has been tougher. The UK had a good quarter with sales up 16% in local currency and we are looking forward to the launch of Internet sales there in the autumn. In the US, sales have strengthened, although from weak comparables. This spring, stores have opened in two new markets, South Korea and Israel. The opening of our first store in Seoul in February and the two franchise openings in Tel Aviv and Jerusalem in March were very successful, so was the opening in Osaka in Japan, which was a milestone as it was store number 2,000.</p>
          <p>H&amp;M has become one of the strongest brands in the world, something that you really can feel in our new markets. I had the pleasure to witness the strong interest in H&amp;M at the openings in Seoul and Tel Aviv and it was fantastic to see how thousands of people were lining up ahead of the opening.</p>
          <p>Sales in Asia were strong in the quarter and we see great potential in the region ahead. In all three of our markets, China, Japan, and South Korea, many people are interested in fashion and their purchasing power is strong.</p>
          <p>This autumn, we will open the first COS store and the first Monki store in Hong Kong. Monki and Weekday continued to expand. In May, the first stores will open in Finland on Helsinki's best shopping street. And in August, the first Monki store will open in the best location in Amsterdam in the Netherlands. Interest in our first H&amp;M Home store, which opened in Stockholm last autumn has been very large. The number of customers has exceeded our expectations so far. Therefore, we will open more H&amp;M Home stores. We will do so in Helsinki, Copenhagen, and London this autumn. And we are looking for more locations for H&amp;M Home in other markets, where we already offer Internet and catalog sales.</p>
          <p>That was a few words on our markets and expansion, and now over to some key figures. The stock-in-trade was 8.4 billion, a decrease of 7% compared to the same time last year. The decrease is mainly related to currency translation effects. We consider the stock-in-trade well composed. The level is good and adequate to support the expansion and positive like-for-like, which March clearly shows. In relation to sales, the stock-in-trade was 8.2%, historically low level.</p>
          <p>Cash from current operations was approximately 5.4 billion compared to 1.2 billion last year. The increase can be explained by higher results, lower stock-in-trade, and lower preliminary tax base.</p>
          <p>Investments amounted to around SEK 700 million, which is almost 500 million lower than last year. Part of the decrease is due to the strengthening of the Swedish kronor and the fact that we are also opening fewer stores in the first half of this year. Our finances remained very strong, liquid funds and short-term investments amounted to 26.2 billion. Return on equity was 41.4%, compared to 39.4 rolling 12 months.</p>
          <p>Finally, in view of the continued challenging markets, we delivered strong results for the first quarter of 2010. Looking ahead, we maintain a positive view on our future expansion. We will continue to expand to new markets and see room to grow also in existing markets. To us, it is important to grow with quality. We always try to do what is best for our customers and for H&amp;M in the long run. Our target remains to grow the number of stores by 10 to 15% per annum with continued high profitability and to increase sales in comparable units. We will also continue our work of making our customer offer even more attractive.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention. We are now happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from the line of Karen Howland. Please go ahead announcing your company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Barclays Capital, thank you. I was wondering if &#x2013; I know you're not going to give clarity as far as the gross margin, what was contributing to the gross margin? I was wondering, though, when you talk about the 80 bps of gross margin improvement that came from the currency hedging, is that off of the 56.6% reported or the 61%, if you adjust for the 420 negative last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's the 80 basis points from the internal hedging, if I understand your question correct, that was &#x2013; been a positive effect on the gross margin compared to last year's first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is that compared to last year's first quarter, the reported number of 56.6% or last year's reported number of 61%, which is then adjusted for the negative impact of the currency last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is in relation to the first quarter this year's sales, excluding VAT.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. I'm sorry. I must not be being clear. The 80 basis points improvement off of the gross margin from last year, I'm just wondering just what that base gross margin was for last year, was it the reported number or was is it the number adjusted for the negative impact of FX?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, if looking &#x2013; I'm not sure if we understand your question correctly, but last year, the gross margin of 56.6 percentages was affected negatively from the internal hedges and also the un-hedged. And the negative effect last year on the gross margin was 420 basis points. And this year, we report gross margin of 61.9 and that is affected positively from the internal hedges by 80 basis points this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the 80 basis points of improvement, it sounds like is off of a more normalized run rate of 61% as compared to the 56.6%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there seems to be some misunderstanding. The 80% this year, we have been helped by the hedges, so it lifted the gross margin this year was 80 &#x2013; without the hedges this year, it would have been 61.1 or something this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that compares to 61% last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well last year, it was negatively -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Affected, so it was 56% &#x2013; 56.6% with the hedges.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To be exact 60.8.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so 60.8 normalized compared to 61.1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, perfect. Thank you. And then the gross margin, I know, again, you're not going to give the &#x2013; what's going to be driving the different pieces of it, but that improvement that we saw, I guess that 30 basis point excluding any FX headwind or tailwind, as well as offset by the price reductions of 160 basis points. Is there any reason that's not sustainable in the second and third quarter of this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we have said many times, the gross margin in itself it's not a goal for us and it's also affected by several, several different factors. We have mentioned that during, for instance, this first quarter, we have had positive effects from the spare capacity amongst the suppliers, also raw material prices, transport costs, and also our internal efficiencies that we have done in our buying process.</p>
          <p>And, of course, when the situation in the macro environment is changing hopefully to the better, of course, those spare capacity issues will also be normalized and how these different factors affect our gross margin and how we use them that we want to keep to ourselves for competitive reasons, of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Richard Edwards. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi. Richard Edwards from Citigroup. It was &#x2013; quick also I get on the gross margin, just the currency stuff. Just to be clear, last year, the gross was adversely affected by 420 bps due to total currency impacts, not just the internal hedge, but all currency-related impacts. What was the equivalent number in this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The equivalent number, if you wanted to adjust for this last year negative FX that was then as we said 60.8 percentage units and this year the internal hedge affected the gross margin positively by 80 basis points, so corrected with that the underlying gross margin is 61.1. But, of course, then we also have the markdowns, which was around 160 basis points negatively compared to last year. So if we're also correcting for them then of course we are up to 62.7.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, the question was not about markdowns, it's simply currency related.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that the plus 80 bps is just the internal hedge as I understand?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is correct <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Whereas the 420 bps is internal and external hedges from last year. And the question was, was the total currency impact in the first quarter this year internal and external hedges, just currency?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We haven't &#x2013; the external, if you're referring to the theoretical dollar effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a negative effect in this fourth &#x2013; first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, again, there is some confusion, because last year there was also around 300 bps from the unhedged part.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And this year that was not material.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. It sounds like if that wasn't material and you had an adverse impact from the theoretical dollar impact, then is it fair to say that the net of the internal hedge actually didn't have any benefit at all in the quarter from currency, i.e. internal was positive, external was &#x2013; the dollar hedge was negative, the two offsetting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we haven't been exactly calculating the theoretical negative dollar effect in the first quarter, but yeah it seems quite reasonable maybe that those two are offsetting each other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Richard Chamberlain. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Afternoon gentlemen, it's Richard Chamberlain from BofA/Merrill Lynch. I just had a couple of questions, please, on different markets.</p>
          <p>So you've seen a recovery in the US and I wondered if that's kind of consistent across the US market or is there still a big difference between performance on the East and West Coast?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We talk about the US as a whole. We don't &#x2013; prefer not to go into detail per state.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I was just wondering, so geographically between West and the East Coast, I know you've had some challenges on the West Coast over the last sort of 12, 18 months, so is that now recovered?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's roughly the same across the nation and we see -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The same development across.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just turning to Spain, can you say how many stores in Spain you expect to open this year, and how you intend to improve your sort of relative performance in that market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't &#x2013; if you look at per market, we &#x2013; it's still approximately &#x2013; we still see a lot of potential, but I don't have the exact number for Spain.</p>
          <p>But even though it's still a tough market, we still see that things are starting to &#x2013; going in the better direction and we're very pleased with the team we have in place. And we &#x2013; the customers appreciate what we do and we have made &#x2013; the customer services approve that H&amp;M has a very good positioning and we look forward to go into the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you. And just &#x2013; sorry, just finally, can you just say what average selling prices have done during the quarter, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's roughly the same. Nothing -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No big changes or impacts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Fraser Ramzan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there, good afternoon, it's Nomura in London. Just a question really on expansion, could you just reaffirm what number of stores you would anticipate opening in the year ahead and where you're seeing the opportunity, because obviously you have reiterated a fairly aggressive space expansion goal today again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The number we stated for this year &#x2013; the approximate figure we said is around 240 and most of them will be in the US, UK, China, France, German and Italy. But we actually see potential in all markets, even in Sweden where we've been for more than 62 years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it the market environment, are you finding it easier to find stores that meet your return criteria, which remain pretty good overall returns?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, it's the contrary. Last year, we did &#x2013; initially we said 225, it became 250 and of course that was &#x2013; lot of that was the result of the macro environment. One of the reasons was that competitors were in trouble and they gave us opportunities to take over their contracts. And also there were a lot of the new projects that were speeded up. So that's why we came out with 250. Some of them were actually planned for this year, whereas this year it's the other way around really, because a lot of the new malls initiatives have really slowed down this year as a result of the financial crisis and a lot of the competitors, I mean, they don't have any plans to open this year or maybe they'll start to expand against it. It's actually looking more difficult this year than last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if I could just ask one very quick cheeky question on top of the two, the non-H&amp;M format, what proportion of your overall space are they now and I'm sure it's pretty small, but is it material as yet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, it's still marginal. Of course, we hope they will become much greater, but they are still in initial phase, but looking good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Fred Bjelland. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon guys. It's Fred from Morgan Stanley. I'm sorry to go back to the gross margin again, but I was just wondering, if you could &#x2013; you didn't make a comment this time about what the internal hedge effect for the second quarter might be, I know it's tailing off and I was just wondering, if there will be an effect in the second quarter as you see it today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's correct. We ended the internal hedging and we estimate that Q2 that it will be tailing off. With these currency rates, we think it will be still a positive effect, but less than in Q1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just to be clear, the effect last year in the second quarter was negative 130 basis points, is that right for the unwinds as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I don't remember, it was exactly 130, but something like that, yes, and it should unwind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, if I could also just quickly ask on CapEx, I mean, clearly you've highlighted the fact that the strength in the Swedish kronor is helping you in terms of your CapEx. I mean, are you guys still comfortable with the 6 billion guidance, or should we be looking for reduction there as space gets more cheaper in local currency &#x2013; in your own currency?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we have been discussing that and maybe after the first quarter, it's too early to say anything. But, of course, we will come back in connection with the Q2, the report, if we see that the appreciation of the Swedish kronor is going on and then it might be that we will go down in the CapEx for the whole year. But as it seems now we will still stick to this 6 billion. But as you said, it can be, of course, affected by the strengthening of the Swedish kronor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And perhaps coupled with that, I mean, you had a pretty big working capital outflow last year. I mean, are you expecting a decent inflow this year, which if CapEx is put down again, I mean what kind cash flow generation or working capital movement are you guys expecting for the year now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, it's very difficult to forecast. It all depends on how the collections are received and how the sales are developing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well perhaps asking in a different way, I mean, your inventory is at a very low point now, I mean do you expect to rebuild inventory or is this something we should be looking to extrapolate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The inventory or stock-in-trade level that's a snapshot or a momentary picture of the stock-in-trade as per end February, and that of course can change within one or two weeks quite substantially and we also have to remember that stock-in-trade of SEK 8.4 billion, that's several, several weeks of selling and we are confident that the level &#x2013; and it's also well composed, and I think also the March figures shows that we had a lot of &#x2013; enough of garments to really have a good March in the turnover.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Luca Solca. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello, it's Luca Solca from Sanford Bernstein in London. Couple of questions, if I may.</p>
          <p>Sourcing costs for spring/summer 2011, coming back from China and having talked to apparel manufacturers there, there is the labor cost inflation issue that they are facing. And as you were pointing out before, capacity utilization has been going up. And you have raw material cost inflation.</p>
          <p>How do you see the environment for yourself shaping up for spring/summer 2011? Do you have, you think, headroom and room for maneuver to offset these negative trends?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's correct that you say that we've seen a trend of raw materials, transport costs and also capacity, normalizing since the end of last year. And, of course, this is neutral for the completion &#x2013; for the business, then how we can handle this, this is something we prefer not to tell our competitors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. In terms of sales in your different geographic markets, do you experience any difference in terms of which part of your assortment has been rebounding and providing the best performance? Is the enterprise points or the higher price points, do you see a mix shift of any kind across geographies, especially I was thinking about markets where the H&amp;M brand stands very strong, especially the new markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually we don't. It's been across spending on concept and price levels and now, I'm sorry, we don't see that trend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And as this year is going to be probably a turning point as far as the new concept developments are concerned, what is the fair assumption as far as the space growth percentage that we would have to look at rather than the full number growth, because I think this is probably going to be affected by the fact that some of your new concepts are actually smaller in size than the average H&amp;M store?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's true that the new formats are smaller and there has been some worries about that this would worsen the &#x2013; bring down the space conversion, but if you look at the figures, so far this year, it's actually been improved. So it all has &#x2013; it has to do, of course, with how the H&amp;M stores, which is still by far the majority, it's more than 90%, how they will develop.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the space growth guidance that you gave for 2010 in terms of percentage points is around?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The long-term growth target it remains the same. It's 10 to 15% number of stores.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And this year, we've guided 240 stores net approximately.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, which in space percentage terms would equate to, in your assumptions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's roughly the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So &#x2013; okay, I see all right. Thank you very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Tony Shiret. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It's Tony Shiret from Credit Suisse. A couple of simple questions. First of all, relative to the comp store sales growth of 2% you've disclosed for Q1, can you tell us what the full price comp store sales growth was for the quarter? That's the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, Tony, but I'll have to admit I don't really understand your question. What do you mean by full price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You've sold &#x2013; presumably you've got a markdown impact on your gross margin and you've cleared a whole lot of stock -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the like-for-like sales probably had a higher proportion of discounted sales in them versus full price. So I just wonder what the full price like &#x2013; the sales were in like-for-like stores?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't really look at it that way, but we haven't given you the &#x2013; how much the discounts have affected the gross margin; that was 160 basis points. But, if you ask &#x2013; if you want to know if it's markdown driven, is that what you're asking for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I just really want to know the number, so I could sort of form my own conclusion, I mean, you can answer that question if you want, yeah, is it markdown driven?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not really. I mean part of it, perhaps in December and January, because we increased markdowns, but not dramatically, no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fine. And sort of related question, when you last spoke on the quarterly, you were talking about essentially investing in price in the current year. I just wondered if you have, in fact, invested in price and if you could give us some sort of quantification or if you could give us some sort of idea of like-for-like pricing and ASPs, that sort of background detail?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As &#x2013; what we did say and do say is that we invest in the customer offer and it could be reduced prices, not necessarily, it could also be increased quality or more value for the money. And yes &#x2013; but, of course, for competitive reasons it's well not to quantify it. But I think that &#x2013; clear that the customer reaction has &#x2013; the response has been good and hopefully it will continue like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Has there been investment in price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it has, not just in value, not just in quality. And actually in terms of the like-for-like prices and the ASPs, you've given those in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, your last question, did what...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Like-for-like prices and ASPs, you've given us those details in the past?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, in the first quarter I mentioned it was roughly the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For both? For both like-for-like sales &#x2013; like-for-like prices and ASPs, yes, some are trading up, not trading down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not really.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Peter Farren. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. It is Peter Farren from Bryan, Garnier in London. Just one question left, it's regarding your hedging policy, which you changed then in December 2009, and I was wondering whether we could expect a positive dollar impact in Q2 given that the dollar actually weakened both in Q4 and Q1 versus the kronor?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we expect a theoretical positive dollar effect in Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And it was negative in Q1 here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Simon Irwin. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Simon Irwin at Liberum Capital. Just if you take the Home business overseas in terms of store growth, does that mean you'll be launching catalogs in these new markets to go with it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well we are &#x2013; the H&amp;M stores will primarily be opened in countries where we already have online and catalog sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. That's obviously not the case in the UK, will there be a catalog to go with it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Initially it's going to be only online, but then...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it will be online; we will start in autumn this year with the online selling.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, but the catalog?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that we will see &#x2013; that we haven't &#x2013; been decided yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And so the &#x2013; the overall online offer, you can't say yet whether there will be a catalog to support it with the clothing offer or the Home offer yet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not in the initial stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And in terms of timing, can you offer any clarity yet as to when in the second half of the year you will be opening up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will come back to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Henrik Fr&#xF6;jd. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Henrik Fr&#xF6;jd from Swedbank. I have just a question regarding the March sales figure.</p>
          <p>You had mentioned that there was a positive calendar effect of 2%, and you mentioned that the Easter had moved and the weekend have actually moved in April, but I just wonder if you could quantify what kind of Easter effect you have seen in the March figure, or is that included in the 2% calendar effect you mentioned?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's on top of the two, but it's very difficult to quantify.</p>
          <p>Because this year Monday, Tuesday, and Wednesday of the Easter week was in March and then the rest was in April. And those days were quite good. But you also have other effects such as salary, you have weather or whatever that can effect. And we have the Garden Collection, which was very well received etcetera, etcetera.</p>
          <p>So &#x2013; but our best guess is that it was positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. But you cannot put the number on it, or you cannot explain how much of the sort of Easter sales that are due to weekend and the week before?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, but of course it will reverse and be negative in April.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay, good, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Ward Davis. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Most of my questions have been answered, thank you. But I guess just from a question earlier &#x2013; you mentioned that you are going to see some negative impact from cost of goods inflation from inflation in labor, inflation of cost of goods.</p>
          <p>What's the right way to think about the timing aspect of that? Is that going to be something that we won't really see this year, it will be more of an impact next year?</p>
          <p>Or when will we start seeing &#x2013; and also as another way of answering that question, what benefit are we getting year-over-year today from the still effective deflation rolling through, where we had labor deflation and excess capacity in Asia? And how is that flowing through now versus when are we going to start seeing a bit of a headwind?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. To start with the timing and the possible effects when the capacity, for instance, and raw material prices are being more normalized and increasing. It's hard to say exactly, but it should be in the &#x2013; maybe in the end of Q4 and the beginning of next year.</p>
          <p>But as we stated several times, that's one or a couple of factors affecting the gross margin. And there are plenty, plenty more factors. And they can work to the positive way when it comes to gross margins.</p>
          <p>But if you're isolating those inflational factors, then it seems more realistic that it will be in the end of the year and maybe beginning of the next financial year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Peter Brockwell. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, just a couple of questions. Firstly on the USA numbers, obviously, encouraging recovery sort of coming through there in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>I just wonder if you could maybe sort of talk about what merchandise changes and/or price changes that you put through there to drive that result? Or was it purely a sort of weak comparative macro story?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a combination of many different factors. The macro, in our view, is getting &#x2013; is improving, but as you said, it's coming from a very low comp. Last year was very bad &#x2013; weak, as you know.</p>
          <p>But we always work with improvements, constant improvement, and it comes through everything from merchandizing, pricing, customer offering. And hopefully we see some of the results coming through now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. I mean, can you be more specific in terms of the merchandise changes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not really, I'm afraid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just a second question, <mark type="inaudible" /> question. But just in terms of segmental reporting. I mean you've got this slightly odd situation where sort of group function that you bear accounts for over 110% of overall company EBIT.</p>
          <p>I just wondered, now that you've ended the hedging of internal markups to subsidiaries, are there any issues there in terms of transfer pricing and subsidiary tax rate? I suppose putting it another way, is the 26% tax rate sustainable? Are you completely happy with that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, coming back to the segment reporting and the background for this, we changed the transfer pricing in 2007, and it's according to the OECD guidelines for transfer pricing with the arm's length principles, et cetera.</p>
          <p>And reason for doing that is of course that it's the legal framework for different governments also to have their fair share of taxes, and also for the global and multinational enterprises to avoid double taxation. So that's the background for the transfer pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, okay. In terms of the countries that you operate in, I mean, presumably most of the local tax authorities, they're absolutely happy with that. There is no issues at all, then, sort of, is there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we have &#x2013; went into this based on the OECD guidelines. And together with our tax advisor, we are confident that this is adequate model that is working.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Robert Miller. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I just wanted to ask for a progress report on China. You've been there a couple of years now, and I just wondered whether &#x2013; what your view is on the productivity of that market? Is it a market where you think you can generate premium returns on sales and capital employed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are quite happy with the development in China, and that's why China this year will be among the most important expansion markets for us. So I think that speaks for itself.</p>
          <p>But it's fascinating how, as you mentioned, we entered China &#x2013; it was 2007. And already this year, our stores in Asia, including Japan and South Korea and Russia, they amounted at SEK 1 billion this quarter.</p>
          <p>So that's quite a big number. And it's growing fast. I think that was 85% more than last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And a separate second question on COS, has there been any some material change to the format since you launched it? And what sort of size of store are you going for now, when you open?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have improved a lot of things, which is normal when you launch a new format. But it's according to plan. We're quite happy. And we are step-by-step improving things.</p>
          <p>We had 24 stores at the end of the year, and this year, we plan to open another 12. And the first &#x2013; so we have 23 stores. And the first store in Hong Kong is planned for this autumn.</p>
          <p>And when it comes to size, it's roughly the same going forward. Around 4 or 500 square meters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a follow-up question from the line of Richard Chamberlain. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks very much. Just have a couple of follow-ups actually, please.</p>
          <p>Could you just say what interest rate you're getting on your short-term investment? I see in the balance sheet you shifted some funds away from liquid funds into short-term investment. Is that a much higher rate than liquid funds? Is it going to give a boost to interest income, or not really?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With the interest levels that we're talking about, it's no dramatic.</p>
          <p>But of course, the reason for putting money on the short-term deposits, we will get slightly a better interest. And we have them there because we will have a dividend payment here coming soon. And of course, we want to gain the best interest as possible, in accordance with our finance policy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And just on the Weekday and Monki formats in overseas markets, how does the pricing compare with pricing in Sweden?</p>
          <p>I mean, <mark type="inaudible" /> H&amp;M typically prices in the sort of 10% range, plus minus, to Sweden. Is it the same for the other formats, or is the pricing different? Are the pricing differences wider, greater?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we would aim for roughly the same price positioning, normally.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The same price positioning, okay. Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Nicklas Fh&#xE4;rm. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I just want to ask you if you can tell us a bit on the actual mix of countries that you source from. If you have any changes year-on-year, such as moving a certain production out of China to other countries. And in particular, if you have any such plans looking ahead into the remainder of this year? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as we talked about earlier today, Nicklas, the sourcing strategy is something that's constantly changing in both. We place orders every day and there is nothing dramatic in this.</p>
          <p>Roughly two-thirds of our sourcing is done in Asia and the rest in Europe still. And of course China is one very important market still, but it can change over time due to changes in fashion and currencies and other factors. But there are no big changes planned going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much, Nils. Can I also ask one more follow-up question? I just wanted to outline your thoughts on the inventory level. If you think it's actually a sustainable level that you have reached right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, as we said earlier, the situation, SEK 8.4 billion, that's just a snapshot, the situation in end of February.</p>
          <p>And the level, we are confident, is according to our plan. And even more important is that it's a good composition in the stock, and that is also the case.</p>
          <p>And we have to remember that we will have incomings, quite huge incomings every week here in March and April. And also the March figures show that we have &#x2013; that it's a level that we can handle even a quite good performance in the sales figure.</p>
          <p>So we are not worried at all when it comes to the size of the stock-in-trade.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Many thanks, Jyrki.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a follow-up question from the line of Peter Farren [Bryan, Garnier]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, just a couple of follow-ups. So, first, I was wondering whether you expect A&amp;P to increase as a percentage of sales this year. I just got the impression I've been seeing more advertisements in general in France and the UK?</p>
          <p>And the second one, just to -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, could we take one question at a time, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A&amp;P, could you please describe what that is for us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Describe &#x2013; advertisements and promotions. Mainly advertisements, that is, for you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We have said earlier that around 3 to 3.5% of revenues is spent on marketing, and we don't see any dramatic change in that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. And the second one, just to clarify on your favorite FX topic. In Q2, the internal hedging, so you expect a positive. Should I read into that positive and also an unwinding of the negative 130 in Q2? Is that what you mean?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, okay. Fine, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We do have a follow-up from the line of Tony Shiret. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, again, it's Tony Shiret from Credit Suisse. Just a couple of things from me.</p>
          <p>Bearing in mind that home shopping is going to get bigger for you, will you be disclosing what the contribution of home shopping is within comp store sales? And as a goodwill gesture, will you tell us what it was in these figures? That's the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When you say home shopping, you mean &#x2013; we say online and catalog sales, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, for us this is &#x2013; it's still a small part of the total business, even though it's growing.</p>
          <p>But for us, it's not so important to specify, because it's really just in one &#x2013; or different channel. The most important thing is that the customer finds what he wants. And since profitability is roughly the same in the channels, it's not that important.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think some of us think possibly it is a bit more important, and not so much for its own right, but well it tells you about the stores, possibly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So will you acknowledge that maybe we think it's more important than you do, and start to tell us what the contribution is at some point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We never ruled that out of course, but we'll just take that into consideration, I promise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'm 54 at the moment. Will it happen before I retire? [laughter] Okay. Dream on.</p>
          <p>Anyway, second question, just your comments earlier on about the sales trends across the quarter. Discounting in December-January, you did plus three, plus one, comp stores. And February, you weren't discounting, you were minus one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It just made me think, do you think that you have &#x2013; and I know that's old season, and new season started okay, but what have you learned about why you did so badly at sales last year, in terms of comp stores? I mean what have you changed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, of course, we were not happy with this minus five in comp stores last year, if that's what you're referring to. But you have to remember, it was one of the worst macro environments since many, many years.</p>
          <p>And I think it's not fair just to look at the like-for-like. I think you have to look at the total figures. And if you look at profitability, we still did quite good compared to the competition. And I think lot of &#x2013; in the market there was a lot of markdowns, but we managed to come up pretty well without making so many markdowns.</p>
          <p>And when you talk about February, I just want to remind you that, at least in Sweden and in most of our markets, actually it was very cold, extremely cold in February. And we had sold out most of the winter garments, and we had mainly spring garments in February. Who feels like shopping spring garments if it's minus 20? I don't know. Not me, anyway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Only poor retailers blame the weather, Nils. [laughter]</p>
          <p>Okay, fine. So you think you did all right last year, and you're doing all right this year, and nothing changes. Is that broadly what your answer is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can always do better, Tony.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question comes from the line of Anna-Karin Envall from ABG. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Anna-Karin Envall from ABG. I have two questions please.</p>
          <p>The first question is, is it fair to say you always have long-term relationships with your suppliers? And is it fair to say that the very favorable trend we have seen now with managing to pressure the suppliers has not been fully effective from U.S.? You're still delivering large volumes to them, and want to maintain the long relationship.</p>
          <p>And then the follow-up question is then, if we looked one year ahead of us, when we would see this trend converse, and we will have a much less available capacity, is it fair to assume that you perhaps will not be as negatively affected, as you still have supported your suppliers with large volumes during this period? Long question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, in general, of course, as we have stated before, we are working in long-term relationships with our suppliers. And also in a situation with different macroeconomic situations the effect might not be so dramatical for us.</p>
          <p>For us, it's so important to have a long-term relationship with our suppliers. And we think that's a benefit for us in the long term as well, than thinking only short term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And now the next question is, I mean you had a very, very strong EBIT margin this quarter, and presumably you have a number of markets which are underperforming the Group average. Can you state how many markets is underperforming the Group margin right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, but I agree that their margin was high. But it was also lifted by the hedges, don't forget that. So it was not as extraordinary high.</p>
          <p>But it's true of course at any moment there are always some markets that do better and some that do worse and I think that will always be the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how many is underperforming now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Depends on what you mean by underperforming?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Below Group average.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, but that is not &#x2013; if we are looking, we are performing well on all our markets and of course as Nils also said there are different cost structures and etcetera in different markets. But going into how many is under average that we haven't actually &#x2013; of course, we have the figures, but I can't tell them at the moment. But that's the dramatical &#x2013; there are no such huge dramatical changes as you are implying that it might be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not implying. I mean, can you give us any indication how &#x2013; why the gap is between the best performing markets and worst performing markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, I'm sorry, we don't want to go into such a detail when it comes to different markets. We are performing well in all our markets. So, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no further questions registered.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much for participating in this conference call and welcome back for our six month results on June 24.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation. This concludes today's conference. And you may now disconnect your lines. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>