<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1288523" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-17</date>
    <companies>
      <company>260</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jim Burns, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Mark Hurd, Chairman, Chief Executive Officer and President</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Cathie Lesjak, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Richard Gardner</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Ben Reitzes</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Brian Alexander</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Kathryn Huberty</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Toni Sacconaghi</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Bill Shope</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">David Bailey</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Amit Daryanani</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Louis Miscioscia</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Keith Bachman</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Mark Moskowitz</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">Aaron Rakers</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Shannon Cross</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the fourth quarter 2009 Hewlett-Packard earnings conference call. My name is Kiana, and I will be your conference moderator for today. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. We will be facilitating a question-and-answer session towards the end of the conference. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded for replay purposes.</p>
          <p>I will now like to turn the presentation over to your host for today's call, Mr. Jim Burns, Vice President of Investor Relations. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good afternoon and welcome to our first quarter earnings conference call with Chairman and CEO Mark Hurd and CFO Cathie Lesjak. This call is being webcast and a replay of the webcast will be available shortly after the call for approximately one year.</p>
          <p>Some information provided during this call may include forward-looking statements that are based on certain assumptions and are subject to a number of risks and uncertainties, and actual future results may vary materially. Please refer to the risks described in HPs SEC reports including our most recent Form 10-K. The financial information discussed in connection with this call including tax related items reflects estimates based on information available at this time and could differ materially from the amounts ultimately reported in HPs first quarter Form 10-Q.</p>
          <p>Earnings, operating margins, and similar items at the company level are sometimes expressed on a non-GAAP basis and have been adjusted to exclude certain items including amortization of purchased intangibles, restructuring charges, and acquisition related charges. The comparable GAAP financial information and a reconciliation of non-GAAP amounts to GAAP are included in the tables and in the slide presentation accompanying today's earnings release, both of which are available on the HP Investor Relations web page at hp.com.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll now turn the call over to Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jim. Good afternoon and thank you for joining us. In the first quarter, Hewlett-Packard achieved solid growth, gained market share in key markets, and delivered good operating leverage. Year over year, HP grew revenue by 8%, or 5% in constant currency, adding more than $2 billion to the top line. We expanded non-GAAP operating margins for the 19th quarter in a row. We generated $2.4 billion of cash flow from operations, and we repurchased $2.7 billion of stock this quarter. We also executed on our cost initiatives and reinvested in the business. The net result of these efforts, a non-GAAP EPS of $1.10.</p>
          <p>In 2009, despite the recession, digital content continued to grow at an explosive rate. And at HP, we continued to innovate. We delivered new high performing products with compelling value for customers. In Q1, as the server, PC, and printer markets returned to growth, HP was positioned to capitalize and gain share in each of these markets.</p>
          <p>ESS [Enterprise Storage &amp; Servers] grew 11% this quarter, fueled by 27% growth in industry standard servers. Our G6 servers give customers a short payback period and are being adopted more quickly than any previous generation. Yet still only a fraction of the installed base has been upgraded. Average selling prices continued to move up, and we delivered over 30% operating leverage in this segment.</p>
          <p>PSG [Personal Systems Group] grew 20% over the prior year. Our innovative lineup of notebooks and TouchSmart PCs continued to push our share gains and ASPs higher as customers vote with their wallet. The US PC market grew more than 20% in the recent quarter, and we gained roughly four points of share in this market with expected gains in both consumer and commercial.</p>
          <p>In IPG [Imaging and Printing Group], consumer and commercial printer shipments grew 18% and 11% respectively this quarter. The printing market is improving and IPG is on the attack, focused on aggressively replacing units with high page consumption. In Q1, wireless printers roughly doubled and ink in the office products roughly tripled. Supplies revenue was up 4% in local currency over the previous year and 1% as reported. We expect supplies growth this year of low to mid-single digits despite currency headwinds.</p>
          <p>We continue to execute our strategy in Managed Print Services, retail publishing, and digital press. These businesses are strategic to us given their growth profile and very high attach rates of supplies.</p>
          <p>We saw continued stability in our services business, which was down a modest 1% from last year. The EDS integration remains ahead of plan. We have a large funnel and had key signings in the quarter. Services operating profits grew 21% over the previous year.</p>
          <p>Our software business, which was flat from the previous year, had healthy margin expansion of over three points from the prior-year period. Financing grew 13% and delivered double-digit return on equity.</p>
          <p>Before I turn the call over to Cathie to review the financials, let me make just a few comments about the three areas where we are devoting a lot of effort, first our portfolio. I believe HP has the best and the broadest portfolio in the industry. We are number one or number two in virtually every category where we compete. We will continue to invest heavily to ensure that we maintain our technology advantage and align our portfolio to lead the evolution of the marketplace.</p>
          <p>The next generation data center will be delivered by the company that can best leverage scale industry standard hardware that is differentiated with software and financed and delivered via global services. Printed pages will be awarded to the company that can deliver the best quality, usability, speed, and affordability. The PC business will be won by the company with scale, innovation, brand, and global reach. As I consider the market trends and survey the competitive marketplace, I like HP's chances to win.</p>
          <p>Second, our market coverage. We address a $1.3 trillion IT market. The enterprise market represents roughly half of that. And even though HP's sales force is roughly 50% larger than when I joined the company, we want to increase that number. We also have work to do to address the small and medium business customers, both domestically and abroad, particularly in emerging markets. We are hiring now and we'll continue to invest in direct sales and channel partners to better reach these customers.</p>
          <p>Third, our cost initiatives. We have made substantial progress in reducing our cost structure and improving productivity, with revenue per employee up double digits over the previous year. But there are still enormous opportunities in areas such as supply chain, overhead, and service and support. We remain focused on rooting out these costs and will reinvest a portion of these savings to further increase our competitiveness and to build for the future. While I'm proud of what we achieved, I'm convinced that HP's best days lie ahead.</p>
          <p>With that, I will turn the call over to Cathie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark, and good afternoon everyone. HP delivered strong performance in the first quarter. We increased revenue, expanded margins, strengthened our balance sheet, and generated $1.7 billion in free cash flow. At the same time, we executed on our efficiency initiatives and invested for growth. Our results demonstrate the strength of our operating model, both the operating leverage from strong hardware growth and the resiliency of our recurring revenues.</p>
          <p>Compared with a year ago, total revenue in the first quarter was up 8% or up 5% in constant currency to $31.2 billion. On a regional basis, the Americas and Asia-Pacific showed strong year-on-year growth with revenue increasing 9% and 26% respectively. In EMEA, revenue increased 1% from the prior year.</p>
          <p>Gross margins for the quarter were 22.8%, down 60 basis points year over year. The decline was due to strong growth in PC and printer hardware revenue, partially offset by rate improvements in services.</p>
          <p>We continue to improve our cost structure, reducing non-GAAP operating expenses as a percent of revenue by one point year over year to 11.6% of revenue. The structural changes that yield these lower costs drive sustainable improvement and enable us to reinvest back into the business to fund innovation and expand our sales coverage.</p>
          <p>Non-GAAP operating profit increased 13% year on year to $3.5 billion with operating margin expansion of 40 basis points. Non-GAAP net income increased almost $400 million to 2.7 billion or $1.10 per share.</p>
          <p>Looking at the details of our performance by business, during the first quarter, revenue in the Imaging &amp; Printing business grew 4% to $6.2 billion. Supplies revenue grew 1% in dollars and 4% in local currency, and we saw the convergence of sell-in and sell-out on a constant currency basis.</p>
          <p>Consumer hardware revenue increased 21%, and commercial hardware revenue grew 4% compared with the prior-year quarter.</p>
          <p>Segment operating profit totaled $1.1 billion or 17% of revenue while driving double-digit hardware unit growth.</p>
          <p>Total printer unit shipments grew 16%, the largest increase in three years with consumer and commercial printer units growing 18% and 11% respectively.</p>
          <p>We are reinvigorating the core business. The strong growth in our wireless and Officejet products shows that customers value innovation. In addition to placing more units, we are driving growth in long-term, high-value annuity businesses such as Managed Print Services and digital press, which experienced double-digit growth this quarter.</p>
          <p>Operationally, IPG has made great progress in the last year and is well positioned to grow share in 2010. We will continue to invest for growth and profitability through our commitment to innovation, targeted share gains, and a focus on high-usage categories and high-value annuity businesses. At the same time, we are focused on improving efficiency through initiatives to streamline our supply chain and lower product costs. These improvements create capacity to invest in unit placements while maintaining industry leading profitability. While laser printer availability will be constrained through the second quarter, we do expect to achieve double-digit unit growth for the full fiscal year in both ink and laser hardware.</p>
          <p>Services delivered revenue of $8.7 billion, down 1% from the prior year. Within Services, the IT outsourcing business grew 2%. Application Services declined 8%. BPO [Business Process Outsourcing] declined 3%, and Technology Services declined 2%. We have a solid funnel of deals and continue to deliver strong customer satisfaction. The EDS integration is going well and this has significantly enhanced our competitive position.</p>
          <p>Segment operating profit in the quarter increased $240 million year over year to $1.4 billion or 15.8% of revenue, driven by synergies from the EDS acquisition. We remain focused on driving operational improvements in the business via efficiency initiatives, process standardization, and automation.</p>
          <p>Enterprise Storage &amp; Server revenue was $4.4 billion, up 11% compared with the prior year and up 4% sequentially, well ahead of normal seasonality. The ESS results were driven by strong performance in ISS, which increased its revenue by 27% from the prior year. The strength in ISS was partially offset by storage and business critical systems, which experienced year-on-year declines up 3% and 22% respectively.</p>
          <p>The latest generation ISS platform continues to deliver a compelling value proposition for customers with over three-fourths of server shipment volumes now coming from G6. Blades also delivered strong revenue growth, increasing 24% from the prior year and revenue for our innovative Virtual Connect product grew more than 100% this quarter.</p>
          <p>With improved performance in the business, we are seeing positive operating leverage in the ESS model. This quarter, the business delivered over $500 million in operating profit and an operating margin of 12.6%, an increase of 230 basis points from the prior year.</p>
          <p>HP Software revenue was $878 million, flat compared with the prior year. On the bottom line, the Software business expanded its margins 310 basis points, delivering 19 points of operating margin in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning to Personal Systems, PSG revenue increased 20% from the prior year to $10.6 billion. The US and emerging countries all delivered strong year-on-year growth, and we saw balanced growth across each of our product categories, with particular strength in consumer demand during the holidays. Total unit shipments increased 26% year on year with notebook unit growth of 37% and desktop systems growth of 13%. Average selling prices declined at a more normalized rate of 5% compared with the prior year.</p>
          <p>Segment operating profit totaled $530 million or 5% of revenue as PSG continues to deliver solid performance and share gains driven by our innovative product portfolio, scale, and global reach.</p>
          <p>Rounding out the segments, HP Financial Services continues to deliver strong, consistent results. In the first quarter, financing revenue grew 13% to $719 million and generated operating margin of 9.3%, up 290 basis points from the prior year.</p>
          <p>Now on to the balance sheet and cash flow, our balance sheet remains strong and we made solid improvements in working capital management year over year. We closed the quarter with total gross cash of $13.7 billion. Our Q1 cash conversion cycle was 16 days, down 13 days from a year ago, and our channel inventory is in good shape. Compared with a year ago, we more than doubled our cash flow, generating $2.4 billion in cash flow from operations and $1.7 billion in free cash flow during Q1.</p>
          <p>We continue to actively repurchase shares, returning $2.9 billion to shareholders through share repurchases and our quarterly dividend.</p>
          <p>And now a few comments on our outlook; for the second fiscal quarter, we expect revenue to be approximately 29.4 billion to 29.7 billion, and our non-GAAP earnings per share in the range of $1.03 to $1.05. Included in these estimates for Q2 is approximately $0.04 of OI&amp;E expense, a tax rate of approximately 22%, and an expectation for a modest decline in weighted average shares outstanding.</p>
          <p>Turning to the full fiscal year, we are raising our revenue and earnings outlook. We now anticipate revenue of approximately $121.5 billion to $122.5 billion, representing roughly 6 to 7% growth, up from our prior outlook of 3 to 4% revenue growth. Non-GAAP earnings per share is now expected to be in the range of $4.37 to $4.44, representing an increase of 14 to 15% over the prior year.</p>
          <p>In summary, we are winning in the marketplace, executing on our cost initiatives, and investing for growth.</p>
          <p>With that, we will now open the call for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question is going to come from the line of Rick Gardner [Citigroup]. You may proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Cathie, I wanted to ask you about component constraints and whether they had a material impact on the top line in the quarter. And then could you also comment on whether the working capital gains that you saw in the quarter are sustainable or was there some one-time benefit there as a result of supply constraints or other non-recurring issues in the quarter?</p>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rich. In terms of the working capital improvement, the 16 days in the cash conversion cycle is sustainable. We didn't have anything from a sequential perspective that was particularly different from normal seasonality. The year-on-year improvement of course is off of Q1, which was obviously a high point last year.</p>
          <p>In terms of the commodity environment, we definitely saw tightness and pricing pressure in commodities, particularly in memory. To be frank, we expected that. I think we called that out actually in our Q4 earnings call. We were able to increase some prices to adjust for that. And you did see ASP, sequential ASP improvement in PCs as an example and also in industry standard servers.</p>
          <p>In terms of commodities going forward, we expect it to continue to have upward pressure, but I'll remind you that in tight supply environments, we actually tend to do pretty well. In fact, we gain more share in these types of environments simply because we've got a real competency around managing our supply. We've got great relationships with suppliers and we've got the scale that matters. And so we anticipate the uptick for the rest of the year but we're well able to manage it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Ben Reitzes of Barclays Capital. You may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks. Can you guys comment a little more about what's going on with printers, 16% growth? Can you talk about how much the constraints are impacting the laser printer segment and talk about what's going on as we go throughout the year with printer growth? Is this actually at least on &#x2013; is this the actual low point for the year in terms of printers in terms of the progression?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben, thanks. It's Mark. Listen, we worked real hard on IPG in 2009. In a strange way, I think 2009 was a blessing for us. It really got us operationally focused, and obviously as you see by the unit growth, probably our best unit growth number in a long time. To be blunt, I wish we had more stuff. We could have placed more lasers. We could have placed more ink units in the quarter. We did our best to handle the demand that we saw. Demand was linear, and was good across the core.</p>
          <p>I would tell you that supplies, as you've seen, sell-out basis, now this is local currency. Make sure I'm clear, Ben; local currency sell-out was also the best number we've seen in a long time, so we got to mid-single digits there. It's a bit complicated because you have the local currency 4% growth, and then because of our hedging, you get to a 1% reported growth. It's important to note on what we said today, we're actually raising that 1% in dollars, in reported dollars, higher even with that currency headwind, so the unit placements are a part of that. And frankly the fact that we are able to deliver at the high end of our profit range in the context of being able to deliver this 16% unit growth is something that very bluntly two years ago, we couldn't have done. I think it shows the kind of strategic work we've done to get the segment in the position we've had.</p>
          <p>We had tremendous demand in the wireless segment. The wireless segment roughly doubled. And I think importantly with some of the laser issues that you've heard, our Officejet business tripled, so our ability to put ink into the office has been a really pleasant thing for us overall.</p>
          <p>So when you look at the whole market, the supplies, sell-out on a local currency basis, you look at the demand on the printing units. You look at our ability to perform relative to &#x2013; from an operating profit perspective relative to all that, we feel like IPG is in strong shape.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben, just real quickly, let me address the year in terms of unit placements. We do expect that for the full year, both ink and laser will grow double digits. Q2 will be a bit tougher. We'll still have constraints in the laser space. But for the full year, we do expect double digits for both ink and laser.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the constraints alleviate in the back half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They do. They do, but listen, Ben, I've got to tell you, we've got work to do because demand is high and we've just &#x2013; as we've improved our availability, demand has improved with the availability. So I'm cautious to answer the question the way you asked it. Let me say it the way I would say it. We will have more availability in the back half of the year, so we're clearly ramping up in both segments.</p>
          <p>While you're on IPG, I would add to it we also had a very good signings quarter in Managed Print Services. It was a very strong quarter yet again for us in that segment, and we began the retail photo kiosk rollout at one of the very, very large retailers on the planet. So we've got a very good start now on retail photo kiosk. And as you know, getting the graphics, retail photo kiosk in MPS segments, which are high annuity, supplies connect kind of businesses are very strategic to us. They don't yet have as big an impact from a revenue perspective as they will in the future, but they're very strategic to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for all the detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ben.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Brian Alexander of Raymond James. You may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess to follow up on that, a clarification, are you actually expecting an acceleration in supplies growth in local currency, or is the dollar growth improvement you're expecting in supplies a function of a more muted currency headwind going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We expect acceleration both in local currency and in dollars. So in dollars, we're calling for low to mid-single digits this year. And the currency headwind that we've seen year on year this quarter pretty much continues the rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a literal improvement, Brian. I know it's against your better instincts, but if you wouldn't run away from my guidance, I'd appreciate it. But it is a literal improvement in terms of the actual &#x2013; to your point and I think well said &#x2013; the sell-out on a local currency basis we actually think improves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the question I have on ESS, the leverage enormous, 33% contribution margin despite all the growth coming from ISS, which I presumed has less leverage than BCS or storage, so what are the key drivers of that leverage? Is it mostly driven by the higher ASPs you're getting on the G6 servers? And given your comments that we're early innings on that upgrade cycle, do you expect that kind of leverage to continue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Brian, you said it. It is both a growth issue and it is an ASP issue. By the time we get to growth and our ability to scale and leverage the costs that we have in the business as well as the fact that ASPs went up, we haven't seen the kind of ASPs that we had in industry standard servers in a long time. In fact, I can't remember when I've seen the ASPs...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They were up both year over year as well as sequentially.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which is good news, and so I think it actually has, Brian, a more strategic question that we're dealing with is that more and more of customers' strategic jobs and strategic apps are going under these kind of architectures. And so we find that our ability to now compete for a different type of application is important, and that has an impact on ASPs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Kathy (sic) [Katy] Huberty of Morgan Stanley. You may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good afternoon and congrats on the quarter. As it relates to revenue growth, much of it came from the transactional hardware businesses in the quarter, and there were obviously a number of catalysts through December. Can you talk about whether that demand strength continued into the month of January and whether you saw anything different between the commercial and consumer segments in the month of January?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Katy, just to make sure I'm specific the way you asked the question, demand was linear across the months of the quarter. That doesn't say our supply was always linear, just to be clear on that because of some of the questions that got asked earlier on laser printer or something like that, but demand was linear across the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It sounds like you did not catch up with supply fully by the end of January.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess the way I'd say it is we exited the quarter in a position we like from an inventory perspective in the channel. Demand was linear and we did our best to catch up everywhere that we could. And we did a little better in some segments than others, and I'd probably leave it at that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just lastly, when would you expect the later cycle businesses like services to return to growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Katy, we're actually &#x2013; in terms of the funnel that we're seeing &#x2013; we're starting to see more activity in the software and the services space. And so we're continuing momentum that we saw in Q4, but it does come a bit later in the cycle than the hardware uptick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Katy, I'd say to you overall to Cathie's point is if the market is better, we will do better. Our view is right now the market is better, but at the same time we think we're giving prudent guidance given what we're seeing. And in Services, we're predicting more of what we saw in Q1 at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Toni Sacconaghi of Sanford Bernstein. You may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Mark, you commented on the need to invest heavily going forward. I think if you just look at R&amp;D dollars, it looks like you're actually going to spend less on R&amp;D in 2010 than HP did in 2000. HP's revenues were less than 50 billion in 2000 and will be more than $120 billion today. How do we think about that? Is that just that you had a lot of wasteful R&amp;D spending before, or your portfolio's really different, or how do we reconcile those statements? More importantly, what is the right level of R&amp;D for this company going forward, and how do you think about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Toni, in terms of our R&amp;D investments, I think one of the things you've got to look at is there are inputs and outputs. And the outputs in R&amp;D really are helping us win in the marketplace, the innovation that we see, whether that's around the G6 blade, the Slate products that we've announced, the web-connected printer, on and on. We've got good new products coming out that are helping us win in the market, and our market share gains frankly prove that.</p>
          <p>But then there are also the inputs into R&amp;D. And you want to make sure that you're investing in the most efficient way that you can. And what we have found is that there are real opportunities to think about R&amp;D as a series of processes, and make sure that we're doing those processes in an efficient way.</p>
          <p>For example, if you think about labs, if you got a bunch of little ones all over the world with a bunch of equipment in them and you've basically got depreciation expenses in, that's one flow. If you go to a more virtualized environment, that's going to be a much more efficient flow. It didn't change the amount of innovation that the R&amp;D engineers are doing. It just simply changed the process and the dollars associated with that process. You have those types of savings that you get in R&amp;D.</p>
          <p>And then also, R&amp;D gets allocated both real estate and IT expenses. And as those have come down at the total company level, obviously R&amp;D benefits from that. The key here is that we've got good roadmaps going forward. We continue to put in the right level of investment into the innovation in our R&amp;D spend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Toni, Cathie gave you a lot of data there, and the key to it is our overhead is down, and that shows up in R&amp;D. R&amp;D was one of the biggest consumers of overhead in the company. That's one point.</p>
          <p>The second point, we're in a mode to look for processes that we can standardize, simple things like testing, QA, how many development tools we've got. All of these have been, because of acquisitions, very random and very unique and very, if you will, siloed. So our ability to get standardized on those processes give us an opportunity to take out cost.</p>
          <p>And the way we look at R&amp;D is we don't look &#x2013; to Cathie's point &#x2013; we look at R&amp;D in the context of overhead, maintenance, and innovation. What we're trying to do is get the innovation dollars up. So when you look at the total R&amp;D spend, it's down. And yet the yield to the product roadmap is up. When you look at the number of introductions of products that have had meaningful change in share position, that number is actually up for us, and that's what we want to measure. We want to get more innovative products into the market sooner.</p>
          <p>So I think the way you should think about it, it's just like somebody asking me if more field selling cost means more salespeople. And the answer is no because you have to break down all of the costs that sit in the R&amp;D bucket or the field selling cost bucket. We've had times in the company historically where field selling cost goes up but sales head count doesn't, and you have to peel back these numbers to understand.</p>
          <p>So I give you a long answer to just simply say we feel good about our opportunity in R&amp;D to get innovative, exciting products in the market like what we've seen this year that have gained share. As we've talked about salespeople, we have a lot of opportunity to get our great portfolio in front of more customers, and that's why it's important to us. And you may actually see parts of field selling costs go down at the same time sales head count go up. And it's the same phenomenon of us making sure that we're as effective as we can be and we have our money in the right place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I could follow up on a separate topic, you had entered the year talking about market IT spending being zero or 2%, and said we feel very confident about our share position; and if the market does better, we will do better. Clearly, you're taking up guidance here. Are you ready to declare that the market might be a bit better? Clearly, it sounds like it might be a bit of both in terms of the market and your performance. But you can comment on that and how you're thinking about overall IT spending and how HP is performing relative to your expectations a quarter ago?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Toni, that we're probably not going to declare as definitive a point as you'd like. I think that our view in the quarter was that we saw an improving Asia. We saw an improving US again. We saw a mixed story in Europe. I can tell you stories in Europe that were a little better in terms of markets and markets that actually showed some rebound and some that looked stagnant to us. And so I think for us to really look at the world as having a robust IT environment, whatever that might be, we would like to see Europe on a little more broad based trajectory than what we have seen today.</p>
          <p>What we do feel committed to, Toni, is that whatever that market does hand us, we'll do better. We feel very confident in our position, confident in our R&amp;D lineup, confident in our acquisitions that we've made. We do have opportunities for more salespeople in the company that whatever that market hands us, we think we're going to be pretty well positioned to take advantage of it. Probably right now, we're going to want to see the whole quarter of Q1 close calendar-wise and get all that data before we make a call on true IT growth for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Toni. Let's move on to the next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Bill Shope of Credit Suisse. You may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Looking at the PC segment and the PC upside in particular, you noted that you saw particular strength in the consumer market, which I think is in line with what most of us saw in the industry. Can you give us a little more detail on what you're seeing in the commercial segment? There has been lots of talk obviously of a refresh cycle this year. Are you seeing any evidence that corporations and even smaller businesses are starting to upgrade their PCs? And if you're not actually seeing the orders come in, are you starting to see RFPs or the pipeline building there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Bill, that's a fair way to describe it. I think we saw a pretty strong consumer. We expect that to continue a bit through the first part of the year. We do think there will be a corporate refresh in the back half of the year. We are beginning to see momentum around RFPs, to your point.</p>
          <p>Again, the only thing I mentioned earlier in my prepared comments that we still want to delineate between market improvement and share gains. We have had some share gains that have been impressive. Bill, I think you know, I don't always feel as good about those as some might think I would because we actually want to see a market strengthening as well as we want to execute into it. So I think we'll still be a little bit cautious on it, but I do think you're right. We think that there is a corporate refresh coming in the back half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of David Bailey of Goldman Sachs. You may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much. I was wondering if you could just give us a little bit more detail on the sequential increase that you saw in internal inventory this quarter, and are there some strategic buys in there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, we feel pretty good about our inventory position frankly. We've improved it both year on year and it's roughly up a tiny bit sequentially, but normal seasonality. We do have strategic buys in there, but frankly we have strategic buys every quarter. They are up a bit year &#x2013; I'm sorry, quarter on quarter, but it's not really something that I would call out significantly. It's basically playing the game the way we have been.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then moving on to your storage business, it seems to be lagging some of your other ESS categories. Are there initiatives that you have underway there to jumpstart that business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have our top guys working on it. So I think for us, we think again there's going to be a pretty strong convergence in the server and storage market. We think there's a move towards more internal storage away from external storage, which we think strategically really benefits the position we have in the server market. And we had a very strong quarter in the LeftHand product line, very strong. So there are elements within storage that we actually feel quite good about. And as I said, we've got a pretty strong push strategically on getting this lined up across the entire ESS product line as well as within storage itself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We also see in storage basically more storage demand in the higher tiers of storage, which also plays very well to our hand where it's more industry standard, lower cost that really again, like I said, plays to our hand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We think that trend is going to continue strategically, so we just need to take advantage of the opportunity, but we feel good about the market direction and the position we've got. We just frankly have to do a better job from an execution perspective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The areas where we are building out coverage is in the storage space, and that is one of the pieces of execution that we're working on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Amit Daryanani of RBC Capital Markets. You may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, guys. I just have a question. Looking at your full-year revenue guidance, we're looking at sales to be down about 5% or so sequentially. Historically, the trend if I include Compaq and EDS has been flattish. Can you just talk about where you guys are seeing the delta that's making us a little bit more cautious beyond the EMEA region that we discussed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what you've got to do, you've got to add EDS in the mix. And once you add EDS in the mix, the local currency normal seasonality decline is about a point. And then we do have the currency headwinds. And then that pretty much takes care of what's going on from a revenue guidance perspective once you layer in the prudence around the EMEA recovery.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, thanks</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Lou Miscioscia of Collins Stewart. You may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. I've got two questions. Both of them are on services. I guess, Mark, last quarter, you talked about strong momentum in signings and that signings were substantially above revenue. How long does it take for that to kick in?</p>
          <p>My second question &#x2013; hopefully it doesn't confuse things her, is on British Sky Broadcasting. There was a lawsuit in the UK that recently I guess went their way. Maybe if you could just talk a little bit about that and if there are any other ones just lingering from the old EDS days before you all acquired them?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Lou, let me take the first one. Listen, I think signings when you get them, they feather in, and so some of the signings we had in Q4 began in Q1. Some frankly are just getting started in Q1. Some don't start until Q2, so you have a lag effect in how these starts occur. Again, as you grow the services business, particularly the outsourcing deals are like a portfolio. Typically when you start, they don't have much of a profitability impact. In fact, in some cases they can be negative as you go through the transition costs. So it does take a little bit of time for those to kick in.</p>
          <p>To Cathie's point earlier though, the funnel is robust, so we have a pretty strong funnel right now and obviously we've got to convert it. But if we execute properly, this could be a good year for us. We'll obviously have to have a couple more quarters to tell, and we tend to not really look at the thing on the quarter. We tend to look at the trailing 12 months and then we look at the full-year forecast because signings really impact over a longer period of time. But right now, the funnel is encouraging. We just have to go execute and convert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lou, in terms of BSkyB, we put out a press release when the judge gave his first conclusions on the liability in that case. And we do believe that we are appropriately accrued based on the ruling, but we still need to get to the settlement piece of the case, and there hasn't been any damages yet assessed. You may have read there was an interim payment made to the tune of about &#xA3;200 million that we made in Q2. And obviously if there's anything materially different than what we accrued, we would call it out to you all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, let's take our next question, please. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Keith Bachman of Bank of Montreal. You may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you. I wanted to ask a question about the Enterprise Storage &amp; Server division and essentially the composition of growth. How long is the x86 cycle, Mark?</p>
          <p>How long do you think that lasts? It appears it's sustainable for 2010. Is that a double-digit growth for the balance of 2010? And on the other side of that is when would you anticipate seeing better results in storage? I know, Cathie, you mentioned sales coverage, but EVA [Enterprise Virtual Array] was down again, which I would have assumed would have been better. So I just wanted to get a little more color on the composition of the ESS growth, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Keith, let me start. I think that we do see a pretty robust server refresh cycle through the year. What quarter hits at what time, when companies do what at what point in time, I can't exactly prognosticate to you, but we expect it to be pretty robust and that's contained in our guidance, and what we can see in our funnels looks very attractive to us. As I also mentioned, the payback on these G6 installations, the TCO returns on that are just extremely attractive. So even in a timeframe of tight budgets, these look like very good deals. So we see a pretty strong uptake on it. As far as we can see at least during this year, we think it will continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, Mark, just to follow up on the EVA side, or storage more broadly, I guess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think again, we feel good. If you look at our segments, you've got multiple segments. You've got the high end of storage. You've got the midrange. And I hate to call it the low end, but it's the lower tiers and more industry standard part of storage. And what you have for us is really strong growth in the industry standard part of storage...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...very mediocre performance in the midrange but we think we can improve, and then not a lot of growth in the high end, and we think that reflects market trends as well. We've got to get more of our offering into that industry standard part of the market and have more coverage in relationship to that part of the market. So we feel &#x2013; listen, the good news for us is it's a big opportunity. The good news is we've got a supply chain leveraging industry standards that are extremely scaled. We believe we now have a better lineup than we've had before, and we believe we have a team that's capable of helping us build the answers. So we look at it as an opportunity because we think the market is moving our way and we want to take advantage of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Keith.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Mark Moskowitz of JPMorgan. You may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you, good afternoon, a question here and a clarification. As far as the clarification, Mark, did you say that all the server ASP improvements were related to the richer reconfiguration of G6, or is there any impact there from benign pricing as well?</p>
          <p>And then as far as the question, I was just curious in terms of the full year of revenue outlook boost. Is there any impact from the pull-through effects of EDS contributing to the outlook yet, or is that more of an upside potential for 2011 and beyond?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me try to give you simple answers. I think G6 is the primary driver. I can't tell you there isn't a bit more of a benign pricing environment out there, but I think you should look at the bulk of it being G6. And I think you should look at it as upside as it relates to your second question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take two more questions, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Aaron Rakers of Stifel Nicolaus. You may proceed</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks, guys, a couple questions real quick. First on the Imaging and Printing segment, 17% operating margin despite what looks to be a meaningful snap back in the hardware versus supplies mix; I'm just curious in terms of what you guys have done internally there around the supply chain and the manufacturing processes to change that cost structure, and whether we should be thinking 17% is the right number versus the low end of your guidance of 15 to 17% going forward. And then quickly if you can, any update on the pending 3Com acquisition in terms of closure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the IPG question. We have done a lot of work to get our cost structure in a better position in IPG; and to be frank, we're not done yet. We've made progress. We've made a lot of progress last year on the OpEx side. We're starting to get the results from the work that we did on the supply chain side coming through, and that's really the combination of those that have really enabled us to go out and put out 16% increase in units and still deliver 17% operating profit. That should suggest to you that we're probably going to be at the higher end of the margin range for most of the year since we've still got more savings opportunities and we're going to continue to put double-digit units out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the only caution I'd give you on the rate because I think your question is obviously a good one; we did perform at the high end of the guidance with a very high unit growth. That said, we're gaining share in supplies, and we want to continue to do that. We believe there is more market coverage, believe it or not, in printing that we actually can go get, and we want to continue to place units. So I say I think it's very encouraging that we could put 16% unit growth out there, have the signings in MPS that we had, et cetera et cetera because remember, those MPS signings are a lot like an outsourcing deal. They have transition costs built into them, and we actually absorb those and the unit growth in the quarter and delivered the profit we did. That said, we see opportunities in the market now in printing that frankly we haven't seen for a while. We want to take advantage of it.</p>
          <p>I think back to the guidance, I know there would be &#x2013; I know the math. There would be an interest in running north a little bit on these estimates. My view would be to stay with us here. Let us go take advantage of the opportunity, invest in the market because we believe it gives us long term more meaningful growth that brings leverage to the business and that's what we're going to go do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, as we get our costs down, especially on the supply chain side, that opens up additional units that can be attractive to us that with a higher cost structure just weren't that attractive to us. That gives us opportunities to grow more in the unit space.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is a really important point that Cathie just brought up. As we bring down our supply chain costs and bring down our average unit costs, a placement of a unit that didn't look attractive to us over the course of two years worth of supplies connect, that didn't look attractive now looks attractive. And so it actually &#x2013; not only do you bring your supply chain costs to create more competitive position for you in the market &#x2013; it actually opens up more market for you. And so this for us is just as we've mentioned before very strategic to us, and I think the team has done a good job, but I would be remiss if I didn't tell you we've got a lot of work left to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Any update on 3Com?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From a 3Com perspective, we still expect to close in our second fiscal quarter. We have gotten regulatory approval from the US and the EU. We've still got a few more places where we're going through the regulatory process, but do expect it to close in our fiscal Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll take our last question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our last final question comes from the line of Shannon Cross of Cross Research. You may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. I made it in under the wire. A question for you first on the currency, Cathie. How should we think about your hedging programs? Clearly, currency hedging hurt you in IPG for supplies. How are you balancing overall hedging programs, shall we say, and how should we think about it for 2010 for both the company as well as on the supplies side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Typically what we do on the supplies side as well as on the services side is we hedge over a longer period of time. And that's why you see the headwind that you see in supplies but you don't see that at the company level. At the company level, the other product businesses are typically much shorter term. This is a pretty consistent hedging strategy that we've had now for a number of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then, Mark, if you could talk on 3Com, as you sat back and started to look at it, and clearly it hasn't closed yet, but how are you thinking about the networking opportunity? Where do you think your first positioning will be? Have there been any changes in the last few months since you announced the deal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the only thing I know that changes is ProCurve has continued to gain share both in ports and in revenue, and we're obviously very encouraged by that. As we've mentioned in previous calls, it's an area we're investing into. We think we get a lot of leverage out of our supply chain and a lot of leverage out of our go-to-market.</p>
          <p>Interestingly, 3Com has been gaining share simultaneously separate and apart from HP. As we told you, we're obviously very enamored with the technology. The R&amp;D work they've done has been fabulous. And so we think the leverage of the two is an extremely powerful combination, and we think the market trends tell us that separately. We think together they are going to be a very powerful force in the industry.</p>
          <p>So to your point, Shannon, we're just excited about the opportunity. We just think it's a pretty cool thing to be able to come to the market with such a strong lineup of technology and products. And when you integrate it into our services capability and leverage it across the rest of ESS, we think customers &#x2013; from what we hear from customers, they want us to come help them, and that's what we're going to try to do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Customers are very excited about the 3Com acquisition and the technology that it brings. Just as we went through the process of wondering whether or not what the technology really was and getting more and more excited about it, we're actually finding that with customers as well. So we are very excited about getting this closed and getting proofs of concept out there for customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a real important, Shannon, that Cathie made. We're getting customers asking us for proof of concepts, and we're going to have to get that lined up, and we have to integrate 3Com into the company, which we will. We're real excited about all the people and the capability they bring. Give us the time to get the integration right, get the proof of concepts out there because we're in this for the long haul, and we think this can be a real cool segment to add to our already strong position in ESS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Shannon. Why don't we close up? Listen, I think for us we feel like it was a strong quarter for Hewlett-Packard. We think we advanced our strategic position. We think we executed well within the context of that strategy. As we've mentioned, we're going to raise our guidance based on what we saw in Q1 and our visibility for the rest of the year. And we feel like for us the most important thing right now is to continue to execute on our agenda, which is what we're about to do.</p>
          <p>I probably would close, and I know it's maybe not the place for an analyst call, to just thank everybody at HP. I can tell you this was a real team effort on the part of people across the company and I can't tell you how proud of I am of them. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Mr. Mark Hurd for final remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>No. That was it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>With no final remarks, I would like to thank you for the participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation. You may now disconnect and have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>