<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1155578" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-05-20</date>
    <companies>
      <company>260</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jim Burns, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Mark Hurd, Chairman, Chief Executive Officer and President</participant>
      <participant id="3">Richard Gardner</participant>
      <participant id="4">Mark Hurd</participant>
      <participant id="5">Cathie Lesjak</participant>
      <participant id="6">Ben Reitzes</participant>
      <participant id="7">A.M. Sacconaghi, Jr.</participant>
      <participant id="8">Jim Burns</participant>
      <participant id="9">Shannon Cross</participant>
      <participant id="10">Keith Bachman</participant>
      <participant id="11">Brian Alexander</participant>
      <participant id="12">David Bailey</participant>
      <participant id="13">Jeff Fidacaro</participant>
      <participant id="14">Bill Fearnley, Jr.</participant>
      <participant id="15">Louis Miscioscia</participant>
      <participant id="16">Kathryn Huberty</participant>
      <participant id="17">Clay Sumner</participant>
      <participant id="18">Scott Craig</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the second quarter 2008 Hewlett-Packard earnings call. My name is Melanie and I will be your coordinator for today. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the call over to Mr. Jim Burns, Vice President of Investor Relations. Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Melinda. Good afternoon and welcome to our second quarter earnings conference call with Chairman and CEO Mark Hurd and CFO Cathie Lesjak. This call is being webcast live and a replay will be available shortly after the call for approximately one year.</p>
          <p>Some information provided during this call may include forward-looking statements that are based on certain assumptions and are subject to a number of risks and uncertainties and actual future results may vary materially. Please refer to the risks described in HP's SEC reports including our Form 10-Q for the fiscal quarter ended January 31, 2008. The financial information discussed in connection with this call, including tax related items, reflects estimates based on information available at this time and could differ materially from the amount ultimately reported in HP's Form 10-Q for the fiscal quarter ended April 30, 2008.</p>
          <p>Earnings, operating margins, and similar items at the company level are sometimes expressed on a non-GAAP basis and have been adjusted to exclude certain items including amortization of purchased intangibles and restructuring charges. The comparable GAAP financial information and a reconciliation of non-GAAP amounts to GAAP are included in the tables and in the second quarter earnings slide presentation accompanying today's earnings release, both of which are available on the HP Investor Relations website under Company Information at hp.com.</p>
          <p>Finally, please refrain from asking multi-part questions or clarifications. I'll now turn the call over to Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Thanks, Jim; thanks for joining us. Hewlett-Packard delivered a strong second quarter. It was strong in most every dimension we measure. We grew revenues 11% and earnings per share 24%. We generated $4.8 billion of cash from operations and returned 3 billion to shareholders through share repurchases and dividends. As I said last quarter, our performance continues to be driven by three important factors: cost savings from initiatives across the company, our deployment of additional sales resources, and a diverse customer base and a broad portfolio that's aligned with the growth areas of the market. While we have become more efficient, and I'm pleased with that performance, don't be confused. Our cost initiatives are ongoing and they are significant. And we expect them to create additional leverage in our operating model.</p>
          <p>While we primarily want to focus this call on our quarterly results ant outlook, before I pass things to Cathie, let me summarize what we discussed last week regarding our definitive agreement with EDS. First, we expect the acquisition of EDS to accelerate our reach into key enterprise accounts. As I said before, we are a great engineering and a great customer support company, but we have a market coverage problem. I have spoken to you many times about our efforts to improve our Enterprise account presence, especially in the US. We expect this deal to significantly improve our Enterprise share of wallet and create a platform that gives us opportunities for new business growth.</p>
          <p>Second, we believe that the cost synergies from this business combination are significant and make this transaction very financially attractive, even without the expected revenue benefits. The cost opportunities take many forms, from overhead costs to scale efficiencies to service delivery automation. We have opportunities to materially improve the margin performance of our combined outsourcing businesses. Make no mistake, we will get the cost out and we will create value for shareholders.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn it over to Cathie who will review the numbers from the quarter.</p>
          <p>&lt;&lt;</p>
          <p>Cathie Lesjak, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer&gt;&gt;</p>
          <p>Thanks, Mark, and good afternoon everyone. For the second quarter, revenue totaled $28.3 billion, up 11% year over year or up 5% in constant currency. Non-GAAP operating profit was 10% of revenue or $2.8 billion, up 22% year over year. Looking at revenue by geography, EMEA and Asia-Pacific were each up 16% and the Americas increased 4%. We generated 70% of our total revenue and all of our growth outside the United States.</p>
          <p>Second quarter gross margin was 24.8%, up 30 basis points compared to a year ago. This gross margin increase was driven by a generally favorable commodity environment and disciplined pricing.</p>
          <p>Non-GAAP operating expenses for the quarter were $4.2 billion or 14.8% of revenue, down from 15.5% a year ago. Adjusting for currency, expenses were up just 1% as we maintained expense discipline while investing in sales and go-to-market resources and absorbing acquisitions.</p>
          <p>Non-GAAP OI&amp;E yielded income of $3 million in the second quarter, down from the prior year, primarily as a result of lower net interest income and net losses from our currency hedging program.</p>
          <p>Our non-GAAP tax rate was 21% in Q2.</p>
          <p>Second quarter non-GAAP EPS was $0.87, up 24% from $0.70 one year ago. GAAP EPS was $0.80, which included $172 million or $0.07 per share in after-tax adjustments, primarily related to the amortization of purchased intangibles that were excluded from our non-GAAP results.</p>
          <p>Looking at the performance by business segment, during the second quarter, Imaging and Printing revenue was up 6% to $7.6 billion, led by supplies growth of 8%. Commercial Hardware revenue grew 6% while Consumer Hardware revenue declined 3% year over year. Excluding cameras, Consumer Hardware revenue increased 2%. Segment operating profit was $1.2 billion or 16.2% of revenue.</p>
          <p>In terms of our core printing business, we shipped more than 14 million units in the second quarter, an increase of 6% year over year. We continue to see solid momentum in our growth initiatives in the second quarter. Our Graphic Arts business, which is now roughly 10% of IPG revenue, grew in double digits again this quarter. Color laser unit shipments increased 22% year over year and printer-based MSP shipments grew 41%, buoyed by the introduction of new products this quarter.</p>
          <p>Within IPG, we are also focused on reducing our costs and have a number of ongoing initiatives to improve supply chain efficiency and lower product cost. At the same time, we will continue to invest for growth and profitability through our commitment to research and development, targeted share gains, growth in graphic arts, and expansion of our Enterprise printing sales force.</p>
          <p>Personal Systems continue to post solid results, maintaining the number one worldwide market share position in calendar Q1, with revenue growing 16% to $10.1 billion and unit shipments increasing 21%. PSG maintained balanced growth across the businesses with consumer client revenue up 16% and commercial client revenue up 17%. Notebooks continued to be strong with unit shipments increasing 46% year over year. Segment operating profit for the quarter was $544 million or 5.4% of revenue. PSG operating profit increased 30%, reflecting solid execution and to a lesser extent benefit from a favorable commodity environment. You should expect us to continue to balance revenue growth and profitability by managing our costs and investing in growth.</p>
          <p>Moving to the Technology Solutions group, Enterprise Storage and Servers revenue was $4.8 billion, up 4% year over year. Industry standard server revenue was flat versus a tough 17% year-over-year compare. ISS blade growth continues to be strong with revenue increasing 64%. ESS growth was driven by the strength in Storage and Business Critical Systems, which each grew faster in Q2 than they have in the last ten quarters.</p>
          <p>Revenue in Storage grew 14% to just over $1 billion with the midrange EVA business growing 17% and the high end XP business posting 21% growth. The robust Storage results reflect the continuing improvements in our coverage and go-to-market model and positive reception of the new EVA and MSA storage products.</p>
          <p>Business Critical Systems revenue posted 7% year-over-year growth with Integrity server revenue increasing 35%. BCS grew in every region with significant wins in the United States. Business in markets such as India and China also posted strong growth as these markets build out their infrastructure.</p>
          <p>Enterprise Storage and Service posted solid second quarter operating profit of $655 million or 13.7% of revenue, up 390 basis points from the prior year period, led by stronger performance in Storage and BCS, favorable component pricing, and expense discipline.</p>
          <p>We had a solid quarter in HP Services with revenue of $4.6 billion, up 12% over the prior year period. Technology Services delivered strong revenue growth of 10%. Outsourcing and Consulting and Integration revenue increased 14 and 15% respectively. Operating profit for the quarter was $508 million or 11% of revenue, up 10 basis points year over year. The contribution of strong revenue performance from Technology Services was partially offset by workforce rebalancing in Q2 as we initiated a plan to simplify the organizational structure within Services. We are pleased with the progress we have made in reducing costs and accelerating growth.</p>
          <p>HP Software revenue was $727 million, up 28% from the prior year. We continue to take share in the management software layer both organically and through acquisitions. BTO maintained its momentum with 36% year-over-year growth. Other Software, which includes OpenCall, Business Intelligence, and Information Management, grew 2% to $134 million. Solid growth in Information Management was largely offset by year-over-year declines in our OpenCall business. Software reported operating profit of $93 million or 12.8% of revenue, up from $7 million in the prior year. Strong operating performance within BTO was partially offset by integration costs and investments in Business Intelligence.</p>
          <p>HP Financial Services had revenue of $685 million, up 25% year over year, and generated operating margin of 6.9%. We are encouraged with the growth in our core financing volume and portfolio assets over the last several quarters as well as the strong performance in end of lease renewals and equipment sales.</p>
          <p>Moving now to the balance sheet, HP-owned inventory ended Q2 at 32 days of supply, down 2 days compared with a year ago. With regards to channel inventory, we ended the quarter with ESS down roughly a half a week, PSG up roughly a half a week, and IPG approximately flat year over year.</p>
          <p>Days sales outstanding increased to 43 days in Q2 from 41 days one year ago. Days payable was 53 days, down from 54 days last year.</p>
          <p>Next, property plant and equipment was up $567 million year over year and down 40 basis points as a percentage of revenue. Gross CapEx was $704 million, down 7% from the prior year period. On a net basis, CapEx was $599 million, roughly flat year over year. Capital expenditures were primarily related to assets used in our leasing business and our investment in IT.</p>
          <p>On to our cash balance and cash flow, cash flow from operations accelerated to $4.8 billion for the quarter and free cash flow was $4.2 billion. Year to date cash flow from operations was a very strong $8 billion, up 92% year over year. And free cash flow was $6.8 billion, up 131%. During the quarter, we also had a net cash outlay of about $1 billion for acquisitions.</p>
          <p>In addition, we spent $2.8 billion on share repurchases during the quarter, representing approximately 56 million shares. At the end of the quarter, we had roughly $4.5 billion remaining in the current share repurchase authorization. Finally, we paid our normal quarterly dividend totaling $197 million.</p>
          <p>We ended the quarter with a strong balance sheet, including total gross cash of $11.8 billion and net cash of $3.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Now a few comments on our outlook for both the third quarter and the full fiscal year, neither of which includes any impact from the acquisition of EDS we announced last week; we expect Q3 fiscal 2008 revenue to be approximately 27.3 billion to $27.4 billion, in line with typical seasonality. Given our significant international exposure, our results may be favorably or unfavorably impacted by currency. Assuming exchange rates stay roughly where they are and given our assumptions about hedging and pricing, we expect full year revenue will be approximately 114.2 to $114.4 billion.</p>
          <p>Regarding earnings, there are a few variables to keep in mind. First, we expect the component pricing environment to be less favorable in Q3 than it has been in the last several quarters. Second, we estimate non-GAAP OI&amp;E to be approximately zero for the remainder of the year due to lower interest income and higher costs of currency hedging. Finally, we expect to continue to repurchase shares in the coming quarters with a modest decline in weighted average shares outstanding in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>With that in mind, we expect Q3 '08 non-GAAP EPS in the range of $0.82 to $0.83. For the full year, we expect non-GAAP EPS to be in the range of $3.54 to $3.58, representing growth of 21 to 22% on revenue growth of roughly 9.5.</p>
          <p>Overall, we delivered solid results in Q2 and increased our outlook for the year, reflecting the strength of our business model and our progress to date.</p>
          <p>We will now open the call for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from the line of Richard Gardner with Citi. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Mark, I just wanted to ask a quick question about the ISS performance in the quarter. I know that Cathie mentioned that you were up against a difficult 17 or 18% year-over-year compare, but it still looked like you were down a little bit more than normal seasonal in the quarter despite the solid growth in blades. I was hoping that you could provide some color there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure; thanks, Richard. I think down a little, but seasonally you're on it. It was against a tough compare of 17% the year before. Good blades growth within it but very frankly, we picked our spots. We saw some spots where we thought we could take advantage of things and we did. There were also in there, Richard &#x2013; blades being one of those. There were a couple deals we missed that we would have liked to have had, and that's an execution issue that we'll be looking through. I'd say it's really a tough compare. We picked our spots, some good numbers in there, for example the blades that we described, and a couple of deals that we would have liked to have had that we didn't get.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, would you say that there has been any significant change in the competitive environment in terms of pricing or how your competitors are approaching the marketplace that factored into the performance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Spotty, I would not say globally. I would say we saw some spotty stuff in different markets. But as I always tell you, Richard, I have a hard time with the &#x2013; I can't remember when it wasn't competitive as opposed to when it is. But yes, a couple of spots where it was a little bit more competitive than perhaps what we've seen in the last couple of quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I would also to add the fact that we ended channel inventory in really good shape for ISS and ESS, so we're going into the quarter in good shape.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Richard, it's another point that Cathie hit on, which I think is great. We were pretty prudent with the way we looked at inventory and while you see the ESS number in total, within it, the ISS channel inventory was pretty strong, pretty strong being defined we have less inventory in the channel at the same time as we're going up against that compare. So that's really the ISS story.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I know Jim is going to kill me for asking a three-part question, but do you feel like virtualization is having any impact on your x86 business at this point with customers virtualizing with VMware on existing hardware as opposed to buying new hardware?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly not materially in the quarter. Richard, as you look at the $60 billion server market and the opportunity to replatform from non-industry standard platforms to industry standard platforms, the industry standard server platform is really the beneficiary of that transformation. So depending on which way you look at the virtualization question, virtualization actually can be in many ways a driver for industry standard server growth; so I think my answer to you is intra-quarter within that node.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Ben Reitzes of Lehman Brothers. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, good afternoon. Mark, could you talk a little bit about Europe? There are some worries in the marketplace about Europe and what that's going &#x2013; and what the momentum of business is going into your July quarter. And then if I could also sneak in similar questions around PCs, it actually seems maybe that units picked up in April. I was just wondering if you could characterize the PC market and competition given what's going on there. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I tell you we're having a tough time with discipline on the multi-part questions, but Ben, I'll go take them. Europe was strong for us, obviously 16% growth year on year. It's up to 42% of the company. The performance across Europe was strong. It was broad across all of our divisions, very strong. I would tell you that within linearity, and I won't answer it specifically into PCs, but within the quarter we had a pretty normal quarter in terms of linearity. If anything and I say this cautiously, we were probably a little stronger in April than traditional linearity. I only say that cautiously because I don't want somebody to run too far with it, but the quarter behaved roughly as we would have expected perhaps. As you saw, we obviously beat our guidance from a revenue perspective and April was a healthy month for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And competitively in PCs, you were able to have that even with the competitors filling the channel? I was just wondering...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we felt very good about the PSG quarter.  Obviously we're going up against &#x2013; talk about tough compares, this was a huge quarter for us last year from a growth rate perspective in PCs. And dialing in to 16% growth number here was, again probably to be very blunt, a little stronger than we had expected and that we had modeled. So PSG had a very strong quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from line of Toni Sacconaghi with Sanford Bernstein. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Mark, I was wondering if you can talk at all about the economic environment. The thing that struck me most was the US growth rate actually looked like it was slightly negative in the quarter and that's down from 6%, 7%, and 12% growth in the last three quarters. Additionally if I look at your guidance and run my little currency model, it looks like you're guiding for about 2.5% growth at constant currency year over year in Q3 and 2.7% in Q4; again, very tough comparisons, I completely understand that. But if there's something here, particularly in the US, that caused that pretty notable deceleration in the second quarter in your business and something around the overall economy, maybe US centric, that has you forecasting a revenue growth rate that was ultimately below your target model and I think would certainly be the lowest reported growth rate to constant currency that you have had since you joined HP?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Toni. By the way, if you'll send me that little currency model, I'll review it and give you some thoughts. Back to the overall situation, I mean the fact that we could have a flattish performance in the US and grow the company 11% I think is indicative of the position of the company. To be very blunt, Toni, we pick our spots. We look around where we see the opportunity and we try to be nimble enough to take advantage of those opportunities as we see it. For us, as you know, we have to position inventory. We have to position to align our demand to where we see the opportunity. I think to be blunt with our businesses, we did a very good job in the quarter trying to line up to fulfill the opportunities that we saw.</p>
          <p>The US, to be specific, was just spotty. We had some very good numbers in the US. Cathie talked about Storage. She talked about Business Critical Systems. IPG had positions of strength. So there are some very &#x2013; I could go on. I mean there were some positions that were very positive. And to your point, we're going up against tough compares. I hate to give you so much data. I usually try to make it a little bit more concise, but the US is a tale of many stories and spotty would be the best way to describe it. I wouldn't describe it all bad, but I wouldn't describe it all good either. And then within that, we frankly spun the dials to the opportunities that we saw to take advantage of what we saw in the market and we really &#x2013; while we look at countries, we look at the optimizing the entire business as we go, and that's what we did, Toni.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But is the choice around where you chose to play, Mark, are you effectively saying there are parts of the US market because of the growth or because of the pricing that's required that you chose not to play in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't go to elasticity so much, Toni. I think it's really the alignment of demand. I don't think in the US that I would go drive right down to pricing, although it's an element of what we look at. We try to line up where the demand is. Again, I think the best thing I can tell you about the US and it's probably where I'll leave it, it's just right now a very spotty market and one that we try to maintain caution around.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Toni.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Shannon Cross with Cross Research. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, just a question on cash flow because obviously at 4.8 billion, it was quite strong in the quarter. Can you, Cathie, provide us with any puts and takes, things to keep in mind as we look for the full year since obviously you did as much cash in the first two quarters as you did I think in all of 2005? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We laid out some guidance around cash flow from operations at the Security Analyst meeting in December and we said we thought we would be about 11 billion. Basically having done 8 billion so far this year with only half completed, we clearly expect to do a bit better than that. We are ahead of plan. Part of that is due to earnings. And frankly part of that is due to some improvement in the working capital space. We really focused on getting inventory in better order and making good progress there. And we're focusing on accounts payable as well, so definitely some upside to cash flow for ops this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Shannon, there's clearly some inter-quarter movement across cash, so I wouldn't make it all additive and I wouldn't double 8 billion to 16. But we'll clearly do better than our forecast. We'll have to see how it eventually lands in, but clearly this has been a very strong performance for us. It's no one thing; it's a multitude of things that have occurred. So to Cathie's point, we'll clearly beat this forecast.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you talk anything about your share repurchase strategy with the acquisition of EDS? And then, that's my last question. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With the kind of cash flow that we're generating, we fully expect to be active in our shares, even post the EDS acquisition, probably not too dissimilar from the programs that we run today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We like our shares pretty well, Shannon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Keith Bachman with Bank of Montreal. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you; I had a couple of questions &#x2013; a question rather on the ICC group. Cathie, a clarification though, Consumer printer hardware units on the slide deck says up 4%. I thought you said it was up plus 2 net of some Consumer units. I just wanted you to clarify. But then, Mark, on a broader scale, I was just hoping you could speak about how we should think about the inkjet side of the business in terms of unit potential as well as on if you can guesstimate a little bit on the supply side of inkjets and how we should be thinking about that market evolving. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Keith, let me just orient you on the first question because I was &#x2013; one is units. So we're up in units 4%. In revenue, if you adjust for cameras, we're up 2%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but Cathie, can you adjust for cameras on units please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We could try, Keith. We'll try to get somebody to get back to you on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't count cameras considering...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's really not in the unit count anyway, Keith,</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it really hits the revenue number but not the unit number as we calculate it. But let's go back to the inkjet thing. Inkjets actually look pretty strong. Within the rounding of the inventory too, we have done a good job on our channel inventory. Demand looked better so overall good ecosystem result would be the way I would describe it, Keith, in the context of both unit placements and the supply attach associated with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So Mark, just the broader question is when we talk about slowdown in the US or the economy, are you seeing or have differences in terms of the, what's happening in the inkjet because this quarter was frankly a little bit easier of a compare than the last couple of quarters? Are you seeing some reaction due to the consumer slowdown here in the US or otherwise on that particular business unit? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say that we saw no material change in inkjet in the US. If anything, and again I say this on the margin, if anything, perhaps a little bit better. And it's back to my earlier answer to Toni. The US, I would not want you to walk away from a call with HP said the US is all bad. That's certainly not what we're seeing. We're seeing spotty results in the US. It's a little different by industry. It's even a little different by geography and it's a little different by business unit. And within that, I could tell you a Storage story. I could tell you a Business Critical Systems story, an inkjet story, and it's just a mixed bag. And so what I tried to do today was not go into all of that detail because I think it would take a long time to go through. But there are good numbers in there, Keith and there are some numbers that we wish were better, but we think it's a factor in the market. We also feel very good about our share position within the context of all that. So long answer but that's what we're seeing, Keith.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the other overlay to that is the fact that we had said last quarter that we didn't execute as well as we would have liked. We would say that we executed better this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is an IPG comment that Cathie is making. I think last quarter, we left some units on the table and we didn't feel as good about the execution and this was a better execution from IPG's perspective this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Brian Alexander with Raymond James. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Mark, this is on the PSG side. This is the first quarter where I think Commercial revenue grew faster than Consumer since January of '05, albeit the delta was small. It also represents a slight deceleration in the contribution margin for PSG, but still strong 9%. I'm not sure if I should be connecting those two factors but the questions would be do you expect the mix shift to continue toward Commercial? And two, is there still a sizable gap in operating margins between Consumer and Commercial such that this creates an additional headwind going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I appreciate your analytics, Brian. You've done a nice job with that. You're connecting dots I wouldn't connect. Don't connect Commercial and Consumer. Don't connect the mix. There are also loads that go in which are not unique to each business in terms of costing loads, so I would not connect those dots. I would not connect the dots of a shift in mix. I would not connect the dots of different contribution margins based on those shifts and anything material to the business.</p>
          <p>I would say that PSG saw opportunities in the Commercial segment, took advantage of them, had some very, very strong wins in the quarter that we were pretty pleased with. Their operating margins are on the margin, if that makes any sense; but I mean the difference is on the margin. And again, I'd say PSG as we went into the quarter, because we're trying to pick our spots prudently. As we look at the market, PSG performed in line with our expectations, Brian, if not a little bit stronger than what we thought. So we felt very good about the PSG quarter and their position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of David Bailey with Goldman Sachs. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much. The slowing growth in the US is not a big surprise given what's going on in the economy, but your year-over-year growth in APAC at constant currency dropped a fair amount this quarter. Can you comment on how much of that is macro driven; and more broadly, what you're seeing from a demand perspective in Asia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We felt pretty good about Asia, David. We grew obviously 16% and you've got to look at currency on a year-over-year and sequential basis. One thing about currency to be a little bit cautious about is when you look at the cycle times of our business, not all of that currency &#x2013; I don't want to get into a big currency dialogue because this could take up longer than we have left for the call. But when you look at the cycle times in some of these businesses, the currency doesn't all stick to your fingers so to speak because of the speed by which these move across. It's a little different in each business. So I wouldn't read as much into as I think many people do into those things. I still think this is the right way for us to report it. But we felt good about Asia. We felt good about the demand and the position in Asia, our share position in Asia. So we came out of the quarter in Asia pretty encouraged, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Jeff Fidacaro with Merrill Lynch. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for taking my call. Mark, I was wondering if you could give us a quick update on some of the operational savings as far as the data centers and where they stand as far as percent completion of closings as well as the applications. I know you have been working them down from 6,000, getting toward your target of 1,500, if you could give us a quick update on where that stands?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, I'll give you some rough numbers. We closed the quarter with 2,500 applications running at Hewlett-Packard. We've got about 65% of our data centers now closed that we will close. We believe by the end of Q3, we'll be about 90 to 95% of the way through and finished by the fiscal year. So a couple of points on that, Jeff, that I think we are in position to get the full run rate savings in '09 as we have talked about. I think we'll be at the &#x2013; somewhere a little higher than 1,500; but 1,700 &#x2013; 1,800 applications by the end of the year. I think 1,780 is the destination point.</p>
          <p>This puts us in a position to do a couple of things; one obviously finish off our transformation but to do two things. One, to integrate any other acquisitions that we do or at least the one that we talked about last week, which is a big issue for us to be in a position to have that kind of capacity and capability to integrate, and that's significant for us. Secondly, we've got an opportunity now to start working on our applications and the productivity that comes from the applications now being integrated. We've given examples before that we had 18 planning applications in the company. So I don't know how many different ways you can plan but we found 18 different ways to do it. We now plan one way. I can go down this area by area. Consumer actually we had 75 and now have one. So the fact that we now have global application sets allow us to now accelerate our productivity process by process as we go across the company.</p>
          <p>One last one I'll give you free of charge is we used to deal with our channel partners where any time a channel partner wanted to give us information, we accepted the format that the channel partner gave us so we had however many channel partners, that's how many different ways that we accepted data, which isn't just an application, it's different processes. Getting those all collapsed into one global way to do it gives us an opportunity to increase our productivity. So darn near completed, very good job I think by our IT, now capable of with capacity to be able to integrate an acquisition like we've talked about in addition to the fact that we now have a productivity model that allows us to enhance our global applications because we now have a simpler environment. So maybe more data than you wanted, Jeff, but that's where we are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just one quick follow-up, as you look at your data centers and get closer to completion, what sort of utilization levels do you have available for like an EDS type integration? Is there a lot of room to move them to your data centers and/or automate their processes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So yes, we could completely house them in our existing capacity. And yes, we have an idea about the applications; and yes, we have an idea about how to globalize those applications and those processes. So it's a very &#x2013; to your point, very insightful; it's a very important piece of what we do. And Jeff, we think we've built a competency now in this capability. I can tell you if you look over three years and the total report card and you look holistically over where we started and where we've come to, that capability and that asset for Hewlett-Packard is now a big opportunity, big advantage for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Bill Fearnley with FTN Midwest. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I'd like to switch gears, if I could, to Storage. Mark, how do you rate your performance in relation to competitors, especially in Storage? Have you turned a corner here and are you gaining new customers or selling more to the existing base?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bill, good question. I think it's a lot better, so I'm happier. I just gave you an incremental metric. On an absolute basis, we can just do better than this. And we've got new product we have announced into the market during the quarter in the Storage space that we're excited about. We've begun to bring together some of the acquisitions we've done in the line of some of our Storage essential software with our platforms. We're doing more work in the channel and it turned into good growth. For us to get mid-double digit growth or 14% growth in the quarter is better than we've seen.</p>
          <p>Would I tell you that &#x2013; if there's anybody taking a lap around the building, I sure haven't seen them because we've got a lot more work to do to be a participant in the way that HP ought to be a participant in the Storage market. So I think it's good and the good news is we're getting it done with good old-fashioned blocking and tackling. There are net new customers in addition to us being able to upsell and cross-sell into our base. We've really got to build &#x2013; do a better job integrating our channel partners' go-to-market because we obviously, as you know, we have got a tremendous server channel support and getting that same support on the Storage side in many of the same partners is important for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you increasing incentives to get them to do that or do you think they're making the proper progress at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't say we have increased incentives as much as we focused those incentives. And we've done some things to say listen, again, back to our previous discussions and calls about sometimes for us, it's the way we spend our channel money and our incentives as opposed to how much. Do we incent on pure volume or pure units or do we incent on attach? If you just went down a metric of Storage attached to our servers, you would get a big growth in Storage volume. The question is why hasn't that occurred? Some of that is the way we incent the channel. It isn't amount of dollars but it's the way we package those dollars. So it's more about that than it is increasing the amount. But getting focus and being very clear to our partners, this is what we value, so therefore this is how we incent. And some of that has occurred in 2008. That's at least a reason why you're seeing some of the improvement that you're seeing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It depends on how we segmented our channel partners in some cases because we didn't have as good a Storage relationship in some of our ProLiant channel partners, and so we've really expanded that. We've also added what we call road warriors to basically help sell the Storage through the channel. That is also showing some early good returns.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cathie's point is exactly right. The ProLiant franchise and what it has driven and aligning that with the Storage group is a very important thing that's going on here. So we want more. We're expecting more good things, Bill, there. I don't want you for one minute think we're satisfied with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for the detail. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Lou Miscioscia with Cowen and Company. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Going back to EDS, I had a couple of quick questions here. I guess your comment that you could completely house EDS's operation in your existing capacity; they spent a ton of money throughout the years on their own IT infrastructure. What were they inherently doing that I guess was less efficient that you can bring to the table? Was it decentralization of their data centers? And then the second question would be if you could give us a little bit more of a comment on just India in the sense of EDS obviously has best shore but they have stumbled a little bit but do have a footprint in India. And can you actually do a lot with that in expanding it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think your comment, Lou, was about EDS and their utilization levels of IT and how they dealt with their IT expenses. That was the question, right, the first one and the second one is India?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great; let me try to nail it. First the data center consolidation you talked about for EDS, I want to make sure it was clear, was internal IT, not trade. So just to make sure there's no confusion, we separate trade and internal IT and what I was talking about was internal IT and I think you were too, Lou. I certainly can't explain to you any historical issues other than what we see and the opportunity we see, which we think is significant to leverage that capability with our capability. So we feel good about it. We have done a lot of due diligence on it. We think it's a pretty significant opportunity that puts us in a better position.</p>
          <p>In terms of India, obviously both companies have a footprint there but we're less these days, and I have tried to mention this several times. We feel very good about India. We think India is an important country. But at the same time we look to optimize in many locations. So India is important, but it isn't the only country where we have significant operations that we leverage. So we're still bullish on India. Obviously, EDS has been bullish on India. They have got some 40,000 employees there, remembering too that of their 130,000 employees, 30,000 of those employees are government employees that work right next to the government because of contracts. So of their 100,000 remaining employees, they have a very significant presence in India. But we continue to optimize the best shore locations as we think it makes sense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Just a quick follow-up, how about what both you and they are doing from IT infrastructure outsourcing? Obviously it seems like you plan on merging the two. Do you think you can get some efficiencies there too?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We think about efficiencies all over the place, Lou. So we think it's material in both process and in what we do, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Katy Huberty with Morgan Stanley. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good afternoon. Cathie, in light of the currency hedge losses that hit the P&amp;L this quarter, what was the net impact of the weaker dollar on the bottom line, and how should we think about that over the next couple quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Katy, I'm afraid I'm going go down an accounting route here that I'm going to lose some of you on, but the currency losses that I was actually referencing are from hedging our balance sheet outside the United States. And that currency loss is &#x2013; a big chunk of that is really just the fact that interest rate differentials have flipped around on us and we are now paying away points when we hedge our balance sheet as opposed to earning points. So it is really not related to the revenue hedging that we do because the revenue hedging is all completely in from the revenue line all the way to operating profit. So we don't actually &#x2013; it's very difficult for us to completely capture the total currency impact on the P&amp;L. I can tell you what it is from a balance sheet perspective easily because it shows up in OI&amp;E, but the rest of it is buried in basically every line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't we take two more questions, operator?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sir. Our next question comes from the line of Clay Sumner with FBR. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. I just wanted to revisit the IPG business. Revenue was up 6% or so. Supplies were up 8%, yet operating income I think was flat in dollars year over year. I assume that essentially reflects a shift in the overall portfolio to laser. Might we expect that wide-format mix &#x2013; Edgeline to halt that shift to laser, and if so when?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Clay, this is Mark here. 16.2 is a pretty good number for us. We usually &#x2013; I remember the days when I got here, we never thought we could make more than 15 in the business, and so 16 is a good number for us overall. We have invested in the salespeople in Enterprise. We have invested in salespeople in the Graphics. Graphics had another good, strong quarter where we're investing some salespeople into that mix. There is shift from laser, as you described, that I would say adds to that portfolio shift, but overall pretty healthy IPG performance all the way around and the fact that we could deliver 16.2, deliver 6% unit growth, turn in 8% supplies growth, and yet also invest in the demand creation for the future in the Enterprise and Graphics.</p>
          <p>I think as Cathie referenced a little bit earlier in her talk, Graphics is now quickly becoming a material piece of the business. It's got a very attractive growth rate and delivers a very positive operating performance for the business. So we are investing into Graphics as we invest into Enterprise. And it's really the mix of those factors that gets to the answer that we did not just laser alone. But I would tell you as I said about Q1 and I'll say this about Q2, IPG had a strong quarter in Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you also need to take into consideration, we've talked a lot about this, whether it's in IPG or other segments, is that we are investing to grow, to Mark's point. But we're also investing to save, to basically set ourselves up with the right cost structure in the longer term. And you certainly saw some of that in the IPG P&amp;L this quarter as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just to clarify, you're suggesting maybe that gross margins were more positive than operating margins because of the investments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are investments in both the cost of sales line as well as in OpEx.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say generally your question &#x2013; your point is right, yes, and that there is some cost for investing to save, as Cathie described. And there is some investment to grow, as Cathie described. It's the combination of those two factors that we think it's prudent to be able to invest to grow and also to invest to take structural cost out of IPG for the long run, and both of those are in the Q2 numbers. And again I'll say one more time, and yet delivered 16.2 as we did it. So we feel good about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Clay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Scott Craig with Banc of America. Go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, thanks. Hey Mark, with regards to Europe specifically, I know you guys have a number of different channels that you're getting hardware product out to. But can you contrast what some of your larger distributors are saying like the Ingram Micros and the Tech Datas of the world where they're seeing weakness in Europe? Typically my understanding was that's a larger channel for you in Europe than it is elsewhere. And then maybe what you're seeing in the direct business or the retail business over there because there seems to be some sort of disconnect from the solid trends you guys are seeing in Europe versus some of your partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott, I very much don't like talking for them, so I don't want to have any effect on them or their commentary. We just saw strong &#x2013; a strong euro. And to your point, we're very diversified in Europe. There is also a very large reseller base in Europe. So if you just looked at sheer number of partners, the way the channel works in Europe is a bit more dispersed than what you would see in the US.</p>
          <p>In addition, Europe is now a very diverse economy between Russia, Central Europe, Eastern Europe, the Middle East. So when you talk about Europe, we combine it into this thing called EMEA. But inside EMEA you have got a whole series of things that go on between more mature euro markets and markets that are actually much more like an emerging market in the context of some of the markets I have already described. So it's really hard to generalize about a conclusion there. And I would not take a result from one of those distributors you described and then try to extrapolate Hewlett-Packard's results across Europe for a quarter. I think it's a very dangerous thing to do because of the disparate nature of Europe today and the different sets of types of partners that are out there. One more time, Scott, I think to your question, Europe was strong for us in the quarter across really everything that we touch. So it was strong across most every segment that we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I think we'll leave it there today. I guess at the end of the day to summarize the quarter for us, we had strong growth in the quarter at 11%. We felt it was balanced and we picked our spots where to participate, and we felt like we got good results from that. We had margin expansion. The company executed from an expense perspective with discipline. Cathie gave you those numbers and we feel good about the fact that when you look at ex-currency, our spending was in line. This is the best cash flow performance we have had in the company's history. And we feel good about that and we were active in the market in terms of share buyback.</p>
          <p>So I think at the end of the day when you think about the second half for us, we go in with a diverse marketplace, diversity of customers, geography, and businesses. And at the same time as we see that from a revenue opportunity, we're going to continue to be very focused on driving efficiency and there is more leverage in our operating model to gain out of the cost actions that we're taking.</p>
          <p>We'll leave it at that today. Thanks for joining us and we'll talk to you again soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation in today's conference. That does conclude the presentation. You may disconnect. Have a wonderful day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>