<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1408274" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-07-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7833</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Manager, Investor Relations">Rob McInnis</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Asim Ghosh</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Vice President">Alister Cowan</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Operating Officer &amp; Head-Refining">Robert J. Peabody</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities Canada">George Toriola</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Dominion Securities, Inc.">Greg Pardy</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (Canada)">Brian Dutton</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="TD Securities">Menno Hulshof</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Katherine Lucas Minyard</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="FirstEnergy Capital Corp.">Michael P. Dunn</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Dow Jones">Edward Welsch</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Glengary LLC">Pat Roche</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Reuters">Jeffrey Jones</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, and thank you for standing by. Welcome to the Husky Energy Second Quarter 2011 Conference Call and Webcast. As a reminder, all participants are in listen-only mode, and the conference is being recorded. After the presentation, there will be an opportunity to ask questions.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> At this time, I'd like to turn the conference over to Rob McInnis, Manager, Investor Relations. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Thank you for joining us today to discuss our 2011 second quarter results. With me today our CEO, Asim Ghosh; our CFO, Alister Cowan; our COO, Rob Peabody; and our Vice President of Midstream and Refined Products, Terrance Kutryk.</p>
          <p>In today's call, we will provide an update on Husky's business strategy and an overview of the results followed by a question-and-answer session.</p>
          <p>Please note that today's comments do contain forward-looking information. Actual results may differ materially from expected results because of various risk factors and assumptions that are described in our quarterly release and in our annual filings, which are available on SEDAR, EDGAR and our website.</p>
          <p>I'll now turn the call over to Asim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning. It's just about a little over 12 months since my joining Husky. So this quarterly report gives me chance to reflect on our recent and expected performance.</p>
          <p>As you can see from our second quarter results, the actions taken to execute our strategic plan are taking root. Second executive &#x2013; consecutive quarter, we've been able to point to strong growth across a broad set of performance metrics.</p>
          <p>So earnings are up 274% compared to the second quarter last year. The cash flow is up 104% and production increased 10%. In summary, we had made significant progress over relatively short time and our goal is to build on this momentum and to continue to execute against our strategic growth plan.</p>
          <p>While it was a strong quarter operationally, we did of course benefit from a number of market factors including higher realized crude prices and increased crack spreads. And most importantly, the quarter was a strong vindication of our, what I've called in the past, very specialized integrated strategy. But what's more satisfying to me is that solid operational execution continued to deliver value.</p>
          <p>Now, as all of you know, we're in the midst of a rather uncertain global fiscal and monetary environment. And we have also a number of very major upcoming project commitments for the next several years. It was in this context that we decided in the second quarter to proceed with a $1.2 billion common share offering. And basically by pre-funding our balance sheet in advance of these major projects and by lowering the risk associated with economic uncertainties, we have now increased our financial flexibility to carry out our growth strategy.</p>
          <p>We told you earlier that we were exploring the merits of a secondary listing of our shares on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. And this was part of our long-term funding plan that I alluded to in our Investor Day last year. We have not reached a decision on the HKSE listing and have not set a timeline either for making a decision. But I do wish to say that with the common share offering now complete, we do not contemplate that if a new listing should occur on the stock exchange, it would be associated with any new equity issue.</p>
          <p>Moving on to production, a key highlight for the quarter is the progress we achieved in increasing production. Production for the quarter averaged almost 312,000 barrels per day, which is, as I said earlier, a 10% increase over the same period last year, and it's towards the high end of our guidance. It's important to note that these gains were achieved despite some significant disruptions, from forest fires in northern Alberta and the shutdown of the Rainbow pipeline and that shutdown continues.</p>
          <p>We were able to mitigate some of the impact, but at the peak of the disruptions in May, production in the Slave Lake region was reduced by about 17,000 barrels per day. By late May, production impacted by the fires was restored. However, the prolonged shutdown of the northern portion of the Rainbow pipeline reduced production by about 13,600 barrels a day through June. And that, by the way, continues, we do not have at this point, a firm timeline on when the pipeline will resume operations.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the next &#x2013; the first of our major growth pillars, which is the Liwan gas project, a significant highlight for the quarter was the approval for the overall development plans, we call it the ODP for the Liwan 3-1 field by Husky and our partner CNOOC in the Liwan gas project. It's a key milestone for the development as in terms of keeping the project on track towards first gas production in late 2015 or early 2014, in that timeframe.</p>
          <p>The next step now is to submit the ODP to the Chinese government authorities for approval. In support of the ODP submission, of course we did execute a gas sales agreement with the CNOOC Gas and Power group. And the gas pipe mechanism basically is in line with the anticipated Guangdong "city gate" market price, which provides a very attractive rate of return for the project. And is basically &#x2013; I think within the constraints of our joint venture agreement, I think I can give you guidance, that is to me $11 to $13 price range, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (6:12) exchange rates. So, that's the real cornerstone development for Husky, as we look to build a substantial energy business in Asia. And we're very pleased with the progress so far.</p>
          <p>In summary, I'd say, we are quite-ly pleased with the progress the company has made over the past year to execute our strategic plan. We took action to hold a slight introduction. We're progressing on the foundations for future growth.</p>
          <p>Number of &#x2013; by the way, in that context, a number of key management hires have been made to ensure that we have the right talent in place to carry out those plans. The Asia management team is fully in place. We have both &#x2013; some of you will be aware, we have built a significant resource play group in western Canada. We have filled out key missing links in the oil sands area. So really all of our based businesses as well as our growth pillars are properly staffed.</p>
          <p>And we continue to achieve significant milestones in advancing the three growth pillars, which I &#x2013; refresh your memory, the oil sands, Southeast Asia and the Atlantic region. And finally we executed the company's financing plans, which ensures that we're well positioned to carry out the growth strategy. So therefore, we have the people in place, we have the funding in place, we have the strategy in place and we have the initial results of our ability to execute against that plan.</p>
          <p>So in summary, I'd say it's been an exciting and rewarding year. A lot of hard work ahead. But it's fair to say that the results of recent quarters show that we're on track. On that note, I will hand you over to Alister to go to &#x2013; get into &#x2013; get you detail on the finances.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Asim. As Asim had indicated, we have had a strong quarter. Our performance has been driven primarily by an increase in production, as well as higher realized crude prices, slightly higher natural gas prices, strong throughput rates of the upgrader and our refineries and improved margins in the downstream sector.</p>
          <p>While the strong Canadian dollar had some adverse impact on our results, we saw more positives on the whole in the quarter. Our net earnings were $669 million or $0.71 per share, that compares to $179 million or $0.19 per share in the second quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Net earnings did include a post tax gain on the property swap of $50 million. Our cash flow, as Asim said, increased by 104% on the quarter to a strong $1.5 billion or $1.67 per share compared to $739 million or $0.87 per share a year ago. The U.S. Downstream business had a very solid quarter with strong refinery operational performance. The U.S. Downstream business's specialized integration strategy has allowed us to capture the lighter heavy oil and brand differentials and reducing the risk and volatility. U.S. Downstream contributed $165 million to our net earnings.</p>
          <p>When we look at the pricing environment, certainly we saw an improvement there and that was a contributor to the quarter's results. Although as mentioned, the stronger Canadian dollar did partially offset some of the gains.</p>
          <p>The average realized crude oil pricing was $86.90 per barrel that compared to $64.75 per barrel for the same period last year. And natural gas pricing did improve modestly to $3.66 per mcf versus $3.45 per mcf a year ago. We did see an increase in the light/heavy crude oil differentials compared to year ago with an average of $17.89 per barrel compared to $14.34 per barrel last year. Then the U.S. Downstream the refining margin averaged US$1.37 per barrel in the quarter compared to US$6.03 a year ago. Downstream as we've said has been a strong story for us. And that's indicated in the first six months of refining margins where we've averaged $19.29 per barrel versus $5.51 for the first six months of 2010.</p>
          <p>When we look at the financing plan on the balance sheet, as Asim had indicated earlier, we did complete the key element of that in the quarter and we closed the $1.2 billion common share offering. And that gives us increased financial flexibility to carry out the growth strategy that we've outlined to you. We do plan to maintain our CapEx spending between $4 billion to $4.2 billion per year through the 2015 planned period. Through the next two years, 2012 and '13, we plan to direct approximately $500 million towards additional oil sands development and $500 million to an emerging oil and gas resource place. And based on those plans, we anticipate production will now be towards the higher end of our guidance of 3% to 5% compound annual growth rate for 2011 to 2015. Just like to emphasize that it will be based on turnarounds or on a lumpy basis, but it will be on a compound basis towards the top end of that range.</p>
          <p>We also anticipate sustaining 3% to 5% compound annual growth and an annual reserve replacement ratio of 140% per annum through 2020 with the funding plan and the growth capital plans we have in place. We do have a strong balance sheet, as Asim had mentioned, with the debt to capital ratio of 18% and debt to cash flow ratio of 0.9 times. Looking forward into the next quarter we do see some continued market strength. And in analyzing our expected performance for Q3 we'd like you to keep in mind the following. We did experience a nine day shutdown of our refinery at Lima in Ohio, as a result of the discovery of a small leak in the crude oil &#x2013; crude unit furnace and that refinery has returned to full operation. And the overall pre-tax impact of that shutdown including the repair cost is estimated at an opportunity cost of between $15 million to $20 million pre-tax and that will be viewed slightly in the Q3 results.</p>
          <p>Our 30-day partial turnaround that's currently underway at the Toledo refinery, as we've outlined in the MD&amp;A, the Lloydminster Upgrader will also undergo a minor turnaround in September and October primarily for inspection and equipment maintenance and during that period the upgrader will be at about 70% to 80% of capacity. The ongoing shutdown of the northern portion of the Rainbow pipeline is expected to curtail production by about 11,000 barrels per day until the pipeline resumes operating and that is essentially light production.</p>
          <p>On the East coast, we have completed a two day turnaround on the SeaRose earlier in July. And the turnover FPSO has a 28-day turnaround scheduled for September. And a recently scheduled 15-week dock site maintenance for the FPSO which was scheduled for this month has now been deferred to 2012.</p>
          <p>And finally looking at the dividend, the Board of Directors did approve a quarterly dividend of $0.30 per share.</p>
          <p>And now I'm going to ask Rob to discuss the upstream operation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Alister. I'd like to begin with a brief word about our continuing efforts to build and maintain a strong safety culture at Husky. Soon more than about &#x2013; soon more than 1,700 contract workers will converge on the Sunrise Energy Project site. In preparation for that, that heightened activity Husky recently held a Sunrise Safety Summit.</p>
          <p>The summit was designed to help key Sunrise leaders understand our safety goals and expectations and to develop and employ a comprehensive health, safety and environmental program for the Sunrise Project. We're building a very strong safety culture at Sunrise and we are making it clear that every worker in contract who are employed at the site that the highest standards and best safety practices will be required.</p>
          <p>Turning to Western Canada, as you know over the last year we have initiated a number of steps to develop our oil and gas resource portfolio. We've made a lot of project &#x2013; progress building the foundation. From a big picture standpoint, we plan to invest about $250 million through 2013 to develop our emerging oil reserves plays and we have a strong pipeline of projects in development and we expect that we will be able to grow into a 30,000 barrels per day business by the end of the plan period.</p>
          <p>On the gas resource side, we also plan to invest about $250 million through 2013 to develop our liquids rich gas assets. Much of those efforts will be focused on our Ansell play where we have a land base of about 150,000 net acres. Taking a look at developments during the quarter, beginning with oil resource plays, we acquired around 11,500 acres of the Bakken formation in South Central Saskatchewan adjacent to our Oungre oil resource play. And Husky now holds about 18,700 net acres in this light oil play.</p>
          <p>At the end of the second quarter, production from four producing wells in the play was approximately 600 barrels per day. Based on these positive results we've committed funds to accelerate the drilling and completion of 10 additional wells in the second half of 2011. Our other oil reserves plays include opportunities in the Lower Shaunavon in Southern Saskatchewan, the Viking in Southwest Saskatchewan and Central Alberta and in the northern Cardium trend at Wapiti and Kakwa in west central Alberta. Spring break up and extended wet conditions delayed drilling and completion plans in the quarter. However, we do expect to accelerate activities in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>We did complete the drilling of two wells at the Central Alberta Viking Resource Project following a six well drilling program in the first quarter. A total of 11 Viking wells have been placed on production from this area along with another three from the Saskatchewan Viking Oil Project.</p>
          <p>In gas resource plays we continue to build our gas resource portfolio in the quarter adding approximately 16,000 acres of new crown land to our existing base of approximately 800,000 acres. A key focus has been on our liquids rich Ansell asset.</p>
          <p>During the first two quarters, we drilled 21 Cardium formation wells. These will be completed in the second half of the year. A further 12 Cardium and nine deeper multi-zone wells are planned in the second half of the year. We are currently constructing additional offload capacity at Ansell which will increase total production capacity by year-end to 56 million cubic feet per day and over 2000 barrels per day of liquids. We believe Ansell has the ability to support a larger development and we took steps during the quarter to seek a joint-venture partner to accelerate development.</p>
          <p>In heavy oil, we continue to make progress on our thermal development. Our goal is to achieve a higher proportion of our heavy oil production from thermal projects at F&amp;Ds and operating costs that are comparable to our current levels of F&amp;D and operating costs for our CHOPS production. Construction of the 8,000 barrel per day south Pikes Peak project was approximately 67% complete at the end of the quarter and is progressing on schedule towards first production in mid-2012. Construction of the 3,000 barrel per day Paradise Hill thermal project is also progressing on schedule towards first production in the third quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>Turning to our growth pillars, Phase I of the energy project continues on schedule towards first planned production or first production in 2014. Drilling was complete in the second quarter on the first 12 horizontal well pairs, as part of the planned 49 initial well pairs for the project. Detailed engineering milestones were achieved on schedule during the quarter and purchases of major equipment and preparation of the surface facility for construction are targeted for the third quarter. Conceptual development engineering for Sunrise's next phase have also began.</p>
          <p>We continue to make progress at the Tucker Oil Sands project during the quarter as well. Production averaged 6,400 barrels per day during the quarter and we exited June with production in excess of 7,000 barrels per day. This is almost double the rate of a year ago. Production in July month to-date is over 8,000 barrels per day with more wells to come on-stream between now and the end of the year. In the Atlantic region, the North Amethyst development continues to perform well during the quarter with average gross production of around 33,000 barrels per day. Drilling was completed on an additional production well and the production well came on stream on June 23rd towards the end of the quarter at a rate of 6,200 barrels per day without water injection support.</p>
          <p>Our supporting water injection well was brought on stream last week and performance to-date makes us confident we will achieve the targeted design rate of 37,000 barrels per day from the North Amethyst project. As Alister mentioned earlier this month we completed a two day turnaround at the SeaRose FPSO. This turnaround as you recall was originally scheduled to last 16 days.</p>
          <p>Turning to Southeast Asia, as Asim mentioned we achieved a significant milestone during the quarter with a finalization of the overall development plan for the first phase of the Liwan Gas Project. Production from the Liwan 3-1 field is expected to come on stream in late 2013, early 2014 ramping up towards a rate of above 300 million standard cubic feet per day growth.</p>
          <p>The overall Liwan Gas Project is comprised of three fields on block 29, 26. Liwan 3-1, Liwan 34-2 and Liwan 29-1. Husky's share of these developments is 49%. And when all three fields come on stream, we expect gross production to reach approximately 500 standard &#x2013; 500 million cubic feet per day in the 2015 timeframe.</p>
          <p>On the exploration side, Husky acquired the exploration rights to two parcels of lands in the central Mackenzie Valley and the Northwest Territories. These lands complement our existing portfolio and we are evaluating the timing of preliminary work on the new concessions, including 3D seismic and well drilling.</p>
          <p>Finally, returning to the production impact at the Rainbow pipeline outage, looking into the third quarter we do not yet have a timeframe on when the northern portion of the Rainbow pipeline will resume operations.</p>
          <p>While we have been able to further reduce the impact of the outage until the pipeline resumes operations, production will be curtailed by about 11,000 barrels per day of light oil production.</p>
          <p>In summary, the Upstream. In the Upstream, we continue to make substantial progress in our emerging oil and gas resource plays and advancing our growth pillars.</p>
          <p>Despite disruptions in the Slave Lake regions we still anticipate production will be at the high end of our guidance for the year. This time I would like to turn you over to the moderator for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is from George Toriola of UBS Canada. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. A couple of questions here. I will start with the heavy oil production. And this question is for Rob. You talk about &#x2013; specifically you talk about maintaining current heavy oil production levels and then you want to talk about the thermal development. Could you break down the current heavy oil production into what is thermal and what is not thermal, and then could you just walk through what you see as opportunity on both sides?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, George. Okay, very briefly, just currently our overall heavy oil production is in the range of 100,000 barrels per day, not all of that is the Lloydminster region, but the vast majority does. Our current thermal production is in the range of about 18,000 to 20,000 barrels per day. Today, with these projects coming on stream over the next five years, we are looking to increase our thermal production into the range of about 40,000 barrels a day. That will be offset by some declining CHOPS production. Because as we've outlined before as we are moving towards the edge of the reservoir on some of the &#x2013; with some of the CHOPS wells, F&amp;D costs are rising. And therm &#x2013; by bringing on these thermal projects, we actually help drive our F&amp;D costs back down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Perfect. So do you expect the CHOPS conventional heavy oil to remain flat or that's going to &#x2013; just looking out five years as well what's that likely to do?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>George, I would like to make the point and I think it's a good opportunity to make a larger point here that when we gave you the guidance in the Investor Day last year, and I could even give that, the events of the recent past and all that we talked about support that, that overall guidance is correct. It's a compound annual growth rate guidance and therefore, it's not &#x2013; please don't translate that to 3% to 5% every year, point number one.</p>
          <p>Point number two, an extension of that same point applies to heavy oil that as we transition to thermal, the thermal projects are lumpy, CHOPS is short stroke. And therefore in fact you might get a slight decline before you get the increase. But in terms of a longer-term timeframe we are comfortable with everything that we have seen on what our thermal, how our thermal plays perform in that reservoir that we will be able to maintain an overall flat perspective, but not necessarily every year. So in other words, I'm giving you a heads up that if you should see a decline in one year don't see it as a reason for despair, because it's just that the thermal plays are longer cycle projects than CHOPS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much. Thanks, Asim. Last question is just about Ansell, and you talked about the intention to seek a JV partner here, could you &#x2013; is this going to be a competitive process? What is this going to be? And to the extent that it is going to be a competitive process where you are in terms of putting out teasers and things like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there is a marketing process that is on. And a marketing process has a number of elements in there. Obviously, price is an element, what a partner brings to the party is an element, but broadly I think we are an open marketing process. And so what the exact criteria are for the final decision, it is a complex set of criteria. I'm not going to hand it out in public, but it is an open marketing process.</p>
          <p>I do want to make the point though, we have what it takes financially and technology-wise to develop Ansell on our own. So the reason for a JV process is simply to accelerate what we could do on our own. It is not &#x2013; we are not looking for either the technology or any other specific skill set in making it happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Greg Pardy of RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Oh, good morning. So I've got three questions, some of those just nitty, but the cash tax number in the second quarter was a lot lower than we would have expected, but just curious if you can give us any guidance as to what that number might look like this year, that's question one.</p>
          <p>Second, you've done a good job I think in outlining what Liwan is going to look like, but I'm just &#x2013; I'm wondering if you can provide us with some milestones, the next milestones and the timelines we should be looking for?</p>
          <p>Third, just interested what you're going to be doing in the Northwest Territories? And lastly, we have seen other companies now moving to spin out midstream assets and so forth and just take advantage of the market. Obviously you've got the JV contemplated at Ansell, but are there any other assets that you might consider moving off your books? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was four questions, Greg, not three. . .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Even if I say four you are going to lose track, so I had to say it was three.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alister, why don't you take the first one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Greg. On the cash taxes, we were lower in the quarter, we will be lower for the rest of the year and the reason for that is we have resolved some tax issues that we had and that we had paid taxes, cash taxes in prior years that we now don't need so we are using these up to satisfy our requirements. So this year it will be slightly lower, probably more consistent with what you saw in the second quarter for the rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on Liwan, the next step is to submit the ODP to the government and then get their approval and all of this will take place between weeks and months. But I'm not at liberty to give you a specific commitment as to when the sovereign Chinese government will give me a response.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just referring to the MD&amp;A, of course, I mean we did update you on all the major deepwater equipment pipelines and installation services are in the process of being tendered and the development wells have been drilled.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. One other one on that, I mean, you've given a CapEx number, pricing production, just curious what the implied royalty we should be thinking about might be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Greg, we probably have to get back to you on that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yep, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next one was -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Northwest Territory.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; Northwest Territory</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>just one other comment, on Liwan, I did see a report that indicated that there was a view that the Liwan cost estimate was increasing. I think that's just a misunderstanding. The original cost estimate of $5 billion was for Liwan 3-1. The $6.5 billion includes the other two fields. So there hasn't been any increase in the cost estimates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's comparing apples to oranges.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, just for clarity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So what was the question on the Northwest Territories? Greg?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>He is no longer on the line. I could ask him to queue up again if you wish.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's all right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I can get the next question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think we will just go on to the next question then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question is from Brian Dutton of Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. If you're counting questions, I have two and a supplemental to Greg's tax question. So maybe I will start with that. On the tax side, Alister, you mentioned about where you thought cash taxes would be, but do you see any changes on the tax partnership side? Now I'm thinking here on the JV or that partnership that you have, you're east coast production fitting in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a good question. Clearly, we all know that there are going to be changes in the federal regulations around that. We're looking at what the options are going to be there. But that will be complex and it will take us some time to work through. So at this point, I think the assumption is that we will gradually unwind over the next five years with the revised regulations, unless we can find something that meets all the requirements and fits within the federal tax regulations. So that's kind of where we're at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So you don't see any big bullet payment or something as a result of that, it would be a gradual unwind?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the rules there as they've been there I think is a five year time period of once we kind of unwind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. A question on the downstream. How large was the FIFO inventory gain in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well we don't &#x2013; while we obviously on a FIFO basis, we don't really have the &#x2013; we don't do our groups on a LIFO basis. But I will give you a range, we estimate it roughly in the range of $50 to $75 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But remember this is not a GAAP number, it's a management estimate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand that. And I guess the last question is giving your spending plans that you outlined earlier on the call, within the context of the current commodity price environment, are you fully funded or do you need or do you anticipate needing to come back and tapping the equity market again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think from the context of commodity prices where they are today, the spending plans that we've outlined to you from an equity perspective we believe we're fully funded. Clearly, there may be some access to the debt market, but we have our balance sheet to review before that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But that's all for equity for now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just on -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Brian. I just reaffirm that we do have the dividend reinvestment program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So there is no new equity raising program other than what's already been advised to the marketplace. So there will be a drift for the next...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Until the end of next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...until the end of next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. I was just going to ask about that. And so are there any plans to extend that or is that a firm close date?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's the plan. There are no plans to extend that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next person is Greg Pardy of RBC Capital Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you thought you were going to get rid of me.</p>
          <p>Just the last question then, one to ask, we're hearing other companies spinning out assets midstream and so on. Any thoughts, plans, internally as to whether some assets you've got buried in the company might make more sense to be in the public market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alister, why don't you take that part?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. So Greg, you know that the strategy we have is from a midstream and a downstream perspective. Those assets are part of our reservation strategy. So from an operational perspective they're pretty key. And we believe they do add a lot of value and mitigate volatility. I am always open to a financing way alternative, but from an operational perspective we do believe that they are pretty critical.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Menno Hulshof of TD Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thanks. I have got a &#x2013; I'm going to start with a question on that $6.5 billion budget. Would that include capital invested to date? And if so, how much has been put to work so far? And then second, what sort of a return do you think you can generate from the project and how would that stack up relative to other opportunities in the portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The $6.5 billion just to remind everybody as Robert said, it's a greenfield development, it's a shallow water facility among the onshore facilities. And I would say that it will be approximately $3 billion of that. It includes a portion of what has been spent on that field to date, but not on the Arctic vessel exploration cost. And I think your last part of your question was that is a stack up as to return, I mean, we think it stacks up very well, with other alternative and a portfolio for a mega project, bearing in mind that the fixed pricing, guaranteed pricing, we're not exposed, particularly to market volatility commodity pricing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So you're thinking like top quartile?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With comparable to the larger project that we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay perfect. And then I've got an unrelated question on Saleski in the -.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We lost that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Has everything gone?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We're going to try to get Menno back on the line here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Why don't we move on to the next question in the meantime?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The next question is from Katherine Minyard of JP Morgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Thanks very much, just a quick question on Liwan. I've realized you guys left a lot of detail on the MD&amp;A and I apologize I haven't gone through it in its totality, but for the Liwan gas sales agreement, can you talk about what volumes are actually governed by the gas sales agreement? I know that it's just Liwan, but then you give a production number for both Liwan 3-1 and then Liwan 34-2 of total production of 300 million cubic feet a day. So what part of the sales are governed by &#x2013; what volumes are governed by the gas sales agreement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, a large &#x2013; Katherine, a large part of <mark type="ph" /> Lafyan (38:53), they wrote the majority, significant majority <mark type="ph" /> Lafyan (38:58) million cubic feet a day comes out of Liwan 3-1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Liwan 34-2 is the smaller, a much smaller field, so a very large portion of <mark type="ph" /> Lafyan (39:09) and it's what the price applies to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The $11 to $13 range that Asim gave earlier is while we try to bring <mark type="indiscernible" /> (39:19). It's comparable to &#x2013; that $11 to $13 is comparable to landed LNG in that area. So, we're well within that range, and we're negotiating the gas field's agreements for the next two fields over the next 6 to 12 months we'll do, we have 34-2 next and then we'll do 20-91 beginning of the next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then if I could just turn quickly to Tucker, can you just talk about some of the factors that are driving the production growth and the improvement that we're seeing? Is it more wells? Is it more steam? Have we hit kind of a turning point in the reservoir's response? What's driving that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rob, why don't you take that one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. Yeah, there is a whole range of things of course driving the production. Now, the major driver is new well and so -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We brought out a number of wells this year. We've got another five to bring on between now and the end of the year and that's what's underpinning the production growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think the point needs to be made that the fundamental change is proper placement of wells.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the big difference between the well program today, which is leading to production versus the historical well program when we did not make our numbers and all the people threw some egg in our faces was the fundamental difference about placements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and the only thing I'd add to that is just this is the real &#x2013; really the first site D project. It was done in a Clearwater formation as opposed to McMurray. And there were a lot of lessons to be learned with how to apply site D to that formation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then just finally, just thinking more broadly about your production and kind of the growth between kind of the first part of the year or the second quarter and then the end of the year especially in western Canada as you kind of compare 2Q to say a 4Q rate or a full-year exit rate, can you kind of quantify that in aggregate? And then maybe discuss the extent to which that's driven by a return of production that was previously shut in or impacted by infrastructure constraint versus what's driven by the kind of more aggressive approach to development that you're undertaking? And I'll leave it there. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, let me just briefly answer that to say, we really expect production to continue similar to what we've seen in the first half, but some of the factors that are helping us on production in the second half are clearly North Amethyst coming up to full production rates and hopefully at some point we will see the plains pipeline situation resolve, but as we've said we've got no real information yet as to when that's going to work.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and we certainly doesn't expect the plains pipeline to return in the next few weeks or months. So, that's all in the immediate future, we are not in a position to give guidance on that because of the fact that's outside our control, but most specifically, I think we are giving annual guidance and I don't think I'm in a position to start giving quarter-by-quarter guidance, it's not been our practice and I don't want set any <mark type="indiscernible" /> (42:33).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Menno Hulshof of TD Securities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, sorry about that. I'm not sure what happened there, but the question was on Saleski and then the carbonates. In the press release you suggested that you're evaluating options for a pilot and I know it's early days, but what are you currently considering and what would the timeline look like?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'd just say I think it's too early to give out any specifics on that just because it is conceptual work at the moment. And what we are looking to do with Saleski is, by the end of the year or as we go into next year and do our normal reserves update we have been undertaking some independent work to get a good handle on the contingent resources we believe are at Saleski. So, we're going to be putting out some information on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. That's it from me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Mike Dunn of FirstEnergy Capital Corp. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning everyone. Couple of questions, Liwan I just want to be clear the US$6.5 billion cost estimates you mentioned in your press release that you're about $3 billion of that, are you 49% of that estimate or is it not quite that mass?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we are &#x2013; Mike, good question, we are 49% of the production, but 3 billion of the cost and the reason for that is the Shallow Water onshore facilities we built slightly larger to accommodate another field in the region that we're not a part of. Therefore we don't have quite 49% of the shallow water and onshore costs, that's why there's a difference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we are 49% of the production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And then in terms of the pricing, one of you mentioned that it was reasonably fixed pricing. Is it fixed versus LNG spot prices or is it more of a longer-term fixed price that you'd be looking at?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, essentially it's fixed in the beginning period, and then we'll fold it in a range depending on the Guangdong "city gate" price, which will depend on essentially LNG going into that market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And just a question on your recent updates, your production guidance, you're looking at sort of the higher end of the range for this year. I just wanted to confirm you're not baking into that any potential plant acquisitions that you haven't yet closed, is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That would be correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. That's &#x2013; thanks, that's all for me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now open the question and answer session to members of the media. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is Edward Welsch of Dow Jones. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. This question I think Greg Pardy asked it earlier was about north-west territories. I was just wondering if you could give a little more color on what exactly you guys are doing out there? I was somewhat curious that the amount that you guys paid for those leases was quite a bit more than what some of the surrounding players paid, Exxon and Conoco. So, any color you could give on what you see for prospects up there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll hand that over to Rob after I just &#x2013; I have to clarify one issue. We have not paid anything of those leases. Our bids were work commitments bid and we have up to nine years to explore these lands and work off our work commitment. So there is actually no payment to be made from Husky. All these were commitment based. Rob, you want to take the rest of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Asim. Yeah, I mean just to put it in context, we have been actively exploring in the Central Mackenzie Valley area for more than a decade and with a couple of previous smaller discoveries in the area. These lands complement our existing portfolio and we believe the lands are perspective and as it's very clear there's an existing petroleum system near the plants at Norman wells of course it's been there for quite a while and &#x2013; you know as Asim said this is &#x2013; this was a work commitment we made and is based on what we believe it will take to go up there and really assess these leases and hopefully based on the assessment move forward with a development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Mr. Pat Roche of Daily Oil Bulletin. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, two questions on Tucker. First of all why did you decide to use SAGD rather than cyclic steam? And secondly, I know hindsight is 20/20. If you had Tucker to do over right from scratch, would you still go with SAGD rather than cyclic steam?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rob, you take that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think overall &#x2013; and just, I mean clearly it was the first application of SAGD and I guess like all first applications it tends to be quite painful. But we are getting reasonable results now, and as we've said before, we now believe this project is going to achieve some reasonable returns for Husky even when we look at the overall life of the project and all the costs that have been incurred there. So I think we're actually, I think the results of the work and of course we're not finished yet, we still got a way to go. But my sense is that when we look back we'll still believe especially as we've now modified it to work in the Clearwater, we actually believe that this is actually going to be a viable technology for developing these types of reservoirs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is a follow up from Mike Dunn of FirstEnergy Capital Corp. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, hi, again, I just want to clarify on the Mackenzie Valley leases, my understanding was that there was an upfront deposit required, I think somewhere around $90 million or 25%, is that refundable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. No, that's not how it works. There isn't a large upfront deposit that is made. So that's, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for clarifying.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Jeff Jones of Reuters. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As my question relates to Liwan, I am just following up on the capital cost and this is kind of a three-parter. First of all, is the $6.5 billion kind of a figure that you had expected this to ring in at, earlier as you were developing it? Secondly what is kind of the payout time at your $11 to $13 Mcf gas price? And thirdly, do you believe that the value of this project is reflected in the Husky share price given that you cancelled the potential IPO of Asia last year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me address that. The $6.5 billion is in line with what we had expected <mark type="indiscernible" /> (50:24) development. So, and Rob had mentioned that earlier so there's no issues there. The payout, we would expect payout in 4 to 5 years on our project. That would be consistent with the economics that we had outlined that I talked about earlier. And then, I think your last question was did we believe the value of Liwan <mark type="ph" /> is itself right? (50:36)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think our firm company position is that our stock price is completely undervalued for all of our businesses, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (50:58) stock pricing you guys kind of do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from <mark type="ph" /> John Wright of Energy &amp; News Today (51:01). Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. You mentioned earlier something about turnaround plans in the Toledo refinery? I'm sorry I had a dropout, I couldn't understand it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" />, (51:22) you want to take that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. So specifically, what's your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>About what units would be involved in the duration, that sort of thing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay. I appreciate the question. Certainly there are some turnaround activities, which are going on there. But with respect to the specific units that are involved and so forth, that's information that would be best addressed in conjunction with our partner. And we don't have that available to us right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Any other upcoming turnaround plans at refineries other than Toledo that you can tell us about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do have some turnaround plans that are relatively minor in nature associated with our Asphalt plant and they've been addressed and I think in more detail in the MD&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no more further questions at this time. Please continue Mr. Ghosh.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you for the questions, a very full deck. So on one final note, earlier this month John Lau my predecessor as COO and he subsequently moved on to better things to get the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:22) announced his retirement effective <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:22). And as you know he was the driving force of Husky over the last two decades, <mark type="ph" /> had to step down in (52:34) retirement. And I'm sure everybody on this call, will join me in wishing him all the best for the next stage in his life.</p>
          <p>And so, as we end I just like to say that, we're comfortable with our strategy and we're starting to &#x2013; I hope it gives some confidence in our ability to execute and we will watch <mark type="indiscernible" /> (53:01). Thank you for joining us. Bye-Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>