<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1140562" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7850</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Ignacio Gal&#xE1;n, Presidente</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jos&#xE9; S&#xE1;inz Armada, Econ&#xF3;mico &#x2013; Financiero (Chief Financial Officer)</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4">Ignacio Galan</participant>
      <participant id="5">Javier Garrido</participant>
      <participant id="6">Manuel Palomo</participant>
      <participant id="7">Javier Suarez</participant>
      <participant id="8">Alberto Gandolfi</participant>
      <participant id="9">Jose Ruiz</participant>
      <participant id="10">Raimundo Fernandez-Cuesta</participant>
      <participant id="11">Jos&#xE9; Luis San Pedro</participant>
      <participant id="12">Antonio Cruz</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We're going to begin the presentation of the results for the First Semester of 2008. The procedure is going to be as usual. So Ignacio, whenever you're ready to start your presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everyone. I would like to thank everybody for coming those of you who are in the room and those who are connected via the web thank you for your interest. I would particularly like to thank the Board of Directors <mark type="inaudible" /> from Brazil. We are happy to have them with us today. And it's an honor to have you with us at this presentation of the results. And as usual I have with me, Jos&#xE9; Armada, the Financial Director and Jos&#xE9; Luis San Pedro, the Operations Director. And the presentation as usual will focus first on the main aspects for the first semester. Then S&#xE1;inz Armada will give details on the results and the financial position of the group and I'll end up with a few conclusions and we'll end up with the Q&amp;A session.</p>
          <p>This first six months have represented a gross operating profit of &#x20AC;3.28 billion with an increase  of 36.5% compared to the first semester last year as a result of the positive performance of all group businesses especially driven by the growing contribution the investments carried out during recent years especially in the international and renewables areas. The effects of this investment process can also be seen in the growing diversification of the group's results sources.</p>
          <p>The traditional energy business in Spain, even though it has increased its figures during the period has reduced its contribution to the total EBITDA from 45 to 36% as a result fundamentally of the growth in ScottishPower and renewables. The current financial position of the group regarding liquidity and the leverage will enable us to attend the objective for our energy plan 2008-2010 while maintaining a strong balance sheet. And regarding regulation in Spain, the situation has substantially improved during the period. Proof of this is the elimination of official tariffs for industrial clients that already represent 50% of the total market.</p>
          <p>I would like to highlight that the net profit increased in the period to 77.9% reaching a figure very close to &#x20AC;2 billion  in just six months. In the operating figures regarding production it amounts to practically 70,000 gigawatt hours with a 27% increase as a result fundamentally of the contribution of ScottishPower which consolidates this semester and an increase in production in Mexico and Iberdrola Renovables more than half to this production has being generated outside Spain.</p>
          <p>Investments in wind energy as well as increasing the group's production figures is considerably improving the company's product mix. Today over 50% of the group's capacity is based on CO2 emission free technologies. After this we add the 5000 mega watts in combined cycles related to long term contracts in Mexico, the capacity percentage which is not tied to development in raw material prices amounts to two-thirds of the total. The greatest activity in renewables and international businesses is also reflected in the group since these areas provide 95% of the total growth in EBITDA which I already said amounts to 36.5%. Consequently Iberdrola today is a more diversified groups with 5 major profit sources the contribution of which is close to 20%. Iberdrola has carried out a deep transformation in just seven years from a company that obtained 99% of its EBITDA in Spain it has become a global group where the traditional business in our country represents <mark type="inaudible" /> more than a third of our operating results.</p>
          <p>I'll now explain with greater detail the main growth factors which have been ScottishPower and Iberdrola Renovables. In the first six months at ScottishPower EBITDA was 898 million euros with an incremental contribution over 500 million to the groups profits there have been three main factors: solid business development and efficiency improvements as well as the contribution of this British company during the entire semester compared to only one quarter last year.</p>
          <p>Both the production and distribution volumes and prices have increased on a homogenous base. And the synergies and cost savings plan has represented a 21% cost reduction in local currency. This figure is even greater when considered in Euros. ScottishPower is also working on its long term growth, as well as moving forward in the projects already included in our strategic plan. The company has been pre-selected in the contest for a project for the collection and sequestration of CO2 which is being called by the British Government and will be funded by the British Government.</p>
          <p>Regarding Iberdrola Renovables, the figures for the first semester are higher than the figures I gave less than a month ago at the general shareholders meeting where we gave some forecasts. The EBITDA during the period has multiplied by 2.2 compared to last year, amounting to &#x20AC;571 million  and the net profit is &#x20AC;194 million which is a figure 4.25 times greater than that obtained as of June 2007. And this has been possible thanks to the increase in production which is more than 8500 gigawatt hours.</p>
          <p>The renewable strategy is focused on the most attractive markets such as the US market. And this means that the average operating are increasing while capacity is also being increased by the import of new assets. In this semester alone 851 megawatts have been put into operation. And the company is building 1,686 additional megawatts. And without a doubt the objective of 2000 megawatts in operation this year will be a reality by the end of the year.</p>
          <p>And in order to maintain the same capacity increase rate in 2009, we will start the construction of another 500 megawatts during the third quarter; this in fact is already started. The growth during the first semester has been put into service in international markets where the total installed power in the semester amounted to 82% of the total. In other words 82% of the power put into  service during the semester has been put into service in international markets. This increases the geographic diversification and this not only balances exposure to the various regulatory regimes but can also compensate the wind conditions in the various areas.</p>
          <p>In order to fund the group's growth plans, Iberdrola maintains a commitment to a conservative financial policy aimed at maintaining our A rating level. Proof of this is that in the last 12 months the strength of the group has significantly improved both in leverage which has been reduced to 41.7 and liquidity since the group currently has an unavailability of over &#x20AC;8.4 billion. This improvement has been attained during a period of major investments amounting to &#x20AC;5.5 billion in the last 12 months.</p>
          <p>Continuing with the guidelines of our strategic plan these investments have been mainly aimed at the geographic areas and basic businesses of the company by geographic areas in Spain &#x20AC;2.5 billion have been invested that is 45% of the total.  A greater figure in relation to the business in our country in the United Kingdom 1.3 billion have been invested a very similar amount to that invested in the United States. And the other of 400 million have been invested in Latin America and other countries. By businesses 55% was invested in renewables, 26% in networks and the rest in liberalized business.</p>
          <p>This pattern will continue during the next few years; the group will thereby strengthen its position in generation distribution and marketing of electricity. In generation we will continue to invest in environmentally efficient technologies and this means that in renewable energy the installed capacity of the group will be 18,000 megawatts by 2012.</p>
          <p>But also in hydraulic technology where the company will install close to 3,000 new megawatts in the next few years as I will explain later. In the network business we will continue to strongly invest to cope with the increase in the demand in the markets were we operate as well as improving service quality for our customers both in Spain and the United Kingdom and Latin America.</p>
          <p>Coming back to the issue of hydraulic capacity as I said we are developing close to 3,00 megawatts most of which are also pumping stations. In Spain we are currently building 1050 megawatts for the <mark type="inaudible" /> pumping plant and the power stations of San Pedro and San Esteban on the Rivas sea which will come into operation in the next few years.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, through <mark type="inaudible" /> nine projects are being built which amount to over 600 megawatts, and they will be completed between 2009 and 2010. In Portugal we have also recently won a public contest build four power stations with a total capacity of more than 1,135 megawatts of which almost spend 900 megawatts are pumping stations and these plants are planned to come into operation as of 2010. Concerning the regulation situation in Spain the latest advances have been aimed at obtaining a fully liberalized market.</p>
          <p>As I have already said the official tariffs were done away with on July 1st for the industrial customers which represent 50% of the market. This will not only improve the competitive situation of the business but will also reduce the possibility of tariff deficits in the future. Regarding the deficits of early years, the recovery mechanisms are operating suitably. Proof of this is that a few days ago &#x20AC;1.3 billion were collected of which 450 million are for Iberdrola. And on September 30th a new auction will be held for the amounts for 2008.</p>
          <p>Finally I would say that the first semester of 2008 has been an extremely positive period for the group. To the already mentioned developments and operating results we have to add the control of financial costs as a result of a conservative financial policy at the group as well as the results of the divestments included in our strategic plan. As a consequence the net profit has increased by 78% amounting to &#x20AC;1.959 billion  and this once again shows that Iberdrola's strategy is combining strong growth with an improvement in profitability and now Jos&#xE9; S&#xE1;inz Armada will comment on some details related to these figures</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Chairman. What we are going to do now, is look into the most important aspects of the operating accounts of the first semester so that we can <mark type="inaudible" /> look into the details that have to do with the most relevant data of our main businesses. And as the Chairman pointed out we have growth of 77.9%. and this is all based on strong operating growth of 36.5% as regards the EBITDA where the international business in Iberdrola Renovables provides 95% of the &#x20AC;87 billion.</p>
          <p>So with the positive evolution of the operating results, first we have the profits arising from the divestitures of non-strategic assets in line with the commitments of the strategic plan 2008-2010 where we have the sale of <mark type="inaudible" /> as the main contribution.</p>
          <p>But if we were to analyze the evolution of the operating results, and if we exclude the impacts, we can see that there has been an 11% increase at an operative level in the basic margin as well as in the EBITDA. And if we were to exclude the exchange rate effect, we would come across an EBITDA that grows by about 15% which shows has been a positive evolution of the Group in operating terms during the first semester of 2008.</p>
          <p>But now moving on to the different items of the accounts, we can see that the income of the Group have grown 78.9% and now stand at &#x20AC;12 billion with significant growth in all businesses because of the rise in energy prices and <mark type="inaudible" /> because of the contribution made by ScottishPower and the gas business in the United States, six complete months, vis-&#xE0;-vis just two months in the first semester in 2007 and the incremental contribution made by the <mark type="inaudible" /> power station that started to work in June 2007.</p>
          <p>And as regards procurements they have grown 118% and now stand at &#x20AC;6,796.6 million in an environment where we have more expenses related to fuel, more thermal production mix in 2008 versus 2007, the consolidation of ScottishPower and the gas business in the States and the greater levels of production at <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>The gross margin rose 36.9% and now stands at &#x20AC;4,915 million. The international area and Renewables provide 51% of the gross margin of the group and also make a very significant contribution in terms of growth, with 77%. ScottishPower has provided 24% of the gross margin of the group with &#x20AC;1,173 million and Renovables 16% with &#x20AC;779 million. The traditional Spanish energy business accounts for 41% of the gross margin and the deregulated business provides 26% with &#x20AC;1,267 million and the regulated business 15% with &#x20AC;774 million.</p>
          <p>But to assess the net impact of the emission rights we've used, as usual, the basic margin concept that's grown 42.8%, which is nearly six points above the growth of the gross margin which was 36.9% because the informed gross margin only covers the negative impact that has to do with the emission rights that have been consumed which total &#x20AC;309 million, whereas the basic margin is obtained by adding to the gross margin the positive effect of &#x20AC;223 million that come from the income produced by allocated free rights that can be found in the items as a lower operating cost.  So that means that the net effect of emission rights in terms of the company's accounts in the semester accounts for &#x20AC;86 million versus &#x20AC;309 million entered as far as the gross margin is concerned.</p>
          <p>So the net operating expense has grown 39.6% and now stands at &#x20AC;1,489 million and it's maintained its growth three percentage points below the basic margin. And as regard to the business units the most important aspects are the net operating expense of the group that we still call Iberdrola has grown16.6% and now stands at &#x20AC;926 million.</p>
          <p>And in the semester that includes the wage updatings that have been produced by the collective agreement signed in October of 2007 so in other words the greater impact of the wage updating process. And what we have to bear in mind that in 2007 we had a typical income totaling &#x20AC;45 billion because of lower expenses associated to the restructuring plan which reduces the comparison base and therefore increased the reported growth.</p>
          <p>So we think that ScottishPower in the second semester, well we think that this is the growth that will reach a plateau, but ScottishPower have provided 25% for the net operating expenses of the group with &#x20AC;368 million. In other words, now that we have six complete months as I said previously and Renovables increases 128% and now stands at &#x20AC;193 million which is the consequence of the growth and expansion of this activity especially international growth.</p>
          <p>And also because there's a different consolidation permitted because PPM has been included together with the Renewables business in the UK.</p>
          <p>And then we also have the tax item that has increased a lot basically because &#x20AC;195 million have been entered into the books and this has to do with the detraction of emission rights. And this provision refers to the allocated and unallocated facilities. And this has been carried out so that we can apply the Royal Decree 11-2007 that extends these rights related to Royal Decree 3-2006. An appeal has been filed and the Royal Decree 11-2007 has also been [denunciated by ENUSA]. We consider that the detraction of emission rights is like an additional tax obligation.</p>
          <p>ScottishPower has provided &#x20AC;23 million more than in 2007 as regards this taxation chapter. And the figures that the larger activity of the Group explains the increase of 23.6 million.</p>
          <p>And our consolidated EBITDA has grown 36.5% and now stands at &#x20AC;3,280 million. And the energy business in Spain has provided &#x20AC;1,169 million with a growth rate of 8.5%. So ScottishPower and Renovables, as the President said, they are responsible for the growth of the total EBITDA of the Group. Renovables has multiplied its EBITDA by more than two and it now stands at &#x20AC;570 million.</p>
          <p>And it covers the positive effects that have to do with normalizing the wind power resources in Spain. We have a greater installed capacity, especially in the international area. We have an improvement of the load factors that have to do with our geographic diversification and higher prices. And we also have a positive impact produced by additions to the consolidation permitter of ScottishPower UK and PPM after the company reorganization in 2008.</p>
          <p>ScottishPower provided &#x20AC;898 million in the first fiscal year since it started with a positive operating evolution as the President pointed out. Latin America is also growing. It's grown 3.6% in the year and some tariff corrections have been carried out in the distributors of Brazil and the weakness of the dollar has affected the business in Mexico. Non-energy products have dropped 17.2%. And the EBIT of the Group has grown 39.4% and now stands at &#x20AC;2,367 million in line with the evolution we've had in EBITDA.</p>
          <p>So amortizations and provisions have now gone up to &#x20AC;913 million. And this has to do with the increase in amortizations. The increase has been 28.5% and now stands at &#x20AC;885 million. And there's also been an increase in provisions of 70.3% and it now stands at &#x20AC;28 million. And amortizations that have been produced by the takeover of ScottishPower are &#x20AC;322 million and they include &#x20AC;113 million because of the allocation of an overprice of assets. And it's 30 that go to Renovables.</p>
          <p>And the financial outcome of the Group has gone up 46.6% and now stands at &#x20AC;471 million. And this increase -- 25% of the increase has been determined by the increase in the average balance in the debt of the first semester. And the rest of the increase is the outcome of lower financial income because there have been less profits in 2008 vis-&#xE0;-vis 2007 where in the area of derivatives we had &#x20AC;30 million and 56 million in the first semester of 2007. And there was also a financial updating for pensions.</p>
          <p>The average cost of debt is now stable in spite of the incorporation of the debt denominated in pounds after the takeover of ScottishPower, the structures of tax, equity investors and the increase of interest rates in the euro area and greater credit spreads.</p>
          <p>Profit before tax has grown 69.3% and now stands at &#x20AC;2,489 million. And apart from the current trends in terms of the EBIT and the financial result, we have to mention an impact of &#x20AC;535 million that arise from capital gains totaling &#x20AC;386 million because 4% of shares in Galp have been sold. And we also have to add to this adjustments in profits because of the sale of <mark type="inaudible" />. And we also have Gamesa portfolio adjustments after IBV sold its package. And we also have to mention an 88.1% increase in the results because of a high contribution made by Gamesa which addresses the results of the sale of its solar business.</p>
          <p>And net profits have gone up 78% and now stand at &#x20AC;1,959 million. This growth is greater than the profit before tax because of the lower taxation rate which stands at 19% because of two reasons. First of all because there's been a reduction of the corporate tax rate whose main cause is a reduction in the Spanish taxation rate from 32 to 30%. And also because of our exemptions in some of the regions that produce tax of 28%. And the rate of taxation in the UK that stands at 28%. And we also have a deduction that is produced by reinvestments. And secondly because there's been an atypical income from ScottishPower totaling &#x20AC;159 million. In the concept that has to do with the reversal of fiscal provisions.</p>
          <p>And lastly, it has to be mentioned that the increase seen in the net profits can also be applied to the profits per share that stand at &#x20AC;0.39 per share with an increase that is equivalent to the net profit. And the funds generated in operations during 2008 represent &#x20AC;2,300 million which is a 33% increase in relation to June 2007.</p>
          <p>And now moving on to what has to do with the analysis of results by business. And starting off with the deregulated business. In Spain that includes generation and non-regulated gas. The results are determined by 71.8% increase in the prices of the pool which is &#x20AC;62.7 per megawatt per hour and a 2.4% increase in demand in Spain. In an environment in which it has been possible to maintain a stable production in the ordinary regime and we stand at only minus 0.8% thanks to the very good second quarter where production has increased 16% with a greater activity in our combined cycles at the nuclear and hydraulic power stations.</p>
          <p>But in spite of this evolution in the second quarter, in the semester we have the same characteristics as in the first one. So in other words we have a production mix which has produced a 39% reduction in hydraulic production and 65% reduction in conventional thermal production. And this has been compensated by normalization of nuclear production after the reloadings programmed in 2007 with a strong increase of 54% in the production of combined cycles. And the average cost of fuel now stands at &#x20AC;47.9 per megawatt in a context in which commodities and their prices are increasing and CO2 prices have gone up from 1.9 to &#x20AC;23.9 per ton.</p>
          <p>And as you can see in the transparency, this increase in the pool price reflects the increase in the cost of fuel and of CO2.</p>
          <p>So all of this means that there's been an increase of the gross margin of the deregulated business in Spain. It's been 27.8% and it now stands at &#x20AC;1,267 million which means that the growth has been much greater than the increase in costs. And the net operating expense has gone up 12.6% because of an increase in the commercial activities and of some atypical items, as I mentioned before, with the employment regulation file of 2007 that reduces the comparison base. So that means that the EBITDA of the deregulated business has grown 15.8%. And it has been affected by the detraction of CO2 emission rights.</p>
          <p>And the gross margin of the regulated business in Spain has grown 4.5% and now stands at &#x20AC;774 million. And this is a consequence of the positive effect of the increase in the remuneration of regulated activities. And EBITDA has grown 3.6% and is now growing again after the 1% slump in the first quarter after an improvement in the changes affecting the net operating expense.</p>
          <p>However this 3.6% increase in EBITDA is slightly lower than what we find in the gross margin because of the non-recurrent impact that I've already mentioned in terms of staff expenses. That means the employment regulation file and the updating of wages according to the 2008 collective agreement. As we mentioned in the results of the first quarter, the EBITA will improve as the year goes by.</p>
          <p>And as regards renewables, the results are determined by a normalization of the operating business conditions and also by an increase in geographic diversification that has produced much better energy prices. So there's been a 48% increase in production and now we have 8,558 gigawatts per hour at an average price increase of 14.5%.</p>
          <p>So these factors mean that the gross margin of the business has grown 123.2%. New businesses provide 47% in terms of the sale figure with &#x20AC;441.5 million, 11% of procurements. So in other words this is 36% in terms of the total gross margin. And the net operating expense of the business has increased 128% because of the international expansion costs of the business that do not yet cover 100% of the sale figure nor does this cover the consolidation permitted through the new business because they do provide 43% of the business. And the EBITDA, excluding the mark-to-market factor has grown 126% and now stands at &#x20AC;587 million. And this impact has been produced by the valuation of gas contracts. And the informed EBITDA has grown 120% and now stands at &#x20AC;571 million.</p>
          <p>The contribution made by ScottishPower in terms of the Group in terms of the gross margin was &#x20AC;1,173 million as regards the basic margin. And by adding &#x20AC;138 million in allocation of emission rights, the contribution now stands at &#x20AC;1,311 million. And in terms of EBITDA, the contribution is &#x20AC;898 million which is 27.4% of the Group's EBITDA. And the mark-to-market effect is positive and reaches &#x20AC;116 million.</p>
          <p>EBITDA excluding mark-to-market now has reached &#x20AC;781 million of which 388 million are provided by the wholesale and retail business, 386 come from the network business and the remaining 6.9 million come from the gas business in Canada. And the impact of the rate of exchange has taken &#x20AC;134 million away from the EBITDA of ScottishPower.</p>
          <p>And the EBITDA in Latin America is growing moderately at 3.6% and now stands at &#x20AC;430 million. In local currency the growth of EBITDA would be 7.3% versus 3.6% of the informed EBITDA, mainly due to the negative effect that has been produced by the exchange rate between Mexico and Guatemala because of the depreciation of the dollar that has been partially compensated by the appreciation of the Brazilian Real. Net operating expenses have increased 7.6% because the Tamazunchale power station in Mexico has been commissioned.</p>
          <p>And moving onto other regions, EBITDA in South America stands at &#x20AC;260 million. That is a growth of 6.8% which basically arises from a 6.1% increase in demand. Regardless of the lower level of payments made by distributors that affected <mark type="inaudible" />. So as regards Mexico and Guatemala, EBITDA has reached &#x20AC;169 million. And the positive effect that has to do with the higher level of production and the incremental contribution made by the Tamazunchale power station has managed to compensate the negative effects that have been produced by <mark type="inaudible" /> in the rate system used in Guatemala.</p>
          <p>And the EBITDA of non-energy products and power has dropped 17.2% and now stands at &#x20AC;200 million. And as I'll explain later on, there were some real estate results, the main reasons. So Iberdrola Inmobilaria has managed to achieve an EBITDA of &#x20AC;73.4 million. And net profits of &#x20AC;44 million. The situation of the real estate market which suggests that we postpone some operations until everything is much more favorable explains why the business was worse -- has been worse in 2007.</p>
          <p>And then the results in 2007 had an extraordinary contribution of &#x20AC;37 million because of the sale of solar. And the dynamic management of the business of Iberdrola Inmobilaria has adapted itself very quickly to the market conditions. And this has made it possible to present results which without a doubt are excellent in the current circumstances in which overall the companies listed on the Stock Exchange have lost &#x20AC;268 million in the first quarter of 2008. And we also have low or adjusted costs and low level of indebtedness which means that it's still producing results at an operating net level.</p>
          <p>And then in the engineering and construction business it's still growing very strongly which can be seen with the 32.2% growth in the terms of the gross margin. And as regards to EBITDA, growth is reduced by 1.3% because of a lower margin of the business in Spain during the first semester which will be compensated in the second semester with a greater level of activity and more growth on the international front. And the project portfolio is now in excess of &#x20AC;2,800 million after growing 27% and after increasing the weight of this area 80% on the international front which guarantees strong activity and better margins in the next few years.</p>
          <p>As regards the financial situation and as the President pointed out, it is excellent because as regards the application of funds it has to be mentioned that with nearly &#x20AC;4 billion that have been used for investments and dividends there has only been an increase in debt of &#x20AC;516 million which allows the Group to continue improving its leverage and the rest of the financial ratios. And it also is fulfilling its investment commitments that were taken on in the strategic plan.</p>
          <p>[Spanish language.]</p>
          <p>...generated through the period come from a cash flow close or over &#x20AC;2.4 billion. There is also a major contribution from the divestments in non-strategic assets in line with the guidelines of our strategic plan. And a reduction in our treasury stock at the closing of the first semester. 70% of the funds generated during the period have been used to fund the investments. And the figure I'm showing are for the period January to June. It's not annual.</p>
          <p>The company's balance sheet is very strong. The adjusted net debt is reduced by 9.6% to &#x20AC;20.9 billion. And while our own assets go up by 19.1% to &#x20AC;29 billion. The investment process carried out by the company, as I said during the previous transparency, to a large extent has been generated by the funds generated through the expansion of the business. Consequently there has been a major improvement in the company's leverage rate which is reduced from 48.6 to 41.7%. And including the impact of the tariff insufficiency the leverage is even better, below 40%. And all the financial ratios improved. Excluding the tariff insufficiency, the funds generated through operations over net debt improves from 14.5% to 26.2. The interest coverage improves from 4.9 times to 5.3 times. And the CF ratio improves from 10.7% to 19.6%.</p>
          <p>Iberdrola estimates a tariff insufficiency at the end of the semester of &#x20AC;1.8 billion. And &#x20AC;826 million belong to 2008. Last July 1st the funds from the tariff deficit auction were collected, a total of &#x20AC;450 million, &#x20AC;386 million of which correspond to the cancellation of the tariff deficit principle and another &#x20AC;64 million the accrued interest. In this way the tariff insufficiency has been reduced from &#x20AC;386 million to 1.5. And in September 2008 there will be a further auction regarding the tariff insufficiency for 2009.</p>
          <p>Our liquidity position is also very positive. We have closed the first semester of 2008 with over &#x20AC;11.4 billion in liquidity and lines that will enable us to cover the strategic plan in 2008 with very hopeful expectations.</p>
          <p>And now the Chairman will conclude the presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Pepe. Before ending this presentation I would like to share some brief conclusions with you. The results obtained during these first six months prove above all that the Iberdrola Group is on the right path to attain the objectives established in the plan 2008-2010. Developments in this semester show the transformation carried out by Iberdrola in recent years, a transformation which has turned us into a company with major international presence which is increasing day by day thanks to the work and the effort of the excellent staff.</p>
          <p>This evolution is clear and obvious. We are no longer a company that depends on a single business or a single market. Now we are a Group that has a diversified business portfolio which covers the whole European and Atlantic area. The traditional energy business in Spain currently contributes only 36% of our EBITDA while the rest comes from new investments carried out over the last few years.</p>
          <p>In these six months of the year all the Group areas have had a positive performance. They have all added, starting with ScottishPower and Renovables which have been the main drivers behind our growth. There has also been a good development in our liberalized and regulated business in Spain. And ending with the activity developed in Latin America and non-energy businesses. And as I say, they have all made a positive contribution to the Group's results.</p>
          <p>I would also like to underline that the Group is facing a situation on the financial markets in an excellent position, as the financial director has just said. This is the result of our conservative financial policy, which means that we have over &#x20AC;11 billion in available liquidity, and the average debt is five years. And we have also improved our leverage level after having invested &#x20AC;5.5 billion in the last 12 months. And this reaffirms our commitment to an A rating level.</p>
          <p>The developments from here to the end of the year enabled us to be optimistic regarding the operating results for the Group. And it's important to also remember that historically the second half of the year has always surpassed the operating results of the first semester at Iberdrola. And this without a doubt will help to palliate the development in exchange rates, and we don't know how this is going to evolve, and which affects the results in euros in our operations in the United Kingdom, United States and Latin America. As well as the delay in the operation of Energy East, which as you all know we expected to be completed before the end of the summer. But, we are still pending the final decision from the New York regulator.</p>
          <p>Regarding net profits they will be positively affected by the good performance of all the businesses, as I said earlier. The coverage of the exchange risk and the lower tax rate that was also mentioned previously. Without a doubt the results obtained during these first six months are an encouragement to continue working as we have been to attain, and if possible exceed, the targets we have laid down with the ultimate objective of creating value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>And now we are open to your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's start with questions from the floor. Javier Garrido</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good morning. Javier Garrido, JP Morgan. I have two questions. The first regarding the strategy regarding treasury stock. We've seen that in the first half of the year treasury stock has been reduced during a period where the stock market has dropped and the share price has also dropped. How do you explain this treasury stock approach and is it to be expected that if the Iberdrola share value continues at the same level could Iberdrola consider buying back their own shares? And could this extend to Iberdrola Renovables shares, which have also dropped in price on the stock market in recent months? And another inevitable question. What is your opinion of the intention of ACS of considering the sale of their share in Union Fenosa to consolidate their position at Iberdrola? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we manage treasury stock in our portfolio with the aim of maintaining it within reasonable limits. And during the year there have obviously been drops in the market but there have also been increases. So, we carry out dynamic management of the treasury stock. We have a treasury stock objective which is relatively low and therefore we manage the treasury stock under those conditions, always bearing in mind the interests of our shareholders.</p>
          <p>And regarding the strategy. Well, that will be decided by the Board. But what I can say is that we have a growth strategic plan, a strategic plan that is going to create value, a strategic plan that means investments of 18 billion, plus the purchase of ScottishPower. A strategic plan where we're seeing enormous opportunities to grow whilst adding value. And I think that the Group, and as I say this will depend on what the Chairman and the Board says, that I think that we have to use this capacity to create value on the medium term. And clearly at this point we are seeing very interesting opportunities for growth in sectors where we have major competitive advantages.</p>
          <p>Well, to complete what Pepe is saying we haven't considered a repurchase. We do have the approach of reducing our treasury stock progressively because we believe that our growth possibilities and the need we have of dedicating these resources to grow more and create value are fundamental goals. So, there is no plan to buy back shares from either Renovables or Iberdrola. We all know the situation of the financial market. Our share performance is slightly better than most indices in spite of the fact that we have had infinitely higher prices in the past few years. Our shareholders have obtained major capital gains. And the aim is to use that as wisely as possible.</p>
          <p>And the second question. I think that when we hear statements that only talk about possibilities and conservations, well, obviously Iberdrola has nothing to say. Iberdrola is a company that likes to talk about specific facts and specific realities. During all these months we've heard so many comments, so many possibilities and so many possible scenarios, that I think that talking about possibilities, conversations, I don't think makes any contribution. We'll speak when there's something specific, specific facts, and not just possibilities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>This one is regarding the target you are mentioning in terms of operating level due to the very strong performance of the first half results, do we have a kind of flavor about, quantifying flavor about, what are you expecting in terms of operating results improvement? And the second one, it's regarding tax rate. You have some specific conditions on the second quarter and a very low tax rate. Do we have an idea of what's going to be this tax rate for the full year please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the forecast for operating results at the end of the year, as I said, our operating results during the second semester have traditionally been better than during the first semester. The ratio is usually 45 to 55 taking an average. This year we have six months to go. What I can say is that the results for the first semester, if we continue with the same operating results as in the first semester, we would obtain better results.</p>
          <p>The elements against? Well, we have the exchange rate, as I mentioned earlier. We don't know how the exchange rate is going to develop. We've partially covered that exchange rate but it will be lower and not higher, not on a level of the EBITDA. And we don't know when we will finally include, if we do finally include it, because it will depend on the decision of the New York regulator, what the conditions are that are established to finally decide whether we include or don't include Energy East in our Group. It's true that Energy East, as of today, is a month late regarding to our plan and therefore it will depend on how many months late it comes in.</p>
          <p>But the positive aspects on an operating level, we are doing better than the forecast. Regarding the changes the situation is worse and we don't know how it's going to evolve. And regarding Energy East we are still waiting for the final date. We have an operating results estimate for the whole year and we'll have to make an adjustment depending on the exchange rate and when Energy East comes in. And based on that we'll have to give specific explanations after making the analysis. But, the operating results are doing well and our expectation is that they will continue to do well.</p>
          <p>Regarding the tax rate. Well, regarding the tax cost, there are two circumstances that have had a positive influence during the semester. One is that we've had capital gains from assets that have been extraordinary. And the tax rate is lower than the average. And secondly, we've resolved some tax appeals in our favor and this has enabled us to apply some tax provisions. The forecast we have for the tax rate for the whole year is more or less what we had in June, that is around 19, 20%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Manuel Palomo from Citi [BBVA Bolsa].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Manuel Palomo from Citi. Yes, a question regarding the regulatory update and those possible conservations that utilities could be having with the regulator to resolve the deficit issue. And I ask the question because as I understood it the utilities overall could propose a number of solutions or provide advice. However, last week another utility, Union Fenosa specifically, put forward the possibility of a reduction in the remuneration for renewables. And I would like to know your view on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think the Minister has said it and the Secretary for Energy have said it very clearly. Recently, both in parliament and the Secretary for Energy at a meeting of the Alternativas Foundation already said what their concerns are and the measures to resolve those concerns. Their concern is how to have a lower foreign dependence. How to guarantee quality supply. How to ensure that we can reduce our emission rate and meet our commitments. And how to do all this in a sustainable manner. And in their scenario they contemplate an element they call the market.</p>
          <p>The Secretary gave a presentation explaining the concentration indices that Spain had versus other European Union countries. Spain is currently in a situation of competition that is higher than most European countries and lower than the indices required by the European Commission to obtain a truly competitive market. And the measures pointed out are a greater liberalization, they prove this with the disappearance of the official industrial tariffs on July 1 this year, and this automatically means that 50% of the electricity generation business will no longer produce a deficit. It will be an open market and they will each have to work competitively on that basis, and also fix dates for the other suppliers, residential and low voltage supplies, to gradually disappear.</p>
          <p>So, there's a liberalization model to look much more at the market and through that liberalization and by looking at the market that issue is going to go away. And the tariff, the last resort tariff, the date he gave said that it would disappear to 2010, 2011, for those low consumption consumers. And it would be additive based on the market, the Spanish market, unlike what some newspapers say the daily pool is less than half of the energy mood. Every day more than half of the energy is being sold on bilateral contracts and term contracts. In other words, it's a tremendously open market where daily movements are relatively small and they don't reflect the reality of the market we're operating in.</p>
          <p>So, the conversations are there following the lines of what the Secretary and the Minister have said. We're going to a more and more liberalized market and a more and more open market. The steps they're taking in this direction are very clear. And what for, to ensure that the measures they are taking are measures that will make sure that the necessary investments are carried out.</p>
          <p>So, the country will reduce its foreign dependence and so the country will have a quality supply and lower emissions in the generation system. And to ensure this they've done two things. Firstly, a national electricity infrastructure has been approved up to 2016, with two aims. To have transmission and distribution networks that are powerful enough to be able to supply the produced energy through the various sources, basically renewables. And cater for the new renewable energy sources set up in the country to increase interconnections also for the same reason. So that the reference grid will be greater and will be able to cover more renewables. I very much doubt that when there is a national priority for the renewables area, and that major renewable source is wind energy, and it's very unlikely that they will do the opposite, a disincentivation.</p>
          <p>And in the case of solar photovoltaic energy, the government has already extensively exceeded the maximum limit for the subsidy of those technologies and the government is not taking necessary measures to comply with what was originally established. This is not the case in wind energy where the figures for the objectives and the construction objectives are increasing. We've gone from around 7,000 to over 22,000 at this time and they are planning more than 30,000 lines. And we're still very much below that objective power that the government has laid down for wind energy. But, we have exceeded the objectives for photovoltaic energy and some kind of measure has to be taken and I'm sure that our colleagues are referring to this kind of technology that were exceeding the objectives that the government had established for them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>We have questions from the web. And we have questions from Javier Suarez <mark type="inaudible" /> and this has to do with the situation, they want to know what's going on with Energy East. What's happening with that operation?</p>
          <p>And perhaps, or another question, is if we cannot carry out that takeover of Energy East, do we have an alternative plan in the United States? And if it were the opposite, if we do close the operation with Energy East, are we going to divest anything to balance the balance sheet, and what are the strategic guidelines of Iberdrola?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as I said before, at this point in time with Energy East we have all the necessary federal permits. We also have the permits from four of the five states where it's operating. We are now pending the final decision of the New York State regulator. And the input we have from a political perspective, that is from the point of view of the Governor and the opposition leader, as well as the parliamentary head of the Republican and Democratic country, through the media, we are being welcomed in our approaches. So, our position is very clear. We've come to the United States with a fundamental priority in our mind and that is to implement renewables, basically wind power. Because any constraints that are applied in that regard, our reply will be no.</p>
          <p>We are in the State of New York and we are in the rest of the States of the Union, we do not want to have any limitations in terms of our wind power development and we say the same thing for grids. Because we think that in the United States, and in particular in the states where we are operating, in many instances some very significant investments have to be made in new electrical grids, in new electrical infrastructures. But if they set up constraints, well it would no longer be attractive for us as an option. And this is what we have made known, we've reported this to the regulators and we also transmitted this information to the bodies we've been in touch with.</p>
          <p>So, we still believe that the final decision is a reasonable decision and that this reasonable decision will allow us to make progress. But, if due to any circumstances there are any constraints that affect our basic objectives, our response will be that we will not carry out that operation, which does not mean that we need to have other operations. Because what we believe is that we still have put our stakes on it. We have a plan which is very ambitious in terms of development. We have many, many projects in the United States and we believe that this is what we will do at a given point in time should this not work. I must say that after reading what people are publishing in the media about the different statements made by the social, economic and political stakeholders of the country we feel optimistic because we believe that the final resolution will be in line with our expectations.</p>
          <p>And divestitures. Well, we don't, we haven't contemplated anything that doesn't have to do with our plan, for our 2008-2010 plan. We had diversities already scheduled but we have no additional actions programmed. And we can see that the results have been good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have some questions on deregulated markets in the UK and Spain and fundamentally they came from the same analysts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Pablo Bennarich from BP.  And the question has to do with dark spreads in the United Kingdom and Spain, and the prospects for electricity pricing in the next few months in the market and in Spain. What sort of a percentage have we sold in 2009 of our generation portfolio and could we have an archive price for those contracts in 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As regards Spain, well, I have some average data from the spreads that have been obtained in the first semester in the case of gas and coal. When deducting the market price and by giving it the variable fuel costs vis-&#xE0;-vis the CO2 cost, well for gas we have a spread of 11 megawatts per hour and for coal it's 7. So, we would have to deduct to obtain the real gross margin, the unit gross margin. We would have to deduct the variable operation and maintenance costs and in the case of gas we'd have to talk about transportation expenses. And this would be the margin we have to cover the fixed costs of operations and maintenance, amortization, etcetera. So, that means that with these margins these power stations are covering their fixed costs.</p>
          <p>But, in the case of the UK, well, they are obtaining -- first of all, we have to analyze what the margin, or the spread, means in the wholesale market, the difference compared to Spain because it is a market of surpluses. But in any case spreads are being obtained by deducting the daily market prices of power with daily market prices that have to do with fuel. And we're talking about 14 for coal and something between 7 and 10 in the case of gas. After that we'd also have to add the value of the free rights, which in the UK are conserved and in Spain this does not apply. So, what I mean to say, is that the margin that is being obtained, the unit margin or the total unit spread that is being obtained in the UK to address fixed costs, is much higher than what is being obtained in Spain. So, there's another thing, Paco can say something about forecasts in terms of energy pricing in Spain, Europe, and other places too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, let's see. Prices in Spain are slightly below the rest of Europe because they are rapidly converging and although the market is very volatile and it's moving around a lot as occurs with the products used for production purposes. So, we could say that it's between 70 to 80%, in a stable manner it's more 80 than 70, wholesale prices, which have to do with the year 2009 and following. So Spain is converging towards that and the prices, the term prices, are reflecting those figures.</p>
          <p>As regards the portfolio we have, we've already got it ready for next year, it's in the second semester when we have most of the sales for the next year, for the following year. But, in any case, the lines we are following, what we can see is that there's lots of continuity with what we have this year. So, it's about one quarter of our production that's going to be sold to customers as we have this year.</p>
          <p>So, there's a big mystery, and that is if the government will dare give permission for the domestics, in other words, for domestic consumers to go into the market so that they can be given offers. And if that were the case, well, we'd be able to increase that production that is sold on a term basis on to customers directly. And then the term market will also represent another quarter. So, it's about 50% or more, 50 to 60%. But, in any case we are currently getting things ready. We are in the preparation stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, as regards the UK we have a specific question from Chris Murray.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is ScottishPower working medium or long term as far as generation goes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if we were to take a look at the same data you can find in the brochure that has been made available to all the investors. What we can see is that in the first semester of this year we are very balanced because production has been 12,881GWh and sales of electricity to customers have been 12,679GWh. So, what we can see is that we have a balance, which is practically total as far as the production of electricity is concerned, and also in terms of sales to the market, retail market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question has to do with the possible effects of the resolution passed by the European Court on Function 14.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I think, I think this is an issue that was already set aside. Nobody expected the resolution for the European Commission to be different. So, in other words, these are situations that I think were taken as a fact by all the stakeholders. I don't really think that this will be able to affect what, under normal conditions, we expected was supposed to happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Javier Suarez has another question and this has to do with the mention we are making of the engineering and construction business that has been affected by the non recurrencies in other shared businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you please explain what you mean when you use that term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, basically, what I mean to say is that the answer is determined by something very specific that has happened. There has been a stagnation, or let's say there's been less activity, in part of the business in Spain, and it's not generated the margins we expected it to initially. But, in any case, it's a business that's going to be re-addressed in the second part of the year as well as in future years. So, this is just a specific stagnation, which obviously reduces activities and the margins because they are costs to be dealt with, and we're going to carry on doing things. But, let's say that during this first part of the year there's been a big slump. But, the activity will be re-initiated in the second part of the year, we're going to increase our international business. So, it's a very, very specific element.</p>
          <p>I think that engineering and construction, too, because we do more construction than engineering, although we do both things. I think that it's a business that is working quite well. But the problem we have is that we too many orders because there are many times when we have to reject a construction project because we do not have enough capability to absorb all the demand we have right now. Because the power stations that are being built right now, we have some projects in the Middle East and the Arab Emirates, where they're building big power stations. In the Urals and Russia and Lithuania where they're building another power station. We're also working in Brazil, Mexico, Russia, or in the Arab countries, in the north of Africa, we're doing things all over the place. So, this is one of the issues. I think that it's one of the businesses that is working perfectly well and, as you know, when there are things under construction there are things that are called work in construction and they can be better or they can be worse in terms of results.</p>
          <p>But what I have to say is the project portfolio is increasing, I think that it's about &#x20AC;3 billion, if I'm not mistaken, as regards the portfolio. So, that means that we have work guaranteed for the next two years and that there will be no problem. We know that the portfolio is becoming very significant.</p>
          <p>Now that we've finished with the questions from the website. Let's move on to telephone questions. If there were any, of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, the first question is from Mr. Alberto Gandolfi from UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I have two questions. The first question is going back to transparency number 31, you're saying that you have &#x20AC;11 per megawatt, but could you please confirm this? Does this only have to do with the price of generation, or does this have to do with the payment for capability and services? And if my calculation is correct are we deducting operating costs from -- in the case of combined cycle it's zero, or it could be slightly negative. So, could you confirm this please?</p>
          <p>And could you also tell me if this is sustainable and if so for how long? And would it be possible to have the domestic consolidation figures? In the press they're talking about now the influence of natural gas. So, do you think that this could postpone or cancel combined <mark type="inaudible" /> projects?</p>
          <p>And the second question is could you give me a figure for EBITDA for the non energy business over this year? And could you please say something about how you think EBITDA is going to change as far as the structural issues are concerned? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as you can see, if you take a look at the transparency, and I'll tell you which one it is exactly. It is transparency number 38. Where we have -- well, here you can see the gross margin of the business and I think that as far as the level of the EBITDA is concerned, well, you can see that there's an evolution that is pretty similar. And let's say that there's a bit more weight in what has to do with real estate operations and construction engineering. Why, because the expenses are somewhat higher compared to the gross margin. So, in the case of construction and engineering the EBITDA, or the margins, are lower than in the other areas, in the other fields. But, if you want later on I'll give you the exact data concerning the EBITDA, but divided by businesses.</p>
          <p>And then as regards the issue that has to do with the &#x20AC;30 million in corporate matters. I think that in the first part of the year we've had a number of expenses, which have also occurred at a corporate level. We've done lots of advertising. We've carried out quite a lot of actions and we also have the severance premium that is another &#x20AC;5 million compared to last year. So, these are expenses that should become more stable, or should be cut back in the growth of the year, in the comparison we have vis-&#xE0;-vis 2007.</p>
          <p>Regarding the spreads, as I said, for gas and coal of 11 and 7 respectively. This doesn't include capacity payments which are around 2 to &#x20AC;2.5/MWh. And regarding the EBITDA linked to the cycles. The unit EBITDA that has been obtained this semester for combined cycles was &#x20AC;6/MWh to cover the financial costs and profitability. And in June 2007 the EBIT for combined cycle was negative. It was minus &#x20AC;3/MWh. So, we're in a typical situation of a marginal power station, but a marginal power station that has to recover its overall investment.</p>
          <p>Answering the other part of the question. As you will understand, this is a situation that's improving and it will have to improve because the situations aren't sustainable. They are transient, they come from the past. But, under normal conditions they have to adjust to reasonable situations as we have in other countries, in the United Kingdom, or other European countries, where those spreads are higher than in Spain to cover those costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question by phone is Mr. Jose Ruiz from BNP Paribas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, and congratulations on the results. I had two questions. The first one is can you tell us what your forecast is for hydraulic production for next winter? And its effect on prices. And the second would be regarding those customers that are going from a regulated tariff to a contract. Can you tell us what kind of price increases are they suffering? And secondly, whether you have any idea as to whether any of those customers are going to disappear because of those strong price increases?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Paco will answer but a comment. I see that we continue to have many questions about Spain and I want to remind you that two-thirds of our business comes from outside Spain. And in Spain half of it comes from a regulated business and the other half from a liberalized business. So, we're talking about a very small percentage for the global company. We're delighted to answer but this is just a general comment because I can see that it's a recurrent theme. In the eight years I've been here we permanently keep talking about Spain and I'm delighted to talk about Spain, but we have other places that -- I would also like to talk about other places since we have that possibility. But Paco can talk to us about hydraulic production and the customer contract rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, regarding contracts we're signing around 7,000 contracts per week, basically. Yes, small volume industrial contracts because the major contracts are practically already established. So, around 1,000 customers a day, 7,000 a week. Regarding hydraulic production. How much are you going to produce in the second semester and how do you see it? It'll depend on how much it rains. Well, we've measured hydraulic production up to September, around 1,000/1,500GWh, but we don't know for the year. If it's an average year most of our production will be in January and February, around 3,000 or 4,000. And if it isn't an average year, if it's a dry year or a very wet year, that can range from half of that to almost double that figure. So, we don't have any figures on what the hydraulic production might be for the last quarter.</p>
          <p>In any case I would like to make a comment. The reserves we currently have mean that we're around 6,000GWh stored and this has increased considerably since the month of May. We had a very bad year during the first few months. The rainfall in spring means that we have substantially increased production in the last few months and our reserves have substantially increased compared to the beginning of the year. And we currently have reserves of around 6,000GWh, which is a level of around 50/55% of our total capacity. And this is a reasonably good situation, more than the average year. Yes, the next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the next question Mr. Raimundo Fernandez-Cuesta from Credit Suisse. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good morning. I had two questions. The first on ScottishPower, which after the Chairman's comments I assume he won't get angry at this one. As for the second one, we've heard Scottish and Southern in the United Kingdom say that the second half of the year is going to be a more difficult half because of the increase in fuel costs. And the unknown quantities about the price increases that may be made by the major distributor, Centrica. And how are you going to respond competitively? So, there's going to be a more difficult second half and I would like to know how you see that from ScottishPower? And the second question and the Chairman may get upset with this. Regarding Energy East. What will happen if it doesn't work out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think it's been explained in the last few months. But I think that what the market wants to hear maybe it looks very much in the short term that the company is not going to make any acquisition but re-invest the money it made from the capital increase last year in the renewable area, the strategic plan, and in the environment of a difficult market to obtain more capital. And I know, I would like to know whether this can be made clear? I assume that the Company will always look at other opportunities in the future. But I would like that to be qualified because I think that the message has changed somewhat. But I don't quite clearly know what's going to happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'll say that regarding Energy East. We still believe that Energy East is going to work out. All our forecasts with all the inputs we have from everywhere is that the proposals we've made, which are reasonable proposals, have been absolutely well received by all the social and political agents in the State of New York. As they were well received by the States of Maine, Connecticut, New Hampshire, exactly the same, with the same approach in all the states. The approaches have been reasonable and we've, as I say, made reasonable approaches. And the inputs we've received from all social and political agents and they've even made this public in the media and therefore that's what we believe. And we have the feeling that it's going to be resolved soon. And that those social and political agents are asking the regulator to make a decision quickly. Therefore I think that we continue to think about these plans and therefore we're not putting forward any alternative plan because we think it's going to happen. If that weren't the case the next opportunity we'll tell you about it.</p>
          <p>But, as I said earlier, that we don't like to talk about possibilities, or possible possibilities, we like to talk about realities. And the reality is that today we think that that's the most likely thing to occur. So, we're not wasting time thinking about what we can do if that doesn't happen, because we are fairly convinced that that is going to happen. And if that weren't the case and if something happened that didn't make sense you can be sure that we're going to tell you what we're going to do in detail. But the scenario we're currently contemplating because of all the inputs that you will also have read about in the media from the State of New York, they all point in the same direction. ScottishPower, Jos&#xE9; Luis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's clear that in the United Kingdom the current retail prices are not justified in the current price environment for commodities reflected through the wholesale prices. And we cannot indefinitely extend the protection to the retail customers as they are currently being protected. So, sooner or later there will have to be retail price increases in the United Kingdom. We haven't considered them in our budget but it seems obvious that sooner or later those price increases in the retail market will have to take place in the United Kingdom. Because obviously other operators that don't have the balance situation that we have regarding production and sales, as mentioned earlier, are going to be forced to carry out those retail price increases. Yes, next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the next question is from Mr. Antonio Cruz from Banesto Bolsa. Please ask your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. A very quick question, what has the contribution of the gas EBITDA been to the Spanish business. The first quarter I think it was 32.5% and I would like to know what the accumulated figure is for this first semester? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The contribution of gas wholesale sales I think was 34 million and retail sales to customers, I think that the gross margin was 11 million. Those are the two figures I can give you. In round figures 45 million to 50 million. It's in the brochure. If I may add that comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that we have no more telephone questions. We have a last few from the website. First, regarding the hydraulic contest recently awarded in Portugal. They ask about the new costs or the expected investment costs and whether the premiums, or the costs we're going to have to tackle, are coherent with other competitors. In other words, how much premium have we paid to obtain that contest in Portugal. Victor Peiro asked about the same thing and <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>A collateral question to this one. If in Portugal we're competing with EDP in hydraulics and we also compete with renewables, does it make sense to continue to be shareholders of EDP?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the second question, I've already said it. Our participation in EDP is a holding we've had for many years. It's a historical issue. We've been there since '97 and, as I say, it's in the freezer for a better opportunity. And we'll see whether we pull it out of the freezer or leave it in the freezer. I think that our behavior towards them is a behavior with a company with whom we have magnificent relationships at all levels and we are not a bother to them as a partner, quite the opposite. Although we have interests elsewhere and although we also share common interests that we'll continue to share. So, this is our position.</p>
          <p>Regarding hydraulics. Paco perhaps you can say something about it. But before Paco says it I want to express my satisfaction and my recognition for the whole team, the generation team, the hydraulic generation team, that have carried out a very thorough study. So that a project, which was a contest of 400MW our specialized people, they have been specialized for over 100 years, in designing and building dams, and the contest was 400 but they saw there was room for 1,200. I think that this is the success of our engineering capability, our technological capability, and I feel extremely proud of this. I think that discovering, seeing a location that others haven't seen, and our people with this thorough analysis of seeing that the possibilities are three times greater than those laid out in the contest, I think this is a tremendous success. And, obviously, this means that the economic stakes we put into the contest is in line with what we plan to build. But Paco you can give more details.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think the key is what the Chairman has said. We put our emphasis on being able to obtain the greatest possible business and we put forward a design, which from the technical point of view was very similar to the other two competitors, from the point of view of size, and in possibilities we practically doubled what they had said, which multiplied by three or four the installed capacity that the Portuguese government put out for tender.</p>
          <p>The investment is around 1,200, 1,300 euros per kilowatt. This is lower than what others offered and where we don't see too much consistencies in the second contest where there wasn't a possibility of obtaining more business and we found premiums that from the winner and others that didn't win but took part in the contest for the first time, we've seen figures that are completely out of proportion. And the only explanation we can find is that they are making a certain effort.</p>
          <p>There's three or four times as much and these figures weren't used in the first contest, which is surprising. It's a sort of mini <mark type="inaudible" /> with three power stations, it's impressive what can be done there. And what is surprising is that in that contest they didn't offer those premiums and then they offered three or four times as much for the second contest, which is a single station downstream, and this has surprised us quite honestly. But, our unit price is lower than the other competitors and is about 1,200/1,300 euros per kilowatt, and it will take 10 years to be implemented, and we hope not to be mistaken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if there are no more questions. Well, thank you very much. Enjoy your summer and I'll see you again after the summer. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>