<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1532517" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-02-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7850</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Unverified Participant</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Jos&#xE9; Ignacio S&#xE1;nchez Gal&#xE1;n</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Operating Officer &amp; Executive Director">Jos&#xE9; Luis San Pedro Guerenabarrena</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Jos&#xE9; S&#xE1;inz Armada</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="JB Capital Markets Sociedad de Valores SA">Miguel Medina</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International">Fred Barasi</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Mizuho International Plc">Michael A. Ridley</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Pablo Cuadrado</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG Sucursal en Espa&#xF1;a (Broker)">Virginia Sanz de Madrid Grosse</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Banco Portugu&#xEA;s de Investimento SA (Spain)">Gonzalo S&#xE1;nchez Bordona</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Carolina Dores</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Director-Administrative, Elektro - Eletricidade e Servicos SA">Marcio Henrique Fernandes</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Alberto Gandolfi</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc (Italy)">Javier Suarez</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="SG Securities Services (Spain)">Jorge Alonso</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="corprep" affiliation="Director &amp; Chief Corporate Officer, Scottish Power Ltd.">Keith Anderson</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Thank you for attending this full year 2012 presentation here in our offices in London. The presentation will be structured as usual, three different speeches. The first one to be given by our Chairman and CEO, Mr. Ignacio Gal&#xE1;n, then Mr. Jos&#xE9; Luis San Pedro will explain in detail the latest development in the Spanish regulation.</p>
          <p>The presentation will be in Spanish, so I highly recommended you to take these operators for translation that you have on the back on the room. And finally, Mr. Jos&#xE9; S&#xE1;inz, CFO, who will explain the results in detail.</p>
          <p>The Q&amp;A session is as usual, first, the question from the room, then the one coming from the telephone. And finally, the one received from the website. Finally, the duration of this presentation maximum probably will be in the range of 90 minutes.</p>
          <p>Mr. Chairman?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So good morning, everyone. Thank you very much for attending this presentation for those who are here physically in London and those who is now connected to the webcast. I always appreciate very much your interest in our company.</p>
          <p>Following our presentation in the October 2014 outlook that we present here in London, we would like to start saying that Iberdrola is on track to achieve the objectives set for the period. In the most difficult year experienced in the last decade, affected by both economic crisis and regulatory uncertainty, the company has continued to achieve improved results. Sales have increased 8.1% up to &#x20AC;34.2 billion and in spite of a lower production registering 2012 and thanks to better prices. EBITDA went up 1% to &#x20AC;7.7 billion, 75% for which came from regulations on our business.</p>
          <p>Operating cash flow has increased 2.5% reaching &#x20AC;6.2 billion and contributing to strength in liquidity position of the company. Investment accounted by for &#x20AC;3.2 billion in line with our 2012-2014 plan. We also progressed positively in the completement of our divestment plan by signing an agreement to sell assets for &#x20AC;850 million, of which &#x20AC;400 million will be cash alone first semester 2013.</p>
          <p>All of the above has allowed the company to reduce net debt, which fell by &#x20AC;1.4 billion along the year. And finally, net profit has increased 9.3 percentage, a ceiling once more during the crisis &#x20AC;2.8 billion. Adjusted sales have increased 8.1% in the period boosting gross margin to &#x20AC;12.6 billion with increase of 4.6%. In network develop contribution of Spain due to the reduction of distribution and remuneration is offset by the improvement raised in United Kingdom and the states in Brazil.</p>
          <p>Renewables has significantly contributed to the positive evolution of their gross margin, thanks to 10.7% increase in production based on a higher leverage load factor and the growth in operating capacity. Finally, generation and supply has already a positive contribution to growth in gross margin thanks to higher prices and increased customer base and in spite of the lower production.</p>
          <p>EBITDA in the period increased 1% to &#x20AC;7.7 billion by businesses and that will register a 1.4% decline as the considerable increase in the UK and United States are only able to partially offset the increase in Spain and Brazil, whose EBITDA once eliminated the evaluation of the Brazilian real effect remains flat.</p>
          <p>Renewables, on the contrary, rose by 13.8% thanks to the increase in group margin, 10.5% and the efficiency gains that have allowed the company to keep net operating expenses flat along the period. Generation and supply shows an EBITDA increase of 3.7% with a good performance in all areas, especially in United Kingdom where we have considerably increased the number of customers with a significant reduction of cost per unit.</p>
          <p>All in all, as I mentioned before, 75% of EBITDA comes from the regulated renewable businesses, they're more stable in predictable activities in those times. This predictability of cash flows is one of Iberdrola's differential features over the competitors. But in the year 2006, when Iberdrola began its international expansion, our businesses mix was similar to that of our European peers today with a much longer contribution of the liberalized business to EBITDA. Three years later, three quarters of our EBITDA come from regulated and record businesses while the European peer remain in 47%.</p>
          <p>Iberdrola's net profit in 2012 amounts to &#x20AC;0.841 million, with an increase of 1.3% thanks to the international expansion that last year's 45% comes from UK and United States, 20% for Latin America while profit in Spain accounts for 30% of total results. Iberdrola has the most traded &#x2013; this has taken the right decision to deal with a tough economic environment the last years. The focus in regulated businesses achieved through its internationalization phase has allowed the company to obtain solid and sustainable result in 2008 while CESPs had declined in the volatile results.</p>
          <p>Following one of our main 2014 guidelines in 2012, all our business integrated cash flows exceeding net investment. Total operating cash flows amount &#x20AC;6.2 billion, growing 2.5%. After deducting investment, this figure almost reaches &#x20AC;3 billion. Also, according to the provision of the 2012-2014 outlook, Iberdrola has suggested investment to &#x20AC;3.3 billion to the end of 2012. 61% we are signed the networks and 23% to renewables.</p>
          <p>By geographic areas, almost 50% of our total investment were addressed to United Kingdom and United States, in line with the contribution to the net profits. For our divestment plan in 2012, Iberdrola has signed agreements to sell non-core assets and assets in non-core countries for &#x20AC;850 million, completing 40% of our prerogative. Among others, we agreed the sale of our wind farms in Germany and France and our stake in Gas Natural Mexico and Medgaz.</p>
          <p>Other operation in the final state of negotiation will be announced in the next few days. We are confident that the complete fulfillment of our &#x20AC;2 billion divestment plan will be sufficient to meet our net debt reduction estimate for 2012-2014 outlook. I would like to stress that with financial management put in 2012 have allowed us to preserve our financial strength in a very difficult environment.</p>
          <p>We have reduced net debt in almost &#x20AC;1.4 billion. This amount reaches &#x20AC;2.2 billion once you include the cash receivable from deficit securitization, security in this first week of 2013 and from the divestment increase at the end of 2012 to be cast in 2013. This enabled Iberdrola to reduce our leverage from 48% last year in 2011 to 47% including the financing of tariff deficit, excluding the later leverage fall to 45%. Additionally, we have closed the year with a liquidity position of &#x20AC;12 billion, which covers more than 36 months of our financial needs.</p>
          <p>Finally, we have had access to the capital and bank market in a favorable condition, enabling us to refinance our debt and maintain an average debt maturity around 6.2 years. Once included the last bond issue and for <mark type="ph" /> just (8:43) January 2013.</p>
          <p>Now, Pepe S&#xE1;inz, the CFO, will explain the information with more detail. Jos&#xE9; Luis San Pedro, as was already mentioned, will make a brief description now of recent regulatory <mark type="ph" /> Iberdrola (8:58) in Spain, then I'm sure that you have already interest on it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning to you. Basically, I'm going to give you a description and assessment of the three last measures published by the Spanish government 31st of December, over the Royal Decree Law in February and the draft version of the ministered order of feeding tariffs.</p>
          <p>I should give you a brief description, first of all, of the most important regulatory measures, which you're already familiar with, and which have come out through &#x2013; out 2012. Okay, the first of them is Royal Decree Law published in January 2012. It was a very quick measurement taken by the Ministry of Industry creating a moratorium for the new renewable energies and heat and power generation of cogeneration, i.e., all technologies which had incentives and which were not registered.</p>
          <p>Now the second measure taken was an unexpected cutback, an unexplainable cutback, of remuneration of regulated transport and distribution networks. And the third was the fiscal measures published on the 26th of December, fiscal measures for energy sustainability, which account for seven &#x2013; or five different tributes for different generation activities.</p>
          <p>Now the first issue, the moratorium, seems to me was a reasonable measure since there was a growth in incentives. They were growing &#x2013; were exponentially and sufficient at the same time because what should've been included were all of those plants &#x2013; already registered plants but whose inflation had begun. Not having done so, meant that this year, the more than 1,500 megawatts of renewable energy came on the line.</p>
          <p>The second decree, which affects the cutbacks in transport and distribution, was a very strong cutback, completely unexpected, and unjustified too. It doesn't answer any new model of remuneration for distribution, and my own personal opinion is that it should've been proposed by the National Energy Commission and published whereby a carry forward, not as a royal decree.</p>
          <p>The third measure, the fiscal measures, which came out in due of the final publication was in December this year &#x2013; sorry last year, is a five tribute, so taxes, all of them, are aimed to very clearly regulate and they're aimed at reducing the tariff deficit. There's a general tariff, a 7% tax which applies to all generation. We also had two other taxes, or tributes, nuclear and hydropower. We have another tax which is applied to fuels. The aim here is to reduce emissions. The coal &#x2013; this is coal and gas consumption tax.</p>
          <p>So the effects now of these taxes on the sector, of the levies on Iberdrola and our deficit as following, the first one, it is only applied to facilities we do not -that do not exist, had no short-term effect, although they will have substantial impact in the middle and the long-term. The second levy, i.e. on distribution for our sector, meant a cutback of our remuneration of &#x20AC;689 million on a total which is approximately &#x20AC;5 billion.</p>
          <p>And for Iberdrola, it meant a drop in &#x20AC;234 million cutback in remuneration, which all these levies which are going to be applied in 2013, and which corresponds to Law 15/2012, came out on the 26th of December, meant a new fiscal load for Iberdrola &#x2013; of &#x20AC;690 million per year for the sector, &#x20AC;3 billion &#x2013; &#x20AC;3.6 billion per annum in other &#x2013; for these two measures, in other words, which bring something like over &#x20AC;4 billion, the aim was to reduce the tariff deficit.</p>
          <p>Now, as I've said before, when faced with these two new taxes, have an effect on the profit-loss account. The first one is the distribution. We try it here or we're trying to &#x2013; we have tried and we will try to compensate this with a substantial reduction of our investments, that's like 50%, as well as a substantial reduction to our operating costs, both personnel costs and external services. And we've taken these measures, for example, reduced 400 head counts in the distribution and personnel in Spain, a reduction of external services too.</p>
          <p>Now, turning to how we're going to look at the increase in taxes, &#x20AC;680 million &#x2013; &#x20AC;690 million. This will depend a great deal on the rest of the sector, mainly how those units which are secondary or non-core, which might transfer to the price of these taxes. For example, for coal, all of these levies accounts for an increase of price between &#x20AC;9 and &#x20AC;10 per megawatt hour. In gas, something like &#x20AC;7. Now these are units which are marginal and which are going to pay for the price of energy.</p>
          <p>Now insofar as these costs are passed on, because of tax to the price of energy, an important part of these taxes, of the &#x20AC;3.6 billion, don't know how much will be passed on to the customer via the final price for energy.</p>
          <p>Now let's look at more up-to-date things. It was the 31 of December, I believe. The Spanish government had brought out a Royal Decree Law, which had two aims. One, was it recognized the deficit stipulated for 2012, which it was &#x20AC;1.5 billion, had been exceeded with &#x20AC;5.5 billion. The basic result of this deviation, well, various reasons for them, but the main one was that part of the income which we were counted on to increase costs in the sector were not put in the general budget of the state.</p>
          <p>For example, the operating incentives which are given for islands to compensate for the costs they support above the average peninsula cost. And so therefore, the first thing the government had to do in this Royal Decree Law is they recognized that they have not fulfilled their deficit objective and that the deficit had been accepted &#x2013; exceeded a great deal.</p>
          <p>Now the second aim, and this is a positive one, it seems to me, if this law had been applied as it was, without this new Royal Decree, this excess of deficit should have been passed on automatically to the 2013 tariffs, giving rise to a substantial increase in tariffs, and particularly, giving rise to regulatory uncertainty in this sector, which was pretty substantial because if the tariffs increase a great deal, the aim of the government would have been to try to find new cutbacks in the sector.</p>
          <p>This has not been the case. It has been &#x2013; this capital has been recognized as a securitization deficit. We could securitize it or give it this year &#x2013; or seed it this year, through the company <mark type="ph" /> Ibea (17:35) the company which is looking at the securitization of all this issue and it could be securitized this year and the following year.</p>
          <p>Now, so it has been a realistic royal decree on one hand, and on the other hand, it's not been too good &#x2013; not too bad for our sector. Let's look at the last two measures now. The Royal Decree Law 12 of 2013 defined as urgent measures for electric and financial sectors.</p>
          <p>As regarding the electric sector, first of all, the first measure is that in the rate of &#x2013; I'm sorry, the uptake rate which has been used now to uptake the value of incentives of premiums and in general, all regulated costs, was the IPC minus 5.5 points of the retail price index, the RPI, sorry. So the numbers of the RPI are desegregated from the energy costs and other levies.</p>
          <p>Now, the effect of this change has a negative effect which is one-off, because in the long-term as a trend, these two rates would need to be similar. And then the change of the index has a logical reason for it, the regulated costs are not &#x2013; did not have a great deal to do with the increase in taxes and don't have rate include energy costs. So the measure as a measure has its logic behind it but it does have a negative effect on remuneration of the sector for 2013.</p>
          <p>The reason is that in 2012, the RPI was highly conditioned by taxes for example, basically VAT, so part of the 3% of the increase of the RPI last year was due to an increase in VAT.</p>
          <p>Now the second measure is the &#x2013; it's a substantial change in the remuneration system and the special regime. So those facilities have a special regime, which wants to go to the market &#x2013; don't give premiums or don't want to go to the market but have to go to a tariff regime.</p>
          <p>Now this measure, from my own point of view, has two important effects. First of all, is that it didn't seem to be reasonable or logical that a renewal of technology could go between markets and going to the tariff because the forecast for market price has been low. Well now I'm going &#x2013; not to the market because the prices are going to be high. This kind of arbitrage in a business, which is purely regulated, didn't make much sense. And so from the conceptual point of view, this measure doesn't really seem logical.</p>
          <p>The second one, the most important reason for me, is that since we went from the markets to tariff, a reduction is essential because tariffs give you a remuneration with notably lower than what we've got on the market plus the premium.</p>
          <p>And the third consequence, which seems to me important is that they don't even call it a premium, they're called tariffs. A tariff is something which is there to define in the criteria for remuneration and the value of this remuneration in the National Commission of Energy and the Ministry of Industry. In other words, currently again in my opinion, all renewables as well as transport and distribution are activities which are regulated, whose remuneration and whose procedures of calculation for that remuneration belong to the regulator, which are the National Energy Commission and the Spanish Ministry of Industry.</p>
          <p>With that, we hope, is that all technologies would be dealt with in the future on an equal footing. We cannot think, for example, one regulated activity should be remunerated with a certain level of 6%, another one with 12%. This is the most important thing for me. These are the definition as a remuneration system for all the regulated businesses. And this is the whole thing about the tariff.</p>
          <p>And finally, well, the effects. What about the effects, which this has had on this sector, on Iberdrola itself, of this Royal Decree Law has been a change in the system of updating, of retribution, of remuneration. The RPI, retail price index, without levies and <mark type="ph" /> treaty (22:38) and this is a reduction of cutback in the distribution transfer of &#x20AC;10 million and, in sector as a whole, &#x20AC;70 million.</p>
          <p>And then we have a special regime. This effect, plus the change to tariff for Iberdrola, means a cutback of &#x20AC;100 million of the sector as a whole, &#x20AC;600 million. In other words, with this Royal Decree, in addition to other objectives which are, where we regulated, means a drop in the deficit for 2013 of &#x20AC;670 million. For Iberdrola, the cutback in this remuneration falls by &#x20AC;110 million, but we'll see that there are other aspects which are contemplated in what I'm going to be talking about. This is the proposal of tariff orders and it sort of completely obliterates these effects as you'll see shortly.</p>
          <p>Now the proposal of the tariff order, which has not come out yet is still a proposal. It's in draft. Maybe it'll come out tomorrow or on Friday. The idea is to freeze feeding tariffs, i.e. there will be no increase in access tariffs or feeding tariffs. And secondly, most importantly, it's believed that the whole series of new income, which will tend to finance the regulated cost of the sector.</p>
          <p>What are these new sources of income? First of all, the levies or taxes which are going to be got or gotten with this layer of sustainability which came out 26 of December, which I've just mentioned. The calculation of tariffs is regarded as &#x20AC;2.9 billion. Now in our calculations, some &#x20AC;3.5 billion can be found. But initially, the law says that either the general budget of the state only take onboard &#x20AC;2.9 billion, although we believe this figure will be higher.</p>
          <p>The second effect is that 90% of the revenues from the auctions of CO2 emissions will reduce the tariff deficit. This has been calculated &#x20AC;450 million. It seems to me, these government figures, that this is optimistic. Bear in mind, the quotations we have for CO2, the third which was the most surprising of all is that a credit, an extraordinary credit from the government to the Ministry of Industry for the &#x20AC;2.2 billion to tackle not only sector costs of this credit, but the ministry, or the regulator, will be using &#x2013; gradually using as first initial settlements as we get negative results. In other terms, initially, this credit will replace financing which has been given to companies to date.</p>
          <p>Now in addition to this, it's a grant, it's a non-returnable grant, it's public debt regarded as this, it's also regarded as public debt, I repeat. And finally, this whole tariff order, like the previous one, also considers that in the island incentives for 2013, which is &#x20AC;1.7 billion, will be regarded as expenditure in the general state budget for 2014 and therefore they will not consume tariff deficit.</p>
          <p>Now these are &#x2013; this is new revenue if you add them all up, the final figure I believe is &#x2013; I've written it down somewhere &#x2013; &#x20AC;7.3 billion, something like that. Again, another positive aspect is that we have a whole series of costs which are recognized for 2013 and which have already been recognized in previous years but have not been paid to us. I'm talking more specifically about the fact that we have &#x20AC;732 million for costs of transport and distribution and to compensate or offset the incentives which we had assigned to us for improvement in the quality of the service or a result of leakages of energy loss.</p>
          <p>Total amount of costs which applied &#x2013; we don't know the &#x2013; what I'm talking about something like &#x20AC;500 million for distribution but it will be applied on &#x2013; part of it will be in cash flow because they recognize this from past years and part will be on income, accounted income for 2013. Now after that, the regulation system changes of the interim for customers who can do this or the interruptions, we have an increase in costs but this does not affect us directly nor does it affect our deficit.</p>
          <p>And finally, it also considers provisions. We'll see whether these are implemented or not, which will come out &#x20AC;308 million earmarked for updating the financial cost, which we have to finance our debt. I'm talking about five companies in a sector which are &#x2013; have recognized &#x2013; has recognized 2% as a ruling of the Supreme Tribunal is that we should have all of these costs recognized. They devote part from &#x20AC;200 million &#x2013; &#x20AC;250 million to the updating of this kind, of this interest rates. Then we have the &#x20AC;100 million to be given, to be returned by the ruling of the Supreme Tribunal certain payments for certain aspects or certain items.</p>
          <p>Now, so here, we have the calculation for the forecast for our tariff deficit 2013, which is done by the Spanish ministry by the way. The regulated costs, without an increase in tariffs and with an increase in demand of minus 0.2%, is simple, I think. The other income I've already mentioned &#x2013; CO2 auctions, fiscal measures and government or extraordinary credit access costs or feeding costs.</p>
          <p>Fixed data, you know this already, special regime as we go and add new facilities with the same as we've had to date or calculated in line with the price of electrical tariff. Transport intuition against a fixed figure deficit or annual deficit which are pending or which are securitized, again, fixed figure. Depend deposits, depends on interest so I'd say that of this calculation, we have three uncertainties. One, if the demand is going to grow, so minus zero two or minus &#x2013; zero minus one.</p>
          <p>Here we have an uncertainty of &#x2013; the other one is the fiscal one for &#x20AC;21 million. And if these are carried out as the law, if we carry out all incomes would bring down the deficit, we could have &#x20AC;3.5 billion. Now the third uncertainty is to see whether in 2014, the ministry is going to take charge of the cost of the incentives, which are paid to the islands, i.e., &#x20AC;1.7 billion. I'd say that all told, a reasonable probability we've not seen in the past is that we can fulfill this deficit. Although we'll be very clear if we don't get it, we'll get near to it.</p>
          <p>Now by way of conclusion, on these last few measures, what I say here is that at least initially, these three measures have a neutral effect, if they have any, on Iberdrola's financial results. Secondly, that these measures, at least from my point of view and from the regulatory point of view, seemed to be correct, to be right. They made later foundations to have a regulation system, which is stable and transparent visibility.</p>
          <p>And thirdly, the calculation of the deficit made by the government for 2013 seems to me, personally, pretty realistic. Having said &#x2013; that said, I'd like to add that I also believe that in spite of a fact that there had been very harsh measures for this sector as was for the consumer, I believe it's reasonable to think that with these measures in 2013, we will put an end, for once and for all, with the tariff deficit.</p>
          <p>That's all I have to say. Thank you very much for your attention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. So we shall now proceed briefly to analyze the relevant issues of the income statement, the performance of the different businesses and the group's financial situation. The chairman has pointed out, despite the difficult environment, the group shows a 1% and a 2.5% growth in EBITDA and customer generation and reported net profit is up 1.3%.</p>
          <p>Net sales are up 8.1% to &#x20AC;3.4 billion and procurements froze 11.2% to &#x20AC;21.5 billion, maintaining the growth trend during the year. Gross margins increased 4.6% to almost &#x20AC;12.6 billion, thanks to the higher international activity and the positive foreign exchange impact. The basic margin is up 3.5% to &#x20AC;12.7 billion, slightly below the growth of the gross margin as revenues from CO2 allowances fell 51% due to CO2 lower prices and consumption.</p>
          <p>Net operating expenses are up 7.7%, due to higher nonrecurring personnel expenses associated with efficiency plans that will have its returns in next year some plant closures. But recurrent net operating expenses were up only 1.5%, mainly due to the Elektro consolidation. They would have been flat otherwise or would have fallen 1.9% excluding the FX impact. Net personnel expenses rose 11.9% due to a &#x20AC;160 million of non-recurring costs related to efficiency plans and plant closures, recurrent net personnel expenses rose 1.7%.</p>
          <p>Net external services were up 4.4% considering a net &#x20AC;23 million negative impact of non-recurring expenses associated mainly with penalties paid in 2012. Recurring net external services rose 1.3%. Levies are up 6.9%, despite the favorable Spanish Supreme Court ruling that exempts generation companies from financing the social tariff, the social bonus and the reversion of Castilla-La Mancha eco tax after a positive court ruling. The increase is due to the higher local taxes in Spain and higher costs related to the CERT/CESP programs in the UK, where levies have increased &#x20AC;134 million due to the requirement to be completed in 2012.</p>
          <p>In Spain, levies were up 12.3%, excluding these court rulings. Nevertheless, there are several taxes that Iberdrola has appealed, still pending on court decisions that hopefully, we will have impact positively in our P&amp;L in these next years. As already explained by the chairman, the 1% growth in EBITDA is driven by our international activities, which account for 52% of total EBITDA and for a positive FX impact of &#x20AC;114 million. Both generation and supply and renewals have seen their EBITDA rising 3.7% and 13.8% respectively.</p>
          <p>While networks EBITDA fell 1.4% to &#x20AC;3.8 billion due to the cuts imposed by the Royal Decree that Jos&#xE9; Luis has just mentioned to &#x20AC;133 million on the Spanish networks and a fourth quarter one-off impacts in Brazil and the U.S. Spain represent 35% of EBITDA, the UK 25%, the U.S. 18% and Brazil 22%.</p>
          <p>The Q4 one-off can be explained in the U.S. by the impact of the Sandy hurricane that has had a negative impact of &#x20AC;48 million for our operations in the U.S. and that will be recovered in the next first case. In Brazil due to the drought, distribution companies have to buy thermal capacity despite at higher prices that will be passed through to the consumers in the next yearly review period. So we are right now buying at higher prices but that will be passed to the consumers in the next review period.</p>
          <p>There has been for that reason another minor reasons, a &#x20AC;74 million negative impact due to the IFRS accounting methodology. If we would have been accounting this through GAAP, we wouldn't have seen this impact on the accounts.</p>
          <p>The review month for Elektro is August and for Neo is April. So as I was mentioning, the negative impact should be compensated by a positive one after the review has happened. The impact is a spread during one year until the next review, so this negative impact is compensated through a one year after the month of August in the case of Neo, in the case of Elektro, and in the case of Neo after April.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, the outlook for 2013 in Brazil still is challenging. In addition to the drought that continues and we are seeing these negative impacts in the months of January and February, there is also a lack of access to generation PPAs as auctions were canceled and producers are selling their electricity in the sport market. This is forcing Elektro to buy around 8% of its needs again in the market at higher prices with the same negative accounting impact as the drought. So, this will be also be recovered in the next tariff review.</p>
          <p>EBITDA in Spain networks fell 13.3% due to the &#x20AC;233 million cut as I mentioned, which represents an 8.5% drop in the regulated revenues. As a consequence, the gross margin fell 8.2%. Net operating expenses grew 6.5% due to higher non-recurring costs linked to efficiency measures as Jos&#xE9; Luis just pointed. That will provide a positive impact in the following years.</p>
          <p>Also, levies increased by 20% due to higher local taxes. EBITDA in UK networks was up 12.6% to &#x20AC;937 million, driven by the higher revenues as a consequence of the record investments of &#x20AC;560 million that Storage Power has done in the UK this year in distribution and a positive impact of this appreciation of the sterling of 6.6%. So the EBITDA in pounds was up 5.2%. Net operating expenses increased by &#x20AC;30 million due to the higher costs associated with the complying of the <mark type="ph" /> DP share of (39:42) regulatory targets and the FX impact.</p>
          <p>The U.S. network's EBITDA under IFRS rose 20.5% to &#x20AC;660 million, including a positive impact of &#x20AC;50 million but compensated with its &#x20AC;48 million negative impact of the Sandy. So, the underlying positive &#x2013; the underlying evolution of the business has been very positive and we are close to our return on equity targets. This has been caused by higher revenues from the red cases and an increased contribution from the main transmission line, despite also the sale of some non-regulated companies.</p>
          <p>Despite the dollar strength, there is also an improvement in net operating expenses due to some non-recurring conditions and the different scope of consolidation. EBITDA in Brazil has decreased 7% to &#x20AC;827 million as a result of the fourth quarter mentioned impacts with an impact of &#x20AC;74 million at EBITDA level together with the Elektro lower tariff in place as you know since August 2012.</p>
          <p>The 4.6% increase in demand and the full consolidation of Elektro are more than compensated by the above mentioned negative effects. In addition to this, we have an exchange rate adverse impact in the case of the real of &#x20AC;63 million. Net operating expenses were up 23%, due basically to the Elektro full consolidation and the additional activity of the companies.</p>
          <p>Now we will analyze the generation and supply business that includes Spain, UK and Mexico. EBITDA is up 3.7% to &#x20AC;2.3 billion, improving the fall of 1.7% at September with good performance, as the chairman has mentioned, in all areas, as lower outputs and higher costs are more than offset by better prices and positive FX impact.</p>
          <p>Spain has had a better performance growing 2.2% compared to the almost flat September EBITDA. This, together with the good evolution of the business in the UK and a positive FX impact in Mexico, compensates the &#x20AC;221 million negative impact of the third CESP programs in the UK. Net operating expenses are up 12% mainly due to nonrecurring efficiency measures in Spain and the UK.</p>
          <p>Levies are up 1.4% as the favorable Spanish Supreme Court ruling that exempts generation companies does not compensate the increase in local taxes. And obviously, the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (42:34) impact. About the generation and supply business in Spain is worth highlighting that demand was down 1.4% in 2012.</p>
          <p>Iberdrola output in the ordinary regime has been down 15%, driven by a 39% lower hydro production and a 64% lower combined cycle production, partially compensated by a 7.1% increase in nuclear production. The basic margin is slightly down. Net operating expenses increased by 10%, due to nonrecurring effects and other expenses related to supply business.</p>
          <p>Excluding nonrecurring, net operating expenses in this business is down 3.9%. On the other hand, the lower levies as a consequence of the Spanish Supreme Court ruling about the social bonus compensates the slightly drop of the basic margin. However, excluding this effect, levies are up 7.2%. EBITDA is finally up 2.2% to &#x20AC;1.6 billion.</p>
          <p>For 2013, 45 terawatt hours of production have been sold on prices similar to last year. The basic margin in the UK generation and supply business has reached &#x20AC;1.1 billion, a 23% increase maintaining the growth path of September, driven mainly by the supply business with margins recovering since minimum levels in 2011, thanks to the improvement in the procurement cost and a 7.7% increase in new customers, which is very important.</p>
          <p>It also reflects a positive FX impact of &#x20AC;75 million. All of these effects more than compensate the 20% lower output due to plant stoppages and lower gas spreads that have affected the business. Tariff increases compensate the higher non-energy cost that suppliers are suffering in the UK. Net operating expenses have risen 8.2%, affected by efficiency measures and the appreciation of the pound.</p>
          <p>Finally, as levies have increased &#x20AC;138 million due to these programs, EBITDA growth is lower to 4.5% in British pounds. EBITDA in Mexico grew 5% to &#x20AC;380 million. The operating performance of the business shows a 9.5% rise in gross margin level with better margins compensating plant outages and with a positive FX impact.</p>
          <p>Net operating expenses have increased &#x20AC;24 million, &#x20AC;9 million of them out of the FX impact and the rest from non-recurring items as lower compensation from suppliers that we had for damages in 2011. Renewables improves its performance as the 4% higher operating capacity to 13,735 megawatts and a 2.5% higher load factor to 26.3% resulted in a 10.7% higher output to 31,784 gigawatt hours with growth in all geographic areas that has driven EBITDA of 13.8% to &#x20AC;1.6 billion. The main drivers, as mentioned, are the 10.7% higher output and the higher average prices, &#x20AC;71 per megawatt hour versus &#x20AC;69 per megawatt hour in 2011, due to the exchange rate evolution and the higher contribution of the areas with a higher selling price.</p>
          <p>Net operating expenses are flat due to non-recurrent expenses, but there is a 4.6% improvement of net operating expenses per megawatt. All these factors have driven a 15.8% growth in EBITDA from the pure renewable activities. The installed capacity is up 14,034 megawatts or 2.5% up after the sale of the wind farms in France and Germany. So we have already taken away the wind farms in France and Germany from this figure.</p>
          <p>EBIT drops 2.8% showing a worse evolution on EBITDA mainly due to a 7.6% increase in amortizations due to plant closures, the integration of Elektro and the investments in networks and renewables partially compensated by the increase in the useful life of wind farms. The 1.1% increase in provisions included in 2012 write-offs linked to renewables canceled projects, some nonrecurring provisions in Brazil related to bad debt, another write-offs that we have accounted in gas assets in the U.S. 2011 including almost &#x20AC;300 million of provision related to thermal assets, mainly Longannet, which have been replaced by the previously mentioned write-offs.</p>
          <p>The net financial results have increased 3.6% to minus &#x20AC;1.1 billion driven by two factors. First, the interest expense that are &#x20AC;19 million more than last year. This is a consequence of the higher average debt, partially compensated by a decrease in the cost of debt to 4.5%, even after including a seven basis points impact in increase due to the full-year consolidation of Elektro, which has <mark type="ph" /> 13 (48:07) reales. The increase in cost debt is more relevant if you consider the reduction to almost half of our alliance in commercial paper and the increase fixed component of it.</p>
          <p>Second, the lower market value of FX hedges linked to the results in foreign currency, as last year, both the sterling and pound &#x2013; both the pound and the dollar dropped in value versus the euro. And in 2012, they have reversed. Derivative negative results have been compensated by a one-off positive effect due to the Medgaz sale agreement of &#x20AC;105 million accounted in Q4. In this line, as it is considered &#x2013; or it was considered as a financial investment.</p>
          <p>As a consequence of all this, the reported net profit is up 1.3% to &#x20AC;2.8 million or &#x20AC;2.840 million as positive number current tax impacts more than compensate write-offs at the provisions and the results on company consolidated by the equity methods. Funds from operations have increased 2.5% to &#x20AC;6.2 billion.</p>
          <p>The write-offs amount &#x20AC;428 million, of which &#x20AC;144 million is included as provisions have already been explained and &#x20AC;199 million are provisions that we have done in the value of the stake of Gamesa, due to the new expectations from the new business plan. This &#x2013; it has been partially compensated with positive number current results of &#x20AC;91 million, mostly related to capital gains for asset sales and in the U.S. and Medgaz.</p>
          <p>The effective tax rate is 6.7% as a consequence of &#x20AC;700 million of positive corporate tax impacts. Main tax impacts are the following, Elektro's goodwill deductibility for &#x20AC;275 million and reversion of fiscal provisions for &#x20AC;259 million, mainly in the U.S. and a two percentage points lower tax in the UK &#x2013; tax rate in the UK.</p>
          <p>Going to the financing part. During 2012, there has been a reduction in the tariff deficit spending collection of &#x20AC;582 million. During 2012, Iberdrola collected &#x20AC;1,951 million, &#x20AC;1,754 million through the tariff deficit securitization program and &#x20AC;197 through tariffs. But we still have pending &#x20AC;2.4 billion at the end of 2012.</p>
          <p>In 2013, &#x20AC;1,479 million has been collected for this sector. &#x20AC;1 billion from a further public placement and &#x20AC;479 million through four private placements. As a result, Iberdrola has collected in 2013, &#x20AC;460 million additional. So, for the sector, &#x20AC;3.6 billion out of the &#x20AC;7 billion already transferred are still pending to be securitized and as Jos&#xE9; Luis San Pedro mentioned, the 212 tariff deficit excess of &#x20AC;3.6 billion has been entitled to be securitized as well, so the total amount pending for the sector to be collected is around &#x20AC;7 billion and in the case of Iberdrola, &#x20AC;2.4 billion.</p>
          <p>Iberdrola during this year, as the chairman has mentioned, has reduced its leverage from 48.8% at the end of 2011 to 47.1% while our debt has gone down at the end of 2012 by close to &#x20AC;1.4 billion to &#x20AC;30.3 billion. And as you can see, all the financial ratios reflect the level of reduction and the cash flow growth meeting the year-end target of FFO over net debt about 20% and retained cash flow over net debt of about 16%. Retained cash flow over net debt shows an almost flat evolution even considering that the 2012 ratio includes two dividend payments and the 2011 ratio included only one dividend payment.</p>
          <p>So, as of today, there are an additional &#x20AC;866 million of debt reduction, including the divestments already done but not collected. So the divestments done in 2012 at the end of 2012 have not been collected, this is meth gas and renewables in France and Germany. And the deficits securitizations of 2013 already mentioned, not including in the 2012 year ended.</p>
          <p>This reduces our debt on a pro forma basis from &#x20AC;30.3 billion to &#x20AC;29.5 billion. Including these assets disposals and the securitization proceeds of to-date in 2013, our solvency ratios improved even more, compared to 2012 financial ratios reported, as you can see, in the bottom part of the slide reaching an FFO over net debt of 21% and a retained cash flow net &#x2013; over net debt of 17.6%.</p>
          <p>As you can imagine and expecting new divestments and new securitizations in the next days or weeks, we feel very comfortable in terms of the outlook of our debt. The securitization process continues under the divestment plan together with a cash flow generation makes us feel that we will continue to reduce our debt as expected or even further.</p>
          <p>Iberdrola has increased its liquidity up to &#x20AC;12 billion from &#x20AC;11.3 billion at September, of which &#x20AC;3 billion are in cash and almost &#x20AC;9 billion in unused credit lines, of which &#x20AC;5 billion mature in 2015 onwards. With this position, we have liquidity assured for the next three years and for 30 months even in the most stressed scenarios.</p>
          <p>So Iberdrola has a comfortable maturity calendar of its debt. We have up to December 2014 debt maturing for &#x20AC;5.4 billion, or only 45% of the total liquidity available. We have also maintained our average debt maturity in 6.2 years after the last liability management transactions in January with an issuance of an end year bond in the Euro market for &#x20AC;1 billion and the exchange of &#x20AC;721 million of bonds maturing in 2014 and 2015.</p>
          <p>So let me conclude reiterating our confident outlook that we have in a positive evolution of our debt and the financial strength of the group. And now, the chairman will end up the presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the result we are presenting today once again &#x2013; the ability of Iberdrola to obtain increased result even in this difficult environment and this regulatory scenario. Although the phase of international expansion of Iberdrola began six years ago, the company has already developed a management model that has allowed us to overcome this year of economic turmoil and regulatory instability.</p>
          <p>Thanks to this model focused on the diversification of businesses, EBITDA in total growth, 1% to &#x20AC;7.7 billion with 75% of regulated renewable business and for us has been always treated as regulated as now is recognized by the Spanish government. Our net profit amounts to more than &#x20AC;2.8 billion with an increase of 1.3%, boosted for the international activities as well. We've contributed to 70% of our total net income.</p>
          <p>During 2012, our financial management strategy has already delivered positive result with a net debt reduction of nearly &#x20AC;1.4 billion with adjustment that the financial director was mentioning, with the funds received from the deficit securitization in the first week of 2013, and the cash receivable from divestment already collected &#x2013; signed at December last year. This amount reaches &#x20AC;2.2 billion reduction. Moreover, we have been able to significantly improve our liquidity position from &#x20AC;9.3 billion to more than &#x20AC;3 billion has been mentioned as well from the financial director.</p>
          <p>The result obtained during 2012 allow us to face the coming year with a confident and despite the significant challenges to our businesses in 2013, we're on track to achieve our 2012-2014 outlook. We will face the accomplished macroeconomic environment with presence in market with growth prospect in Latin America, United States and United Kingdom.</p>
          <p>According with the latest international market forecast, 2013 GDP growth in these areas will be 3.5%, 2%, 1%, respectively. The present evolution of exchange rates and the strengthening of the euro represent an additional challenge for ourselves. We are prepared to confront that through a strategy based on a diversified structure of debt and exchange rate hedges.</p>
          <p>As for regulatory issues, as been mentioned by Jos&#xE9; Luis San Pedro, I will have to stress that despite uncertainty that was in 2012, we now have greater visibility than a year ago.</p>
          <p>In Spain, the measures recently adopted have an impact in our businesses but give more rationality to renewables activities and networks, constituting in a step forward to eliminate tariff deficit, it has been ensured system sustainability.</p>
          <p>Concerning the UK, the further definition of the energy market reform to be concluded in 2013 in order to provide clarity needed to promote required investments, beside the written market review, should help implement a real true and free energy market.</p>
          <p>Under these circumstances, we will affirm our commitment for strengthening the balance sheet and we expect to reduce net debt faster than estimated, through our cash flow generation capacity and the divestment program underway. Furthermore, this decision process has been reactivated, allowing us to cash more than &#x20AC;1 billion since October.</p>
          <p>Additionally, we will work to preserve our liquidity position in order to have our financial need covered by at least two years at any time.</p>
          <p>From the different business perspective, growth will be focused on regulated activities in UK and United States. Additionally, and in spite of increasing environment obligation in non-energy cost, I would like to underline the positive prospect of our retail business in UK, which has grown its customer base reflecting the improvement of our service.</p>
          <p>It has been highlighted in the last customer satisfaction survey in which the ScottishPower appears as a company with the highest customer satisfaction rates. Also, ScottishPower has obtained the lowest complaint level of the end report of complaints performance. They are released this morning.</p>
          <p>Finally, let me underline the positive evolution of the operating figures recorded along these first months of the year. In particular, a good performance of wind and hydro output will help us to mitigate a bit the negative impact of the drought in Brazil and the new taxation in Spain.</p>
          <p>Progress in the achievement of 2012-2014 outlook and in particular in the net debt reduction of the &#x20AC;2 billion in roughly four months, has allowed the board of directors to submit to the general meeting the following two proposals.</p>
          <p>Firstly, a total shareholder remuneration of approximately &#x20AC;0.305 per share in line with the policy disclosed during last Investor Day. &#x20AC;0.143 we already paid last month and the rest will be distributed in July. Moreover, the company will pay as usual, an Annual General Meeting attendance premium of &#x20AC;0.005 per share.</p>
          <p>The surprise additional &#x2013; and that is absolutely new, a 2.4% capital reduction instrumented through a redemption of the existing 1.4% treasury stock and 1% share buyback program. The capital reduction is offset by a hybrid bond which provide accounting and fiscal advantages. This capital reduction requested by some of our shareholders minimize the dilution effect of this scrip dividend while keeping its fiscal advantages.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention. Now, we will reply to your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are going to start with the questions from the room, first question? Miguel Medina from JB Capital. Please, but wait, on the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Miguel Medina from JB Capital. On the issue of questions, the first one on distribution in Spain, you mentioned that you're expecting to reduce CapEx by 50%, as a result of the changes in regulation. Is this one-off or you see CapEx sustain at those levels for the coming two, three years?</p>
          <p>The second question is you mentioned the impact of the cost of Sandy in the U.S. &#x2013; in the New York business. Are you planning to bring forward the rate case review on the back of the impact of Sandy?</p>
          <p>And the third and final question in the &#x2013; our financial section, you address the &#x2013; this hybrid issue to cover the cost of the buyback. Can you give us an idea of the cost of this hybrid issue? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I think you start with this one we had.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we will launch it. We have obviously a target cost. And if we are able to get the cost and we hope that we will, then we will &#x2013; we will issue. But right now, the idea is to launch it and we will see how it goes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So related, first one, the distribution in Spain, as you remember in our presentation of our outlook to 2014, 2012 to 2014. We mentioned in Spain we are going to reduce the investment and we are going to reduce the cost, expecting the new framework for distribution.</p>
          <p>So in this moment, we are already, we have certain signs but still we have not enough clarity. So I think we are already managing this one if the model we'd finally, is produced we hope we will produce during this year, allow ourselves in the &#x2013; to get the proper return in investment, we will have active investment whatever is should be already properly paid. So I think that is today for this year but it should be modified we have certain flexibility according with the expected return on the new framework that they are going to &#x2013; they're planning to present to us.</p>
          <p>Relative to Sandy, so our plan is correct to me, I don't know if anybody from United States. So the plan is in this year, we in any case, we are going to present &#x2013; Javier is here, right? &#x2013; this year we are going to present the real case to be applied by 2014 onwards. So I think it was planned with Sandy, and without Sandy in any case. So at certain &#x2013; is that we'll include it in the new rate case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, Fred Barasi, at the back, behind...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, it's Fred Barasi from Goldman Sachs. Three questions from me, firstly just continuing on the Spanish electricity distribution, I wonder could you give any update on when we might expect some clarity on the regulation? I understand that that's something that they're looking at in the relatively short-term. Do you expect that, say in the first half of this year?</p>
          <p>Secondly, on the tariff deficit, you say that the 2013 deficit should be close to zero, which makes sense but clearly, &#x20AC;2.2 billion of that is an extraordinary low which is one-off in nature. What are your expectations for the 2014 deficit? And do you have any &#x2013; do you see any risk to further intervention there?</p>
          <p>And then finally, again on the buyback and the scrip dividend you are &#x2013; currently, you remain in treasury shares now. Can we expect a larger buyback potentially next year or would you consider maybe discontinuing the scrip? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, good question. So I think perhaps the two, the second and the third, I can already reply together. So as in &#x2013; for the moment is very positive, the fact that for first time in the last &#x2013; I'm in the company for three years now. So in the last two years, we've been facing this deficit and no one single penny has been already taken from the national budget into the tariff, but we have been putting a lot of money from the tariff into the national budget.</p>
          <p>It's the first time in three years, when funds from the national budget is already allocated into national tariff, which I think is a very good sign. So I think it's a very good sign. The fact as well then it's consider that inside on the tariff this year that is going to be included for next year budget. So the extra cost of the island is a very good sign as well.</p>
          <p>So I think these two things I think it's a change on trend for what we've been leading up to now. So what is going to happen in 2014? Certain <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:06:10) trends. I'm not seeing why there are any reason to withdraw those ones. So I think the problem will remain, they are already committed with this action of the government to end with the deficit. You're now seeing why they are going to change the trend afterwards.</p>
          <p>So I think that is not a loan, that is just money taken from the treasury, inside they call it a loan, but whatever you would like to call it. But it's money which is, as the general director was mentioning, if that is a Spanish deficit and a Spanish debt. So it means it's money from the national budget into the system, which I'm not seeing any reason why next year they have the same problem. They cannot be already put it out there.</p>
          <p>And that's the same thing with the buyback. I think for a long time, certain of our investors, especially the institutional, has already been and they understand why we are making this great. That is because our retailers are very pleased with us because they have already tax, very favorable taxation.</p>
          <p>So well, they said yes, they had very favorable taxation but what about ourselves? It's the first time we take the decision. I think we've been already in our 2014, 2012-2014 outlook.  I was mentioning that we are thinking on the possibility, now the possibility is decision. The decision, why? Because the things are going better in terms of that than they were expected. And the results are going better than we were expecting, that's why we took the decision.</p>
          <p>So I'm not saying the things goes in the same direction. If we start &#x2013; could is possible that but we are not &#x2013; what we commit now is what we commit. And I think it's a good change of trend, that's it. We should see what is going to happen. If it's going well, probably the trend will continue but I'm not committed more than what we are committed now is what we are going to present in the General Shareholder's Meeting. So for 2.4% of buyback shares, that's it. But in both cases, it's a good sign.</p>
          <p>Electricity distribution clarity. Correct me if I'm not already completely &#x2013; if I'm not wrong. So in the regulation Jos&#xE9; Luis San Pedro mentioned that in all these things of the tariff, there was something like &#x20AC;500 million extra for distribution. And for &#x2013; why this &#x20AC;500 million extra for distribution? They're underlying that we &#x2013; they are recognizing the investment, the remunerated investment, we made in 2011, which I think that's positive as well.</p>
          <p>So it means &#x2013; it seems it's a sign as well in the direction they are going to move is that the investment &#x2013; the future investment we are going to make will be already remunerated in a certain manner. So there is certain clarity of the reduction very, let's say, with not enough logic in March last year. Now they are already moving back in a direction that practically they are paying back again half of the amount we have been deducted or reduced in March. Why? Because they are underlying that recognizing the remuneration existing plus remunerating the investment already done in 2011.</p>
          <p>What we expect? We expect during the year that these can be already put it black-and-white in the same direction, but the sign is positive as well in this direction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question this gentleman. Here. And then Pablo Cuadrado.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think San Pedro had been saying to me that roughly from this &#x20AC;500 million, roughly 35% to 40% is for ourselves. So that is for your information.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Michael Ridley from Mizuho International. Two questions for me. Your October strategy presentation, you talked about long-term goals of pulling net debt to EBITDA below 3.2 times and net debt to below &#x20AC;26 billion. You didn't mention either of those two targets this morning. I'm just wondering if those are still targets you hold or if FFO debt is your main target.</p>
          <p>And secondly, just a bit more clarity maybe on your hybrid. I'm wondering, EDF's done a multi-trans multi-currency hybrid. Is that something you're looking at or would you just look for the one currency and presumably you'd look to go well after Telecom Italia. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, obviously the targets are absolutely in place is 3.2 net debt to EBITDA and this &#x20AC;26 billion absolutely in place. And in the hybrid, we are going to do a very small hybrid. So I don't think that we need to do any trans basically. As we are mentioning, the amount of the hybrid is the one that will be able to offset the capital reductions. So we will be talking around &#x20AC;500 million, not more, and it will be &#x2013; we are not going to increase it and et cetera. That is the amount that we are targeting to do. A small hybrid to offset the capital reduction, &#x20AC;500 million around is the maximum amount that we are going to be making.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, now in the center, Pablo Cuadrado.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning everyone. It's Pablo Cuadrado from Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Just a few questions, the first one totally focus on the regulation, looking to the latest measures and also looking to the change that it was coming from the Secretary of Energy, et cetera. Can you clarify as if you are seeing the government in a more willingness position in order to negotiate the reforms that still are pending for the industry?</p>
          <p>Second question more on the numbers, I would like to have a view about the CapEx, I think this is the second year in a row where CapEx is going down, clearly you flagged that already, Capital Market last year, but I wanted to know which is the level that you are seeing the CapEx for 2013 onwards, basically where &#x2013; if you did the same reference that we have seen during 2012?</p>
          <p>And just the third question on a little bit of guidance for 2013, if I may, particularly on the tax rate and later on, I think you have properly explained how the year is looking to Brazil, looking to Spain, et cetera, how do you see the EBITDA or the net profit performing versus 2012? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you talk about regulation, I understand it's Spain, we are part of this thing, we have regulation in other country. 70% is our growth of Spain.</p>
          <p>So I guess in 2015 because systematically, you see in the early kind of regulation is in Spain, fortunately we have Spain another one. But saying that, I think the general director was very clear on that. I think the new general secretary has absolutely a different approach. He's trying to add much more dialogue, he's trying to put rationality into the things and the connection and the level of capability of approach in whatever thing is much better than it was.</p>
          <p>So I think we are not already &#x2013; they are not working for one side, we are working from another side. We are, let's say, much working together. Of course, the decision is taken for themselves, but I think they are much closer than any shared relationship than it was in the past, so certain on this one.</p>
          <p>In CapEx, the level is very similar to what we make in 2012. So I think the level &#x2013; we are a company, when we commit with something, we try to be very rigid, those things that we can manage. When we commit a certain amount &#x2013; our outlook with a certain amount of investment, and that is going to be the investment, that's it.</p>
          <p>So I think last year we make some amount which are going to be something similar next year is going to be the rest of what we committed. So I think that is quite clear.</p>
          <p>2013, so most that I can say, as I say it's a challenging year, but that in this challenging year allows ourselves to reach our outlook of 2014. So this year is a challenging one but the things are moving in the direction, then 2014 goals are going to be achieved. And they are &#x2013; in certain of these have already been achieved quicker than we expected as is the case of debt or is the case of ratios.</p>
          <p>I cannot say we are in February yet. So I think I say it as much as I can say in this moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Next question Virginia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Virginia Sanz from Deutsche Bank. I have a few questions for 2012 results. Just wanted to know if the restructuring costs you have included in 2012 are all the restructuring costs for the plan we're going to see or whether we are going to see further in the next years. And also if you have the net forex impact in EBITDA of the different currencies that you have mentioned for the year?</p>
          <p>And then two questions for 2013. One regarding the cost of debt, whether you see chances for it to continue to come down, and also what do you expect for the renewables achieved price whether it can be maintained at those levels or will be going down after what has happened in Spain?</p>
          <p>And last, if you could give us an update on your forward contracting position in Spain for 2013 but I'm especially interested if you have done already something for 2014 and if we are going to see there some of the pass through of the taxes to the power price? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So with, yeah, the restructuring cost. So I think all our plan to restructure is basically there. That doesn't means that we cannot be restricted in the following years. But in this moment, there are not any special plan as we did last year for those things.</p>
          <p>So we will continue with our efficiency measures in all the countries. With that can cost something but we have not at today any extraordinary plan as we did last year for making an extraordinary reduction of personnel as we make. We will continue in a normal basis but not in extraordinary.</p>
          <p>Sales rates?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The impact of the &#x2013; is &#x20AC;148 million, but I have to disclose it by currencies, I can give it to you later, but it's basically the dollar and the sterling on a positive side and the real on a negative. Real I think is around 60 negative and the rest is half and half between the dollar and the sterling.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Cost of debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cost of debt, we're expecting that it will go down a little bit, taking into account that we have an important part or that is at a fixed price, so we are expecting this to come down a little bit but not a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on renewables &#x2013; so in Spain, as the General Director mentioned there probably will be a little reduction, still we don't know how much but I think there are some reduction on impact in the win in Spain, okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Inaudible" /> (01:17:38)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So you will reply. So Spain now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, besides Spain prices, are you able to explain what is going to be the impact. I mean in the U.S., we are expecting on a slight increase in &#x2013; also in the UK and a bigger increase in what is the rest of the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The prices cover, Paco, in the 2013 to 2014 in the case of Spain, you came ready reply.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes I was here collecting the figures, firstly, we have 45 <mark type="indiscernible" /> ( 01:18:17) already contracted. The price is above 60, 60-something. And for 2014 I think we are extremely proud and because of the necessity of seeing what happened with the internalization of the taxes on the prices but I think I have about 10 or something like this already contracted and the price is there's nothing to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>More questions or we are passing to the telephone questions. If everyone is &#x2013; coming from BPI, and follow Sante Boron, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question comes from Gonzalo Sanchez from BPI. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning everyone. I have a couple of questions. First one on divestments and the potential additional divestments that were mentioned in the strategic plan for 2012 from 2014 last October. I was wondering, given the right direction that the net debt evolution has taken in the past few months, are you still considering this additional divestments and especially I would like to hear from you about the UK or U.S. regulated businesses as which there are some rumors about sale of minorities in those businesses?</p>
          <p>And also if you would consider this as a good time to sell them your stake in EDP given the value of the stock as seen in the past few months? And that some other shareholders, namely the opportunist traders are selling right now?</p>
          <p>Also, regarding the outlook for generation business in Spain and we've heard that you have contracted already quite a big amount of your production for 2013 at over &#x20AC;60 per megawatt hour. I was wondering if there is a price that you consider, it already includes the pass through of the taxes or that is a price that was contracted before that, and you will take this into consideration in 2014 and onwards? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think in divestment, I think we would like to be absolutely clear so as I've mentioned in my presentation, we have no plans to sell anything in this year around any presentation of our position in the ScottishPower on United States. So it's not any plan of selling any minority stake. We don't need at present to sell anything apart of those things. We are selling only non-strategic countries, non-strategic assets. In a few days, we will announce another important divestment and we'll walk in this direction.</p>
          <p>Related to EDP, as you know, is already in our balance sheet as positioned and ready for selling asset. So it means if we find out a good price at any time can be already divested. So it's not already a strategic asset is not considered a strategic asset for ourselves. So I think with these two I could quite clearly question how.</p>
          <p>Relating the price. &#x2013; relating the price I think, what I can say is what we globally achieving in this moment as a whole is prices in line what we were foreseeing in our presentation of October. So I think roughly the prices is in line what we are expecting. What is  internalization? I don't like to comment to these things. I'd see that then is a price and the price we put in our plan is more or less in line today what we are achieving with the price we have foreseen in our October presentation. Correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gracias.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now is turn of Carolina Dores from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Carolina Dores from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Good morning everyone. I have three questions. One related to the fiscal year 2012 results. You mentioned in the liberalized business in Spain a positive impact on cash management. I was wondering if you could quantify that and if you can expect this positive impact to be recurring in 2013? The second question is on Brazil, on the Elektro exposure to the spot market that the 8% of total demand &#x2013; is it that passed through already authorized by the regulator or this is something that you would need to seek compensation?</p>
          <p>And my last question is on Energias, if you have any updates on the renegotiation of the shareholder agreement so you can consolidate a 100% of it? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We made around &#x20AC;50 million in gas management. We took advantage of the very good prices in the international markets and this year, we will see what we look. But largely, it was an extraordinary year and as we have always said, we have the flexibility, we don't burn the gas in our combined sectors. We can make profit by selling them in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question relating to Elektro, I think he's with us, the President of Elektro, Marcio Fernandes, he's going to reply. Marcio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Related to the spot market in Brazil, the answer is yes because it's a question, not a contract, but we start only on the tariff adjustment in the Elektro's case as presented today here, starting on August 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Related our talks with our partners in Elektro in Energia, so we have already shareholder's agreement we done since last 50 years, it has been very successful. I think we've been doing a lot of things together, the company was growing. We have probably very clear defined responsibilities with each of the shareholders, in our case, we have the responsibilities of the management of the industrial companies, I mean the distribution companies in the power generation. We have the right to appoint our members of the Executive Board in this.</p>
          <p>We've been already trying to, because of this account in things to look for a change in the framework in such a good and allow ourselves to consolidate in a different manner. So for the moment we have been impossible to reach an agreement. In fact, if we continue with the same situation, I think we have already in the during 50 years.</p>
          <p>I think the agreement is fine. I think the company is well-managed. We have a very good new president, which is &#x2013; she is doing a great job after we introduced to you when we make the presentation of 2012 to 2014 outlook, she was here. Unfortunately she couldn't come today but &#x2013; and the people is surely &#x2013; we will continue on the same basis we were before. So we forget for the moment to do anything different although or changing anything different or the one we have been already living with in the last 50 years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question from UBS, Alberto Gandolfi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Alberto Gandolfi from UBS. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning. It's Alberto Gandolfi of UBS. I have four if I may, just on numbers. On the D&amp;A line can you please state if you have a D&amp;A and provisions, if you have any non-recurring and what do you expect for 2013? Also can you elaborate a little bit on the tax rate for 2013 because definitely in the 7% right now it doesn't appear sustainable but I don't quite know for how long you can enjoy some break.</p>
          <p>Thirdly, assuming &#x2013; well, before and in tariffs deficit securitization which clearly you cannot directly control, what would you expect net debt to be in December 2013 and very, very last one for 2013 you're talking about the challenging ability year, obviously, your currency is going against you, deviations in Brazil, all the taxations, you have disposals and some non-recurring items, positive non-recurring, that you had like in generation so on. So directionally, we should expect EBITDA to be down, correct? Because I can see you're not comfortable in providing a specific guidance. Can you just comment on that? Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I was already and somebody asked to me about what is our forecast for 2013. I was already saying that it's very challenging year 2013 and in 2013 we are doing is all the necessary for achieving our targets or our goals, or our outlook by 2014. So I think by 2014, the debt should be &#x20AC;26 million by the end of 2014. The EBITDA in end of 2014 will be in line with EBITDA of we had already in 2011 and the net profit will line with EBITDA, with the result of 2011 as well.</p>
          <p>Meantime, we will keep in 2013 is a level of dividend by 2014 as well of the level of &#x20AC;0.3 per share in the period. So I think that is at most we can say today in February, related to 2013. All the things are established in such a way that we will achieve the outlook we provide to the market in October by the end of 2014.</p>
          <p>2012, we have already achieve and we have already overpass this month and by 2014, all the things will be achieved in 2013, I'm sorry we cannot already in February to said more than what we have already said up to now.</p>
          <p>The non-recurring and all those things, Pepe, do you have anything with tax rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the tax rate, the average tax rate is around &#x2013; normally, we forecasted tax rate in the 25% area. This year still, we have some recurrent items like a 1% decrease in tax rate in the UK. So hopefully, we will be below that number.</p>
          <p>Regarding the net debt assuming that we don't securitize any part of the tariff deficit, which is highly probable, given the circumstance of the market, I think that we will be comfortably in the &#x20AC;28 billion area but I cannot tell you more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question from Javier Su&#xE1;rez, Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Javier Su&#xE1;rez of Nomura. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, and many thanks. This is Javier Su&#xE1;rez at Nomura. Three questions if I may. The first one is on the dividend policy and again and excuse me for insisting on that. But I just wanted to clarify if the company is planning to maintain a strict dividend policy in 2013, 2014 or to come back to all in cash dividend policy?</p>
          <p>The reason why I'm asking this is because I think that the management on HSB has mentioned that the cancellation on the is trying to compensate that dilution that investor are suffering as a consequence of the scheme and that is something that is going to continue happening in 2013 and 2014 or either the company continues cancelling themselves or this dilution is going to reappear.</p>
          <p>So what do you think is the company strategy likely to be in dividend terms, is it going to be maintain the strict dividend policy or coming back to an all-in cash dividend payment?</p>
          <p>Second, a related question is what do you believe is a rational &#x2013; a payout level for all in cash for a company like Iberdrola?</p>
          <p>And the third question is regarding the regulatory outlook in Spain. I think that yesterday there was an intervention by Minister of Industry &#x2013; sorry, of the Parliament. And he said something like the government is working in finalizing the energy reform to be for a more stable framework to the electricity sector. I just wanted you to elaborate on what do you think of the Minister of Industry is working or what adjustment needs to be done?</p>
          <p>My view is that obviously the proposal that the government has done implies a significant amount of money assumed by the budget, and that is something that we are not going to know until the approval of the values of 2014. So through the whole year, 2013 maybe, there is going to be some more regulatory noise. Many thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I don't know if I can reply to your question you asked because I hear very badly. So I think, for the first question related to scrip, as I mentioned before, scrip has a lot of advantage for retailers, and I think retailers, most of the people who have already are in retail, they have a very good advantage because they have already a very positive fiscal situation. Is they have not to pay 27% taxes which I think is a lot of money, and these people are delighted with that one.</p>
          <p>So we took a decision now. What we are going to propose to the other shareholders meeting to compensate as well another part of the equation, so for the dilution with &#x2013; for the first time in the company in many years, so to make already a shared buyback.</p>
          <p>So that is the scrip we plan. As far as the taxation will continue, we have planned at least for the period in our forward outlook up to 2014 to continue with that one.</p>
          <p>So from 2014 over, we shall see. At this moment, we are talking 2013 to 2014. So the plan is already contemplated, if the taxation, favorable taxation, of the scrip continues, to keep and maintain the system.</p>
          <p>Related to make or not to make more share buyback, as I have mentioned before. So it's the first time we probably make, we should see how the things are moving and we will take the decision at the right moment. In this moment, the only decision is affecting the 2.4% of the capital, what is going to present to the Annual Shareholders Meeting.</p>
          <p>Opinion of the, if I understood, measures of the ministry. So I think the general director was mentioning already that the last things with this new General Secretary of Energy has already made are in the right direction, but we don't know more things than those one is published. So I think we don't know what is in their mind. But the signs are positive, and he intends to try to put rationality, intends to take measures which are rational and even those rational measures, certainly not affecting our city in the short term, but in long term, I cannot really provide certainty what in any regulatory framework we are looking for.</p>
          <p>Certainty and predictability, a stability of a proper return. And I think that one of these lines has been released. They are signed and they are moving in the direction. We don't know more what are in their mind. I think is we will see what they are doing in the past. What I heard is they are already, it is public, they are trying to make already a low <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:33:51) will already try to close all the situation we have been facing during this year of lack of clarity, which &#x2013; and that's positive instead to be changing everything every fortnight, I think they are trying to make one small error on something will provide more clarity, stability and predictability. But I cannot say more on this respect because I have no more information.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the last question comes from Fernando Garc&#xED;a from Espirito Santo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>The last question comes from Jorge Alonso, Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, can you hear me? Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, almost all of my questions has been answered but I will like to know the non-recurring items on provisions of the amount and what do you expect for normalization in the provisions aligned for 2013 and 2014?</p>
          <p>And also I will like to just to check that if the extra remuneration of distribution assets in Spain would effect on Iberdrola by &#x20AC;180 million as it has been mentioned just to check if finally the government will pay this extra remuneration for the distribution.</p>
          <p>And lastly, I would like to know your view on the UK offshore wind for the coming years and also the situation of the wind market in the U.S. for the coming years? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think, Keith, can you reply this offshore wind in UK?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jorge, in the UK we are working strongly on West of Duddon Sands in the east Irish Sea. The project is progressing well. It will get into the two-lot mechanism and that's obviously what we're looking to do to push that project forward as quickly as possible. And we're obviously then talking to the government about the future, long-term future, of offshore wind under the energy bill and those conversations are progressing well with the introduction of the contracts for difference, which we believe will deliver the long-term certainty to allow us to continue to invest and grow in that business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pepe, your comment about the provisions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have put almost &#x20AC;300 million of extraordinary provisions. So at what point &#x2013; at some point that will normalize. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jose, you reply on this point related to the compensation of distribution Jorge mentioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to speak in Spanish. In terms of tariffs, what we have are &#x20AC;297 million to consider the investment for 2011 which will be income for this year and so we will get 37% of that amount. The rest are provisions to pay for the quality and loss incentives from previous years that have &#x2013; were not remunerated. How much of that is for us? Well, that depends on the decisions taken by the regulator on compliance. But I personally believe and I don't know if I'm being excessively optimistic here, but I think that we'll have a proportion equal to 35%. Now, how much is that for revenues for this year and how much would be for past years? Well, the exact figure I don't know, probably about 50% and 50%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think thank you very much. I think very good questions and I hope we can &#x2013; have already given you as more clarity as possible about how the things are being already positive during the year. Thank you very much to everybody. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no more questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>