<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1490216" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7850</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Director of Investor Relations">Ignacio Cuenca</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Jos&#xE9; Ignacio S&#xE1;nchez Gal&#xE1;n</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Jos&#xE9; S&#xE1;inz Armada</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="JB Capital Markets Sociedad de Valores SA">Cesar Gonzalez</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Operating Officer &amp; Executive Director">Jos&#xE9; Luis San Pedro Guerenabarrena</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Cygnus Asset Management SGIIC SA">Alejandro Vigil</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Banco Esp&#xED;rito Santo de Investimento SA (Sucursal en Espa&#xF1;a)">Fernando Garc&#xED;a</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Pablo Cuadrado</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Carolina Dores</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">Jos&#xE9; Javier Ruiz Fernandez</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Alberto Gandolfi</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG Sucursal en Espa&#xF1;a (Broker)">Virginia Sanz de Madrid Grosse</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc (Italy)">Javier Suarez</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="La Caixa">Fernando Murillo</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC">Jose A. L&#xF3;pez-Borges</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. We're going to begin the Results Presentation for the Second Quarter of 2012. We will follow the usual procedure. Once the presentations have been given, we'll have questions from the room, then by phone and finally through the website. The event will take an hour and a half, so we expect to finish by 11. And I'm now going to hand the floor over to the Chairman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Thank you very much for attending this results presentation, both those of you in the room and those that are following it by phone or the website. As usual, I have Jos&#xE9; Luis San Pedro; and the CFO, Jos&#xE9; S&#xE1;inz Armada, with me. As Ignacio Cuenca said, the presentation will consist in &#x2013; my presentation with the main highlights for the semester. Then the CFO will give more details on the results and finally we will move on to questions.</p>
          <p>The current year, as everyone knows, is extremely complex, both because of the economic crisis we're affected by, especially in the Eurozone and particularly Spain, as well as because of the situation of the power sector in our country. In spite of this, IBERDROLA has continued to improve its results, thanks to an international diversification process which has enabled us to attain in this semester a net profit of &#x20AC;1.8 billion, where the growth is 74% in our International business, which has more than offset the 44% drop in the Spanish business. And the Spanish business contribution represents less than 25% of the results for the group.</p>
          <p>Regarding the first semester of 2012, all business have grown except for the liberalised and regulated business in Spain. The liberalised business in Spain has been affected by a 24% drop in output under the Ordinary Regime, as a result mainly of the low hydro output this year. The lower results of the regulated business is mainly a result of the impact of the regulatory measures approved by the government on March 30. And with all this, the group EBITDA in spite of this grew 2% to &#x20AC;4.087 million. What's more important is that the operating cash flow increased 5.8%. And last year, we grew by a similar amount to &#x20AC;3.3 billion, contributing to the strengthening of the liquidity position of the group, which amounts to almost &#x20AC;10 billion, with which we can cover our financial needs for the coming 24 months.</p>
          <p>I would also like to highlight the strong commitment taken on by IBERDROLA of maintaining its financial strength in a year characterized by a high degree of uncertainty, which is negatively affecting companies in the sector in Spain. And in view of the very difficult market conditions, flexibility and foresight are best tools to increase solidity. These tools have been very highly valued by the international financial institutions, which has enabled us to continue to pick up resources under very favorable conditions.</p>
          <p>As I said earlier, the diversified business model has enabled IBERDROLA to increase its EBITDA as of June 30 to &#x20AC;4 billion, with a growing contribution of the regulated and renewable businesses, which is almost 75% if we include the regulated generation in Mexico. The regulated EBITDA is 5% mostly, thanks to the integration of Elektro since May 2011, which more than offsets the impact of the Royal Decree 13/2012 which represented &#x20AC;117 million less in earnings in the first semester. In renewables, there is a 12% growth in EBITDA as a result of greater output in all the geographic regions where we're present. And this represents an increase of 12.6% for the group compared to the same semester last year. Finally, the liberalised business represents a drop of 4% in spite of the improvement in the United Kingdom as a result of the worst results obtained in Spain, where the higher market prices have not offset the drop in production.</p>
          <p>The contribution to EBITDA from the International businesses has been a decisive factor with an increase of 13.4% during the period and with all businesses growing. And I would like to highlight that if we even discount the contribution of Elektro, the EBITDA for the International business increased by 6.6%. On the other hand, developments in Spain have been negative. EBITDA dropped 8.3% during this period. The regulated business had a drop of 13% because of the regulatory measures. The liberalised business dropped its EBITDA by 10%. On the other hand, the EBITDA for renewables in Spain grew 23%, driven by the 11% increase in wind power production, which was favored by the positive developments in wind power resources during the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>As mentioned earlier, one of the main objectives for IBERDROLA is to maintain its financial strength and reduce the debt level. And for this, we continue to work on the optimization of the financial structure for the group. We've closed the first half with a liquidity position of &#x20AC;9.551 billion which enables us to cover our financial need for the next two years, as Jos&#xE9; said earlier, and the average debt maturity is 6.3 years, and the CFO will give us more details on this. We have also reduced leverage, which has gone from 46.4% at the end of 2011 to 46.1%. And this is reflected in our main credit ratios. Lead ratios are also being favored by the good developments in the operating cash flow which, as I said earlier, amounted to &#x20AC;3.3 billion, an increase of 5.8% compared to the same period in 2011.</p>
          <p>The net profits increased by 15% to &#x20AC;553 million. This &#x20AC;553 million are mainly from the International business, and we can also highlight the change in the fiscal clause in the United States as a result of a favorable ruling from the tax authorities and the recognition in Brazil of the possibility of deducting the goodwill in the purchasing of Elektro. And additionally, these results include non-recurring expenses of &#x20AC;171 million of &#x2013; because of the write-down of the investment in Gamesa and the provisions associated to wind power projects which were finally cancelled. So the growth in net profits for the group, as I said, is fundamentally due to the contribution of the International business, &#x20AC;1.363 billion, offsetting the 44% drop in the Spanish results which were up by &#x20AC;438 million, a fourth of the total.</p>
          <p>And now, I'll briefly go over the regulatory situation in Spain and in the United Kingdom. In Spain, the tariff deficit problem requires an urgent solution if we want to guarantee the economic sustainability of the system. The uncertainty generated in recent months have taken Spain to risk levels that are having a major effect on the financing of a sector that is as basic as the power sector in our country. In order to tackle this problem, IBERDROLA, as always, is open to collaborating with the administration to adopt new measures, which should be objective and not discriminatory to have an effect on those factors that have generated the deficit. So we need a transparent and interactive model that will have a clear and defined objective and we should first define if the purpose is only to collect more taxes or to optimize and have an efficient operation of the system and the sustainability and safe operation of the system or if the aim is a mere price reduction. We must also consider the effects that this can have on investments in the sector and, therefore, on tax earnings. We need a model that is based on uniform, reasonable and explainable criteria and not discriminatory reasons based on turnover, unit cost, availability of equipment, profitability of the investments, et cetera, et cetera. We also need a model that should be based on reliable and real data from reliable sources, and finally, a model that will take into account the court rulings.</p>
          <p>Regarding this latter aspect, in 2012 in June, the Supreme Court has passed three relevant rulings regarding the claims made by solar producer associations. The last of these in June confirms the possibility of modifying the remuneration framework under the special regime in order to maintain reasonable profitability criteria according to Royal Decree 661/2007, which establishes a return rate of 8%. And the ruling says that those rulings and clauses that have effected in the past should not be deployed that will have an effect on future results. And again, the ruling also said, if the new economic circumstances imply adjustments in many other production sectors with obvious difficulties for their activity, it is not unreasonable that those also extend to the renewable energy sector and that wished to continue to receive the regulated tariffs instead of resorting to the market mechanisms, and more so before situations of a generalized economic crisis. And in the case of power, in view of the growth of the tariff deficit, it rises from the impact of the calculation of the access tolls which has an effect on the cost of the power system.</p>
          <p>And finally, the text also says that it's logical that faced with any technological modification or before significant changes in the economic situation, the initial determining parameters need to be reviewed in order to calculate the regulated tariff. And the aspect of legal certainty cannot oppose this principle. Therefore, the Supreme Court rejects the possibility of maintaining an unmodifiable economic regime and refers to the economic circumstances and the technological maturity in the same way that this occurs in the United States remuneration regime to avoid unreasonable returns, although the Americans do not talk about retroactivity, but about a remuneration adjustment. And it's well known that the President of the government is a prudent, honest and a man with common sense, and he's having to make brave decisions at this difficult time. Therefore, I trust that he's going to do everything that is necessary to put an end to this scourge of the tariff deficit and, as he said, through a model that will be economically and environmentally sustainable. So it doesn't seem reasonable to have a cheap power station shutdown. While power stations are in production, the energy of which costs us seven or eight times more, such as the case of some solar plants. So as I said, the deficit problem will only be solved by acting on the factors that caused it and not on those that are outside the area.</p>
          <p>In the United Kingdom, on the other hand, important steps have been taken in defining a predictable and stable regulatory framework for some of the sector activities. In the grid business, we have regulatory stability, both transmission and distribution, with tariff frameworks that will be enforced up to 2015 and 2021 respectively, thus ensuring a sufficient and predictable remuneration for the planned investments which in our case amount to &#x2013; close to &#x20AC;6 billion over the coming years. However, it is necessary to still complete the definition of the regulatory framework for the generation activity in order to offer an adequate remuneration that will provide incentives for the major investment required to replace the obsolete current generation facilities. And in this sense, we need to continue with the reform of the electric power market to establish a sufficient remuneration framework, both for our nuclear and combined gas plants, and renewable plants as of 2014. In the case of renewable plants, they have a transient period between 2013 and 2017, and the remuneration framework called Renewables Obligation Banding Review has been made public today with a sufficient remuneration adapted to the degree of technological maturity, as we have defended over the last few months.</p>
          <p>And now, I'm going to hand the floor over to the CFO, Jos&#xE9; S&#xE1;inz Armada, who will explain the results in greater detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Chairman. Good morning. As we can see and as the Chairman said, in spite of the difficult economic conditions that we are going through in Europe, the group continues to grow in its operating lines and cash flow. Elektro contributed to the results in the first half of 2012. Last year, it contributed since the month of May and the exchange rate is also favorable since 53% of the EBITDA in these first six months is outside the Eurozone, which is an important characteristic in this group. Therefore, we've been favored by the revaluation of the dollar and the pound although we are partially affected by the devaluation of the real. And as the Chairman said, there are non-recurrent items that have an impact on net profit and the details of which I'll give later on.</p>
          <p>Sales increased 9.3% to &#x20AC;16.992 billion and purchasing 14% to &#x20AC;10.595 billion. The gross margin grew 3.2% to &#x20AC;6.309 billion, including a positive impact of &#x20AC;112 million due to the exchange rate. Excluding this effect, the businesses contributed a further &#x20AC;83 million. The main items responsible for this growth are Renewable and regulated businesses and especially the International business. Our growth is 9.1% in the UK, 9.7% in the United States and 41% in Brazil, with the greater contribution of Elektro. Renewables grew 9.1% in gross margin. This offsets the weak performance of the business in Spain, showing reductions in the gross margin, both in the liberalised business, 11.8%, and the regulated business, 8.3%, because of the lower output and regulatory impact. The 2.3% increase because of the increase in emission rights assigned has fallen by 46% because of the lower price. The net operating cost grew 5.7%. The consolidation of Elektro continues to have an unfavorable impact since it's being consolidated since May 2011. The exchange rate has increased the net operating cost by &#x20AC;32 million.</p>
          <p>In the operating cost item, personnel rose 4.8% to &#x20AC;886 million. However, here we have some non-recurring effects linked to restructuring costs and the efficiency measures, which carried a greater weight during the first quarter, which were diluted during the year and which will have a positive impact in the coming years. Net outside services grew 6.5% to &#x20AC;914 million and as well as the Elektro impact, we have a seasonal effect associated through storms and maintenance work in the United States.</p>
          <p>Regarding levies, they dropped 6.6% to &#x20AC;481.5 million after the impact resulting from the ruling of the Supreme Court regarding the social bonus, which &#x2013; most of which was registered during the first quarter. However, as we'll see later on, we continue to pay higher levies, both in Spain and in the United Kingdom. As explained by the Chairman, the 2% growth in EBITDA is based on our diversified business model with renewables and the regulated business, which includes the generated business in Mexico contributing 74% of the total EBITDA. And the EBITDA of the International business is almost 55% of the total.</p>
          <p>Starting with the EBITDA of the regulated business, which was almost &#x20AC;2 billion, and 66% of which comes from outside Spain, that is from the United Kingdom, United States and Brazil, the United Kingdom grew 8.2%, United States 6.5%, and Brazil 36%, because of the incremental contribution of Elektro. These advances in the International area offset the lower contribution of our business in Spain. The EBITDA of the regulated business in Spain dropped 12.6% to &#x20AC;682 million because of the cutback of &#x20AC;117 million during the first six months, and during the year this will increase in the remuneration of the business according to Royal Decree 12/2012. The gross margin dropped 8.3% because of this impact. The net operating expenses grew 4.5%. As I said earlier here, we include higher maintenance costs and other costs related to efficiency measures that will have a positive impact in the coming years. Additionally, and this is something we want to highlight, levies in this business also increased 13.7% because of the higher local levies. The regulated UK business obtained an EBITDA of &#x20AC;446 million with an increase of 8.2% associated to greater investments and the positive effect of the exchange rate, &#x20AC;21 million.</p>
          <p>The net operating expenses increased &#x20AC;11 million, including expenses resulting from the need to comply with the quality standards linked to DPCR5, part of which have been transferred to the rates. And also because of the exchange rates, the regulated business in the United States provided an EBITDA of &#x20AC;356 million according to the IFRS regulations, which is equivalent to a growth of 6.5% including &#x20AC;24 million because of the exchange rate. The underlying evolutions has also been positive regarding gross margin with &#x20AC;13 million linked to higher returns and the incremental remuneration of the main line. Regarding the GON, it grew 14.9% because of the expenses as a result of the storms last year and the revaluation of the dollar. EBITDA in Brazil grew 36.1% to &#x20AC;495 million with Elektro included in the perimeter since May 2011. This has represented &#x20AC;124 million more in this semester. Additionally, the 6.1% growth in power demand in our area, the positive tariff readjustments at the generators and the greater unit margins are other factors that have contributed to growth. The exchange rate impact in this case is negative and &#x20AC;22.4 million. The net operating expenses grew 54.3% to &#x20AC;203 million, of which a significant part is due to Elektro and the rest is related to cost inflation and a higher activity. Excluding the impact of Elektro and the exchange rate, the recurring EBITDA in Brazil grew 2.6%, or 7% with a homogeneous exchange rate.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the liberalised business that includes Spain, the UK and Mexico, EBITDA falls &#x2013; and here we include Mexico because of reporting issues, EBITDA falls by 4.2% and now stands at &#x20AC;1.2 billion. Spain provides 66% of the EBITDA. The main growth factor in June is still the United Kingdom that provides 19% and this has had a very important recovery as regards to previous fiscal year. The business in Mexico provides 15%, with a positive impact in accordance with the rate of exchange for the positive business. And the net operating expenses have grown 5.2% because of an increase in the trading expenses. Levies show a decline of 18.8%, which is lower than the figure presented in March because of the positive impact of the court resolution.</p>
          <p>And starting off now with the liberalised business in Spain, demand in Spain has fallen 0.3% although it's 1.5% when adjusted. The ordinary regime production figures have been reduced by 24.4% as a consequence of a drop of 57.1% in high-quality production and more than 67% in combined cycle production that has been partially offset by an increase in nuclear power and coal, although we have very little in Spain. Prices have gone up a little bit also because of the generation mix and they now stand about &#x20AC;60.</p>
          <p>In 2012, all the production has been sold at prices similar to those of the first semester. The basic margin falls 13.1%, also affected by capacity collections that are reduced by &#x20AC;7.5 million, also affected by the Royal Decree. However, the reduction of levies in part offsets the decline in the basic margin. However, after excluding the impact of the social bonus, the levies paid by the business are increased by 10%. So we've increased levies in the transmission and generation business in Spain in a recurrent manner.</p>
          <p>The basic margin of the liberalised business in the UK now stands at &#x20AC;598 million, thanks to the retail business with its margins recovering from the minimum levels of 2011 because of the improvement and procurement costs and because of the increase in rates of August 2011. That includes &#x20AC;26 million in positive effects in the rate of exchange and these effects have been partially compensated by a 14% reduction in production because of shutdowns and because of lower spreads that have affected the wholesale and generation business.</p>
          <p>Net operating expenses have gone up 7.5% and now stand at &#x20AC;290 million and they include non-recurrent effects that affect the annual comparison. So the business' EBITDA has recovered partially and now stands at &#x20AC;242 million. However, we still have very tight business margins. And it was only 2.1% as regard to EBIT relative to sales, recovering in relation to 2011, which was negative, although very far away from the levels reported for 2010.</p>
          <p>EBITDA in Mexico has grown 8.4% and now stands at &#x20AC;131 million. The rate of exchange has added another &#x20AC;13 million to the EBITDA and the gross margin grows 10.6%. And the evolution of the business after excluding the exchange rate effect is also positive because of the heat breaks and because of the increases in plant capacity, although there have been some shutdowns. There are also some non-recurrent maintenance costs, which have penalized the net operating expenses in such amounts that the EBITDA has grown somewhat less than the growth we've had in the &#x2013; the growth in the gross margin. EBITDA in our renewables business has grown 12.2%. And this is thanks to a very good second quarter.</p>
          <p>On the whole, production grows 12.6% with an average load factor of 28.7%, which improved 27.4% of the same periods of previous fiscal year, which means that the EBITDA of the wind business has grown 19.7%. The average price also has gone up, up to &#x20AC;69.1 per megawatt hour because of the change, because of the modifications of the rate of exchange. Operating capacity now stands at 13,560 megawatts and installed capacity has reached 14,171 megawatts.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses have improved with a drop of 0.9%, because we've had less non-recurrent expenses. And efficiency improvements also show that the GON megawatt ratio has improved to 4%. The EBIT of the group has dropped 3.3%, which has a worse evolution than EBITDA because of an increase of 142% in provisions, fundamentally linked to the integration of Elektro and some non-recurrent provisions basically in Brazil, and other measures that have to do with promotion of the pipeline as the President pointed out, which affects the United States and which reached &#x20AC;44 million.</p>
          <p>So on the whole, non-recurrent provisions are for Brazil as well as of the pipeline, represents something like &#x20AC;100 million. And an increase of 4.6% in amortizations is due to the integration of Elektro and also because there are larger amortizations brought about by investments in the grid. And this has been in part compensated by the extended life cycle of the wind farms. And we can also see that there has been a negative impact produced by the rate of exchange in terms of provisions and amortizations. The net financial results have grown 17%. And this17% increase is due to two factors; firstly, because there's a lower market value of the hedging factors for rate to exchange, because last year the dollar and the pound were devalued vis-&#xE0;-vis the euro, whereas this year it has been just the opposite, and this lower market value is something you can see in the financial costs; and secondly, because there's been &#x2013; there have been more financial expenses because of the greater average of debt relative to the first semester of the previous fiscal year.</p>
          <p>Secondly, because there's been a greater cost of the debt after integrating Elektro, so we can say that the cost of the debt has hardly changed relative to the previous year. And the reported net profits have grown 15.2% and now stand at &#x20AC;1.8 billion because of the impact of positive non-recurrence at a fiscal level, partially compensated by measures taken in terms of provisions and in terms of consolidation by the equity method. So now, we're talking about &#x20AC;1.4 billion. We've also taken measures in relation to assets totaling &#x20AC;171 million related to the cost of developing renewables. And secondly, we've also taken actions in relation to the Gamesa portfolio that has to do with the equity method. We have included another &#x20AC;127 billion in the book, and we consider that the prospects arising from the analysis are positive as regards the business in the future.</p>
          <p>We have two very significant issues. First, we have the deductibility of the Elektro business after reorganization process carried out in our Brazil organizations. We've had profits of &#x20AC;280 million because we've applied fiscal deductions for the price paid for Elektro. And secondly, we have some fiscal provisions in IBERDROLA USA totaling &#x20AC;142 million after a recent ruling &#x2013; favorable ruling from the American court in relation to a fiscal lawsuit that has been won and has risen from the purchase of Scottish Power. And we will have a reduction of 1% in the tax rate in the UK, although this is some more of a recurrent nature.</p>
          <p>And moving on now to the financial side of things, in the first semester of 2012 there's been a reduction of the tariff deficit totaling &#x20AC;281 million, from &#x20AC;2,991 million to &#x20AC;2,710 million because we've generated another &#x20AC;933 million in terms of new deficit and we've securitized a total of &#x20AC;1,200 million. So the debt now stands at &#x20AC;32 billion. And this has been affected by two factors, by the net variation of the deficit which in this quarter has reached a figure &#x20AC;699 million, and we also have the effect of the rate of exchange that has been &#x20AC;503 million in the quarter. As you can see, this has to do with appreciation of the dollar and the pound. After excluding both effects, the group has generated a net cash flow &#x2013; positive net cash flow of &#x20AC;834 million in the second quarter of the year. And the increase in the debt reduced by the rate of exchange is also compensated by the fact that the rate of exchange have also include those improved our cash flows, as we pointed out throughout the presentation. So therefore, we are still improving leverage and the FFO debt and RCF debt ratios relative to the previous trimester, and we will believe that we'll obtain the ratio in excess of 20%, that is in terms of FFO debt and RCF debt 16%.</p>
          <p>And as the President pointed out, we could also point out our excellent liquidity position. We have &#x20AC;9.5 billion in liquidity and the credit line is available, which allows us to cover more than 24 months of financial needs, especially if we bear in the mind the maturity profile of the debt where we don't have any significant maturities in the midterm. We have less than &#x20AC;500 million in maturities in the second semester of 2012 and the average life of the debt is maintained at 6.3 years since the closing of the 2011 fiscal year, thanks to the active management of the group during the semester.</p>
          <p>Now, the President will conclude his remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Pepe. I think that once again, these results of the first semester show how in this complex macroeconomic environment, especially in the euro area, the internationalization of the company has made it possible for the results to improve. And thanks to this, cash flow has grown 5.8% and now stands at &#x20AC;3.3 billion, which has improved our financial position which is a key element for our business model. On the other hand, net profits totaled &#x20AC;1.8 billion with 74% growth of the International business vis-&#xE0;-vis a reduction of 40% in Spain. So the International business represents more than three-quarters of the total profits of the group. So considering how successful this strategy has been, this internationalization process will have an influence on our growth in the future and our investments will focus on those countries and businesses that offer a stable and objective regulation. So therefore the &#x2013; what we'll do is give priority to opportunities based on criteria of security, profitability and short periods of execution. And according to these premises, our investments will go mainly to regulated business and to a less extent to renewables, and all of this within the framework of our firm commitment to strengthen the company's balance sheet.</p>
          <p>So based on this commitment, our strategy will be focused on optimizing our financial position through generating free cash flow as the top priority, cutting back on investments, selecting only those that are much more attractive in terms of predictability and profitability. We have to actively manage our portfolio and we have to consider divestitures of assets that are not strategic as we have been doing or we have to hold minority shares in some businesses. We have to maintain our efforts to improving our efficiency. And for that, we will reduce our operating expenses in all the activities and in particular in those areas in which they are much more penalized from a macroeconomic or regulatory perspective.</p>
          <p>So with this, what we want to do is reduce our level of indebtedness and we want to go on improving &#x2013; as the Financial Director said, we want to improve the financial ratios and the liquidity position of the company in order to be able to maintain our remuneration policy to the shareholder, as we've done in recent years. So, these are going to be the basic elements of our upcoming strategic approach that we will present on the Investors Day and we will send out the call once we've &#x2013; once the reform of the electricity sector has been presented in Spain. And you can be sure that all of us people working for this company will do whatever is required to carry on improving our results in the future.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much, and now we're going to move on to your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. The Q&amp;A session starts now. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cesar and then Alejandro Vigil at the back of the room.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Cesar Gonzales from JB Capital. I have three questions. The first one has to do with regulation. A couple of weeks ago, there were a number of measures in the press that apparently the Ministry of Industry is contemplating. And I would like to know what you think about this. Up to what extent do you believe this information is critical and what do you about &#x2013; think about the timing of this reform, because it has been postponed for many months? And secondly and also in relation to this issue, should the final impact be as bad as we considered it to be? In other words, it would be several hundreds of millions of euros if the strategic guidelines you've just pointed out &#x2013; do you think that they could be modified as a consequence and do you think that the shareholder remuneration policy could also change? And also I would like to know something about Brazil, because in The Economist there was a news on the IPO that is being considered. So what is the situation then as regards to the activities in that country? And finally, could you say something about the rate of adaptation for the fiscal year? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as far as the first question is concerned, I think that I said things very clearly, that in spite of the noise and the rumors and news, there's nothing of what I said before. And I have to repeat this, and that is that I'm sure that these characteristics of that show that the President of the government is a person of common sense and is very fair. So whatever is done &#x2013; is going to be done has he's pointed out on many occasions, and things are going to be done sustainably from the economic and environmental perspective. But I just wanted to give you a figure, because this year the Spanish people have had an increase of 6%, 7% or 8% in their billed in spite of the fact that the price of power &#x2013; in other words, what we produce &#x2013; what we've produced have slumped and in spite of the fact that the prices of grids have been increased because of the Royal Decree of the month of March and they are paying more. But apart from that, we are still funding the &#x2013; we've provided nearly &#x20AC;2 billion to cover that deficit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, so that these power stations that produce between &#x20AC;300 or &#x20AC;400 can carry on producing, so that we're shutting down power stations that are producing &#x20AC;50 or &#x20AC;60.</p>
          <p>So if we believe that you can maintain a system by this based on subsidies that could total &#x20AC;8 billion or &#x20AC;10 billion or if we think that &#x2013; well, I think that there is an issue that is not sustainable from the economic or the environmental perspective, even more so when we have Supreme Court rulings that clearly state what you cannot do and when there's a legislation that talks about a reasonable degree of profitability which is the degree of 2007.</p>
          <p>So talking about retroactivity or non-retroactivity, and this is something <mark type="ph" /> the President of (39:16) the United States, they call that remuneration adjustment. Retroactivity is something that comes from the past, not from the future. So if the technological and economic conditions change or the environmental conditions change, the logical and reasonable thing to think of what you should do is review those parameters, even more so when we all know that they are completely wrong. So I think or I hope and trust that what the government does under the leadership of the President will be firm and balanced and that it will do something that is sustainable in the future.</p>
          <p>Now moving on to your second question concerning Brazil, well, this thing about the IPO is nothing new and you know that we've had this shareholder agreement for the last ten years. So any of the partners, whenever they consider that this is pertinent, they can apply for it and we already have a structure in place which is a control block and part of it that &#x2013; would then be traded on the stock exchange at a given point in time. So this is nothing new and this is something contemplated by the shareholders' plan. And any partners can apply for this measure. And this hasn't taken place in ten years, but in any case a partner could apply for this measure and ten we have <mark type="indiscernible" /> (40:33) taxation for 2012 which I think you can answer. Well, the normal rate is something like 25% or 26%, the current rate. So in this semester, it's been much lower. So I suppose it will be &#x2013; the average will be something like 14% or 15%, I assume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jos&#xE9; Luis, would you like to add anything on the first question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the information we received is that what has come out is just an internal draft of the Ministry of Industry and that they are reviewing it. In fact, it hasn't been approved yet.</p>
          <p>But regarding the levies, the nuclear levy of &#x20AC;10 per megawatt hour, if we work out the numbers, if I take the Garona power plant and if we accept the operating and maintenance costs they've given, which are old, &#x20AC;30 per megawatt hour, we add a levy of &#x20AC;10, we're at &#x20AC;40 megawatt hour. Garona planned recurrent investments that were already included in the budget for the next six years of &#x20AC;60 million, &#x20AC;60 million more that are added because of Fukushima, makes it &#x20AC;120 million, plus the &#x20AC;60 million they have, &#x20AC;180 that they have to amortize in six years, &#x20AC;30 million per year since they produce 3,500 gigawatt hours per year. That means that the cost of this new investment is &#x20AC;10 megawatt hour, &#x20AC;40 they had already, plus &#x20AC;10 in investments, &#x20AC;50. 4% of this environmental levy, Garona has a price then of &#x20AC;52 during the last ten years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How many years have nuclear power plants had earnings over &#x20AC;52?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Only one year, in 2008. This year, at pool prices of around &#x20AC;54 megawatt hour to which we have to add &#x20AC;3 for power guarantees, that makes it &#x20AC;57 megawatt hour, &#x20AC;58 megawatt hour. The average earning of nuclear power plants has been &#x20AC;47 megawatt hour. So I don't know where those extraordinary earnings come from for the power plants. Where an amortized power plant is going to lengthen its life is going to have a price of around &#x20AC;50 megawatt hour, not including the regional or local taxes, which is another &#x20AC;5 megawatt hour. And regarding the hydraulic levy of &#x20AC;15 megawatt hour, I estimate that during the slump hours, there are many hours where the price is less than the &#x20AC;15 per megawatt hours during the value times. There have been many hours this year at price zero. So what do we have to do with water when the price is under &#x20AC;15 megawatt hour? Throw it away, otherwise we're losing money. A pumping station, I've done the calculations with the prices given by the Chairman of the liberalised business. La Muela &#x2013; The La Muela power plant with &#x20AC;20, &#x20AC;25 per megawatt hour has a price of around &#x20AC;90 per megawatt hour with the &#x20AC;15 levy. How many hours can a pumping station operate if it has to charge a minimum of &#x20AC;90 megawatt hour and it doesn't contribute a single euro to profit, so zero hours. With these levies, we first of all have a change in the relationship between the price of the technologies and this is going to change the optimization of the energy system in a negative way. And secondly, we are assuming profits and applying levies to those profits when those profits don't exist. So, I think that this has been an initial draft as a ministry and I obviously hope it will be corrected.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I would like to add something. As Jos&#xE9; Luis San Pedro said, since this hasn't been fully developed, I'm sure the solution will be to produce more cheaply, that is more efficiently follow the rulings of the Supreme Court. And that will take us to a reasonable situation. I believe that any other situation means that you have to stop investments, stop operating and maintenance costs, carry out rationalizations, et cetera, et cetera. I don't think it make &#x2013; it doesn't make sense to continue just to shut down efficient plants to build non-efficient plants. And recently, as a result of the paralysis of the renewable plant, they've continued to build thermal solar plants that they're going to represent &#x20AC;300 million more in cost for the Spanish people over the year. I don't know how many in the next few years, if somebody doesn't correct this, and this is an aberration. And since I profoundly believe that we have rational rulers, I'm sure they'll do something logical and rational. So the dividend issue, I don't think it's going to be questioned among other reasons because we have half a million Spaniards that are our shareholders and to a large extent they live off that dividend. So, there's an important social issue to provide just a few taking away the premium from the power sector. So, we are a large base shareholding company and there are hundreds of thousands of families that have their savings in our company. So, we have to do everything that is possible so that, that dividend policy won't be questioned in the future and in order to maintain that policy through the investments we're making in much more predictable and much safer assets. And I'm sure that things will be done in a rational way in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, Alejandro Vigil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good morning. Alejandro Vigil from Cygnus Asset Management. Continuing with your answer to the previous questions, in view that, that draft isn't mature, what do you think the timing is for this energy reform? Do you think it will be postponed until after summer or until the end of the year, or will it basically change the schedule? And the second question, I don't want to be catastrophic, but if we now look at the Spanish debt spreads and it's possible that Spain will lose its investment grade, and what would the effect be for IBERDROLA regarding bonds or access to liquidity, et cetera?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't know about the timing. It's a government decision and therefore it's up to them. If we go by the rumor &#x2013; noise in the media, in the next few weeks. But I don't have any information apart from what we see in the media. And would you like to comment on the spreads, Pepe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in the lines we currently have, if the cost goes up or down depending on the rating, but if the rating dropped very much none of the lines would disappear. All the lines are insured and they are insured with top world banks. So in that sense, we feel very calm about it. And if there was a situation where Spain lost its investment rating, and we hope that won't happen, and if that had its impacts we have several scenarios we've already worked on where the funding for the group could be done in different ways and &#x2013; in a very efficient way, and perhaps even more cheaply than what we're doing now. And apart from that, as the Chairman said, we have a divestment plan, et cetera, the liquidity position. I think that everything is very calm. We're working on what we need to work on. We've considered all the scenarios. We are in touch with the rating agencies. So for us, it's business as usual.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good morning. Fernando Garc&#xED;a from Espirito Santo Investments. I had two questions. The first one, could you tell us something about the new strategy of having a positive free cash flow and specifically regarding investments? The company is investing around &#x20AC;4 billion per year. What investment figures could we see in the future? And the second question, continuing with Alejandro's earlier question; could you tell us about the new strategy for debt referencing for the company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as I said, we want to hold an Investor Day and as soon as the Spanish measures come out, we want to evaluate them and put out the call for the meeting and we'll explain everything in detail, all the figures, et cetera, et cetera. And the CFO said something about the funding strategy and I don't think we can say much more. Our cash flow generation to a large extent comes from outside Spain, and our funding so far has been heavily based on Spain, so clear the ex and you'll draw your conclusions regarding the free cash flow. We're going to reduce investments in general for the group and we're going to concentrate on fundamentally Renewable businesses and fundamentally, in those countries where the framework is perfectly defined for the coming years. Either UK, I said that we have a clear framework until 2021, and since we know what we have to do, we know how it's going to be paid, well, that's one of the fundamental areas. In the countries we're in, therefore, somewhat less in renewables and a lot less in the traditional generation industry. So globally, there would be fewer investments and that will generate more cash flow. If we've had &#x20AC;4 billion in organic investment, this will go down substantially. But let me tell you about that on Investor Day. Otherwise, we wouldn't have anything to talk about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more questions? Yes, Pablo and then Miguel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good morning. I'm Pablo Cuadrado from Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Two or three quick questions; the first regarding debt. Is there any element that in the first semester has had an effect on the tax changes in the corporate rate or business tax in Spain? And also, could you give us a figure for the debt plan for the end of the year, assuming there is no more deficit securitization? And the second question regarding divestments, and in your presentation you focused a great deal on the International business, and thinking about the future strategic steps and the portfolio of the company with the potential divestments, I assume that you don't want to touch the International side. I'd just like a confirmation of that thinking. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Will you answer the first question, Pepe, regarding debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I believe that we have low cash outflows because of the debt payment system. I assume that's what you were referring to. But the amounts aren't big. So, we're not talking about a big impact. And regarding the debt at the end of the year, we've always said that we were below &#x20AC;30 billion. If the deficit isn't securitized, we would go up in that proportion. So, the aim was around &#x20AC;29 billion. We'll discuss this on Investors Day, but we're also speeding up some of the divestment issues. So, we'll probably offset the situation if there isn't a deficit securitization. Well, as I said earlier, we've been divesting non-strategic assets and we just announced a new one, a commercializer in the State of New York that wasn't compatible with our regulated business. Over the next few days we'll make another announcement for another country. So, it's not a matter of in and out. It's a matter of not being strategic nationally or internationally. But we have a tremendously liquid asset portfolio and infrastructure funds internationally have quite an appetite for them. So the sale of minority packages, whether Spanish or foreign, for those infrastructures is relatively easy, and we'll also be doing that. So, there'll be national and International in minority packages again and assets that we consider to be non-strategic for whatever reason, for the geographic situation or because that's a business we don't want to be in, et cetera, et cetera, and we'll also announce that over the next few months. I think that during this year, as the CFO said, there will be news on things that we're currently negotiating and that we'll be able to confirm over the coming months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> Miguel Medina (55:57).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. <mark type="ph" /> Miguel Medina from Hotare Capital (56:01). Two questions. The first has to do with what you said about the write-off of the promotion costs of these operations in the United States. What is this due to or is this related to a pessimistic outlook on what's going to happen with the PDTs in 2013 in the United States? And the second question has to do with Gamesa. Could you please give us the value of the shares in Gamesa after this deterioration test that has been carried out? And is this related to the change in the presidency of Gamesa or is there no connection?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as far as these farms are concerned, the truth is that with the gas prices that they have at the United States and with the uncertainties that exist in relation to incentives, foreign investments, well, it is to be expected that there will be a reduction in divestments in the United States. And the pipeline we had in the United States had to do with a certain investment regime which we've maintained in recent years. And it's decreased significantly, so we think that's illogical to maintain a high pipeline. But what we have done, we've stopped supporting a number of operations that had something like &#x20AC;44 million in support, which is what we have modified. Well, as far &#x2013; Gamesa is concerned what we do is evaluate the business plan and what we're seeing right now is that the business prospects, because of the crisis, they are less positive than what we had in the past. So, this is why we have made adjustments now. We're talking about &#x20AC;6.8 per share, which is the book value basically of Gamesa's equity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more questions from the room? Let's move on to the telephone then. The first question comes from Morgan Stanley, Carolina Dores. Please go ahead with your question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I have a question about the scrip dividends policy. Are you going to maintain this policy? And what are you going to do in relation to the shares you have in bank yet? And what are the plans for the next two years? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you repeat the second question because we didn't understand you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What are your plans for 2013, 2014? This has to do with banking I think, doesn't it? Isn't that what you were saying?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the scrip dividend, fortunately, there are some tax advantages that are very important for the shareholders. And as you know, it's 20-something percent in tax savings. And there's been a very high degree of acceptance amongst the shareholders. So, it's something that is very favorable and 60-dd percent of the shareholders have accepted this. So, it's going to be very difficult for us to do without this, although I think it's the shareholders that are benefiting from this tax situation. And the second question was what? Well, this is one of the possibilities we've mentioned many a time and it's an element that is to be studied and we have not yet taken any decisions. And as far as debt is concerned, well, the level of debt, I think that the objectives we have would be to have an FFO to the debt above 20% in this ratio for the next few years. And rate in cash flow relative to debt in &#x2013; at the high teens, and these are the objectives we're currently working on right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question comes from <mark type="ph" /> Juan Carlos Sanchez (01:01:00).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have two questions. The first question, I wanted to know what you think about the regulatory charges for renewables in the UK and how this could affect future investments of IBERDROLA. I suppose that we'll be receiving more details in the strategic presentation, but I'd like to know if any growth can be expected. And the second question has to do &#x2013; would it be &#x2013; would it make sense to increase the treasury stocks or would it be necessary to reduce our exposure to Gamesa?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mentioned this in the case of the United Kingdom perhaps and &#x2013; well, Keith Anderson has been negotiating this issue. And I think that what they've done makes sense. And as I said before, it contemplates two things. One is reasonably extensive <mark type="ph" /> grid adaption (01:02:09) for what is already underway. And secondly, this is a slight decrease off of the ROC from 1 to 0.9 that can't be absorbed by technological improvements that are being included in the system, which is what I said in the case of Spain.</p>
          <p>Economic rationality, well, is related to some vertical modifications. So this is what is reducing our costs. And this, obviously, did affect the remuneration system. And the figures that have been obtained are reasonable and which were in line with what we expected. As regards to the price of the shares, it is true that we are suffering a lot in this respect, not only IBERDROLA, but also all the other Spanish corporations. And if you take a look at the behavior of other companies, well, it is independent relative to the results we obtained in our internationalization process. We are subjected to much more macro variables. We have the uncertainties and the effects from the euro, et cetera. So these are elements that we are looking into. And on the Shareholders' Day, this would be one of the subjects that we would also be able to explain to you and debate. And we'll be talking about the actions that we're going to take in that <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:03:30), if we do anything of course. So I would like to leave some things for that day, for the Shareholders' Day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Jos&#xE9; Ruiz [Exane].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You said that you're already cutting back costs, and I would like to know if this one was part of the old plan or does it have to do with the new plan? But then we have a problem with the EBITDA and its inclusion in the books for 2013. Could you please explain the options? And thirdly, could you say something about the levels of coverage as regards forward sales for 2013? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, part of the reduction plan we have comes from the previous plan and what we're doing is accelerating things. So this is why we've made a number of provisions as regards start expenses this year, so that we can be freer when we establish the guidelines. And then there's something else that we're looking into and it's something that we will present on the Investor Day too, which will, obviously, be related to the changes in the gross margin of the business.</p>
          <p>Well, as regards Brazil, I already mentioned this, and the trading on the stock exchange is not done to solve problems here. We have a shareholders' agreement and we've had that agreement for more than ten years. It's in force and it will require some minimal adjustments, so that from the accounting point of view we can consolidate our participation according to the new regulations in EFRs. So trading on the stock exchange doesn't have to do with this. It was an issue that was covered by the current agreement and which we've got &#x2013; are going to maintain in the future. So that &#x2013; if that &#x2013; if they want to apply for it, they can and we will give our support. But one thing is completely unrelated to the other. So we're talking about some very, very minor modifications according to the current shareholders' agreement. So we have to reflect what we have been doing for the last 15 years. So it's putting in writing what we have been doing for some time. And the other issue has already been addressed and shareholders can have access to this. And I think that yesterday, it was pointed out that some of our partners that they want to achieve liquidity for their shares. And we think that that is wonderful and that is also covered by the agreements we've signed and which we've been working and we've had very high degree of success in recent years.</p>
          <p>And if we look at what Nova Energia was like ten years ago, it's completely different. It was a company with only 5 million points of supply. Now they have more than 11 million, more than we have in Spain. And they didn't have any electric power stations and now they're going to have more than 4,000 megawatts, fundamentally hydroelectric. And they didn't have any wind farms but now they are constructing wind farms totaling 300 megawatts. So, it's a company with an absolutely enviable financial situation. So, it's logical for the partners in view of how successful this has been. Sometimes if they feel like doing so, they consider &#x2013; they contemplate trading on the stock exchange, not only have three of us there but there could also be many more shareholders enjoying the success of that company.</p>
          <p>And then something about hedging?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sales fully closed; in the year 2013 we have something like 12%, about 10 <mark type="ph" /> terras (01:07:48) approximately.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question from Alberto Gandolfi [UBS].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have several questions. But there's an elephant in the room, as they say in English, at least that's what lots of investors think. Can you rule out an enlargement of capital? Secondly, what can be done about the deficit or would it be necessary to change the structure and be more creative or transform it into something that is more hybrid? Thirdly, as regards investments, we're talking about recurring investments. A very quick question to Pepe. The lines of provisions and amortizations are somewhat different than what I expected them to be, but could you please say something more about these items and could you give us your thoughts and what you think is going to apply to 2013? And finally, for the President; last year, there was a possible merger with a German company and what you said is that we always speak to everybody. So in a very tough environment where the market is penalizing a company like yours only because you are trading on the IBEX, would it make sense to merge with another player or would that be nonsense only?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I can see that you are very imaginative this morning. And as regards the capitalization, no, I have to say absolutely not. I've said this many times before, no, no. This is not in any of the analysis of that we haven't &#x2013; we don't have to change capital. We are running in the opposite direction. We are in a situation in which we are making the company &#x2013; the company has to reduce its investments. It has to improve our free cash flow. We have carried out divestitures to reduce our level of indebtedness, et cetera, et cetera. So we are moving in a completely different direction, not in an expansive matter, but rather we want to fully rationalize and solidify our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>As regards to securitization of the deficit, well, with all the ideas that you have or just send me a list of all the possibilities, because to date, the situation we have, and this has to be done through the <mark type="ph" /> Favve (01:11:19) and there's a brochure that has been sent by the Stock Exchange Commission mentioning a number of issues and what <mark type="ph" /> Favve (01:11:25) authorizes is that resort to public or private issues, but that's what we have noticed. But if you have any ideas, I'd love to have them because without a doubt I will present them to the government to see if the issue can also solve the problem. And the third question was what? And yes, I think that that's about &#x20AC;3 billion in the year roughly, and if not it will be along those lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the final question, amortizations and provisions; well, now as far as the provisions are concerned, there are two non-recurrent impacts. So we have the line of amortization that I think is consistent with what we have been talking about. So therefore, we are at something like &#x20AC;2.6 billion. And next year, well, it would be similar too because now the level of investments is not going to increase pretty much. As regards provisions of the &#x20AC;186 million, there are 100 of them that are non-recurrent and one of them has to do with Brazil, which is something that we mentioned in the first quarter because of bad debt issues that we are currently covering and this totals &#x20AC;50 million and then we have the &#x20AC;45 million from the pipeline &#x2013; the renewables pipeline. So in total, we're talking about something like &#x20AC;95 million that are non-recurrent. So therefore, as far as the semester is concerned, what is recurrent is about &#x20AC;80 million and as regards the year, well, it could be more or less double that figure. And the last question, the merger, well, no, certainly not. None of the scenarios has contemplated a merger.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Virginia Sanz at Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. I also had two questions, one regarding the CapEx. I thought you were going to give us more information when you announced the new strategic plan. But to understand the flexibility, I would like to know how much of your current CapEx is directly linked to maintenance, how much is linked to the regulated UK business? And there's going to continue to be investments in this area and how much is committed to the transmission line in the United States. And my second question, in a regulatory scenario where what is decided in the end may be not as prudent as we would like. What capacity would you have to start shutting down facilities in Spain, generation facilities, as we see that the German companies are doing? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, regarding the CapEx, we have the regulated business in UK and in the U.S., not just the transmission lines, but also distribution. And then, what we're committed to is what we're building in renewables. And all the rest is maintenance with the minor exception of completing what we're doing in Spain, some small hydroelectric investments in Galicia and finishing what we're doing at Cortes-La Muela in Valencia. But these are absolutely marginal issues, the rest is maintenance.</p>
          <p>So regarding generation, I don't know the exact figures. But massively, it's maintenance. And regarding the rest, it's basically half on the regulated side &#x2013; or half is maintenance and half is expansion. But that maintenance is also regulated. So to all effects and purposes, the commitment is the same. In global figures, and correct me, Pepe and Juan Carlos, I would say that around 70% are investments linked to regulated businesses and the rest are investments that is maintenance or similar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And where is there room to play?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, basically, in renewables that we can lower more or less, and in Spain we can lower it more or less depending on the framework at any specific point in time. Sorry, the power stations. Well, forgive me, Virginia, but I still believe in common sense. And since I still believe in common sense, I don't think it makes common sense to shut down what's cheap in order to run what's expensive. So since I believe in common sense &#x2013; well, if I see there's no common sense, I'll comment on our plans and what we'll do about it. But right now, I want to continue to have the hope that common sense, economic rationality and non-discrimination will continue to prevail in our country before the pressures from the lobbies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question from Javier Suarez from Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hello, everybody. I also have three questions. The first regarding working capital, any deterioration in the working capital of the company as a result of the economic situation of the country? And the second point, you've spoken about the possible sale of assets. Although this probably is more for Investor Day, but could you give us a figure that the company would feel comfortable with in the next few years? And the third question, regarding output for 2012 and 2013, and I would like you to give us some forecast for 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, <mark type="ph" /> Paco (01:17:55), perhaps you can talk about the figures. You spoke about them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I spoke about sales at the closed price. Well, there are different sales of coverage in closing for the sales. What was &#x2013; Luis San Pedro gave us is the sales volume, which has an absolutely closed price and we can't transfer any cost increases from taxes or wherever except by breaking the contract, which has been done, but which we're not at all considering at this point. The sales level with an assured price, which I think is the question, goes from 10 to 30 and the sales price for those 30 is similar to the price we closed for this year. This closed price means that we have some capability to transfer possible increase in prices. We have some capability to transfer it as long as it appears in the wholesale price. So it's not a fixed price. Let's say that we have a sort of price floor, I would say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, regarding working capital, do you want to comment on it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the working capital at risk, I assume that you refer to the customers' account and NPAs. The debt pending collection that has been deferred significantly was basically from the public administrations and practically all the debt we had before December 31, 2011 has already been collected. What is pending is the debt that is now being generated, but we are still at an NPL level that doesn't concern us from the economic point of view. The sale of assets, I'm not going to give a figure, but I'm going to say something very simple. We're going to sell the necessary assets to reach the ratios that the CFO said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So how much will it be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, enough to reach the ratios that we want to achieve. And he very clearly explained what we expect FFO over debt, cash flow over debt, et cetera. And we'll do whatever is needed depending on the free cash flow we generate. We will complete that with more &#x2013; fewer divestments to reach that objective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Fernando Murillo from Caixa.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I think that practically all the questions have been asked. But is Gamesa still strategic or could there possibly be a divestment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, over recent years, we've said that Gamesa for us is a company which apart from the investment is a very major supplier for us. And a lot of our wind power machines are Gamesa machines and we've always wanted to be near them in order to be updated about any changes, improvements, et cetera, et cetera. There have been some complicated moments in the supply of machines and we've had the machines we needed for our expansion. So this is the issue. More than a financial investor, we're a technological investor. The investment volumes in the renewables area, well, the financial investment in this is absolutely irrelevant compared to the total investment in wind power. We've invested some tens of billions of euros and an investment of a few hundred millions in this is irrelevant compared to what they can provide from the technological point of view, et cetera, et cetera, and the support they can give us. And that's been our philosophy and that will continue to be our philosophy in the future. That means having 20%, 10%, 16% or 21%. Well, that's irrelevant. This is what we've been doing during all this period. What is relevant is being close to them because we believe that it's useful for both companies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the final question over the phone from Jos&#xE9; Antonio (sic) [Jos&#xE9; Lopez] (01:22:25) from HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Good morning. Jos&#xE9; Lopez from HSBC. A couple of questions regarding the UK. What plans do you have to replace the generation lost from the shutdown of coal plants? I understand that it could be replaced with gas. And I'd like to know if any work has been done to start building new gas plants. And aren't you concerned that in the future there could be a situation in the UK, like in Spain, where there will be a firm gap because of the wind power generation?</p>
          <p>And the second question is how much you think the CapEx would cost to build new nuclear power plants in the UK and whether this plan in the UK you have is realistic, especially in relation to the balance sheet, the pressures in Spain, et cetera, et cetera? Eon, Scottish and Southern have withdrawn and there's a state company that's still involved that follows different principles. So in conclusion, what is the nuclear situation in the UK from your point of view? And secondly, how do you plan to replace the coal plants that are going to be shut down in the near future to maintain the upstream/downstream match?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, in the UK, we are the first wind power producer in the UK. We continue to build wind farms. Onshore, this year, there'll be 300 megawatts to 400 megawatts. We're building some also offshore in West Duddon Sands and the Irish Sea. We have some projects in East Anglia. Therefore, we're already doing it. We don't have to replace. We're already replacing. But apart from this, correct me, <mark type="ph" /> Paco (01:24:27), I think we have three projects with very advanced permits to build combined cycle plants, some of them in our own locations and others in different locations, some existing gas plant locations, others in some existing coal plant locations and others at different locations in different parts of the country, some in the north and some in the south.</p>
          <p>And regarding the nuclear issue, well, our policy is a very prudent policy. We haven't taken on any commitment to buy as our colleagues have done regarding locations. We have a team of people working together with our colleagues from Suez/Gaz de France. But we have not made any decisions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What are we waiting for?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For combined cycles and nuclear plants to clarify the energy reform.</p>
          <p>And regarding the possibility of doing something wrong from the point of view of the cycles, et cetera, et cetera, well, I think that in the UK, they're way ahead of what's being done in Spain. They're aware that non-predictable plants like wind power plants need the backup of other kind of plants, basically gas. And one of the things they've clarified is that from the beginning there will be a capacity payment system. We'll see how that materializes.</p>
          <p>Secondly, regarding the nuclear issue, there's a tremendous debate as to what the funding system is going to be. If there isn't a certain safe for price that can provide levels of profitability and security on the middle and long term, the possible decision is not to do it. If there's a fairly reasonable remuneration, et cetera, we'll think about it. But right now, no decision has been made in the nuclear field. Apart from the studies, there have been no expenses. We haven't bought any locations that you have to pay hundreds of millions of pounds for. We have solutions for locations at very attractive prices, but until 2015 we don't have to say yes or no to buying that location. So I hope that from here to 2015, the whole framework will be much clearer. And regarding gas plants, we haven't stopped, we have the locations, we have the availabilities, we have the approvals, very advanced, in some cases they are practically completed, it is just a matter of saying go ahead and once it's clear what the framework is. Meanwhile, what are we doing? Well, we're already replacing our production more than extensively with the wind power production in the country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's 11:00, we have two more questions over the webpage that &#x2013; which we'll answer through the Customer Relations department. So, we can close. Well, thank you very much. Have a nice summer and let's hope we won't have any more bad news over the summer and that things will sort themselves out. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>