<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1198005" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>FY 2008 Guidance Call</title>
    <date>2008-11-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1430</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Gareth Davis, Chief Executive</participant>
      <participant id="2">Thomas Mulier</participant>
      <participant id="3">Gareth Davis</participant>
      <participant id="4">Robert Dyrbus</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>...and welcome to the Imperial Tobacco Newswire Conference Call. Today's conference is being recorded. At this time, I'd like to turn the call over to your host today, Mr. Gareth Davis, Chief Executive. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and thank you for joining us today. I am here with other members of the Imperial executive team, and after taking you through the key points of today's announcement we will take any questions you may have.</p>
          <p>In a year of significant achievement, we completed the Altadis acquisition and grew our cigarette volumes and shares in both mature and emerging markets. In terms of headlines, our global cigarette volumes increased by 46% to just over 290 billion fixed. Adjusted profit from operations was up by 51% to over &#xA3;2.2 billion and adjusted earnings attributable to ordinary shareholders was up by 26% to a little under &#xA3;1.2 billion. In line with existing policy, we're proposing to pay half of this as ordinary dividends, also representing a 26% increase. Therefore, the Board recommends a final dividend of 42.2 pence per share, bringing the total for the year to 63.1 pence per share after taking into account the additional shares in issue following the completion of the rights issue. Adjusted earnings per share were 136.9 pence, a 15% increase on 2007 after adjusting last year's EPS for the bonus elements of the rights issue.</p>
          <p>It's pleasing to report that we have achieved further growth in both mature and emerging markets, and I'll start my operational review by giving you a flavor of our progress in mature markets. In the UK, we remained the market leader with the best selling cigarette, fine cut tobacco and rolling paper brands, Lambert &amp; Butler, Golden Virginia and Rizla. Our value cigarette brand, Windsor Blue, continues to grow and now accounts for over 3% of the market. The economy sector has grown as consumers down-trade to cheaper brands and products, and this trend is likely to continue in the current economic climate. To capitalize on this we launched the JPS Silver range a few weeks ago. We think it's a great product and have high expectations for its success.</p>
          <p>Down trading is also a key dynamic in Germany, and we've benefited from this, increasing our cigarette shares to 27.4% and our share of other tobacco products to 20%. Now cigarette success has been driven by our value offering, JPS, which is now the number two cigarette brand in Germany with just under 8% of the market. At the other end of the price spectrum, our premium brand, Gauloise Blondes, was resilient in maintaining its share of 5.6%, as were our other premium offerings, Davidoff and R1.</p>
          <p>As a result of the Altadis deal, we have an enhanced position in France and have become the market leader across all tobacco categories in Spain. We increased our cigarette share in France. We've gained from our key brands, Gauloises Blondes, JPS and Fortuna, while in Spain growth from our cigarette brands, Nobel and Ducados Rubio, was complemented by a good performance from Farias mini cigars. Elsewhere in the EU, our cigarette brands across all segments performed well with particularly strong volume growth from Davidoff at the premium end and JPS at the value end. We've also been swift to capitalize on the growth in fine cut tobacco in EU accession countries, particularly in Hungary and the Czech Republic, where we substantially increased our market shares.</p>
          <p>We are delighted with the progress we're making in the United States. We made further cigarette gains in the year and launched Davidoff in key cities and Fortuna in Texas and Florida. Our natural wrapper cigar brands, Dutch Masters and Backwoods, performed well and we significantly improved our fine cut tobacco position achieving a September spot share of around 8% compared to just 1% a year ago.</p>
          <p>Our success in mature markets is complemented by a growing presence in emerging markets, and this year we achieved excellent results in Eastern Europe, Africa and the Middle East. In Eastern Europe, our strong performance was driven by cigarette gains in several markets. We continue to take advantage of the growth in premium brands, and we're achieving considerable success with Davidoff in a number of countries. In Africa, we significantly improved our volumes and market shares and our portfolio of strong local brands, while Gauloises Blondes, Gitanes Blondes and Davidoff continued to make great strides in the Middle East.</p>
          <p>Asia is another key growth area for Imperial. We made further good progress in Vietnam and Laos and will be improving our competitive position in Taiwan with the opening of our new cigarette factory in January.</p>
          <p>Whilst driving the operational performance of the enlarged group, we've continued to make very good progress on the integration of Imperial and Altadis. Last week we concluded the consultation process in France, and we'll be in a position to begin implementation in early 2009. Elsewhere, we continue to have constructive dialogue in Spain and Germany, and we've completed the mergers of the Imperial and Altadis sales teams in Russia, Ukraine, Poland, Austria, Belgium and Italy. Our cigar and fine cut tobacco factory in Slovakia has been closed, and consultations on the closure of our Bristol cigar factory and the restructuring of our Nottingham cigarette factory have concluded, enabling implementation to begin early next year.</p>
          <p>Maintaining this positive momentum will be a key focus going forward, and I can confirm that we remain on track to deliver the previously announced annual operating efficiencies. It's regrettable that these projects are impacting our employees, and we are providing a comprehensive range of measures to support those affected by integration. Integration will remain a priority going forward, but will not detract from our operational performance. The versatility of our portfolio with strength in both premium and value brands and products provides many growth opportunities. Going forward, we'll build on our strong presence in mature markets by enhancing our positions in the EU and further developing our US business whilst maintaining our excellent growth momentum in emerging markets.</p>
          <p>Following the success of the rights issue in June and the two bond issues in September, we are comfortable with our current financing position. Global economic conditions are turbulent and are unlikely to improve in the short term, but our business is both resilient and highly cash generative, and we remain well placed to continue to create sustainable value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Thanks, ladies and gentlemen. I'll now take any questions that you might have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We will take our first question now from Thomas Mulier from Bloomberg News. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Gareth. This is Thomas from Bloomberg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Thomas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I was just wondering if you could comment on JPMorgan is estimating that UK tax impacts of the preannouncement yesterday, they're estimating there could be an increase of about 0.20 to 0.30 pence per pack on cigarettes next year, is that &#x2013; how likely do you see that happening and what would be the effect of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not quite sure how JPMorgan have calculated that. I think the situation that was announced yesterday with the package of tax cuts in Britain, and basically on tobacco what they did was &#x2013; obviously the VAT reduced, but the other aspect of excise duty were increased to compensate for the loss of the VAT. That all worked out as broadly very neutral for us, sort of arbitraging between that and ad valorem. Now if we look forward, I think what was being pretty much signaled up by the government was what I would describe as sort of normal inflation type increases that we've seen over the last few years. So I'm not quite sure where the JPMorgan number comes from. Certainly, if one was looking at normal inflation, it would be significantly less than that JPMorgan number. So I will have to speak to them to see how they calculated that, but it seems very odd to me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And maybe if I just do one &#x2013; second question, in the Kantos interviews, Bob Dyrbus says that Imperial may try to make some headroom before some financing matures in July 2009. Could you elaborate on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'll do better than that, Thomas. I will get Bob Dyrbus to elaborate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>He's by my side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thomas, good morning. As you said, we have no requirement. We may do &#x2013; it all depends on the market conditions. We constantly monitor the state of the market effectively. It's a question always of supply and cost. One of the positives is we have seen, for example, and you will have seen recently, the markets do seem to be open now for tobacco companies. In fact, Altria, PMI, and VAT having gone <mark type="inaudible" /> admittedly at some cost recently, it's something we just constantly monitor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And would that be advanced sale or would it be <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The short answer is it really depends on supply and demand and what's in the position access to whichever market and which is the more attractive at the time. So I think that we have no absolute requirement, but if we see an attractive opportunity we will take it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We'll take a next question from Mark Potter of Reuters. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just following on from that, are you giving any guidance on net debt for the current financial year, how much you expect to reduce it by and also on the cost of the debt, I see it's 5.5% for the year just ended?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think I'll let Bob take that one as well. Bob?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, we will be giving guidance of 5.5% for the current year as well as last year. We've got a presentation on financing debt later this morning, so we'll be breaking out that then. In terms of what we're doing, we're using our free cash flow in the short-term to reduce debt, and obviously &#x2013; I mean again we have supplied a mix of currency to the debt and currently of &#xA3;11.5 billion at the year end, about 1.1 &#x2013; just over 1.3 billion sterling, about $2.5 billion and about just over &#xA3;7 billion worth of euros. We have free cash flow, we had free cash flow in 2008 of &#xA3;1 billion. So &#x2013; I mean we are very cash generative and we started this year well. So we're also focusing on working capital. And basically our debt presentation will be available on our website after 10 o'clock this morning. If you want any further information on it, feel free to come back to me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I will take a look. Are you able just to &#x2013; just to give an overview as to how you're planning to keep the cost of the debt stable because most even though seem to be expecting an increase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, basically, there are I suppose &#x2013; firstly, we have an interest rate fixed, so &#x2013; we have obviously an interest rate-fixing program. Our debt is comprised of three components, the underlying cost of debt, the drawn margin, amortization of fees, and in fact with that plus potential headroom for potential further refinancing, we're comfortable with the 5.5%. The reality is on the floating rate element of our debt, we've seen interest rates coming down, and we also have a large proportion of euro and U.S. dollar debt, and of course those interest rates are lower than the sterling rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And finally, is there any guidance on what you expect to reduce &#x2013; what you expect net debt to be this time next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't actually give guidance on net debt. Effectively, our free cash flow will be going to reduce our net debt, so &#x2013; and I'm afraid if I could &#x2013; if I said what our free cash flow was and that's obviously <mark type="inaudible" /> not going there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We have a follow-up question now from Thomas Mulier from Bloomberg News. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Just maybe two more questions on the debt, if I may, if no one else has other questions. One is that many of your loans have been underwritten by Lehman Brothers, by Citigroup, which is now propped up by the government. Is that a concern? Will you be seeking different banks to refinance your loans, or will you be &#x2013; I mean what is the strategy there? And the second question is, there is a rising trend for companies to tie the pricing of their loans to credit default swap prices. Nestle and Nokia have done this recently instead of tying it to another benchmark. Would Imperial Tobacco be considering that? Would it be happy with that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Firstly, obviously consolidation reduces the choice, but it's not significantly impacted on us. We &#x2013; I mean Lehmans were part of our original syndicated facility and with their collapse, we lost about &#xA3;200 million of headroom, which wasn't of concern to us. We're comfortable with our relationship and the group of relationship banks that we have.</p>
          <p>In terms of basically pricing on loans and pricing on bonds, it depends which market you are in, it just <mark type="inaudible" /> markets who have had possibly credit default swaps. US market potentially more &#x2013; were current &#x2013; <mark type="inaudible" /> trading. And really, if the CDS market was completely functioning, you would find the way your bonds are trading in the market bears quite a good relationship to CDS. So, I &#x2013; basically we didn't tie our last ones to CDS. Obviously, it was one of the factors in terms of the cost of issuance. But basically tobacco is seen as very defensive, very resilient, good cash flow characteristics, and so we've not seen the need to do that in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll take a follow-up question now from Mark Potter of Reuters. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I just wanted to ask about JPS Silver and your hopes for it and the competitive landscape in the UK?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We launched it about three weeks ago now, Mark. I mean the early times are very encouraging. It's achieved a very wide level of distribution in a short time. And the early results feedback is, as I say, very encouraging and very much in line with what we expected from the brand. It does have a tremendous heritage as a brand, and certainly we are seeing many &#x2013; or most of the leading multiples have taken the brand up and obviously it's very popular in the independent trade as well. So, this is all very encouraging at the moment. Certainly, our previous value offering, Windsor Blue, improved very strongly and that's now got a spot share of over 3%. So we would expect I think at least as good a performance from JPS Silver if not better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We have a question now from Michael Carmen of Dow Jones. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just back on the Altadis question, given that it's going so well, is there any temptation to raise the synergy targets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think at this point in time, no. I mean certainly we've been concentrating on the actual process of negotiation and consultation and we've largely come to the end of that, still some work to do in Germany and in Spain, but it has gone well. For the moment, we stick with what we promised. Obviously, that is something that we view over time in the light of experience and certainly next year we are anticipating roundabout 180 million pounds of &#x2013; euros of synergy during the course of the financial year we've just started as far as a big year for the synergies. So probably we maintain the figure at the moment, but obviously we've got teams working together. The process is doing very well so far, but we've got many joint teams working together sort of focusing on growing the business, so a lot of effort going to topline growth as well. So far I mean the chemistry has been extremely good and this is one of the best integrations in our acquisition history that I have seen that has been very smooth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. As we have no further questions, I'd like to turn the call back over to you, Mr. Davis, for any additional or closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thanks very much for joining us, ladies and gentlemen. As I said, we are extremely pleased with this year's outturn. It has been a hell of a year for Imperial with all the transactions of Altadis and Logista and many other related transactions. So we've been fairly pretty quick this year. But as you see from the results, we've not taken our eye off the goal in terms of the operational performance and that's considered to &#x2013; continue to plough ahead.</p>
          <p>So thanks for taking the time to join us. And if you have any further questions throughout the day, please give us a call. Have a good day. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That will conclude today's conference call. Thank you for your participation, ladies and gentlemen. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>