<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1474250" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-05-01</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1430</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive Officer &amp; Executive Director">Alison J. Cooper</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Director &amp; Finance Director">Robert Dyrbus</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (United Kingdom)">Erik A. Bloomquist</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Director-Group Corporate &amp; Legal Affairs">Matthew R. Phillips</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">David H. Hayes</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Oriel Securities Ltd.">Chris W. Wickham</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Jonathan S. Leinster</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep" affiliation="Sales Director">Arthur van Benthem</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Fulvio Cazzol</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">James Bushnell</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies International Ltd.">Dirk Van Vlaanderen</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Adam J. Spielman</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Jonathan P. Fell</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Investec Bank Plc (Broker)">Martin J. Deboo</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Rogerio S. Fujimori</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA (UK)">Chas Manso</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Marketing Director">Roberto Funari</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well good morning, everyone and welcome to our Half Year Results Presentation. I'm Alison Cooper, Chief Executive of Imperial; and with me is Bob Dyrbus, our Finance Director; and other members of the Senior Imperial team, including Matthew Phillips, who'll be appointed to Board as Corporate Affairs Director in June. I'm pleased Matthew's joining the Board, and his appointment reflects the important of Corporate Affairs to our sales growth strategy. After a brief overview of our first half performance, the team will take any questions.</p>
          <p>Our strategy continues to deliver sustainable returns to our shareholders and we remain focused on realizing the potential of our assets. We maximize shareholder returns by driving sales, generating high-margin profit and using our cash to reward investors and support the development of the business. It's a growth model that continues to create significant value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>The four sales growth drivers are central to our success, and I'll be talking more about them later. Our focus on driving growth through our unique total tobacco portfolio whilst effectively managing costs and cash has delivered a number of highlights in first half. And the sales momentum we're generating has been reflected in the strong performance in the second quarter, with tobacco net revenues up 8% against the same period last year.</p>
          <p>We delivered good first half growth from our key strategic brands, Davidoff, Gauloises Blonde, West and JPS, with combined stick equivalent volumes up 5% and brand net revenues up 12%.</p>
          <p>Fine cut tobacco volumes declined 1%, driven by market weakness in Poland. Excluding Poland, our volumes were up 3%. We improved volumes of our luxury Cuban cigars by 3% and revenues by 8%, with strong growth in emerging markets. And we again delivered excellent results in smokeless, improving snus volumes by 74%.</p>
          <p>On a constant currency basis, our portfolio gains resulted in growth in both tobacco net revenues and adjusted operating profit of 3.3%.</p>
          <p>We continue to invest in the business to build sustainable revenue growth whilst maintaining strong tobacco adjusted operating margins at around 43%. Adjusted earnings per share rose 5.1%, we increased the interim dividend by 13% and intend to continue growing annual dividend ahead of adjusted earnings per share growth. In addition, we completed the &#xA3;500 million share buyback announced this time last year. And the buyback will continue at this annualized rate going forward.</p>
          <p>On a half yearly basis, stick equivalent volumes were down 4%. The first quarter was challenging due to a number of specific external factors, which clouded our true achievements. And looking at the second quarter figures gives you a much better insight into the sales momentum we're generating. We delivered a strong performance with volumes down just 1% and tobacco net revenues up 8%, and that's despite the impact of the Syria sanctions, which we're still lapping. While second quarter growth reflects the success of our key strategic brands, with combined stick equivalent volumes up 6% and revenues up 15% against the same period last year, a very pleasing performance and we'll be building on this sales momentum in the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>So that's an overview of what we've achieved. I want to now focus on the how. How we're realizing the potential of our assets to drive sales growth and deliver high quality sustainable earnings growth.</p>
          <p>We have a winning mindset, a best-in-class reputation for managing costs and industry-leading margins. And we're very focused on delivering sales excellence across the business through our four sales growth drivers. These are portfolio management, innovation, customer engagements and pricing. Applying consumer and customer insights across the four growth drivers is key to the work we're doing to drive sustainable sales growth. We're enhancing our expertise in all these areas and we're very pleased with the results.</p>
          <p>Let's start by looking at portfolio management. It is about capitalizing on our portfolio strength, realizing the potential of total tobacco to maximize our share of consumers and consumption, reaching more consumers on more occasions.</p>
          <p>We've been very successful in achieving this with Davidoff, generating strong sales growth in emerging markets where disposable incomes and consumer preferences for luxury brands are increasing. Half-year volumes were up 2% with further gains in Asia and the Middle East, and we grew second quarter volumes by 5%, reflecting the brand's positive momentum.</p>
          <p>In Eastern Europe, we put Davidoff into profitable high-growth segments such as king-size, super slims and queen size, significantly increasing our volumes for these formats. Davidoff growth was also strong in Asia Pacific where brand volumes were up 11%. And there's much more to come. Davidoff has huge potential, and we're currently finalizing a number of key initiatives to fuel further growth in the second half and into next year.</p>
          <p>Gauloises Blonde is our largest brand, with annual stick equivalent volumes of around &#xA3;30 billion. It's a brand that's well-positioned in the EU and growing fast in Africa and the Middle East. The success of Gauloises Blonde is driven by its iconic branding, emphasizing freedom and joie de vivre. We're currently rolling out a new global campaign called Light Up Your Life which highlights the brand's sense of free spirit.</p>
          <p>These initiatives are designed to build on what was a great first half performance from Gauloises Blonde. Volumes were up 11%, driven by strong gains in Africa and the Middle East where volumes increased by 20%. We've also extended the franchise with Gauloises Tactil, a new cigarette blend in an innovative GlideTec pack. It's just been launched in France and the initial response has been excellent.</p>
          <p>Overall volumes of West were flat, but we're achieving in numerous emerging markets in Eastern Europe and Asia, with Taiwan up 35% and further growth in Russia and the Ukraine. Consumer demand for innovation remains strong in Eastern Europe. The launch of queen-sized West compact in Ukraine and West Duo with a crushball filter in Russia is supporting our ability to capitalize on these growing trends.</p>
          <p>JPS has been a star performer for several years. By making JPS increasingly relevant to value-seeking consumers and creating a total tobacco brand franchise, we've transformed its performance. Annual volumes reached 25 billion stick equivalents in the year to March and we continue to build on the JPS success story. We increased volumes by over 4% in the first half, achieving growth in a number of markets with strong results in the UK and Australia. And there's further untapped potential in JPS. We recently completed a major rejuvenation project aimed at reinforcing the brand's credentials.</p>
          <p>We're world leaders in fine cut, and we've been reinforcing this position by strategically managing share and profits to maximize returns. Overall volumes were down, due to a weaker market in Poland compounded by destocking where we increased our share. We're focused on driving profitable growth in the make-your-own category in a number of markets through JPS, Ducados and News. Our leadership in fine cut tobacco is supported by our ongoing success in papers and tubes where volumes were up 5% and 10% respectively in the first half.</p>
          <p>We delivered another strong performance with our luxury Habanos cigars, particularly in emerging markets. Growth is being supported by limited editions, such as the Cohiba Behike line. We increased overall volumes by 3% and sales were up by 8%, with emerging market volumes up 12% and sales climbing 17% as a result of excellent gains in China, Russia and the Middle East.</p>
          <p>And our Smokeless business continues to go from strength to strength in Scandinavia, where we developed a dynamic snus portfolio that's in tune with what consumers want. The portfolio is well-placed to reach more consumers on more occasions, with a strong presence in both premium and value. The new factory is enabling us to keep pace with the growing demand for our brands. In the first half, we improved volumes by an impressive 74%, and increased market shares in Sweden and Norway. And we further strengthened our position in Sweden by launching a new brand to compete in the value segment. Sm&#xE5;lands Snus is named after the region where our factory is based and will further enhance our ability to maximize growth opportunities.</p>
          <p>I gave a flavor of our innovation work earlier. It's an important driver of growth and we're making great strides in building a bigger pipeline of scalable innovations based on consumer insights. These consumer-led innovations are expanding our total tobacco portfolio. They're focused on giving consumers what they want and we're applying innovation to brands, products and markets in a way that will be margin-accretive. Pack innovations provide smokers with choice and reinforce brand differentiation. Branded tobacco packaging enables smokers to distinguish one brand from another, which drives effective competition between tobacco companies.</p>
          <p>Through GlideTec, we've developed some industry-leading innovation built around consumer insights into the sociability of smoking. It's an innovation that strengthened Lambert &amp; Butler's performance in the UK and we expect Tactil to do the same for Gauloises in France and Fortuna GlideTec to deliver similar results in Spain, following its launch last week.</p>
          <p>Capacity investment is supporting GlideTec's international rollout with a number of other brand and market launches to follow. Setting the pace for innovation and being first to market is important and we're also focused on gaining share in high-growth segments and I highlighted some of these to you earlier. Here, you can see some other examples.</p>
          <p>We've been active with crushball filter technology. West Duo has also been launched in Russia and Poland and we have a Fortuna version in France. Lambert &amp; Butler Fresh Burst has just gone into the UK and there will be further crushball launches in other markets. We're also introducing queen size variants across many territories, including the current launch of L&amp;B Profile in the UK. More initiatives are underway as we continue to focus on building a pipeline of fewer, bigger, better innovations that are scalable and will deliver high returns.</p>
          <p>Customer engagement is about maximizing the availability and advocacy of our brands and products at the point of sale, leveraging our strong retailer partnerships to grow our share of consumers and consumption. We have a great reputation for customer engagement, and we're focused on enhancing our expertise in this area even further.</p>
          <p>Customer engagement is a key focus area across our markets and it's particularly important in product display brand environments. We've made great strides in Australia, where our strong trade relationship have supported excellent share and volume gains. In the UK, we've been working with large retailers in the run up to the first stage of display restrictions, which came into effect last month.</p>
          <p>We've also extended our UK sales force coverage and are increasing the frequency of our visits to independent retailers, reducing their working capital requirements and rewarding availability and advocacy. This activity is strengthening our position in the UK and is a key element to get consumer traction with innovations such as Lambert &amp; Butler GlideTec, Profile and Fresh Burst.</p>
          <p>The fourth sales growth driver is pricing, maximizing revenue growth by taking a strategic approach to pricing opportunities by brand, pack size and sales channel. This is about detailed price analysis and modeling across our footprint, as well as further enhancing our approach to engagement with authorities on excise matters.</p>
          <p>Our pricing strategy for the Fortuna brand franchise in Spain is a good example of how we're applying this thinking. We offer consumers choice and value through differentiated Fortuna variants. And when we raised our prices last July, we positioned the Fortuna family at various price points to reach a broader range of consumers. This has helped us get Fortuna back on track, on a growth trend and its brand share is driving higher. We're implementing the same strategy in other markets, focused on maximizing share and revenue growth.</p>
          <p>From a group perspective, we've already achieved over 80% of our pricing assumptions for this financial year. Applying all four sales growth drivers across our footprint is key to building sustainable sales and is delivering positive results across our regions.</p>
          <p>This slide shows the recent upward trend of our cigarette and fine-cut tobacco shares. In the EU, we continue to focus on balancing share and profit to maximize returns. Some shares have been under pressure, but we're addressing this through the growth drivers. We generated positive results in our cigarette and fine-cut tobacco shares in our most of our major markets in the second quarter compared the first quarter of this year. That includes Spain, the UK, Germany and France.</p>
          <p>Outside the EU, our U.S. share has been under pressure in what remains a very competitive market, while in our rest of the world region, there's growth in value and premium above product. We're capitalizing on key consumer growth segments through the success of our key strategic brands and our strong portfolio of local and regional brands, achieving particularly good results in Asia Pacific and Africa and the Middle East. This reflects the strong second quarter momentum we generated across our regions, and we'll be building on this in the second half.</p>
          <p>And I hand you over to Bob to take you through the financials.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Alison, and good morning, everyone. I'll start with an overview of the results. This table includes the reconciliation between reported and constant currency numbers. I'll be focusing on constant currency-adjusted numbers for all of my comments. Results have been adjusted and presented on our usual basis, with details in the appendices.</p>
          <p>Tobacco net revenues were up 3.3%, with positive growth mix offsetting volume declines, whilst logistics distribution fees declined 1.8%, a robust performance given the economic climate. Tobacco operating profits increased 3.3% and logistics operating profits decreased 3.8%, giving a combined growth at the Group level of 3%.</p>
          <p>We continue to invest in the business to drive long-term growth whilst generating high margins of around 43%. And after tax, being charged at an effective rate of 24.5%, which remains our guidance for the full year, earnings per share grew by 5.1%.</p>
          <p>In the EU, I'll start with the UK, where our financial performance benefited from a favorable comparative due to the timing of price increases. Revenues were up over 12%, and operating profit up more than 9%. In Germany, both revenues and profits were up over 3%. In Spain, revenues declined 4% and profits 2% as a result of further weakness in market volumes. In our rest of EU region, we grew revenues by 4% and profits by over 5%.</p>
          <p>In the Americas and principally the U.S., our profits and revenues declined in a competitive market, partly impacted by shipment timings ahead of our price increase last year, whilst in our rest of world region, revenues increased by over 6% with profits up over 5%.</p>
          <p>Volumes in Eastern Europe declined 9%, impacted by conditions in the Ukraine, where there was a distributor destocking and market softness following a tax increase. This was partially offset by growth in Russia. Eastern Europe remains a key strategic growth region for the group and we're continuing to invest to support our portfolio and strengthen our competitive position. We continue to make excellent progress in Asia Pacific, growing volumes over 4%, and gaining share in most of our key markets. Revenue increased 16%, benefiting from improved mix, and profits were up over 23%.</p>
          <p>In Africa and the Middle East, we increased volumes, revenue and profit despite the impact of Syria, driven by a number of strong global and regional brand performances. In logistics, profits declined 3.8%, a robust result, given the difficult operating environment. In tobacco logistics, growth in cigars and fine-cut tobacco has helped offset the decline in cigarette volumes, while in other logistics, our transport operations performed well. We grew our market share in our Pharma division, and in our lottery business, we have added new point of sales to the network. Our ongoing cost savings program continues to focus on maximizing profitability.</p>
          <p>Our average all-in cost of net debt was stable at 5.5%. W e expect this to be slightly higher at around 5.7% for the full year. The net interest charge is stable, given our normal first half working capital outflow, the final dividend payment, and buybacks. The appendices contain further details on our debt maturities.</p>
          <p>Turning to the financing of the business, our closing adjusted net debt for this half was &#xA3;9.9 billion. Working capital followed its normal pattern with a significant outflow in the first-half of just over &#xA3;1 billion, due to a number of factors, including preproduction ahead of January and February duty increases. Net capital expenditure was &#xA3;152 million, and our cash conversion declined as a result of the higher working capital outflow this half year. The impact of foreign exchange movements was minimal. As you've seen from the second quarter, there's strong sales momentum in the business and we want to maintain this over the long-term and we'll continue investing in our products, portfolio, our sales force, and other areas of the business to support our sales growth agenda.</p>
          <p>As we've previously stated, we envisage net CapEx of around &#xA3;400 million in 2012, reflecting our investment in capacity to meet demand in consumer growth segments and continue building our innovation pipeline. Our focus for the remainder of the year is to continue applying our sales growth drivers to further enhance sales and profit momentum.</p>
          <p>This is supported by our work on key enablers, particularly when it comes to managing regulation and tackling illicit trade. We'll continue to vigorously challenge extreme regulatory proposals, such as plain packaging, which are not based on credible evidence, and will only serve to further fuel the illegal trade in tobacco. We expect the outcome of the court hearings in Australia to be announced later in the year and we'll make a comprehensive submission to the UK government for  consultation.</p>
          <p>From a footprint perspective, we expect EU consumers to remain focused on value, and we will be capitalizing on this dynamic with our total tobacco portfolio. In the UK, we expect further market volume declines and we'll continue to focus on reinforcing our leadership position. The market remains buoyant in Germany and we'll be seeking to capitalize on growth in fine cut tobacco and improve our cigarette share. Spain remains challenging, but as you see, we're improving our performance across our total tobacco portfolio.</p>
          <p>Outside the EU, we see significant opportunities across our portfolio in value and in premium and above. And we'll build on the excellent results we have delivered through Davidoff, Gauloises Blonde, West and our luxury Cuban cigar portfolio. The U.S.A. remains challenging and highly competitive and our new management team are focused on improving the performance of our core brands through the sales growth drivers, with the benefit of critical mass from the combined cigarette and mass cigar business.</p>
          <p>And finally, in logistics, we'll continue to identify opportunities to grow the business whilst maintaining our cost discipline.</p>
          <p>Thank you. I'd like now to hand back to Alison.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We're generating momentum behind the top line through our strategic brands and total tobacco focus. You've seen that from our second quarter performance. And our priority is to drive sales further through our focus on the four sales growth drivers.</p>
          <p>Our portfolio has never been in better shape. We've been very active across our brands and products and have a number of exciting initiatives in hand that will fuel further growth. One major development involves accelerating Davidoff sales. This will be launched in the second half and represents a key milestone in realizing Davidoff's global potential.</p>
          <p>Our total tobacco portfolio combined with our focus on consumer-led innovation, gives Imperial unique opportunities. As well as driving growth of our key strategic brands, we'll be enhancing our fine cut tobacco performance and maximizing the growth potential of Habanos and our high-performance Snus business. The work we're doing in customer engagement and pricing is integral to our overall sales focus.</p>
          <p>All four drivers need to work together to maximize returns and our people are embedding this approach across the business. It's the people at Imperial and the values they demonstrate that are making the difference, bringing our growth strategy to life on a daily basis throughout the organization. Their talent and their relentless focus on sales, costs and cash management gives me great confidence for the future.</p>
          <p>The external environment is tough in some areas, but we've consistently demonstrated our ability to grow the business in this environment. We're generating good sales and profit momentum and the remainder of the year is all about building on this performance. The combination of our highly energized people and our unique total tobacco portfolio puts us in a strong position to maximize growth and further reward our shareholders. Thank you.</p>
          <p>We'll now take any questions you may have. As usual, the presentation is being recorded, but please wait for a microphone, and give your name and organization before asking your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Erik Bloomquist, Berenberg. Two questions. Firstly, the release in your comments indicated the Q2 might be indicative of the second half. Is that a fair interpretation of that statement and how do you think about the momentum in Q2 maintained into the second half?</p>
          <p>And then second question is with respect to plain packaging in the UK. What do you expect out of the consultation and what kinds of actions do you &#x2013; can you handicap the government is likely to take? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Okay. And the second question to get to plain packaging on price. The first question on Q2 I mean, clearly there is very strong momentum coming through in Q2. Volumes are only down very slightly. In fact, if you allow for the Syria lapping, they're actually up a bit, and 8% increase in revenues and clearly, that momentum we see coming through into the second half as well and that's very much in line with what we're seeing in terms of the overall market views on the numbers for the current year.</p>
          <p>But also we're going to take the opportunity to invest. And if we do see growth coming through ahead of our expectations in terms of the top line, we're quite happy as well to see opportunities to further invest that in the business to drive further growth and into next year as well. So we'll be balancing that equation in terms of the growth momentum we see coming through in the second half.</p>
          <p>On plain packs I thought I'd maybe take the opportunity for our newly-appointed Corporate Affairs Director to comment on that, particularly in relation to the UK consultation and really the business issue that we see that to be currently. Matt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, morning. The easiest way to sort of to think about this is that the consultation only kicked off in the UK two weeks ago. So it's a bit early to be drawing any conclusions. I think we were slightly surprised by the tonality of some of the introductory comments. That's something that we have &#x2013; we've taken up with the government separately. But the reality is that the consultation runs for another three months after which they will reflect on how they want to take the issue forward.</p>
          <p>I think there have been &#x2013; clearly in the meantime, there will be the results coming out of Australia which we expect in some time in the next six months potentially as early as July. That will inevitably, depending on which way it goes, influence some of the contributors to the debate. But then we've also had the EU commissioner come out in the last couple of weeks. I don't know if you've seen some of his comments, but basically saying that whilst packaging is important and is something that regulators need to look at, the EU is not interested in going as far as Australia is.</p>
          <p>So the debate is going to happen for the next few months and it's going to be a prolonged period before we have clarity. And I think the other point just to bear in mind is that whichever way the Australian court case goes, the court case hinges on the constitution of Australia, and as it is going to everywhere else that this debate happens. And so therefore whether we're successful or whether we're unsuccessful in Australia doesn't actually read across to what's going to happen on a wider basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think an important point for me as well, this is quite a significant business issue from a UK perspective, one I'm sure Glen is talking to the press about today as well because it's not really ultimately just about tobacco regulation. It's a wider consumer regulatory point, I think, and one that we're very engaged on. Who should be next? Just start at the end, David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's David Hayes from Nomura. Just firstly on Spain. In the last few days, we've seen some sort of price recessing by PMI and some others just for bringing back L&amp;M, I guess particularly to parity with some of your value brands. I just wondered whether you're comfortable with that parity or whether you think this could potentially be a risk that this kind of &#x2013; we saw last year sort of differentiation of brand positioning starts to become a bit of a theme?</p>
          <p>And then secondly on the UK margins down 180 basis points in the half is that a trend or is there some one-off factors? I know you obviously talked about the shipment phasing. I just wondered whether that's an influence on that and whether that stabilizes here or whether we should have assume that margin in the UK keeps coming off and is offset by other margin performance elsewhere? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I mean, maybe <mark type="ph" /> after Matt will (29:23) briefly comment as well. But I mean, Spain, I think all we're seeing at the moment is some tactical shift around &#x2013; if you look at where the market now is in terms of the span of price points it covers, I think partly if you like, driven by us, there's now a lot more price points in the market. There's a lot more variety, a lot more opportunity to continue within terms of price points. I mentioned the Fortuna brand in my presentation and we now have that in the market, I think, in 24s, in various pack sizes, in various offerings for the consumer.</p>
          <p>So you have got quite a different spectrum of price points in Spain than you would have seen, say two years ago, in the market, and opportunities for the consumer. But I see this as tactical. I don't know if there's anything you'd add <mark type="ph" /> after that (30:00) okay. It is just tactical at this point, I'd say.</p>
          <p>That was Spain, then the other point was in relation to the UK margins. Very much, I see those coming back a bit more strongly in the second half. So yes, there are some factors that impacted it, but some &#x2013; yeah, UK as we've always said is there or thereabouts that level of margin. We'll stick with those comments <mark type="ph" /> when we go (30:22).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I started in 1996.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So yeah, we see a stronger H2 in terms of margins, but we are going to be there or thereabouts in terms of the UK margins. I think I said along to Chris and then we can go &#x2013; keep going down the row to Jon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Chris Wickham from Oriel. In terms of the fine cut shares that you disclosed, and obviously you're losing in the second quarter share in fewer markets than you were across the half as a whole. I was wondering if actually, you could give us a bit more detail on the competitive dynamics in fine cut and whether you're now on a sort of fight back to be able to keep any potential new entrants out of that market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me split fine cut into its two key dynamics. One is in terms of roll-your-own and traditional roll-your-own brands. Yeah, you're very familiar with such as Golden Virginia and Drum and that aspect of the market. And those you know we've had some pressure on some of our shares for a while. We'll be, I think, for the first time in a while we've actually got Golden Virginia now growing in the UK. So even though you see some share pressure because of the growth in the market, we're doing very nicely with that brand in the UK in terms of overall volume growth currently.</p>
          <p>So that's something we continue to address and there's a lot of initiatives in Roberto's area around Drum and Golden Virginia to say what are our other opportunities to move those brands back into stronger share growth. But the dynamic has been very strong for us and very strong for us over the last few years has been Make Your Own, and that's where we've seen significant growth. In fact, we've created segments in areas of Central Europe for Make Your Own as well. So therefore &#x2013; as I said before, when you do create a segment, the only way the share is likely to go unfortunately is down to some degree because you start off with most of it and clearly, it's an attractive segment and there's competition in it.</p>
          <p>And that links back to the point I was making around balancing those share and profit opportunities in a number of those markets. And we have taken some price decisions. But we also have got some very good share momentum. We've got some fantastic growth in Ducados, for example, in News, and in JPS Make Your Own across Europe. So it is a question of getting into the granularity a little bit in some of these segments. And as I said, apart from Poland, where we gained share but the market was significantly down, we did grow our overall volumes 3% in the first half. Jon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jon Leinster, UBS. A couple of questions. On the share repurchase, you said it was going to be &#xA3;500 million going forward, is that a one year statement or is that a medium-term expectation? And secondly, on the U.S. business, I mean that's been sort of marginally disappointing or a bit disappointing, under pressure for a number of years. Does that remain a core business for the Group? Is there any real overlap with the rest of it? Or frankly, is it just turn around and maybe look at the options there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me pick up on the buyback point and I'll give Arthur a two-second warning. But I think it would be useful just to talk around how we see the U.S. business currently shortly, after I've made some introductory comments.</p>
          <p>On the buyback, I think I'm a bit reminded of the auction man who told his wife he loved her and then 50 years later, she said, do you still love me? You've not mentioned it for the last 50 years. And he said, I told you once. If I change my mind, I'll let you know. So buyback is our current statement. It's at &#xA3;500 million and it'll continue at &#xA3;500 million until we tell you otherwise. So that's where we are.</p>
          <p>We are, as we said, consistently, to be slightly more helpful, in a balance sheet rebuild as well still. That's the buyback, we said that we were still going to do a bit of that while doing the &#xA3;500 million buyback. And also clearly, we've got the increase in dividend growth trajectory as well. Don't get carried away, like one of the press did, that 13% was some indication. It's clearly a third of our last year's full-year dividend. As we've indicated, it's formulaic for the first half.</p>
          <p>On the U.S., we've been very transparent about it. It is a difficult market for us. It has been for a while. And I think looking at some of the releases from some of our competition in the market, they're also finding it quite tough currently, too. But we've got a new management team in there. We've got a lot going on keying into the sales growth drivers, and maybe, Arthur, you could just give a bit more flavor to what's happening in that business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, indeed. Results to-date have obviously been not satisfactory, satisfactory at all. What we do is also not a surprise. We do have new management in place. We do believe that the critical mass that we will achieve from combining mass cigars with cigarettes is going to be an advantage for us in the marketplace, as well as in the strategy development going forward.</p>
          <p>And we're working very hard on a number of key things to improve the performance of that business, which we need to give time to actually work, one of which is a state-by-state pricing strategy, which we think is going to give us the right competitive set of our brands versus the competition. We're moving quickly to actually change our strategy from being wholesale-focused to be retail-focused and we have a number of portfolio innovation plans ahead of us, which &#x2013; all three of which are going to help us to actually move that business forward, which is going to give us the time that it needs to actually start getting onto a positive trajectory.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Okay. Next? Next row back now as you work along?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. This is Fulvio Cazzol from Goldman Sachs. I was just wondering on the working capital, I know you highlighted the timing of excise impacting the production in the first half. I was just wondering how much of the increase in working capital is structural i.e. to support new innovation capsules, the new packaging and so forth.</p>
          <p>And secondly, I was wondering if you can give us an update on illicit trading in Spain whether that's moved materially since you last updated us? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll pick up the working capital. Yeah. Indeed. In fact, as we said, basically cash conversion is an important metric for us and it was impacted this year effectively by a working capital swing. To an extent, working capitals are coming from normal levels. If we take a look at last year, the year to March 2011 and I think it's necessary to look at working capital over a 12-month period, because it picks up the business cycle in terms of what's happening. We had a very strong performance in the 12 months to March 2011, which benefited 2011 results. And as working capital has come back to a more normal level in 2012. Effectively, that's adversely affected the first half result.</p>
          <p>If I take a look, and it's probably better looking at the absolute level of working capital. If I take a look at the absolute level of working capital at March 2012, despite the passage of two years, it's at the same level it was in March 2010, so there isn't a massive structural change. There will inevitably be small changes to working capital, the growth agenda. Interestingly enough, it's not so much to do with the innovation and that coming through, I mean, that's generally &#x2013; that comes through with an increase in our capital spend, that we're talking about &#xA3;400 million of CapEx this year to support that. And some people say that it's not really machinery, it's actually off of consumables because a fully loaded make pack complex will pay back itself in terms of the margin it generates over a very short period of time, often in less than a year.</p>
          <p>But, so but the &#x2013; where there will be some, and a minimal working capital movement is obviously as our customers in those countries where we'd offer it through distributors were actually selling more. Maybe their credit limits go up a little, but it's not significant in the scheme of things. And we do expect the &#x2013; currently expect the first half working capital to unwind, as it has done in previous years, by the year-end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And some of the illicit trade in Spain, I mean, there's always still hard numbers to get your head around. But we're still very much at the sort of the high single digit level in terms of penetration of the Spanish market. Clearly, that's a lot higher in Southern parts of Spain. So this is a key aspect for us still in our discussions and debates with government.</p>
          <p>As part of that pricing sales growth driver, excise strategy is really important within that. And clearly, in the excise, similar like Spain, particularly, the impacts that can have on illicit trade is really key. So even though we've had a price increase recently with excise, actually, the bottom of the market hasn't moved up too much, which I think is quite helpful from a consumer perspective and the range of prices offered to consumers in the market. And clearly also, the fine-cut aspect, too.</p>
          <p>Who's going next, going on the row? Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Hi, good morning. James Bushnell from Exane BNP Paribas. Two questions, please. Firstly, just going back on the question on sales growth. You mentioned if the full-year sales growth was above your expectations, you may choose to reinvest. Would you be able to tell us what your full-year expectations are? And question two, on Australia, taking the hypothesis that plain packaging happens in December, do you think that's likely to change the profit growth trajectory in that market? And if so, how? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in terms of the first point, clearly, we've given the rules and everything else. We don't give out explicit numbers in terms of forecasts. Clearly, if we're uncomfortable with where the market's sitting, we need to say something. So that's the answer to your first question.</p>
          <p>Second question is in relation to plain packs. I mean, clearly, that's into our next financial year in Australia because it's some &#x2013; it's 1st December, if it happens and we're end of September year-end. And as I've said to everyone, since this happened, we have a plan B clearly for that environment. We're not very open or explicit about it, because we think we've got some great ideas. So from a competition perspective, we're not going into details.</p>
          <p>But needless to say, I think there's some good examples of what we have done in the Australian market over recent years in already a highly regulated environment. So we've got a display ban there in all the states currently. It's already very high regulation and look at our Australia growth trajectory. You saw it on the customer engagement slide. We've focused on the customer engagement aspects very heavily. We've focused on getting the portfolio right and you can see some great growth from JPS particularly in the Australian market, but also across the total tobacco portfolio.</p>
          <p>We've got innovation opportunities, and clearly, we've played the price sales growth driver as well in that market. And it's come together very well for us and resulted in the share growth you've seen. So we have a lot of confidence going into that environment around how we manage in that environment and we've got some great ideas. So, no, there's no real expectation changes as such yet. Clearly, though, it's brand new, so we'll have to be very vigilant and see how things develop and be agile in responding, depending on what happens in that market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Pass it down. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I sure like this format.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Dirk Van Vlaanderen from Jefferies. Given the step-up in innovation rates that we've been seeing, is that level of CapEx something we should be thinking about longer term as well or is this here a bit of an exceptional?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It depends on the innovation I suppose. When you look at GlideTec and you can see with our first moving pictures ever in our half year presentation, the nature of that innovation is more capital intensive. So, we've had to start it off on much slower, or smaller, old HLP1 machines. We're now looking to move that onto high speed machines. The opportunity we see is significant. We need the capacity. So that's going to have an impact.</p>
          <p>But not all innovations are like that. So, some of the innovations being more format-based and more blend-based, those areas clearly don't need investment in that sort of way. So I think it's going to depend on the sort of innovation we're doing and we'll keep you up to speed and up to date with our views on how we think the capital will develop off the back of that. I mean, as Bob alluded, the capital spend on some of this sort of key is not long in terms of payback period. If you've got the right innovation which, as I've indicated before, we're very keen on making sure we get that correct consumer insight. So we're back in the right horses in this area and not just taking upon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> Green, (43:11) your last question, I suppose? Pass it down to Adam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Adam Spielman here from Citi. Can I ask one sort of numeric question? I want to follow up to your answer in Australia. The numeric question is quite simple. Are you able to say in the UK what the impact was in terms of volumes, sales and profit of the trade loading, unloading issue we saw so we can try and back that out?</p>
          <p>The non-numeric question, you've said a couple of times focus very much on retail engagement, can you say exactly what you're doing? Because I had had assumed in Australia that you're gaining share simple because you had lower prices on JPS. But clearly, you're saying it's more than that. So how are you engaging with the retailers? How was it different from what BAT is doing, because they always talk about their direct store delivery being an advantage and it doesn't seem to be. And then also, you're talking about price, everywhere across your market, you've got increased pricing complexity. The whole structure of pricing is harder now. How is that an advantage, what's it do to the market? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. <mark type="ph" /> We'll mop up (44:21) in Australia to give you &#x2013; get more granularity there and I've totally forgotten the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll pick up the numeric question, shall I? If you're talking about the impact of the price increase moving in the UK, Adam, it's basically order of magnitude high-teens in terms of the profit impact. And if I'd have to pick a number, &#xA3;0.5 billion, just over &#xA3;0.5 billion in terms of volume impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the underlying performance in the UK is probably flatter in terms of volume, but still mid-to-high single digit revenue growth effectively coming through, translating into stories and mid-single digit profit growth. So it's this sort of dynamic you would expect from the UK if you strip it out. I also think if you strip out that effect, but also, we've got effect in the U.S. in all those various aspects in terms of first half net-net, you get next to no impact at all in the overall headline numbers of 3%, 3.3% revenue and on profit growth, if you allow for all those various factors going in and out.</p>
          <p>In terms of Australia, if you want a bit more granularity, I'll let Arthur maybe speak for a few minutes in terms of exactly what we're doing there around the customer engagement and the pricing aspects. But it's not purely &#x2013; I mean, is it the best in market? JPS is not on its own at the price point it is in the market actual. In fact, to be honest, in our segment was led by peer long before we got involved in it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It was a question more general than Australia. What does retail engagement mean for you in practical terms, in hard terms?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (46:02).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're recording though, so it's probably better if you take the mic Arthur.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Customer engagements &#x2013; let me answer the question on Australia and then take it broader, if that's okay. The &#x2013; in Australia, what we're doing is very clearly all of the drivers being at play very consistently over the years and having stepped that up even in more recent times. So very clearly, if you look at the portfolio, having been able to stabilize and even have slight growth on the Horizon brand, and on top of that, build the JPS brands, has really enabled us to become the number one in value for money. That's what &#x2013; very clearly what we're focused on in Australia.</p>
          <p>Then on top of that, we're making very good inroads with Peter Stuyvesant or Stuyvoes as it's called in Australia, and they're doing very well at the premium end of the segment as well. But very, very clearly focused on value for money. And over time, that portfolio has really solidified the brand equity with consumers, which is a very, very solid foundation. Now on top of that, the pricing lever is being played. It is BPPC, which we've talked about on several occasions, brand pack price per channel is something that is an art and a wisdom that Australia plays to perfection, with a number of different pack sizes at different price points being made available not everywhere in the same way, but really state-by-state, channel-by-channel, customer-by-customer.</p>
          <p>And in terms of customer engagement specifically, very clearly, we have a DSD system in Australia that works very, very well with our distributor, with our call center. And we're very focused specifically of independence in driving on-shelf availability for the flip side to out-of-stocks, as well as actually efficacy, and now being able to, on a month-by-month basis, being able to track and to monitor, to measure, therefore, the efficacy of retailers of our brands is helping us to improve the key areas for doing even better going forward.</p>
          <p>Already, we know that from an efficacy point of view, from a top supplier point of view, we outstrip all other manufacturers of tobacco in Australia and we have one or two to go in total FMCG. So we really look at all FMCG and preferred supplier opportunities in the Australian market. And that is what the agenda is actually to do also in terms of customer engagement, not only in Australia, but also in other markets and looking for ways to actually make that happen also and focused at the moment on the UK, on the U.S. and more recently, also for looking for opportunities like that in the French market.</p>
          <p>So it's on-shelf availability and efficacy, in particular, to your question that we're looking to drive in a number of different markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we talked significantly about consumer insights. We're doing an awful lot of work on customer and shopper insights as well to drive that. So it's very, very detailed around what aspects you need to get right to ensure that availability in particular in individual outlets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (49:28).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What's the advantage? It's a consumer-focused approach to give consumers what they want and particularly when you look at the EU markets, and okay, let's include and Australia, because those mature markets have sort of got more of a value-seeking trend in them as the prime trend, giving them opportunities across different price points in order to keep them within your brand franchise effectively. So yes, it does add a degree of complexity, but clearly, our challenge always, I've talked about before, is to make sure we manage out the bad complexity. We're happy with what we call good complexity where we need to manage it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're keeping on going. Come &#x2013; now, Jon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Jon Fell at Deutsche Bank. A couple of things. First of all, just general numbers, one on operational leverage. In the first half, we had tobacco revenue growth up about the same amount as profit. Is that lack of operational leverage down to what you might call voluntary increases in cost, like increase in the marketing spend, innovation spend? Or to what extent is that driven by involuntary factors?</p>
          <p>And then second question is on the UK. You said you're stepping up the visit frequency to UK outlets and trying to help them more with working capital. Could expand on that? Are you actually delivering more product to outlets physically now? And more generally, given where prices are now, how much of an issue is availability becoming? Certainly when I visit my local corner shop, sometimes the shelves seem a bit more sparsely stocked than they once were. How do you deal with that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let's pick up on that working capital one. I mean, the UK market because of the costs of the product, one of our fairly obvious findings, I suppose, is the fact that you do need to more frequently be restocking retailers, and therefore, that's the point for them, is that they can manage down their working capital a bit, we will therefore increase our frequency of core coverage in those outlets, so it's a very simple and very practical point for them.</p>
          <p>But you're right I think because of the high cost of the product now, we identify quite early on more of a global stat, that there was actually a much higher level of out-of-stocks at shelf. It's obviously in the shop, but it's not on the shelf than I think the industry stats have indicated historically. So that's why we focus on availability and advocacy because that availability point, there are huge wins against in a lot of markets. And yes, as I think Arthur highlighted at the Investor Day, however long ago it was, 18 months ago, the reality is that consumers quite often don't switch. If their brand is not available, they walk out of the store. And that's not what we want in terms of our brand portfolio.</p>
          <p>So then we've got some significant opportunities there, and that's all work done in the UK, but it is. It's nuts and bolts, nits and grits stuff. It's not waving your magic wand and getting it right, it's actually just getting the focus. And it's a horrible phrase, isn't it, about retail being detail, but it is really just that ongoing grind and making sure we get that, that availability right in outlets, and build those relationships. I mean that's why I think in Australia, the support of the call center has been quite effective as well to help build that.</p>
          <p>In terms of the investment question or the cost base and how that's moving versus the top line, I mean, yes, we are investing more. We're investing more in terms of A&amp;P, although that's grown probably broadly in line with revenue growth in the first half, but we're investing in things like non-tobacco materials in different formats. We've got new machineries. And also, you get clearly, the mix of markets that we're selling impacting that as well. So there is an investment agenda. But you can't see it transparently through one particular line, but that is clearly coming through in terms of the overall profile of the P&amp;L in the first half and also clearly some of the things that we experienced in Q1 impacted that, too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, actually to build on that point, if the comment was, are we going to see operating profit and revenue just grow in the same proportion, the answer is no. There've been impacts. There's a significant impact, in fact, both &#x2013; market mix is a significant impact if you're trying to dissect it into any one period. So it's &#x2013; the operating leverage of the business hasn't changed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now to you, Martin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Martin Deboo at Investec. A question on Make Your Own and a question on the UK plain packaging. Make Your Own looks poised to take off. But my concern, though, is does that have any dilutive effect on your margin mix? I mean, Bob, you said in Runnymede that fine cut was actually accretive to gross margin. But what does that look like for MYO? The thought that's going in my head is it does have potential to drive some complexity into your business. So comments on that would be helpful.</p>
          <p>On UK plain packaging, just to return to, I guess my question is, to what extent is this high noon? Do you carry on down this sort of polite, patient evidence-based approach or you're now seeking to change the terms of debate? It may be difficult to talk about at this point, but I think that has to be the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. In terms of Make Your Own, we were trying to give you a global perspective on fine cut previously, but clearly this is very market dependent in terms of its profitability and it also depends in its stage of maturity as well in market. So for example, in Central Europe a few years ago, our margin on Make Your Own was quite low when we were establishing the category. And then we've increased prices and therefore, those margins are built quite nicely in those markets now and are contributing significantly to a market like Poland, despite the market size reduction.</p>
          <p>If you look at other markets, then it's inherently highly profitable to begin with, such as when we've launched Make Your Own in the UK, given the excise structures and the margin structures here. So it does depend on a market-by-market basis. And the comment I was making around fine cut and Make Your Own in the presentation is that we will continue to balance that and take leadership of that in terms of our portfolio and how we look at the volume opportunities versus the margin and the profit opportunities.</p>
          <p>And I think so far, if I looked at Spain as well and what we've done with Ducados, we've achieved a similar result there in terms of getting the category established. And now we're moving margins up in that category as well. So that does depend on the market and particularly the structure in the market. On UK plain packs, I think Matt wants to make a further comment on that, but I think it's a pertinent question, Martin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as I said before, I mean, the consultation is only two weeks in. So it's probably a bit early to be making a call in terms of how it's going to pan out. The reality is the concession runs until the middle of July. Then, there will be three or four months or even longer while the government reflects and decides what to do. So we're a long way off the government actually deciding whether it's going to legislate in this area or not.</p>
          <p>Without going back through all of the strong logical arguments that we have, we are very hopeful that the UK government will run a genuine consultation where it listens to the genuine debates, listens to the genuine potential unintended consequences of going down the route that is currently being considered. And I think our approach will be influenced by how genuine that consultation both is and appears to be.</p>
          <p>So it's a bit too early currently to make a call for this. But the first &#x2013; the announcements of the consultation was and the tonality around it was &#x2013; did raise concerns. And as I said, that's something that we have raised with the government and we'll see how that develops. But is &#x2013; we're very much working towards this being a three-month consultation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You want to speak up, Roger?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Rogerio Fujimori, Credit Suisse. I was just wondering if you could quickly update us on Russia and the factors behind the sequential share trends in Q2? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I have to mention first of all that clearly, we've had the Balkan Star headache for a while in Russia, having made the decision to improve the profitability of the brand and accept some of the volume losses. And clearly, that's ameliorating, but that's only one factor. The other factors are in relation to some of the growth in West, some good growth in Style. So from a mix perspective as well, it's very much more at the higher priced end of the portfolio, so that's good from a gross margin perspective. And also, we're continuing to invest in that market as well. So overall, you can see some pressures on Eastern Europe because of the Ukraine situation which we flagged at the first quarter. But volumes in Russia were up 5% in the first half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How did Davidoff perform?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Davidoff is doing &#x2013; is performing reasonably. I think we are looking at ways to boost that yet further. We've put some different formats into Russia, so I think we can do more. So to say I'm overjoyed with how it's doing would be wrong, but it's doing okay. I think can do a lot more with it.</p>
          <p>Chas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Chas, thanks. Chas Manso from SocGen. Two questions. Firstly, could you give us an idea what's happening to sort of smoker dynamics across the EU in terms of segment growth, in terms of how you see the value segment growing versus the premium segment growing across the EU?</p>
          <p>And the second question, picking up on the margin question earlier on, and the answer being that operational leverage hasn't changed. Could you sort of put that in context with your innovation drive? Is it that you're saying that your innovation drive won't affect the operational leverage of the company or maybe there's an <mark type="ph" /> escrow (59:57) of where it's initially a headwind, but afterwards, it becomes a tailwind? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me just pick up briefly on the guidance. So I think from an EU perspective, we've been seeing the value dynamics for a very long time. There's nothing new about value dynamics in the EU. And that's very much where we're seeking to play the total tobacco portfolio, as we have done both with our cigarette portfolio and with fine cut.</p>
          <p>I think, though, if I just change the bias very slightly, what we're looking to do with our sales growth drivers as well and with some of our innovation agenda, is to also give consumers the reason to maybe to stay in a slightly higher price point as well. So I wouldn't call it up-trading, but I would call it people having a bit more of a reason to stick where they are, rather than seeking a lower price brand, seeing more value, if you like, in the price point that they're already in. And that's what we're successfully delivering with GlideTec currently, with L&amp;B in the UK.</p>
          <p>I was reflecting, actually, on putting this presentation together, I don't think L&amp;B has seen so much activity in the UK since it was launched. And we've got some significant initiatives around GlideTec, around Fresh Burst, and around the queen-size variants as well coming into the market, which is one &#x2013; somebody else wanted to know, it actually has nothing to do with the Diamond Jubilee, that we're launching a queen-sized version. It's actually called profile in the market.</p>
          <p>So all of those activities are clearly also benefiting the mix in somewhere like the UK as well. So the value dynamic, though, is here to stay and that's what we've been playing. But it's truly that value and it's making sure that you are giving the consumers a value at the price point that they're willing to purchase at. So, that's the value dynamic. And then the operational leverage, do you want to comment further, Bob? I mean...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think, Alison, you've picked up most of the point. It depends what innovation is being deployed where. some of them are &#x2013; you could imagine that something like GlideTec, whilst we're using it and if you a look at &#x2013; yes, it does cost more than the normal L&amp;B pack. But if it's stopping downtrading, then you could take what we are selling and apply a multiple to that, a significant multiple to the additional cost in terms of the loss of margin that we're not suffering as a result. So therefore, I don't think it always plays on to the &#x2013;  it's not a straight one for one onto that.</p>
          <p>And secondly, in other markets, you can potentially imagine something that has that characteristics being on a premium product. But in those markets, people are asked to pay an additional premium for. So I don't think it's significantly going to change the operating leverage of the business at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our innovation, we've been clear. It's focused on doing a few things well and it's focused on margin-accretive innovation. And what we're saying around the second half is if we see what we're looking at, some very good momentum in the second quarter coming through into the second half, then as we deliver those sales and maybe we'll look at some opportunities to reinvest some of that into the business.</p>
          <p>So I'm not sure whether that's your headwind or tailwind. I'm not sure about the specifics. But we're not looking to invest significantly ahead of the curve, I suppose, in that sense. David, we're probably going to have to close the call soon because I think Bambi is starting in about half an hour, for those of you who want to avoid the rain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a very quick follow-up. Just on L&amp;B in the UK, you have got the share of L&amp;B this last quarter and the quarter this time last year. Have you got information just on what that share has done, just trying to get a feel for some of the things you've talked about? The second thing about Davidoff, you've kind of said a few times that there's very exciting things coming in the second half of Davidoff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't know how much more you can go into &#x2013; no, I guess &#x2013; or maybe just the performance of Davidoff, 5% growth last quarter. If it's not double that, would you be disappointed, because it's so exciting in terms of those mischief? And then lastly, just on cost savings, I think it was the last element of the advertised integration with the German plant closure. I'm looking, if that's wrong. But did that happen potentially and therefore, is that the element of cost savings now finished and how much was it in the last half in terms of that last element of cost saving? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Maybe for the L&amp;B briefly, then maybe a quick one on cost. I mean, we are talking fairly marginal, I don't think we've got it to hand, otherwise, Gerry can update you on it afterwords, David. And then I think we'll finish on Davidoff, unless you got any more burning questions today and I'll let &#x2013; we'll let Roberto give you an insight, but not tell you what we're doing with Davidoff.</p>
          <p>But the basis on which we're driving it forward, and some of the insights you might remember, some of the needs-based work that we've done as well around that to finish off. So with L&amp;B, I showed the slide, the CAGE conference actually, which you can probably take off the website if you want to, it shows the L&amp;B share flattening, which is, you might think, well, flattening isn't growth. But honestly, believe me, L&amp;B share flattening is a great win. It's a high margin product and we're very pleased with that. So we do see opportunities though to also turn that around and get that growing, just if you'll appreciate we only put the full range into &#x2013; so the menthol and the gold as well into GlideTec at the back end of the calendar. So it's still in build mode really in terms of the market. But we're very pleased with how that's been developing.</p>
          <p>On cost, Bob? Can we just...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you called them synergy. But I think &#x2013; firstly, they are a very small number. If I had to choose a number, you're talking about high single digit millions potentially. However &#x2013; and the however is, these offerings were effectively negotiated back in 2007. There's no labor plans that would cross-border European plans. And therefore, we knew that we would be making those savings and therefore, taking that mentality into what we're doing across the group as a whole. You don't have to negotiate that, so you're doing other things. And effectively, what we did is that you could have said we could have moved on or might have moved on a bit earlier than our normal business. But we didn't, because we've got it there. We're doing other things. I'd say it's just caught in the cut and thrust and the numbers involved with cut and thrust of what happens in a normal year in our ongoing business. So, it's not something that's impacted the results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A final comment on Davidoff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Davidoff. Davidoff is our high quality asset that we have and has been demonstrating, over the years and recently, outstanding performance momentum, but also, brand health indicators are extremely healthy with Davidoff. So what we are looking at through consumer needs and looking at how can we accelerate growth, look at more occasions where consumers can reach Davidoff. That is the strategy that we're going to put in place and accelerate in the second half.</p>
          <p>In our consumer needs, if you recall from the Investor Day, we have looked at brands to activate more consumers in more occasions, and Davidoff is one of the key assets we have that has the opportunity to affect multiples of more occasions than we are doing today. And that is the structure that we're going to start implementing with Davidoff in the second half. So it's a high quality asset, has full footprint, so whatever we're doing with Davidoff, we can scale across the full of our footprint. It is top end of our margins back to operational leverage, it is a key component to us. So we believe we can concentrate and focus and make Davidoff, over time, one of our highest-return assets we have in the business. So that's broadly where we are going to, without going through the specifics of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And I have big ambitions for the volume growth. But I'm not going to tell you what those are. So, all right then, we'll draw it to a close at this point. Thank you very much for your questions. And yeah, go enjoy the rain now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>