<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1349294" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-11-02</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1430</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Iain J. G. Napier, Co-Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Alison J. Cooper, Chief Executive and Operating Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Robert Dyrbus, Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">David Hayes</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Chas Manso</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Jon Fell</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Iain Napier</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. To those of you here in the room and everyone watching via our webcast, welcome to our 2010 Preliminary Results Presentation.</p>
          <p>I'm Iain Napier, Chairman of Imperial, and I'm here today with Alison Cooper, our Chief Executive and Bob Dyrbus, our Finance Director, and as always, we have various Imperial senior management team members with us.</p>
          <p>Our strong results in 2010 demonstrate the success of our strategy. Tobacco net revenues were up 3% to &#xA3;7.1 billion, benefiting from strategic cigarette brands, excellent fine cut tobacco volumes and strong pricing. Good revenue growth supported by ongoing cost optimization resulted in adjusted operating profits growing by 5% to &#xA3;3.1 billion. We delivered 11% growth on adjusted earnings per share to 178.8 pence, a strong performance in what remains a challenging environment in a number of our key markets.</p>
          <p>Our focus on cash generation has resulted in further excellent progress in reducing our level of adjusted net debt, which fell by &#xA3;1.5 billion to &#xA3;9.3 billion. The board is proposing a final dividend of 0.60 pence per share, bringing the total for the year to 84.3 pence per share, which is a 15% increase.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, I believe we are in a strong position. Central to everything we do is our priority of creating sustainable value for our shareholders. The combination of our people, our brands, our market footprint and our unique total tobacco approach offers us many opportunities to build long- term sustainable growth across the business.</p>
          <p>I now hand you over to Alison, who'll take you through some more detail.</p>
          <p>Alison?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Iain, and good morning. This has been a significant year of evolution for Imperial, one in which we've shifted our strategic focus. At the heart of our strategy is our sales-led agenda complemented by our focus on cost optimization and cash utilization to drive sustainable shareholder returns. Our strategy is delivering strong results, and there's positive momentum in the business.</p>
          <p>So let me start by looking at some of our key achievements this year. Our global strategic cigarette brands, Davidoff, West and Gauloises Blondes, have benefited from recent rejuvenations ensuring they remain dynamic and appealing to consumers.</p>
          <p>These brands now represent 22% of all our cigarette volumes and are a growing part of our business. We grew Davidoff volumes by 3% and West volumes by 2% with both brands performing strongly in Eastern Europe, and Gauloises Blondes volumes recovered in the second half, growing 4%.</p>
          <p>Our key regional brand, JPS, had another excellent year growing 13% in the high-margin markets of Western Europe and Australasia, and we grew our total fine cut tobacco volumes by 8.7% on a white stick equivalent basis with a strong performance in Central Europe particularly in make-your-own.</p>
          <p>Turning to revenues, we grew our net revenues in the mature markets of the U.K., Germany and the rest of the EU, again highlighting our ability to deliver top-line growth and margin performance in mature markets. We also grew net revenues in a Rest of the World region, with particular strength in the emerging markets of Eastern Europe where the spread of our portfolio enabled net revenues to grow 7% despite some volume weakness. Cash conversion was very strong at 97%, resulting in closing adjusted net debt of &#xA3;9.3 billion, &#xA3;1.5 billion lower than last year.</p>
          <p>Let's look at some of our brand performances in more detail, starting with Davidoff. Positioned in the super premium segment, we've grown Davidoff's volume consistently, and in Eastern Europe, which accounts for around 1/5 of the brand's volumes, volumes have grown 20% compound since 2006.</p>
          <p>This strong performance reflects the alignment of our portfolio with changing consumer trends, particularly in respect of slims and superslims, which now account for 27% of Davidoff volumes. And Davidoff's success is not limited to Eastern Europe. We've achieved a total compound growth rate of 6% over the past four years, and following its successful rejuvenation we're excited about the brand's ongoing growth potential.</p>
          <p>Gauloises Blondes is our biggest selling brand. Whilst volumes were impacted by temporary supply disruption in the first half, second half volumes grew 4%, reinforcing the strength of the brand's potential, particularly in Africa and the Middle East. We've added a 1-milligram variant to the Gauloises portfolio, which has been introduced into Central Europe, and it's being extended into a number of Middle Eastern markets to capitalize on this growing segment.</p>
          <p>West is our leading international value brand, and the rejuvenation program continues to be rolled out across our business. We can already see the newly modernized brand franchise delivering results. We achieved total brand volume growth of 2% in the year, and if you exclude Germany the growth rises to 6% driven by the success of new innovative brand variants, particularly in Central and Eastern Europe as well as in Taiwan and Turkey.</p>
          <p>JPS has delivered another outstanding performance this year, with the U.K., Germany, Australia, Portugal and New Zealand all contributing. Since 2006, the brand's cigarette volumes have grown at a compound rate of 12%, whilst in Germany, where 44% of the brand's volumes are sold, compound annual growth of 21% has been achieved since 2006. It's a great success story of a quality brand at an affordable price.</p>
          <p>We're the world number one in fine cut tobacco and have grown our overall volumes by 4% compound since the loss of singles in Germany in 2007. Staying with Germany, this year we grew our German fine cut tobacco volumes by 6% whilst our growth in the rest of EU region was 19%.</p>
          <p>And it's not just our leading cigarette and fine cut tobacco brands that are performing strongly. Habanos brands are, without question, the world's leading luxury cigar portfolio. Sold in more than 120 countries, our Cuban cigar sales, partly helped by favorable comparatives, grew by 10%, a pleasing performance given the economic climate.</p>
          <p>And we've grown combined volumes of our snus brands, Skruf and Knox, by 24%, a great performance on which we'll build and capitalize on further opportunities when our new factory comes online next February.</p>
          <p>We made good operational progress in 2010, leveraging our brand and product portfolio across our geographic footprint. This resulted in Tobacco net revenues rising by 3% despite significant headwinds in the U.S. and in Spain, with price increases and improving market shares in cigarette and fine cut tobacco in a number of key markets.</p>
          <p>Our white stick equivalent volumes grew in most of the higher-margin markets in the European Union, with growth in the U.K., as well as in Germany and the rest of the EU, reflecting broadly stable cigarette and rise in fine cut tobacco volumes. Group white stick volumes were down 2.9%.</p>
          <p>Cigarette volumes were down 4.2% of which 1.4% could be attributed to one very low margin brand in Russia, Balkan Star, where despite lower volumes, brand profitability has risen.</p>
          <p>A further 2.1% can be attributed to two markets, Spain and the U.S. In Spain, cigarette market volumes have fallen significantly as a result of a difficult macro environment. And in the USA, large duty increases last year had a particularly marked impact on our first half. As I previously mentioned, our fine cut tobacco volumes were up 8.7% on a white stick improvement basis.</p>
          <p>Before talking about our operating performance in our different regions, let me give you an overview of the trends we're seeing in our mature Western European markets.</p>
          <p>We estimate white stick volumes have declined 2% per annum since 2006, with cigarette volumes declining 2% per annum and fine cut volumes generally in growth, increasing 1% compound since 2006 or 5% since 2007 off the loss of singles in Germany.</p>
          <p>With rising tobacco duties and high levels of unemployment in some markets, down trading within cigarettes and into other tobacco products is ongoing as consumers seek value. Around 50% of our cigarette volumes are in value brands, and with our portfolio across cigarette and fine cut tobacco, we continue to be well positioned to benefit from this trend.</p>
          <p>Unfortunately, a growing source of cheap products is in the form of illicit trade, whether smuggled or counterfeit, and as announced in September, we've signed an agreement with the European Commission and the EU member states to tackle illicit trade. This is an important alignment of resources, addressing an issue that benefits no one but the criminals involved, adversely affecting governments, consumers, retailers and the legitimate tobacco industry.</p>
          <p>Let me now move on to look at how we performed in our mature European markets, starting with the U.K. I'm very pleased with the results from our U.K. business, which has delivered another strong year with top-line growth and improved margins. We've improved revenue and profits and grew our cigarette share to 45.4%.</p>
          <p>U.K. consumers are continuing to seek value, and we've responded by leveraging the strength of our key value brands, JPS Silver and Windsor Blue. Both brands gained share during the year and together they now account for around 47 &#x2013; 41% of the growing economy sector.</p>
          <p>In fine cut tobacco, Golden Virginia Yellow and Gold Leaf continued to grow, with strong volume gains in the year. And overall, a good performance in the U.K. We have a diverse portfolio and remain focused on balancing our market share targets with sustainable profit growth.</p>
          <p>We take a similar approach in Germany, where our overall cigarette share was just under 27%, and both revenue and margins were up. A number of consumer focused initiatives, including new variants and soft packs, have driven JPS's September spot share up to just under 10%. And from 1st of April this year, Gauloises Blondes was incorporated into our distribution network, and we've since extended its coverage, leading to an improvement in brand share against the first half. Our total fine cut tobacco share rose to 18.2%, with both JPS and Route 66 growing strongly to a combined share of over 11%.</p>
          <p>In Spain, we focused on maintaining profitability by leveraging our market leadership position and our total tobacco portfolio. Whilst our domestic blonde share has been impacted by decline in Fortuna, we have been active in addressing this, and just last week we launched Fortuna Red Line as a brand extension. Nobel produced a resilient performance, and Ducados Rubio increased its share.</p>
          <p>In June, we extended the Ducados Rubio brand franchise with the launch of the first expanded "make your own" product in the market, which has since captured the September spot share of 5.8% of the fine cut tobacco segment. In Cigar, Coburn continued to benefit from the move to smaller formats, growing its market share to 11.7%.</p>
          <p>In our Rest of European Union Region, we delivered strong growth in a number of markets. In France, our domestic blonde share was 23.6% with News, JPS and Fortuna all performing well.</p>
          <p>And in Greece, against a background of excise increases, our share was up, with Davidoff performing particularly well in maintaining its share. Elsewhere, we grew cigarette share in Austria, Czech Republic, Hungary and Portugal with good performances from a number of regional and local brands such as JPS, Route 66 and Golden Gate.</p>
          <p>And regional fine cut tobacco market volumes were up 5%, and we made share gains in all the Central European markets in which we operate, with particularly strong performances in Poland, Czech Republic and Hungary.</p>
          <p>Our primary focus in the Americas is the USA where we estimated the overall cigarette market declined by 7% in the year. The USA remains competitive, and we're pleased that we have been able to broadly maintain our cigarette share in the second half of the year at 3.9% with an improving trend in recent weeks.</p>
          <p>We remain well positioned, with our brand portfolio predominantly in the discount sector, and I'm confident that we will benefit from consumer's ongoing search for value. We're in the process of rejuvenating the majority of our domestic brands, the most important of which are our two main discount brands, USA Gold and Sonoma, and are continuing to extend their distribution.</p>
          <p>And in Cigar, we continue to grow our sales with the benefit of good pricing. The mass market segment is growing strongly in the year with consumers continuing to migrate to cigarillos where we are growing volumes with our natural wrapper brand, Dutch Masters.</p>
          <p>In the homogenized wrapper segment, Phillies cigarillos have grown share following a number of promotional and packaging initiatives. As in our premium handmade cigar business, we outperformed the market with our luxury brands, Montecristo and Romeo y Julieta, gaining share.</p>
          <p>Before I talk about our performance in the Rest of World region, I would like to discuss the trends we're seeing in some of our emerging markets. In Africa and the Middle East, volumes in our main market, Morocco, were up 2% with a majority of other markets stable or growing.</p>
          <p>In Eastern Europe, many countries have been impacted by economic downturn with unemployment rising. In addition, there've been significant increases in tobacco duties, resulting in cigarette market volume declines in some markets, with both Russia and Ukraine declining by 10%. However, pricing's been positive throughout the region resulting in strong revenue growth.</p>
          <p>In Asia some markets have declined, particularly in those countries where tobacco duties have increased, but profitability is improved with the benefit of pricing.</p>
          <p>Turning to our performance in the Rest of World region, we had a good year in Africa increasing our share in a number of markets. Fine and Excellence continue to build on their positive growth trends with good volume gains of 11% and 6% respectively.</p>
          <p>In Morocco, we've redeveloped our route to market and maintained our momentum by leveraging our local and international brand portfolio placing us in an excellent position ahead of the monopoly ending in December.</p>
          <p>And our Middle East region, we again grew our total share across the region and in a number of markets, notably in Saudi Arabia with Davidoff and in Turkey with West.</p>
          <p>In Eastern Europe, we launched rejuvenated Davidoff and West packs throughout the region and launched superslims and kingsize superslims format of these brands in a number of markets, resulting in regional volumes of these brands up 20% and 3% respectively.</p>
          <p>In Russia, although our market share declined as a result of reduced volumes of Balkan Star, we delivered positive volume performances from our key brands, Davidoff, Style and Maxim.</p>
          <p>In Ukraine, Davidoff showed strong growth, increasing its share to 1.2%, and we increased our total market share to 20.8%.</p>
          <p>Elsewhere in the region, we grew our share in Azerbaijan to over 44% driven by Davidoff, West and Classic, and also grew our share in Serbia, Kyrgyzstan and Macedonia.</p>
          <p>In Asia-Pacific, we've delivered an excellent performance with market share, volume and profit growth in most markets. In Australia, we grew our cigarette share to 17.5%, driven by the ongoing success of JPS.</p>
          <p>In Asia, we improved our share to 11% in Taiwan with our expanded portfolio and changes in our route to market resulting in gains across our brands, including Davidoff and West. And we also increased our share in Laos and Cambodia.</p>
          <p>Following our agreement with KT&amp;G earlier in the year, Davidoff kingsize was launched in South Korea in May. It's selling in almost all of the country's 12,000 convenient stores, the key outlets for international brands, and by September we already had an estimated spot share of 0.4% in this channel.</p>
          <p>And finally our Logistics business, which has performed robustly with operating profit remaining stable in spite of the current economic conditions. Despite tobacco market volume declines in Spain, tobacco distribution's remained resilient, offsetting lower volumes with price increases and cost savings.</p>
          <p>France also performed well with market volumes broadly stable, and in Italy our results benefited from price increases.</p>
          <p>In other Logistics, our focus continues to be on maintaining our profitability through improving revenues and managing costs. We've continued to gain share in French wholesale distribution. We've grown revenues by almost 20% in our pharma division and maintained sales in our transport activities despite the difficult operating environment.</p>
          <p>And during the year, we entered into a joint venture to provide a range of services to ONCE for their Spanish lottery operations. This is a great opportunity to expand into a new area. We've made an upfront investment and commenced operations in the second half.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the regional outlook. In the majority of the mature markets of the European Union, we expect cigarette volume trends to continue their normal long-term rate with moderate declines, being partly offset by further growth in fine cut tobacco.</p>
          <p>Market conditions are likely to remain challenging in Spain in 2011. However, we have a number of portfolio initiatives in the pipeline which, combined with recent management changes and our enhanced sales focus, leave us well-0placed to further develop our business in this important market.</p>
          <p>We expect profitability to increase across our mature markets. We have the scope to raise prices, and we'll maintain our focus on cost optimization. Our focus on global, strategic, regional and local brands will continue, and our strength in value products means we are well-placed to benefit from the consumers' ongoing search for value in these markets.</p>
          <p>In the USA, we'll continue to focus on expanding our distribution and building our position in the value segment. Through continued brand rejuvenations, market volumes revert to the long-term trend.</p>
          <p>In Africa and Middle East, we expect the long-term favorable trends to continue, and we'll seek to capitalize on our successes in Morocco, Sub-Saharan Africa, the Middle East and Turkey.</p>
          <p>And while we expect volume declines to continue in Eastern Europe over the short term, we expect to improve our profitability through pricing and mix building on the success of Davidoff and West, while continuing to develop our regional and local brands.</p>
          <p>In our Asia-Pacific region, our portfolio's strength leaves us well-placed to build on the successes of 2010 across the region, including in our two key markets of Australia and Taiwan where there's good momentum.</p>
          <p>In Logistics, we'll further consolidate our market-leading positions and focus on our core profitable activities with an ongoing emphasis on cost saving initiatives. Driving our sales growth agenda is our key priority, that's positive momentum in the business which is complemented by our focus on optimizing our cost base and efficiently utilizing our cash flow.</p>
          <p>We continue to drive our performance through our brands, products and geographic footprint, and we're in a good position heading into 2011.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand you over to Bob to take you through the financials.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Alison, and good morning, ladies and gentlemen.</p>
          <p>Let me start by providing you an overview of our results. Tobacco net revenues grew 3% to &#xA3;7.1 billion, as our enhanced top-line focus benefited from strong pricing across our total tobacco portfolio and volume growth within our global strategic brands. The decrease in Logistics distribution fees reflects the challenging economic environment in Spain. Tobacco adjusted operating profit was up 5%, and total adjusted operating profit for the group also grew by 5%.</p>
          <p>Cost optimization continues to be an important aspect of our strategy, complementing our sales-led agenda, and when combined with the benefits of price increases, delivered an improvement in our Tobacco operating margin to 40.9%. The interest charged for the year was down &#xA3;100 million to 600 million, reflecting our proactive approach to financing and an excellent performance in converting 97% of our adjusted operating profit into cash flow after CapEx.</p>
          <p>After a tax charge and effective rate of 25.8%, adjusted earnings per share grew by 11% to 178.8 pence or 12% excluding foreign exchange movements. Dividends per share rose ahead of earnings per share to 84.3 pence per share, an increase of 15%.</p>
          <p>Results have been adjusted and presented on our usual basis with the main differences to reported numbers being amortization of acquired intangibles of &#xA3;451 million and fair value gains on derivative financial instruments of &#xA3;210 million, and there are further details in the Appendixes.</p>
          <p>Taking a closer look at our tobacco net revenues, they grew 3% on a constant currency basis, whilst our Logistics distribution fees declined 2.6% excluding foreign currency effects. We delivered organic tobacco adjusted operating profit growth of 3.1%, and the Logistics adjusted operating profit was broadly in line with last year.</p>
          <p>The Altadis integration is nearly complete with cost and revenue synergies on track. To date, we've generated &#x20AC;300 million of cost synergies with the 2010 incremental synergy target of &#x20AC;110 million delivered, and we expect to achieve our projected savings of &#x20AC;400 million in 2012.</p>
          <p>Tobacco profits grew 5% to just under &#xA3;2.9 billion, despite input cost headwinds including leaf inflation which added a further 20% to our overall leaf cost, including the impact of foreign exchange.</p>
          <p>Total profit growth reflected 2% growth in the U.K., excellent results from Germany where profits grew 7%, in Rest of the EU where profits were up 13% and the Rest of the World where profits rose by 12%.</p>
          <p>Despite lower net revenue, profits from our Spanish business were stable excluding the impact of foreign exchange driven by price increases and cost synergies.</p>
          <p>In the Americas profits declined 15%, but the trend is improving with the decline moderating in the second half to around 3%.</p>
          <p>In Logistics, profits declined by 1% due to the impact of foreign exchange and the start-up costs of the ONCE Spanish lottery joint venture.</p>
          <p>Moving onto adjusted net debt where our focus on maximizing cash flow produced an excellent result, we've adjusted net debt reducing by &#xA3;1.5 billion to &#xA3;9.3 billion from September of last year and &#xA3;2.1 billion from March this year, as our usual working capital pattern continued with an outflow in the first half of the year followed by a significant inflow in the second half.</p>
          <p>Over the course of the year, there was a small working capital inflow of &#xA3;200 million, around half of which was due to our Italian Logistics business where we made sales ahead of a price increase in late September, and we expect this gain to unwind in the first half of 2011.</p>
          <p>Tax and interest payments were an outflow of &#xA3;0.9 billion, and our dividend payments were &#xA3;0.8 billion. Foreign exchange movements gave a small benefit. The denomination of our closing adjusted net debt was 50% euro, 23% U.S. dollar and 27% sterling.</p>
          <p>We have no refinancing requirements until July 2012, but we'll continue to actively manage our financing position and hold committed facilities at the year end of around &#xA3;11.9 billion. Our average adjusted net debt was &#xA3;10.9 billion, and our average all-in cost of debt was stable at 5.5% to give a net interest charge of &#xA3;600 million and interest cover on an adjusted basis of 5.1 times.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead into the current financial year, we're expecting good cost headwinds to persist in 2011, with non-tobacco material costs estimated to rise above inflation and further leaf cost increases to continue following the removal of EU lease subsidies. But we are working to mitigate these effects.</p>
          <p>The Altadis synergies are firmly on track, and we expect our working capital to follows its normal pattern with an outflow in the first half followed by a reversal in the second half.</p>
          <p>We expect our all-in cost of debt to be around 6.25%, reflecting the impact of rising interest rates on variable loans and expect the tax charge to remain around 26%. We remain committed to optimizing our cost base and effectively utilizing our cash to support our sales growth strategy.</p>
          <p>With our strong cash generation, we aim to increase dividends ahead of earnings over the next couple of years, and as we emerge from being focused on debt pay down, we expect to be in a position to consider alternative value-creating options for our cash by our 2012 financial year.</p>
          <p>So thank you, ladies and gentlemen. I'd now like to hand back to Alison to conclude the presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bob.</p>
          <p>Let me return to the core of our strategy: sales growth. 2010's been something of a transitional year for us. There's strong momentum behind our enhanced sales focus. We continue to grow our strategic cigarette brands and fine cut tobacco volumes, and we achieved good revenue growth across the business, particularly in some of our emerging markets.</p>
          <p>I'm very optimistic about the future, and we'll maintain our sales focus to drive our brands, our unique total tobacco portfolio and the expansion of our market footprint. Our global strategic brands, supported by regionally local brands, will continue to drive sales growth in both mature and emerging markets.</p>
          <p>Our understanding of our customers and consumers' requirements will be crucial in maximizing our potential.</p>
          <p>Creating sustainable value for our shareholders is embedded in our DNA, and I'm confident that we have the assets, the opportunities and the capabilities to take our business forward and deliver on our strategy.</p>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now take any questions you may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The presentation is being recorded, so it'd be great if you'd wait for a microphone before speaking and then give your name and organization.</p>
          <p>David Hayes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a reputation for asking the first question. Hi, it's David Hayes from Nomura. Two quick questions if I can? Firstly, just in terms of Russia, obviously you've kind of made a decision, it looks like, to rationalize some of the Balkan Star brand. Can you just talk about where you are with that in terms of whether that's done now or that starts to lap, and what you might have for next or for this year? And then I guess putting together all the comments you talked about in terms of trends, the medium-term target you talked about is flat volumes, circa 3% price, 5% operating profit. Can you talk about whether that's the kind of shape we should you expect for this year, and if not, where the deltas on that we should be looking for?</p>
          <p>And then just very quickly on the leaf cost, just to push Bob on what the inflation is expected to be on leaf for this year? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will kick off with Balkan Star in Russia. We clearly inherited this brand with the Altadis deal as part of our portfolio in Russia, and I think the question for us when we took it on was whether or not we were happy to let it continue growing, but ultimately at quite an unprofitable level or whether or not we saw opportunities to put a bit more profitability in the brand, but at the same time, off the back of that, realize we would have to sacrifice a little bit of volume.</p>
          <p>I think the reality is, given the trends in Russia though, that volume sacrifice has probably been a little bit higher than we anticipated. But I still think the call was right to try and push more profitability into that brand from the position that it was in the market historically. So that's the story on Balkan Star.</p>
          <p>The other side of the story, you can see, is the growth that's coming through with Davidoff and West, and in particular Davidoff in Eastern Europe, up 19% this year, so some strong growth from the upper end of the portfolio in Russia.</p>
          <p>In terms of the trends and volumes and what the outlook for FY '11, I think the best way of describing it is if we look our NSV guidance of 2% to 4%, we're very much in that target range for next year in terms of where we see our numbers. At the moment, I would like to see the volumes up a little bit on this year as part of that mix. But I think, as we talked about at the Investor Day, the tobacco model is strong, and if we do end up with some aspects of volume weakness in a market like Spain or in Eastern Europe persisting a bit, clearly prices coming through strongly, particularly in Eastern Europe and, therefore, from a sales guidance perspective, I think that's the strong point I would communicate. Volumes I think I would like to see them a little bit up, but clearly you can appreciate there's some sensitivities at the current time in terms of some markets.</p>
          <p>And then on leaf, Bob, the inflation for this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Leaf cost, going forward into the current year, anticipate inflation to be around about 10%, high single digit 10%, higher than underlying &#x2013; the underlying &#x2013; what's happening in terms of the market. Two reasons, one, the removal of the EU subsidies being the impact. We've obviously bought a large proportion of next year's leaf already. However, what we are seeing is the supply/demand balance actually changing rather more quickly than we anticipated. Partly, everybody's talking about softness in world volumes. That obviously impacts in total world demand for leaf. And so supply/demand has actually, sort of, crossed over, and we're in a little bit of excess supply. So when I talked about mitigating the impact, we may be able to do some, for example, spot leaf purchases to bring that down slightly. So I would hope to benefit from that.</p>
          <p>And in terms of year on year, in the current year the 20% was about 10% underlying and 10% FX. Next year, again, we've purchased most of it. We know the exchange rate. There's no real FX benefit year on year so that, as I say, it's about, roundabout 10% but we hope to mitigate that 9%, 10% total.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> certainly taken to the like-for-like FX and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you like <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes total &#x2013; 20 this year, well let's say 10 next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Less change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So for the leaf environment is shifting, as Bob says, and I do think going forward beyond that, we see some better opportunities in terms of leaf costs.</p>
          <p>Yeah, Eric?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, two questions please. Firstly, if you could comment and update us on the plain packaging initiative in Australia and where that stands and what we might expect into the next year? And then secondly, with respect to price increases, we understand there's increases coming in Germany and in France. Particularly in Germany it sounds like there's an emphasis on increasing the lower-price brands more than, perhaps, the other priced brands. Could you just discuss the situation as you understand it in Germany with what's happening there? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let's kickoff with plain packages in Australia. The situation is still somewhat unclear in terms of what's happening next with the new government who seem to be putting a little bit of a pause button on it around quite what it's going to look like and how they're going to put the legislation together. But clearly, that doesn't mean we're sitting on our laurels to any degree at all.</p>
          <p>We've very active with the rest of the industry in Australia in putting our arguments forward and working with the various stakeholders in the Australian market around our strong arguments against this approach by the Australian government, and those are both legal arguments but also IP arguments. But there are also quite logical arguments around illicit trade, the implications for putting, ultimately, the industry into the hands of crooks and away from the legitimate tobacco industry.</p>
          <p>So we're marshaling all of those arguments in our debates with the stakeholders in Australia. As you've seen from recent comments from some of our competitors as well, we're going to throw everything at this. The arguments are strong, and we'll see how that develops over the coming months.</p>
          <p>In terms of price, I mean France we've clearly got a price increase going through this month of &#x20AC;0.30 going through in terms of our French market. In Germany, I think you're talking more of a debate around excise currently rather than a price increase being debated in a manufacturer sense of price increase.</p>
          <p>It's, again, an unclear situation at the moment. There've been various "to-ings and fro-ings" with the German government. I'm sure my colleagues in Germany are being pushed on this point by the German press as I speak. But at the moment, we continue to engage with them. I think the good news is whatever they do, I think, will be a moderate approach. So we're not going to see any knee jerks that are going to suck illicit trade into Germany beyond the levels already existing in the German market. But at the same time, it's still very much, it's a very political item and it's very much in the melting pot currently.</p>
          <p> John?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, a couple of questions. I think historically you've talked about sort of increased A&amp;P spend during 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And obviously you referred a number of times to the benefits of down trading for your market shares. But obviously in some of the core countries, market shares have gone backwards despite both of those factors. Do you need to spend more on A&amp;P, is the first point?</p>
          <p>And secondly with regard to the global strategic brands, is that something you've changed internally? Is there a difference in the way that that's being pushed internally, or is that really just an external label for some of those brands?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let's start on A&amp;P. Yes, we've increase A&amp;P this year, as we talked about at the half year. And that was partly around, as you linked very strongly in terms of your question around the global strategic brands in reality, in that we rejuvenated those, particularly Davidoff and West this year, and clearly there's a cost associated and an investment associated with rejuvenating those brands. So that's come through in terms of the numbers this year and going forward, we've highlighted that we see A&amp;P continuing to increase, but at around a level of NSV increases, not above that sort of level. So some additional investment this year, and we're continuing to invest behind our brands both global and regional.</p>
          <p>In terms of our positioning in the value segment, yes, we've got strong brands in the value segment and also, clearly, our competitors are active in that segment because that's where the consumer's going in a number of markets and has been going for sometime in reality. But we are strong in value, not just cigarette, but as you can see particularly our fine cut value performance this year as well, where we've grown very significantly in a number of markets, up 8.7% on a white stick equivalent basis.</p>
          <p>The U.K., you can see the activities on Windsor Blue and on JPS coming through, so our share is in slight growth in the U.K. France is down very slightly at the moment, but I think we're still seeing some very good momentum behind our brands there. It's difficult to say whether it was value or not in France given the narrow band around pricing. But, yes, the shares that we've got positioned at the bottom part of the market are doing well, just some pressure on Gauloises, basically. The rest of them are Fortuna, News, Ivern and JPS all in growth.</p>
          <p>Germany, I think it's positive inroving momentum and then some JPS, as I said nearly 10%. Actually in October, we're now hitting the 10% mark in Germany. So JPS continues to hit the mark with consumers on value, 13% growth across the globe in the year at very good margins.</p>
          <p>And Spain, clearly, the difficult environment for us currently and we're doing, as you can see, a lot with the portfolio, Ducados and Fortuna. I think those of you who heard the investor presentation at the Investor Day can see what we're doing to try and push that share forward and really give the consumers what they want in that environment.</p>
          <p>So I think the value aspects we push very hard in the business. But it isn't just about value, it's also about our other brands and, as you say, a lot of focus behind Davidoff, behind West which is coming through in the numbers as well.</p>
          <p> Walter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Can I ask about the industry volume outlook in Spain? Obviously, the unemployment's still high. You have the smoking ban coming, but the comparison base is easier. So is it another year of double-digit decline, mid single-digit decline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's been &#x2013; I don't think we'll have as difficult a year as 2010. I think it's still tough in Spain and, at the moment, we see some of those pressures in terms of volumes potentially. We're protecting them coming off a bit in the coming months. But it's still a tough market. So I think, at the moment, I would say we're seeing it getting better, but clearly we've got the six impacts coming through next year as well which you've seen before is a little bit of a dip and then things will get better over a period of time. So I would still be probably in high single-digit declines in Spain in terms of volumes next year. So it still got a lot of pressure in terms of market, but price opportunities, portfolio opportunities in that market for us and then also, again, across the total tobacco category not just cigarette.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the second question on fine cut tobacco, have you seen any change in combative behavior or tough as usual?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, clearly we've done very well with fine cut this year, and that's partly because I think we're getting a few things right with our roll-your-own portfolio, but also the make-your-own phenomenon is huge, particularly in Central Europe. We've clearly introduced into Spain as well with some very good initial success, and we'll continue to focus on that opportunity. So yes, the competitors are in it. If you look around the markets, make-your-own is very often an FMCG &#x2013; or FMC cigarette-branded offering. But I think, yeah, we've been very much ahead of the curve on it in terms of where the consumers are going, and you can see that coming through in our numbers. But like anything in the EU, it continues to be competitive. It's a competitive market.</p>
          <p> Adam?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of questions, if I may. Firstly to Bob, you said that revenue synergies were on track. I was just wondering if you had a number for that for the year? Secondly about the U.S. cigarette, you mentioned several times rejuvenation, and obviously we are aware that market share had declined. I was under impression that was all due to aggressive pricing from Pall Mall, and the brands were fundamentally in fine shape. But I was wondering if you could say if you thought that wasn't really the case.</p>
          <p>And then finally, you said you were thinking about alternatives where you're delivering value to shareholders from FY '12. I was wondering whether that meant really in FY '12 or in FY '13 just to be picky. I think that's what you've said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think my words were actually by FY '12.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's in FY '12?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I said by FY '12. Your first point is fairly easy. In terms of the 60 million of synergies, about 40 million at the moment and well on track for the 60 million target; a number of initiatives in terms of cross-selling, actually using combined, if you like, a combined scale to renegotiate -- when we negotiate -- we negotiate, I'll get the word right eventually, distribution fees and things after that. So we've got about 40 million of the 60 and well on track for the 60 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the U.S. cigarette share, around 3.9% for the year, another sudden improving trend in recent weeks, which is looking good. In terms of the brands though, I mean we do think they're strong brands, I think what we've seen in the last year with very, very significant competitor activity both with Pall Mall, but also with discounted Marlboro. I think the brands have been very robust given that environment and the amount of money in investment put behind the competitive brands in the market.</p>
          <p>What we're doing, really, with the rejuvenation is the sensible stuff you should do with any brand over a period of time. You can't just leave it as is. You've got to look at opportunities to move it forward and, U.S.A. Gold in particular, I think what we've done with it is quite interesting in terms of the refreshment of the brand, but also the traction that's had with consumers in the market when we've researched in terms of the shape of the brand going forward. Sonoma's about to come down the line. But yes, they needed some, just updating really. It's not a question of the brands, a question mark over the brand strength. It's just good housekeeping.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When you say updating, you usually talk about refreshed packaging or something of that sort.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's mainly packaging really, yeah, quite conservative consumers in terms of some &#x2013;  not anything too radical.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Julian?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I've got a question for Bob. Bob, I just wondered if you've done an update at all on the returns from the Altadis acquisition and which you could share with us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes, yes we have. Our latest number in terms of where we are in the current year is roundabout just under 8% post-tax return. I think we were about just below 7% last financial year and about just under 7.5% at the half year. We're roundabout the 8% at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's for FY '10 full-year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, that's the current year, yes, absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which we think is just about looking at our weighted average cost of capital that check point two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And secondly, can you just update us, get, kind of, your thoughts on what is an optimal capital structure would look like, what metrics on an optimal capital structure would look like for you? And, I mean, given your comments about this, sort of, effective interest rate movements this year versus last, there's clearly a structural upward pressure as you are paying down debt because of the structure of all your debt. Does that sort of accelerate your thinking about what you might want to do in terms of capital structure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hopefully, I've got it all. I mean, basically we are massively cash generative. In terms of our stated strategy, it's to have an optimal capital structure, if you like. Where we were historically was absolutely right for the times and as we come out of that, we will look at the most effective way of utilizing our cash flow for creation of value for our shareholders, and we talk to our shareholders about that. That's not to say nothing is given just because our competitors have their payout ratio of X does not mean that's a default position. We are about value creation for our shareholders. We'll take a look at that.</p>
          <p>In terms of debt, I mean, debt comes in, goes out over time. You're talking about margins and debt gets refinanced. We are looking at the profiles of our debt and looking at, effectively, how to effectively manage this. So if I take a view that isn't a snapshot of the 12-month period, I have no good sense at all. The overriding, overarching comment if we will remain investment grade because you would not run a tobacco company ungeared, and you need to be investment grade to access the pool of investors. But we will be looking very carefully at how best to maximize value for our shareholders from our cash flows going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Robert JPMorgan. Just a question where Logistics fits into the sales growth agenda. On Slide 31, you've got tobacco revenue organic at plus-3, Logistics minus-3 The Logistics, profits are flat, and, obviously, Logistics is more of a passive business, I guess. We can't get the marketers behind it, so just where Logistics fits into this new agenda as it were?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of results this year, Logistics has clearly had quite a tough time in Spain with its exposure to Spain. So I think we're riding that particular issue in Spain, so to get through it and figuring out once you get beyond that and gets more positive for the business. Clearly, the sales focus is very much part of our core tobacco piece in terms of what we're driving. Logistics is a very solid business in terms of what it delivers. We've got very, if you like, happy customers in our Logistics business. In terms of our fellow competitors, ultimately, in the industry and the tobacco business is a very solid business. It's a very fantastic cash generator as well in terms of what it delivers.</p>
          <p>We've got the non-tobacco Logistics piece, which I've made no secret of the fact that we've been tidying up, and it's nice to see some of the growth coming through this year despite the difficult environment in some of the sectors of the non-tobacco business. But we have done things to tidy up publications, for example, in Spain, and we continue to see some great opportunities, particularly with the ONCE, the lottery business, a very nice natural synergistic fit with the core distribution operations. And also, I think pharma is still coming through quite nicely in term of the opportunities for that.</p>
          <p>So I think it's a business with potential. I think we've made no secret of the fact that we're very happy to hold the business given the cash dynamics and the ongoing robustness of the business, but of course staff agenda is clearly very much about what we're doing with the core tobacco business at Imperial.</p>
          <p>Is that it Robin, yes, so checking Robin was finished?</p>
          <p>Chas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Chas Manso from Evolution. Three questions for me. I suppose one on debt still. Could you, in layman terms, explain to us how you got the 400 million FX benefits given that year on year FX doesn't seem to have made too much difference elsewhere. And given that you are, sort of, 400 million or 500 million ahead on net debt to where everyone had, does that mean you can end the debt pay down mode sooner than in 2012 or by 2012?</p>
          <p>Second question on your stated aim to increase distribution coverage, particularly in the U.S. and Russia. Could you sort of update us on what has been the level of your coverage gains in those two key markets this year and whether we ought to expect something similar for next?</p>
          <p>And the final question, your fellow competitors have mentioned recently that market growth in Western Europe has deteriorated in calendar Q3, and given that Western Europe is so key to Imperial, whether you could update us on how that is impacting you? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to kickoff, Bob, with the 400 million FX on debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, yeah, in fact, Chas the bridge chart, I think it's chart 34, is a better one because, in fact, you're talking about the 400, which is a reconciliation of reported to, sorry &#x2013; from the opening net debt to the closing net debt. It's got 400, which is FX, but there is actually &#x2013; there is almost a couple of hundred within the derivatives because the 400 is on absolute debt because derivatives, we use synthetic &#x2013; we use derivatives to create synthetic debt if we're swapping debt from currency one into currency two. So in fact the number is closer to the 200 million year-on-year movement which you saw in on the bridge chart, I think it was chart 34, where we start with the opening net debt on this wonderful &#x2013; if you're color blind, they're probably not good for people, but they're red and the red and green bands. So it's a closer to 200 million, which reflects the opening and closing. And there were some changes because you're talking about spot rates on the day, obviously, for that. So that's why you've got 400, which is that.</p>
          <p>The second one is debt pay down, you're saying, obviously, I suppose it is a truism. If you're paying debt down quickly, you'll reach the point to which you want to do more quickly. Of course, one knows where our exchange rates go, so I'll hedge my bet as the Finance Director.</p>
          <p>We keep this under review all the time. I can't stress enough that we're in the business of creating value for shareholders. We're looking at effective uses of cash, how to finance the group the whole time, and obviously sitting here today I'm not going to make a statement apart from agreeing with you that as you pay down debt more quickly; one thing that I did also mention is around about 100 million of that 200 million working capital inflow will reverse. So we're not doing quite as well we're doing very well, actually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're clearly ahead of where we thought we would be at the time of the Altadis deal. We took the 1 billion of working capital we took out last year, and there might have been some questions as to whether or not that would be embedded in the numbers. Clearly that's come through plus a bit more in this year's numbers. So despite the fact that you all have to travel that roller coaster with us of it's the half year, oh, working capital's gone the wrong way. It's the nature, the flows. Hopefully, you're getting used to it now in terms of what happens in this business.</p>
          <p>There are huge cash flows that go to this business because of the GT aspects and, therefore, sometimes there are some timing impacts. But you can see it coming through strongly. You can see the reduction average debt, how that led to impact the interest charge as well this year. So, I mean, yeah, we are ahead of the curve where we thought we'd be when we did the Altadis deal because of what we've done with working capital and the opportunities in the business. So it's great to be here now in 5 times interest cover. And, yeah, it's a good performance on the debt front.</p>
          <p>Let me pick up on the other two questions. On distribution gains in the U.S. and Russia, maybe I'll let Greg pick up with you asking on specific percentage shifts. But I mean clearly we've added significant numbers to the sales force, both in the U.S. and Russia in the last year. We're very much driving, if you like, the pull-through system in terms of our brands and products, and you can see that, I think, particularly having effect with some of the brands in Russia. Style, for example, has done very well from that enhanced focus through the outlets.</p>
          <p>I think it's very necessary in terms of the evolution of that market and where it's going that we have a strong sales force on the ground. And clearly in the U.S. as well, it's very much helped maintain our position in what's been quite a difficult environment with the competition. You can see the shares held up well, and now I think we're going to move more into a growth mode as the market stabilizes; gets more back to a normal trend, if you like, over the next 12 months.</p>
          <p>And finally, Western European growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Same as the gains next year? This is ongoing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the U.S., we'll add, I think, a bit more in terms of the overall sales force next year, again, and look at some other opportunities in terms of how we manage the U.S. business. Russia, we're having further evaluations to where we are and whether or not we should put some more investment behind that.</p>
          <p>Western European growth? I put up the chart in this presentation. You saw the Western European trends over the last three years in terms of the cigarette market and the fine cut market and how the two interplay and, therefore, pretty much what I would say fairly normal trends in Western Europe. If you look at it in its entirety, and if you look at the last year, the U.K. has been pretty robust. The German market's been pretty robust. The French market's been pretty robust. And yes, in Spain we focus on, and then you look at a smaller market like Greece.</p>
          <p>Other than that, I would say, the Western European market environment, I still see, as pretty robust in terms of how we've seen it historically, how we see our brands performing, how we see the profitability coming through.</p>
          <p>Yes, there's pockets of greater economic pressure within the Western European environment, but what we've seen so far in terms of governments, their approach to looking at excise in our big markets, it's all been pretty sensible stuff. So no guarantees when it comes to governments, clearly, but I think it's a fairly robust environment still, the Western European markets, from how we see it.</p>
          <p>Jon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Jon Fell from Deutsche Bank. Just a quick clarification on the all-in cost of debt next year. That rise from 5.5 to 6.25, is that due to what you already know will be happening in terms of what you're raising, the debt you're paying down, the different rates and more facilities, or are you forecasting a rise in interest rates for next year as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, to an extent. We do have &#x2013; about 40% of our debt is floating, and if you take a look at the implied yield curve, then effectively it is saying, as it has been saying and did say at the beginning of this year, that interest rates are going to rise. Our experience in the current year is that rise hasn't actually come through, and you've almost got a waterfall that's going away from you. However, and when we put together a forecast, we don't call anything, but the yield curve that's there in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>I think, coming into this year, I think we'll be giving guidance of around &#x2013; just 6.25% for the current year. So there you go. I go back to next year looks exactly like this year, looked at the beginning of this year. Yes, inevitably at some stage. I mean, we talk about 2012, you won't leave it until 2012 to potentially do some refile and there's an implied, some assumptions in there. But there are a lot of assumptions rather than &#x2013; and we will seek to, as well, I said we will be managing that chart so, and possibly very slightly a tiny bit conservative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You spoke to that like a good Finance Director.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What do you expect Finance Director.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's one more over here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Going to have the last question...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, just in the U.K., it looks like price mix is being offset in terms of the down trading to economies. Obviously, you mentioned the release is quite aggressive. Is that a trend now? Should we assume price mix is a thing of the past in the U.K., or what changes for that to get better? Is it more pricing? Is it less down trading?</p>
          <p>And just on the U.S., coming back to the market share discussion, in terms of these companies that have disappeared, are you seeing that benefit already, or is that something that only starts really impact FY'11 is therefore, you mentioned the last few weeks improvement? Is that part of that coming through now? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'll deal with the last one first, just quick. I mean, is really more of a future feature in that, I think, it's more FDA-related. Some of these smaller manufacturers are going to come under pressure to go out of business. And clearly, that's clicking over the coming year or two in terms of money-factoring practice and all those aspects in the U.S.</p>
          <p>If I look at U.K. and price mix in the second half, I think we probably just need to do a bit of a history lesson here around the U.K. and how we play the U.K. market because our strategy is clear around, we clearly want to target good market share in the U.K. But at the same time, we always balance profitability and growing profits with where we're sitting with market share. And if I was sitting here, I think, this time last year, there was some question marks over what our market share was doing in the U.K.</p>
          <p>And back to that balance, the growth within the economy segment, the consumers were looking for value. I always use that phrase, "mind the gap," in terms of the U.K. market because you've got to watch the bottom of the market, where the opportunities are, where the consumers are going.</p>
          <p>We weren't getting our fair share of the economy segment versus our overall market share. So we put a lot of focus behind JPS, behind Windsor Blue. We've now got our share of the economy segment up to a similar level, if a bit above, where our overall market share is. So, therefore, you can see the dynamic coming through in terms of share beginning to pick up a bit in the U.K.</p>
          <p>But clearly, that's the part of the ongoing dynamics we see in the U.K. market, that we take those moves, then you see the pricing coming through, the lovely price leverage in the U.K., a percent on the retail price and roughly three-and-a-bit percent, even more when you're looking at the value end in terms of the manufacturers' price take, and that model will just come through in terms of improving profitability going forward.</p>
          <p>So I don't see this is a sudden shift in dynamics in the U.K. If you just go back through the history of what we've done when we first put Richmond into the market, for example, you see these sort of dynamics coming through.</p>
          <p>Fine cut clearly will also impact in terms of our NSV position in terms of price mix, but clearly the profit has come through very strongly on fine cut at the trading level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I suppose the other thing is off on that because of the growth in the economy sector, particularly, what we recall or what we now classify as economy and value combined are now 60% of the market. And, therefore, I also talked in the past about when you take price increases, the impact of the price increase tends to be bigger at the bottom end in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me try and take one last &#x2013; sorry you had another one, did you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a quick one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's on the working capital cycle, you gave this inflow and outflow. I mean, if you look through the year, it's about at peak at March and about the best in September. Is that about or are there other months that stand out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It may peak at various times. It tends to be peak around about March, and that's just because of when timings are. If you take a various government excise moves and if you take a look at the cycle, it's generally around about then. In fact, actually when the U.K. budget moved the year before last, in fact, that moved a few hundred million pounds in terms of working capital between a couple of months, and it tends to be those things. I would say in September will be a normal level because, except when there's occasionally a price increase, it's more of an excise increase, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Maybe take just one last question behind you there, unless there's any other burning ones because I think we've covered most of your points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mine's a bit picky. So just very small ones. In Taiwan, is that factory actually being built yet and is operated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's open and running, and, in fact, part of our strength now in Taiwan is the fact there was &#x2013; we are able to participate quite strongly in the value segment in Taiwan with brands such as West, and we've introduced a brand called Moon as well, which are doing particularly well in Taiwan and being produced in our local factory there. So the Taiwan factory is very much on line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When was that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>18 months. It was at beginning &#x2013; yes, beginning of last calendar year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And secondly, just currently is the U.S premium cigar market, is that still the bulk of the profitability of that U.S. cigar business or not really?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, never has been. Mass market cigar is incredibly profitable in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is the much more profitable part?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And if you look at absolute amounts of profit, yes, much more profit from the mass markets and mass market cigar business to premium. That is a much smaller segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well, maybe I could bring our presentation to an end. Thank you, as always, for your keen interest in Imperial. The management team will be around over the coffee if there's any more detailed questions you want to get involved in. But thanks again for you keen interest in Imperial.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>