<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1432330" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-11-01</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1430</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Non-Executive Chairman">Iain J. G. Napier</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Executive &amp; Operating Officer &amp; Director">Alison J. Cooper</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Director &amp; Director-Group Finance">Robert Dyrbus</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (United Kingdom)">Erik A. Bloomquist</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">David H. Hayes</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Jonathan P. Fell</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Rogerio S. Fujimori</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Toby J. McCullagh</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep" affiliation="Director-Research &amp; Development">Walter Prinz</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Jonathan S. Leinster</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International Ltd.">Nico J. Lambrechts</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Investec Bank Plc">Martin J. Deboo</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Marketing Director">Roberto Funari</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Fulvio Cazzol</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="corprep" affiliation="Director-Group Corporate &amp; Legal Affairs">Matthew R. Phillips</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen to those of you here in the room and everyone watching on our webcast, welcome to Imperial Tobacco's 2011 Preliminary Results Presentation. I am Iain Napier, Chairman of Imperial, and I am here today with Chief Executive, Alison Cooper and CFO, Bob Dyrbus. As well, of course, as a number of Imperial Senior Management Team.</p>
          <p>We delivered a good set of results and this year we continued to focus on maximizing returns to all of our shareholders. We grew sales across our portfolio in many markets whilst effectively managing our costs and optimizing our cash flows.</p>
          <p>We continue to drive growth through our total tobacco portfolio increasing tobacco net revenues by 2% as a result of gains in EU and non-EU markets. Tobacco operating margins were once again above 42% driven by positive pricing and ongoing cost optimization.</p>
          <p>Free cash flow was strong at &#xA3;1.6 billion and we continued to reinvest in the business both in supporting our brands and in our manufacturing capacity. Adjusted earnings per share increased by 5.4% to &#xA3;1.88 and the board is proposing a final dividend of &#xA3;0.57 per share bringing the total dividend for the year to &#xA3;0.951 per share.</p>
          <p>This is an increase of 13% taking the payout ratio to slightly over 50%. We are well placed to build our sales growth momentum, which supported by our ongoing focus on cost and effectively using our cash will enable us to continue to create significant shareholder value for all shareholders.</p>
          <p>I'll now hand you over to Alison, who will take you through the detail of the presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, Iain, and good morning, everyone.</p>
          <p>There have been two key areas of focus for Imperial in 2011. As always, it's been about delivering the results. And I'll come back to those shortly. But it's also been about gearing up behind our sales growth agenda.</p>
          <p>There has been a huge amount of activity across the business looking at how we maximize the potential of our assets. And this has included work on our four sales growth drivers, our focus for excellence. Our sales growth drivers are portfolio management, which is our drive for more consumers in more markets on more occasions.</p>
          <p>It's about innovation, delivering new products based on consumer insights. It's about pricing, how we model pricing strategies and manage excise to maximize revenue growth. And it's about customer engagement, partnering with our trade customers and enhancing the advocacy and the availability of our products.</p>
          <p>These growth drivers are supported by our three key enablers, where are focus is to continue developing better consumer insights, further aligning our operations behind our sales growth agenda and proactively engaging with stakeholders to shape our environment.</p>
          <p>The team have made fantastic progress with our strategic agenda this year. Some are here today, many are watching via the webcast. A big thank you to all of you and your teams.</p>
          <p>Against a tough economic backdrop, I'm pleased with our performance this year, as we've continued to drive sales and profit through our unique total tobacco portfolio. This portfolio gives us access to and the ability to create consumer growth segments in every market, and we're capitalizing on these portfolio opportunities.</p>
          <p>In the EU our operating model continues to deliver, including good profit growth in Germany and the rest of EU. Consumers are seeking value. We've continued to make gains in our cigarette portfolio, and our excellent performance in fine cut reinforces our world leadership in this growing category.</p>
          <p>I'm particularly pleased with our Non-EU performance, where we delivered strong results in emerging markets with profits up 10%. Growth was driven by our key strategic cigarette brands complemented by great performance from our luxury cigar portfolio.</p>
          <p>Cost optimization remains a core strength, and despite facing leaf cost pressures during the year, our disciplined approach to investment delivered Group tobacco margins above 42%. And in Non-EU markets margins were up 150 basis points.</p>
          <p>We continued to drive efficiencies across the business including the 3% productivity improvement. Cash conversion was strong at 88% and we generated &#xA3;1.6 billion of free cash flow an excellent results given our increased capital investments.</p>
          <p>And we're increasing returns to shareholders. We grew the dividend by 13% and also bought back shares worth of &#xA3;181 million.</p>
          <p>When looking at our performance I'll be referring to constant currency numbers.</p>
          <p>Our performance this year was impacted by the exceptional circumstances in Spain as well as the change in trade buying patterns in the U.K. As at the half year, I've highlighted our performance excluding these impacts to give you a better sense of how the business is performing.</p>
          <p>With these adjustments our Group stick equivalent volumes were flat, whilst tobacco net revenues were up 4.5%, and tobacco adjusted operating profit was up almost 6%, reflecting the very strong performance in our non-EU markets.</p>
          <p>Our total Tobacco approach has been being key to our growth. Our key strategic brands, Davidoff, Gauloises Blonde, West and JPS had another excellent year with overall stick equivalent volumes rising 4%. We also delivered another excellent performance with fine cut tobacco growing volumes 4%, complimented by 5% growth in papers and 9% growth in tubes.</p>
          <p>Our premium Cigar business Habanos grew by 4% in non-EU markets. U.S. premium cigars were up 9% and in the EU, mass markets cigar volumes rose 8%. We always had a strong year in snus with the volume growth of 30%.</p>
          <p>Let's look at the brand and product performances in a bit more detail. We increased Davidoff volumes by 6% due to another impressive performance in non-EU markets. Continued growth in its core classic line, after last years rejuvenation and new variant launches in key growth segments led to increased volumes in eight of its top 10 markets.</p>
          <p>Highlights included growth of 9% in Saudi Arabia, 11% in Taiwan, 12% in Ukraine and 33% in Russia. Elsewhere, in South Korea, we continued to make encouraging progress following last year's launch.</p>
          <p>Gauloises Blonde growth of 2%, reflects strong underlying momentum, impacted by sanction compliance in the Middle East. We've expanded distribution and we grew volumes by 12% in the brand's top five markets, and there was an exceptional performance in North Africa, up by 28% with gains in Algeria and Morocco.</p>
          <p>West volumes declined by 2%, primarily due to market weakness in Poland and Turkey but we've been making good progress in consumer growth segments in the emerging markets of Eastern Europe and Asia. The consumer trend to value has been the driver of growth in Taiwan and in Eastern Europe where volumes grew 8% in Russia it's also been about value trends combined with slimmer variants.</p>
          <p>JPS had another excellent year with volumes reaching 24 billion compared to just 9 billion six years ago. A tremendous achievement, reflecting the way we developed the brand in line with consumer trends. The brand is growing in seven of its top ten markets. Highlights include 8% cigarette volume growth in Germany, 34% in the U.K. and Australasia volumes have more than doubled.</p>
          <p>Fine cut tobacco continues to grow particularly in the EU where it's a great value proposition for consumers. Fine cut tobacco now accounts for more than 110 billion stick equivalents in the EU more than one in every six stick equivalents smoked in the EU, is a fine cut tobacco product. And we continue capture growth in this dynamic category.</p>
          <p>We grew overall fine cut tobacco volumes by 4%, largely due to an outstanding growth of Route 66, which was up 49%, achieving great results in Germany, the Czech Republic and in Poland. West was up 16% with strong growth in Netherlands, whilst JPS grew 14% boosted by a successful launch in the U.K. and Australia.</p>
          <p>In Spain, we positioned Ducados Rubio Make Your Own to meet consumer value trends with great results. We've increased the brand share to over 16%, making its Spain's number one fine cut tobacco brand.</p>
          <p>Habanos brands over that question the world's leading luxury cigars, and luxury products also increasing in demand with non-EU volumes up 4%, reflecting excellent momentum in high growth market such as Brazil, Russia and China.</p>
          <p>Our successful launch of new exclusive editions during the year made sales grew ahead of volumes at 5% and 12% outside the EU. If you look at our total tobacco performance across our market footprint, it's clear that in the EU there's a strong value dynamic. We capitalized on this by responding to change in consumer preferences. In addition, we have increased prices supporting profitability in all price segments.</p>
          <p>Our EU volumes were down 4% and sales declined slightly, largely a result of the 13% decline in the Spanish market. Adjusting for this and U.K. trade buying patterns, volumes were only down 1% and sales increased 4%.</p>
          <p>Outside the EU, value is also the key consumer driver in the U.S., whereas our rest of world region has seen growth in both value and premium-and-above products. We delivered a strong performance in emerging markets, driven by Davidoff, Gauloises Blondes and West, leading to an overall 1% growth in our Non-EU volumes and a 5% increase in sales.</p>
          <p>Turning now to our logistics business, where our profits were up 4%, reflecting the great resilience of the business, given the economic and competitive environment. In Tobacco logistics, we offset the impact of significant volume declines in Spain by delivering strong performances in France and Italy, whilst driving cost efficiencies and benefiting from increased distribution fees. And in other logistics, we've been active in restructuring a number of the businesses during the year, which has resulted in stable sales, very pleasing results against the difficult backdrop.</p>
          <p>Let me now hand it over to Bob to take you through our results in more detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alison. And good morning, everyone. I'll start with an overview of the results.</p>
          <p>This table includes a reconciliation between reported and constant currency numbers. And I will be focusing on constant currency analysis in all of my comments.</p>
          <p>Tobacco net revenues were up 2% with positive price mix offsetting volume declines, whilst logistics distribution fees declined slightly. Tobacco adjusted operating profit increased by 1.3%, and Logistics adjusted operating profit was up 4%, giving combined growth at the Group level of 1.3%.</p>
          <p>After tax being charged at an effective rate of 24.3%, adjusted earnings per share grew by 5.4%. Results have as usual been adjusted and presented on our usual basis and details of the main differences are in the appendices.</p>
          <p>In the EU, the operating model continues to deliver. In the U.K., we maintained our market leadership, although volumes were down due to market softness following the VAT increase and excise tax changes in the budget. Sales and operating profits declined, impacted by the change in trade buying patterns. Excluding this factor, both sales and profits were up.</p>
          <p>We had a very strong performance in Germany. Profits grew 7% with volume growth, higher prices and higher margins all contributing.</p>
          <p>Profits in Spain declined 25%, in line with our recent guidance. We've recently increased prices across our portfolio, and all products are now priced at or above the levels at the start of the calendar year.</p>
          <p>We outperformed the market in our rest of EU region, with our stick equivalent volumes declining 1% against a regional market decline of 2%. Sales increased over 4%, and profits were up over 3%.</p>
          <p>In our non-EU markets, sales increased by over 5%, and we delivered excellent overall profit growth of 10%. In the Americas and principally the U.S., our profits declined 1%, reflecting stable cigarette share and unfavorable mix.</p>
          <p>Turning to the Rest of World region, volumes in Eastern Europe were broadly flat, but grew 2% excluding Balkan Star in Russia. And sales were up over 10%. Volumes in Asia-Pacific have been strong growing 5% and we've gained share in most of our key markets, with sales increasing 14%, an outstanding result. In Africa and the Middle East, we grew volumes and revenues, driven by a number of strong global and regional brand performances. Demand for our luxury Cuban cigars continues to grow in emerging markets, with volumes, sales and profits all increasing.</p>
          <p>Overall, we increased profits in our Rest of World region by 14% with profits in Eastern Europe, Asia-Pacific and Africa and Middle East regions growing by 21%, 27% and 8% respectively.</p>
          <p>Our average all-in cost of net debt rose slightly to 5.7% partly as a result of refinancing at higher rates and because a cash flow can only be used to repay the relatively low margin revolving credit facilities. The net interest charge fell almost &#xA3;40 million to &#xA3;562 million as a result of reduced debt levels, while our interest cover improved to 5.5 times, up from 5.1 times. And the appendices contain further details of our interest rate fixings and debt maturities.</p>
          <p>Turning to the financing of the business, our closing adjusted net debt for <mark type="indiscernible" /> (16:58) was &#xA3;8.8 billion. Working capital was stable year-on-year, a pleasing result, given the unwinding of the &#xA3;100 million Italian logistics benefit we had in 2010.</p>
          <p>Net capital expenditure increased by &#xA3;85 million as a result of greater investment in machinery to support our growth and innovation pipeline. And our cash conversion was 88%, another excellent result despite the increase in capital expenditure.</p>
          <p>Tax payments increased &#xA3;164 million, whilst interest payments were down, as we continued to reduce our debt. And the impact of foreign exchange movements was minimal.</p>
          <p>Following the acquisition of Altadis in 2008, the Group has actively paid-down debt and undertaken a series of bond issues. This has seen our maturity profile improved significantly. In June 2008, the profile was front-end loaded and heavily reliant on bank debt. But today, we're more weighted towards bonds, and the average maturity has increased from 3.1 years to 5.2 years.</p>
          <p>In December 2010, we refinanced a new &#xA3;2.5 billion five-year bank facility and issued two bonds with long dated in maturities. And we will continue to manage our maturity profile, further reducing refinancing risk.</p>
          <p>Guidance for our average cost of debt for the financial year 2012 is around 5.8%. Our tax rate will remain at around 24.5% and capital expenditure will remain slightly higher, reflecting our on going investment in capacity to meet demand in some of our growth segments and to continue building our innovation pipeline.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, we expect the EU consumer to remain focused on value and we are well placed to capitalize on this given our Total Tobacco portfolio. Outside the EU, we see opportunities across our portfolio, in value and in premium and above. And we will build on the excellent results we've delivered through Davidoff, Gauloises Blonde, West and our luxury Cuban cigar portfolio.</p>
          <p>So far this financial year, we've already raised prices in the U.K. and France, and we see a full year's benefit from price increases implemented last year in a number of markets, including Germany, Spain, the U.S.A, Russia and Taiwan.</p>
          <p>In the U.K., we expect moderate market volume declines and a continued trend towards value products, and the focus on reinforcing our position as market leader through various initiatives, including the national launch of Glide Tec Lambert &amp; Butler.</p>
          <p>In Spain, we expect market volumes to be down by a high single-digit percentage. And we'll continue driving the momentum of our value focused portfolio in cigarette, fine cut tobacco and cigar.</p>
          <p>In the U.S.A, whilst the market remains competitive. We've maintained our share and the integration of our cigarette and mass market cigar businesses will strengthen our position.</p>
          <p>And finally, in our logistics business, we'll continue to identify opportunities to grow the business whilst maintaining our cost discipline.</p>
          <p>So, thank you and I'll now hand it back to Alison to conclude the presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>These pleasing results highlight the growth momentum in the business and our strong platform for future success. Like any other business, we face economic challenges, but also the regulatory pressures prevalent in tobacco. But we have a strong track record of successfully managing these pressures, and we continue to fight disproportionate regulation.</p>
          <p>The economic environment remains uncertain in many markets, but tobacco is a resilient category and we're well placed with our total tobacco portfolio. We're realizing our top line potential through our focus on our four sales growth drivers. Through total tobacco, we have the portfolio to grow sales by meeting the needs of more consumers in more markets, on more consumption occasions, This has been key to our results in 2011. We are not just about cigarette, we're growing in fine cut tobacco, cigar and snus.</p>
          <p>We're positioned to capitalize on consumer value trends, while also driving growth in premium through Davidoff, Gauloises Blonde and luxury cigars. And as we get in even better understanding of consumers, we'll further develop our sales opportunities.</p>
          <p>Consumers are increasingly demanding value, quality and innovation and we're further developing our pipeline scalable innovations, based on consumer needs. Glide Tec is a great example of this, national roll-out in the U.K. is ongoing and we're finalizing plans to scale this exciting initiative in other markets, whilst progressing a number of other innovations to add to our sales growth potential.</p>
          <p>And pricing, a key component of revenue growth. We're enhancing the way we develop our pricing and excise strategies, focusing on our opportunities by brand, pack size and sales channel. Delivering excellence in customer engagement is critical to the success of our innovations as well as our other portfolio initiatives, and we're developing even stronger connections with our retail partners to maximize the advocacy and availability of our brands and products.</p>
          <p>The work that's been done over the past year in these four areas has been excellent, supported by great progress in deepening our consumer understanding, doing even better at joining up our sales operations with our sales agenda and proactively shaping our environment. This gives me real confidence in our ability to realize the full growth potential of our business.</p>
          <p>We've made strong progress this year with the continued focus on driving growth through our total tobacco portfolio. We've been alert to consumer dynamics enabling us to capitalize on both value seeking consumer trends in the EU as well as the growing demand for our global brands and products in non-EU emerging markets.</p>
          <p>Our margin performance and strong cash conversion demonstrates how we are reinforcing our costs and cash credentials. We'll continue to make disciplined investments to support our sales agenda including further M&amp;A, if it satisfies our strategic criteria and creates additional value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Imperial's DNA has always been strong in relation to our costs and cash disciplines, a great basis to which we've added our passion for sales growth. The positive momentum in the business is tangible. We are very focused on delivering sustainable returns for shareholders and I am excited by the growth opportunities that lie ahead for us in the coming year.</p>
          <p>Thank you. And we'll now take any questions you may have. As usual the presentation is being been recorded, so please wait for the mic and give your name and organization. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. Erik Bloomquist, Berenberg Bank. Two questions.</p>
          <p>One on the U.K., Imperial according to the tables at the back has lost share in both the U.K. cigarette and fine cut markets. What would be different in 2012 to reverse that?</p>
          <p>And then secondly on the U.S., it's been quite flat ever since the deal really. What's the outlook for that improving and is it simply a question of being up against much bigger opposition and not being able to do much or is there something that Imperial can do to influence its future in the United States? Thank You.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Erik. Let's kick off with the U.K.</p>
          <p>Our cigarette market share is down a couple of bps, but for me, we've talked about the U.K. before as being a balancing between profit and market share in the U.K. and largely that's driven by the impacts of timing of price increases and one  is different competitor price positions in the market. So I don't see that as any significant point for us. We've got a strong position in the U.K.</p>
          <p>The portfolio &#x2013; the economy end's performing very well and we're also looking to help in terms of the mix impact with L&amp;B with this Glide Tec initiative which we've been really pleased with. It's only in the selected number of outlets currently, were it has achieved about 0.2% of market, but if you scale it up, it's about 4% of market in the outlets were its available. As we scale it up across the U.K., I see some really good opportunities for the cigarette portfolio of the back of that initiative. So the cigarette &#x2013; the share for me in the U.K. is also all about how manage that U.K. business in terms of the profit share equation.</p>
          <p>The fine cut share it's been under pressure for a number of years because we have some fantastic margins and fantastic brands with Golden Virginia. But it's at the premium end of the market, that's where our portfolio is biased and the trend in the market is towards the value-end of the fine cut portfolio. We've put a number of initiatives into the market over the years including Gold Leaf. JPS Roll Your Own is really getting the momentum in the market and we'll keep pushing that. Make Your Own is going to be a slower bum because it's not a habit, that's a very familiar in the U.K. yet in terms of making your own cigarettes.</p>
          <p>We'll keep driving that with the trade in particular and advocacy with the trade. And we'll keep working on that share and we're looking to moving it in the right direction. The economy side is growing very well, but clearly we have to mitigate the premium losses but the margin on that is fantastic. So I think we're playing the game right in that area.</p>
          <p>On the U.S.A, we're still hanging in there at 3.9% share, and it does feel like that at times because it is very competitive. And you can see all the results recently in terms of Reynolds and Altria and the competitive situation in the market, and we are facing it times Marlborough at a discount to U.S.A. Gold, a lot of the time we are facing Marlborough at a discount to U.S.A. Gold. So, that's pretty good result given that sort of competition.</p>
          <p>We are still there for the reasons we were there in the first place. It will be a growing profit pool. We've seen price increases recently there. We are strengthening our business by integrating our cigar mass-market and cigarette operations. That's giving us much better critical mass with the trade, and we'll be taking that forward and pushing the benefits of that over the course of the coming year.</p>
          <p>But the premium cigar business is doing fantastically for us currently up 9% in a year, so it's again about playing the whole portfolio and not being solely focused on 3.9% cigarette share although clearly we are. We want it to grow. David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks. It's David Hayes form Nomura.</p>
          <p>Margin, second half, ex-Spain, <mark type="ph" /> if you make the (28:36) adjustments I think we're down. Is that indicative of a step-up in investment behind innovation and the sales growth strategy? Is that something we should look for carrying into 2012?</p>
          <p>And then the second question was just to clarify on the CapEx. Obviously as you made the point, you're investing there more. Is that &#xA3;340 million, &#xA3;350 million level we saw this year, the new level or will it go again in 2012, was that &#x2013; as that continues to be the strategy? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And you want to pick on CapEx and margins Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I thought I might get the numbers questions.</p>
          <p>In terms of margins, underlying margins are actually fairly strong. Okay, you said ex-Spain and I'm not sure to what place of decimal you're working, they maybe down a little. I'd point out the 150 basis point improvement in margin in Rest of World. We know the Spanish market.</p>
          <p>And to an extent, if we're looking at the U.K. margins, again to bring up &#x2013; to go to Alison's point on tempo, it's a question of timing on these things. We took a price increase in September in 2010, then there was a VAT increase, so, prices to the consumer went up in January. There was a budget increase. That led to some down trading and effectively because our price increases are in October, there's also been a pullout effectively at the gross margin level rather as we commented at the half year on U.K. So, I think the business from a margin perspective is in very good shape. And Alison commented on the number &#x2013; oh, I commented actually, on the number price moves that have already taken place. So the model is working and working well.</p>
          <p>In terms of CapEx, yes, we have upped the level at or about &#x2013; and we are still investing in terms of the pipeline. Our longer term cash conversion, if you're looking out to the longer term, we'd still say 90% to 100% type cash conversion longer term. But in the short-term, yes, we are investing behind our pipeline, and I think you can expect at or around that level or maybe even a little higher. But remember this is investment behind growth, and therefore, effectively, if I look at the payback of a fully loaded cigarette <mark type="ph" /> made (30:57) pack complex, its actually quite quick, and other people in other industries would call them consumables.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to highlight, David, I mean your margin question; I presume is more focused on where we are going, going forward with some of this as well rather necessary the last year. And if you look going forward, I mean clearly the U.K. is going to pick-up from where it was this year, we see the price increase we've just taken coming through.</p>
          <p>And also Spain, we are now back of pricing either the same level or be &#x2013; above where we were at the beginning of the calendar year. And also the U.S. will be picking up, and we'll have some integration benefits coming through there. So some of the areas where you do see margin softness in 2011 are clearly going to pick-up and improve and improve therefore the overall position for 2012 yeah. Jon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Jon Fell from Deutsche Bank.</p>
          <p>If I look at the list of market shares in cigarettes and fine cut you that have printed in the release. You are still losing share in more markets than you're gaining. So two questions from that really, if we stuck them all together and looked at total tobacco share, would the picture still be of overall loss or do you think you are holding your own in those terms?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, with regards to the new initiatives in sales and innovation, is it one of your ambitions to turn more of those volume market share figures into positive territory or is that the wrong way to look at stuff, should be still be much focused on overall revenue and profit growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Pick-up on the overall share first.</p>
          <p>The &#x2013; market shares, we've got a number of shares that are down are splits into two categories. There are the ones that have got the odd 0.2, 0.3 which you tend to see around timings of price increases, things go on in the market, which for me are just the noise in the market, in terms of ongoing regular competitor tactical activity. And I'd include the U.K. and I would include Germany in that as well, where we've had a good share trend in Germany, overall during the year, but clearly the timing of some of the recent price increases, has just tweaked that back a bit for the full year. So those are markets, which I think are part of the on going competitive position. And you don't need to really worry about those if you saw an ongoing deterioration in them.</p>
          <p>Then we've got some markets, where we have got some share challenges. I think the two key, ones there are Spain, which we probably talked until the cows come home about this year. We can talk about some more, but we are positioning our portfolio there to compensate for some of the pressures we've had on Fortuna historically. We've put Fortuna Red Line in which is responding well. We've got soft pack variants, which are responding well. We've got Nobel Queen Size all of those variance we've put into the market to address the share issues are showing some nice traction.</p>
          <p>We're still in a little bit of &#x2013; I would say market settling down post all the events of the summer and let's see how some of that plays out the coming months, but we're taking portfolio actions there to restore our share position.</p>
          <p>But again as you can see fine cut we have played very well in Spain with increases in volumes of <mark type="ph" /> Ducados (34:00) of 16%, I think a very good result. So we are playing the portfolio there, mass cigars also.</p>
          <p>We've got a number of shares, we're holding flat pretty well. Morocco is a lovely example of that. We're clearly post the end of the monopoly, you would expect there to be some pressure on our share, but actually we've had great growth in Gauloises. We're managing Marquise, the local brand very well. So we're doing a very good job there and holding share, maintaining profitability.</p>
          <p>And then we've got some really good results, in terms of share.  Australia for example I am delighted with in terms of its share performance over the last year, Ukraine similarly Taiwan, some nice share developments in a number of markets.</p>
          <p>Fine cut overall is growing &#x2013; we're growing slightly less than the overall growth in the fine cut market. That's absolutely no surprise to make as we've created the segments in a number of these markets and as we've created the segment in a number of the century European markets and they've been successful. We're also moving up profitability as well. We're bound to get competition and when you gave from a 100%, it's a bit difficult to grow from that point of profit going back was a little bit, but if we're building profitability that's good.</p>
          <p>Rogerio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Rogerio Fujimori, Credit Suisse. Could you give us a little bit more color on some of the &#x2013; for the outlook for some of the areas that held back volume performance recently Balkan Star in Russia, Syria and for Spain the guidance of high-single digits decline is primarily due to the lapping of the smoking ban in January? And the other question is in terms of the balance of the Altadis costs synergies left, how much do we still have for 2012? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Bob can pick up on the cost synergies in a minute. And I'll go through three your three optimistic questions around Balkan Star, Syria and Spain.</p>
          <p>Let's pick up on three negative. Balkan Star the story is very consistent with where it's been historically. We made the call for profitability in terms of Balkan Star probably the best part of the couple of years ago now, so we will continue to see that brand declining to some degree, I think it will lose another about 0.5 billion sticks, if I remember rightly in 2011 but Gerry will correct me &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; 1.5 &#x2013; missed a number out before the point, another 1.5 billion sticks in 2011, so that's &#x2013; that was the call we made and therefore we keep reporting against it.</p>
          <p>The rest of the portfolio in Russia and particularly where the margins really is in terms of Davidoff growth, which has been fantastic <mark type="ph" /> journey (36:20) up over the 33% in Russia. We're also growing West. We're growing Style and that means in terms of the money and the profits, you can see that coming through in the Eastern European performance and with profits up 21%. So, I think, it was a good call overall for the portfolio, but clearly the 1.5 billion sticks hits the numbers.</p>
          <p>Syria, clearly, no option, but sanctions and we would always fully comply with any sanctions in relation to market like Syria. And therefore we've had the impact of the duty free business coming through in terms of holding back volumes and some profit there as well, which we flagged. I think it was at the third quarter statement basically. So we'll continue managing that situation as you're well aware hasn't changed. So that will continue through into 2012.</p>
          <p>Spain the market was down roughly 13% in 2011, our predictions going into '12, I think, Bob mentioned, are that it will still be high single-digit, and that's still our best guess at the moment in terms of where the market is going. We'll continue to play the portfolio. We've got some price coming through now after the summer, lets see where we get to in terms of the overall business, but it's a better outlook going into 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, sorry &#x2013; the synergies number, effectively as I said at the half year, the one thing remaining to deliver the full synergies at the full &#x20AC;400 million of synergies of the Altadis integration were the &#x2013; is the closure of Berlin which is scheduled for &#x2013; effectively well its actually running down now, but it will be finally fully closed in May, June of next year as planned, that will deliver the synergies. Order of magnitude and you'll realize these have been baked into your numbers since I think 2008 when we first spoke about them so. Order of magnitude, there's about &#x20AC;50 million &#x2013; &#x20AC;40 million, &#x20AC;50 million coming through &#x2013; to come through in addition to what's in this year's numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Euros.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's euros, yes sorry, thank you about currencies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Toby, then pass it back to Jon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Toby McCullagh from Morgan Stanley.</p>
          <p>Just on the cost optimization you highlighted a 3% gain in FY '11. Is this beyond the Altadis synergies that are coming through? And perhaps can you just expand a little bit on what the main drivers are and if this is a sort of sustainable level that we should think about going forwards?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We highlighted I think the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (38:40) as an example really of the continuing focus on costs within the business. And given the &#x2013; we've had I think the manufacturing team has done fantastically in terms of the overall performance of manufacturing part of the business to still &#x2013; to be realizing the efficiencies through there. And Walter do you join to just comment a couple of seconds on the key initiatives to drive that 3% productivity improvement. Can we have a mic, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well. Sorry. Yeah. Good afternoon. I'm Walter Prinz. I'm Head of Manufacturing and R&amp;D.</p>
          <p>As Alison said the 3% productivity improvement was mainly driven of course through I would say machine efficiencies. We had the rightsizing of our factories. You heard from Bob, we are closing Berlin down. So we are in the middle of the reallocation of the production volumes.</p>
          <p>Complexity reduction was one of the key topics. So, blends down by 8% roughly. Ingredients, we reduced. So the SKU reduction program was very, very successful. On top of that I think the whole non-tobacco material costs we had very much under control. So there is a very big competition or we had a very big competition with all of our suppliers and the same applies for our leaf costs. So I think the leaf costs were very, very good for us this year. And I think overall the cost was quite significant reduced. So, these were more or less the key drivers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Walter. Jon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Jon Leinster, UBS. Few random questions, if I might.</p>
          <p>First of all, is there &#x2013; were there any &#x2013; at the end of the day after all the various price increases and declines in Spain, was there any actual stock profit or losses in that distribution business?</p>
          <p>Secondly, just following on from that comment there, what's the outlook in terms of cost, in terms of leaf and non-tobacco materials?</p>
          <p>And thirdly, &#x2013; following on really from David's question. Going back to the CapEx, obviously shutting Berlin, there is going to be some reinvestment there, but I mean, what exactly are you increasing spending on, is it new machines or is it &#x2013; are you actually building out right new factories or is it to run R&amp;D center?</p>
          <p>And lastly, I think Alison you made a brief comment at the end about M&amp;A potential, and I was just wondering whether there is anything &#x2013; out there which actually does fit those criteria as far as your concerned of any significance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine. Okay. Kick off with the Logista stock profit. I mean the stock profit in Logista is very much part of the model and has been for years, in that &#x2013; there's the ongoing distribution fees. But the arrangements always allow for stock profits in Logista. In fact, it's probably slightly wrong name. I think we tend to think about stock profits in the U.K. and other Central European markets historically around what was called forestalling, that was a terms of &#x2013; that was really quite &#x2013; this is not forestalling in that sense.</p>
          <p>This is basically buying at a certain price and then selling at a higher price, because there has been a shift in the meantime. So it's not just a retranslation of holding stock, for example. So, it's important to understand it's part of the business model, and we have to highlight during the years some of the impacts of the price decrease absolutely. But it's been a continuing part of the Logista business model for years. So there will be ups and down in any year around this and Louis and team manage it very successfully, usually ups though.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (42:38)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, still positive over the year, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's been positive over the year, and some of the reasons for the big swings actually, and I think the numbers would be bigger than they normally are, is because what happened in the Spanish market is on the way down and on the way back, quite a lot o &#x2013; and you have to understand Logista stock for the entire Spanish market, went down through the effectively the minimum incidence of tax. And therefore, all the way down, it was an entire excise. So rather than what we normally be stock profit on just, if you like an element of it within the entire tax absorption on the way down and bounce back on the way up. So it's &#x2013; the numbers will much more significant because of that in the current year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. On the cost point looking forward as Walter indicated the NTM inflation, non-tobacco material inflation was very much kept under control. Manufacturing delivered some significant improvements against our estimates at the beginning of the year, we went into the year on NTM. And that continues going forward in terms of the outlook.</p>
          <p>Leaf costs were a higher element in terms of inflation in the year just gone. We flagged to you the subsidiaries if you remember before. Those still run into 2012, but there will be lower overall leaf inflation impacting on 2012, again as we've highlighted previously.</p>
          <p>Capital, is a mixture of new machines. So behind the innovation, Glide Tec investment for example, Investment in formats, slims, king size, super slims, queen size. Investment in time, just in quality, to make sure we are on &#x2013; manufacturing to the right quality if machines are getting a bit old. And also factory, snus new factory in 2011 and clearly, other factory investments as appropriate. So it's a whole mix of things behind the growth agenda.</p>
          <p>Anything I missed out &#x2013; and income as well, yes that's very good point. The expansion capacity that we have. Our bespoke expansion technique, that is proving very successful for us in terms of Make Your Own and more putting more investment into that. Because that's a real consumer USP in terms of our Make Your Own products.</p>
          <p>Have I missed something John? Oh, M&amp;A, well I mean, Imperial and M&amp;A kind to go together and we have been doing it for years, so we think it's important not to lose it off the radar. We've talked frequently around the opportunities that are out there and we will continue to look at opportunities that make sense from a strategic criteria, but also from a financial criteria perspective and that's really unchanged.</p>
          <p>Nico? Sorry, down here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Three questions, could you give us a sense of directionally into fiscal '12 how you expect volumes to go? You say this year underlying was flat and pricing was 4%. You've given us indications that the U.K. and Spain should be better than this year, could we assume that overall volumes then should be better and pricing maybe some other levels? That's question one.</p>
          <p>Second question is, could you give us an indication what percentage of your global brands, Gauloises, West and JPS are other tobacco products. Because I see you, you show those on a stick equivalent basis. And would you ever launch Davidoff other tobacco products?</p>
          <p>And then a third question, there has always been the question is Habanos and Logista strategic could you maybe update us on your thoughts on that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. As a forecast for FY'12, I am not going to gave very granular because I am not going to do your forecast &#x2013; directionally. In terms of volumes, I mean clearly we've had some significant headwinds this year in terms of Spain for our overall volume, so we are expecting Spain to ameliorate next year.</p>
          <p>I would expect there to be a better volume environment next year therefore for Imperial but that's let's see how that plays out, but clearly our underlying volumes were flat this year. So that was a good performance in this environment and we always will be striving to do better but as I say not writing the forecast.</p>
          <p>On the top line similarly pricing we've had very strong opportunities to take &#x2013; for us to increase our prices over the recent months. And as Bob indicated we've already banked a number of price increases in a number of markets. So I think that's sets up very well in terms of the price dynamic for the top line. It gives me confidence in our delivery there in 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>These banked price increases &#x2013; sorry these banked price increases would they already give you a pricing for the full year ahead of what you achieved in fiscal '11. Could you give us indication on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of the top of my head no but they give us a very significant number already for 2012, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Prepare to give a little bit closer to that significant number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Quite straight forward there. Where do we go the next, was the OTP  percentage &#x2013; the percentage in terms of the volumes there from the specific brands I think I just have to get Gerry to get back to on the detail and I haven't got a top of my head I can do it on bits and pieces of the brands, but not specifically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that still very small and possible to grow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. Not in respect of JPS or West.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because they've been key brands for fine cut for years. Gauloises we're growing very nicely in fine cut at the moment. We've made some &#x2013; some I think it was around 9% growth in terms of our Gauloises fine cut volumes over the year as well. So we're building in Gauloises, which leads me nicely on to your question on Davidoff and I suspect not.</p>
          <p>And certainly had the odd person suggest we do a roll your own called Dave but I am not sure that's really going to fly. Roberto squirmed at that point, I think. So right, two more Habanos and Logista, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we've covered your questions. Habanos, I mean, I've looked to the performance of that &#x2013; that portfolio this year and it's very exciting to see how it moves forward. It does go through different channels. It has got a connoisseurship that potentially fits with Davidoff and but less so with some of our value brand portfolio. But it's a great relationship builder and it's performing exceptionally well. The progress in emerging market has being fantastic. So it's a good asset, very good asset and I &#x2013; we see the opportunities for it and driving it forward. So I am very pleased with Habanos business and its performance.</p>
          <p>Logista, again Louis and the team I mean if you  look at the environment you look at results for Logista this year, they have done a fantastic job with our business. It shows its resilience and the tobacco aspects of the business are coming through very strongly. I've always said in terms of the spectrum in terms of what's core and what's non-core to Imperial, it's going to sit down lower end to the spectrum but its doing very well for us and it's a great business. And it's performed very well for us in 2012 and '11 and to it's got good plans for 2012.</p>
          <p>Martin? I thought <mark type="ph" /> Grant (49:50) was going to ask a question then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Alison. It's Martin Deboo, Investec. Can I refer back to the investor seminar at, Runnymede. We had two very interesting presentations, Roberto and Arthur.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And a just value flavor from you or from Roberto and Arthur if they are here in terms of the progress you feel you're making on those plans. I am not  sort of expecting Rome to be built in a day, but I'd be interested in you take in terms of what's happening in terms of the organization, the way it's thinking about markets, trade channels et cetera, that will give us some indication that the culture and capabilities are evolving on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I actually will ask Roberto to comment in a second. I gave you few comments in the presentation around the four sales growth drivers that we talked to you about in Runnymede. Arthur actually isn't here today because he is doing some further work with the senior teams in the organization in terms of further taking that agenda that forward. But Roberto may give you a couple of comments on how the organization is being taken forward in relation to that agenda.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. For those I have not met yet, my name is Roberto Funari, Group Marketing Director. Yes, we have done tremendous progress on that. We are in the process of training the organization across the growth drivers and <mark type="ph" /> we want to see (51:10) the broader organization. So have a clear program on that. And we are on track with that program.</p>
          <p>We're also looking at already going for the phase of planning, but starting executing activities around the drivers. So the drivers are embedded in our planning and also embedded in the way we manage performance of the business. So that's one of the milestones we have set for ourselves, as well. So that is in place.</p>
          <p>In terms of how the organization has reacted to that, as part of Imperial culture, and that's probably one of the biggest trends of Imperial that is part of the intangible. The culture of the company is to embrace change and integrate new capabilities. And they took it as one of the challenges on that area, as part of a business that has been integrating a lot of companies and different type of business, is a very, very well prepared business to make changes and embed it in a very faster pace.</p>
          <p>In my experience, I have been quite amazing to see how fast this has been taken over by the organization. So it's not just a nice chart driven by the senior leadership team. It has been part already from the different organizations. It's part of the sales conferences and so forth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Roberto. And the piece that the Roberto has been also spending a lot of time in is our consumer insights piece, which &#x2013; a whole methodology around that in what we're doing is yielding some very interesting ideas for us to address going forward, both from an innovation perspective, portfolio perspective and also actually from a customer engagement perspective as well. So some interesting things going.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> Adam (53:07)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Can I ask a couple of questions? First of all following that up, this is a question for you Alison. When would you be &#x2013; well, we've just have the rollout or the announcement of rollout of Glide Tec. When would you hope to see another similarly important sort of new product that's really tangible, that we can get our hands around? And when I guess would you be &#x2013; so that's one question.</p>
          <p>Another question is can you be specific in terms of the numbers on the impact of &#x2013; in the U.K. on sales and profit of this change of the date of the price increase?</p>
          <p>And then finally, on fine cut versus cigarettes, obviously, and I suppose what I'm trying to find out is on a like-for-like, apples-to-apples basis, what is the relative profitability of fine cut versus cigarettes. And so I suppose what I'm thinking about, if you look at, let's say JPS in Germany, on a white stick equivalent basis, what's the relative profitability of fine cut JPS and factory made cigarettes? And I suppose, without getting into one brand, if I looked again at Gauloises Blonde in France or JPS in the U.K., so trying to get away from the geographic skew that these things have. Does that make sense?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Still not a simple answer, but it makes sense. [laughter]</p>
          <p>First of all, in terms of next innovation to get your hands around, and I'll get Roberto to note you need someone to add them in the post, okay? So you get hands around it. It will be during the course of the next financial year.</p>
          <p>So there will be things coming out and we've got a number of things in the pipeline. But remember, we didn't say that we are going to do lots and lots of bits and pieces. We said we were going to do a few scalable things that would deliver incremental volume, and but we do them in a big way.</p>
          <p>So it's not going to be, I am going to come up to every other week and go, oh, look here here's our new little pack here and this is what we're doing here. So I would just put it in that context. They're going to be things that we really do want to make something big of and not just lots of ideas.</p>
          <p>And we have actually subsequent to the Investor Day, we've launched &#x2013; it's like a round, plastic pack &#x2013; there's actually a display outside, &#x2013; no, there isn't &#x2013; that we're using. I think it's gone into Germany and Australia. I think we are using the JPS, which is again &#x2013; it's more like a I suppose the chewing gum type pack best to describe it as. I'll find you one. We will send you one that you can put your hands around.</p>
          <p>In the U.K., the trade volume patterns &#x2013; Bob, do you want to comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Order of magnitude, they will be close to what we were talking about last year, where we were talking around about order of magnitude 700 million sticks, in terms of volume. And I think we were talking about little more than 20 million then. I'd say it's a little higher, because obviously, we're working at new prices. Because those would have been pre the September last year price increase. So probably a little higher. Say 25, 30, order of magnitude.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>25 or 30 of sales or profit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Broad that was &#x2013; the 20 was the profit number. But don't forget, that was a gross margin, and it was therefore &#x2013; I think you have to &#x2013; you can cross reference a margin to the numbers I talked. But it's significantly higher than 60. Closer to 80 actually. So that was U.K.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then we got fine cut versus cigarette profitability. When Bob showed you some charts in Runnymede to give you the big picture view, clearly that does get clouded by geographies, when you're comparing a cigarette profitability that includes rest of world, for example, in that profitability, versus fine cut, which is largely EU biased. So &#x2013; but it gives you a feel therefore &#x2013; for the trade, which is what Bob was trying to do at the time. The trade-off between the two.</p>
          <p>If you look at the specific market, it is very specific to the market, is the next bit of the answer and that in some markets for example, in Central Europe, where we put some Make Your Own in, for example, as a sleeper to begin with. The profitability was absolutely lower than cigarette. But what we have done is we've built the position. These products have now got traction in the market. We've done what you would expect us to do, which is segment that bit of the market, put different brands in and build the profitability.</p>
          <p>And so, that's now moving up. Is it cigarette profitability yet? No. But it's moving very rapidly in that direction. Versus some brands in the market, it will be better.</p>
          <p>If you look at somewhere like the U.K. and we've said this for years, it's not a like-for-like brand because it's largely Roll Your Own in the U.K., which is different branding for something like a Golden Virginia. But even at the lower-price brands, you're looking at something that's very similar if not better in profitability than the value brands in the market. And similarly in Germany, you've got very good profitability in fine cut as well.</p>
          <p>So it does depend on the market specifics and the excise structure in those markets, as to what is the case market-by-market. So &#x2013; and you've got <mark type="indiscernible" /> (57:55) margins as well, which you mustn't forget, which is that lovely increment on the margin on the chart that Bob presented at Runnymede.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I came back to make it more specific about U.K and Germany <mark type="indiscernible" /> (58:10)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I have to look at other assumptions in the mix. But in Germany and U.K., it's so profitable in those segments, you'd probably be there or thereabouts in terms of profitability. But then you'd have to get into the granularity of Route 66 and JPS, which <mark type="ph" /> products is in in relation to the swing into (58:31) but it's high profitability in fine cut in those markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. It's Fulvio Cazzol from Goldman Sachs. Just a couple of questions.</p>
          <p>Firstly, if you can give us an update on the situation in Australia with the fine packaging situation then?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, last year, you signed the cooperation agreement with the EU to fight illicit trade. Can you give us an update of what trends you're seeing recently on illicit trade in the European market? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll ask Matt to answer on the questions, maybe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good mooring. Matthew Phillips, the Corporate and Legal Affairs Director, and I'll try and answer both.  I didn't see where the question came from.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's there, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Australia is in a similar state to the presentation I gave back in June/July time, in the sense that government is still trying to bring in legislation for the 1st of January, and with the sell-through period from the 1 of July.</p>
          <p>What's happened in the last 48 hours is there was supposed to be a vote in the Australian Senate, which is the higher second parliament &#x2013; second layer of parliament. And the Federal government were expecting that to go through on the nod, and basically it didn't. And so they've now got a bit of a headache, because they've got 15 days between now and the end of the year, in order to get this passed, and the senate haven't got space on their agenda to actually &#x2013; to actually try and pass it.</p>
          <p>So whether they are going to get force it on, whether they are going be able to kick out one of the other things that they are desperately trying to manage at the moment, we'll have to wait and see. But the government are making more and more noises about the need to delay the implementation. So we'll have to see how it actually transpires.</p>
          <p>Illicit trade &#x2013; I would &#x2013; the big shift is into these things called <mark type="ph" /> illicit whites (60:47) and counterfeit. It's not the contraband. It's not our products that are the areas that are of concern. Of course, that's one of the reasons that we wanted to sign this agreement with the EU is actually to try and act in partnership with governments to try and tackle counterfeit. So I would say that &#x2013; taking the U.K., for example. Of the level of seizures that have been made, 95%, 96%, 97% of them are &#x2013; maybe even higher, maybe 98% &#x2013; are illicit whites and counterfeit products, to give you some kind of framing of the scale of it.</p>
          <p>But it is fair to say, off the back of the excise hikes that we've been seeing in various countries, illicit trade is starting to sneak up, but it's really difficult to measure as you'll appreciate. But we are starting to see, for example, the U.K. level starting to rise slightly. Spanish level starting to rise slightly. Which is just purely a combination of price, effectively. And these counterfeits and illicit whites are very, very cheap in the markets.</p>
          <p>So I don't know if that gives you enough of a flavor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But it's something we clearly very active in. I mean it's nice &#x2013; I think the example of Ireland we talked about in July. Where actually focusing with the government on excise and regulation things they are doing, we've actually seen a slight decrease in Ireland in terms of illicit trade which has been good.</p>
          <p>But I think it's also important and almost back to the questions around fine cut, that we also have value portfolios in markets for consumers. I think one of the dynamics in Spain has been that the consumer's seeking value who's been able to go into products like Ducados Rubio, which has been great for protecting the legal market, as well.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> David (62:48)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just got up quick on that trading point. In terms of sort of a view as to whether it's obviously going to move slower than the government hoped <mark type="indiscernible" /> (62:54) Is it going to be delayed? Is it going to be amended I guess is the other element? I mean is there anything that you'd say has changed since you spoke in June, over the last few weeks, as to what the outcome might actually be? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not really. The &#x2013; I mean the government have clearly made a number of concessions to their starting point. So they've backed-off no markings on cigarettes themselves. And there is a load of things that they've actually conceded, now that they realized actually what it is that they are trying to do. I think when they first started, they perhaps weren't aware of some of the knock-ons of some of these sorts of things.</p>
          <p>And it's really difficult to call, because as I said to you in July, ultimately this is a politically driven issue, and the governments are very determined to try and bring something in at the beginning of January next year.</p>
          <p>But as you know, there are legal complications associated with what they're trying to do. And I think tobacco manufacturers have been clear that there will be domestic challenges within Australia. And there are also issues, as I spoke about previously, at the WTO level, in terms of the views of other countries with what Australia are trying to do.</p>
          <p>So it's still in the same sorts of areas I spoke about previously. It's uncertain. And to answer another question, we can't actually start bringing legal challenges until this thing becomes law. So it's got to go through the Australian legislative process before we take any further steps.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we'll continue to fight, and we'll continue to work on plan B, which is very exciting.</p>
          <p>One more, Nico, and I think I'm probably going to have to do the other urgent ones first and wrap up soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Alison. Just a question with regards to the cost of competing and driving the sales line.</p>
          <p>Would it be an unfair assumption to think that your CapEx &#x2013; it was &#xA3;260 million, &#xA3;340 million this year &#x2013; that will be somewhere just over &#xA3;400 million next year? And actually remain at the higher level? Because if there is another big innovation, that would assume there is more CapEx related to that. So is it a totally unrealistic assumption to think the CapEx level will remain higher going forward?</p>
          <p>And then if you could maybe also comment with regards to competing on the ground. I see that your selling and distribution costs were actually flat year-on-year. Is that all related to efficiencies and underlying actually having to spend little bit more money? If you could -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fine. I mean in terms of capital expenditure, I'm not expecting to it to suddenly accelerate to above the 400 million level. And we were around, yeah around the 350 million, maybe in the 350 million to 400 million range for next year. But we are putting a chunk of money behind some of the capital investment we need for growth. And that will, as Bob indicates, meet our usual payback and views on what we need to do, to make sure that delivers in terms of the returns.</p>
          <p>So I'm not going to predict it's going to go 400 million and above, and maintain at that level. But we will make selective investments behind the things that we think we need to drive the growth agenda, and we won't hold back on that.</p>
          <p>We've actually also made investments this year actually on giving ourselves more flexibility. So for example, on reducing lead times, we used to work on much longer lead times, and <mark type="ph" /> Helen (66:49) and Walter, the manufacturing supply chain teams, have come up with some fantastic initiatives to mean we've got very short lead times on machines now.</p>
          <p>Now that's involved a little bit of our front investment. That's going to be a one-off. It's not going to repeat. Because we've now got the mechanism we need to achieve that, for example, which is what would give me confidence in it not keeping on ranking up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It should step down in 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Potentially so. But I think we'll be transparent about initiatives we see, and the progress of it. But I can't see it going up above the 400 million level.</p>
          <p>It's taken a step up this year around that 350 million to 200 million range for next year. But we've also had factory build in that as well. So it's not just about machinery, and we always have factory builds going on, so -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (67:30)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (67:32). Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then sales distribution, the cost -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sales distribution, I mean, as a specific cost, I mean we're investing in the business. I think that's what we have been trying to talk about.</p>
          <p>So you can pick on different aspects of investment. We will allocate that investment as appropriate, whether it be A&amp;P, whether it be sales and distribution, whether it be capital expenditure, which we talked about a bit this morning. Whether it be actually into things that you don't really see like costs more to produce the superslims than it does to produce a king size, or whatever it happens to be in terms of the packaging you use and everything else.</p>
          <p>All of that would be factored in, in terms of the investment we're putting behind the growth agenda. And we'll continue to do so, so in that that we've invested more in the business in 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more burning questions?  Are we done. Thank you everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>