<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1135607" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2007 Earnings Call - US Presentation</title>
    <date>2008-02-20</date>
    <companies>
      <company>613</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Gemma Bucks,</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John C.R. Hele, Executive Board Member and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Farooq Hanif</participant>
      <participant id="4">John Hele</participant>
      <participant id="5">Koos Timmermans</participant>
      <participant id="6">Chris Hitchings</participant>
      <participant id="7">William Elderkin</participant>
      <participant id="8">Tom McInerney</participant>
      <participant id="9">Bruno Paulson</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to the ING Q4 Results 2007 and Embedded Value Presentation Conference Call. Throughout today's recorded presentation, all participants will be in a listen-only mode. After the presentation, there will be an opportunity to ask questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>I would now like to hand the conference over to Ms. Gemma Bucks. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Gemma Bucks for ING Groep, welcoming you to ING's U.S. Investor and Embedded Value Presentation Conference Call. Before turning this over to John Hele, Chief Financial Officer; and Koos Timmermans, Chief Risk Officer, let me first say that any forward-looking statements in today's comments are subject to a number of variables, they include interest rates, foreign exchange rates, inflation rates, movements in securities markets, including equity markets and underlying economic health and changes. The realization of forward-looking statements could be materially altered by unexpected movements in any or all of these and other variables.</p>
          <p>That said, John and Koos over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon in Europe and good morning still in the Americas, I would like to welcome you to the embedded value call as well as general call with analysts, here in the afternoon. In addition to Koos Timmermans with us today, who is the Chief Risk Officer of ING Groep; we also have Tom McInerney on the line, the Executive Board Member responsible for the Insurance Americas.</p>
          <p>We have a short presentation to walk through; first, just to give some key points and highlights on the embedded value. On page 3 of that presentation has the key points and the first point is that the embedded value is 32.5 billion, before dividends up 17% from 2006.</p>
          <p>Our group embedded value where we take the life insurance embedded value and make a few adjustments to move from statutory accounting to IFRS accounting, and then add the book values for our banking and asset management and non life businesses is 21.19 per share up 6% from 2006.</p>
          <p>Our value of new business in 2007 increased 38% over 2006, which is a very significant increase and we were 1.1 billion euros in value. The VNB was up in all regions with Central Europe and the Americas showing the largest increase. Developing markets delivered 61% of the group value of new business.</p>
          <p>The embedded value profit was up 41% and the return on embedded value up 97%. This was of course driven by high VNB and positive operational variances. The higher return on embedded value was driven by the EV profit and favorable impact of economic assumption and discount rate changes. Importantly though the assumptions that we use is tied and much more aligned to market rates and the positive return on embedded value came from all the different drivers and across all regions.</p>
          <p>You can see this graphically on slide 4, where we show from 2004 to 2007, the build up of our value of new business, so we've come from a level of 600 million now to 1.1 billion and you can see the growth across the board in all the different business lines.</p>
          <p>In particular, we had a large increase in the Romanian second-pillar pension fund and that's been a real addition for this year. Nevertheless even excluding that, we've had a very good increase in value of new business from 2006.</p>
          <p>At constant FX rates on slide 5, you can see the quarterly progression and we have adjusted the Q4 number for the change in the discount rate, so you can see a more comparable pattern across the board.</p>
          <p>As you look at slide number 6, this is the developing markets, delivered the 61%, and I think importantly to point out is that the U.S. value of new business was up 48% from 2006, thanks to much better sales in the life insurance business and getting the statutory reserves modified and also with their new variable annuity product that is doing extremely well in the second half of 2007.</p>
          <p>The embedded value on page 7, as I said earlier, is up 17% before dividends. We have paid a large dividend of excess capital out of the insurance entities up to Group, so the embedded value at year end is 26 &#x2013; 27 billion euros. But nevertheless, this is really a dramatic increase and you can see the major components and sources of that.</p>
          <p>On slide 8, you can see the historical view of EV profit. EV profit is a key measure that we use across the Group and is actually in the <mark type="audio gap" /> accounts across the Group. The continuation of EV profit, you can see solid progression.</p>
          <p>On slide 9, you can see the Group embedded value and the important number I think that people need is the adjustments for embedded value and this is a &#x2013; and we list the components of it to get there, and we are at &#x2013; ending the year in quite good shape, 21.19 per share.</p>
          <p>We show on the next slide just to give you a comparison, an easy reference point to where the key assumptions were for interest rates and discount rates for our embedded value in 2006; the 2007 calculations which we set in the middle of the year and then also with the most recent implied risk free rates at that time. So there are slight differences as the markets move around. But in general, we are pretty close to where we were. For your ease of reference, we have given you the sensitivities across the board here for the changes in interest rates, for each of the currency zones and that's on slide 10 and 11. So if you want to make any slight adjustments, you're welcome to do so.</p>
          <p>On slide12, we have the waterfall effect showing the major components of moving the total Group embedded value, what we consider to be an EV profit and the major changes across the board with some explanations.</p>
          <p>We then on slide 13 give it for insurance Europe, and you can see VNB increase from 219 to 400 million euros, a very dramatic increase. We also, in the EV profit, had the investment performance on equity and real estate gains that was helped by the ABN AMRO and Numico extraordinary capital gains that we received this year. But there are many other positive contributors here, both with lower lapse and maturity rates and some refinements to the economic assumptions and discount rates.</p>
          <p>On slide 14, in the Americas, you can see the value of new business had been 270 million and large contributions from Life and Wealth Management as well with 271. These have all been in the EV profit for the year of almost 500 million euros.  And what has made a major impact of course in Insurance Americas taking a billion off of the embedded value was strengthening of the euro against the Americas' currencies. So I think given this is still up, quite dramatically it's really a testament to the strong results that have happened and in addition to the pension fund being acquired and Latin America added 497 million of embedded value.</p>
          <p>Turning to Asia/Pacific, again 442 million, one of the largest single contributors to VNB, and along with some other positive points and some slight model changes in Taiwan and Korea reduced the number to 1.9 billion. We show for you and highlight for you the sensitivities to embedded value and combination of increasing and lower interest rates. We also show 1% change in long-term assumptions for equity and real-estate returns and immediate fall in the market values of equity and real estate. And we have had some adjustments since year-end in this.</p>
          <p>But this is a global change in all markets in the world. So although some markets are down, they are not all down at this level. So you have to do the calculations around the world as to where you think it's going to end up. But we give the sensitivity by each major line of business.</p>
          <p>On the VNB, the VNB sensitivities are on page 17, where we show the various points there.</p>
          <p>So in summary, we are quite pleased with our embedded value performance this year and our life insurance businesses, we think they are up solidly. They are contributing solid value to our overall group. Our sales are very strong, we have good returns, good IRRs across the board now, in all of our major lines of business. And we see a solid value of new business contribution. And also our management worldwide in addition to new sales is really focused on the growth of the entire book. And you can see that being reflected in a very solid embedded value profit and a return on embedded value.</p>
          <p>With that, we will be &#x2013; Koos, Tom and myself will be pleased to take questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator instructions" />. Thank you. Our first question comes from Mr. Farooq Hanif with Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello again, this is Farooq Hanif from Morgan Stanley. I had a couple of questions actually. Firstly, the Romanian pension business; when work out the margin, it's huge, it's about, I think 163% or something like that on the Q4 numbers. That just seems really, really high and I was just wondering why it's so high? Is it because you are assuming that customers make extra increments in future? Is it because there is a longevity assumption? Are they kind of reincarnating or something? That's question number one.</p>
          <p>And question number two is, in Taiwan, you've had some pretty good, some overall numbers for a while now, for a few quarters, you are happy with your new business profits. I think you made a comment already about the reserve adequacy in Taiwan going up and you've lessened your criteria for what reserve adequacy you kind of need in Asia as a whole. When we are going to see IFRS profits coming through in Taiwan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, your first question on the Romanian business, it's recorded as an annual premium business because, of course, we sign people up and they are going to be paying us deposits for the next forty, for the next thirty years or so. So, the net present value of that is pretty good business. We now have 9 billion in assets in Poland from this type of business that we signed up many years ago. So, the ratios are &#x2013; if you look at VNB over APE, it's quite high. If you look at it, in terms of the present value of premiums, which we published on page 15 as embedded value report for Central Europe and Spain, it makes a more sensible ratio because we're locking such a very long business here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry to interrupt you, may I just ask what longevity you're assuming in approximately, the duration of a customer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's around 20, the duration will probably be close to 20 or 15, 15 to 20 in terms of, sort of measurement because the net present value of duration changes. It's very long. The people are young and they've all signed up for these pension programs generally. It's around for a long period of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the Taiwan business, well, the VNB is extremely attractive right now in Taiwan. The rates are set by the regulators there and so we're very pleased and we're becoming more productive with our sales force and our business there, I think that we have a policy, which we have published in terms of the reserve adequacy and when we would start to see some profits there. We'd want the reserve adequacy to be over 70% ending the year and then we could start to see some profits to be released in the next year. We did not end above 70% at year-end, so we will not have profits in 2008. But that will be an annual thing that we look at year-by-year. This is a very long tail business and the in-force book takes sometime. So, the VNB is helpful to it but it's going to take some time to recover from that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But I thought that in Asia/Pacific that the adequacy was sort of 70% overall, wasn't it and?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, for Asia/Pacific but not for Taiwan yet. The test for profits in Taiwan are at a business unit level not at a Asia/Pacific level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then what is the number for Taiwan for reserve adequacy on the similar basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Close to that number where the reserve adequacy was at the end of the year &#x2013; for Taiwan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The Taiwan number at the 50% or at the 70%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what was the number? I think it was around 60. But I can double check that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I don't have it here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's definitely not 70, because otherwise we'd be doing some profit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you mean it's just a bit below...so it's improved.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it did. It's definitely improved. It's not near the 50.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It just seems to me that Taiwan and Japan are the two areas that have been already low or lower than we all thought in Asia but could be an upswing and I am just kind of wondering what....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Japan it's highly volatile, as you can see, quarter-by-quarter depending upon the volatilities and the hedging and it's been very volatile of course for the world markets particularly, in some of the funds both currencies and interest rates and equities. So, we've had all three areas really affecting Japan. And Taiwan, well, is a long-term issue before we ever get to our profits there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The reserve adequacy was just below 70%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, if we have kind of a positive yield curve situation, I guess then there is a good chance you might see something in 2009, but that's a big "if"?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the Taiwanese market is very tricky; there is currency controls and it does not follow the normal market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's true.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so you just have to wait and see how that develops with the country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Farooq.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Thank you our next question comes from Mr. Chris Hitchings, Please state your company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's Chris Hitchings from KBW and hello again. Can you take tell a little bit more on these model changes. There seems to be a very large positive in the Netherlands and negatives almost everywhere else. And you described it as sort of truing up target asset mix at Nat-Ned. It just seems a very large number for something which, yes just a little bit more outlook on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure, the insurance Europe model changes of 642 million is basically all from Nationale-Nederlanden and it was an asset mix change of assumptions, where we change the business of the total assets side for matching the liabilities. So not just for the capital and surplus but lending a mix of equities, real estate and private equity, which is essentially how we have been managing the business but adapting it for the entire business and for the longer term liabilities and we want to put that through as a model change versus as a financial variance in the group to not have that artificially going to embedded value profit.</p>
          <p>The other ones that were negative in particular in Asia/Pacific is the change to greenfields, where we don't penalize the VNB for greenfield start ups anymore and that got moved to the embedded value and some model changes in Korea and Taiwan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see, so just again, just try, and I'm probably seeming terribly stupid here, but 682 in Netherlands reflects the change in the asset mix, i.e. the reduction in equities. Is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it actually reflects a change in our asset mix that backs the liabilities. The equities that we dividend out from the Netherlands were all backing mainly free surplus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Europe there's a large free surplus starting the year and 5.5 billion of it is dividended out. So this is an asset change that affects the entire asset mix, where we assume, and we have actually changed now the asset mix after a long study of the optimal asset mix, to back these liabilities, which is a blend of corporate bonds, government bonds and allocation to equities, real estate and private equity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So what's the significant asset change that you have made in Nat-Ned. I mean, is it the reduction in equities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was a slightly higher allocation to real estate and some to equities, including private equities, I think it moved up by about 5%, and that kicks out in net present value, because you get assumed higher margins under this style of embedded value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, I see, so, all right, so it's a riskier asset mix that's giving you higher margins which spews out &#x2013; or projected higher margins you hope...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And it spews out as instant profit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's how it works under this form of embedded value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Wow &#x2013; perhaps you could do that in Taiwan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I wish, I could! But we base these assumptions on reality.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, that's all, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, our next question comes from Mr. William Elderkin. Please state your company name followed by your question</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon everyone. It's William Elderkin from Citi. Three questions please. First of all, could you explain in more detail what's being, why you have been doing so well with the U.S. variable annuity sales, you mentioned this morning you had some more, more wholesale, could you talk a little bit more about the product and so on?</p>
          <p>The second question was, could you give us the EV sensitivity for Taiwan if you assume that bond yields remain at their current level as oppose to trending up, I think to 3.9% or so, is what's assumed?</p>
          <p>And then finally with the Dutch life business having taken out very much reduced to free surplus, I just wonder what the impacts or implication of that was for the Dutch life segments IFRS earnings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, that's great. The first question, I would like to turn over Tom McInerney, who will explain our great success in the U.S. variable annuity business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John. And, William, I would say that we have a very good mix of products, in particular we launched a new withdrawal benefit, LifePay Plus that has been quite successful in the marketplace. So I think it's the combination of having a broader way of products both living benefit products and withdrawal benefit products.</p>
          <p>And we did &#x2013; we have been adding to our wholesaler group for the last couple of years. In 2007, we added 18 wholesalers that I think brings us up to 125 wholesalers. So it's the combination of having good, broad products and increased distribution capacity. It was the driver on the VA side.  And I am very pleased with, both the growth sales, as well as the net flows on the VA side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, William your second question on the EV sensitivities. On page 28 of the embedded value report, you can see a &#x2013; the decrease in new money rates, and it depends whether you wanted the discount rate as well, so we give you the combination of those two as well at the bottom.</p>
          <p>And for a 100 basis points even reduction across the board it's minus 978 million euros, but this would not be &#x2013; you want to flatten it out, so I suggest you interpolate, sort of, between the two. Current rates were about &#x2013; swap rates about 2.6%, 2.55% today in Taiwan. So it's about 100, but on the long end, and the way we do this modeling it takes 20, 30 years before you ever get to that rate. So it would probably far &#x2013; it would be less than half of that amount, I would estimate. We didn't run that, but its &#x2013; you're going to be in that ballpark because it takes so long to surpass the testing to get out there.</p>
          <p>Your last question on the impact of the dividends from Nationale-Nederlanden and the impact of the Dutch life business that will be a reduction in earnings compared to the earlier part of '07 of 250 million a year pre-tax.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just that, just kind of coming from that one, I think you mentioned in the third quarter stage that the Dutch, the third quarter life profit, was a more realistic run rate. And &#x2013; is the movement within the free surplus already excluded from that by the time we got to the third quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A piece of it was because we paid a 1.7 dividend in the &#x2013; at the end of June as the total of 5.5 taken out. So it's, just go in the ratio in my head here, so it's, you know, maybe another 175 lower from rate per year, pre-tax.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So is that &#x2013; so somewhere between third and fourth quarter a reasonable sort of basis for thinking about the earnings level for '08 and beyond?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just look at the third quarter...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The underlying &#x2013; it was 136 in the third quarter, I think, and 192 in the fourth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Life insurance there was 129 in the third quarter and 165 in the fourth quarter, so you definitely in that ballpark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from Mr. Bruno Paulson. Please state your company name followed by your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. This is Bruno Paulson, Sanford Bernstein [Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co.]. Three questions; firstly, given that we are now seemingly within a whisker of turning the Taiwan IFRS switch, what would the earnings have been in 2007? I know there about 38 million in Q1.</p>
          <p>Second question is, obviously we saw this downward rebasing of the Dutch IFRS earnings as the asset gains have come out. In the U.S., are we at sort of normal earnings levels? Or how far are we from the normal earnings levels from things like private equity and unusually low, other than this quarter, bond losses?</p>
          <p>And finally, Mr. Timmermans was saying there is a main risk he saw as to earnings was from equities moving. Can you give us some guidance as to the sensitivity of IFRS earnings to say, a 10% move in equity prices? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I'd &#x2013; I had it on mute. The first question is on Taiwan regarding on how much the amount was that we put away into reserves in the year. I just have to look that up for you and get back to you, so we will &#x2013; I'll come back on that question. The assets point I am going to ask, maybe, perhaps if Tom can answer that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You want me to talk about the normal earnings flows? Is that &#x2013; in the U.S.? Is that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I was just, I mean, we've had the unpleasant surprise in the Netherlands so I was just &#x2013; wondering what kind of unpleasant -- whether there has been private equity or other earnings boosting the U.S. numbers as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I guess what I would say, first of all, in terms of looking at underlying earnings, I think the best page is probably in the U.S. statistical supplement, page 7, which lays out the earnings by the key businesses over a quarter. So I think, obviously in the fourth quarter of '07 we had &#x2013; the S&amp;P 500 was down about 4%; it was up about 6% in the fourth quarter of '06.  So there was a sort of 10% swing that obviously had an impact in retirement services and the variable annuity businesses.</p>
          <p>And on the fixed annuity we did &#x2013; we have a accounting/economic mismatch between our indexed annuities and while, obviously, in the current environment those are &#x2013; we are not really selling a lot of those products, but they do have a  swing and I think there was about, quarter-over-quarter, fourth quarter '06 to fourth quarter '07, there was about a 60 million swing in terms of the accounting and the economics, because of the &#x2013; how the accounting on the hedges work versus the economics.</p>
          <p>So I think you got to take that &#x2013; those noise out.  But I think if you look at those quarters, on average, if you took the earnings and eight &#x2013; cumulative for those eight quarters divided by eight, that would probably give you a decent normal &#x2013; normalized picture, I mean there are pluses and minus obviously as the equity markets go up and down.</p>
          <p>And then I guess the other, just to give you a rule of thumb, there can be other things that could factor into this in terms of where interest rates, but for a &#x2013; in the U.S. business, for a 10% drop in the equity markets that occurred on &#x2013; at the beginning of the year, you know, down 10% and then we grew at sort of our long-term assumptions, which is that the index, the S&amp;P will grow at 7.5% and a 1.5% dividend yield, you have about &#x2013; in Euros about a 200 million reduction in earnings on the U.S business overall, principally focused on the wealth management businesses, retirement services, and variable annuity. We'd have about 30 to 35 million for reduction in fee income, lower assets times the fees, about 100 million for DAC unlocking because, as you know, we don't do mean reversion or quarter effect like most of our competitors. We are actually looking at that, but at this point we do full unlocking, so that would be about 100 million of the 200.</p>
          <p>And then the balance would be, so call it, 50, 75 million euros would be for the collateral impact you would have in that kind of an equity market for things like alternative investments, private equity, etcetera.  So that's sort of a rough rule of thumb.  Obviously there can be other factors that could move that up or down, but I think it gives you a pretty good sense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bruno, on your first question regarding the Taiwan, we put about 140 million of earnings into reserves last year, and -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's pre-tax earnings?  Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pre-tax, pre-tax, and that's the max you could think of, because once we are at and above 70, we would release earnings to the extent it doesn't make the reserve inadequacy more.  So it will be a piece of that. Of course, as it develops, and as it gets better and moving above 70, we would issue more earnings, so it would be a ratio between zero and, you know, in the range of 100 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the U.S. guidance on the impact of the 10% equity fall is very handy.  Is there any guidance anywhere else in the &#x2013; I presume it's mainly the insurance businesses, but the insurance businesses about the impact of the 10% equity fall?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it is a little complex because you've got various offsetting items across the board here.  But we do have some basic rules of thumb in terms of earnings at risk from our risk dashboard that we published last September on our Investor Day.  Koos?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, maybe I can add, like the European &#x2013; the nature of the European exposure is slightly different, because there we have the direct investments.  If we look at the European portfolio, there is approximately 8 billion of equities in there, so a 10% move would have an 800 million value loss, but not an earnings loss because then we talk about the unrealized buffers which we have in there.  But the European business, there we don't have a similar magnitude of the fee income exposure like in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the U.S. is our largest single sensitivity to this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are there any more questions from anyone on the call?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  We have a follow-up question from Mr. Farooq Hanif.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.  I just thought I'd ask another question, I'm very sorry to ask so many.  On a similar subject to Bruno's theme, in Japan, obviously we &#x2013; you had negative earnings, and partly that was because of, you mentioned the CDOs, partly the volatility, and the new business margins are also down in Japan.  I was wondering if you could just explain what conditions, so what maybe kind of level of percentile volatility has to go to for you to get to your new business margin assumption?  And what really needs to happen for the situation in Japan to sort of improve on an IFRS basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there are two main businesses in Japan, the SPVA business and the COLI business and both have interesting times from time to time.  So let's first start talk about the IFRS earnings, which year on year had a pretty large swing, the underlying profit before tax for the whole Japanese business from '06 was 156, and then was 24 in '07, and that swing mainly was caused by the SPVA business due to the massive change in volatilities, as well as tracking error from the hedging program versus the underlying funds.  Now, we are taking steps to improve this, and the new product we have in Japan, the new SPVA product in Japan, has a much better tracking of the underlying funds to our hedging programs.  But we have an in-force book that is still somewhat volatile, and the volatilities in the fourth quarter were very high in many different types of funds that we have.  So, those hurt the hedging program.</p>
          <p>At the same time with the COLI business, which has been steady in terms of earnings with the exception of this quarter when we had the loss on the asset, which caused a negative point, but the overall business in COLI from a profit point of view is quite stable.  The sales in COLI have been down because of uncertainty under the tax code.  They are now back up again actually in early '08 as the tax law gets changed and modified.  So, there's a bit of sales going on right now in COLI.</p>
          <p>The SPVA business had sales reduced starting in the fourth quarter last year.  The government passed a new law of disclosures for all types of financial products, that includes mutual funds, stocks, variable annuities, and that's really slowed down sales across for the industry.  We still have #2 in terms of market share in Japan in the fourth quarter, but the overall level was down compared to the third quarter.  We sold single premiums of &#x20AC;1.2 billion in the third quarter, 700 million in the fourth quarter.  But we believe this business will give us the &#x2013; through the cycle, an appropriate return. And the COLI business, we're quite well positioned for the coming tax law in terms of how it's going to perform, and we think we have a solid position there.</p>
          <p>The guidance on the profits in Japan are volatile and will continue to be volatile, but they will average out over time. These contracts are 10 years in length, and our guidance was in terms of assets about a 30 basis points pre-tax margin, we expect on these variable annuities through the cycle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on the new business margin, I mean what &#x2013; I think volatility has got to &#x2013; has gone up &#x2013; spiked up to sort of a 99th percentile or something, and I was wondering what it has to come back to, to get to your assumptions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We actually factor in the VNB of higher hedging costs due to lower interest rates, which is sensitive to it on higher volatilities.  So, we adjust the VNB each quarter for it, so that that was a major impact in it.  And also the COLI business, selling less, had some acquisition expense overruns in the quarter, and so those get deducted right off the point.  So, those two, the lower COLI sales and the higher hedge costs, were the major change in terms of the reduction in VNB.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the second half margin basically gives you an indication of current &#x2013; yeah, okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have no further questions at this point.  Please continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on behalf of the entire Executive Board and Tom McInerney and Koos Timmermans and myself, we'd like to thank you for calling in and listening this afternoon after a long day of disclosures.  We hope we've clarified our positions and the strength of ING Groep in these turbulent times, but we will continue to execute our strategy as planned.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that concludes today's conference call.  Thanks for participating.  You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>