<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1514584" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-11-07</date>
    <companies>
      <company>613</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman-Executive Board &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Johannes Henricus Hommen</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Michael van Wegen</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Risk Officer &amp; Member-Executive Board">Wilfred F. Nagel</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="ABN AMRO Bank NV (Broker)">Jan Willem Weidema</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Member-Executive Board">Patrick G. Flynn</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Andrew P. Coombs</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Francesca Tondi</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane BNP Paribas SA">Fran&#xE7;ois Boissin</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Administrative Officer">Matthew J. Rider</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Plc">Michael I. Huttner</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Gordon Aitken</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Marcus P. Rivaldi</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">David T. Andrich</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Manish Bakhda</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. This is Yvonne, welcoming you to ING Q3 2012 Conference Call.</p>
          <p>Before handing this conference over to Mr. Jan Hommen, Chief Executive Officer of ING Group, let me first say that today's comments may include forward-looking statements, such as statements regarding future developments in our business, expectations for our future financial performance and any statement not involving historical fact.</p>
          <p>Actual results may differ materially from those projected in any forward-looking statement. A discussion of factors that may cause actual results to differ from those in our forward-looking statement is contained in our public filings, including our most recent annual report on Form 20-F, filed with the United States Securities and Exchange Commission and our earnings press release as posted on our website today. Furthermore, nothing in today's comments constitutes an offer to sell or a solicitation to buy or to offer any securities.</p>
          <p>Good morning, Jan, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Welcome, everyone, to our third quarter 2012 results conference call. We posted solid third quarter results particularly seen against the backdrop of the weakening economic environment. I will talk you through the presentation now and then we have Patrick Flynn, Wilfred Nagel, and Matt Rider here, with me, and we all will be available to answer your questions.</p>
          <p>Unfortunately, this will be the last time that Matt Rider is present at this call. He will step down and he will return to the United States to join his family and look at other opportunities outside of ING. First, before we start the call, I'd like to take the opportunity to thank Matt for his many years of dedicated service to ING and to the insurance, as well as the investment management operations. Matt, thank you very much.</p>
          <p>During the third quarter, I'm on slide 2, we continued to deliver our restructuring plan amid a challenging operating environment. The group posted an underlying net profit of &#x20AC;719 million. The bank underlying profit before tax increased to &#x20AC;1.021 billion, supported by &#x20AC;323 million gain on the sale of Capital One, which largely offsets the &#x20AC;258 million of de-risking losses and the &#x20AC;173 million negative credit adjustments.</p>
          <p>Insurance operating results declined to &#x20AC;238 million, primarily driven by lower investment margin and lower non-life results. Underlying result before tax were &#x20AC;44 million, which includes negative results on hedges in place to protect our regulatory capital, mainly in the Benelux and in the U.S.</p>
          <p>We have continued on slide 3 to make good progress on the European Commission restructuring program. We have announced the first resales of our Asian Insurance units. And our U.S. organization is preparing to file a registration statement with the SEC. At the same time, together with the Dutch state, we have made good progress in our constructive dialogue with the European Commission about revisions to the restructuring plan.</p>
          <p>Slide 4. In October, we reached agreements on the sale of insurance units in Hong Kong, Macau and Thailand, and the insurance operations in Malaysia and also, our 33.3% stake in China Merchants Fund. The process for the remaining businesses is ongoing and further announcements will be made if and when appropriate.</p>
          <p>Proceeds will be used to reduce the double leverage, while at the same time maintaining the current leverage ratios in the insurance holding companies. It's, at this moment, premature to look at this on a deal by deal basis. We will assess the potential dividend upswing once we see all of the Asian deals completed.</p>
          <p>Slide 5. We continue to discuss various options for ING Life Japan, including the closed block VA business. The closing of sales of our other Asian insurance units may trigger a charge to strengthen reserves for the Japanese closed block VA under our reserve adequacy policy.</p>
          <p>ING measures reserve adequacy at a business line level, where excess reserves in other Asian business units currently offset a shortfall related to the Japanese closed block VA. The reserve inadequacy for the Japanese insurance business, including the VA guarantees reinsured to ING Re, is approximately minus &#x20AC;0.5 billion at the 50% confidence level, and that includes approximately a &#x20AC;1.1 negative billion for the closed block VA, which, again, is offset by about &#x20AC;0.6 billion plus for the corporate-owned life insurance business.</p>
          <p>The nature and timing of any P&amp;L charge from such reserve inadequacy will depend on the closing of other divestments in Asia, as well as on various options currently under investigation for ING Life Japan. We will make further announcements when we can make them and when appropriate.</p>
          <p>Slide 6, in the U.S., I must say I'm very pleased with the progress that our management team has made as they work towards an IPO. ING U.S. is preparing to file a registration statement with the SEC in connection with the planned IPO. And upon filing and upon the SEC review, any company S-1 amendments will occur over the following three to four months. This means that we expect that somewhere in 2013, we plan to be ready to execute the first tranche of the IPO, with timing being dependent on market conditions.</p>
          <p>Also, slide 7, good progress was made by our team in the U.S. to become a standalone company. Capitalization has improved with the estimated RBC ratio at 516%, compared to a target of 425%. And note, however, that the RBC ratio excludes our offshore reinsurer, SLDI, and that SLDI is still supported in part by a $1.5 billion contingent capital level of credit with ING Bank that was put in place, as you probably remember, last year.</p>
          <p>We will continue efforts to achieve a 25% debt to capital ratio and to redeem the $1.5 billion contingent capital letter of credit. But 25% is more or less a number that people expect for IPO companies. Given the various capitalization targets, we cannot rule out that part of the IPO may be needed to support the capitalization of insurance U.S. and replace the contingent capital facility.</p>
          <p>Slide number 8, Insurance Europe. We have stepped up our efforts to prepare the business for the base case of an IPO. And as part of this preparation, we have appointed Delfin Rueda as CFO; and Dorothee van Vredenburch, who will handle communication, HR and our transformation process as new members of the management board Insurance Eurasia as of the 1st of November of this year.</p>
          <p>We also announced that Insurance Europe is accelerating its transformation program to sharpen the strategic focus of its business units at Nationale-Nederlanden. And the strategic actions includes that we are launching a new defined contribution pension solution business; that we are helping customers transition from defined benefit to defined contribution pensions; that we are accelerating retail life strategy through the introduction of new products; and that we are increasing the focus on service and efficiency of cost and capital and existing closed book life; strengthening the position in the SME markets by rationalizing our product offering and focusing on very specific segments.</p>
          <p>Slide 10, an addition to the transformation at Nationale-Nederlanden, Insurance Europe will also delayer the support functions to reduce overlap and streamline the organization. Combined, these programs will result in a reduction of around 1,350 FTEs in 2013 and 2014. A restructuring provision of approximately &#x20AC;150 million after tax will be booked in the fourth quarter of this year. And then additionally, IT investments of about &#x20AC;75 million after tax will be made over the coming two years to improve processes and systems. These costs will be booked as special items over time. Cost savings generated by these measures are expected to reach a run rate of &#x20AC;200 million by the end of 2014.</p>
          <p>Slide 11. ING Bank continues to deliver on its strategic priorities. We did sell our equity stake in Capital One. We announced the divestments of ING Direct Canada and the UK as part of sharpening our strategic focus. We also accelerated de-risking, selling &#x20AC;4.9 billion of European debt securities and thereby releasing &#x20AC;6 billion of risk-weighted assets in the first nine months of this year.</p>
          <p>In October, we sold another &#x20AC;3.5 billion additional debt securities, releasing another &#x20AC;1 billion of risk-weighted assets. Furthermore, we are making clear progress in our cost initiatives in retail banking Netherlands, which is ahead of plan. And finally, we achieved another &#x20AC;5.2 billion of balance sheet integration initiatives in the third quarter, and that brings the total to &#x20AC;33 billion since the beginning of 2011.</p>
          <p>Slide 12. Following a strategic review at commercial bank earlier this year, we decided to accelerate the implementation of strategic adaptations, including the run-off of certain leasing units, the right-sizing of the equity businesses and operational improvements in several units, including our PCM business, our payment and cash management business.</p>
          <p>These measures are expected to result in a reduction of about 1,000 FTEs over the next three years, for which we will take an after-tax provision of about &#x20AC;150 million in the fourth quarter of 2012. Cost savings are expected to reach an annual run rate of about &#x20AC;260 million in 2015. The review is ongoing and may lead to further changes in the future.</p>
          <p>Let us now turn to the results for the third quarter on slide 14. On slide 14, you can see that the bank posted a solid quarter, up both year-on-year and sequentially. At insurance, we kept hedges in place to protect our regulatory capital. However, losses on these hedges continue to affect, of course, our result. As a result, net underlying profit of the group at &#x20AC;719 million in quite some challenging environments.</p>
          <p>Let's go to the bank on slide 16. The bank posted solid third quarter results, as a the gain on the sale of our equity stake in Capital One largely offset the losses from de-risking and the negative impact from credit valuation and debt valuation adjustments. Risk cost increased slightly from the second quarter. Underlying result before tax rose to &#x20AC;1.21 billion, which is up 16.3% compared to the same quarter last year and 2.6% higher than the second quarter of this year. Underlying interest margin on a sequential basis improved to 1.33 percentage points.</p>
          <p>On page 17, during the third quarter, we had de-risking efforts, in particular, in the Eurozone area. Total bond sales amounted to &#x20AC;2.4 billion, for which we took a loss of &#x20AC;258 million. Sales were focused on the Spanish covered bonds, Spanish and Irish RMBS and European CMBS. When we clean up the numbers for these and other market impacts to make them more comparable, the gross result went up by 12.2% versus the third quarter last year, and up 2.8% if you compare that with the second quarter this year.</p>
          <p>Interest result was up by 2.2% from a year ago, and 3.6% sequentially, primarily due to strong results in financial markets. The margin rose to 1.33% from 1.26% in the second quarter and mainly by higher interest results, as well as lower average balance sheet level during the second quarter &#x2013; during the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Margins on savings are under some pressure, despite reductions of client rates in many countries, reflecting the impact of lower interest rates and the de-risking. Margins on lending improved in the third quarter, supported by moderate volume growth in mortgages and, of course, by re-pricing of loans that came due.</p>
          <p>Operating expense, we continue to put high priority on cost containment. Operating expense increased marginally by 0.5% from the previous year. Strong cost control that was able to offset the annual salary increases, the fact that we have higher bank levies and one-time additional tax on employee salaries and negative currency effects.</p>
          <p>Compared with the second quarter 2012, that included a &#x20AC;38 million reimbursement from the old deposit guarantee scheme in Belgium, and we had lower performance-related expenses. If you eliminate that, expenses rose by 3.9%. The underlying cost income ratio was 58.7% or 56.9% when you include the market impacts on the CVA/DVA adjustments. We believe that Q4 expense will be impacted by a new Dutch tax of about &#x20AC;175 million.</p>
          <p>Risk costs. The weak economic and business fundamentals continue to contribute to elevate levels of risk cost in the third quarter. Although the net addition to the provision for loan losses rose only by 2.6% to &#x20AC;555 million, it increased 59.5% if you compared it year-on-year. The modest increase compared with the second quarter was mainly attributable to the mid-corporate and SME segments in the Benelux and provisioning for a CMBS position in ING Direct. ING expect risk costs to remain elevated, reflecting the weakening of the economic climate.</p>
          <p>Non-performing loans, slide 21. The ratio remains stable at 2.3%. Ratios in mid-corps and SMEs, and real estate finance and leasing, and thus, the run-off, continued to be relatively high, and we saw that again in previous quarters. Loan loss provision for real estate finance declined to &#x20AC;102 million from &#x20AC;120 million in the previous quarter. NPL ratio for REF increased to 8%, compared to 7.3 at the end of June, which is mainly driven by the Netherlands and, to a lesser extent, by the UK.</p>
          <p>Non-performing loans in our &#x20AC;2.7 billion real estate finance portfolio in Spain remained high at 19%. And risk cost on this portfolio increased to &#x20AC;51 million in this quarter, reflecting lower real estate valuations following our regular appraisal of collateral. Given the deteriorating commercial real estate market in Europe, we expect that risk costs for REF will remain elevated.</p>
          <p>Risk costs for Dutch mortgages declined to &#x20AC;44 million from &#x20AC;53 million in the previous quarter and that included a model update at Westland Utrecht Bank. NPL for the Dutch mortgage portfolio increased slightly, but has remained relatively low at 1.3%, supported by, again, a relatively low unemployment rate in the Netherlands.</p>
          <p>As house prices are expected to decline further and unemployment to increase, we expect risk costs for the Dutch mortgage market to remain elevated. Last Monday, a new government was installed in the Netherlands. Their plans to &#x2013; for the coming years includes housing market reform, among which a gradual decline and the tax deductibility for new and existing mortgages, and also, a reform of the rental markets.</p>
          <p>Slide 24. Given the further weakening of the Spanish economy in the third quarter, we continue to proactively de-risk our exposure to Spain to reduce our concentration and to mitigate risk-weighted assets migration. The bank's total exposure to spend was reduced by &#x20AC;1.8 billion, including &#x20AC;0.2 billion in the lending book and &#x20AC;1.8 billion in the debt securities portfolio, mainly as a result of sales of covered bonds and RMBS.</p>
          <p>The Spanish funding mismatch, defined as the Spanish assets outstanding minus the local outstanding, has reduced from &#x20AC;13.8 billion at the end of Q2 to below &#x20AC;10 billion at the end of this quarter. Spanish covered bonds will be further reduced as our portfolio is maturing.</p>
          <p>Slide 25. The core Tier 1 ratio increased from 11.1% to 12.1% and that was, of course, supported by the gain that we made on the sale of our Cap One stake and strong reduction in RWAs following de-risking and the sale of the stake of Capital One. If we will include the sale of ING Direct Canada and ING Direct UK, the pro forma core Tier 1 ratio is at I think a very robust 12.6%.</p>
          <p>The new accounting on pensions will come into effect on January 1, as far as we know, and that will require immediate recognition of actuarial gains and losses through the equity account. Based on the numbers of September 30, this would have an impact of about 50 basis points negative on the bank core Tier 1 ratio. The deduction was already included in the fully loaded Basel III pension impact.</p>
          <p>On page 26, you see the timing of the CRD IV implementation and the final form of it are still very uncertain. In the consultant's paper that we got from the DNB, Dutch National Bank, it indicates that the revaluation reserve for debt securities will be phased in rather than applied immediately.</p>
          <p>As a result of these changes and the introduction of IAS 19 on pensions, the impact on Basel III is estimated to be a negative 140 basis points when we will introduce it and later, when it will be phased in, on a plus of 20 basis points.</p>
          <p>The impact excludes our deferred tax assets, which are expected to be used prior to Basel III implementation and retained earnings after September 30 of this year. So Q4 is not included yet. Furthermore, management actions are expected to reduce our risk-weighted assets by at least an &#x20AC;18 billion, of which &#x20AC;8 billion has already been achieved so far.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to insurance, slide 28. Results from insurance declines as de-risking measures and low-interest rate environment put pressure on the investment margin. Also, our non-life results continue to be impacted by high disability claims.</p>
          <p>Together, they reduced the operating result for insurance by 39.3% compared with a year ago. Underlying results continue to be impacted by losses on hedges that we maintain in order to focus on protecting our regulatory capital amidst these very volatile financial markets.</p>
          <p>Investment margin declined compared with the last quarter, reflecting the impact of de-risking in the Benelux, as well as exceptionally high dividends that were paid in Q3 of last year. The investment margin also declined from the second quarter, mainly reflecting seasonality. Q4 rolling &#x2013; the fourth quarter rolling average investment spread was 130 basis points, which is down from 133 basis points in the last quarter, again, reflecting de-risking and the low interest rate environment.</p>
          <p>Technical margin, fees and premium-based revenues totaled &#x20AC;784 million, which was down 2% excluding foreign exchange. It was up 0.3% if you compared it with the second quarter this year. In the U.S., higher fees and premium-based revenues from the ongoing businesses were more than offset by higher hedge costs and lower fees on the closed block VA.</p>
          <p>Technical margin improved to &#x20AC;122 million compared with &#x20AC;100 million a year ago and reflecting both improvements in the U.S. as well as the Benelux. We continue to be very tight on expenses and they did increase slightly from the previous year, reflecting investments for growth in investment management in Central and Eastern Europe, And while expenses remained flat in the Benelux and Insurance U.S. reflecting, as I said, very strict cost control, ratio was 47.6%.</p>
          <p>As mentioned earlier, Insurance Europe is accelerating its transformation program, which is expected to generate cost savings of approximately &#x20AC;200 million by the end of 2014. If we take a closer look at our business areas, we see that Insurance Benelux posted lower operating results as the impact of de-risking and higher dividends in both comparable quarters led to a decline in the investment margin. And non-life results continue to be impacted by the higher disability claims in the Netherlands.</p>
          <p>Underlying results, including market-related impacts, remain volatile as Insurance Benelux continues to focus on hedging to protect regulatory capital that leads to volatility in our P&amp;L. Underlying profit for the quarter declined significantly from a year ago, but it did improve compared to the second quarter. Lower sales in the Benelux compared to the same quarter last year were offset by a 13.3% higher sales in our Eastern European and Central European businesses and driven, in particular, by increased sale in life and pensions.</p>
          <p>Insurance U.S. had a strong third quarter operating results of &#x20AC;195 million. That was 14.1% better than the same quarter last year and 12% better than the second quarter. The increase over both quarters reflect improved results in the retirement solutions business.</p>
          <p>Underlying result before tax increased strongly to &#x20AC;398 million and that was supported by gains on the sale of securities and positive DAC unlocking following model refinements and assumption updates. Sales were flat, as higher retirement sales were offset intentionally by lower annuity and individual life sales.</p>
          <p>Results from the U.S. closed block VA continue to reflect the volatility, as the hedge program is focused on protecting regulatory capital rather than mitigating earnings volatility. The underlying results declined to a negative &#x20AC;348 million, reflecting the hedge losses and other reserve changes and a &#x20AC;104 million charge related to lapse assumption refinements.</p>
          <p>Reserve adequacy has improved to the 74% confidence level. As a result, reserves are projected to remain adequate even in a 25% down shock scenario. While the focus on capital protection continues to cause IFRS P&amp;L volatility, earnings sensitivities, at least, are now more symmetric.</p>
          <p>Insurance Asia posted another strong result in the third quarter, despite the sales process for these businesses. Operating results increased from higher investment income, which rose on strong general account asset growth as well as the &#x2013; we saw improved mortality results in Korea.</p>
          <p>Sales declined from last year. That was mainly in Japan, because of tax law changes that was affecting our COLI cancer product sales, but increased from the previous quarter driven by growth in Malaysia and Hong Kong, as well as in Japan from products diversification.</p>
          <p>So, let me wrap it up quickly. We continued to deliver on our restructuring program. We announced already three sales of our Asian insurance units and the process for the remaining businesses is ongoing. U.S. is preparing to file a registration statement with the SEC and Insurance Europe is accelerating the transformation program to sharpen strategic focus of business units at Nationale-Nederlanden.</p>
          <p>The bank had a good quarter, but the commercial banking franchise has decided to accelerate the implementation of a number of strategic adaptations that will lead to cost savings of about &#x20AC;260 million by the year 2015. The group has a net underlying profit of &#x20AC;719 million. As I said, a very strong or very solid quarter for the bank with results both year-on-year and sequentially, and underlying results before tax and insurance declined primarily due to negative results on hedges that we use to protect our regulatory capital.</p>
          <p>And with that, I think we are ready to answer your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question is from Jan Willem Weidema from ABN Amro. Please go ahead. I'm sorry, the first question is from Michael van Wegen from the Bank of Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes morning, guys. Mike van Wegen, Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Two questions please. First of all, you make comments in the press release that you're making good progress with your discussions with the European Commission. If I remember well, at the beginning of the year, you indicated your ambition to repay at least part of the state support before year-end. I don't think there is any news on that today.</p>
          <p>Would you &#x2013; should we conclude from that that you're comfortable or hopeful that you might reach an agreement with the European Commission before year-end and want to wait therefore with an actual announcement? Or how should we interpretate that?</p>
          <p>The second question is, you touched upon the changes in the Dutch tax legislation for mortgages. What's your opinion on the impact on the housing market this will have and the potential losses for mortgages? I know that you've said risk costs will remain elevated. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Michael, good morning. We have made good progress in our discussions together with the Dutch state and with the European Commission. And good progress really means that &#x2013; means good progress, but we don't have anything to report at this moment. As soon as we have and as soon as the European Commission has, I think we will do so.</p>
          <p>Our payment intention with the Dutch state continues. We would like to pay them back as soon as possible, but we also need to be mindful of the ability to do so and the consequences of a full repayment. So I have said indeed, earlier this year, and I will continue that again, that we'd like to make at least a part repayment this year to the Dutch state. But I think it's better to wait for the final arrangement that we hope to make with the European Commission before making any further comments.</p>
          <p>On the mortgages in the Netherlands and the tax consequences, the changes in the tax law, they are not really that significant. They are over time. They are declining from an ability to deduct 52% in a number of years, almost 20 years, down to 38%. So that's a very gradual decline. I think more important, this government has taken, I think, very concrete steps to deal with the housing market in a wholesome way, not just looking at homes that you can buy, but also the rental market.</p>
          <p>And it's too early to say what the implications will be. That hangs too much together with what will happen with the total economy. But I think in general, these are good steps forward. I don't know, Wilfred, anything to add?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, maybe just to add a bit of color to it. If you look at the measures that are being contemplated or introduced, as Jan was saying, the deductibility itself will probably not have a lot of impact. What has a bit more impact is the fact that new loans will have to amortize in order to qualify for tax deductions, so that will gradually reduce affordability a bit. At the same time, of course, the houses most affected by that are also coming down in price.</p>
          <p>So net-net, whether the affordability is really that much affected remains to be seen. Maybe the bigger impact on this will come from the increased health insurance premiums that will reduce spendable income and have an indirect impact on the housing market and ability of people to service their loans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from is Jan Willem Weidema from ABN AMRO. Please go ahead. Mr. Weidema from ABN AMRO, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry about that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That's okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For your Basel III guidance, if I remember correctly, your old guidance was an impact of 80 basis points, now fully facing 120 basis points. Can you take me through the difference there between the old and the new guidance?</p>
          <p>And secondly, can you comment on the impact of de-risking of the NIM going forward?</p>
          <p>And finally on your U.S. RBC ratio, can you comment on the impact of the dampener for low rates and how big is the benefit and do you expect that to come down in the coming quarters, if rates stay where they are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrick will do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In respect of the Basel III impact, if I recall last quarter, we said the impact was, I think, around &#x20AC;160 million in aggregate, of which half of it came immediately and half of it was phased in. What we're showing now is the overall impact is slightly bigger, it's about &#x20AC;170 million, although the timing of the impact has changed, principally because of IAS 19, which will accelerate some of this into immediate impact, so the 50 basis points from the pension comes in immediately.</p>
          <p>Also, as Jan mentioned, the Dutch regulator has indicated that the mark to market on bonds will be phased in rather than immediate and that defers some of the benefit later. So what we're seeing broadly in aggregate, the same overall impact &#x20AC;160 million, &#x20AC;170 million, but some further acceleration of the impact because of IAS 19. By the way, we're not even sure that Basel III will come in in Q1 next year, because we haven't seen CRD IV ratified yet. And the other impact, RBC, yeah, there's been some benefit from unrealized gains due to low rates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Andrew Coombs from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I have three questions, in fact. The first question relates to slides 10 and 12, the two cost-save initiatives announced. Perhaps you could also provide thoughts on what the revenue attrition associated with those cost saves might be? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question, on slide 21, you've detailed the NPL increase in real estate. But perhaps you could shed some color on the increase in corporate and in leasing there, and if you could also provide how or give an example of how the coverage ratios would change in each of those buckets, that would also be appreciated.</p>
          <p>And then, the final question is on de-risking. You've done &#x20AC;5 billion of reduction year to date with a loss of &#x20AC;475 million. You mentioned October, there's another &#x20AC;3.5 billion reduction with a loss of &#x20AC;119 million. Just interested to know your thoughts on how much more de-risking you're planning to do? How much of that is probably to be achieved by active sales, or whether that's more likely to come through natural amortization from here? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, just referring to the Nationale-Nederlanden and the Dutch expense savings programs, we would not anticipate any impact on revenues. These are purely expense saves, with some investment required to be able to get there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the same, I think, for the commercial bank. There is some impact on revenues, but they are completely outweighed by the big benefits we are seeing on the expense side. Wilfred, anything else to add?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I understand the question was you see the NPL numbers for real estate, but can we add some color on corporate and leasing beyond that, is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If you look at the commercial banking portfolio overall, the NPLs were up slightly from 4.3% previous quarter to 4.5% this quarter. And digging a little bit into those numbers, the general corporate lending went up to 3.9% from 3.6%, and leasing to 7.8% from 6.8%, REF you've seen; the structured finance number actually came down a bit from 2.4% to 2.2%.</p>
          <p>And in terms of the risk cost, the corporate lending book risk cost was down from &#x20AC;105 million to &#x20AC;65 million, leasing went from &#x20AC;35 million to &#x20AC;29 million, and the structured finance risk cost went from &#x20AC;55 million to &#x20AC;40 million.</p>
          <p>The coverage ratios, generally stable. If you look  at the commercial book overall, it's around 40% and the general lending book went up a bit in cover from 50% to 52%. The structured finance came down slightly from 53% to 47%, and the rest was pretty much stable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just on the de-risking?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And specifically, I guess the question would be on Spain and we have said all along that this was a large book that, in terms of quality, is definitely not a major concern, but it's just large in a difficult economic environment. So we've actively managed it  and as and when we see opportunities to do so at attractive prices, we will continue to do that.</p>
          <p>But at the same time, I think you referred to that and there is a natural run-off in the book that is quite substantial. It would be about &#x20AC;2.6 billion next year on the scheduled loss alone and another &#x20AC;2.5 billion the year thereafter. So it will continue to come down, but we may, if we see opportunities, actively manage it further.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think it's fair to say that the biggest de-risking exercises that we have done are basically behind us. From time to time and when we see an opportunity, I think we'll take advantage of it. But the big stuff, I think, is basically done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think the concentration for now is more on RWA migration, and not so much on risk mitigation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Francesca Tondi from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thank you very much. A couple of questions also on my side. Looking not just on your net interest margin, but your net interest income progression, you seem to be having a positive trend in most of the parts of the business. Could you expand a little bit more on where that progression is coming, especially in retail Benelux and Belgium, sorry. We're actually seeing quite a bit of an improvement versus the Netherlands, which see some decline, somewhat improvement in the commercial banking business. I don't see a significant improvement on the lending, on increasing the lending, so if you could expand on the reason for the increase?</p>
          <p>Going back for a moment to your Spanish de-risking, interested in your comment that the large part has been done. I see, however, that actually credit spreads are still contracting and was a bit surprised that actually what you did in third quarter seemed to be less than the second quarter with bigger charges. Can you just expand a little bit on what are the trends that you're seeing there and why you think that the big part has been done? Would it not be making sense to accelerate a little bit more? And, yes, that's pretty much it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. With respect to the interest margin, yes, you're right. Not only did the &#x2013; in basis points term, we have a nice uptick to 133 bps, part of which due to balance sheet reduction but also the interest earnings, as you say, did increase. That's up &#x20AC;107 million. About half of that is in commercial banking in financial markets.</p>
          <p>Whilst that can be volatile in terms of the composition of financial markets income, I think it's important to point out that the revenues there have been pretty solid, over &#x20AC;300 million both quarters. You don't necessarily see that on the bottom line, because of the volatile CVA/DVA. But  financial markets has held up pretty well.</p>
          <p>In terms of the core businesses, what we're seeing is a small increase overall, and in interest margins, both in Belgium and the Netherlands, you refer to them, the interest costs have been reduced by about 20 basis points, the most we pay on savings, which is a positive. However, that didn't offset fully the impact of lower interest rates, so the net earnings were slightly negative in terms of the core savings piece.</p>
          <p>In terms of lending, the margin improved, again, marginally, small increase but that was on the back of re-pricing on higher cost of funds, which is a positive and demonstrates again further commitment to maintain discipline in pricing.</p>
          <p>So what do we think in terms of outlook? Going forward, yes I think it should hold up reasonably well at these levels. We would expect that the impact of the price reductions should offset, and you'll see the full effect of that more in the fourth quarter, should offset broadly the impact of the lower interest rate environment, that's in the near time. And obviously, going forward, we still believe that &#x2013; we will migrate towards the longer-term, 140 basis points, 145 basis points targets that we set at the Investor Day, supported by balance sheet optimization, which we have more to do on, and gradual repricing of the loan book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just looking also at the benefit in the finance division, how do you look at the trends on your hedges? Because clearly, rolling over time at a lower yield clearly has a drag effect, so positive this quarter versus what you see that's the trend going forward on that side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The hedges typically in the bank are what you would call accrual accounted.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The key thing there is that the margin on new business and the hedges were rolled in to the cost of funds. And what we're trying to do, we've done it in retail and mortgages as well as commercial, you are looking to execute on our strategic ambitions which involve reflecting the higher cost of credit. So it's more about repricing the cost to the customer, and the hedging is wrapped into the cost of funds. So you're not necessarily going to see that in terms of separate impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But do you think that then net, then you'll be able to more than offset the negative roll-off of the hedges and therefore, seeing that as positive then, trending towards your &#x2013; <mark type="ph" /> so I would cross the margin (45:50), what I'm saying here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think the issue which may be negative is that there's maybe lower volumes as prices go up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And since you have touched upon your, effectively, the reorganization of the balance sheet, if you wouldn't mind just giving us a quick update on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the ambition is to &#x2013; we have, as I mentioned earlier, &#x20AC;11 billion of retail inflow, that's on the back &#x2013; sorry, deposit inflow, half of which is retail, half of which is commercial. Core strength is the ability to generate deposits. What we aim to do is to continue to migrate our lending capacity to areas where we have deposit generation. So it is about moving commercial banking origination capability to Belgium...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...and into Germany, where they're our strengths.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what is the update on this quarter for what you've managed to do so far?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, I think we've given that in aggregate. It's not something we're going to give quarter by quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, then that's fine, and then my last question, if you don't mind, about the Spanish deleveraging and why is it that the biggest chunk is done?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, on that, if you look back over the past quarters, second quarter for us was mainly about reducing the absolute volume of the exposures and the mismatch. Third quarter was more about risk mitigation. As I said earlier, what we're now looking really is more the risk migration risk than anything else and to control that.</p>
          <p>And your comment about credit spreads and improvement in pricing, I mean, looking a little bit beyond the weekly volatility there, the overall prices currently in October are pretty much where they were in June. So there's not a massive change. And to us, that signals that yes, there is volatility, but there's not really a big trend at the moment.</p>
          <p>The other observation is that we do have a serious and sizeable client franchise in Spain, and the objective is to gradually reduce our investment books there and replace them with originated assets. And the current run-off of the investment book supports that nicely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I understand. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Francois Boissin from Exane BNP Paribas. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, gentlemen. A few questions, please. The first one on the Japanese VA book. Basically, could you just walk through &#x2013; walk us through the various scenarios, interest potential hit that you could take according to your, let's say, disposals?</p>
          <p>Second question is on risk-weighted asset migration in Spain. You mentioned this risk. Can you maybe quantify the additional risk-weighted assets that we can see in the coming quarters in Spain?</p>
          <p>And then finally, about the competitive landscape in Netherlands, could you maybe just give some color about competitors' behavior in terms of pricing? And if you are able basically to reprice loans as in line with your expectations, or do you face hurdles? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just with the respect to the Japan VA book, I think we disclosed them this quarter that we do have a reserve inadequacy of about &#x20AC;500 million for the totality of Japan, COLI plus the VA that is reinsured with ING Re. That is composed of this &#x20AC;1.1 billion inadequacy for the VA block and it's compensated by a &#x20AC;600 million adequacy or surplus, if you will, at the corporate and life insurance business.</p>
          <p>We disclose it in this way because, actually, the consequences of when things get reported as losses crystallized are very, very much dependent on the timing of the closing of the various transactions, in part that we've already announced and in part that we will be announcing. So it's a little bit early to talk about overall impacts because we need to know the timing of those transactions, the amount of those transactions and actually, the ultimate resolution to what we do with the sale of the overall Japan business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, maybe just a follow-up question on that. What are the sensitivities here? I mean what could cause the inadequacy to rise and what could basically ease this shortfall?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The inadequacies are the inadequacies. So the point is, when the stuff ultimately gets reflected in our financial accounting and the way that we publish our results. So the sensitivities are basically the timing of the various transactions, the amount of the proceeds, the gains and losses that we would see on those. That's the sensitivity.</p>
          <p>I would add also that these are generally IFRS impacts and that from a capital standpoint, we've already had the capitalization correct in ING Re.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So there is no real market sensitivity here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is market sensitivity, but it has more to do with the impact of, let's say, financial markets and negotiations on the ultimate &#x2013; the prices that we get for these assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you know, we have announced several of them. There will be several to come, but it has more to do with that than anything else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. So, about the risk-weighted assets migration and competitive landscape?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We're getting to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, I think this is more about &#x2013; what we're talking about here is avoiding the potential for this to happen in the future. So what we've done is looked at &#x2013; taken preventative action to particularly in &#x2013; as a back security space to get ahead of the curve. So it's avoiding what things that might come, rather than guiding for future increases. We're trying to avoid negative impacts and I think we've done that reasonably successfully so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the competitive behavior in the Netherlands, I don't think we can say much, except that we do what we do and competitors do what they do. We are tight. We are pricing our product as we see, based on new capital rules as we need to price them. And I think we're very diligent and very disciplined in our pricing behavior. What others do is what others do. We just follow the lines of ING.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Michael Huttner from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fantastic. Thank you very much. I had three questions. The first one is if I &#x2013; just to get a feel for the banking profitability. So &#x20AC;1 billion is reported underlying pre-tax. You had a target of 10% to 13%, which I think was between &#x20AC;3.3 billion and &#x20AC;4.2 billion net. So assuming the &#x20AC;1 billion annualized at &#x20AC;4 billion, then, net of tax about &#x20AC;3 billion, so you got &#x2013; there's a gap there and I'm just wondering how quickly you can close that gap and where does it come from?</p>
          <p>Then, you talked about the &#x20AC;1.5 billion letter of credit. It wasn't clear to me how this was going to be repaid. Is it the U.S. IPO or is the U.S. going to raise hybrid debt on its own and that will replace it, so it wouldn't necessarily infringe on the IPO proceeds?</p>
          <p>And the last one, is looking at slide 5, the &#x20AC;1.1 billion book value for ING Re is from your new disclosure? I'm sure I missed it somewhere before, but what I noticed that it's not on slide 4. In other words, we still have &#x2013; it's gone up because we're in Q3 rather than Q2, but about &#x20AC;6 billion, &#x20AC;7 billion in total, &#x20AC;6.9 billion in the tangible book of Asia assets. And then now, we've got this &#x20AC;1.1 billion. Does it take &#x2013; should I take that to mean that ING Re is now also to be included in the assets for sale relating to Asia? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If you look at the bank, the bank is making &#x20AC;1 billion before tax. And if you relate our numbers, we are making a 10% return on a 10% core Tier 1 ratio as we have defined that. So we're basically in the range that we have said before, between 10% and 13%, already there. If you compare that on the actual equity that we have today, it's a little bit lower, but I think you need to calculate that over time on what the target ratio will be for our capital. And at this moment, we are maintaining internally a 10% core Tier 1 ratio as a target capital ratio for core Tier 1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And this is core Tier 1 fully loaded?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. But it is fully loaded as we have it today. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the &#x20AC;1.5 billion facility that we have is the U.S., all we have done here, as we have mentioned to you, that there is a facility and &#x2013; a credit facility available that needs to be dealt with. And we are not, at this moment, saying how it will be dealt with. We are going to take a look at that very carefully, over time, together with our U.S. colleagues. But it could potentially have an impact and that's what we have been willing to flag today, just to have full disclosure.</p>
          <p>Patrick, on the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (55:55)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In respect to Japan and the capital in Japan, it was disclosed last quarter, albeit I think in the table, you're referring to, if I recall correctly, it was a footnote. But it was isolated before, so it hasn't changed in that respect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But should I take it to mean that the ING Re is now for sale or is it not for sale or &#x2013; I'm puzzled, because it appears in one table and not in the other, and I'm not sure and clearly, the tables related to the extent that you &#x2013; the VA provision kind of affects all of these things?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. ING Re is not for sale, but it includes reinsured transactions other than that of Japan. Obviously, when we complete all of the Asian transactions, this will &#x2013; the element in ING that relates to them will come out in the overall result.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Gordon Aitken from RBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning. A couple of questions, please. Firstly, insurance sales are down 1.4%. Just talk a bit about how your insurance businesses are being affected by the knowledge that in two years' time, they will be under different ownership? How many percentage points do you think that's knocking off the groove?</p>
          <p>And secondly, on the Dutch DB market, just wondering how many schemes you took on in the third quarter and what's your outlook for this market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'll take both those. In terms of the insurance sales, I think what we're seeing is the figures &#x2013; so your specific question is, what impact is the announcements of divestitures having on insurance sales overall? And in general we're seeing actually, we are seeing movements in the sales numbers but they're not really as a result of the announced divestments. We're seeing actually, generally flatter sales in the retirement business in the U.S.</p>
          <p>We've seen some reduced sales in the life insurance business in the U.S. as well as in the annuity business, but those are more management actions as a consequence of the lower interest rates, so we intentionally saw a little bit less of that. We see continued pretty good sales within Asia, I think we saw that on one of the other slides. Within the Benelux, I think we're seeing lower sales, again as a consequence of more lower interest rates than anything else, on the life insurance side, particularly in the Netherlands and in Belgium.</p>
          <p>But then in CRE, we're seeing sales up 13% over the third quarter last year, of which is 10% is life. So in those areas, we see actually some pretty good sales growth. So kind of a long answer to your short question, we're not seeing a lot of impact as a consequence of the announced divestments.</p>
          <p>With respect to the Dutch defined benefit market, that's one I think we have to come back to you on. I don't know exactly what we've done in the third quarter with respect to new plans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Marcus Rivaldi from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. So as to your original EC <mark type="ph" /> state a (59:07) decision, EC oversight on hybrid calls seems to fall away on 18th of November. So my question really is, should subordinated bond holders expect this original agreement to hold or could an extension to this behavioral restriction form part of a new agreement with the EC and the question really is because there are a clear number of bonds coming to call in December?</p>
          <p>And then related to that, what are you planning to do with bonds that were not called during the course of that period of EC oversight? Do you need the capital, would you just call them, do you envisage tenders and exchanges?</p>
          <p>And then just a final question, please. Any comments you can make around the potential for ING involvement in a potential SNS <mark type="ph" /> property finance buyout (59:54) bank solution? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are, as I said earlier, we are making good progress with the European Commission. We are doing that together with the Dutch state. We cannot at this moment give you any more information than that and give you more color, than that we have made good progress.</p>
          <p>Under the arrangements we have, we have to ask the EC for permission to make calls and to do repayments. And I cannot give you any further answer than this &#x2013; on this subject. You will have to wait until you see at the end what decisions are coming out of Europe. And we don't know them today and so, we cannot tell you right now.</p>
          <p>With respect to the, let's say, participation by SNS or by ING in that potential with SNS, so I cannot give you any comment. I have absolutely no comment to make on SNS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, just coming back then to the bond thing, I guess the issue or the confusion is, is that you have an existing agreement which seems to end on the 18th of November. So should we consider that to be null and void at this stage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I cannot help you. I'm sorry I cannot help you. We have made good progress with the European Commission, but you are basically on your own at this moment. I cannot give you any more help.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much, anyway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from David Andrich from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I just had a couple of questions on the Benelux insurance business. First of all, I was just wondering in terms of the non-life performance, what actions you have taken to address this?</p>
          <p>Second, well, if I look at the second quarter results, it was down from 2Q 2011 by about 7% for Benelux sales and, particularly, Individual Life and in this quarter, I see &#x2013; I think it's down by about 23%. And I was just wondering if this is kind of a trend which you see continuing and/or if it's kind of leveling off?</p>
          <p>And then finally, I was just wondering in terms of the IGD ratio for the group as well, as I was wondering if you had it broken apart for the Benelux or European business as well? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take these piece by piece. So, first of all in the non-life business, you all recognize that our non-life results were down in the third quarter. We have taken a charge as a consequence largely of claims in the disability area and we have strengthened the provisions there.</p>
          <p>The actions that we take, well, aside from strengthening the reserves, of course, are to increase premiums. We have stopped sales of certain sickness types of products. We have instituted programs to get people back to work more quickly, so this is more of a claims handling type of &#x2013; types of issues. So I think that we have taken quite some actions just from a pure business standpoint to get that back on track. So it's a disappointing result, obviously, for the third quarter, but we take some actions which I think will bring that back into line, all of it, of course, driven by the difficult economic environment here in the Netherlands.</p>
          <p>With respect to the sales, what you've seen is declining sales as a consequence largely of retails sales within the Netherlands and in Belgium. And what you're seeing also is that certain of our products which had previously been insurance products are now being transformed into sales of what's called <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:03:39) products, and these are not included in the APE figures, but they are included in the figures of the bank, and you'll see that a bit in our disclosure. But clearly, life sales are a bit lagging here. There's also some seasonality to the numbers, so when you look at comparisons quarter-on-quarter, they become a little bit difficult.</p>
          <p>With respect to the IGD ratio, we don't provide any further breakdowns of that overall. We do provide at year-end some information on capitalization of some of the bigger businesses, but we don't disclose that on the in-between quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The final question is from Manish Bakhda from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just one further question from a debtholder perspective. I appreciate your comment on what's going in with the EC, but given bonds issued out of the insurance hold co. have very specific language around the state of the insurance businesses, does ING view these calls on these bonds any differently to other bonds?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have no better answer than the one I have given you earlier. I cannot comment and you will have to have some patience.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Well, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for being on the call. I think this is the final question. If you have any more calls that we did not answer, please direct them to Dorothee and team. They are very capable and very willing to answer your questions. In the meantime, thanks a lot, and have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. This does conclude today's presentation. Thank you for participating. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>