<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1208404" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-02-18</date>
    <companies>
      <company>613</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jan Hommen, Chief Executive Officer designate</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">John Hele, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Koos Timmermans, Chief Risk Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">Marc Thiele</participant>
      <participant id="5">Jan Hommen</participant>
      <participant id="6">John Hele</participant>
      <participant id="7">Farquhar Murray</participant>
      <participant id="8">Koos Timmermans</participant>
      <participant id="9">Duncan Russell</participant>
      <participant id="10">Chris Hitchings</participant>
      <participant id="11">Bruno Paulson</participant>
      <participant id="12">Frank Stoffel</participant>
      <participant id="13">Farooq Hanif</participant>
      <participant id="14">Johnny Vo</participant>
      <participant id="15">Nick Holmes</participant>
      <participant id="16">Tony Silverman</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Welcome to ING's Analyst Conference Call.  Before handing this conference call over to Jan Hommen, Chairman of ING Supervisory Board and CEO designate, John Hele, Chief Financial Officer, and Koos Timmermans, Chief Risk Officer, let me first say that any forward-looking statements in today's comments are subject to a number of variables including interest rates, foreign exchange rates, inflation rates, movements in securities markets including equity markets and underlying economic conditions and changes. The realization of forward-looking statements could be materially altered for unexpected movement in any or all of these and other variables.</p>
          <p>Good morning Mr. Hommen, Mr. Hele, and Mr. Timmermans. Mr. Hommen, over to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Welcome and thank you for joining us this morning.  I am here with John Hele, CFO, Koos Timmermans, our CRO, and Eric Boyer, the acting CEO.  Before we go into the results of Q4, I want to share briefly with you of my observations since being named CEO designate a few weeks ago.  This includes the lessons learned from the financial crisis, both for the industry as a whole and for ING specifically. And then I will talk you through what we are doing to address these concerns, the measures we have taken to strengthen ING and the change program we are implementing to build ING into a stronger Company.</p>
          <p>The financial crisis has had a profound impact on the entire industry, and the magnitude of the crisis has left few companies unaffected.  For ING, we entered 2008 still focused on growth, and we were overtaken by the pace and severity of the deterioration in financial markets in Q4.  The need for many companies, including us, to seek government support has raised some new and important issues, including the level of capital financial institutions should hold, regulatory issues, and the role that banks play in society.</p>
          <p>If you read the newspapers these days, it is clear that the crisis has damaged the confidence in the financial industry. We are fortunate that our customer base has remained stable, but we are very aware that we must continue to work to earn our customers' trust every day.</p>
          <p>From the crisis we have learned how important it is that we live up to our responsibilities to all of our stakeholders.  For customers, that we provide them stability and be a trusted financial partner. And that we offer them transparent products at fair prices. For employees, that we give them clarity on ING's future, that we keep our staff motivated and focused on the customer.  We must partner with regulators and governments and society to build a strong and stable financial sector. And we will continue to make credit available to sustain a healthy economy. And of course we need to take into account that we can only do that at market consistent rates and in line with our underwriting standards. And for investors, we need to strengthen ING's financial position, improve our earnings capacity, provide more clarity, and reduce our volatility.</p>
          <p>For ING itself, we must also draw some important lessons from the current crisis. And we must accelerate the transformation of the Company in light of the changes that are happening in the industry.  Our focus on growth over the past years and our ambition to be one of the leading financial institutions has resulted in many good market positions.  However, it was also supported by tailwinds in the markets, which masked some of our underlying cost and performance challenges. Simply put, we must take a more disciplined approach to growth, to cost and risk, and we must be more selective in where we focus our efforts to build towards a truly leading market positions. My overriding short-term objective is to navigate ING through the crisis by addressing these issues head on, while anticipating possible new challenges that may emerge.</p>
          <p>We've taken a more selective approach to growth within our current risk and capital constraints. For example, we had decided not to launch ING Direct in Japan and not to launch the life insurance greenfields in Ukraine.  We are further reducing our risk and our leverage, and there are many examples of that.  We are reducing volatility in equity by shrinking the available for sale portfolio.  We will maintain our capital levels in line with market expectations, and continue the dialogue with regulators and rating agencies to assess the level of capital required once the crisis subsides.  We will bring cost in line with the reality of today's leaner operating environment.  And also, we must be outwardly focused and alert to changes in the markets. We will increase accountability within the organization, and we will certainly reduce the complexity of the Group and focus on the basics.</p>
          <p>As you can see, we have already taken some measures to stabilize and to strengthen ING.  The Illiquid Assets Back-up Facility with the Dutch State offers now protection on 80% of our Alt-A portfolio.  It will strengthen our IFRS equity by 4.6 billion, and reduce Risk Weighted Assets by about 13 billion, adding about 37 basis points to our Tier-1 ratio.</p>
          <p>The sale of our Taiwanese life business significantly reduces interest-rate risk and economic capital requirements in the insurance company. And the divestment of ING Canada sharpens our focus on core businesses, and generated cash proceeds of 1.4 billion.  These measures have further strengthened our cap [capital] ratios, but we have to remain vigilant of what is going on in 2009.</p>
          <p>On our priorities going forward, we are reducing our exposures to market volatility, reducing the size of our available for sale portfolio to limit volatility in the IFRS equity.  We have hedged most of our direct public equity exposure.  We have disposed parts of our investments and real estate and private equity.  And we are reducing the size of our bank balance sheet by about 10%, not by restricting lending but by decreasing the non-lending assets by about 25%.</p>
          <p>Cost reduction is a major priority going forward, and we have announced measures to reduce operating expense by 1 billion in 2009.  This will lead to annual savings of about 1.1 billion going forward from 2010 forward. We are reducing head office expense. Looking at marketing, we have already announced the Formula 1 that we will stop this year when the contract is up. And we are looking at third-party staff. All in all, it involves a head count reduction of about 7000 people.  And in every thing we do, modesty must we prevail in order to align our cost base with the environment where we are in now.</p>
          <p>We also continue to work to preserve our capital, focusing the organization and divesting non-core activities.  We will stop setting up new greenfield operations in new markets, and we will work to buyback the Tier-1 securities from the Dutch government once the crisis subsides.  This is by no means all we need to do. Indeed, you should consider this a first wave of what will be a substantive journey to clarify our portfolio and prove our position.</p>
          <p>As you can see in the Change Program for 2009-2010, let me put it in context for you what we have in mind.  Over the last three weeks we have developed an outline of a program to strengthen and transform ING over time, consisting of four major elements.  The first priority is to strengthen the financials and restore credibility in dealing with the crisis, for which we have already taken some initial measures. And they include, of course, reducing costs &#x2013; the 1 billion that I just mentioned &#x2013; dealt with Alt-A, and de-leverage the balance sheet by a combination of reducing the asset size and preserving equity.  In parallel, we will start reviewing the portfolio to determine where we create value for our customers, our clients and employees, and of course for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>All options are open as far as I can see it.  We want to reduce the number of markets in which we operate.  We have accelerated our review of where we really want to compete and are able to do so effectively. We have taken some initial steps here by stopping new expansions, as ING Direct in Japan and insurance greenfields in Central Europe, as well as the sale of ING Canada.  And after conducting this review, we need to act decisively but prudently on our conclusions: reduce the complexity by disentangling businesses and operations to improve agility and speed.  We will invest in those markets where we choose to focus to improve the operational and commercial performance and build the necessary scale.</p>
          <p>Over the last couple of years, the emphasis of ING on growth has led to less of a focus on operational and commercial efficiency.  To create strong and sustainable franchises, I believe we need to take the following actions:  steer towards top quartile operational and commercial effectiveness in our relevant markets and sectors.  There is some low hanging fruits that we are already addressing, but we need a fundamental change in our mindset towards leading in operations. We will review whether we have and how we can create market-leading positions through our organic investments and our portfolio choices.  We can only deliver this program if we build a stronger organization that enhances accountability, is simpler to manage and is more responsive to customer needs.  This transformation of ING will require adjustments to the organization.  It will enhance our performance culture with clear, personal accountability; steer better on operational and commercial performance; it will increase the frequency and depths of dialogue moving towards transparency in our businesses; place more emphasis on consequence management; strengthen and simply governance; further empower our risk and finance functions; tighten up the management of the business; speed up decision-making; and simplify some of our internal structures.</p>
          <p>We will continue to innovate by analyzing changing client needs and develop the appropriate production process to accommodate these needs, but to do so in a manner that takes far better use of our increasingly scarce resources.</p>
          <p>Well, the crisis was evident in the fourth quarter financials.  I can walk you through the bullets quickly.  Q4 2008, an underlying net loss of 3.1 billion, driven by market volatility and declining asset prices.  Banking underlying net loss of a little bit more than 1 billion in Q4, but full-year we remained profitable with a little bit more than 700 million of profits.  Insurance underlying net loss of 2 billion, from investment losses and DAC unlocking.  Divestments and special items totaled a negative 611 million, brining the quarterly loss to 3.7 billion.  But, our commercial performance was resilient in 2008 despite the headwinds we saw in Q4.  Full-year 2008, our net production of client balances of 93 billion.  Client savings and deposits were 21 billion of this. And our Value of New Business was down 8.1% for the full-year, as especially weakness in the second half was offsetting the solid performance we had in the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>Let me now hand over to John for an update on the financials.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I'm on Slide Nine, and I'll just highlight some of the key results of our quarter and the year, walk you through our commercial performance in 2008, which should hold up throughout the year pretty well despite the headwinds in the fourth quarter, talk to you about our expenses as well as our capital ratios.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, we show you the full-year and the fourth quarter results of Bank and Insurance in Group.  I think it's interesting to note the Bank for the full-year was profitable and Insurance had a loss of approximately 1 billion for the year.  I think this puts the Bank in line or slightly better than many other banks for the full-year 2008.  And Insurance was dramatically impacted by the financial markets.  I think the equity securities, the hedging programs that we did put in place compensated for a good part of that, while the credit markets, other debt securities as well as hedging and the volatilities of the markets took their toll on the results, particularly in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>As you look at it by a line of business on Slide 11, the Banking business, in particular Wholesale Banking, had a hard fourth quarter that was driven by real estate re-evaluations and credit related markdowns and impairments.  The commercial performance in General Lending and Structured Finance was resilient throughout mostly all &#x2013; in fact all of the year.  And risk costs increased as the worsening economic conditions started to take their toll.</p>
          <p>Retail Banking had a lower fourth quarter that was driven by two major factors.  Number one, we had higher costs in the quarter as we got ready for the integration of Postbank and ING Bank.  It was for temporary workers to prepare for the integration that is happening this quarter, and that will be going away throughout the course of this year.  We also saw quite a competition for savings, particularly in the Netherlands in the fourth quarter.  We're pleased to announce that we see that subsiding a bit and continued growth in Q1 so far in Retail Banking savings.  ING Direct saw a loss in the fourth quarter driven by a fundamental change in view on impairments with the Alt-A portfolio that Koos will speak about.  The interest margin has gone up in ING Direct globally as interest rates have come down around the world. And we're now seeing positive flows coming through in ING Direct as well in this quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning to Insurance on Slide 12, you can see the impact in the fourth quarter across the board in the three lines of business in Insurance, driven by asset classes and also volatilities in both the Americas and Asia-Pacific due to single premium variable annuities, hedging, as well as DAC unlocking.</p>
          <p>The equity markets on Slide 13 had an impact on our DAC unlocking in the United States.  Also in the quarter, which had, we'd not seen much of before, we saw a little of it in the third quarter, our Other impacts on DAC unlocking, in particular lower interest rates. And that had a reset we had to do for the DAC in this quarter.  Now this gets reset each and every quarter as equity markets improve or as interest rates go up. Then these come back again, and this averages out over time.</p>
          <p>The market volatilities in Slide 14, this shows a graph of the tracking of the assets and liabilities, and how well we track on that.  We saw &#x20AC;184 million of hedge ineffectiveness, hedge losses, in the U.S. in the quarter. And in Japan, &#x20AC;252 million.  This is caused by extremely large inter-day volatilities for, from our dollar-hedging program.</p>
          <p>On Slide 15, I just want to spend a moment here on our reserve adequacy. You'll see in our press release we mentioned two areas that fell below our 50% confidence interval. Under IFRS, we're required each quarter to assess the reserves on the Insurance side, are they adequate.  ING tests at both the 50% level, which is common under U.S. GAAP and many other insurers, but also at a 90% level.  So you can see this representative by a cumulative probability curve here to show the 90% and the 50%.  We tested a business line level and a business unit level.  In total the U.S. business, which is a business unit, is sufficient at 99%. And we give the numbers where the U.S. is sufficient in terms of euros as well. It is important though that for both Japan, as a business unit, and for the Retail Annuity business they fell below the 50%. And what that means is the business lines are sufficient, so we have excesses elsewhere in the business lines or business units. But these units are an early warning indicator, and the units will work on plans to strengthen their reserves. And that can be from new business. That can be from working on a different accounting systems. That can be from de-risking, adding more hedges. So there's a wide variety of activities at the unit they can work on. And they'll be working on that in the next quarter, and ING will back come with more details on that at the end of Q1.</p>
          <p>When it comes to client balances, the fourth quarter also saw a net production loss of 6 billion, and that was driven both in Asia/Pacific, ING Direct and Wholesale Banking. But clearly the market performance was the major, and FX, was the major two impacts on our overall client balances to end up at &#x20AC;1455 billion.</p>
          <p>The retail savings flows on slide, on the next slide, we have seen, we did see a decline in Q4. But we have seen a new inflow up to 5 billion in ING Direct in Retail Banking, which has compensated now, just in January alone, for the outflows in Q4. So it's a very positive trend.</p>
          <p>The interest margin has improved to 1.19.  Now approximately half of that is due to a higher interest result in Wholesale Banking, which is partially offset by a negative impacts in other income; that's how products are booked.  So the true underlying driving margin is, say, about 1.10 or so.</p>
          <p>Our new life sales on the next slide are also driven down a bit as the market turmoil took its toll on sales. And also value of new business is down because of margin pressure, primarily in variable annuity products, higher hedging costs and lower interest rates.  We adjust our VNB each quarter for the actual hedging costs that are incurred in that quarter and the margins that are incurred in that quarter. And then they're assumed to average out and revert to a mean over time. But we do reflect each quarter the true costs ongoing that we see.</p>
          <p>Our Embedded Value saw the impact of the financial variances in the market turmoil as well. We have a complete Embedded Value report that's also been published this morning.  I have a slide here that just highlights the large change in financial variances from asset revaluations, asset impairments. There's also a change in economic assumptions. We've got a 2.3 billion reduction in Embedded Value.  We did see some favorable expense mortality, and morbidity, but these were more than offset by the financial and economic assumption changes.  And in total we ended up at 23.0 billion, which includes an injection of capital out from the Group into the Insurance businesses.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, we will be working as Jan mentioned, reducing our costs, and we give some details here by both the cost reductions by the business line and the FTE reductions.  The 1 billion of operating expenses is 35% in employee costs and 65% other expenses.  As Jan mentioned, we're reducing overhead, Formula 1, third-party staff. And that's where we were first looking at reducing the structural expense changes.</p>
          <p>On Slide 23, we give &#x2013; - Slide 22, we give the adjusted equity changes, and we even show how those moved in terms of the net result.  This is adjusted equity. So this is for regulatory and rating agency purposes.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the key capital ratios and solvency ratios.  We are within our own internal standards.  We're within what we believe are the market norms today, and what the rating agencies expect.  We have not set new targets.  We're in discussions with rating agencies and others as we see how the market norms move out as we move through this crisis.</p>
          <p>Our Shareholders' Equity has been boosted by 3.9 billion from the Assets Back-Up Facility.  We show for the Bank the pro-forma impact in this slide.  We also show you if our Bank debt was mark-to-market &#x2013; and some banks do some or all of their senior debt and hybrids as a mark-to-market &#x2013; that would add 6 billion of equity.  And I think it's important when you compare banks to analyze this and get them all on an equal footing.  It is a little complex, but an important aspect when comparing ratios of equity, IFRS equity to the total balance sheet.  Also, it's quite different under U.S. GAAP from IFRS, which is another adjustment that you really want to make sure you look out for.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, we have notified you that in early January ING Direct reclassified 22.8 billion of Available-for-Sale assets. And these are listed between other ABS, CMBSs, covered bonds and RMBSs into loans and receivables, as we're allowed to do under IFRS.  These are all in Europe, and the negative pre-tax revaluation reserve is still not too big. So these are priced at 95%.  We see no market in these today, and that's why we've reclassified them. We will hold for the foreseeable future. And these are for our core ING Direct businesses in the Euro zone.</p>
          <p>We show you on slide, on the next slide, the funding profile we have.  We had a large amount of funding we were able to execute in 2008.  We were very active in the first half of 2008, which was a very good thing.  We have a manageable funding profile for this year in 2009. And we've already issued, due to the pre-announcement, we took advantage of the opportunity to issue 6 billion senior debt in the Bank under the Dutch guarantee program.  So we already have 6 billion of the required 2009 needs.</p>
          <p>With that, I'm going to turn it over to Koos Timmermans to talk about risk.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on the risk side, Page 28, a few things to go through.  One, well personal role, it's been a tough quarter with asset prices going down, but also earnings and real economy deteriorating which had, it impacts on delinquency, in delinquency rates in our U.S. housing portfolio.  So, what we do is we'll talk about Alt-A. And we'll talk about the U.S. mortgage delinquencies, and about our credit losses which we estimated at a higher level.  Also, we'll talk about our structure, what we have done with the Dutch State. And then we'll zoom in on the rest of the balance sheet, so the exposures on interest rate, equities, ABSs. And we look at the overall asset allocation, what we have done. And then we'll zoom in on the loan portfolio.</p>
          <p>So with that I'd like to first go to the Alt-A mortgage delinquencies.  What we've seen in Alt-A is underlying, we saw an increased rate of delinquencies happening over the fourth quarter.  So, Alt-A delinquencies had increased from 9.7% to 12.7, and on some tranches like the '06 is from 12.3 to 15.6.  So, there was at the moment in the fourth quarter not an evident that delinquencies were leveling-off. And the outlook of course was not getting better either. And that was evident, amongst other, by Moody's who revised their ultimate loss expectations. And that went from 4-8% to 20-24%. And then we are talking about cumulative losses of mortgages.  So that is not the same as our RMBSs, because we hold credit enhancements, but nevertheless you see that those cumulative losses were increasing.</p>
          <p>So what we do is we don't look so much when we project credit losses at the market value of the bonds.  We do look at the underlying cash flows, and we test them. And with that in mind and with the increased delinquencies and with the worsening outlook, we felt that we had to take a harsher look at our cash flow testing. And this harsher look at cash flow testing resulted actually in an anticipated credit loss of 303 million on the Alt-As in the fourth quarter. And that 303 million on page 30 we are, that is approximately 260 in Direct and 40 in the Insurance company.</p>
          <p>Now where does it come from?  You know from us that we normally bucket our Alt-A portfolio, and then we tell how much of cash flow protection do we still have due to credit enhancement. And if it's in Bucket 1 then it means our cash flow tests say there is insufficient coverage. Bucket 2 says well the credit enhancement is still in 1 to 2 times bigger than the anticipated losses, or it has very low market prices. And then Bucket 3 are the ones where the credit enhancement is ample. So, what we did is we redid that testing, and what you in essence saw is that Bucket 1 has completely been impaired. And if you look at Bucket 2, 62% of the ones with a coverage between 1 and 2 were in there, and also a small part of the Alt-As with a mortgage, with a price lower than 60.</p>
          <p>Now that is in as far as we are talking about the credit side. But then what you can see is it has overall an impact on the impairments because the 303 million of credit losses resulted in a write-down to market value of 1.8 billion, hence the higher pre-tax impairment over the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Then let us zoom in on another aspect with the Alt-As.  We have seen and that is what you see on page 31, a Risk Weighted Asset growth driven by downgrades with Alt-A.  You see overall that we had in growth in Risk Weighted Asset to 14.2. That 14.2 on top there, that is the impact of the rating migration of Alt-A. The moment that bonds become downgraded or are rated at the level of BB or below, then what you will see is that in general you will take a 1-for-1 capital deduction.  So that is one of the issues which is of importance to note with the securitization portfolio.</p>
          <p>In general, what you can say is that those securitization transactions have a higher sensitivity to credit migration than if you look at the normal loan book. Because I'd like to point out on the loan book in general and what you see on the loan book in general is that a one notch downgrade &#x2013; if you take the whole lending portfolio of ING &#x2013; if you then take a one notch downgrade over the whole portfolio that translate into a 60 basis point increase or decrease in the Tier-1 ratio.  And so, you see a lot lower or a lot smoother migration with the normal loan book than with these particular Alt-A credits.  So this is also one of the reasons why the Facility which we have done with the Dutch State help.</p>
          <p>So, then let us move over to Page number 31, I believe, and that is the page which is there introducing the transaction which we have done with the Dutch State.  What we have done with the Dutch State is we have done a transaction where we start to share the risk, 80% of the risk goes to the State, 20% of the risk stays with us.  In essence, if we look at the transaction the day one P&amp;L, once the transaction starts, is approximately P&amp;L neutral.  We sell at approximately at the price of 90. We re-impair somewhat the impairments, and overall your day one P&amp;L is kind of neutral.</p>
          <p>At the same time, if we look at the Tier-1 ratio, that clearly improves because we have a reduction in Risk Weighted Assets by 13 billion, but also what you see is the cash flow will change as well.</p>
          <p>In other words what will happen is the State, they will receive a coupon on the Alt-A of 4.5% approximately.  So, we take 21.9 billion times 4.5, that goes to the State.  At the same time, we receive a coupon or a receivable from the State, and that is partly fixed and that is partly the 1-month LIBOR. And there we approximately receive a coupon of 21.9 times 3%, prior 50.  So, overall, we have a lower cash flow which we receive due to the transaction with the State.  But at the same time, we have lower future impairments and what we also have is less of a credit migration issue.  So, all of these things help to stabilize cash flows, and it makes sure that the results get less volatile.</p>
          <p>Let us now go from &#x2013; - and by the way, if we look at this cash flow and if we look at the 100 million per quarter approximately what you see as a lower cash flow, that will start to level off with the prepayment of the Alt-A portfolio.  And if you take the normal prepayment speed, which we see right now, then you would assume that it's approximately 50% lower by year five.</p>
          <p>Let us then look at Page number 32. And there we take the overall pro-forma balance sheet at 2000 (sic) [2008] year-end.  The wheels which we normally show where you see total assets for the Group, the Investment portfolio and the ABS portfolio, like I've shown previous quarters are stated here.  What I've done is said well what is the impact of the Facility, what we have done with the State.  So, in essence, what you see there is that we get a government receivable back instead of the Alt-A portfolio. And the government receivable is higher in notional than the Alt-A portfolio. And you get on the liability side a re-valuation reserve which is reversed which increase shareholders' equity.  So that is in a nutshell the points which you will see. And then in the breakdown of the investments what you see is that I have a lower amount of ABS, so that's in the middle, the dark blue part. And I have on the right hand side, a lower amount of Alt-As.</p>
          <p>If we move then to Page 33 and we look at the ABS portfolio, overall what you see is a decline in the portfolio. 81 billion at Q3, it was 72 billion at the fourth quarter due to lower valuations. Then it became 57 billion because of the Illiquid Assets Back-up. And now, what John already alluded to, we do partially a re-classification. So it will be 44 billion going forward after the reclassifications.  The reason that we do it is we want to bring the accounting more in line with the buy-hold nature of this portfolio, and at the same time we want to stabilize our IFRS equity volatility.</p>
          <p>Talking about the ABS portfolio, I'd like to zoom in on the CMBS portfolio.  If you look at the CMBS portfolio, it declined in market value from 9.5 billion to 7.3 billion.  And, so we had a fair amount of negative re-valuations happening over the fourth quarter.  If you look at the characteristics of the portfolio, 430 bonds, with quite a lot of underlying commercial mortgages &#x2013; 26,000 in the different type of trusts.  One of the things we have to note is that those underlying mortgages, it's commercial mortgages and it can be of various types. It can be more of the shopping malls. It can be more of the offices. That means the underlying diversification is a bit higher than if you look at a normal mortgage borrower, what you see on the Alt-A side.</p>
          <p>The particular things what we look at in this portfolio is, well, first, the credit ratings. They are relatively high.  The credit enhancement on this portfolio on a weighted basis is relatively high. And we look at the debt service coverage ratio which is for us important there, which is holding up well at this moment. Wide debt service coverage ratio, you rather look at debt service coverage in this case rather than your annual CPRs and your CDRs.  That's a better way to project how this portfolio is performing.</p>
          <p>If we go to, from the CMBS portfolio to the CDOs and the CLOs on Page 35 then what you see there is in general a decline of the CDO/CLO portfolio.  What happened there, in general there was a sale in Insurance Americas of 650 million [Euros]. At the same time the Wholesale Banking side they closed their positions in the CDOs, CLOs as well.  There was a fair value decrease happening. The only offset was, there, was a reclassification which I had from Insurance Euro where something was booked under European ABSs which SME has underlying and that is now booked under CDO/CLOs.  But overall what you see happening is net net, we have been declining in this area.</p>
          <p>Then let us zoom in on the Investment portfolio, Page 36.  Overall in the Investment portfolio what we, what happened is we increased our weight in government bonds, especially in the U.S., actually over the last quarter. And what you see is clearly our ABSs went down partially because of the Illiquid Assets Back-up Facility, partially because of re-valuations. And we went down in the equity part because of hedges and because of sales. And actually what we'd like to do in the Investment portfolio is to bring that down slightly further, partially by integrating a bit of ING Direct's balance sheet by making sure that we put ING-originated assets in the ING Direct balance sheet where regulators allow us so. And where we can sell part of our own portfolio. So that is the point, what we try to do is partially integrate balance sheets. So also make sure that we can continue to lend money and therefore also reduce our re-valuation sensitivity.</p>
          <p>With that I'd like to move more to the equity part of the Investment portfolio, Page 37. On the equity part of the portfolio what you see is over the year, post-2007 to 2008, we have been declining in the equity part, both on the Insurance side as well as on the Banking side. And where we do have the equities, we do hedge this portfolio to a reasonable amount. Still, we have the basis risk, and that is you cannot precisely replicate the IFRS impairment rules with equities with put options. Thus, roughly speaking, we have a hedge on the total portfolio. Also from time-to-time, we hedge some of the DAC unlocking in the U.S., if we have a very negative view about the market.  So that is something which we do for opportunistically.</p>
          <p>If we then move from the equities to the Real Estate side. On the Real Estate side, what you see is we still have the 9.8 billion investment and seed capital in the Real Estate Funds which are re-valued via the P&amp;L. You see in essence no material change in inventory.  We divested some, and that is 0.4 billion. But again this is a market where it is difficult at this moment to lay-off exposure elsewhere.</p>
          <p>A brief update on the Real Estate Funds. What you see is 66.5 billion in Real Estate Funds. Why a lower amount? That is more a lower re-valuations of the portfolio, not necessarily outflows. Most of the funds are not open-ended, and they are not open-ended retail-based type funds. A few words on the debt financing in the funds.  Overall, there is approximately 22 billion of debt financing in the funds, 4 billion funded by ING there.  Over the next year, the refinancing requirements are approximately 10% in the funds, which is a relatively modest amount there.</p>
          <p>Then moving from the Real Estate side more to the de-risking on the Insurance in the area of interest rates.  One of the thing what happened is the sale of the life business in Taiwan. It had an reduction in economic capital of 5.7 billion.  It increased our market value of our balance sheet by 3.4 billion.  And in essence, that is the case because we have a lot of guarantees at a lot higher rate than the current swap rate in Taiwan for 10 years, which is at this moment at around 1.43%.  So it helps to shorten the duration of the liabilities in the Insurance side.  Meanwhile, over the fourth quarter what we also did is we lengthened the asset duration on the Insurance company. And we did it by investment in government bonds, interest rate swaps and swaptions, wherever we get a reasonable accounting treatment for this.</p>
          <p>Then moving to Page 40, overall balance sheet reduction.  One of the things is we reduced our balance sheet already in the fourth quarter by 41 billion, and we want to cut it by another 70 billion in '09.  Where do we do that? There's a few obvious ones: reverse repo, interbank activities as well.  But there is another one, and that is what I already mentioned before. That is trying to bring down the investment portfolio and to basically use savings money to fund loans rather than the investment portfolio as well.  Overall balance sheet reduction does come at a cost, and what we expect over 2009 is 130 million P&amp;L impact because of the balance sheet reduction.  But what you see as well there is that our lending as a percentage of total balance sheet will move up from 57% 3Q '08 to 64% at the end of '09. And that is something which we are aiming to do.</p>
          <p>Then, if we move to Page 41, we look at the loan book because we're now at the loan book.  What you see actually in the loan book is an increase in the total amount of provisions over the fourth quarter, 81 basis points on a net basis, 94 additions minus 12 releases. So, in general, a higher number there.  Where does it come from?  You see it higher in the mortgages, and that is delinquencies in the U.S. You see it a bit in the Private Banking area. You see it in the Structured Finance area. And you see it in the corporate loan book in a few sectors as well.  So it's a bit widespread over a number of areas.</p>
          <p>Then if we zoom in on the mortgages, because let's split the loan book. And half of it is retail, half of it is wholesale.  If we take the Retail part, the mortgages, that's the biggest chunk of it. There what you see is the NPLs in a matrix. And overall what you see on the 267 billion, you see that the non-performing loans have moved up gradually from 0.09 to 1.1, where the U.S. in this case is the biggest contributor. The right hand graph puts it a bit in perspective. What you do see is an increased amount of delinquencies, and that is the red line there.  It is going in line with basically the prime mortgages. So, yeah, in general that is a bit a characteristic of the portfolio. But then again, delinquencies across the board are increasing in the U.S. market at this moment.  What we do do actually, is we do have strict underwriting.  If you look at our loan-to-value's index for property values right now, they are at 75%. And also what you see is new production. You do it on an average LTV of 63%, and in general, what you find is an interest margin.  If you look at an interest margin that is basically the rate minus the cost of funds, minus repayments, minus commissions, that is at 150 basis points.  So it is at healthy prices. But at the same time, you do see an increased amount of delinquencies overall in the portfolio.</p>
          <p>If we then move from the retail side to the commercial side, and that is on Page 43.  In general, if you look at our commercial loan book, what we have is either a high rating or we want to have a high degree of quality collateral with customers.  And if you look at the commercial loan books, it's relatively diversified. That's what you see on the left-hand side, diversification per type of industry. And on the right-hand side you see the diversification per geography.  Although there is a strong focus on the Benelux because the light blue and the dark blue side clearly indicate that half of the portfolio is in the Benelux. If you look at the non-performing loans, it increased from 1 towards 2% of the commercial loan book. And that had to do with the real estate, the builders and the automotive, in particular.</p>
          <p>Then if you look at final point from my side on the risk, on the Alt-A side, yes, we have seen an underlying economy deteriorating. And therefore, we have taken steps to both first impair more, and second, to do our illiquid asset transaction with the State.  Second point is we are de-risking the balance sheet, and that means reducing the balance sheet.  We are reducing our exposure to interest rate, equities and ABSs. And we are trying to integrate the balance sheet a bit more where regulators and the positions allow us. So a third thing is if you look at the risk costs increase in the book, I mean that was on the fourth quarter, it was a relatively high number. And it was driven by the various sectors, it had, partially by the wholesale and partially by the retail side.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'd like to hand it over to Jan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you Koos. A few closing remarks.  It will be clear that our objectives short-term are to strengthen ING, and deal with the impact of the crisis by quickly reducing costs, by monitoring and reducing risk and our capital exposures, and by de-leveraging further the balance sheet with our reduced assets and preserve our equity. And all that, of course, keeping in mind that the customer is critically important to us.  It is their willingness to do business with us that makes us a successful Company.</p>
          <p>Further we will take a very hard look at how we can reduce complexity of the Group.  We're going to review our portfolio of businesses in light of the changes that are happening in the industry.  We do that with the collective Executive Boards, and we have a process already designed in order to get the data and get us the conclusions in a few, in a relatively short timeframe.  And we are going to focus on fewer businesses and fewer markets.  We're going to have a more focused Company which will be easier to manage and easier to run.  And at the same time, we want to strengthen the institution and those activities that we will declare to be the portfolio that we want to be successful with. And we will really look at how we can make that portfolio more effective, more efficient, but also do that in a culture of performance with clear accountability. And we want to simplify the way that we operate, simplify the governance structure of the Group. And be of course very outward looking to our customers.</p>
          <p>Having said that, I think we are at the end of the presentation, and we want to open it up for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Marc Thiele from UBS.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning.  My first question relates to the earnings power of the Group going forward after all these de-risking efforts. You've already told us about the impact from transferring the Alt-A portfolio, and you have given us a bit of flavor from the de-risking of the Bank.  But maybe you can give us a bit more insight into what sort of earnings power will be left of the Group after you've been reshaping it?</p>
          <p>My second question is related to the operating life results in the Americas and Asia.  There are losses that are flagged on the Slides 58 and 59, and it seems that the cost reduction programs are not enough to fix this. What other alternatives do you consider in terms of getting those businesses back into profits? Or are they part of the problem, and will be regarded non-core going forward?</p>
          <p>And then the third question regarding the capital targets, you said earlier there's still a bit of uncertainty regarding how the rating agencies will treat the capital positions going forward.  But am I reading too much into it that you're sort of introducing more of a corridor when you talk about 100 to 120 in terms of the coverage ratio versus the 120 that I thought was the previous minimum? Or how do you think the numbers will shift going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let me deal with the first question, the earnings power.  I think the intention of our portfolio review will be to create a business that going forward on a sustainable basis will be a profitable business.  And that is I think what we have in mind when we do the review.  I cannot tell you exactly what it will be at this point in time.  I think you need to give us some time to go through that review. But as soon as we have that done, I think we will report it back to you.  I think, John, would you like to deal with --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>-- the life?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the life insurance margins, Marc, in both Europe and America as well, of course, there's a large investment variance in the quarter that we see.  The technical margins bounce around sometimes quarter-to-quarter in that.  The investment margins are kind of flat as you can see from the margin analysis on those pages.  The expenses were up in Americas.  The expenses in this analysis reflects all the DAC unlocking and all the DAC adjustments in it.  So, there's a large negative DAC hit in both the third quarter and fourth quarter. And that's why in the Americas it's a long way above the run rate, and there's a bit of that as well in life insurance Europe.  So that's why we've seen some pressure and squeeze in the margin analysis. But if markets stay flat you don't, or flat-ish and just slowly go back to normal, then the DAC unlocking becomes non, not an event. And of course if markets recover, then the DAC is a positive unlock from the expense side.</p>
          <p>On your question on capital targets and ratios, the -- we still have an AFR to EC for the Group, and we said it was kind of a 120 number in times, of normal times.  But we always want it to run at a buffer, because this number is highly volatile.  I think you've seen it's highly volatile particularly in the third and fourth quarter of this year.  And so, the Group AFR/EC is at 136, but that's again, it's a very volatile number.  We want to be running that as a buffer, and that can come up and down in any one quarter.  You need to average these out over a period of time. And you got to, and in particularly in the volatile markets that we're in today, these numbers will bounce around quite a bit.  But I think in terms of how we set all these, there's a lot of uncertainty today we find in speaking with the broad constituents on what the target should be. We noticed the other day that the targets, say in the Bank a year ago, that was the target for many banks being a Tier-1 ratio is now the target for their core Tier-1 ratio.  And that's a dramatic change in the course of a year.  I think 2009, we think is going to be, continue to be challenging, and we need to ensure that we have enough capital margins to ride through this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question comes from Farquhar Murray from FPK.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there, good morning.  It's Farquhar from Fox-Pitt here.  Two questions, if I may. Just starting with Risk Weighted Assets, which I think given the reclassifications and the transactions, probably about 330 billion.  Could you split that between the loan book that you've given the 60 basis point guidance on and the prime CMBS and sub-prime components of that, the Risk Weighted Assets?  And can you also on the 60 basis points guidance, could you just clarify that if that does include the reclassified component as well?  And then just turning to strategy, I just wondered if you could give us, it's probably to early to get anything particularly concrete, but just in terms of criteria, could you give us some sense of the criteria you're thinking in terms of disposals and consolidation? And also what timeframe you might think disposals would occur across?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Farquhar maybe, it's Koos Timmermans.  On the loan book, the guidance is given.  On the sub-prime part, to be honest, the impact on Risk Weighted Asset is nothing because that's all on the Insurance part. So that is where I don't have it.  Prime, there we are talking about the securities, and the securities are part of the investment books. And as long as they are high-graded, which is the normal type of ratings for this portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Uh-huh.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I don't have anything particular on this area to mention.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, with respect to the strategy, I would say our basic strategy continues to be that we want to deal with savings and investments for our customers. That is the foundation for our strategy. And then the criteria that we will use to determine which are the businesses that we want to continue with, there'll be a number of them. I, just, let me mention a few.  We want to look at market position that we have.  We want to look at capital requirements.  We like to look at the risk that's involved in these businesses.  We like to look at the consistency of earnings that you have, the volatility. So all these things together I think will be evaluated, and will be then scored. And I think we like to end up with a portfolio of businesses that really hangs together, that's very coherent and that's for the future in the new environment in which we are in will give us a consistent franchise and a consistent pattern of earnings. I think that's what we are looking for as criteria.  But you need to give us a little bit more time to work this out because we just started with that. And it's a process that we need to do extremely well because this is an important decision point. We cannot afford to make mistakes here.  So we need to do it on the one hand very good, and on the other hand, yes, we need to do it fast as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question comes from William Elderkin from Citi.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning everybody.  I've got two questions on Slide 10. First of all, the Insurance commercial result in the fourth quarter, 348, is that a good reference point to the likely level of earnings over 2009? And if not, can you explain what the exceptional adverse effects are within that 348 number?  And secondly, in terms of the risk costs in the fourth quarter of the Bank, again, is that a sensible reference point to when we start to think about risk costs over 2009 and 2010?  And then my final question is, with ING Direct having headed through about them with a fairly separate balance sheet and then, as I understand it, moving towards more integrated approach, why wasn't that done previously? I assume there must have been positive reasons for the previous strategy, and really what the positives and negatives of a change are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  I'll take the first question, William. This is John here.  The 348 in Q4, you'll see that's below the full-year of 2 billion for Insurance. Q4 saw some squeeze in margins in the basic commercial result on the Insurance side.  It's hard to predict, very hard to predict the global economic view in terms of margins that we're going to see in sales and expenses.  We do have an expense reduction system that will be gearing in, kicking in throughout the year.  So I'd say it's probably between the two.  But again, it's highly variable, and it will depend upon a lot of -- you'd have to read our full forward-looking disclosure to put on that number, I would say today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But would, just on the, if you assume that the very difficult conditions of the fourth quarter were to persist through 2009, for example, is that a sensible reference point in terms for us to be thinking about possible level of earnings?  In other words, there's nothing extraordinary --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let me say, answer it this way. There's nothing exceptional in Q4 other than the higher, slightly higher expenses that can be adjusted for, and some thinning margins. It's a global insurance business, it's, there's a lot of factors going on all over the world that impact that basic number.  But the fourth quarter reflects a pretty hard quarter for the basic business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Maybe on the second question, is the fourth quarter 81 basis point a reference point going forward for our loan losses? I find that an extremely difficult question to answer.  I mean the first thing is the economy in the fourth quarter came to a standstill. And what you see is that some of the companies, therefore, were brought into difficulty and that resulted in the high loan losses which we have right now.  But it is very difficult to foresee at this moment what the real economy will do over this year.  And therefore, yeah, we assume that the loan losses will stay at elevated levels, but to give a precise mark at this moment is more difficult than it ever was.  So I would not like to do that.</p>
          <p>To come back on question number two, and that is the more integration of ING Direct, well, there's a few things. The first is we set it up, ING Direct, separately, and it gives an ease in terms of accountability, in terms of measurability. And at the same time, we also have to note that you set up a business on the ground quicker this way. What was never an issue overall is an overall balance sheet length. We were always working within the rating agency and within the capital constraint, which were there. And an absolute size of a balance sheet was not so much of an issue.  Since it is more open issue right now, you more look at how can I grow my loan book and how can I reduce my re-valuation sensitivity. And at the same time, keep on originating loans. And that is why selectively you try to create some integration between the Direct units.  But the caveat there is the way, how you try to do it is by basically running off or selling some of the bonds and then replacing it internally with loans. But it all has to fit within the regulatory structure and environment as well.  And that is the part what we are pushing on right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question comes from Duncan Russell from JPMorgan.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Hi. Good morning. Okay, so the first question is could you just comment on the duration of the government bonds you're buying? So is it short duration, long duration?  And second question is, you obviously did quite a lot of asset reductions in the fourth quarter. Some CDOs have been and the Alt-A, as well. Have you continued that in the first quarter, and if so, what have you done?  That's it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on the duration side, if we talk about the, we can talk about two types of duration. One is from an pure interest rate perspective. And then from an interest rate perspective, you can say that part of the portfolio where we have floating rate Alt-As, there we also have floating rate facility with the government. And where it's fixed, it's fixed.  So in that sense that is a neutral part. But if we talk more about the contractual obligation, like when do we expect the payback in this transaction or the unwind, I already mentioned something, and that is you expect basically a 50% reduction in five years time.  We are working with an average prepayment fee of approximately 10% per annum on this portfolio.  So it's in line with what we had with the Alt-As.</p>
          <p>If we talk about further reducing exposure, I think if you look at it, yes, this is an ongoing activity, what we have.  For example, over the month of January and in the fourth quarter, we also reduced our hedge fund exposure by 10 billion. And there's more and more of this happening at this moment.  But not in a type of a fire sale type of approach, but selectively.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, on the government bonds, I meant there's a slide which says that you've increased your government bond exposure, both in Insurance and in Banking, I think from 31% to 36, or something like that.  That was more of what I was referring to, what duration of government bonds are you buying?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, okay. On the government bonds, sorry I thought it was more on the government facility, illiquid assets facility.  No, the government bonds that we have been buying have been long-dated because it sort of solves an interest rate-risk gap which we had on the Insurance side.  So I think it is probably more in the 10- and in the 30-yeare that we've been buying. And, David?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's correct, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, 10- and 30-years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question comes from Chris Hitchings from KBW.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks very much indeed.  A couple of issues I'd like to get your thoughts on.  One is dividend.  I think you made a statement somewhere &#x2013; I was trying to find it &#x2013; but it's hard to tell what dividend you're going to be paying in '09.  I think three months ago certainly you were suggesting that the aim would be to try and pay something. Has that view changed?</p>
          <p>Secondly, you made some comments about flows in Retail Banking in January. Do you have any other comments about what went on in the business in January? I think it will be quite helpful</p>
          <p>Third question, yeah, looking at your loan loss provisions, one of the things that I think has worried some people is your loan book to real estate developers, and what the, and what risks are there? I know you said that although, yes the real estate loan loss charges have gone up, could you tell us a bit more about loans-to-value and the actual risks there and where the portfolio is?  And thirdly, just thinking through, you're de-risking the book, you're going into long-term government bonds, there's a view -- how vulnerable do you think ING is if in three-years time to two-years time the principle problem of the financial sector is seen to be very high inflation? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, let me deal with the first question on the dividends.  We have announced that we will not pay a dividend, the final dividends over the year 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And anything related to 2009 is highly speculative, because, first of all, we don't know the numbers yet in 2009. And secondly, I think you need to have more data, also not just 2009, but also more look into the future to see whether you can consistently pay your dividend.  So this is an issue that we need to postpone to a future date.</p>
          <p>With respect to the retail business, I think our retail business in January was doing quite well.  We have seen also ING Direct, it was picking up some nice balances and increasing them.  In fact together, I think, in the last 10 weeks, we have seen more or less roughly a billion increase in savings together.  So it looks like our business is doing relatively well.  And I cannot make any comments on the Insurance because that's a little bit longer dated, and we don't have too many detailed numbers there yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do know, Chris, this is John, that sales although being down, as best we can tell are really in line with what other players are doing.  So it's not, we're not losing market share as a ranking point of view. But clearly we're seeing an overall reduction in unit-linked sales in Asia in variable annuity sales.  They're still being sold, but we're seeing a lower level of activity around the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Uh-huh.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what we're seeing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You, and you had a question on the loan book on real estate. Just I'll clarify it and then Koos can jump in.  The real estate finance are loans to properties, and they're developed in the Netherlands as well as across Europe. It's not to real estate developers.  We do have a development book of our own, which is about 2 billion of properties that we control and we manage. But that's not the real estate finance book.  And Koos, do you have the loan to values on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's quite good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, maybe if, I don't have it here at hand, but I had disclosed at the last time that the loan-to-values of that book is 66 or 67%.  But otherwise, I can look it up. But that is probably what the number is. If I look at the breakdown, Chris, of this portfolio, it's 36 billion real estate finance, 20 or 19 billion of it is in the Netherlands. And then it, the other part is broken down over different countries. Countries of interest: the U.S. has 4.6 billion in there, and Spain 3.5.  So that is, if I look at the country breakdown and for the rest there is other EU in there as well, and relatively small U.K.</p>
          <p>If I then look at the different categories where we are in, it's both residential, offices, real estate and industrial. And in general what you can see there is in a clear division in there: that residential 6; offices 12; for real estate 10; and industrial, 5.  So, and then you have a category, other.  So, it is a relatively diversified portfolio which covers both a different end of the spectrum in terms of types of industry as well as country, but with a big bias in the Netherlands.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Uh-huh. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question comes from Bruno Paulson from Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.  A couple of questions. Firstly, following up on what William was asking earlier, I'm trying to understand the commercial result, which is meant to be the stable bit. It was running at about 2.2 billion a quarter in H1 across Insurance and Banking. Dropped to 1.7 in Q3 and 1.3 in Q4. And I was just trying to understand what's changed, and to the extent that 1.3 is a normal level?  And my second question is, you say that the Risk Weighted Assets in 2009 in the Bank should be roughly flat, ex- the pro-cyclicality, is this excluding the or including the Alt-A deal, which obviously reduces the Risk Weighted Assets? And what is your current best guess of the rough scale of the pro-cyclicality effect to the nearest 5% or so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Bruno, this is John. The commercial result, yeah, you're very correct. The commercial result's been decreasing.  We are driven a lot by client balances, and that is one key factor.  The, second of all, I would categorize would be just spreads in general across the board.  The interest result is, it's slightly up, but then in other spots, in some lines of business, it is down.  We've had some expenses clearly in Q4 and Q3 in various areas, that say late '08 compared to '07 are higher. That's why we're taking strong steps to rectify that, but some of that was also driven by the Postbank and ING Bank movement.  So, also sales are down, which also has an impact across the board for our margins and our businesses.  So I think it's a combination. I would call it general business environment that's driving the lower basic commercial result.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe on the Risk Weighted Assets, on the Risk Weighted Assets side, I stated in my section that overall we expect a more flat-ish type of results. And the flat-ish type of results is, we already, we cash in the 13 billion of Risk Weighted Assets due to the State.  That's fine.  But overall, then, net net, we will get more loan production. So that is a plus in Risk Weighted Asset, but that will be offset by the fact that we try to reduce the investment portfolio.  So, that's a minus. So those two will net out. And then the only thing what you do get is your credit migration, and that brings you to the pro-cyclicality.  And there, I think the only indication which I have for you right now is indeed the 60 basis point. But that would happen if all of your borrowers migrate with one rating category.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, just to be clear, the flat pre-, there were three factors in the first half.  There was the 14 you've got rid off. Then there was the reducing the book. And then there was the increase in lending.  Are you saying the reducing the book and the increase in lending cancel out?  Or the 14 and the reducing the book and the increase in lending cancel out?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I see is the 14 is a plus. And then what we try to do is increase in loans will be offset by the decrease in the investment book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, so you've got, before pro-cyclicality, you've got the gain of what you've unloaded on the State.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question comes from Frank Stoffel from Merrill Lynch.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  It's Frank Stoffel from Merrill Lynch.  Just a few questions, please.  The Alt-A migration in the quarter was quite material, and AAA tranches for example went down from 87% to 65%, I believe. And could you please elaborate how a downward migration of such magnitude is consistent with a 90% Alt-A valuation, in particular as the rating agencies also base their rating on cash flow expectations?  And related to this could you please tell us the share of BBB and BB rated tranches within the Alt-A portfolio at the end of Q4?  Then on your real estate portfolio, which is valued through the P&amp;L, the value in the Netherlands declined by about 12% during the fourth quarter. Is this a genuine value reduction or does this include any disposals?  And related to this, could you please elaborate on the loan-to-value development of your Dutch mortgage book in the fourth quarter?  And lastly, and probably you might have said this, but I might have missed it, the &#x20AC;40 billion balance sheet reduction in the fourth quarter, how much was this in Risk Weighted Asset terms, please?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Maybe let me take the first one on the marks of the market prices of the Alt-A versus the transaction which was done with the State.  I think there is to a certain extent an apples and an oranges there. And one of the things is if I need to sell a 22 billion portfolio to the market, then I will have to pay even probably lower marks than what is currently quoted in the market. But you've to realize that even those market quotes are very thin. We did not for nothing re-classify quite a lot of the portfolio to level C, because it's increasingly difficult in the spectrum of Alt-A to find market prices.  But the biggest part of the difference is that we basically fund this portfolio.  So, in other words, it's not directly a sale price. It is, you could say, the price for our cash flow swap. And that is what this 90 is. What we did is we reconstructed.  We said if a market price is not a market price, let's start with the book price and amortized costs, and then let's take a severe scenario of credit losses. We deduct that from it, and then you end up basically at risk-free cash flows.  And then we say what is the value of those cash flows?  So, we replicated a market price by not looking at markets for this.  So that is basically how we came to the pricing of this transaction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not referring to the market price or to the 66, but just to the fact that the rating agencies when they downgrade the tranches which they have done during the fourth quarter, they also look at cash flow expectations.  And having seen downgrades of the magnitude we have seen in the fourth quarter, how can this be consistent with a 90% valuation which is based on cash flow expectations as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The difference in the --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, but even if you take the following, and let's take Moody's as an example.  They made an outlook and they said we expect 20% cumulative losses on '06, '07 tranches of Alt-A.  If you take 20% losses over time and you have a 15% credit enhancement on the bonds right now, then you expect somewhere down the road 5% of losses to happen on your bonds.  And if you start to discount it, you could even say that is a price of 90 not even at this moment too low a price.  I mean you have to take all those factors into consideration. What the price was based on was basically the input of a company called Credit Dynamics as well, and they looked at factors, and they were actually in line or even a bit more drastic than what Moody's did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. Thank you. Do you have the BBB and BB tranches as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think we were originally in only the AAA type of tranches. But, yes, we did get a serious amount of downgrades as well to BB. But that's where the preliminary or that's, those were the beforehand AAA tranches. And we never invested at beforehand, at the outset into BB tranches.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, sure, but, how much of the portfolio was BBB and BB rated at the end of the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would have to look it up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Frank, this is John.  Your question on real estate, the impact in the Netherlands, that was from re-valuations of the investments that the Netherlands Insurance business has in real estate.  It was not from disposals.  Yeah, your question on the loan-to-value for the, I think you asked for the Dutch mortgage portfolio, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's about 80%. It's about the same as what it always been.  So, there's no major change there.  And, your final question on Risk Weighted Assets, I think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Balance sheet, 40 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, the 40 billion. That was mainly from financial markets and also loans and short-term loans and short-term receivables from banks.  So it didn't -- I don't think there was much of an impact in Risk Weighted Assets from the reduction so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  So, pretty minimal in Risk Weighted Asset terms?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question comes from Farooq Hanif from Morgan Stanley.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there.  I'd just like to focus in two areas. Just stepping back and looking at the big picture again, it seems to me that the gigantic strategic question mark hanging over the future of ING.  The description that you give of what criteria you will have for looking at which businesses you keep and what you do to the shape of your business, the reduction in balance sheet, it all seems to be geared towards paying back the Dutch government. Could you just comment on that?  Is that really underlying all of this, your primary goal, just to pay back 15 billion to the Dutch government? That's question number one.</p>
          <p>Question number two, I'm little bit confused about the reserving adequacy in the US. You say that the, at the 50% confidence level you have quite a small deficit in US retail annuities. But what would that be at the 90% confidence level? And which is more important?  Secondly, you say that on a best estimate basis under U.S. GAAP everything seems to be adequate. But that doesn't stack-up with the 50% confidence level remark that you make. And in terms of the actions that you're going to take, what &#x2013; - isn't there a risk that they might have to be pretty significant, a bit like Taiwan. So you're ending up either reducing your new business growth by a large amount or basically taking away earnings to build up reserves like you did in Taiwan?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Let me mention to you the question related to the strategic question that you ask of paying back the Dutch Government.  I think the most important thing that we need to do, and that has consequences for I think everybody, is to make sure that we create a business that has the ability to generate earnings on a consistent basis. And that will create value for the shareholders as well as for ING.  And I think that is the fundamental, I think, solution also to get the government paid down.  And I think I cannot find another way how we could do this.  This is not going to be a fire sale of activities because that would be the wrong thing to do.  I think we need to look at our opportunities that we have.  We need to put ourselves in the new environment that's coming.  And I think we need to create the best portfolio of businesses, and then run those businesses as hard and as well as we can.  And I think that will create the best possibility for value, as well as to make sure that the Dutch Government will get repaid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When will you be able to come back to us on this? So that, it feels to me like all of the detail that we're looking at in the numbers are kind of irrelevant until we know what that picture is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'm very eager to know that myself.  And I think what we will do, as we will, together with our team that we are looking at, we will come to a conclusion, I think, relatively quick. We need to know that quickly because we want to know how we can get to a more stable position and a better position going forward than we are in right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And on the reserving?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure. The, well the 90 per cent's our core test at a business unit level around the world. And the whole US business is more than sufficient by 900, 600 million at the 90% level, and 2.3 billion positive at the 50% level.  So that's the range and magnitude that we have for the total reserves.  The US retail business which is one business of, that's the VA business and the Fixed Annuity business together, those two product lines have a slight insufficiency at the 50 level.</p>
          <p>And why it this different between this and U.S. GAAP?  We do stochastic testing. And that's why the US Retail Annuity business with low interest rates, you do it, all these stochastic tests and you take a median of that. And that's how you get the insufficiency. U.S. GAAP is just a straight-forward best estimate.  And so you don't see any difference in that when you're just above -- say the guarantees are just above being in the money.  The way we do it is we do this, these, all of these stochastic testing &#x2013; - we did this for years in Taiwan. We were an early warner in Taiwan. We're not saying this is Taiwan, but we will start to deal with this earlier and more proactively because we do this type of testing. And we added the Retail Annuity business in here because what we had in Japan, we figured, you don't ask the question, if you have inadequate in Japan what's going on in the U.S. business.  So, we decided to just give this to you as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The only reason I ask the question was that things have got, obviously got worse since the end of 2008, and I guess I just wanted to get a feeling for really how worried you are about the earnings impact of all of this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, this won't impact earnings at all for the foreseeable future because we have such adequacies for the whole business unit for the U.S., and it, this was -- this inadequacy came because of stochastic testing.  So, it's taken into account a potential worsening situation already in 2009.  And so I think that that's the one thing, if rates stay down and stay low, you will see some DAC adjustments on an ongoing basis.  So, that is what you may have from an earnings impact, because DAC is reset each quarter. And then you move back to basic assumptions going forward. If DAC stays down, stays lower, things don't get worse then you do always have this DAC adjustment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay thank you very, very much.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question comes from Johnny Vo from Goldman Sachs.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi guys.  Just a couple of quick questions.  Just in relation to the pre-release statement and what you've released today, in terms of the capitalization ratios.  All the ratios were broadly in line except for the double leverage ratio, which increased by about 1.2%; which equates to around about, I don't know, &#x20AC;500 million-odd difference.  Can you firstly explain that?  And second thing, in terms of the Taiwanese business that you've sold, how fungible is that capital in the Insurance division to subsidize any other areas of the business where you might need capital? And that's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Johnny, it's John.  Yeah, we, when we gave you the preliminary numbers, we were speaking to the auditors whether or not we needed to accrue the 425 million coupon for the core Tier-1 securities in our IFRS balance sheet because it's not paid yet. We typically don't accrue dividends to shareholders, but due to the complexities of this, we decided to accrue that. And that's the slight difference of the debt equity of the Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the fungibility, the way it all works is that within a business line at a reserving level, the reserves within Taiwan -- so, that is all fungible within the reserving test systems that we have within a business line.  The capital itself, we never put all the capital that we needed into Taiwan. We notionally allocated it and reserved it for us.  So, that is available for us to handle over time. Insurance, particularly in life insurance, these are very long-term contracts. For example, the Taiwan need for capital wasn't going to happen for another 10 or 15 years.  And so, that's why you have these capital budgets. So capital gets released. If it's tied up somewhere, it will be released over time.  So, but we manage that on an ongoing basis. And that of AFR and EC freed up is clearly available, but we do check the duration in cash flow, timing of all this to make sure that it is appropriate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, brilliant.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question comes from Nick Holmes from Nomura.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi.  I had one question firstly on the U.S. Life, which is with the other DAC unlocking in Q4 which you have, which is pretty big, can you tell us what the key assumptions are? What are the equivalents to the 2.25% equity growth? Perhaps you might want to answer that one first, before I move on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, yeah, it varies a lot by product name &#x2013; - it's John. But it's that the interest rates drop and I think also some lapses a little bit. But that was mainly the interest rates being lower, and have to be, get, have to reset.  And -- well, there's the equity and then there's the interest rate. And the interest rate piece was the big piece in -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>this quarter, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you give us any sensitivity for that, because it's quite a big number isn't it, 525?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's much harder to do than the equity markets. But we'll try to work on that for you guys to see if there's something that we can do.  I'm not sure It's kind of tricky for us even, but...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll try to see if we can do something for you on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.  Second question is just looking at the bank bad debts, you said this is pretty difficult forecast for '09. But I wondered how concerned are you that the provisions loans seem to grow very rapidly in '08.  They seemed to grow by 73% from 4.5 billion to 7.8 billion.  What -- whereas the actual provisions only grew by 31%. Does that indicate that something is not quite right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Koos here.  I think what the growth implicates is that we come from a very, very low basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We didn't provision anything at all over the last years 2005, 2006, and 2007. And I think that is what this indicates.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which we're not allowed to under IFRS, Nick. So I mean -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we have nothing to provision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we have to have objective evidence in order to create the provisions. And we had two factors happening. One is less objective evidence to provision, as well as a lot of releases happening from good work-outs of a lot of the problem loans from 2002.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so, now you're getting the other -- the other factor that happens in IFRS is as you enter the cycle, you have less releases and you have to provision relatively more as you enter. And it's sharpest right about now, when you're coming from a very low base and you start to get on track. And then what'll happen is, as the economic cycle let's say steadily gets worse instead of sharply increasing getting worse, then these things start to even out a little more instead of the very sharp turn you've seen in 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.  Okay.  But the NPL coverage, if you want to describe it as that, has deteriorated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, but I think Nick, the NPL coverage doesn't tell too many things, because then you also have to look at what type of loans are non-performing and is there some collateral behind there as well.  So, if you have a mortgage defaulting or non-performing, then given a high collateral under there, your, in general, your amount of provisioning is lower.  So I find it difficult to automatically agree with that statement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so if you had a credit card portfolio, you'd have a very different relationship between your provisions to your loan balances, than if you have low LTV retail mortgage portfolio in a stable environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much for that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question comes from Benoit Patak.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  Slide 43, on the commercial loan book, could you give us the total exposure, as well as the part which is unsecured? And the NPL increase from 1% to 2% in '08.  How much of the increase is actually -- well actually happened in Q4?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Size of the total loan book I think it was something 250 or about.  So, that was the first question.  Second question was on the -- then we are talk about the total NPL increase where the whole of this happened over the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that right?  Just one second.  Okay, I'll come back to you on that question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the question is on Basel II, you give some guidance, 60 basis point guidance. First off, how much notch downgrade do you expect in 2009?  And second, when are you going to provide some more detail, sensitivity analysis, I think on the Basel II on the third-pillar you need to disclose some more on the PD and LGD sensitivity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think in general you will get more of this information in the pillar three disclosure because what we have given you is not so much forecast. What we have given you is a sensitivity, and we said let's not discriminate. All the loan portfolio goes down by basically one rating class, and that is the sensitivity which we have given.  But, it is difficult to translate that into a rating forecast right now. Both internal and external rating, they are pretty volatile at this moment.  But I just wanted to indicate it to you like what does it do to the loan book. And I think it was more the conclusion for me is that a loan book in general has less capital sensitivity than the securitization book if it comes to very low-rated tranches. And that is said, that was the aim of what I try to explain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do not downgrade, that's based on your internal rating or just based on the external rating?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Internal rating.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, internal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Internal rating.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  The next question comes from Tony Silverman from Standard &amp; Poor's Equity Research.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I've just got a couple of questions.  I wonder if you could clarify what you were saying about deposits at ING Direct, which came off a little on -- in Q4. Were you were saying that there any, just in total, that had all been recouped in this quarter?  And the second question was returning to the 525 million of other DAC unlocking on Slide 13.  Is there any element of that that we should in principal add back to the 348 million of commercial results for Q4 in Insurance on Slide 10? And also on the 525 million, some of it is, in the narrative it's said to be due to higher hedging costs.  And I was wondering how much is that element and would that continue going forward if volatilities of equity markets stayed where they are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, on the deposit side, ING Direct, I can say that in the first half of the year, so far year-to-date we have more than recovered what was decline, the decline in Q4. And in fact we have doubled the decline in Q4.  So we have 7 billion so far this year, an increase compared to a decline of only 3 in Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the DAC unlocking, the 525, includes as we said lower interest rates. It also reflects higher credit spreads as they've readjusted the models because that impacts the spreads in fixed annuities going forward.  So, you're going to have just some lower margins and all that is net present value.  How I view all these things, Tony, is, and to the DAC unlocking, if you think the world will stay for the next 5, 10, or 15 years at this level, then this is a correct DAC unlocking correction. If it stays down and slowly gets better, if you think it's going to recover a bit, maybe not in '09 but in 2010, 2011 then a portion of this will all come back into earnings.  So, you have to average these things out over time. Clearly we're at a new level, down, in both equity markets and interest rates, and much higher, I mean, dramatically higher credit spreads. And -- but in my mind, I give credit for this coming back in over time because I expect things will mean revert not to the levels of say the last few years but to a better long-term return that we've seen over a 20-year period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I can just come back on that if I may. Where is that 525 in the Insurance column on Slide 10?  Is it in the 348, or is it in other rows? And it does refer to hedging costs on the right hand side of that Slide 13, and I was wondering how much of it was hedging costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's all in here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's all in other, the great FX hedge, other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which is 736 for Insurance in Q4 and -- well, I'm sorry Tony, what was your second question on the 525 on Slide 13?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It refers to hedging costs higher -- lower interest rate -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>and higher hedging costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so in the quarter we had higher hedging costs, and then we &#x2013; so we took the current volatilities, and then we mean revert those back over a period of time to the norm, to an average. And, but that reduces my margins I'm going to have the next few years as it reverts back. And that's reflected in the DAC unlocking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And over what period do you revert them back?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, is it five years?  Three to five years, I think. It depends upon the -- which assumption, which product we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Thank you, sir.  There appear to be no further questions.  Please continue with any further points you wish to raise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Then I think, we thank you for attending this session.  And we will be back with you in the near future.  Thank you very much.  Bye, bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes the ING's Analyst Conference Call.  Thank you for participating.  You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>