<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1511325" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-01-17</date>
    <companies>
      <company>270</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Mark Henninger</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Paul S. Otellini</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Vice President, Chief Financial Officer &amp; Director of Corporate Strategy">Stacy J. Smith</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Ross C. Seymore</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">C. J. Muse</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Wells Fargo Advisors LLC">David M. Wong</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Vivek Arya</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Joseph Moore</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co. LLC">Stacy Aaron Rasgon</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">Sumit Dhanda</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Glen S. P. Yeung</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="FBR Capital Markets">Craig S. Berger</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies &amp; Co., Inc.">Mark J. Lipacis</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Securities International, Inc.">Romit J. Shah</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (USA) LLC (Broker)">John W. Pitzer</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (USA), Inc.">Shawn R. Webster</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen, and thank you for standing by, and welcome to the Intel Corporation's Fourth Quarter 2012 Earnings Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference may be recorded. Now it is my pleasure to turn the floor over to Mark Henninger with Investor Relations. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Julian <mark type="ph" />, and welcome, everyone, to Intel's Fourth Quarter 2012 Earnings Conference Call. By now you should have received a copy of our earnings release and the CFO commentary that goes along with that. If you've not received both documents they're currently available on our investor website, intc.com.</p>
          <p>I'm joined today by Paul Otellini, our President and CEO; and Stacy Smith, our Chief Financial Officer. In a moment we'll hear brief remarks from both of them followed by Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Before we begin, let me remind everyone that today's discussion contains forward-looking statements based on the environment as we currently see it and as such, does include risks and uncertainties. Please refer to our press release for more information on the specific risk factors that could cause actual results to differ materially. If during the call we use any non-GAAP financial measures or references we'll post the appropriate GAAP financial reconciliation to our website, intc.com.</p>
          <p>And lastly, I'd like to highlight that this year and going forward we'll be holding our annual investor meeting in the fall rather than in May. We'll send out a save the date notice this spring with all the important event logistics; and we'll look forward to seeing you there.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn the call over to Paul.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark, and good afternoon.</p>
          <p>In 2012, Intel generated almost $1 billion of net income every month. This was in an environment of relatively soft PC demand and weak macroeconomic conditions. From a product perspective, 2012 was a year of significant transitions in our markets and a year of important milestones for Intel. I'd like to take a moment to recap a few of the most significant developments.</p>
          <p>The Data Center Group saw a comprehensive refresh across its product line last year. Romley brought the Sandy Bridge architecture to servers for the first time while the launches of Knights Corner and Centerton in the fourth quarter expanded the range of DCG solutions from teraflops to a few watts. Knights Corner, or Xeon Phi, brings 60 cores and the familiar Intel architecture programming model to supercomputing applications. At six watts, Centerton is the industry's only low-power microserver SoC that delivers critical enterprise features like 64-bit, ECC and virtualization.</p>
          <p>Over the last 12 months, we also worked with our industry partners to bring Ultrabooks to the main stream, ramping from roughly 20 designs to more than 140. At CES last week, I was struck by our industry's renewed inventiveness. PC manufacturers are embracing innovation as we are in the midst of a radical transformation of the computing experience with the blurring of form factors and the adoption of new user interfaces. It's no longer necessary to choose between a PC and a tablet. Convertibles and detachables combined with Windows 8 and touch provide a two for one no-compromise computing experience.</p>
          <p>Ultrabooks have also served to accelerate the trend towards thinner and lighter notebooks. For example, the volume of systems less than one-inch thin grew 18-fold last year in the U.S. and we expect to same trend continue around the world. Last quarter our customers also began shipping tablets based upon our Clover Trail SoC and Windows 8. These systems boast up to 10 hours of battery life, three weeks of connected standby and come in a range of sleek ultra-light form factors all while bringing the benefits of software compatibility with the millions of Windows applications written for Intel architecture. There are now 10 Clover Trail tablets shipping today with several more launching in the coming months.</p>
          <p>2012 was a milestone year for Intel architecture in smartphones with our customers now shipping seven devices across 20 countries. These phones use our 32-nanometer Medfield SoC and are extremely competitive with the best ARM designs on performance and equal or better power and battery life. We saw the introduction of our 22-nanometer manufacturing process and along with it, a revolutionary new Tri-Gate or 3D transistor technology. Twenty-two nanometer products represented more than half of our volume in the fourth quarter as the rest of the industry works to ship its very first Tri-Gate designs.</p>
          <p>In July, we announced an important strategic relationship with ASML, which combined with our process technology expertise will, accelerate deployment of EUV and 450-millimeter technologies, helping to ensure the future of Moore's Law and our growing manufacturing leadership.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead to 2013, I'm excited about the strong pipeline of products we have coming to market. In the first half of this year we will launch Haswell, enabling one of the most significant changes to the PC since Centrino in 2003. Haswell was designed from the ground up to enable breakthrough innovations in form factor, battery life and usability. It will deliver the single largest generation-to-generation battery life improvement in Intel's history, and is inspiring a new wave of ultra-sleek convertible touch-based designs across our customer base. Later this year, we will ship 22-nanometer versions of our Xeon and Atom products for the Data Center, bringing the power, performance and efficiency benefits of 3D transistor technology to our entire Data Center product line.</p>
          <p>In 2013, we'll also begin to deliver the industry's first 22-nanometer tablet and smartphone SoCs to OEMs. We are now shipping our single-mode data LTE baseband to customers and over the course of the year, we'll begin delivering multi-mode data and voice modems to customers giving us a full complement of competitive technologies to grow our Device business. Last but not least we will begin our transition to 14-nanometers as we begin the world's first 14-nanometer products towards the end of this year.</p>
          <p>We see the industry in a period of transition and hyper-innovation. We are well positioned to take advantage of these trends across the spectrum of computing, from the lowest power portable devices to the most powerful data center servers and everywhere in between.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn the meeting over to Stacy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Paul.</p>
          <p>The fourth quarter came in consistent with our expectations. For 2012, although our financial results were below our expectations entering the year, we launched leadership products in every major business segment, and we extended our manufacturing leadership. In 2012, revenue was $53.3 billion, gross margin was 62%, operating income was $14.6 billion, net income was $11 billion and earnings per share was $2.13.</p>
          <p>For the year, the business continued to generate significant cash with almost $19 billion of cash from operations. We increased the dividend per share by 7% resulting in over $4 billion in dividends paid and repurchased roughly $5 billion of stock. We continued to invest in our manufacturing leadership. We purchased $11 billion in capital assets, primarily building and equipping leading edge factories and made a $3 billion strategic equity investment in ASML. Lastly, we took advantage of record low interest rates and borrowed $6 billion.</p>
          <p>Total cash investments ended the year at roughly $18 billion, up approximately $3 billion from a year ago. Revenue of $53.3 billion was down 1% from a year ago and below the expectations we had at the start of the year. Worldwide GDP growth was significantly less than we had thought entering the year and the PC market segment was impacted by the growth of tablets.</p>
          <p>Our PC client group was down 3% from a year ago. The data center group grew 6% year-over-year as a richer mix of products and significant growth in the Internet cloud segment of our business was partially offset by weakness in the enterprise server market. Gross margin of 62% in 2012 was flat to 2011 and at the high end of our historical range for the third year in a row. Our investments in industry leading manufacturing process technology continued to pay off through leadership products and a highly responsive factory network.</p>
          <p>We invested over $10 billion in research and development in 2012, up almost $2 billion from a year ago. The increase was driven by investments in Ultrabooks, the data center, phones and tablets. In addition, we made investments in core capabilities like security, SoCs and extending our process technology leadership. Spending as a percent of revenue was 34%. Fourth quarter revenue finished at $13.5 billion, in line with our expectations. We believe the worldwide PC supply chain saw a continued reduction in inventory levels in the fourth quarter as customers reduced inventory of older generation PCs.</p>
          <p>Gross margin of 58% was up one point from expectations and down five points from the third quarter. The drop from the third quarter was driven primarily by excess capacity charges as a result of the aggressive tactical actions we took to reduce inventory levels and to redirect space and equipment to 14-nanometer. Our inventories decreased almost $600 million from the third quarter as a result of these actions.</p>
          <p>Separately, we started production on our next generation micro architecture product code named Haswell, which we expect to qualify for sale this quarter. This production prior to qualification for sale resulted in an increase in inventory write offs. Operating income for the fourth quarter was $3.2 billion with earnings per share of $0.48.</p>
          <p>As we look forward to the first quarter of 2013, we are forecasting the midpoint of the revenue range at $12.7 billion, down 6% from the fourth quarter. This forecast is in line with the average seasonal decline for the first quarter. We are forecasting the midpoint of the gross margin range for the first quarter to be flat at 58% as the impact of higher factory start-up costs and lower volumes are offset by lower excess capacity charges and the qualification for sale of Haswell.</p>
          <p>Turning to 2013, we are planning for revenue growth in the low single digits and forecasting the midpoint of our gross margin range at 60%. Capital spending for our Core business should be expected to be roughly flat to 2012. Additionally, we will spend roughly $2 billion to start building our first 450-millimeter development facility. We are forecasting spending for the year at $18.9 billion, a $700 million increase from 2012. This is the full year impact of the increase to investments in R&amp;D that occurred in 2012 and annual salary increases for 2013.</p>
          <p>As a result of the significant progress we made in 2012 across all of our product lines I enter 2013 optimistic about our long-term prospects. A year ago we were just introducing the concepts of Ultrabooks to the world. Today the market has been redefined with thin, light powerful Ultrabooks and convertibles. A year ago Intel was not shipping products into the tablet market. Today we have Clover Trail tablets shipping in the market delivering performance and power benefits versus what our competitors can do.</p>
          <p>And in 2013, we will ramp our next generation tablet SoC code name Bay Trail in both the Windows and Android markets. Intel is now inside seven shipping smartphone designs and here again the third party benchmarks show that we're not only capable of matching the competition in power efficiency, we are leading them. In 2012 we built on the strength of our Data Center offering and we expect to return to double digit revenue growth in 2013.</p>
          <p>And lastly, we built on our manufacturing lead and are well into the ramp of our 22-nanometer factories and will start production on the 14-nanometer process this year. This puts us significantly ahead of the competition. The combination of new products and design wins across all segments and our manufacturing leadership will benefit our business in the quarters to come.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn it back over to Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you, Paul and Stacy. We'll now move on to Q&amp;A and as is our normal practice we ask each participant to ask one question and just one follow up if you have one. <mark type="ph" /> Julian, please go ahead and introduce our first questioner?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sir. Our first question comes from the line of Ross Seymore with Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One for Paul. If I look back between the last two years and then heading into what you just guided to for 2013 it seems like your CapEx and your OpEx are outgrowing revenues. I guess if I partner that together with where the stock's trading valuation-wise, it really looks like investors are dubious as to when any returns are going to come from those investments. So I guess the question after that is, when do you see the investments come &#x2013; or the return on these investments coming? How long do you think this investment stays last and what are some of the mile markers we should look for to see those returns being generated?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there's two parts to the CapEx this year, I mean two large parts to the CapEx this year, Ross. One is you're starting to see our first significant investments in bricks and mortar and some equipment for the 450-millimeter transition, which happens later part of this decade. We have to make those investments earlier. Those are &#x2013; now that we've solidified our relationship and contractual relationship with ASML, it gives us line of sight to that conversion and therefore we're now in a better position to predict the exact timing and deploy capital for that. So I would treat that as a more of an extraordinary event that's not related to the day-to-day business in terms of volume in 2014, 2015, 2016.</p>
          <p>The CapEx that we are projecting on a base level, $13 billion minus the $2 billion is $11 billion which is about what we spent last year and as I look forward into the business, in 2014 and 2015 as we finish up the 14-nanometer factories and begin deployment of the construction of and equipping of the 10-nanometer factories, we need those factories. Principally for our view of the computing market and in that I would include tablets, and certainly the Data Center. So as we look at it, it gets used. Remember the leading edge capacity is the lowest cost for us on a per unit basis, the highest performance and the lowest power. So regardless of what you think the size of the market is, those leading edge fabs are the single greatest asset that we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess as my one follow up just playing off that, is the capacity that you're going to have and I realize the 450 stuff isn't coming until later but is most of the incremental capacity for your Core PC related business or when you say computing is it more DCG and I guess the word computing could even include tablets and smartphones?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, when I'm talking about that, I was specifically including the enterprise business, Data Center business, the PC business as we've known it and as it's evolving and I would include tablets in that because as we look forward it's very difficult to distinguish between a detachable clamshell notebook and a tablet. The form factors are going to blur here. The performance requirements are going be the same spectrum of performance requirements that we think we've seen in the PC space over the last few years. I kept phones separately out of that discussion because I think the relative volume in phones in terms of this deployment of CapEx is still relatively small.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Our next question comes from the line of C. J. Muse with Barclays Capital. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon. Thank you for taking my question. I guess as a follow-up to Ross' question on CapEx, if we exclude that $2 billion on 450 and we look at the core spending, can you talk about the spending on bricks and mortar last year and anticipated this year as a percentage? And also how we should think about equipment spend as part of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Hi, C. J., this is Stacy. I'll take that. Yeah, let me break out that capacity-related CapEx in a couple of different ways.</p>
          <p>First if you look at it by process, it's very much driven by building for the peak of 14-nanometer. And then it's the start of the investment in 10-nanometer. So just building on what Paul said, if you think about that, it's really building for units that we expect in 2014 and 2015 because that's where you start to see the peak of 14-nanometer and the start of the ramp of 10.</p>
          <p>In terms of the breakout between what's for facilities versus what's for equipment, as I had showed at the investor meeting back in May, we're seeing that the facility-related spending is coming back in a higher proportion &#x2013; it's coming down and a higher proportion of that CapEx is for equipment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just as part of that, are you capitalizing investment in ASML or the R&amp;D investment in ASML?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. That's not a capital expense. It was an investment expense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. And I guess as my follow up, in terms of the guidance for low single digit top line growth in 2013, can you walk through the underlying assumptions particularly as it relates to your outlook for PCs and the DCG group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we said on the &#x2013; I said in my prepared remarks we expect the Data Center Group to return to double digit revenue growth. And just diving into that, it's the cloud data center plus our participation in portions of the market like storage and some of the networking sections of the market. It's both unit and ASP based on the strength of our product line and sellout. And then for the kind of core PC market, the traditional PC market, we have pretty modest expectations around units and we think where the growth comes from are these devices that sit in the middle, so the convertibles, kind of the best of the tablet and the PC and then our beginning of participation across the tablet market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Our next question comes from the line of David Wong with Wells Fargo. Please go ahead. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. The $2 billion for future 450-millimeter production, is this an ongoing expense? Will you need to put in a similar amount next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so as Paul said, what changed over the course of 2013 is the industry consortium around 450 triangulated on first equipment to be available in 2015, which is why people are starting to talk about pilot lines in that timeframe. And frankly a lot of that was enabled by our investment in ASML allowed kind of the alignment around that timeline. And so when we look at 2015 as the time where we can have equipment available, we want to start the production or the construction of a development facility. That's typically a couple of year cycle. And so I'd expect there's some facility-related spending next year that's kind of in the range of what we're spending this year. And then we won't get into the capital-related spending for this into the back half of the decade &#x2013; but the production-related capital spending into the back half of this decade.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks. And does the beginning of the 10-nanometer spending that you'll be dealing with this year, does that assume immersion lithography or EUV?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I'll save that disclosure for our technologists. We tend to be pretty close to the vest with those kinds of things for obvious reasons, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Our next question comes from Vivek Arya with Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. Paul, there are some reports about Intel potentially manufacturing some ASICs for Cisco. My question is not about Cisco per se but it's really a broader question is that, is Intel fundamentally set up from an operational or a financial perspective to become specialized foundry? And what would be some of the financial metrics and the kind of end markets that you would target?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, my view on this, Vivek, hasn't changed since the analyst meeting, the investor meeting, in May so I can reiterate that for you. We are very interested in being a selective foundry manufacturer for certain customers. We don't see ourselves as a general purpose foundry or competing with the general purpose foundries. The kinds of things we would do would certainly not, we would not take business that would enable a competitor. We would certainly consider business that would enable and strengthen relationships with strategic partners. The kinds of things that we've announced so far have been in the programmable logic area, which is an area that Intel is not in today, so that makes perfect sense. And those kinds of companies need leading edge technology. So that's the pattern for which we would do this.</p>
          <p>So, yeah, we are in a position to be able to handle those kinds of customers. It's &#x2013; we've been building up that capability for several years now, and we're now going into production. I described this I think in May as a crawl, walk, run strategy, and we're still in the crawl part of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And to the second part of the question around our expectations around return, I mean, it's pretty simple. We want to &#x2013; to the extent that we engage with these foundry customers we want to make money at it. We want to get paid in terms of margin, and we want to get a return on our invested capital that's commensurate with our technology leadership.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thank you. And as my follow up, we have recently started seeing an increased adoption of ARM's Cortex-A15 processors. And I believe earlier today TSMC spoke about their optimism with the 20-nanometer process ramping up next year at a faster pace than they had ramped 28-nanometer. So my question is, do you see the competition catching up in terms of performance? Or in general, how should we view the computing landscape? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't. I view us now that we've matched the power performance, the power battery life curves and we're still on 32-nanometers. As we move to 22 and 14, you'll see us accelerate. We've looked at the A15, we've looked at the A-15 specs and we know our own silicon in terms of Bay Trail and Clover Trail plus and we're very comfortable that we can maintain a performance lead here. Microarchitecture is hard, and it's something we've got 30 years of experience at. And these devices are simply becoming very small computers, and that's what Intel is exceptional at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Vivek.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from the line of Joe Moore with Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you, just a follow up on the foundry question. You did say at the analyst meeting that you hadn't earmarked any of the capital spending for foundry. Is that still the case when you look at the 2013 spending?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean, other than two small customers or three small customers that you've heard of, it is not driving our CapEx.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And if you talk about getting your historic returns, what does that imply on the price per wafer that you would charge relative to what other foundries charge on an apples-to-apples basis? Or is that too difficult to think about because you're a process node ahead?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, we're pricing real time with customers. So it's not per wafer. Most people are now pricing &#x2013; the foundries are pricing per die or per millimeter-squared, and that tends be the model that we would use here, too, for the most part depending on the level of technology we're talking about. And the pricing here is going be value based pricing. I mean, obviously it has to be competitive, but the value that we bring in terms of the technology is, I think, pretty exceptional.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Our next question comes from the line of Stacy Rasgon with Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Thanks for taking my questions. It sounds to me like you're guiding traditional PCs down a ton this year and yet you seem to be making a very big bet on revenue growth into 2014 because it seems like this slug of CapEx doesn't really start getting depreciated until then. So how much, I guess, do you need to take in terms of share within tablets? Or how much of that tablet market needs to be eaten up by your convertible PCs in order I guess to fill that big bet in 2014 that you seem to be making and avoid the underutilization that may otherwise happen from the CapEx that you're spending?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I guess I'd take issues with the characterization of guiding PCs down a ton and then some big snap back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You said revenues were up 2% with Data Center up in the double digits which implies that &#x2013; and phones and tablets ramping which implies that the Core PC business is down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, so I said for the company it's low single digits in terms of our expected revenue growth. Data Center up in the, back into the double digits. You still end up with client growth when you go through that. And I think the point that Paul was making earlier is a really important one, which is, the lines between a traditional notebook, a convertible, a tablet I think have blurred to the point that it's a market for computing and we are expecting some units.</p>
          <p>Now Q1 we think is seasonally down. That's what we guided, but when we get into the back half and you have a combination of new products in the market and an improving macroeconomic environment, I thank that's a fairly reasonable assumption on the year. As we think out into the future, we kind of are thinking of it as just more or less normal growth consistent with what we've historically seen from a unit standpoint. It's just growth across a much wider range of devices than what we've historically supported.</p>
          <p>I don't know if you want to add anything to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I guess to follow-up on that, I mean my math suggests that you're guiding depreciation this year at a $1.7 billion quarterly run rate which is kind of flat, which suggests to me that the CapEx, that your incremental CapEx you're spending this year doesn't actually start getting depreciated next year, which again tells me that you're looking for a fairly solid amount of growth in 2014 to cover that. At the same time I know you talked about phones and Data Center and PCs and everything adding to that. But the Data Center business you sell, what, right now 16 million chips a year or something like that, which can't fill a fab. You have phones, which Paul admitted were probably still going to be small, then you have tablets where the dies are a lot more smaller. So unless you're driving tons and tons of volume there's actually not a ton of wafer volume, so what sort of growth I guess what sort of &#x2013; is it enough to &#x2013; is sort of your historical level of unit growth enough to fill the CapEx you're putting in? And what gives you confidence that you can even have that same kind of historical level of unit growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it is, Stacy, and I think that we have line of sight into what our customers are designing around Haswell, which is this year's innovative new Core product, and Broadwell, which is next year's. We know the specs on those. The customers know the specs on those. I've seen the prototypes of the industrial designs. They're really exciting products. Our customers have not had this level of performance and this kind of form factor before. So you know, to some extent we're branch predicting that that level of product will generate sufficient excitement to keep the client growth going. We're not project &#x2013; we're not in any of our numbers, in none of our numbers are we projecting an inflection point upwards or downwards. We see renewed growth around these new form factors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You have room to modulate CapEx down the rest of the year...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Stacy, we want to make sure we get time for everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. You bet. Thanks, guys. Appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you sir. Our next question comes from Sumit Dhanda with the ISI group. Please go ahead. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. A couple questions. One question on what happened in Q4 seems like your PC client units were down 4% so third party data for PCs was up 2% to 3% sequentially, depending on who you look at. Was this mainly an inventory drain? And perhaps if you could talk just broadly about the inventory picture at your customers, Paul, as you exited the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'll take that. Yeah we think that there was a inventory drain in the worldwide supply chain for PCs in the fourth quarter. Our channel checks would suggest that a lot of older generation Windows 7 PCs were burned off in the quarter. When we look overall at inventory levels across the downstream inventory, we think it's a healthy level of inventory. It looks appropriate for how we see demand. And then in terms of our own inventory levels, obviously, we reduced them significantly in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then for my follow up, it's on ASPs. They're up both in the Data Center and the PC client group. Any particular dynamic at work? I know in the third quarter Data Center ASPs are weak because of the mix. If you could shed any light on both those categories? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. In the Data Center, as I said in my comments, the big driver was Romley, was shipping, which is the Sandy Bridge server part. That drove the mix up and it drove the mix to MP up and that helped drive the overall richness of the Data Center business. On PCs what we saw was strength in the Core product line, principally going into Ultrabooks and laptops and a little more weakness than we would have first thought in the bottom of the PC market in our Celeron and Pentium product lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Our next question comes from Glen Yeung with Citi. Please go ahead. Your line is now open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I guess question for you Paul on the potential for hybrid or even just Ultrabooks in the second half of 2013, and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (32:26) pointed out that, I think we're starting to see a bifurcation where we're selling these small tablets and they seem to be selling well. And actually the 10-inch tablet maybe not be selling as well as one would have expected and I wonder if that's not somehow opening up opportunity for the laptop, the Ultrabook, the hybrid to make a bit of a comeback?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think you're &#x2013; the &#x2013; I mean coming out of CES the trends are pretty clear, certainly in Asia in terms of the buying patterns. Phones are getting bigger. And you saw the "phablets" which is a phone-tablet sort of form factor emerge, which are 6, even 7-inch phones. And then, of course, the shift of tablets from 10 to 7 inches. And I think that's probably what you're going to see is that the market will bifurcate between sort of the 5 to 7-inch type of products and the 10-plus inch type of products. And the 10-plus inch type of products, particularly as you get to 12, 13 inches, are going be more classic PC level of performance and now enabled by these convertible, detachable form factors that only get thinner as Haswell and Broadwell come on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, interesting. And maybe as a follow-up, Stacy, just trying to think through the cash balance that Intel's comfortable working with because it is a lot of spending coming up in a year where it's kind of anemic revenue growth. What's the level of cash at which you feel comfortable? And is there any need, I know you raised debt recently, any need you think to have to do that again at some point during the course of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not need, but we would certainly look opportunistically like we have been. And we certainly have capacity if we ever wanted to. But I think it's instructive to just look at where we are. If you just take Q4 which we would say was a relatively tough quarter at the top line, macroeconomic weakness, the impact of tablets on our business, we generated $6 billion of cash flow from operations. We had $2.5 billion of CapEx. We paid a little over $1 billion in dividends. So we're generating plenty of cash to invest in our business and to pay the dividend and protect the dividend. So I'm not worried about it from that standpoint. And as I model out 2013 I get to a similar model where I'm generating more cash than I need for those two things.</p>
          <p>In terms of the cash balance that I'm comfortable with, I'm &#x2013; I'm comfortable with how much cash we have today. I could live with a little bit less also. And we make those decisions tactically as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Glen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Next question in queue comes from the line of Craig Berger with FBR Capital Markets. Please go ahead. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. Thanks for taking my call. I wonder if you could update us on your acquisition of Infineon Wireless? It's been almost a couple years and specifically where you are with 4G LTE? Where you are with an integrated baseband plus Atom part? And when we can expect to see more progress on handsets? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Well, Infineon is doing well. They are well on their way to an LTE solution. I talked about that in my commentary, but to reiterate what I said was that we're shipping the data mode now. We'll have the dual data mode and the voice mode shipping later this year. First LTE phones I would expect to launch early next year, principally around MWC [Mobile World Congress] 2014. We believe we have a very competitive solution. The Infineon team is known for not necessarily being first to market, but being really good at engineering a very solid solution and being cost effective and cost competitive. And I think that they're doing a very good job on the specs of this product. In terms of integrated solutions you'll see higher levels of integration from us next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Craig, if I could just add to that, too, Paul talked about our roadmaps. The thing I'm struck by in this space is how hungry it is that the customers are to work with us in this space. So I think it's a nice combination of &#x2013; we're &#x2013; got a good rollout of products across the year and it looks like people are really lining up to have us as one of their key partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just following up on the &#x2013; on this topic of conversation. Any plans to do anything more interesting strategically in terms of putting them in PCs? Or any plans to develop Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, GPS, NFC to integrate down the road? And lastly, do you expect growth from Infineon in 2013? Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on the middle one, all of the above. We have many of those technologies in house now, and we are doing levels of integration that make sense at the right time. In terms of PCs the problem has not been technical. The problem has been price, and most PC manufacturers would prefer for IP and royalty base reasons to not build that into their PCs. And to have it be either an add-in chip through a slot or an add-in service through a dongle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Growth in 2013? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. We forgot about that. I would expect that as the LTE solutions are ramping in the marketplace, we'll start to see growth. So I don't think it's going be much in 2013 and then it kind of goes from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Craig.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Our next question comes from Mark Lipacis with Jefferies. Please go ahead. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question. The question I have is on your &#x2013; if you could share with us your view on price elasticity in the client PC market in either an aggregate or on the notebook side. And I guess what I'm wondering is for the better part of last decade the model seemed to be &#x2013; you dropped your prices something on the order of 5%, 6% a year. You drive like and then that drove 10% to 12% unit growth and you got mid-single digit revenue growth. Then in 2010 and 2011 you crushed the revenue growth, your prices went up but your unit growth really did not. Now in 2012, we have a down year, 2013 is low single digit growth. And I'm wondering if you think there's elasticity in the market and if you expect to drive your ASPs down in order to drive that elasticity? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think there's &#x2013; Mark, thank you. I don't think there's classic elasticity in the &#x2013; there's much elasticity in the classic form factors. What we saw &#x2013; actually if you wind the tape back earlier than your comments, what we saw was a similar kind of price elasticity in the desktop in the 1980s and 1990s. When PCs broke $1,000, volume went dramatically up and then the desktop PC continued to drop down until it stabilized at sort of the price points where minimum margin was available for all the players. And the cheapest desktop was a $299 sort of model or something like that. Notebooks went the same way. First notebooks were $3,000, now notebooks are $299 to $1,299 in terms of the sweet spots. And I think people will buy based upon their need within those price points, but it's very difficult for me to see them going from $299 to $99. The bill of materials just doesn't support it.</p>
          <p>What we're likely to see and what we saw in the fourth quarter in fact in the Windows 8 touch enabled models was that people were willing to spend a little bit more to get a more capable product. And that's certainly been true in the Apple model for many, many years, and I think that there is a model of getting paid for innovation. Intel's Core product line has always shown that. Now you're starting to see it I think in the system level price points as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. For a follow up, if I may, EUV, do you guys have a view on when you can expect to start putting that into the factories? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, again, this is the immersion question. It's one that we keep those things pretty close to our vests. So it's not what I'm prepared to talk about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Our next question comes from Romit Shah with Nomura. Please go ahead.  Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks a lot. Stacy, if I take the 10 year median for revenue growth starting in Q2 I only get to flat revenue growth for 2013. So it looks like you're expecting a better than seasonal quarter. Could you talk a little bit about just how the year may play out in terms of trajectory?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I don't think you mean better than seasonal quarter for Q1. I think you mean a better than &#x2013; a back half that's stronger than normal seasonality. Is that what you mean?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah, and that's consistent with our view. And first and foremost it comes down to if you look at consensus GDP estimates, the consensus today is that there's a pretty significant strengthening in the worldwide economy over the course of the back half of this year. Over that same 10 years, the first correlation of our business is GDP growth. And then beyond that it's the kinds of things that Paul's been talking about. You have Haswell coming into the marketplace, Windows 8 gaining traction, touch gaining traction. So you have these great devices that are coming in that are convertibles and kind of the best of the PC and the tablet experience. And then we become more and more represented across both the Windows tablet section of the market and Android over the course of 2013 and the combination of that puts us into a situation where we believe we have kind of more than seasonal second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm a little confused on how to think about Q2. It seems like seasonality is changing, the 10 year median's down 1%, but I've noticed just over the last couple years, Q2's been actually up anywhere from 1% to 5%. How do you guys look at it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll talk about Q2 in 90 days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Romit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, we're going to go ahead...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. We're going to go ahead and take two more questions if you would please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sir. Our next question comes from the line of John Pitzer with Credit Suisse. Please go ahead. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon, guys. Thanks for letting me ask the question. Paul, in 2011 the emerging market was perhaps a better cushion then investors thought for the Core PC business. In 2012 it was kind of maybe a bigger headwind than people thought coming into the year. Kind of curious when you look at the 2013 guide, how are you thinking about emerging market? Was 2012 all just about decelerating GDP? Or do you think there was some interplay of some white box tablets starting to cannibalize within that region as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think &#x2013; I think that in particular in China, the market dynamics are not much different, at least in the Tier 1 through 3 cities, different than the U.S. So yeah, there's clearly some tablet sales that impacted low end or first time buyer PCs in China. But I think the bigger issue is &#x2013; was, in China and in Brazil last year which are the two largest emerging market countries, was their overall economic health. Remember Brazil started seeing inflation that slowed down PC sales. China, the growth dropped and they had a regime change. And we saw people stalling around what the policies would be post regime change and so forth. And now as we look into 2013, as Stacy said, China is still outgrowing any other large economy in the world and I think will be a driver for PC sales.</p>
          <p>We've been pleasantly surprised by the data center growth in China. They're deploying fairly large amounts of servers for infrastructure build out and that's helped our overall revenue picture in that country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Paul, that's helpful. And as a follow up, Stacy, on the OpEx side, other IA in the quarter is now annualizing on almost a $2 billion operating loss. As you think about kind of the OpEx, is this now the right run rate for all the new initiatives? And how do we think about that other IA category maybe marching towards a breakeven number as tablets phones become a bigger part of the revenue stream?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the &#x2013; we're not increasing &#x2013; we're not making incremental investments in 2013. And so if you look at 2013 we expect employment to be pretty flat. So I think that the answer to your question is yeah, we think we're investing at the right level. We do have an increase in OpEx as we go from 2012 to 2013, and it's just the full-year impact of the R&amp;D investments that we talked about in 2012. And that's investments that are really been driven by Ultrabooks and tablets and phones and our SoC capability as well as our process technology leadership. And it's interesting. I think that it's &#x2013; that when you look at our performance in the business, we've got some great products in the market.</p>
          <p>I think 2013 will be a year where we're fighting and hopefully winning some big designs. I think you'll see many of those designs coming to the market in the tablet space as we talked about. In the phone space, it'll &#x2013; the volume will grow over time. And we expect that the business grows into this investment level over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And our final question will come from the line of Shawn Webster with Macquarie. Please go ahead. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks for squeezing me in, guys. Fist question on gross margins. They're a little bit &#x2013; looks like they're a little better. I was wondering if you could share with us, you said your utilization rates would be below I think 50% in Q4. I was wondering if you could share with us where they landed? And what you expect the trajectory to be in Q1 and maybe even beyond if you can?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Yeah, we came in at a gross margin level a little bit better than expected in the fourth quarter and it played out from a utilization standpoint pretty much as we expected. We brought the loading down in the factories significantly. It was below 50%. We redirected equipment to intercept some of the leading edge process technology and we managed to bring inventory levels down on the order of $600 million which was all consistent with what we said.</p>
          <p>As we go into Q1 the forecast for gross margin is roughly flat. What you're seeing there in terms of excess capacity is we'll continue to see improvement in excess capacity and we're going to start to see the increase in start-up costs. And those, at rough order those two things offset and there's a couple of other puts and takes but it ends up with a flat gross margin.</p>
          <p>As I think through then the shape for the year which is the last part of your question, when I get to Q2, I think what happens is we see the further reduction in the excess capacity charges. In fact, they'll be pretty much gone in Q2, but Q2 is where we will peak in terms of the start-up costs. And I think that the start-up cost impact is a little bit more than the reduction in the excess capacity so I'd expect gross margin in Q2, everything else being equal, to be kind of flat to down.</p>
          <p>Then we put 60% out for the year so you should think about the second half expectations of gross margin back into the low-60s. And when I think about the drivers of that, it's the reduction in start-up costs because we peak in Q2 and they start to come down, it's increases in volume which would be consistent with a seasonal second half and then our costs come down over the course of the back half of this year and those are the three tail winds that I project, get me back up above 60%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks. And if I might I have a question on some of the other &#x2013; I mean if we load in the low single digit revenue growth you have for this year and we throw in the double digit data center and we throw in a single digit growth in PC client, that means the rest of your business must be falling something like 8% year-over-year for calendar 2013. And some of these segments like the other IA group include some of your growth areas like you've been talking about in tablets and smartphones. Can you share with us your build plan, I mean not your build plan but your plan for the year or how you're thinking about some of these other groups over the course for the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. At first, I don't get to the same math and so we'll just start there. We talked about both the PCCG Group and we've talked about the Data Center Group being back in the low double digits. When we kind of run through the rest of the businesses, we would expect to start to see some progress in tablets over the course of the year. I think phones is going be &#x2013; we'll be winning designs but it's not going to move the needle from a revenue standpoint. We talked about IMC in terms of I think that growth returns to that business as LTE ramps which is really come out in time or the end of this year and into next year. We expect embedded will see some growth. It's been nice growth engine for us and we think NAND grows.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I hit them all there. I don't think I missed anything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, Shawn. All right. Thank you, Julian <mark type="ph" />, and thank you all for joining us today. Julian <mark type="ph" />, please go ahead and wrap up our call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sir. Ladies and gentlemen, this does conclude today's conference. Thank you for your participation and have a wonderful day. Attendees, you may disconnect at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>