<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1275852" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-01-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>270</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">R. Kevin Sellers, Vice President, Finance and Director, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Paul S. Otellini, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Stacy J. Smith, Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Ross Seymore</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Timothy Luke</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Mark Lipacis</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Uche Orji</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Doug Freedman</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Adam Benjamin</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Manish Goyal</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Stacy Rasgon</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Glen Yeung</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">John Pitzer</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Sumit Dhanda</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">James Covello</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Graham Tanaka</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Craig Berger</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Suji De Silva</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Auguste Richard</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="analyst">Brendan Furlong</participant>
      <participant id="21" type="analyst">Hans Mosesmann</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to the Q4 2009 Intel Corporation Earnings Conference Call. My name is Christina, and I will be your coordinator for today. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise. After the speakers' remarks, there will be a question and answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>As a reminder, this conference is being recorded for replay purposes. I would now like to turn the presentation over to your host for today's call, Mr. Kevin Sellers, Vice President of Investor Relations. Please proceed, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Christina, and welcome, everyone, to Intel's Fourth Quarter 2009 Earnings Conference Call. I'm joined today as usual by our Chief Executive Officer, Paul Otellini, and Chief Financial Officer Stacy Smith.</p>
          <p>Our earnings release and updated financial statements were released today at approximately 1:15 Pacific Daylight Time and can be found on our investor website, INTC.com. This quarter we continued the practice that we started last quarter of posting additional management commentary from CFO Stacy Smith to our investor website. This commentary was posted at approximately 1:30 p.m. Pacific Daylight Time and contains added detail about our quarterly performance that was previously reviewed in prepared remarks during our conference call.</p>
          <p>As we begin our call, let me remind everyone that today's discussion contains forward-looking statements based on the environment as we currently see it and as such does include risks and uncertainties. Please refer to our press release for more information on the specific risk factors that could cause actual results to differ materially. If during our call today there are any non-GAAP financial references made, we will post the appropriate GAAP financial reconciliation to our investor website.</p>
          <p>So with that, let me now hand it over to Paul for some comments, followed by brief remarks from Stacy. Paul?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Kevin.</p>
          <p>Our fourth quarter results cap a great year of execution and innovation for Intel. We started the year in one of the deepest recessions in our history and emerged from it with better products and technology driving new demand for computing worldwide. Our restructuring efforts have borne real fruit by improving the operational efficiency of the company, driving relatively good results in challenging times, and exceptional results in a stronger market.</p>
          <p>The demand picture in the quarter reflected broad-based strength across all regions and all product categories, with notebooks leading the way. Our product mix was also a notable highlight. Demand for our latest generation of processors, both PC and server, was particularly strong, providing an ASP uplift in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Inventory levels remain in good shape, with OEM component inventories roughly flat quarter on quarter and below levels of a year ago. Distributor inventories are down sequentially. The combination of much stronger sell-through and lower year-on-year inventory levels gives us comfort that the supply chain continues to operate very efficiently.</p>
          <p>Looking across our product segments, servers had a very strong quarter. The value proposition of Nehalem is clearly evident, and we are seeing a demand shift towards the high end of the performance stack, improving average selling prices. Looking ahead, over the next three months, we are planning to refresh our entire server product line with the new 32-nanometer Xeons in the single, dual, and multiprocessor segments. It is noteworthy to point out that the Nehalem EX, our multiprocessor version, represents the biggest leap in performance in the history of the Xeon brand.</p>
          <p>We remain in an excellent position to benefit from the build-out of cloud infrastructure, as well as a reconfiguration of existing data centers for power performance efficiency improvements. Our Atom processor business also continues to do very well, both in netbooks as well as in winning new designs for our growth initiatives. Atom design momentum is very strong, with our new Pine Trail platform in over 80 netbook designs. In the embedded space, we now have over 600 Atom-based design wins and over 2,500 design engagements across 230 customers, 93 of which are brand new customers to Intel.</p>
          <p>At CES, we also demonstrated progress with handheld and consumer electronics platforms built around Atom Cores that were very well received. We demonstrated for the first time the LG GW990, a smartphone built with our yet-to-be-released Atom Moorestown platform, which was awarded best smartphone of the show. This demonstrates the power of our architecture in bringing an uncompromising computing experience to handheld devices. Expect more meaningful news and announcements around these businesses during 2010.</p>
          <p>Our notebook business was exceptional this quarter, with demand very strong across the globe. We have been carefully preparing for the shift to mobile, and our product strategy is a reflection of that. To further enhance our PC lineup, at CES we formally launched 27 new processors produced with our leading-edge 32-nanometer process technology, the biggest consumer launch of new processors since Centrino. Our new Core processors are the first-ever mainstream PC processors to integrate the graphics engine onto the CPU. This is Moore's Law at work, driving increased performance and improved power and form factor characteristics to our new platforms. Our new graphics engine is notable in that it offers full HD video, great mainstream gaming, and enhanced 3-D capability. I'm happy to report that early demand for these products is excellent.</p>
          <p>In closing, we had an outstanding quarter and enter 2010 in a very strong position. We have delivered breakthroughs in our product offerings and our competitive positioning through the Tick-Tock development model. Our recently launched 32-nanometer process technology is the critical process capability that will not only bring computing to new levels but also allow us to broadly offer Atom System-on-Chips into many new product categories. We are pleased with our current momentum and look forward to an exciting year in 2010.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn the time over to Stacy for a few comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Paul.</p>
          <p>The fourth quarter was one of our most profitable quarters ever due to a combination of solid execution, the ramp of innovative new products, and a healthy consumer market. Fourth quarter revenue of $10.6 billion was up 28% from a year ago, the largest year-on-year percent increase in more than a decade.</p>
          <p>Our financial results reflect both significant improvements in our cost structure and higher microprocessor average selling prices. The impact of these improvements can be seen in the gross margin percent of 65%, which was up 7 points from the third quarter and is the highest gross margin percent in our history. In the fourth quarter, we achieved $2.5 billion in operating profit and $2.3 billion in net income. The PC market has recovered nicely, with our microprocessor revenue excluding Atom growing 42% since the market bottomed in the first quarter. In the same time period, Atom microprocessors and associated chipset have grown to $438 million in revenue in the fourth quarter and $1.4 billion for the year.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter gross margin benefited from lower inventory write-offs, improving costs, and our exceptional product lineup, as we ramped and sold the first products manufactured on our 32-nanometer process technology. Total inventories increased $450 million due to these new 32-nanometer products. For 2009, gross margin was 56%, including a 20 point increase from Q1 to Q4. For 2010, we are forecasting continued strong gross margin with the midpoint of our annual forecast at 61%.</p>
          <p>As a result of capital reuse and achieving efficiencies, we were able to ramp 32-nanometer process technology and still bring down our capital forecast from our expectation at the beginning of the year. Our capital purchases for the year of $4.5 billion is down from our original forecast of around $5.2 billion and was less than the annual depreciation run rate.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses remain in tight control. This is most clearly seen in spending as a percent of revenue. In the fourth quarter, spending for R&amp;D and MG&amp;A as a percent of revenue remained constant at 29%, down from 35% in the first quarter and 32% in the second quarter. The number of employees decreased by 1,000 people in the fourth quarter as a result of planned factory actions announced early in 2009. Revenue per employee for the year is $440,000, the third-highest in our history.</p>
          <p>The fourth quarter of 2009 demonstrates the strength of our execution and business model. Excluding the impact of the $1.25 billion AMD settlement agreement taken in the fourth quarter, operating profit was a quarterly record $3.7 billion and as a percent of revenue was 35%. Total cash investments comprised of cash, short-term investments, and debt security trading assets, ended the quarter at $13.9 billion, $1 billion higher than the third quarter. Cash flow from operations was more than $3 billion. During the fourth quarter, we paid the AMD settlement agreement, paid nearly $800 million in dividends, and purchased $1.1 billion in capital assets.</p>
          <p>For the first quarter, we were forecasting a seasonal decrease in revenue, taking the midpoint of our forecast range to $9.7 billion, a 36% increase from the first quarter of 2009. We are forecasting the midpoint of the gross margin range to decrease 4 points from the fourth quarter to 61%. In addition to the impact of the unit decline, the decrease is primarily due to the higher cost associated with the early ramp of 32-nanometer-based products.</p>
          <p>The fourth quarter was a strong finish to what turned out to be a good year. The improvements we have made to our cost structure and efficiency levels have led to exceptional financial results in the fourth quarter and serve as a strong foundation upon which we can build in 2010 as we refresh our product line and ramp 32-nanometer process technology.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn it back to Kevin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. Stacy and Paul. We'll be now happy to take your questions. As most of you know, Intel has a large number of analysts that cover our company. Like we did last quarter, and in an effort to include as many of you as you can, we'll be limiting each caller to one question only. If you need clarification on that question, do please ask. We want to make sure we answer your question adequately, but please no follow-ups and no multipart questions. Christina, go ahead and introduce the first questioner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your first question comes from the line of Ross Seymore with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Congrats on the strong results. Just a question on what your mix assumptions are for your first quarter and full-year 2010 gross margin guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Let me start with what we saw in the fourth quarter. I think that kind of serves as a baseline then to talk about Q1 and 2010. What we saw in the fourth quarter was really a very rich mix. We saw strength across the board on our new products, and in particular what we saw was, is we took the first production on 32 nanometer. We filled from the top, and there was good market acceptance of those products.</p>
          <p>And so the combination of that led to a rich mix in the fourth quarter. I expect that that comes back down into a more normal mix range as we go across 2010. And particularly we'll be bringing out mainstream and value versions of the 32-nanometer products, and that should say that the sales mix gets into a more normal range as we progress across the next several quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that will offset any of the enterprise improving year-over-year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>From an overall average selling price standpoint for 2010, we're predicting kind of a normal decline year-on-year. Keep in mind you have lots of things that go up and down. We'll have a rich mix at the beginning, you have enterprise coming in, but at the end of the day, we do bring pricing down because we see unit growth potential in consumer segment of the market, in emerging markets, there's good price elasticity there. So it's kind of consistent with what you've seen from us the last several years. The price comes down and we drive unit growth with that, and it ends up driving incremental gross margin dollars.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ross. Go ahead, Christina, next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Tim Luke with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much. And congratulations on your strong execution in the quarter. Stacy, I was just wondering if you could clarify how you perceive that you would like your inventory levels to trend as you move through the first quarter and through the year? If you could provide any incremental color on the mix of the inventory that seemed to move up somewhat in the calendar fourth quarter with your stronger revenue. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Yeah, Tim, in Q4, it pretty much unfolded as we expected and as I'd articulated on the last call. We saw an increase in inventory. It's entirely due to the new 32-nanometer products. If you look at it on a unit basis, it's pretty flat quarter on quarter. But we did have the cost associated with 32 nanometer. Those early wafers tend to be pretty high-cost products, and as you have seen us do in prior transitions of new process technology, we pretty quickly build inventory on the new stuff. You saw it in Q4.</p>
          <p>I'd expect to build a little bit more inventory in Q1 as I ramp 32-nanometer products. It won't be the same magnitude that we saw this quarter, but it'll be up some. And then it starts looking a little more normal as it progresses through the year and &#x2013; relative to demand. But this is what we do, is we ramp a new process technology. It's pretty normal. It's consistent with what I was expecting when I started the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Paul, you said that your channel inventory was flat in the disty and then you commented on the OEM inventory. Could you just give your &#x2013; reiterate that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I said it was down sequentially, Tim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yep.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Channel inventory is down sequentially, of our product.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And the OEMs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you'll have to ask the OEMs, wait for their calls.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our view of our their component inventories in terms of the hub, is that we &#x2013; you know, the hubs and the see-throughs from the hubs that we have, suggest that they're roughly flat quarter-on-quarter and well under a year ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim, I think if you just kind of step back on this one, when we look across the supply chain, and it's a very complex supply chain, so looking at our authorized channel, those inventories are down. We have visibility into OEM inventories, and a lot of that's now held in our hubs, and what we see in the down channel, so retail and in the shipping lanes and stuff. What we see is a healthy level of inventory relative to the demand that we see out over the next couple of quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd add two more things on, Tim. One is that remember that two of our &#x2013; our largest two customers have their quarters ending in January. It's not a <mark type="inaudible" /> Q4. And secondly, Chinese New Year's is a bit earlier this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tim. Christina, next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mark Lipacis [Morgan Stanley].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking my question, and thanks for all the detail in the release and in the script. You have three quarters in a row of double-digit growth. I just went back to the model. I had to go back to the late '80s, I think, to see that. And I guess a lot of people are probably going to be wondering if there's &#x2013; you know, what happens next.</p>
          <p>You guys talked about the inventories, and I guess my question is, can you help us understand what percentage of your revenues do you have visibility &#x2013; where you have visibility into the inventories? Can you see pretty much 100% of the inventories at every place that you sell into? And does the release of your products in Q1, or the new product cycle in Q1 versus Q3, does that risk changing any kind of customer order patterns? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I got &#x2013; admittedly got a little lost in the question there, so let me take a shot, and if I miss something that you asked, we'll come back to it. The part of your question of what's our visibility into the supply chain, you know, it's not perfect. It's a broad, complex market out there. It ranges from emerging markets with small white box players to big MNCs. But I'd say it's pretty good. We have, I think, a fairly sophisticated way to look across and see how much inventory is out there, and relative to what we believe demand is, I think that it's a appropriate level of inventory.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just &#x2013; a little more color on that, Mark. Our distributor inventory, we have 100% visibility into, and that's about 25, 30% of our business in units and dollars. So &#x2013; and that's the number that I gave that was down sequentially.</p>
          <p>The OEM inventory, we have hub systems with our largest customers representing the vast majority of our OEM volume, and so you're dealing with something well above 50%, probably &#x2013; I don't know the exact number, but I suspect in the aggregate between OEM hubs and distribution, it's 75% of the numbers that we've got very good visibility into.</p>
          <p>On the Q1 cycle, we actually moved towards a Q1 refresh cycle quite some time ago. It was better for our customers. They liked it. They liked to have the new &#x2013; they don't want to have a disruption before holiday, so it either is in the early summer late Q2 or it's in January, February. And that works out best for them in terms of inventory management and gets new products out there for what is becoming a big part of the cycle, that's Chinese New Year's.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark. Christina?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Uche Orji with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Paul, just as a way to understand your 2010 outlook especially relating to gross margins, given the way 2009 played out, what is your sense as to how 2010 seasonality should play out, and especially if you can touch on corporate spending since we saw a flush in Q4? Should we anticipate some more spending from corporate in the future? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, I don't know how it's going to play out, Uche. Our view in terms of what we've built into the model, our model, for 2010, is a normal seasonal year off of a very good Q4, right? So in general, when you extrapolate that out and do the math, that gets you to double-digit growth year on year because of the high peak in Q4 and the trough that you had in the first half of 2009.</p>
          <p>We're building into our number set a modest recovery of corporate purchases of PCs. That is, we're not building in any kind of &#x2013; anything extraordinary out of that. Just sort of normal return to deployment as the evaluation cycles for the new hardware and Windows 7 get completed. What we are benefiting from in the second half of the year &#x2013; and I think we'll continue to benefit from throughout this year &#x2013; is the extraordinary return on investment that is incurred by deploying new server technologies. I mean, the last technology was sort of a 9 to 1 ROI kind of technology. As we deploy the new Xeon products out, it's 15 and 20 to 1. So we think that that is compelling, the power conservation associated with that is compelling, and that's one of the things that gives us optimism independent of PC refresh in the enterprise for 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Uche, I think the other part of your question was gross margin seasonality. I'd say it's a typical year from that perspective. We've put out the forecast for Q1. 61% is the midpoint of that forecast range. Typically we would see a second quarter from a unit standpoint is going to be seasonally down.</p>
          <p>That means that typically the second quarter gross margin is going to be a bit below that 61%. And then when we get into the second half of the year, my expectation is it's a bit above that 61%. And that's how we get to 61% on average for the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Uche. Christina?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Doug Freedman with Broadpoint AmTech.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks for taking my question, guys, and congrats on a strong quarter. If we look at your business model and all the efforts being placed on sort of new growth streams of revenue, can you talk a little bit about the impact that you expect that to have the longer-term operating model and especially on the operating income line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Doug, I'm going to go through that in quite a bit more detail in the upcoming May Investor Meeting, so I think I'll save the longer answer for that. I'll just say our expectation is that based on our performance leadership and the software compatibility and the value proposition around IA, that we can grow those businesses with a very healthy product margin, not dilute the overall gross margins of the company. We're on record of saying that. And I think if you look at the two businesses that are at significant size today, they're both consistent with that belief.</p>
          <p>Our embedded business, it's a billion-dollar-plus business. It's running at product margins that are a little bit ahead of what the rest of our Core business runs. Atom and netbooks, we've grown that to be now a 1.4 billion business for us in 2009. Also at a product margin that's right in there with the rest of the Core business. So that's our expectation, and we'll talk more at the Investor Meeting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Doug. Christina, next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Adam Benjamin with Jefferies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, guys. Just a question on price elasticity. Obviously in 2009, the end market pricing for PCs came down pretty dramatically. You know, roughly 20, 30% in some instances. I'm just curious as you guys plan for 2010 how you guys are thinking about that driving the elasticity of unit growth that we saw in 2009, and then how it could potentially impact pricing plus or minus? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, 2009 was a funny year, Adam, as you &#x2013; because we all went through it and know. The first half of the year, the lights had gone off, right? And so what we saw over the course of the year was growth, particularly in notebooks and some netbooks, around consumer purchases. It was not a robust year for corporate purchases. And that alone, that mix shift alone, to consumer and away from corporate, was part of the reason you saw PC prices on average being lower, dropping faster than you would have ordinarily seen, point 1.</p>
          <p>Point 2 is that there really wasn't a new refresh cycle in terms of hardware last year. We had versions of our Core product line that were out there, but they were extensions of the existing technology. So there was nothing really to drive sell-up. The new Core products we've just introduced, particularly the i5 and the i7, have great new technology in terms of the wireless display technology and Turbo, which gives you the performance boost when you need it and power savings when you don't. And I think that those &#x2013; the early excitement on those two product lines gives us some cause for optimism even in consumer space for an improved sell-up cycle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. So it's fair to say that as you guys are planning for 2010, you guys are thinking those two dynamics, one a mix shift back to the enterprise and one with new products, can drive end-market pricing back up and should help you guys drive your ASPs up as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I didn't quite get there. I mean, those were mature market comments. On top of that, I think there'll be continued growth just like there has been over the last three or four years in emerging markets, where the emerging markets outpace the mature ones. And clearly in emerging markets, the average selling price of computers is lower than it is in New York City.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think it's important to kind of separate the mix within the segments of the market from the overall mix of our sales. We're refreshing products. We're likely to have a nice benefit from that inside of each of the segments, but the driver over the last four or five years, Adam, has been emerging markets growing faster than the mature markets, consumer grower faster than the rest of the market, and there's good price elasticity there. It benefits us to bring the price down and sell our technology into those segments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks, Adam. Appreciate it, bud.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Christina, next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Manish Goyal with [TIAA-] CREF Investments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, thank you. The question is on operating expenses. You guys showed good a discipline in quarterly results in 2009, and when I look at your first quarter guidance of $3 billion for $9.7 billion of revenue, I'm a little bit surprised, because it's roughly the same revenue number that you had in first quarter of 2008, yet your operating expenses are $200 million lower. So I just want to understand what changed and why you're not seeing better leverage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi Manish, and congratulations on getting on the call two cycles in a row. That's great. Yeah, let me take a shot at that.</p>
          <p>First off, let me go back to the commitment that Paul and I made &#x2013; have made historically. We're still absolutely on the path that over time we're bringing down spending as a percent of revenue. And I think we have had some good results in the last couple of quarters, and our goal over time is that we're going to continue to do that.</p>
          <p>When we look at 2010, you can kind of think of our spending in a couple of different buckets. First off, we are making some investments in R&amp;D projects this year. We've had five years in a row of year-over-year employment declines. We'll actually grow employment a little bit in 2010. So you haven't seen that from us in a long time. But we have some high return on investment projects where we're going to go make some incremental investments.</p>
          <p>Secondly, there's a series of things that aren't really related to the employment level that are going to impact the spending level in 2010. One is the categorization of how we categorize process engineering from year to year. Remember, last year it was cost of sales; this year it's R&amp;D. So that shift happens in kind of a digital fashion, and so that impacts the quarter-to-quarter walk that you're doing. We're giving raises, we have revenue-dependent spending this year that's going to be higher than last year.</p>
          <p>So the combination of those two things is really what you're seeing on the spending line. Neither of those changes the commitment that we're getting great results through our focus on efficiency, and we plan to continue to bring that down over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just if I may have a follow-up on that -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Manish, I'm going to have to cut you off, because we've got to just do one question only. But was there something on that question you didn't -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, just a little &#x2013; same question for full year. If I look at your first-quarter guidance of 3 billion and full-year guidance of 11.8, are you suggesting that even if you continue to hire, your operating expenses will remain roughly flat quarterly, or is there any other way to think about this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'm not making a specific forecast for any quarter in the year, and I'm not making a specific forecast for 2010. We've articulated a goal as a longer-term goal to bring down spending as a percent of revenue. We've made good progress on that, and we're going to continue to drive it over a longer-term horizon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks, Manish. Christina?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Stacy Rasgon with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Thanks for taking my question. I think to follow up on that OpEx question from Manish, if I look at the OpEx this quarter, you have guidance on network down a little bit, but it's still around 3 billion, and you've got total OpEx for the year pretty close to 12, which would imply &#x2013; it seems like it would imply flat OpEx on an average basis going forward. And this is a case now where you potentially have, like you said, OpEx moving from cost of goods back into R&amp;D. You're building out new businesses that you're not in right now around the mobile space and whatnot. I'm just wondering, is it actually &#x2013; if you'll walk a little bit more through some of your assumptions around the OpEx growth going forward and that number that makes up the guidance for 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just so I'm answering the right question, Stacy -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; is your question on why is it so flat over the course of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I'm actually wondering why it's not even up a little bit more than it is, given you have these other drivers again. Unless all of &#x2013; with process development moving back into R&amp;D and with new businesses that you're ramping from relatively nascent amounts today. I'm just wondering why the OpEx growth wouldn't be expected to actually be higher than kind of the flat level that seems to be implied off of the Q1 guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the OpEx growth, when you kind of think of it over the course of the year, there's a couple of those elements that just get spread quarter to quarter. So the categorization of the research and development has happened digitally. The &#x2013; I failed to mention we're also picking up Wind River in 2010. That was an acquisition that we did in the back half of last year, so that's kind of spread across every quarter. We do the same with the profit and revenue-dependent spending.</p>
          <p>So it's probably a little flatter than you would expect. And the increase in R&amp;D projects in the scheme of things doesn't move the number that much. And we are, as we have been, we're finding efficiencies in other places that offset some of that. So when you kind of take all that alchemy together, you end up with a number that's kind of flattish quarter by quarter by quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And you don't need to build any more SG&amp;A to start selling more into the mobile space, for example, with the new Atom applications?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nope, our finance group is so efficient we can sell a lot more than we are today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sales group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And sales group, too. They're efficient as well, Paul points out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Stacy. Christina?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Glen Yeung with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Can you guys quantify how much ASPs were up in Q1, how much you expect them to be down &#x2013; I'm sorry, up in Q4, and how much you expect them to be down in Q1? And what's normal ASP decline for a year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I can do it at some level of precision because all of those hit the gross margin reconciliation. And so when you &#x2013; if we start with Q4, and you just kind of think about the gross margin in Q4, the increase we saw, the ASP accounted for about 2 points of that increase. When, then, we think about over the course of 2010, I'm showing you my 2010 gross margin reconciliation versus 2009 that I think the decline in ASP is worth about 2 to 3 points, and I'd say that order of magnitude is pretty normal. And Q1 will be a small step on the way; I think in the gross margin recon, you'll see that that's worth about half a point down in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to clarify though, if you say it was worth 2 points in a quarter of gross margin, does that imply that the average ASP was down 2%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was up in Q4 -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, up. Yeah, but I mean, is same magnitude is how I should read that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We all struggle to say the word "up" because we don't see that all that often -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; just because of the phenomena we said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you can work through the gross margin math on that. You'll come up with something a little different than 2 to 3%, but the gross margin was up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay. All right. That's helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Glen. Next question, Christina.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of John Pitzer with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon, guys. Congratulations. Paul and Stacy, I guess I want to revisit the mix question for this year with your guidance that 2010 will see normal ASP degradation. You kind of have some tailwinds that should be helping you. Consumer moves to corporate, you've got the server cycle, you could make the argument that you'll have a more robust CULV product line this year, and you've got the introduction of Dales, and so I'm kind of struggling with why this wouldn't be a better-than-average selling price year. Is this sort of an implication that Atom reaccelerates as a percent of the mix, or can you help me reconcile what I see as more tailwinds than headwinds on ASPs? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll try and give you some color on that, John. I'm not sure I can fill in all the holes. I mean, we're all guessing, right? I mean, no one knows for sure. As I said earlier, we're not programming into our guidance or our estimates any kind of overnight recovery of the corporate market. I think for a variety of reasons, that will start coming back, but it'll come back based upon eval cycles, qualification cycles, and IT shops.</p>
          <p>And then as corporate budgets open up, they have to decide whether they want to first buy PCs or servers. So I think &#x2013; in terms of IT equipment. And we really haven't enough so far, except the server run-up in the second half, to be confident on when the &#x2013; when and what the rate of corporate PC refresh would be, although we have built some into this.</p>
          <p>Number two, in terms of Atom, we've now been at this for 18 months or a little bit more than that, and up to this point in time, now that &#x2013; with all that data, we have not seen any meaningful cannibalization of the notebook market by netbooks. Netbooks look to be for 90% of them are clearly additive, and they're clearly going into market segments that were unaddressed prior to this. In the first 18 months of the netbook, most people who bought them were buying them as incremental machines or travel companions, principally in mature markets or Tier 1 cities of emerging markets. I think that in 2010, you'll start seeing that phenomena move into emerging markets.</p>
          <p>And as that does, there may be a slightly higher mix of Atom, but it certainly wouldn't be cannibalistic to our notebook business. And so we're just &#x2013; we're kind of playing all these together in a stew and saying this is how we see the year coming out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, guys. That's helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John. Christina, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Sumit Dhanda with Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Stacy, a question for you: On the 32-nanometer products or the new architecture products that really helped your selling prices in the fourth quarter, I guess was that the primary driver for ASPs within the client group given that the volumes were likely not very large, or did your older 45-nanometer generation products also help the ASPs? Did you sell much a higher mix within the 45-nanometer products?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it was &#x2013; within the client group, it was I'd say a mix of both, but the 32-nanometer effect was pretty pronounced. As Paul said in his prepared remarks, we brought out dozens of new products across the client on 32 nanometer. The way we plan our manufacturing is we kind of started the manufacturing at the highest end first, and worked our way down, and we're still working our way down into the mainstream and value price points, so that was a pretty pronounced impact in terms of the mix that we sold in Q4.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Despite the fact that this wasn't a big volume component of what you sold within the client business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was a not insignificant component of what we sold. We ramp these factories pretty fast. You can see it in our inventory results, and you can see it in our sales mix. Or I can see it in our sales mix. We don't show it to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Sumit. Appreciate it. Go ahead, Christina.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jim Covello with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. Good evening. Thanks so much for letting me ask a question, and congratulations on the good results. Just one question. Could you give us some estimate of what you're going to do with factory loadings in Q1 and Q2?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably not at the level of granularity that you're hoping for, but I'll give you a sense. And then this is an another one where in May, we're pretty specific, and we'll show you kind of quarter-by-quarter utilizations as well as a forecast going into the future. We're in the sweet spot of loading. We're running nicely full. We had the ability to respond to some upsides. We always want to have some of that, but we're full to the point that we're getting really good cost results. I'd expect that to be the norm for this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jim. Christina?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Graham Tanaka with Capital Management (sic) [Tanaka Capital Management].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Congratulations on the ramp. Just a little bit more on the 32-nanometer ramp, pretty fast, I just get a feel for what proportion of sales might have been 32 and more importantly what that might be by the end of the year? And it seems to me that that is probably one of the more important reasons for both the sales and ASPs going up in the margins, is the 32 ramp being faster than expected and higher utilization. Is that true?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I wouldn't say it's faster than expected. We expected it to be pretty fast. And beyond that, I'll punt on that one as well, and we'll deal with it &#x2013; we'll show you that data in May when we have the Investor Meeting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you kindly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Graham. Appreciate it. Go ahead, Christina.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Craig Berger with FBR Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Nice job. Thanks for taking my question. Can you just explain why the first quarter gross margin guidance is 61 and then the year is also only 61, and any other color around that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I'll be happy to. So I'll apologize in advance, because I think to explain Q1, I have to explain Q4, and to explain the year I've kind of got to go through a walk. So if you'll bear with me, Craig, I'll do that.</p>
          <p>Q4 came in, several of the elements, as we expected. We did see good news associated with the qualification for sale of 32-nanometer products, as well as sell-through of some of the previously reserved material there. That was about 2.5 points of the increase we saw in Q4. We got the good news that we were expecting in CPU volumes. They were seasonally up in the quarter. We got the good news we were expecting in lower excess capacity. In fact, our excess capacity charges have now gone to zero for the quarter, which we haven't been there since the end of last year.</p>
          <p>The places where it was a little unexpected is the bump we saw in CPU ASPs. That was a couple of points of good news that I wasn't expecting when I first set the forecast, and it was a little better in terms of unit costs than I expected. Not a lot, but a little.</p>
          <p>Then if you move into Q1, the drivers that take us from 64% down to 61%, first &#x2013; 65%, sorry. It's even hard for me to say that as an all-time record, 65% down to 61%. The first is we're going to see some higher CPU cost. This is very consistent with what I showed you at the Investor Meeting last May. Those first wafers coming off of 32 nanometer as we're loading the factories tend to be pretty expensive. That's what ended up in inventory. That what ships out in Q1. That's going to drive a little bit of a cost increase. And then we kind of come down as we go through the year. So very consistent with what I showed you there. And it's a seasonally down quarter from Q4, so we get a little bit of downward pressure as a result of lower CPU sales volumes. And then I do expect in Q1 my mix is a little less rich than what I sold in Q4. That's about half a point. So that's how you get to the 61%.</p>
          <p>I'll pause there and see if that makes sense, and then I'll take you through the year so I don't get too far ahead of you. Is that -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It does.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So in a previous question, I kind of gave what I expected to be the shape of the year. We start at 61, Q2 tends to be seasonally down, so I expect that to be down some from 61. Then if you do the math, you'd say that we're forecasting a second half gross margin that's something above 61% in the low 60s. And I think the debate you and I will have at some point is why is that in the low 60s versus in the mid-60s, and it really comes back to the conversation we've been having on ASP.</p>
          <p>A lot of things go right to get us into that low 60s. We've got unit costs coming down, relatively benign period in terms of other cost of sales, so we don't have significant startup costs or excess capacity charges, or anything like that. Paul articulated we're anticipating robust unit growth. That keeps the factories pretty full. But we are anticipating that pricing comes down some from where we are today, and that brings us down a couple to a few points over the course of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just a follow-up on the tax rate, is 30% the long-term go forward? That's higher than it used to be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Craig, fair question, but we said no follow-ups. Let me go to the next one, and we'll &#x2013; somebody may ask that one for you, and you and I can talk afterwards if that's all right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Christina, go ahead, next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Suji De Silva with Kaufman Brothers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks. Nice job on the quarters, guys. Just a follow-up on that question on gross margin. What could make your 61% assumption for the year conservative? What are some of your assumption that might be able to upside there, just to understand the level here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, great question. You know, first of all, I think we have to put 61% in perspective. 61% is a great gross margin. It says that -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&#x2013; a lot of things are going right for us, so I don't want to jinx us by talking about what has to go from a great gross margin to a perfect gross margin, if you will.</p>
          <p>The forecast is assuming declining unit costs. It's assuming that we're in kind of the benign cycle in terms of startup costs and other costs of sales. It's assuming good volume growth. So all that's baked in. We're also &#x2013; we see just continued great performance out of the factory network from a productivity and an efficiency standpoint. That helps our costs.</p>
          <p>You know, if you wanted the scenario that would take us higher than that, it would be a flattening out of the ASP curve or a richer mix or more units than what we have baked in. And likewise, I could come up with a list that takes me into the lower end of the range, where we have a less rich mix or the unit growth isn't as robust as we thought, and our factories aren't as full.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Suji. Go ahead, Christina.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Gus Richard with Piper Jaffray.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for taking my question. And congrats on a good quarter and a good year. Just real quickly, I'm just curious if you'd talk a little bit about the carrier as a channel and as you're thinking about upside to the year, may that play a factor? And sorry, it's a second part, do you feel comfortable that you're going to have enough capacity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Trying them out. The carrier as a channel has been around for a while in notebooks, and it wasn't &#x2013; it's good, but it's not explosive. What we saw in netbooks in the fourth quarter, last three or four months of the year, was carriers became a very significant portion of the volume of netbooks, probably in the range of a quarter of them, 25%.</p>
          <p>And what we're seeing &#x2013; what led me to my comments earlier about netbook growth in emerging markets was really based upon our view that the carrier model will be very efficient in those markets, because it's a low entry price subsidized model just like cell phones are, and you get the PC and the bandwidth at the same time. So I think that's likely to be a good piece of the netbook business, a growing piece of the netbook business over the course of 2010. In terms of upside, we've built a pretty significant growth into the number set already, so I don't know that it'd be much upside there.</p>
          <p>Secondly in terms of capacity, no, I don't see any issues on the horizon. We're planning for a very high end of a robust growth from a capacity standpoint in terms of the wafer starts that we need to put in place, and even then we have time to make some incremental decisions for the, say, fourth quarter '10 kinds of volumes over the course of this year.</p>
          <p>So we'll watch the first half of the year, and then make the calls. But right now, we believe we have enough buffer capacity coming on between &#x2013; particularly on the 32-nanometer ramp &#x2013; and we have the older 45-nanometer line still intact to be able to handle virtually anything I could imagine being thrown at us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Gus. Hey, Christina, we're going to take just two more questions, if you would.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Brendan Furlong with Miller Tabak.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much for squeezing me in. A question on the embedded/other Intel architecture, if you could give some color on what their expectations are for 2010? And you mentioned 600 design wins. What's your expectation of time from design win to revenue with all those new design wins? Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't you handle the embedded/other and I'll just &#x2013; let me speak to design wins, and Stacy will tell you what he thinks is in the embedded and other and direction on that.</p>
          <p>Typically there's no such thing as an average design win in embedded, but typically it is &#x2013; it's sort of a year to 18 months from initial conversation to production. And along the way in that initial conversation, you end up closing the design maybe a third of the way through that. So a lot of &#x2013; and then these units tend to run for multiple years. In some cases, 10 years.</p>
          <p>So we're not projecting &#x2013; our embedded business has grown at double-digit percents the last few years. It will continue to, I think, outgrow the company in terms of revenue, but I'm not going to give you a precise number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Brendan, did that answer your question, or did you have another question about the other Intel architecture segment? I wasn't sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that pretty much answers my question. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Brendan. This &#x2013; Christina, we'll have this be our last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your last question comes from the line of Hans Mosesmann with Raymond James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. A question about the transition of Westmere as it replaces Penryn. How quickly can we see the crossover there in terms of units, and if you can also explain that with regard to Pine Trail over the existing Atom? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think on the first part of the question, Hans, Stacy already answered that we are not in a position to show you that number today, and we'll show you in gruesome detail at the analysts meeting in a couple of months. But what we're doing with this cycle in general is using the technology to move 32 nanometers into the mainstream more quickly than we did with 45.</p>
          <p>And the rate of crossover between 32 and 45 will be more a function of second half demand in total than capacity planning to cut one off versus the other. I mean, if demand is red hot, the transition will be slower even though we'll ramp 32 as fast as possible. And if it's less red hot, it'll be slower.</p>
          <p>In terms of Pine Trail, I think we'll move pretty quickly to transition that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very well. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Hans. I want to thank everybody for joining the call today. As a reminder, our quiet period for the first quarter will begin at the close of business on February 26, 2010. Our first quarter earnings conference call is scheduled for Tuesday, April 13, 2010.</p>
          <p>Thank you all, and good night.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation. You may now disconnect. Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>