<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1494107" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-08-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>52770</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Managing Director &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Enrico Tommaso Cucchiani</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods Ltd.">Ronny Rehn</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Carlo Messina</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Equita SIM SpA">Matteo Ghilotti</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Francesca Tondi</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Joh. Berenberg, Gossler &amp; Co. KG (United Kingdom)">Marco Troiano</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Kepler Capital Markets SA (Italy)">Anna Maria Benassi</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Alberto V. Cordara</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Domenico Santoro</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Mediobanca">Andrea Filtri</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Conference Call of Intesa Sanpaolo for the presentation of the 2012 Half Yearly Results, hosted today by Mr. Enrico Cucchiani, Chief Executive Officer. My name is Clara and I would be your coordinator for today's conference. At the end of the presentation there would be a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Today's conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>At this time I would like to hand the call over to Mr. Enrico Cucchiani. Sir, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Good afternoon, good morning or whatever. Thank you for joining us on this call to discuss Intesa Sanpaolo's results for the first half of 2012. and I would like to especially thank the ones of you who are listening from a nice beach somewhere in the world and I would also like to thank the patient ones of you that are only a couple of conference calls away from a tropical beach. I'm Enrico Cucchiani, and I'm joined by Carlo Messina, our CFO.</p>
          <p>I said at the Q1 stage that our strategy was focused on the de-risking, balance sheet strengthening, liquidity, superior execution and performance. Halfway through the year it is now clear that we are delivering on our promise. As we can see from the executive summary on page one, we have made considerable progress during the first half of the year, despite the ongoing recession and the associated credit quality deterioration.</p>
          <p>We have continued to strengthen our balance sheet. The capital position has improved with the core Tier 1 ratio at 10.7% versus 10.1% at the end of 2011 and the EBA capital ratio is up at 10.1% versus 9.2% at the end of 2011. The leverage is deliberately low at 19.3; significantly lower than most of our international peers. The liquidity position is already compliant with Basel 3 requirements for 2018. Both liquidity coverage ratio and net stable funding ratio are above 100.</p>
          <p>We have also further increased our loan provisions buffer. We have continued to deliver high quality earnings, almost &#x20AC;1.3 billion of net income for the semester, &#x20AC;470 million in Q2. Even on a normalized basis, H1 net income is solidly above &#x20AC;1 billion. Compared to last year, we delivered higher operating income, plus 2.6% and lower operating costs, minus 1.9%, which translates into a sound operating margin of &#x20AC;4.5 billion, that is plus 7.4% versus last year and let me say that this is the highest of the past eight semesters.</p>
          <p>We addressed the deteriorating credit environment by increasing provisions faster than non-performing loss formation. We have also activated a set of short-term profit improvement levers, which have already delivered approximately &#x20AC;600 million before tax during the first semester on top of the buyback and the LTRO benefits. We have started a transformation journey to reposition the bank in order to deliver superior performance also in the new normal. Finally, in July, we conducted a successful buyback of &#x20AC;1.5 billion of debt, creating a pre-tax profit of &#x20AC;330 million, which of course doesn't show up yet in the results of the first half.</p>
          <p>Let us now turn to page three, the core Tier 1 ratio has increased by 60 basis points from 10.1% at the end of 2011 to 10.7%, as I said before. Let me point out that this is the highest level among Italian banks and the second highest in the Eurozone. The EBA capital ratio has also increased by 90 basis points from 9.2% at the end of 2011 to 10.1% and to the best of our knowledge this is amongst the highest in the Eurozone as well.</p>
          <p>Let us now turn to page four. As I have already mentioned we have kept our leverage at a very conservative level and as you can see from the slide, we are much below the average European leverage and one of the lowest in absolute terms.</p>
          <p>Let us now turn to slide number five and take a look at our liquidity position. The liquidity position is very strong and has further improved during the semester. Since the beginning of the year, liquid assets have increased 14% to &#x20AC;111 billion. Unencumbered eligible assets with Central Banks, net of haircut, remained above &#x20AC;50 billion, a significantly buffer as recently recognized by the rating agencies.</p>
          <p>The loans to deposit ratio is at 102% for the second quarter, down from 105% at the end of 2011. This improvement is mainly due to an increase in customer deposits, the increases being 2.5% versus the end of 2011. The high liquidity level, coupled with strong funding capabilities, makes Intesa a very compliant with Basel 3 requirements for 2018. In fact, both LCR and NSFR are well above 100%. To be more specific, NSFR is approximately at 108%.</p>
          <p>Let us now turn to slide number six where we can appreciate the strength and quality of our provisioning. We continue to build up the stock of loan loss provisions, in particular, specific loan loss provisions stock went up by 12.5% in the last year, which to be precise is 20% higher on a like-for-like basis if you include the effect of the doubtful loans sale that we performed in recent months.</p>
          <p>We also continued to build up our performing loans reserves, which increased by 8.5% in the last 12 months. Our non-performing loans coverage ratio has increased by 60 basis points from 44.6% at the end of the first half of 2011 to 45.2%, which is very conservative considering that our recovery rate is comfortably above 100%. In fact, it is at a 146% to be more specific.</p>
          <p>Of course, one could question whether such a high recovery rate is sustainable. Let me just point out one fact. If we take, for instance, the average loan to value of our mortgage portfolio, we see that it is around 50%, loan to value as I said, 50%. This allows us to both maximize the recovery when a client becomes distressed and to have a very large buffer in case any realistic real estate deflation scenario. And incidentally, let me say that so far in Italy we are seeing only very modest declines in real estate prices.</p>
          <p>In addition, we also have a comfortable &#x20AC;2.6 billion countercyclical buffer on performing loans, which has increased by 10 basis points to 80 basis points from 70 basis points a year ago. We have now analyzed the strength of our balance sheet and in particular of our capital position, of our liquidity and of our provisioning.</p>
          <p>Let us now turn to the P&amp;L and in particular to the Q2 results on slide number seven. We see a decline in operating income, in operating margin, in pre-tax income and in net income. However, I believe that these results are strong considering a few facts. First, the macro environment has deteriorated in a major way. GDP last year &#x2013; has shrunk this year by 2.1%, while last year it was growing at 1%. The spread has ballooned from 160 basis points to 400, 500 basis points. Additionally, last year we had substantial one-offs such as the Prada IPO and the Findomestic sale which generated &#x20AC;426 million of operating income.</p>
          <p>Finally, loan loss provisions have gone up by 31.5% during the second quarter. The good results of Q2 are on top of a good Q1, so let's now look at the performance of the entire first semester on slide number eight. The first half waterfall analysis confirms the quality of the results. The net income increased 3.6%, net fee and commission income was down 5.9% year-on-year due to a decrease in commissions from asset management and advisory, reflecting adverse market conditions.</p>
          <p>Profits on trading were up 6.8% to &#x20AC;877 million, which benefited from capital gains of &#x20AC;274 million before tax, and there is a &#x20AC;183 million after-tax from the Tier 1 buyback in Q1 and benefited as well from &#x20AC;94 million from the sale of our participation in the London Stock Exchange, which took place in Q2. Insurance results have increased by 59% and all-in-all, operating income has increased by 2.6%.</p>
          <p>Personnel and admin costs have significantly gone down, reflecting our focused cost reduction program. The resulting operating margin is a solid &#x20AC;4.5 billion, up 7.4% versus last year. Loan loss provisions for the semester reflect our prudent provisioning policy in a deteriorated environment and are up 36.5%, leading to a pre-tax income of &#x20AC;2.3 billion. Net income is at &#x20AC;1.3 billion, solidly above &#x20AC;1 billion even on a normalized basis.</p>
          <p>Let us now turn to slide number nine. The waterfall analysis of net income development versus last year highlights the impact of our actions. We improved net interest income by &#x20AC;172 million through loan repricing and increased focus on deposits. We increased the insurance income by &#x20AC;168 million. We posted &#x20AC;550 million of additional provisions to face the challenging credit environment.</p>
          <p>In addition, we enjoyed a one-off tax provision release of &#x20AC;173 million, for which of course we cannot claim any credit. However, let me point out that our tax rate after this one-off tax provision release is still high. Tax rates without the tax provision release would be 42%, with the tax provision release is 34%, but it's still higher than the European average which is 27%. All-in-all, our net income is only 9% lower than last year, despite 36.5% higher loan loss provisions.</p>
          <p>Now let us turn to slide 10 to take a look at the return on sales. Very quickly on this indicator, which is generally not analyzed in banks. As you can see, the operating margin is at 50% and the cost/income ratio stands at 49.8%. The overall return on sales on a pre-tax basis is at 25%, a pretty high level in this market.</p>
          <p>Now we can turn to slide 11 to look at the contribution by business unit. All business units showed positive contribution. Public finance included a unit which reported a very negative contribution in 2011 year-end results. Italian Retail remains stable versus last year, notwithstanding the low interest rate environment and indeed it has improved against the previous quarter. Italian Private Banking performed strongly versus first half of 2011 and CIB remains a strong contributor with excellent performance.</p>
          <p>The International Subsidiary Division was down on the other side by 53%, compared to first half of last year, driven mainly by Hungary and in particular by the credit deterioration and the deleveraging taking place in that country and in that bank. Insurance business has showed a very strong performance versus the first half of 2011 growth, increasing by 124%.</p>
          <p>Let us now take a look at the cost side on slide number 12. We have once again delivered an additional decrease in operating costs, which decreased by 1.9%, which is equivalent to &#x20AC;86 million in the first half of 2012. And, in fact, we see an acceleration of the improvement since in the second quarter year-on-year we had a decrease in operating costs of 2.2%.</p>
          <p>Our aggressive cost containment measures delivered a 3.9% reduction in admin expenses, coupled with 1.4% reduction in personnel costs. This along with our topline growth leads to a best-in-class 49.8% cost/income ratio. It will be higher by year end, but Intesa will continue to be one of the lowest cost producer in the European landscape.</p>
          <p>Let us now put this semester in the right perspective. As you can see on slide 13, Intesa has delivered the highest operating margin of the past eight semesters at &#x20AC;4.5 billion and let me point out that in 2012, in a very negative environment, the performance has been 17% higher than the average of the past four years. This is clearly encouraging and demonstrates our resilience despite the economic challenges.</p>
          <p>Let us now focus again on credit quality and provisioning &#x2013; that is on page 14. The prolonged negative macro-environment is generating further credit deterioration as evidenced by doubtful and substandard loans inflow, which shows an increase of 20%. To tackle this development, we have beefed up provisions by a significantly higher proportion, that is, we have beefed up provisions by 37% vis-&#xE0;-vis an increase in inflow of 20%. However, we also have to point out that we see positive results from our dedicated NPL task force, of which we will talk later on in the presentation.</p>
          <p>Growth rate in inflow of new, doubtful and substandard loans slowed down in Q2. The average for the semester has been 20%, but it was 25% in Q1 and is now down to 13% in Q2. The high cost of risk, of course, reflects the credit landscape and our very conservative and rigorous approach. Provisions on performing loans are best-in-class, I would say are best-in-class by a wide margin and are at 80 basis points, as I mentioned before.</p>
          <p>Let us now quickly compare our performance to European peers. On page 15 we have very a synthetic ROE tree. Despite operating in a shrinking domestic economy our bank is performing better or in line with European peers on several KPIs. Loan loss provisions, which reflect the country-specific environment sandbag overall performance.</p>
          <p>On the other side, we consider our low level of leverage a key strength in the current economic environment, despite the negative impact on pre-tax return on tangible equity, which is down to 14.4%, slightly below the European average. We have simulated the results applying average European provisioning levels. In this case, our return on tangible equity would be well above 17%, that is above European average.</p>
          <p>Let's now do some benchmarking on efficiency. On slide 16, you can see that Intesa has the third lowest cost/income ratio among peers and shows the second best year-on-year improvement, reflecting our progress on both costs and income. Our cost/income will deteriorate slightly in the remainder of the year, but will continue to be at the bottom of the scale.</p>
          <p>Let us now consider some of the short-term levers we implemented and the first steps of our transformation journey. Please bear with me and jump to slide number 18. Earlier this year, we committed to activate levers to improve short-term profitability and to develop a transformation program to reposition the bank to successfully compete in the "new normal" and I'm using this term "new normal" borrowing it from my former colleague, Mohammed Al-Arian. For the ones who might not be familiar with the term, it refers to the fact that the future macro landscape is going to be significantly different from the past and certainly not any better.</p>
          <p>In the first half, we have implemented a full set of high impact short-term profit improvement measures that have already delivered substantial results as we will see in a minute. In addition, we have also started the transformation journey, have developed eight work streams to make Intesa more competitive. We have defined new performance management tools, key to foster a focused performance culture. And we have also simplified a focused structure and strengthened the management team.</p>
          <p>Let us please turn to slide 19 to see the impact of our short-term levers. On slide 19, on the left-hand side we recap the promises and on the right-hand side we will see the delivery. We report a cumulative &#x20AC;300 million increase in net interest income from repricing. We have converted &#x20AC;665 million of capital that was tied up in activities generating negative EBA, converting them into value creating &#x2013; converting the use of the capital into value creating activities. We keep our focus on aggressively reducing costs. We delivered cost reduction, as we said, of 1.9% in the first half, which translates in real money in &#x20AC;86 million of savings. And as I said, reduction is both in admin expenses. minus 3.9%, and personnel expenses, minus 1.4%.</p>
          <p>Now we have 400 FTEs working as members of a task force activated on loan portfolio of &#x20AC;6 billion, okay, on non-performing &#x2013; on problem loans, which are worth &#x20AC;6 billion and we have achieved already a release of &#x20AC;135 million in provisions. Finally, the net present value of our liquidity management program is now at &#x20AC;1.5 billion.</p>
          <p>More details on liability management on slide number 20. This slide illustrates the key elements of our liability management and the way we have used the LTRO. We have issued three unsecured bonds between January and July for a total amount of &#x20AC;3.5 billion. Key message is, demand that was &#x20AC;8 billion and exceeded target by 125%. 70% of demand came from foreigners and also let me point out that we had great timing. For instance, the last bond was issued &#x2013; was announced right after the June 29 summit when spreads were at a low point, and I point this out because it indicates that we have some smart guys and they are capable of very good execution.</p>
          <p>We've also performed two successful buyback programs totaling &#x20AC;2.7 billion. &#x20AC;1.2 billion of Tier 1 subordinated notes was performed in February and &#x20AC;1.5 billion of senior notes and subordinated notes in July. We've also aggressively drawn down LTRO facilities for &#x20AC;36 billion.</p>
          <p>In summary, great timing, excellent execution, important impact. First buyback &#x20AC;274 million capital gain before tax, second buyback in July not yet in the accounts you have seen, &#x20AC;330 million capital gain before tax. Overall, the net present value impact including the LTRO is approximately of &#x20AC;1.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Now let me talk a little bit about the transformation journey. Our transformation journey includes eight strategic work streams, retail banking, corporate and investment banking, international subsidiaries, credit, operating costs, wealth management, product factories, digitalization. These are not just projects; they are pervasive work streams to revisit the delivery system of the bank. That is the way we operate and interact with the customers. As such, most of these work streams will generate the evolution of the business model and our operations over time in the coming years.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to slide number 22 to briefly discuss some important enablers from the transformation journey. Key enablers of the transformation journey are performance management tool and the development of a strong performance culture. We have developed a state-of-the-art performance measurement tool that allows us to measure at a very granular level, that is, when I say granular and modular level it means that we can measure it at divisional level, bank level, regional level, area level, branch level, what have you, okay. And we can measure and we can understand at the operational level again with the same granularity the full value chain. We can also benchmark our results against budget, against historical figures and against relevant competitors.</p>
          <p>The newly developed tool supports a dynamic and effective performance dialog, where we have that &#x2013; a top-down approach allows us to challenge the bottom-up planning. And, most important, we can have a strong focus for timely correction of problems and timely capture of opportunities.</p>
          <p>Let me now talk briefly about organization and people and we can do so turning to page 23. Focus, simplicity, clarity, meritocracy are the guiding principles of the reorganization process. We have no major form of disruption of existing organization in order to minimize the shocks, that is, internal and external shocks. I've seen a lot of reorganizations when organizations are turned upside down, going from geographic to functional, to metrics, to whatever. Whenever you do something like that you have a prolonged period of total disruption, internal disruption and disruption in customer service.</p>
          <p>I try to stay away from this and to upset the formal organization as little as possible. The focus is on significant simplification, clear focus and clarification of responsibilities. Sounds like plain vanilla, but I can assure you that in any large corporation, any complex organization there is a huge room for improvement just doing this basic &#x2013; following this basic philosophy. And also I think that now we have some of the best senior executives in the industry placed in the key positions of our bank.</p>
          <p>In addition, we are strengthening the bench, recruiting high profile potential with strong international background and they can be Italians or non-Italians, but they all have a strong multi-cultural background. They will be fully involved in the transformation journey and in the steer-in process and this will be a great chance to test them, to prepare them and test them for future larger responsibilities. Typical background of these people, ladies and gentlemen, will be a degree with highest honors from a top university, at least, I mean, a master degree, an MBA and possibly more than one from a top international business school, significant experience with a &#x2013; typically with a professional firm, management consultants, commercial and major international commercial investment banks. And age-wise they would be late 30s to mid 40s.</p>
          <p>Let us now turn to slide number 25 to talk a little bit about the outlook. First, the Eurozone, which seems a key driver of anything these days. The Eurozone, I would say, seems to be in a state of confusion and the roller coaster would be the best analogy of the Eurozone experience. However, despite this state of confusion we cannot suffer from myopia either and we cannot discount the positives. The Eurozone fundamentals continue to be strong and I would say they are the strongest among Western economies, our industrialized countries.</p>
          <p>Political leadership is gradually, I mean to say slowly, but gradually it is developing awareness of the severe shortcomings in economic governance and is timidly, too timidly, but still it is committing to create the necessary infrastructure, that is banking union, fiscal union, finally political union. We are witnessing a tango dance, two steps forward, one back, but overall the direction seems clear. The real question mark is the sense of urgency and the execution capabilities.</p>
          <p>Now a brief comment on Italy. The real economy, there is no doubt, is suffering from the continued recession and from the high spreads and credit quality reflects this sector. Credit quality has been deteriorating and I think the credit quality will continue to remain an issue beyond 2012. The political outlook is under development, but I am significantly more positive than the general perception outside of Italy, as here we can definitely sense a very concrete and mounting pressure on Mario Monti to stay on and to continue the turnaround program of the country, which he has successfully started, even though the job is far from finished.</p>
          <p>Now a few words on Intesa and on our outlook for 2012. In this volatile environment, we forecast solid and reliable P&amp;L results, backed by a strong and solid balance sheet. Core Tier 1 and common equity ratios are set to remain well above 10% and capital ratios well above the EBA threshold. Our conservative approach of low leverage and high liquidity is key in these uncertain times and generous provisioning provides a prudent and countercyclical buffer.</p>
          <p>In other words, strong capital, high liquidity, redundant provision, and I underline the word redundant, okay, because I believe that we are particularly prudent in our provisioning. We could perhaps more easily present easier figures, but under the current uncertainties, I believe the redundancy is an important factor and for us is a priority. In addition, we maintain a very strong focus on performance, while starting to re-engineer the bank and preparing it for future challenges.</p>
          <p>Let us not forget, and I'm sorry if I repeat myself that in July we conducted this successful buyback, which brings us &#x20AC;330 million before taxes of additional profit and which doesn't &#x2013; hasn't shown up yet in the accounts.</p>
          <p>And finally, our dividend will be at least equal to that of 2011 and I would say, with a generous dividend yield, at least at current prices and let me end on this note.</p>
          <p>Let me thank you once again for your kind attention and we are now ready to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Ronny Rehn from KBW. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon and thanks for taking the time for the call. A few questions from me. The first one on the impaired loans. I can see that your impaired loans went up almost &#x20AC;2.3 billion in the quarter, which is we haven't seen that for a while. And your total adjustments for impaired loans went up &#x20AC;250 million and were basically helped by a release of performing loans represented by securities. And so, actually coverage in the quarter has declined overall by 2 percentage points. I just want to see how you tied it in with your comment of a very conservative provisioning policy? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And the second question is on funding cost sensitivity. You obviously heard from this ECB yesterday that they may, going forward, target the short end of the yield curve and we've seen some positive market reaction to that. What is your sort of sensitivity level to a 1 percentage point decline in the two-year bond yields in Italy?</p>
          <p>And lastly, on the business plan targets as they stand, you're looking for flat costs by 2013, how much room for improvement do you see on that, your current target? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not so sure I've heard well the first couple of questions. I'll leave them to Carlo. I'm not so sure either where did you see our cost for 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In the old business plan, you know?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The old business plan, but the old business plan has been pronounced dead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Completely dead?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, I would say, quite a few months ago and hasn't been revived. So that is part of the "old normal". We are gearing up pretty aggressively for the "new normal". So please continue to expect a committed, determined, focused attitude at cost cutting in the coming months, in the coming years, at least as long as I'll be around, there'll be a very strong focus on cost cutting. Now perhaps, Carlo, I don't know if you have understood...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I'll try to elaborate. I understood on the sensitivity related to the ECB news and the impact on the short-term part of the curve. In my opinion, the impact on the net interest margin of these maneuvers will not be so relevant. So we can confirm our sensitivity on the net interest margin, it is 100 basis points, &#x20AC;300 million of possible increase. Then you have to consider the mitigation that we can do looking at the repricing action that we have on the markup. But I ask you if it is possible to have some more details on your question, so I can ask...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, more details, I just want to see, obviously, there has been a lot of complaints in the market that the yields have gone too high and the funding costs have gone up, so I just thought if you get now some support from the ECB to at least bring the short-term end down of the yield curve, what kind of impact that might have, with a read across to retail bonds' deposit price?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, looking at &#x2013; yes, okay. So, I understand. So the real point is that looking at the sensitivity will remain what I told you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Looking at the retail bond funding, so looking at the &#x2013; in the medium term part of the curve, in our opinion it is possible to have some benefit, you have to consider that in this moment there is a nice correlation between the spread BTP-bond and the retail medium-term cost of funding, as if you look also at the wholesale cost of funding is related with the spread BTP-bond. So, in my opinion, we can have some positive contribution from these statements from the ECB and we will see in the next month. But if you look at our funding plan, we are well above the target, so we can stay out of the market without any kind of problem for our liquidity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And one quick question on the existing retail bonds, could you give us the current sort of average carry or average yields that you have on those retail bonds?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the average cost of our retail bonds is in the range of 120 basis points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The overall yield, what is the spread?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is the spread on all our retail bonds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, thank you. And then just on the first question I had on the impaired loans, did you catch the question or you want me to repeat it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Repeat it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so impaired loans, total impaired loans went from &#x20AC;43 billion to &#x2013; &#x20AC;43.3 billion to &#x20AC;45.6 billion, so &#x20AC;2.3 billion up and your total adjustment to loans went from &#x20AC;22.3 billion to &#x20AC;22.5 billion, so &#x20AC;200 million, &#x20AC;250 million up, so almost didn't go up at all. And the main item here which was positive was a release for loans represented by securities, performing loans. And so, how do we think about it? I mean how sustainable is that given the deterioration in the book, you might not be able to release this forever?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I cannot understand your point. The dynamics of our non-performing loans was the one that we have in the figures in the presentation and considering the different items of our provisioning we had and a stable amount of generic provision and an 80 basis points of generic provision. So we have not any kind of release in our generic provisioning. So the increase in the gross non-performing loans is then related with the net &#x2013; with increase in the net performing loans, having in mind the average coverage rate that you have in the presentation. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And maybe this is wrong in the Excel file. Then I'll follow up with IR on this, yeah. That's fine. Thank you very much for your answers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Matteo Ghilotti from Equita. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Just a couple of questions. The first one is on the growth of gross total impaired loans, which were up 5% quarter-on-quarter. They were up 4% in the first quarter. So there was a mild acceleration in this dynamic. Just would like to have your sense on this growth rate, if you believe that it's going to accelerate further because of the recession in Italy, or you see more stabilization if you have any feeling about that?</p>
          <p>And the second question is more a general question on some big positions, big tickets like Pesaro, Risanamento, just your feeling, if you believe you are still comfortable with the kind of, let's say, provision that you took or is it something that you could reconsider by the end of the year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, I will answer to the first question and then I will leave our Chief Executive Officer to elaborate with the second. So looking at the first question, if you can go to page 55 of our presentation, so we can talk about figures, you have the amount of gross non-performing loans and then the amount of net non-performing loans. You have to consider that in the first quarter, we sold non-performing loan for an amount of &#x2013; a gross amount of &#x20AC;1.6 billion, so you have to consider this amount into the dynamics of our stocks. And then if you go to the page 56, you have the inflows from the performing loans.</p>
          <p>That is something that we consider in elaborating for the &#x2013; for what would be the future amount of our non-performing loans. You can see that looking at the past due, we have an increase and it typical in this phase of the cycle, because we have the part of the credit that is deteriorating and you can see in the past due. But looking at non-performing loans, doubtful loans and substandard loans, the amount is &#x2013; now the inflow are down compared with &#x2013; versus first quarter 2012. So the point is that our view is that the amount can increase in the second part of the year, but not in a so relevant amount looking at actual figures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Concerning the big ticket items such as the Pesaro, first of all, let me tell you about our policy. When we see a problem or an issue our policy is to acknowledge it right away. Okay? Last year, we had a provision on Pesaro for approximately, if I remember correctly, &#x20AC;300 million, and we have checked of course against the current situation and we believe that it is perfectly adequate. In fact, I think we stand a chance to have a good recovery. We monitor the situation very carefully. There is the disposal of one asset, which &#x2013; I mean the value is not yet totally clear. If it is at the upper range we will recover, I would say, almost all our provisions. If not, our provision should be adequate, at least that is our assessment for the time being. We are determined on all assets that could be associated with question marks; we have determined to proceed as firmly and as fast as possible without any discount, without any flexibility. Okay, the fact is that of course the market is what it is, but we are not timid in moving &#x2013; in addressing these issues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I mean we will see next quarter and the following quarter or so, but we don't have a policy of postponing things. We acknowledge facts as we see them. Okay? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Very clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The next question comes from Francesca Tondi from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Thanks very much for the presentation. Couple of questions also on my side. I mean, first of all, there has been a lot of debate as to whether the ECB at some point may consider taking down the rate on the excess reserve and the deposits of the ECB into negative territory. If that were to be the case, what would be the impact for you in terms of profitability, if any, and how do you think at all you would react in terms of an ALM strategies in your treasury, that would be quite interesting? Is that relevant, or for you ultimately what is relevant really is the change in the rescue rate. With reference to that you just mentioned 100 basis points would give you about &#x20AC;300 million plus or minus net interest income. Is it correct to assume it's a plus or minus are parallel depending on whether rates at this point more likely will be going down, is that already net of hedges?</p>
          <p>And then looking at your NPLs deterioration for this quarter, could you give us a little bit more color of where you have seen some of the changes? A lot of increase in the past dues seems to be concentrated there. Is it more corporate or SME, is it more household, and how do you see this behavior? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So looking at the ECB negative rate, in my opinion what could change could be the amount of commercial papers that we can place on the institutional investors, so only in this case, in my opinion, we can have a positive impact, otherwise no change, no relevant change on our ALM strategy. Looking at the net interest margin...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Will you &#x2013; sorry for interrupting &#x2013; will you then be looking in a different way at your excess reserves, or no matter that you will still be happy to keep whatever that you have as excess reserve, if any?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Francesca, I didn't understand that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I didn't hear you very well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, clearly the negative rate would likely be placed on the excess liquidity reserve that one has at the ECB. Would you change your strategy on the excess reserves, would you change your strategy on where you keep your liquidity, for example?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't have any kind of deposits with the ECB. So we will not have any impact with ECB because our liquidity reserve is mainly in short-term government bonds. So it is not a matter of having an impact on our asset size. What could we have, it could be an impact on our liability side, because in my opinion with a negative yield to the institutional investor or other investors that are depositing money through the banks in the ECB there could be a switch from ECB to wholesale funding for the good quality banks and so, in my opinion, we can have an increase in the commercial papers funding. So, looking at the asset size, in my opinion, we will not have any kind of impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As a matter of fact, Francesca, if I may interject, there was something that was actually voiced from the sound banks to Mario Draghi encouraging him to move in this direction, so that we actually, we might be able to stimulate the wholesale interbank market, which is otherwise dead. We don't know if it will work or not, but it was actually one suggestion that was coming from some sound banks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, coming back on sensitivity on net interest margin, the sensitivity is considering the hedging, so it's considering our actual hedging position. But as you know, this is only a formal indication, because in reality you have to consider the ability of the bank to manage markdown and markup. And as you know, we are in a very strong process of repricing with relevant impact that you can see in the presentation. And those who are looking at the markdown, have it in mind that we are mainly a retail bank. So, the impact is very important for us, but we are managing also the markdown. So, in my opinion, on the &#x2013; looking at reduction in the interest rate, the impact could be absolutely lower than &#x20AC;300 million for our banks, but on a formal basis, so using that model, this is the result of the sensitivity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The theoretical impact. On the markdown, if I may ask, I noticed from the Central Bank data that on average the pricing on deposits on the banking system that is gone up by around 15 basis points year-to-date, whilst I see actually, obviously, a substantial decline in the Euribor. So it actually seems that the markdown compression at this point is not really happening. Could you comment on that, what do you see?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In our banks we have a reduction in markdown. This was true because it is automatic with the decrease in the interest rate, but the reduction was absolutely lower than our competitors. As you know, we are in a very good shape looking at retail funding and so also the ability of the bank to manage markdown is very strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then answering to the last question, so looking at the &#x2013; where we have the increase in past due is mainly related to the Banca dei Territori area, and in looking at the sectors in which we have past due is mainly concentrated in construction services and distribution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, however, I mean it's a relative concentration. I don't think that we have any alarming situation. What you actually &#x2013; what you actually see is that the Italian companies that are very much in &#x2013; engaged in international activities, exports, outside production and so on are not suffering, while the ones that have a domestic focus and domestic limitation, of course, are going down with economy. And I mean one of the things &#x2013; I mean I know talking to you is stating the obvious, but one of the things that I try to explain to people that are not so familiar with the dynamics is when a country goes in a recession of, let's say, their GDP decreases by 2%, the fact is that 50% of the public sector is not affected, then there is a part of the public &#x2013; private sector, such as agriculture and so on, where the output is not really affected. So that 2% becomes a 10% decline for a good part of the real economy and then of course is affecting the quality of the performance of this company, so their ability to repay loans, so that is the fact. And the fact that we have to address is that &#x2013; which is a macro effect, we have to address the spread issue and I mean personally the &#x2013; the way that I see out of the situation is that we &#x2013; besides the technical things that have been discussed like the banking license to the ECM, the ability of the ECB to intervene, blah-blah-blah, but we really have to pressure the move towards greater integration in Europe, because otherwise we create distortions.</p>
          <p>There is one economy, one large economy which is taking advantage of the subsidies deriving from negative interest rates and the other countries are paying a price that exceeds what should be the normal risk premium. So I think that &#x2013; I mean we should not just be spectators and watch this show developing in a way that that is a little bit paradoxical and we have &#x2013; I'm sorry, if I make this detour in this concord, but we have to have a reality check and just as you &#x2013; sometimes you see that bubbles are formed because of the Herd syndrome, everybody goes after something that is unjustified by the fundamentals, sometimes the reverse is happening and I think we have to be among the ones that work to stop this. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Marco Troiano from Berenberg. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. I just wanted a bit more color on the net present value of the LTRO benefits, in particular the &#x20AC;900 million? And can you just maybe share what the benefit was in the semester on the P&amp;L and how you've come to the total number net present value? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me see if I understood, the communication was not too clear. It was on the LTRO benefit, right; the net present value.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Carlo, why don't you share the details, please? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so looking at the &#x20AC;900 million you have to consider that we had a realized profit of &#x20AC;140 million on trading in the first quarter and then we had another &#x20AC;50 million on the government bond portfolio, so in the net interest margin, and then another &#x20AC;20 million of reduction in cost of funding, this is for the first six months. And looking at the second half of the year, you can have the benefit of the net interest margin and the reduction of cost of funding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Anna Benassi from Kepler. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Thank you for the presentation. My question relate to the messages and the indication you were giving about the internal reorganization and also some recent management reshuffle. We hear from all the trade unions messages of worries on what is going to happen and you are looking for cost cutting to rebalance and recover profitability. Can you give us a little bit more view on what we should expect in the second half of the year, and more important in 2013 in terms of cost savings on one side, but also some revenue defense, if I may, something that can help you to defend the existing strong position, but which currently is not enough, in fact, to maintain a cost/income ratio similar to in the best years and not as you were saying at the beginning what the plan was going for. So can you give us an idea what is going to &#x2013; what is happening on your cost base, in fact? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a second, I'll ask my colleagues if I understood, I missed part of your question. On the cost/income you are asking which are the levers for improving the cost/income, is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, in part, because the cost/income &#x2013; in fact I hear an echo &#x2013; cost/income, in fact, is cost on revenues. My question is very specific on costs and the action you have put in place that are making in fact trade unions so worried, then you had couple of days of strike. Just to understand if what we have read on press is true and what is going to happen, in fact, to your distribution and how much you have in mind in fact to save in order then to have a better cost/income, in fact, in 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, first of all, with the strikes I think we have to put that within the general context. There is no question that the Italian banking system, if you look at all the macro figures, this is well known, it's overstaffed, over-branched, relative to the rest of Europe to Continental Europe. If you look at the Italian branching system vis-&#xE0;-vis, the northern countries, well, then I mean the gap is even much, much higher and the average return in the industry, in the banking industry is too low. I mean the ROE in 2011, you know, was very low for the industry. So it is clear that in this situation all banks have to act to revisit to the business model and to improve efficiency. Now what is happening is that typically, I mean, we are the largest bank in Italy and we've always been, not only the largest but the leading bank and I mean basically the rest of the system follows us.</p>
          <p>So there is a great sense of attention at what we are doing and our internal situation, I mean, in terms of strikes or whatever is certainly &#x2013; I don't see it as any different from that of any other bank. So I think it is more of a general movement, rather than company specific. I think when you look at the picture, personnel costs are one item, okay, they're a big item, of course. And it is clear that &#x2013; I mean you want banks to &#x2013; we need banks that are profitable that are performing and their reward capital. And so it's clear that there is a certain level of uneasiness, but I would also say that there is cooperation on the side of the workers and they are &#x2013; we are exploring ways of achieving savings in &#x2013; that in a way that makes a sense from both the sides, okay.</p>
          <p>And, I mean, we are really studying a lot of options in that respect and frankly I would leave it at &#x2013; I wouldn't go any further in my remarks on this topic. I think we have to be determined but sensible and I'm pretty sure that we will also find a sensible counterpart that understands also why we have to move in a certain direction, but I repeat in a sensible way.</p>
          <p>Now, of course, when you're talking about the cost/income it's not only the numerator, there is also the denominator which offers room for improving the overall ratio and that is an area where with the quality of service, quality of product and may I say, on account of the fact that that Intesa Sanpaolo is a very solid bank, a very solid bank and that is in itself a very important factor for the market, for our customers. I think that we can move very effectively to improve this indicator or at least to keep it at a good level, because frankly, a cost/income of around 50% is not too bad. I mean until recently I lived in a country where the cost/income of this sort looked like a mirage.</p>
          <p>I think we will &#x2013; we have room to work on both numerator and denominator. At the same time, okay, we also have to invest. It is very important that we do not work on efficiency alone, at the expense mortgaging our future. We have to invest whatever is necessary to make this bank a best in class competitor, not only in the Italian market, but by European standards or by international standards. And that would call for investments in technology, will call for investment also in people, in communication and whatever is needed, okay? So again, I mean we have to walk a tight path, because I mean performance is a must, there is no question performance will be our main focus, our priority, because we cannot be satisfied with a general performance of the sector, okay? We have to outperform at least our peers and the current levels of return of the banking sector. But we also have to build a future, a solid future, a future in which Intesa can be a highly competitive, best-in-class bank according to any parameter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for deep comment. So if I take 2011 it closed with sort of &#x20AC;16.8 billion revenues and &#x20AC;9.1 billion costs. Is this something you'd see significantly changing, any one of the two, as you said you are working both on revenues and on costs? What of the two will change the most this year and next year more importantly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you know, let's not forget, I mean that we also live in a volatile, highly volatile market. And just &#x2013; so that you understand what I'm also telling my colleagues within the bank is that when you're in a recession the priority is certainly not expanding market share, at least on the credit side. I want to make &#x2013; to be very clear on this. Expanding market share on the lending side in a recessionary environment is not a priority. It is the easiest thing one can do, but you pay a very dear price if you do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In financial services this is a golden rule. I don't put market share on credit in the target of anyone in our organization, at least in Italy. Not &#x2013; there is not a single person in the organization that has that as a target. The target is delivering true bottom line with very conservative provisioning and we are not going after achieving good results in 2012. Whatever we do has to be good also for the long-term. As I said before, whatever over-performance we get, in this environment I prefer to have &#x2013; to be over-provisioned. I hope I've been very clear on this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, very clear. So the thing we take for the capital gains which have been already pretty significant in H1, but H2 will be again strong after the bond buyback. So I take this comment like using also these extraordinary income to help cover even better your books?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am in for having long-term customers, I consider you a long-term customer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I want to be able to surprise you with good performance, not this year, not next quarter, but in the coming years as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we will do whatever it takes to make that happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I take it, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a question from Alberto Cordara from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. When we speak with Italian banks nowadays we hear a lot about leveraging and the leveraging is becoming a key theme for the industry. But when I look at your numbers I can see that quarter-on-quarter your loan to cash must have come down, but then on the other hand the total assets have increased and they have increased pretty materially, particularly versus the end year. In this quarter there has been an increase in the financial assets, both for trading and AFS and I just wanted to question you on this and what is the strategy here and why when the sector is actually going through the leveraging process you increase the size of your balance sheet? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, but it is completely different to increase the balance sheet with loans or medium-term loans or with the short-term government bonds. So, the point is that we are increasing the very short-term part of our government bonds financing with some REPOs from the market. So we are in any case best-in-class, looking at leverage and it is not that kind of assets, the point of the leveraging that all the banking system will have to do and we have already done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, it is very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question is from Domenico Santoro from Nomura. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Just a little bit more visibility here on the NII to understand the mechanics here at page 37 on the presentation. I see, first of all, this other item of &#x20AC;64 million, so I was wondering whether you can comment on that. I assume it is higher cost of funding in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Then the second question on NII again, was wondering whether there was any change in the hedging policy here in the second quarter in terms of deposit hedged? And I appreciate actually all your comments on repricing of loans, apart from costs. I was surprised as well that there is no sign of a major de-leveraging here in the quarter. But since you are stressing a lot the repricing here, I was just wondering whether you can give us some visibility on the evolution of the NII in the third quarter considering also that rates are <mark type="audio gap" /> (1:16:00)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...the end of the second quarter lower than 40 basis points and this is very important for understanding the dynamics of our net interest margin. In page 37, you have the impact on a quarterly basis that is probably the one that you want to stress, because on a yearly basis it is easy to understand that the impact is on &#x2013; our pricing spread is the effect of the very strong repricing on our loans. That is more than compensating the reduction in markdown related to the reduction in the Euribor. So for the first time, when we had a decrease in the net &#x2013; in the Euribor, we have an increase in spread.</p>
          <p>So this is the results of our repricing actions and looking at yearly basis, we have an increase in the so-called other that is the increase in the government bonds. Looking at the cost, it is something that we had specific in this quarter. You have an increase in the hedging and so that is the contribution from our hedging facility and I confirm that we didn't change our position looking at the hedging, so same amount, same net interest on these hedging facilities. Looking at the spread, we have the impact of the markdown that was exceeding the impact of the repricing, because if you look on a quarterly basis, we have a very strong impact on the reduction in the Euribor, adding up the last part of the decrease of the first quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>Looking at the other part, so it's the part that in which we have a combination of a set that we can go see there probably as one-off, because we have a reduction in the portfolio of our investment bank, so Banca IMI and we have a reduction in the net interest margin, but is more than compensated by the increase in the profit from trading. So at the end we have increasing revenues deriving from the reduction in portfolio in Banca IMI, so we have a reduction in net interest margin that can be considered as one-off and an increase in profit from, realized profit from trading in Banca IMI. Then there is a reduction in the money market revenues, because in our treasury departments we have an impact from the reduction of the Euribor, looking at the Refi rate at 1%, it was in the first part of the second quarter. Now with the Refi rate that is 75 basis points, we are increasing, again, our revenues in the money markets part of our portfolio. And then you have the increase of our government bonds portfolio with a contribution to the net interest margin.</p>
          <p>Looking at the third quarter, it is not easy to say what could be the dynamics of the net interest margin. For sure, we will have again a reduction in markdown, because Euribor is again coming down. And so it's with the falling of Euribor, we will have a reduction in markdown, but the re-pricing is still giving us a very good contribution. And also the negative impact of the one-off on Banca IMI and on money market activity, in our opinion, we will not have in the third quarter. So it is likely that we can have a good performance of net interest margin, but the sign of increasing or decreasing will depend on markdown and the &#x2013; on the impact of the Euribor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have a follow-up questions, sorry, on the deposit, because I have noticed actually that deposits are pretty much stable, this is a key difference vis-&#xE0;-vis other peripheral country, there is just a light correction in some lines in your presentation. Is there any significant change in customer behavior in the third quarter or in the sum that you want to flag?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you look, our deposits &#x2013; deposit base, you have to consider the difference between retail and wholesale, because we have some bond on the wholesale part of our funding maturing during this quarter and so not replacing. So, it is a negative part of &#x20AC;3 billion, because we had something like &#x20AC;4 billion maturing and only &#x20AC;1 billion increasing. And so the only part of our deposit side that is in a reduction but was a planned reduction is that the wholesale, medium-term wholesale, and then looking at the retail side that we are in increase also in the second quarter, not so relevant but it is an increase. And looking at the comparison with the end of 2011, we have good dynamics on the retail side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If your question implies &#x2013; there is an implicit question are some customers withdrawing money, certainly not, certainly not. And there is another point that you should be aware, that our costs on deposits is significantly below market, okay. It's a very important point. So we have abundant deposits and cheap deposits and there are other banks in the system that are on the other side for whatever reasons, they are paying extremely high interest rates on deposits. We are not. We are significantly below mark in average and retail deposits are not shrinking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. This is very useful. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You are welcome. Thanks. Next, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Andrea Filtri from Mediobanca. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. Just one question from me. Mr. Cucchiani, if you could give us a bit of color regarding the strength of the insurance contribution year-on-year, what is driving that and was the impact of the spread widening on this item in Q2? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Carlo, do you have specific numbers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't you &#x2013; let Carlo give you the figures and maybe I give you the color.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So if you look at the contribution of our insurance companies, we had very good contribution in the first quarter of this year, was mainly driven by the financial parts of the results and also in the second quarter with the reduction in revenues, but with a very good contribution, with a contribution deriving from the government bond portfolio and from the financial parts of our insurance companies, that is mainly related to the realized profit and to the net interest income that we can have from our bonds portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Give us the detail of the two numbers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you give us the detail of those two numbers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Of the net interest margin and of the realized?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>60% is realized and 40% is the contribution from net interest margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so I see no other questions and no other &#x2013; no one else lined up for questions. I presume that that is also related to the fact that you're not yet on vacation and you're going to move on to another conference call. If so, I thank you once again very much for listening in and I hope you can all have a break, summer break, and wish you a nice and enjoyable and relaxing vacation and we will see all in the fall and look forward to doing so. All the very best and many, many thanks. Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This will conclude today's conference call. Thank you for your participation. Ladies and gentlemen, you may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>