<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1142742" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>FY 2007 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-03-20</date>
    <companies>
      <company>52770</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Corrado Passera, Managing Director and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1">Luigi Tramontana</participant>
      <participant id="2">Corrado Passera</participant>
      <participant id="3">Pier Passerone</participant>
      <participant id="4">Matteo Ghilotti</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="6">Marcello Zanardo</participant>
      <participant id="7">Eugenio Cicconetti</participant>
      <participant id="8">Francesca Tondi</participant>
      <participant id="9">Fabrizio Bernardi</participant>
      <participant id="10">Andrea Vercellone</participant>
      <participant id="11">Riccardo Rovere</participant>
      <participant id="12">Roberto Marchesi</participant>
      <participant id="13">Guglielmo Zadra</participant>
      <participant id="14">Matteo Ramenghi</participant>
      <participant id="15">Jeremy Sigee</participant>
      <participant id="16">Carola Bardelli</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Good afternoon for some of you. Thank you for joining us today. We're presenting our 2007 results and a number of ideas we have in mind.</p>
          <p>Difficult times on the market, for sure. But I'm talking on behalf also of my top people in the team that manages with me Intesa Sanpaolo. We are confident that our business is in very good share and that is the reason why we confer our financial targets and our goals for the Business Plan 2006 and 2009. I will obviously elaborate on all the details. But let me just give you my feeling about this confidence on our results.</p>
          <p>The 2007 results taking apart the trading revenues are well in line with our target for the year. The integration process that is a very complex one has been implemented in a very successful way. We believe that we are ahead of schedule and that was the main challenge in 2007.</p>
          <p>And during these 15 months, the Bank has been able to build a number of engines, the number of drivers that will create growth and we will reach speed during 2008, full speed during 2008. So first point, we confirm our objectives.</p>
          <p>Second point, during 2007 we had, as you know, a number of very significant capital gains. We decided to use part of them to make our P&amp;L and our balance sheet stronger in the future, what I mean. For example, we had a number of legal situations that might have lasted for years and would have cost a lot in terms of legal cost and also in terms of mediatic effects. So we decided to close them.</p>
          <p>Parmalat is the most well known. It's something that was expensive, because more than 100 million had to be added to what we had already provisioning for. But that's closed. Another way we used the &#x2013; some of our capital gains was a very prudent evaluation of all our shareholdings, of all our assets, and that's the reason why we had decided to impair the value of Nextra, that was both the occasion of the agreement with Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole and that accounts for 260 million on the fourth quarter results and then on the year results.</p>
          <p>In the fourth quarter, we have other two effects that are negative, if we look at them immediately, but might be another &#x2013; other good reasons for making our results stronger in the future. One is the fiscal effect of the improvement of the tax rate. Because of the reduction of the tax rate this year, we had to pay almost 380 &#x2013; almost 400 million because the future fiscal benefits we had in our accounts had to be corrected with the new lower tax rate. And so in the fourth quarter of this year, we have a total unexpected effect of 385 million.</p>
          <p>And the last effect is trading profits. Trading profits in the fourth quarter were negative, 65 million negative. But given the situation, we consider it to be a very reasonable result. That comes from a number of components. The main one has to do with the structured credit products, where we took devaluations, write-downs non-realized losses, something that might come back in the future for 360 million.</p>
          <p>So if you take these four elements, the Parmalat and the other legal case settlement, the Nextra impairment, the fiscal changes, the fiscal &#x2013; the tax rate charges and the devaluation, they're very prudent. I will talk about it because we will give total transparency to that. So they're very prudent devaluation of the structured credit products portfolio. I mean, you get more or less to 1 billion. So we used &#x2013; let me use this word that is not right, but gives the feeling &#x2013; part of our capital gains for these four elements. We then got to &#x20AC;7,250 million worth of net income and we confirm the dividend, both the ordinary dividend and the extraordinary dividend.</p>
          <p>What else before we start with the figures. The situation on the market is difficult. I don't have to tell you why, and a lot of banks have been and will be affected by this situation. We strongly believe that our bank will be much less affected than others. First of all, because of our strong liquidity position, we are structurally imbalanced. Our customer loans are financed by customer deposits. So we don't have to rely on external markets to fund our industrial activity, that's a very safe and comfortable position.</p>
          <p>The second is the business &#x2013; our business model. We are simple. We have four businesses. The retail, the Banca dei Territori one, the Corporate &amp; Investment Banking one, the Public Finance one and then we have our International Subsidiary Division. Four businesses, very clear, very business. The largest part of our revenues come from retail, more than 80%, to a large extent, to a certain extent foreseeable. I mean, something that you can count on.</p>
          <p>The Corporate &amp; Investment Banking activity is strong, is 16 or 18% of our portfolio. But very much basic things, very strong relationships with long-term customers; a number of activities where we are leaders in our market, no finance kind of things. So the business model is simple and to a certain extent less effected by market turmoils. The liquidity, market model, and the third, is the very prudent evaluation and devaluations we have made of our proprietary portfolio. We will go through that, because we will give you all the details and &#x2013; but comfortable position also in that respect. In such a situation, a bank like ours might have and might enjoy some opportunity, some good opportunity in the future.</p>
          <p>As you know, we have a number of very focused acquisitions in mind to strengthen our businesses. Nothing on the table today, but the Business Plan provided for some acquisitions in Eastern Europe and we got the right thing in Ukraine. We want to reinforce asset management, but we decided not to do it now. Let's wait for the market to settle down. So we will be able to do that because of liquidity and equity stability.</p>
          <p>Second, we might have some more opportunity because of interesting assets that we might find on the market. I'm not talking about distressed assets. We are not going to buy any kind of distressed asset. But we might find in the next month good assets at distressed value, at distressed prices, so who knows, maybe. For sure, we will finance new acquisitions with divestment, and we have found a number of non-core activities in our portfolio that if needed are &#x2013; can balance our investment. So that's another message I wanted to convey at the beginning.</p>
          <p>Last point is about transparency. We've always been transparent; we will always be transparent. But we decided to go a step further. According to what Pillar 3 under Basle 2 provides for and according to what a number of people believe, we too believe. So we have to make a further effort in terms of transparency to help the market get out of the situation. We all have to be committed to recreate trust on the market, and transparency is a key element for building trust and confidence. So we are going to give you all the details of our, for example, credit structured products, nothing to hide. And for each component we will give you what it is, what's the collateral, and then how much we evaluated the item. So you have to know what we know, and I'm sure you will agree with us on the fact that we have been very prudent in evaluating these assets.</p>
          <p>So now I will go through the usual presentation and then we will have all the questions. The first two pages are the methodological pages; the parameters, the consolidation areas. I mean, I will not go through them. You will get these details when you want.</p>
          <p>This is a summary of the summary, and of the points that I made. The recurring operating performance is better than what we had in our target. What I mean by recurring is whatever is not trading, keeping up our trading. That as I said was a negative in the fourth quarter. But the rest, the industrial activity is well in line with our business target.</p>
          <p>Second is the point I made about the asset valuation, very prudent, that will help us in standing the situation also in 2008. Third point about 2007, we had a commitment to give &#x20AC;5 billion worth of dividend, 2 billion of them extraordinary dividend, we confirm it. For 2008, we are helped by the valuation we made in 2007 and these are the two main points. We will complete the integration that is ahead of schedule, I will give you some evidence of it. And we will complete the development of drivers for growth. I mean, they have to be at full speed by the end of the year in order to reach the accrued speed we had in mind for 2009.</p>
          <p>We confirm the ordinary dividends, the dividends we committed for in the Business Plan for 2008, but I will comment on dividends a little bit later. And same thing for 2009. Net income of the Business Plan was 7 billion. Dividends were 4.5, we confirm them. And the only change we made is the 6%. On the results of 2009, if everything has gone according to plans, we will distribute to shareholders whatever is in excess of 6%. In the Business Plan we had 6.5%, but we believe that a company that at that point is a company capable to create &#x20AC;7 billion worth of net profits every year and has gone through the complete restructuring of the Group, can afford this kind of Core Tier 1 ratio and that's the only change versus the Business Plan.</p>
          <p>Results of the year; growth, that is the main point. You remember we have a four pillar strategy; sustainable growth, very strict cost control, very strict risk control and investment. Now, we added one point to the four pillar strategy of the Group. We added liquidity, very strong attention to liquidity. So growth is the first of four elements that have become five.</p>
          <p>Growth, recurring growth is here. We are in &#x2013; almost in line with the 7%, but the 7% is what we have to have on average. The first year was the year of the restructuring, of the firings of the people, of the transfer of the people. So we are very happy about this 5.5. New &#x2013; 200,000 new customers, a good value that has to be exploited in the future.</p>
          <p>Costs better than what we had in mind. You will see 3.7. The real comparison is 1.1, because we had an extraordinary benefit from the change in the TFR legislation. But minus 1.1 before the merger synergies, because we will start getting the synergies in 2008 and 2009, is a good performance. The combination of growth and cost control bring us to 15% growth in operating, recurring margin that is more than in line with our Business Plan target.</p>
          <p>Cost of credit, in line. You might remember that we have 40% &#x2013; 40 basis point as our target; is 41, but actually is 38. Because in the first quarter we decided to change a number of mortgage contracts to make our marketing efforts easier. So the real recurring is 38. So in line with the 40 basis points we had in the Business Plan.</p>
          <p>The quality of our assets, so far in line. No real evidence of a change of or a decrease in the quality. The non-performing loans down total amount, absolute amounts down versus the end of 2006. Very strong generic reserve is the reserve we have on performing loans, 2.2 billion. And then as I said before, we closed a number of litigations, a number of legal situations that might have been annoying. Liquidity is what I said. I don't want to repeat.</p>
          <p>Dividend; dividends exactly what we said, almost 5 billion in terms of yield on &#x2013; I don't know which price, some days ago price is between 9 and 10%. Future dividends, we confirm all the dividends &#x2013; we are at page eight, I am saying that for the people that are just listening to us and not watching the presentation, sorry, I haven't done it before. Page eight, our future dividends, we confirm all the dividends that we had in the Business Plan. Then we have two question marks because we cannot say or not commit for extraordinary dividends in 2009, not foreseen in the Plan by the way, or in 2010. But as I said before, we will distribute extra dividends should the Group have a Core Tier 1 in excess of 6%, not 6.5 as previously provided for.</p>
          <p>Page 9 and page 10. I don't want to take you through all these figures, but you will find these pages useful to make the comparison possible, because there are so many exceptional items. The merger cost, amortization, the asset available for sale, divestment, the Parmalat rather than other legal cases, the trading profits. So here you see what I mentioned before. In terms of tax rate, in terms of tax charges, we have almost 400 million extra charge. So we are paying 39% that is far from being our running rate.</p>
          <p>Actually, we will have &#x2013; thanks to the new regulations, we will have from now on no more than 30, that is less than what the Business Plan provided for, 33 becomes 30. While in 2008 we pay this extra charge. So I will not go through that, but you have to keep in mind in comparing the results that items like the extra impairment of the tax rate or the Parmalat or the trading profits, are items that make the comparisons very difficult.</p>
          <p>Same thing for the last quarter where we have all the effect of most of these items. So if you compare the two quarters, the fourth 2007 is better than 2006. While if you take at face value the figures, you are a bit intrigued.</p>
          <p>Summary, we said some of these figures already. In terms of operating income, plus 5.5%; operating costs, minus 1%; cost/income down to 51; operating margin up 15; pre-tax income up 15%; net income &#x2013; okay, but we have all the capital gains here.</p>
          <p>Liquidity, as I said before, the direct customer deposits, the structural deposits of the Bank are stronger than the loans to customers. So this balance, this structural balance between customer loans and customer deposits make our liquidity situation rather comfortable.</p>
          <p>Here you've all the details of the P&amp;L. I don't repeat what I've already said before. These two arrows are to &#x2013; but we will comment on each line. For sure the 11% growth in net interest income is a good figure. And we see these figures continuing also in 2008 and 2009 because of the performance in terms of volume. I will tell you when we get to that point.</p>
          <p>Let's keep going. The portfolio, as I said, 82% comes from retail and private, and the rest is also very sound. But it's a point I already made.</p>
          <p>In net interest income, 11% year-on-year, that figure comes from page 15. I keep forgetting to give the page. Page 15, 11% growth in interest income. We have volumes going up more or less on average 10%, but different growth rates. SMEs have to be kept under control if we want to keep the quality of our loan portfolio at the level where we are. We have to be prudent. But volumes 10%, markups well defended; markdowns, obviously, widening because of what happened in terms of market yields during 2007. The last quarter was the best quarter ever recorded in our accounts.</p>
          <p>Commissions, commissions down as foreseen a bit lower than expected, but we have already commented this trend. The reason why we are down 2% is to a certain extent because of the physiological effect of the merger, customers move between the two product offers in order to get the best prices. And we are &#x2013; for example, we are concentrating our current accounts in Zerotondo, that is zero commissions, so we had during the year a number of customers moving there, rationally moving in that direction and so we lost probably around of 80, 90 million.</p>
          <p>The big lack of commissions was with asset management products. It's a market problem. It's a problem about the expectations of people, but it's also a problem of ours that we have to fix. I will elaborate a little. Because asset management is probably the largest opportunity area for us, all the other commissions have performed very well. And what is nice about the last quarter, the reduction stopped and this figure is there despite the fact that we reduced by 50% the front fee income, because, as we said in a number of occasions, we are reducing in a significant way that component of our revenues.</p>
          <p>Trading profit, trading profit down from 1.8 billion to 1 billion, reasonable &#x2013; I don't know if it is reasonable, but that's the case. And this is the 64 loss we suffered from in the last quarter. This 64 million loss come mainly from the decisions we have taken in terms of evaluation of our structured product portfolio. We will go through that in &#x2013; very much in detail. But the 360 million worth of devaluations markdowns to be made according to mark-to-market values brought to minus 64 the quarterly results.</p>
          <p>Let's look at the structured credit product portfolio. In the next pages, you will get the summary. Then in the appendices, you will get some detail and then there is a document with the press release that give all the possible details. We have subdivided the portfolio into three pieces; the subprime, the contagion area, whatever is, there is connected to subprime, and the rest of the portfolio that to a large extent has not been affected by the subprime crisis.</p>
          <p>You'll find that the methodological criteria. It's all mark-to-market whatever is possible to mark-to-market is everything, obviously, according to the international accounting standards. Where there is not a market, there is a mark-to-model. But in that case further external appraisals, evaluations have been asked in order to be sure that what we have is exactly the right evaluation.</p>
          <p>This is the total picture, subprime is minus 49. We are short in the sense &#x2013; and you'll get the figures &#x2013; that our short positions are higher than the long positions. So we are against subprime. The contagion net exposure is 500 million and we will tell you how we have devaluated that. The monoline risks is 61 million. And then we have the portfolio that is not affected, is not very indirectly by the subprime risk and we will give you all these details. If we take the portfolio, all, everything is investment grade. If we take the portfolio from the vintage point of view, 42% is before 2005, 30% is 2005 and then a little part of it is after that.</p>
          <p>Some of these assets come from far away in the past decisions, when we decided we had a lot of free capital to put some of this money in these products with the idea, and we confirm it to keep them until maturity. So most of these products are not liquid, but it was like that. Some of them were inherited by Comet and we decided to wait for them to get to maturity.</p>
          <p>So sometimes when you want to apply market prices to such situations, you have extravagant figures, and we obviously applied the market prices. But this portfolio is kept and will be kept until maturity. We don't have to sell, we don't have any push and any need to sell. So as I said before, some of the devaluations will be &#x2013; will become capital gains at the beginning &#x2013; at the end, sorry.</p>
          <p>Only 11% of the portfolio is US residential linked. This is an example of the kind of figures that you will get with the details afterwards. Take the subprime, long position nominal value, face value 269, short position 220, net position 49. At the end of September, you might remember, 11. That was the situation at the end of September. Then if you take the write-downs or the write-backs, this long position had lost &#x2013; not realized &#x2013; but let's say had lost 195. The short position, obviously, had increased in value and the net effect of write-downs and write-backs is 96. So we have today an exposure of 73 and an edging situation, a short position of 122. So we are short of subprime.</p>
          <p>The area of contagion, you will find each category, the multi-sector CDOs, the Alt-A, the TruPS, the Prime CMO. You find in the black box &#x2013; in the blue box the exposure, the short position we have, the P&amp;L effect we paid during the year, and then you find exactly the content in terms of collateral. What kind of assets is there? What kind of rating are these assets? What kind of attachment point we have? You know that attachment point means the amount until which you don't lose even if the vehicle loses.</p>
          <p>So, for example, in this case attachment point of 30% it means that the first 30% of loss does not belong to us, and then we have taken another 14% devaluation to make sure that losses will not get to us. And the kind of criteria have been used to evaluate, etcetera, etcetera. So for each category you have the detail. Monoline, as I said, is a small position. You have all the &#x2013; some of the detail in this page and other details in the appendices.</p>
          <p>Than you have the rest of the portfolio. And in the rest of the portfolio, again, you have the description of the CDOs or the ABS, and the kind &#x2013; the vintage, the attachment point, the content and the reasons why we have made some write-downs or some write-offs. I will not go through all of them, but you have them in your document.</p>
          <p>Now we are at page 27, 27 is income from insurance business, more or less in line despite bad performances of the market in the second semester, more or less the same performance in the two years.</p>
          <p>Cost, operating costs has always been and will remain one of our strength. We have a good cost control. We have also some contingency in the case some revenue growth has to be balanced in our result. As you know, it's a minus, it's minus also for personnel, despite we don't have yet the exits in &#x2013; or very small part of the assets in 2007. Let's say, everything is really under control and a little bit better than the Business Plan.</p>
          <p>Cost of risk &#x2013; provision for risks and charges. This growth of the risks and charges comes from the Parmalat and the Finmek case. I mean, that's what I described before, most of it. In terms of net adjustments to loans is more or less what we had in mind, and a good part of the growth comes from the extraordinary decisions that we took for marketing reasons, the one I mentioned before at the beginning of the year. And here we have the Parmalat case, so something that I've already said.</p>
          <p>Total bad assets, non-performing loans, if you put all of them together and if we compare the total amount on non-performing loans at the end of 2007 and at the end of 2006, you see that the decrease is significant, because with an increase of 10% of loan value you could have expected a growth in the total amount of net non-performing loans. But that was not the case.</p>
          <p>Capital ratios, we have 6.2, at the end of the year is 5.9 without considering the sale of the branches we had done at the beginning of the year. As we said, we will remain between 6 and 6.5% during the period of the Business Plan, and then at the end we will decide. But our attitude is to bring this level down to 6%.</p>
          <p>An important point is that in this figure we already have the special dividends and we have a good part of the Carifirenze acquisition. These two points are important, because we realized that the possible disposals of non-core assets, we said in the Business Plan 3/4 billion, it will be certainly higher than that. And that will give us the possibility to finance, if any, to finance new acquisitions just by selling assets of ours.</p>
          <p>The subdivision of the result by business unit division, you have obviously all the details in the appendices. But you know that all the divisions without exception is contributing in a very positive way to the results and to the improvement we had in 2007.</p>
          <p>We are now at page 33 and it's the integration chapter. We had the first chapter the results, the second chapter is integration, and the third one is the growth drivers. Integration is going very well. I made just a shortlist of the many things that have been done without any real trouble during 2007. And when you have two banks like ours merging and then becoming one and performing all this tasks at the same time, generally you get a level of disarray that blocks the growth, that creates a lot of trouble. That was not the case and that's thanks to the quality and the commitment and the generosity of our people and the quality of our top team of managers.</p>
          <p>We changed everything at the headquarters. We changed everything in the field. All the management systems have been unified. Union agreements, we made more than 100 trade union agreements during the year. And we've gone through these difficult phase together with all the trade unions that represent our employees in a very responsible and effective way.</p>
          <p>We have chosen the IT system and we were now migrating all the Group to the new system. We have performed all the intra group mergers, the product companies, the international banks in Eastern Europe, the specialized banks, everything has been done, has been at least prepared and partially implemented during 2007. And then, the back-office projects that is underway. This is one of the evidence of the fact that we are in advance. We said the Group will be on the new IT system by the end of 2008, actually we will get to that result by July.</p>
          <p>Second area of advance is that we've done what we said in terms of reduction of people and we have &#x2013; let me use the word reserve &#x2013; that is we have 2,000 people more that might be available to leave, and that will be part of the discussion we will have with the trade unions. That for sure having the potential availability of 2,000 people is an opportunity, as you can understand.</p>
          <p>In terms of shareholding rationalizations, we will do more than what we had in the Business Plan and we are very much ahead of schedule. Cost synergies, only a very small part of them were due in 2007. The good part will be in 2008, but especially in 2009.</p>
          <p>Third chapter, the drivers for growth. These are things that could not be developed during the integration and the first period, where the priority was putting together the two banks. They have been launched during the year and they are now being implemented. They will start giving their results during the next months. They will have to be at full speed at the end of the year.</p>
          <p>This is only to repeat the point that despite the integration we are growing. This is an important point. We are adding 5,000 people to the front end, to the sales force, and that will be done during &#x2013; mostly during 2008, because this year we are creating 3,000 new account managers. But they will start being effective only by the end of the year.</p>
          <p>This is Banca dei Territori with a very large number of projects, more than projects, changes underway. Let me just go through the pages. Page 43 is to say that the new organization on modeling the field has been defined and implemented throughout Italy. Page 44, the rationalization of products that is a massive effort, is underway. The simplification of the contract is &#x2013; will be mostly done during 2008, and we have decided in a number of case to concentrate a very wide product range in just one product. A very large number of new products have been launched, most of them only in the last few weeks and months. So we will get the results during the coming months.</p>
          <p>Page 45, the marketing and sales instruments. We have to create a new CRM, new management system, a new territorial presence coverage. I mean, all the systems are now developed, are being distributed &#x2013; are being distributed in the network, and they will certainly give a strong support to the growth. Intesa Sanpaolo Private Banking is a well kept secret. We have one of the largest private banks in the country, and probably in Europe, because it's already 82 billion worth of assets and we will clearly go well beyond the 100 billion after the full integration will take place. It's a leader in its industry.</p>
          <p>Mediocredito Italiano is another very important instrument. It has been created, the new Mediocredito Italiano, only in the last weeks, is the area &#x2013; is the center of competence for medium and long-term loans for leasing, for whatever, is project finance for SMEs. It works obviously together with Banca IMI that is the main area of competence in investment banking. But it concentrates on the needs of SMEs. That, as you know, in Italy is a very important part of our market.</p>
          <p>Banca Prossima, Banca Prossima is a unique instrument of our Group. I mean, it's a bank totally devoted to social enterprises and to not for profit initiatives. It's a very large part of our society, not only economy, we are talking about tens of thousands of organizations, tens of billions of revenues, hundreds of thousands, millions, actually millions of people involved in the non-profit organizations. We have quite a long experience in this area. We decided to create a dedicated bank.</p>
          <p>The drivers for growth in the Corporate &amp; Investment banking area, that's another leadership position of the Group. We have been &#x2013; they have been able to complete the total integration of the corporate relationship. The new Banca IMI is effective from October 2007. The leader in most of the markets where they operate; equity capital market, debt capital market, IPOs. I mean, we're talking about a very strong organization. We are developing a strong position in International Trade Services.</p>
          <p>We have a unique &#x2013; let me &#x2013; I tend to stress this point not because I want to sell, but because when I say it's unique, like Banca Prossima. Merchant Banking, the kind of people, the kind of skills we have in these unit in our Group are really unique. I mean, the kind of deals we have done in the last few years. The kind of investments and divestments we have done in the last few years have been a very strong contributor to our results, and have proved to be a competitive advantage, because sometimes putting credit, putting loans is not enough. You have to be part also of the equity part on a temporary basis, then you have to divest. But in a number of cases, some restructuring, some generation passes, some big merger, some international project have been &#x2013; have become possible because of this capability of ours to be also equity provider, not only financing provider. Factoring is another area of leadership we've in the country.</p>
          <p>This is Banca IMI. These are two elements of &#x2013; that give the leading position we have in equity capital market and in most debt capital markets in our country. Banca Infrastrutture Innovazione e Sviluppo, we decided to have a dedicated vehicle to public finance. Public finance in our country is a growing area. We have to build infrastructures. We have to optimize the financing of the healthcare system. We have to finance whatever is public and collaboration between public and private. This bank is &#x2013; has become the leading bank in public finance in Italy and we aspect quite a growth from them.</p>
          <p>These are the International Subsidiary Banks. 2008, we'll benefit from a number of investments. We are opening 200 branches. We are completing the merger between the banks we have in different countries. We have created a network of centers of excellence in a number of areas that are servicing all our 10 banks in the 10 countries. And we recently bought, whereby we are completing, finalizing the purchase of a bank in Ukraine. Ukraine was one of the targets of the Business Plan. We almost succeeded in doing something some months ago, but then we failed. Then we found a very interesting opportunity because we didn't want to buy assets or to buy equity in Ukraine. And we wanted to buy a network of branches and we found a network of 600 branches for something in around of $500 million, so is a bit less than 1 million per branch and that will become quite an important, quite an effective platform for our development in that interesting country.</p>
          <p>Here we have some of the details of all our banks in Eastern and Central Europe, and in Egypt. We will not go through these details. These last &#x2013; probably the last point that is a very important one.</p>
          <p>Asset under management, today we are suffering from the market crisis, but asset under management is the single largest opportunity of ours, I said it before. If we take the financial assets of our customers page 57, its 1 trillion, because if you put together the deposits, the asset under administration and the asset under management, you get to 1 trillion. Our customers have with us 1 trillion worth of assets. That's why we believe that just a small percentage of these assets will be certainly moved to asset under management products. And if you make your estimate &#x2013; I will not &#x2013; but even if you take 5 to 10% and you apply market commissions, you will see why we have in mind the results we have for 2009.</p>
          <p>Obviously we have to do something that is not easy. That's why we will probably have to add skills, competencies. We are looking for some boutique. We have looked at a number of opportunities. We are not going to buy anything in the short term because of the market situation. We will not buy anything big anyhow. But this is an area where the goldmine is very interesting. We have to be able to exploit it.</p>
          <p>We already have good people, but we have to add brands, competencies, a network that today we don't have. But this become &#x2013; this will become one area of excellence. The new management we have on board is the right one. Nextra joined the Group at the beginning of the year. So we are just integrating the two asset management companies. It will take a couple of months. But here we have a strong platform for growth.</p>
          <p>Last page, just to remember that 2007 was the year of the integration. 2008 has to be the year of the completion of the growth drivers. 2009 has to be the new cruise &#x2013; the year of the new speed. We will do them. We will do what we have in mind. The kind of investments we are making in capital &#x2013; in the human capital, more 1.5 million base of trading is a massive investment. We will invest in innovation more than 3 billion in the three years and we have not stopped. We have not slowed it down, because we believe that if you have a long-term perspective, that's the way to create value for your shareholders. And so we confirm all the targets, all the financial targets of the Group.</p>
          <p>Conclusions, 2007 has been a difficult year, but a good year. Growth in line, cost better than expected, risk in line, drivers being created for new growth. We have a number of strength that we will try to exploit as well as possible. The main one, let me tell you, is our cohesiveness in terms of tough team is the kind of people, the 100,000 people we have in the Group and their commitment. I want formally, officially thank them because if we got to the results we are showing today is because of their overall commitment to our Business Plan.</p>
          <p>Last point, I will remain here just to make it simple. I mean, I had prepared a very elaborated phrase to say that my commitment in the future, et cetera. If there are rumors about my leaving this Group, they are not true, full stop. Now the questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, sir. Luigi Tramontana from Banca Akros. Just a clarification on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm just looking &#x2013; I am just coming here because I have someone else. Yes, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a clarification on page 20 about the composition of the portfolio relating to RMBS, CMBS, CDOs, CLOs, et cetera. What's the value of this portfolio? Is it the sum of the amount we have above or something different? And the second question is about Telecom Italia, your exposure there. Can you elaborate a little bit about your exposure in terms of equity, in terms of loans? What's your view in terms of valuation? Will you do any mark-to-market on your equity exposure? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First question. The figures you have on the left top side of the page are the net exposure we have in the different categories. How we got to the net exposures is explained in the following pages and in the appendices. Because we start with the nominal value, the write-downs or write-off is according to the fiscal situations. And then we get to the net exposure that is what you have there, if that was the question. The content of each item is also explained in the pages. Is that enough for the first question? No, because it sounds so easy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's just the pie chart, the pie chart where you have the CDOs, CLOs, asset-backed securities, RMBS, CMBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What's the total value of this portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's the one where &#x2013; can we put the page up? It's page number 20. It's always the same amount. These amounts are analyzed by products here, by geographical area here, by vintage here, and by investment grade right here. So this is the total amount of our net exposure and these are the four analyses of those exposures. Each line is further analyzed in the following pages and in the appendices. But if you want to have the net exposure to subprime it's minus 49, to contagion area is 572 and &#x2013; that's the answer.</p>
          <p>Telecom Italia, we decided to invest in Telecom Italia a few months ago. We believe that the value of that shareholding is the one we paid. We expect it to grow. All the investments we have made in equity have been very profitable ones. A very deep job has to be done and performed in the next months and years. I'm sure that Telecom Italia will participate in a successful way in the consolidation of the European market. It's a long-term investment, the same way we have done in a number of other cases. And the reasons why we invested in October are there exactly the same way they where at that time. There was someone here. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Pierluigi Passerone, Intermonte. A couple of question. The first one is that you've been extremely successful on the cost side, thus giving visibility over future cost control. But if you look on the top line, it looks like you should be able to achieve an 8% growth per year in the year '08 and '09. According to the current market condition, it looks a bit challenging as a target. So my question is, can you give us a bit flavor &#x2013; some flavor on how you can achieve this 8% growth? Is it coming from the net interest income or recovery expected in commission? And if I can on the commission, on the net interest income. What kind of spread evolution can we assume for 2008 and 2009 based on current credit condition? Then I have another question. This is just to clarify what's your position on Alitalia because by reading in the press in these days, is not full -.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Alitalia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Yes. And then last question is on, again on the structured credit portfolio. If I understand properly the size, the net size you gave is 6.4 billion. So my question is, can you provide us a figure of how much of this portfolio is accounted under a mark-to-model accountancy and which slice under mark-to-market? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question is about revenues. We will not, as never we have done, we will not give guidance year-by-year on that figure. My suggestion is not to make eight-and-eight, because speed is going in a different way. Some of our projects, first of all, the asset under management project will happen only at a certain time and is not a linear kind of thing. If your point is, how can you grow so much faster than the economy of your country &#x2013; in the country where you operate?</p>
          <p>I can repeat what I've said in a number of occasions. We have been growing consistently year-after-year at four, five times the speed of the economy. Because the total &#x2013; the growth of the total economy &#x2013; the average growth of the Italian economy is not in any way a good proxy for foreseeing &#x2013; for forecasting the growth of a good bank in &#x2013; operating in financial products. The amount of room for growth, the level of underpenetration in so many products and the possibility for a good bank to get market shares from others, you perform the right activities is such that if you take all the year 2000s, we have 7, 8% per year and the Italian economy has always been between zero and 1.5.</p>
          <p>So I'm not saying that we would not be affected by a strong recession. But we don't expect a strong recession, we don't expect even a recession, actually. So our growth that will be this way &#x2013; not this way &#x2013; is consistent with our Business Plan. Should we have a lack of revenue growth, we have some contingency on the cost side that they are already &#x2013; that are already going down a bit faster than what we are foreseeing that we'll show in the Business Plan. So I'm not saying it's easy. I'm simply saying that after looking it in each others eyes together with my top people, we decided that the bottom line for figure was totally achievable and that's why we came here and I'm talking on their behalf to confirm that commitment. The second &#x2013; I remember the third question. The second is...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Italia, just ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Italia. It's not...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It looks like someone is pulling you to participate on this, let's say, partnership to bid for the company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We never invested because we have been called by someone. So &#x2013; and that's the reason why we have always made money on our equity investments. The only thing I can tell you is that there is zero, nothing on the table. That we were not accepted three months ago in the due diligence phase. So we were excluded by the tender at the end of December. So from the end of December, we are not part of any negotiation. It's probably a pity for the seller, but such is the case. So the only thing I can tell you is that there is nothing &#x2013; totally nothing on the table.</p>
          <p>Third point, your question each item is explained and for each item you will see what's the criteria that has been used for the evaluation. Strict mark-to-market, the almost mark-to-market there is a name I don't remember for saying that there is not a price on the market, but you can use comparables and then its mark-to-market. In most cases you have &#x2013; with the super seniors you have to use mark-to models because there is not anything on the market that is representative of the value. But the kind of models are explained and the kind of appraisals we got are also explained. So item-by-item you have in your materials the criteria we used.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I make a follow-up on the first question? Maybe I am wrong, but let's assume that it's 8% growth per year in terms of top line. I understand that this is not the case, but let's assume this is what you are saying. If I understood properly, the biggest chunk of growth is coming from net interest income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It looks like talking about volumes there is being some slowdown in recent months, at least compared for certain division, let's say, residential mortgages for instance. By factoring such higher growth, in excess of 8% for net interest income implies that you are expecting a widening of the margins that you are able to achieve on loans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The answer is yes. The widening of the markdowns that have been gradually achieved during 2007 will be totally available during 2008 and that's markdowns. In terms of markups, let me tell you that it sound &#x2013; it looks easier to defend the markups, given not yet the liquidity problem or the liquidity crunch, but for sure certain resistance of the market to provide fund. So we expect to get a few basis points higher throughout the different segments of the market in terms of markups.</p>
          <p>You are right in terms of volumes. But whatever is retail will be in our opinion in the high single digit for the next months, while we are not pushing that much in absolute values the SMEs financing. Having said that, we have identified 25,000 very good SMEs that are our main targets and that with those companies we will increase &#x2013; we hope we will be able to increase our share wallet. Maybe we can ask if there are questions also from the rest of the world. Another one from here and then we will ask from...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Matteo Ghilotti, Euromobiliare. I have three questions. The first one is on trading income in the first quarter of 2008. Given the widening of the spread, shall we expect a bigger write-down in the first quarter than in the fourth quarter because of market conditions? The second question is on net fees. Again, given the market turmoil, I wonder if it's reasonable from your point of view to assume a further mild decline in net fees in 2008.</p>
          <p>And finally a question on slide two &#x2013; sorry, slide three on the target of 7 billion of net profit in 2009. This is a target that is written in the slide that is assuming the same consolidation area. Can you provide us a &#x2013; let's say, an updated target, given the disposals and acquisitions that you have made? And just a clarification, if this is a target from which we have to deduct the goodwill amortization, which I think is 300 or something like that, &#x20AC;300 million per year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as write-downs in first quarter of 2007, it's always very difficult in a market like this to make &#x2013; to take commitments. But obviously we have made an estimate. And as of today, given the big slope down decreasing this is in the very last days, our estimate is in around of 100 million, maybe would be better. But it's safe to have something like that in mind. Second, net &#x2013; please excuse me, 100 is already quite an answer I gave you, so I don't...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So I don't understand if this is the write-down or is the trading income?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, no, that's only the write-down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the trading number would be higher than that. Net fees we expect for sure and we will not give more guidance than that. We expect a positive sign in 2008. As far as the 7 billion is after the goodwill amortization, so taking into account the cost of the merger. Let's try with someone from outside.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. First question comes from Marcello Zanardo from KBW. Mr. Zanardo, please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Afternoon, everybody. The first question is on asset quality. I see on page 30 that your Sofferenze, non-performing loans have increased by around 6% on a net level and 9% on a gross level. You made some comments on being a bit careful on SMEs, looking for the good one. We're seeing some deterioration also on the retail side at the system level. So the question I have for you is, number one, what is happening there? Number two, because net interest income, having a focus especially on the margins, but I think will continue to be your growth driver in 2008 on the revenue line. What do you expect in terms of loan provisions, also considering these have increased already Q4 from Q3, although I understand the seasonality effect, so that's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question is on strategy. You said you're going to stay there, that's good. You obviously cannot comment on deals, deals are opportunistic, I understand that. But if you can give us some criteria. First of all, would you consider mainly cash, cash and debt acquisition without issuing shares? Second thing, which kind of criteria? For whatever you're going to buy, are you expected to have a positive EPS from year two, year three? So just give us a guidance. Again, I understand that opportunities arrive and then you act, but just to have a feeling.</p>
          <p>And finally a clarification, did I understand correctly before on fees? I don't know if I understood that you expect a positive signs on fee income in 2008 already. If that is the case, I'm just wondering how, because clearly equity performers are carried down, outflows are significantly down, banking fees will attract volume growth, which is going down, and stock broking fees are collapsing because retail clients are just moving out. Also I think to the net interest income level because the banks have got more incentive now to switch to a different product. So &#x2013; but maybe I did understand correctly. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as asset quality point, what is happening, nothing. The growth of the Sofferenze is totally in line with the growth in the portfolio. So we don't feel for the time being any deterioration of the quality. We confirm the 40 basis points total to the net provision estimate of the Business Plan. Second point strategy and acquisitions. Having said that there is nothing on the table, so we are not in the process of buying anything. And also what we had on the table in different areas will be postponed until we see what happens on the market, because maybe multiples will change, maybe some of the economics of some businesses will change. So it's probably not the right time for buying at pre-risk multiples any activity. The criteria first of all are the ones of the Business Plan. If we find nice, good networks of branches in Central and Eastern Europe at the right price the same way we have done it in Ukraine, we might consider that. We tried, for example, also in the Mediterranean area. We tried in Libya. But at the end it proved to be too expensive. So maybe nothing on the table, but maybe something else will come out.</p>
          <p>Second, asset management, I said it in a number &#x2013; on a number of occasions. If we find good companies, small ones, not big ones that can help the strengthening of our asset management capabilities, we will be and we are interested. Then as you said opportunistic ones, we're not looking for anything and probably it's even wrong to say that we will drive opportunity &#x2013; that there will be opportunistic cases. But given such a shakeout in &#x2013; on the market, I think that it is reasonable to say that also in other businesses where we want to grow businesses rather than countries with the exception of Central, Eastern Europe and in the Mediterranean area, in some of our businesses, not only asset management, maybe private banking, we might find good assets at distressed values. So hard to start to answer more than that.</p>
          <p>We have in mind acquisitions that can be financed through the divestment of non-core activities. So cash, but through the divestments of other assets of ours, and that's what we can say as of this day. Commissions, I confirm that we don't want to see any more minus sign on the year-on-year comparison with the 2008 results. And we are confident we will make it, because the kind of growth we have in terms &#x2013; for example, of number of current accounts. The very deep crisis that we had in asset management in 2007 that may be because we are doing a number of things will not be repeated in 2008. And then a number of things, insurance and mortgages rather than bank insurance products, not only life bank insurance, but also others. But for sure bank insurance did not perform that well in 2007. So all these qualitative elements are enough to expect a plus sign on the comparison 2008 versus 2007. That's the guidance we can give you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. So if I may, the very last question very quick. Is there anything else significant left on your balance sheet, which at today's knowledge you need to evaluate. I'm talking some clearly significant things because you started up the conference call saying that this year has been a year of clean-up and we have seen the numbers clearly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'm sorry; I really did not get your question. Could...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My question is after the different clean-up on different issues, Nextra, Parmalat, and so on that you commented at the beginning, is anything else that we know of today that is being left? Because your balance sheet is so big, maybe we don't have a clear vision as of today knowledge.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My only answer is we would have done it. So...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I cannot expect anything as of today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Mr. Eugenio Cicconetti from Dresdner Kleinwort. Mr. Cicconetti, please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Mr. Passera. This is Eugenio Cicconetti from Dresdner Kleinwort. I have a couple of questions. If you can provide specifically the debt maturity in 2008, the percentage you have in 2008. The second question is about loan growth. You have in the Business Plan a loan growth of about 11% for the Group. So I was wondering if we can maintain this kind of guidance. And if not, or if you can elaborate a little bit better, where this growth is coming from? So if you give us more details with the current situation is little bit changed. And the other two are related to GUM, if you can give us a couple of update on that. And on Risanamento, today there was on the press the possibility that you were entering as a partner in Risanamento. I was wondering if you can give us more detail on that. Thanks a lot. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's start from the last one to the first. As far as Risanamento, obviously we don't make any comment on any specific customers of ours. We have said in a number of cases that there are certainly good reasons for believing that company can go through this difficult period of time on the market. As far as GUM, the general answer I gave a few minutes ago holds true. There is nothing on the table. We are not going to buy anything in the foreseeable future.</p>
          <p>As far as the loan growth, I tried to answer your colleague a few minutes ago. We will certainly have a lower growth in terms of volumes, especially because in a number of segments we want to be very prudent. The lack of growth in volumes will be to a large extent compensated by the stronger markdowns and with more dependable markups. So the combinations of these two will make hopefully the trend in interest income compatible with our Business Plan. And that whatever is missing from &#x2013; whatever is lacking in terms of revenues, we will do our best to compensate it with lower costs.</p>
          <p>Maturities and we have on the international funding if that was the question. We have 10 billion during 2008 that is obviously embedded in our forecast and is totally manageable even if there is no way or that would be difficult to launch any funding initiatives on the market. So we are ready in the case. There is no way to do it to compensate with what we have at home. Then we have a number of further reserves, but probably it will not be needed to get those reserves. So it's part of our financial planning that is &#x2013; that in this is &#x2013; that has to be more than one on all the maturities is well beyond one for all the year 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Ms. Francesca Tondi from JPMorgan. Ms. Tondi, please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Mr. Passera. A couple of questions. One, if you don't mind going back to your 7 billion net income guidance, which you've just reassured us you will make in '09. Just looking at the numbers you made today, taking out some of the capital gains, I come with a clean bottom line of 4.5 billion, you tell me more or less from there 4.4, 4.5. It implies 25, 26% earnings growth in '08 &#x2013; in '09 is significant in this environment. You have talked about fees hopefully getting a little bit better in '08 volumes. But it still require a very significant revenue acceleration or a very significant cost decline. Can you just give us a little bit more color, feeling of how you're going to get there? It looks a little bit challenging in this environment at this point, and where you really are, you have the questions in your mind.</p>
          <p>Second point is on capital. I am a little surprised that you are actually lowering your comfortable level if you want you say above the 6% I will be &#x2013; level of,  you said, I will be happy to distribute back capital and it was 6.5% limit one and the half year ago. In this environment, it's counterintuitive, everybody is worried about risks. Are you seeing, I don't know, more questions in your balance sheet, are you seeing a strong benefit about makes easy that guidance loss actually has made a change in that guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I tried to stop you, but you were like a flood. And if you &#x2013; I'll try to answer, but I am sure that I lost part of your last question. I will start answering, then you elaborate, and if you can just talk a little bit slower because of probably line problems. 7 billion, I will not give much more guidance because that's the way we do it. But for sure it's a challenging target. We will be helped only by a much lower tax rate, but the rest is all very difficult. If you take risks and charges, we probably have &#x2013; we probably had higher than the normal risks and charges in 2007. But the rest has to come from revenues and costs. And we have in mind the mix to do it and the number of mixes to do it, but I cannot go much more in that than I did before. Core Tier 1, I just heard that you mentioned the 6%, and yes that's our exit target. The target after the Business Plan, after we have successfully performed the 2006-2009 Plan. At that point a company of this size, of this with business model, very focalized, very low risk, very &#x2013; with very strong critical mass, can be kept. But maybe you asked me something more that I lost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. What I was asking is, I am surprised that in the current environment you felt, say, confident to even lower that threshold from 6.5 to 6. So do you have cushions? Do you feel significant benefit from Basel 2, how should we view?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, but we are not talking about present scenarios, we are talking about 2010. We are in 2000 &#x2013; beginning of 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. This was not clear, yes</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we expect the history not to end with the present crisis. And in 2010 we will be &#x2013; the wheel will be turning in much &#x2013; in a very different way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So it's a longer term trajectory here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. It's not long, it's 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On 2009 results, so spring 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's clear, understood.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Mr. Fabrizio Bernardi from Deutsche Bank. Mr. Bernardi, please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Fabrizio Bernardi from Deutsche Bank. So you said that, it looks today you expect a write-down on, let's say, the structured credit portfolio of around &#x20AC;100 million. But this is a bit low considering that &#x2013; on slide in the presentation there is a &#x2013; you said that there should be a 1 million trading loss for each business point of widening spreads. And as far as the spread enlargement we saw year-to-date is very, very large. So can you comment a little bit more on this? And second one there was a question on the price purchase allocation because I'd seen a slanted &#x2013; sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The allocation of what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The price purchase allocation because I've seen that in the first quarter of the year there is a positive effect of &#x20AC;290 million. What I am asking is the guidance for '08 and '09. So if we have to expect more or less &#x20AC;100 million of price purchase allocation negative impact third quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. As far as the first question, since I was asked a total figure for the total portfolio, I gave you our best estimate as of today. And these estimates come from the estimate based on each item of this portfolio. We are providing you with all the elements we have. So if you think it's going to be different, please do whatever you want. In our mind after looking at each item of the portfolio on the basis of today's prices, that's our best estimate. For sure the very prudent evaluations we have done on the year-end and when we have done them, the year &#x2013; the 2008 year had already started, so our estimate is the one I gave you. Then make your own judgment given that we provide all the relevant information. The second question was about &#x2013; can you...?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The effect of the price purchase allocation in the first quarter of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes. The merger costs amortization, the cost of the merger that was allocated to this year was very low because we had on that item a positive fiscal element. So next year you will have much lower, very &#x2013; almost negligible integration cost and the physiological level of merger cost allocation that will be in the round of 500 million. And that will be a figure that will decrease year-after-year. So if you combine integration cost and purchase price allocation, you get more or less to the same figure you had this year. But the one you asked for will be in the round of 500 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Mr. Andrea Vercellone from Credit Suisse. Mr. Vercellone, please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I have got a few questions. The first one is now that the purchase price allocation process is finalized, if you could give us the carrying value of Fideuram and EurizonVita? The second one is just a clarification on your answer that you just gave to the previous question on the P&amp;L impact of these purchase price allocation, because it does change vis-&#xE0;-vis your target in 2009, since you have just said that the 7 billion net income is after taking into account the purchase price allocation and now you are saying its 500 million. I think the previous guidance was something 300, 350 at the end of the plan. Then on M&amp;A, just an idea on how willing &#x2013; how lower are you willing to go in terms of Core Tier 1 in the event of an acquisition? Because you're talking about small acquisitions and this is the only where you are measuring whether it's a small or large acquisition. Finally, if you can give us an idea of your exposure to the Zunino Group? And that will be it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the last one, obviously, it's not a public information. Second, M&amp;A, we are not ready to go below 6% in a significant way if not for a very &#x2013; even if we go a little bit below 6%, it has to be very temporary. So that is a constraint we give to the bank. Six cannot be a bad number as a threshold. As far as the PPA accounts, I might try to look expert, but I'm not. And the fact that we have changed a little bit the results, given the size and the complexity of this merger, is not strange. In any case at page 64 you find all the details for this year and for the years to come. As far as Fideuram, if I remember correctly the book value is 3.6 and as far &#x2013; and Eurizon Capital is concerned, I don't remember it but I am sure that someone will give you the figure in a short while.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Just to clarify, so your &#x2013; you answered the previous question saying your target in '09 remains 7 billion bottom line no matter what. That was your answer, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the Eurizon Capital book value is 1.6.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. In EurizonVita?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>EurizonVita.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will ask and I will get them in. I have some memory, but I am not so good. I will give you in a minute.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question while we are waiting for that piece of information.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Mr. Riccardo Rovere from Mediobanca. Mr. Rovere, please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Mr. Passera. Good afternoon to everybody. I have just two simple questions. The first one is on Basle 2. If I remember correctly when you presented industrial plan in April last year, you mentioned capital release in the region of 5 billion from the Basle 2 adoption. Do I remember correctly, would you reconfirm again this number eventually? And the second question I have is on tax rate. What kind of tax rate are you expecting with the new budget law with the new financiara? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, the answer to your colleague, the book value of EurizonVita is 2.7. As far as the tax rate that we can use as a sort of guidance for the next year is 30%. And as far as the Basle 2 effect, I would prefer not to make an estimate as of today. In any case, as we said, whatever saving we can get, it will not be in our opinion usable in the foreseeable future. So to a large extent it is not that relevant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, okay, very good. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Mr. Marchesi Roberto from ING. Mr. Marchesi, please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I have some clarifications about the Basle 2 and Core Tier 1 just to make things clear. So when you talk of 6%, you talk of Basle 1 environment refrain, if I understood correctly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And two other clarifications. When you think of an increase of net commissions in 2008, do you think of change in your commercial policy and restart selling products with an upfront? Or do you think waiting maybe for &#x2013; if you say you are stronger Nextra, Eurizon in the future or do you continue with your current commercial policy in the @network branches. And last question is on, you mentioned in the beginning the potential acquisition of assets at distressed prices. But is this statement still consistent with what you said in the past of strong look at Eastern Europe and the specific businesses? Or this can become more generic for banking business, which is outside these two items, Eastern Europe very specific activity such as the asset management for example? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We will &#x2013; as far as the first question, I already answered. The answer is, yes. The increase in net commission will not come from a change in current commercial policies. And as far as our M&amp;A target, even the opportunistic one will not be out what we consider strategically important for the Group. That is, develop our presence in Central and Eastern Europe, in the Mediterranean area, and in selected businesses that have the right size. Already in Italy that might be developed through selected acquisitions outside of Italy. But for certainly we will not diversify the scope of our business portfolio. Being focused in a limited number of businesses and in a limited number of countries, it is going to remain a key factor for success. I believe that above a certain size and above a certain level of diversification, the complexity costs are so high that they kill all the possible synergies. So if your question was, are you going to diversify your business portfolio or your geographical portfolio with the exception of what I said for Eastern Europe and the Mediterranean area, the answer is no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Mr. Guglielmo Zadra from Morgan Stanley, London. Mr. Zadra, please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. It's Guglielmo Zadra from Morgan Stanley. I have two questions. The first relates to structured credit. On slide 20, you showed the net exposure, which you subdivide in three categories depending on the risk profile. Roughly 5.8 billion out of the total belongs to the third category, i.e., the safest. But when we look at the pie chart on slide 20, it seems like US accounts have overall for 36%, so something in excess of 2 billion, which means that clearly the third category had a lot of collateral, which is US. I can see from the details US RMBS, US CLOs. So what is the level of comfort that you have on this US exposure, which if I calculate correctly is over 2 billion, given &#x2013; the message you've just given? And the second is on cost flexibility measures. You said that if the revenues were to be weaker, you will have cost flexibility. Can you highlight which areas and roughly what can be the magnitude of this flexibility? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As far as the first question, yes, we are comfortable, because US is not only subprime and is not only residential related. But again as I said to a colleague of ours a few minutes ago, that's our prudent estimate. And since you will find all the content in terms of collaterals of our portfolio, you can make up your mind yourself. But we consider the evaluations we made at the end of the year very, very prudent, also for the US part. Guidance in terms of contingency, very difficult to say. In any case, I can tell you that we have identified possible contingencies in round of 200 million worth of operating costs, but I will not elaborate more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question is from Mr. Matteo Ramenghi from UBS. Mr. Ramenghi, please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. I have a question not directly related to results and it is more about your view on the Italian economy and the banking environment in Italy, because on one hand, Italy is seen as one of the most vulnerable economies in Europe. On the other hand, Italian exports are now much more geared into merging economies, banks are not driving the credit crunch differently from other companies and some of these do not have an excessive leverage also differently from many other companies. So I was wondering if it was possible to have your view on this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is a long story, especially as far as the Italian economy is concerned. I don't believe that the &#x2013; first point, there is not something that is the Italian economy. There are many Italian economies and it's hard to make any judgment that holds true for the whole country, because we are talking about geographical and industry situations that are very different with very different level of vulnerability and with very different strength and weaknesses. I must tell you that after what I have seen in this last years from 2000 up to now, is that a very large number of companies that had not the strength to compete in the global market have simply disappeared. And these disappearances have been compensated by the growth and strengthening of a number of few thousands of midsize corporate that have done the right job in terms of restructuring, in terms of innovation, in terms of internationalization. And that have built a competitive position that is making them not vulnerable. I mean, maybe we are not &#x2013; I know certainly, we are not in a number of industries, but in large number of sub-industries and in sub-segments. And in &#x2013; you can call them niche of the markets sometimes are niche worth several billion euros, we have a very strong competitive position and as long as the world keeps growing, East Asia in particular, these companies will not suffer very much if we look at the employment rates.</p>
          <p>If we look at the investments in &#x2013; especially in the center and especially in the north of the country, I cannot say that I feel evidence of real weakness in the Italian economy. For sure, a number of areas of weakness are there and I cannot say it's not true. But our &#x2013; if we are good as we have done in the past in being selective, because when I mention the SMEs credit risk, it's not SMEs are bad. Again, you have to be selective and probably in the next few years we will have another wave of selection into that &#x2013; not into &#x2013; in that segment of the market. As far as the Italian banks, I don't want to comment very much outside of what holds true for us. But for sure the Italian banking industry in the last few years has done quite a job in terms of privatization, in terms of consolidation, in terms of liberalization. And I agree with you. A number of Italian banks have structural strengths that made them less vulnerable than most other international banks to the financial crises we are having throughout the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anybody from here, from the room. There is question from here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening. Just very quickly, can you provide some number on your exposure to the real estate development industrial areas of operations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I will wait for it to arrive because I can't remember. But we are talking about a very &#x2013; we had a meeting a few months and a few weeks ago on the issue, and they want to have the updated data. But it's well under control. If there is any other question while we are waiting for that question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, please. Is the Alitalia question completely over, so should the sale of Alitalia to Air France fail, would you be prepared to stand by at one in helping them growing over the collapse of Alitalia or is it your commitment to go totally over?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In order to answer that question, you &#x2013; we should know something about Alitalia itself, because when we left the process at the end of December we could not enter the due diligence. And so it seems we don't know anything about the company. And in order to answer your question we should &#x2013; you should know something more about the company and that's not the case. So as of today we can simply say that we are out. We have not &#x2013; we have been excluded, we have not been allowed to participate in the due diligence phase. So on this basis it's unimaginable to make any offer. So without knowing the situation from the outside, it's really impossible. As far as our share of loans devoted to whatever is real estate from developers to the final steps of the real estate business for the banking industry is 7%, for us it's 5%.</p>
          <p>Is there any other question from the rest of the world? If not, I thank...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, sir. May I go ahead?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question is from Jeremy Sigee from Citigroup. Mr. Sigee, please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. I thought we finished. I will just ask a couple of clarifications. Can you give us any detail of the components in the increase in the bad debt provision charge from 3Q to 4Q? Can you break that into categories? And secondly, I just wanted to come back on to page 36 of your presentation, where you are talking about staff reductions. I just wanted to understand what the final comment implies in terms of &#x2013; does that mean you go above your 6,500 target by the extra 2,000? Is that what you are implying by that comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I lost part of your second question, if you can repeat it and maybe if you can speak slower?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Just page 36, the comment at the bottom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Page 36, let me get to 36 so I can follow what you are saying.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My question simply is, what is meant by the final sentence there at the bottom? Does that mean you're getting more voluntary redundancies than expected and does that lead to an increase in the total number of reductions that you can achieve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That sentence is generic, because whatever we decide to do in that area has to be discussed and agreed upon with our trade unions. But for sure, there is room for increasing the number of people that will leave the bank. As far as the physiological increase in bad debts, there is really no detail to add, because it's totally physiological in the different segments, no concentration in any unexpected segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Anybody else?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sir. Next question is from Ms. Carola Bardelli from Deutsche Bank. Ms. Bardelli, please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good evening. Carola Bardelli from Deutsche Bank. I was wondering &#x2013; a question about Telco actually, I was wondering if capital increase of Telco is actually take place or do you need to borrow over the &#x20AC;900 million financing that you gave to Telco? And also on Telco, I was wondering if the Telecom Italia share price remained below &#x20AC;1.3, would that mean that Telco would pledge more Telecom Italia shares as a guarantee of the debt? Or would the Telco shareholders need to inject cash in Telco? And finally I was wondering if there is maybe any plan to convert Telco's debt in equity and maybe I thought crises(114:27) would happen. And very final question, maybe your thoughts with regard to a potential share issue or capital increase of Telecom Italia, what is your personal view on that? Would you do or would you not do it? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You would be very surprised if I answered your questions. So I cannot comment on any of the point you made. There is not &#x2013; most of them do not belong to any area of responsibility of ours, so if anything is important will be, if ever, communicated by the different companies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>So thank you very much for you participation to this presentation. We tried to do our best. You will find lot of details in the documents, others been attached to the press release. And thank you very much for your patience.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>