<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1228128" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-06</date>
    <companies>
      <company>67493</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Daniela Ueda, FIRB-Financial Investor Relations, Brasil</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Alfredo Egydio Setubal, Executive Vice President</participant>
      <participant id="3">Daniel Abut</participant>
      <participant id="4">Silvio Aparecido de Carvalho</participant>
      <participant id="5">Jorge Kuri</participant>
      <participant id="6">Saul Martinez</participant>
      <participant id="7">Victor Galliano</participant>
      <participant id="8">Federico Rey-Marino</participant>
      <participant id="9">Marcel Thieliant</participant>
      <participant id="10">John Friedman</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. This is Itau Unibanco Holding Conference Call. At this time, all lines are in a listen-only mode. Later there will be a question-and-answer session and instructions to participate will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. As a reminder, this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Ms. Daniela Ueda of Financial Investor Relations, Brazil. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, and welcome to Itau Unibanco Holding Conference Call to discuss the first quarter 2009 earnings. I would like to remind you that this conference call is being broadcast live on www.itauunibancoir.com. A slide presentation is also available on this site. Before proceeding, let me mention that forward-looking statements are being made under the Safe Harbor of the Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1996. Actual performance could differ materially from those anticipated in any forward-looking comments as a result of macroeconomic conditions, market risks and other factors.</p>
          <p>With us today in this conference call in Sao Paolo are Alfredo Egydio Setubal, Investor Relations Officer; Sergio Werlang, Executive Vice President of Risk Control and Finance; Silvio de Carvalho, Chief Financial Officer; Alberto Furuguem, Itau BBA's Vice President; and Marco Antunes, Accounting Director. First, Mr. Alfredo Setubal will comment on the first quarter earnings. Afterwards, management will be available for a question and answer session. It is now my pleasure to turn the call over to Mr. Alfredo Setubal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Welcome to our first quarter conference call. For those who are following through the Internet and through the slides, we are starting on Slide Number Two, Highlights. The first highlight is the earning, recurrent net income of 2.5 billion reais, with an increase of 9.5% when we compare to the last quarter of 2008. This means a recurrent ROE of 23.1. After the deduction of the extraordinary results, net income of 2,015 million reais, with an annualized ROE of 18.2.</p>
          <p>The second highlight is the extraordinary items. We bought during the quarter 3.58% of the total capital of Redecard. With this acquisition Itau Unibanco is the controller, is in total control of Redecard with more than 50% of the capital. In this acquisition, we paid a premium of -- that we deduct in these results of the first quarter, and the net after-tax impact of this acquisition is 491 million reais. Another extraordinary item is the impact of 56 million reais related to economic plans that clients are suiting the bank.</p>
          <p>The third highlight is related to the provisions that we made in the last quarter of 2008. You remember that we made additional provision of 4.6 billion reais in that quarter. We achieved almost 8 billion reais in additional provisions above the level required by the Central Bank. In this quarter we used 539 million of these additional provisions to compensate the increase in delinquency in the quarter.</p>
          <p>The fourth highlight is related to non-performing loans. We show in this quarter, as expected, increase in the NPL that achieved 5.6 against 4.8 in the last quarter of 2008. And the last highlight is the BIS ratio and tangible equity. The BIS finished with 16.5 in the quarter, with a Tier 1 of 12.7. Of this Tier 1 of 12.7 we have a tangible equity index of 9.9. Both numbers are very high and show a very strong balance sheet and position that we have today to face the more difficult environment in terms of economic environment.</p>
          <p>On the Chart Number Three, we can see more highlights, more numbers. I will highlight total assets of almost 619 billion reais, a little bit lower than the numbers that we showed in the last quarter of 2008, which are a reduction of 2.3%. When we compare with the first quarter of 2008, we can see that the total assets increased 27.7. Loans represents 272 billion reais here including all the endorsements and synergies, a little increase when we compare to December, an increase of 0.3% and 25.1 when we compare to March of 2008. The stockholders equity finished off with 45 billion reais.</p>
          <p>On Chart Number Four we can see the recurrent net income and the deductions that we made related to the amortization of the goodwill of the acquisition of Redecard shares, and also the economic plans that we made in terms of provisions in this quarter, and we finished with a net income of 2,015 million reais, compared with 1.8 of the last quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>On Chart Number Five we can see a more details of our result. Managerial margin achieved 10.5 billion reais with an increase of 6.6 in terms when we compare to the December of 2008. This number is split in financial margin with customers of 9.3 billion reais, and financial margin with the market 1.2.</p>
          <p>Banking fees and banking charge, with a reduction of 13.2% we are going to talk later with more details in some charts ahead.</p>
          <p>Managerial results from insurance pension plan and capitalization before claims, 1.4 billion reais, almost in line with the fourth quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Managerial financial margin and banking fees 15.8, in line with the last quarter of 2008. We can see in the next line that the loan losses increased substantially in this quarter achieving 3.9 billion reais compared with 2.9 billion reais in the fourth quarter of 2008, because of the deterioration of the economic scenario in the last quarters. We can see, as we told during the conference call related to the results of 2008, our expectation was -- that this number was going to increase. And it happened in this quarter and probably will continue to happen in the quarters ahead. We use, like I said, part of the additional provision that we made in the balance sheet of 2008 in the total amount of 539 million reais.</p>
          <p>And non-interest expenses achieved 6.4 billion reais in the quarter, lower than the 7 billion in the last quarter of 2007, but higher than the 5.5 in the first quarter of 2008. We don't see much synergies yet in terms of balance sheet but we tell Unibanco that we are going to see more clearly in the coming quarters.</p>
          <p>We used in this first quarter around 100 million reais of provisions that we made for the integration of the two banks that are not included in these numbers. So at the end, we finished with a recurrent net income of 2.5 million reais.</p>
          <p>On Slide Number Six we can see loans by types of customers. We see the total amount of loans of 272 billion reais. Of these 94 billion is related to individuals. We continue to see that vehicles continue to be the most important part of the individual credit portfolio with 48 billion reais, a little bit more than half of the total credit for individuals. The vehicles portfolio increased almost 2% in this quarter. When we see the numbers for companies, we see a little decrease in the quarter of 0.4%, mainly because of corporate business that reduced the total portfolio by 1.5% because of lower demand by bigger companies. But we see some increase in the small and medium market segment that increased in the quarter 1.8%. The credit that we have in the other countries that we have presence in is South America, almost in the same level that we were in the end of the year.</p>
          <p>On Chart Number Seven, we can see non-performing loans and coverage ratios. The average non-performing loan is 5.6% with an increase of 0.8% when we compare to the end of 2008. We -- splitting the individuals and companies we can see in the green line 9.8 for individuals, it's an increase when we compare to 8.1 at the end of the year. When we see companies here, big companies and the small and medium sized segment, 2.5 compared to 1.7. So all the segments are showing some deterioration as expected, as we said, in the last conference call. And the main reason because we made the additional provision at the end of the year of 2008.</p>
          <p>Even with this deterioration we continue to have a very good coverage ratio for loans overdue more than 60 days with 162% when we compare with 184% at the end of the year. 162 is a very comfortable and strong position to face increasing delinquency that we continue to expect in the coming quarters.</p>
          <p>On Chart Number Eight we can see some ratios for loan losses when we compare to our credit portfolio. On the blue line for those who are following through the Internet we can see provisions for loan losses considering specific and generic provisions here compared to the total credit portfolio. We see that achieved 6%. We included this time the green line for the first time that considered the loan losses for a specific, generic and additional provisions compared to the total credit portfolio. And this number achieved a 9%. So we can see that we have very good provisions in our balance sheet to face the increase in delinquency that we expect.</p>
          <p>On Chart Number Nine, funding and managed resources, we can see on subtotal number two funding from customers that we are at the same level when we compare to the end of 2008. The main reason here is because we consider this funding that we -- the deposit that we had from our clients in a good level. We are in a very liquid position in terms of cash in the bank. So we are not paying to have more deposits at this level, because demand for credit also is not very heated because of the slowdown of the economy. So we are seeing more transfer from investors investing more in mutual funds. Again, that's the reason we are increasing the total money from clients considering deposits and reserves from pension plans and assets under management, an increase of 2.6% of the total client's money at the end of the quarter achieving 615 billion reais.</p>
          <p>On Chart Number Ten, we can see that our funding position compared to our credit portfolio is very sound. 85% of funding -- of deposits are being used for the loan portfolio in a much better position when we compare to the end of the first quarter of 2008 when we were 98%, because the demand for credit was at that time very heated.</p>
          <p>On Chart Number 11, we can see banking fees and banking charge. A reduction in this first quarter, especially related to current account services because we stopped charging a credit register renewal charge. This means that 108 million reais. And also we reversed provision for 25 million related to this current service related to 2008. Also we can see reduction in the credit cards fees in the first quarter, more related to the seasonal use of credit cards. Of course in the end of the year, in the fourth quarter, because of Christmas and vacations the use is much higher. It is normal to have this reduction in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>On Chart Number 12, we can see non-interest expenses lower in this quarter when we compare to the last quarter of 2008. Also here we have seasonal effects, because of vacations and provisions that we made before, especially related to personnel expenses that we can see here, a reduction of 10%. But anyway we continue to be very focused in controlling expenses and we are not seeing yet much of the synergy that we are going to achieve in the coming quarters because of the merge with Itau -- between Itau and Unibanco.</p>
          <p>Efficiency ratio on Chart Number 13, in the quarter, 45.3% and in the last 12 months 47.9. We continue to be very optimistic that we are going to see numbers lower than we had before at Itau in terms when we achieve a higher level of synergies in the merge.</p>
          <p>On Chart 14, the BIS ratio of 16.9, 12.2 is Tier 1 with a very strong number and tangible equity 9.9 of this 12.7. In terms of segmentation on Slide 15 we at Itau used to segment in these four blocks and here we change it. Now Treasury are together with the Corporation, remembering that Corporation mainly is the return of the excess of capital that we have.</p>
          <p>When we see on Chart 16, and that is the last one, we can see the pro forma of these four segments. We can see the recurrent net income of the Commercial Bank of 516 billion -- 516 million reais of results for the Commercial Bank. That means a RAROC of 11%.</p>
          <p>In terms of our wholesale bank, Itau BBA, 377 million reais with a RAROC of 13.6. Consumer credit continued to be very strong, 637 in net income with a RAROC of 35.2. And Corporation and Treasury, Treasury in this quarter because of the opportunity in the market, had very good gains. We finished with 1,030 million reais on a RAROC of 57.4. This completes 2,562 million reais in recurrent net income with an ROE of 23.1% in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Now we will finish the presentation and we are open for your questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Excuse me, our first question comes from Daniel Abut from Citibank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. On the very good information you've given on Page Seven, which is the evolution of your NPL ratio divided by segments, we like to have a couple of questions. First of all, if you look at the ratio overall, which increased 80 basis points quarter-on-quarter, yesterday in the conference call of Bradesco we saw really a very similar increase in their NPL ratio. They said very strongly that they believe that with time on our side we will verify that this quarter would have been the worst in terms of one shot quarter-on-quarter increase in the NPL ratio of about 80 basis points and that they would expect further increases but at normal rate in the second and third quarter and the ratio to peak somewhere in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Do you agree with that statement as far as that you are seeing in your own portfolio? And if so, at what level do you think your NPL ratio could peak, and when? And the second question, if you could give us a bit more information on the NPLs on individuals, which saw the sharpest increase of 170 basis points quarter-on-quarter. Was it widespread in your different products? Or was it concentrated in certain products? Could you elaborate a bit more of what drove that sharp increase? Was it credit card? Was it car loans? Any more color that you can give us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Daniel, Silvio speaking. Just to give an idea about the delinquency ratios, we are expecting for 2009 that the ratio will continue. Today we report 5.6. We expect that can achieve in the total of the Bank, 6.9. In -- probably during the second semester, at the end of third quarter, but is a guess. That's our model show us, but everyday we look at.</p>
          <p>In terms of individuals, we expect that this will continue to deteriorate, but <mark type="inaudible" /> we are continuing to expect that it will continue to deteriorate. We are not having any specific segments that you see deterioration. It's in all segments and the products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Silvio, if I could follow up, it seems to me that you are expecting a similar increase of what we saw this quarter in second and third, another 60 or 70 basis points per quarter. Is that the case? Should we assume that your coverage, your excess coverage, your excess reserve, will be consumed in similar levels that we saw in this quarter, about 500 million or so per quarter over the next two quarters? And how low can your coverage ratio get, it's currently at 162%, for you to remain comfortable with?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The idea is that we constitute this provision totalized; it's appearing in our model. A sign is that we have specific deterioration in the economy. We don't have the precise figures. Depends on the other models. This is not a figure that you achieve after this -- to close the books, but it is the consequence of the models that we are running and it did show the number that we utilize.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you may or may not continue to utilize it, but it's <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Our expectation that will continue probably because the ratio will come down. But we are not expecting that to achieve 140.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You are not expecting that it will get as low as 140?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Silvio, very useful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Jorge Kuri from Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, everyone. I have three questions, if I may. The first one is on financial margins. Given that most banks in Brazil are asset sensitive including you, lowers to liquids normally put pressure on margins. I'm not surprised you reported that financial margins fell 30 basis points this quarter from 10.3 to 10. So as rates continue to fall throughout the year how much pressure should we expect for margins, and &#x2013; I mean just doing a quick math here it seems that your margins would fall probably around 100 to 120 basis points this year. Are these more or less the numbers that you are expecting? Or what is your estimate for the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That depends on the scenario that we &#x2013; you work. We are working on scenario that <mark type="inaudible" />  ratio will achieve a 90.75 in June, today it's 10.25. This means that in the second semester probably we will it more impacting our net interest margin that you can know probably we will achieve 100 basis points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So 100 basis points reduction from here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. The second question &#x2013; thanks, Silvio &#x2013; the second question is on pricing power. We've heard from most banks that the way they're dealing with the compression in bond spreads is through charging higher spreads on lending. However, the aggregate banking data shows that spreads have been falling every month this year and you actually also -- you were kind enough to provide us very insightful information about intra-sensitive transactions and spreads in different transactions, and in both cases you showed a decline in spreads. Do you feel that pricing power is weakening maybe because of the economic slowdown or from competition or from government mandates on Banco do Brasil? Or what do you think explains this compression in spreads charge to consumers? And how do you expect this to play out the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In reality the spread is stable. We had some movement in the spreads. We increased in the first moment. Now it's decreased a little bit, but we are not expect that to decrease so much because of the increase in delinquency. In reality, today we are much more selective and we are not targeting increased market share. In reality we are preserving our margin. That's our focus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And then the final question is on expenses. You reported that personnel and admin expenses fell 11% quarter-over-quarter. I know there's some seasonality involved here, but it seems that this decline also includes some merger-related cost cutting. For example, Bradesco's personnel expenses fell like 4% quarter-over-quarter. Yours fell 11% quarter-over-quarter. So it is clearly a much better performance that probably is explained beyond the seasonality. How much of -- what we saw this quarter was merger-related reductions? And what is your expectation for cost cutting this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are considered that this quarter is seasonal. We are not expect that it will be recurrent for the next quarter. We &#x2013; in reality the synergies, <mark type="inaudible" /> we reduce 2,000 employees. We mentioned that the normal turnover of the bank means a reduction of 10,000 people through the year. I think we will continue in this track. We expect that this year this synergy will be small. Probably the most part of the synergy will happen in 2010, 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. So most of what happened this quarter is seasonal. That's what you're saying?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Saul Martinez from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, gentlemen. First question is on your accounting policies. I'm curious as to why the logic changed for how you classify additions and subtractions to excess reserves as recurring or not. Obviously in the past, additions to your excess reserves have been treated as a non-recurring item. This quarter you released excess reserves and classified them as core or recurring income. And I just want to get a sense for what drove the logic of that change and if you continue, should we expect to continue to have essentially reserve releases benefiting your book value and your recurring earnings going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This subject is polemic. Many analysts mentioned that we had to have this approach, but many of them mentioned that we are okay. We discussed this subject in relation to the reserves, or was it the reserve a lot here in the bank. And there are a conclusion, are a consensus that you are much better to report in the way that we report, because when you constitute this provision in the end of the year, we constitute <mark type="inaudible" /> to ordinary gain. If you did do that, we have not to constitute this provision. It is better to constitute it here in the quarter, not to report an extraordinary at that time. The principle that we take into consideration that it is -- this situation is not a recurring situation. It is just for 2009 that we had this situation in Brazilian economy. That is the reason that we did not put this figure in the recurrent space.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, okay. No. I understand that. But beyond your provisions...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. Sorry, every disclosure is very, very detailed, and you can choose your material, the option that you want.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. No, that's fair. But I guess beyond &#x2013; I guess what was clear to me was beyond the big provision even in the fourth quarter, in the past when you have taken additional -- what you classify as extra reserves, I remember I think in '07 or in '08 you did that for a stressed scenario for your auto book, you've always treated that as non-recurring. And it just seemed a little bit inconsistent with your past disclosures this quarter to treat that as sort of a recurring net income figure. And don't get me wrong, I think that is part of your capital. I've long argued that that was the best source of balance sheet strength, but it did to me, and this is my opinion, it did seem a bit inconsistent with previous accounting standards and previous disclosure standards.</p>
          <p>Second question -- I'm sorry, on your effective tax rate, Silvio, what do you -- what do you expect? Obviously, how much more do you have in tax credits and what do you expect for your effective tax rate going forward with the potential increase in the social contribution rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We have a footnote with that disclosure, that is 2.2 billion reais. That's the total tax credit we didn't book yet. And let me tell you our principle. The government increased last year the social contribution from 9% to 15. The <mark type="inaudible" /> here in Brazil, under the banks in general, believe that this measure from the government is not fair with the other sect of the financial segment. This is discretionary approach, and we comply against that. And we believe that we win. That's the reason because we keep 34. That's the total income tax plus social contribution. And this means that you continue to report lower than 30% in the line of income tax rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but you've had basically what, 25, 26% in recent years? And I guess you can partially activate those tax credits to, you know, while the Court case gets resolved, to sort of shield your effective tax rate. But if you don't win, when would you utilize all of those tax credits?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we don't win, we will book ahead in using tax because of -- we have to book all the tax credits immediately. That's the accounting procedures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in that scenario, your effective tax rate would go up by six percentage points from about 32?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we are paying already. We are paying already because the <mark type="inaudible" /> is in the market already. You have to come to attend that, and we are paying that. But we are in the same moment booking the tax credit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah, but your effective tax rate in that scenario would go up, obviously by 6 percentage points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No doubt, no doubt, but we don't have the other measures to comply. Other point, we are consolidating Redecard now. Redecard has a high income tax rate. This changes the total consolidated figures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. What do you expect for the effective tax rate in 2000 and, you know, going forward in the rest of the year and for 2010? Do you think it's still 26%, 27%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It will be around 28 -- 26, 28.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Victor Galliano from HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, yeah, a couple of questions. First of all, if you could give us any kind of idea of guidance on loan growth for this year, and if you could maybe give us again something of a breakdown there in terms of consumer, corporate, and SME. And my other question is about personnel levels. We saw the personnel level come down 2.4% quarter-on-quarter, which meant, I think, 2,600 people left or whatever. Is this a natural attrition rate? Were there any layoffs included in that number? And can you tell us what you kind of expect going forward if this is a natural attrition rate? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was rather a long road. We expect that this year we will grow around 10, 15%. If you break down this level we can mention that in our market we expect that we will grow 25%. But remember that the base is small. Current levels will be around 10% to 12 in this level. And SME around 17%. The other segment is around 15%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of the expense, important information that we are not hiring anybody to date. The reality, we are adjusting the workforce in relation for the areas that need the personnel and the areas that have excess. And we are allocating people here, but normally like we mentioned sometimes, the normal turnover of the Bank is around 10,000 people. This will continue in the next quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>10,000 a year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. In the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In the merged entity, yeah?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Federico Rey from Raymond James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, gentlemen. I have an additional question regarding the loan growth. And if I understood correctly, you're expecting to increase in terms of loans in the range of 10 to 15% during 2009. And my question is if you expect that strong recovery during the second half of the year, what would be your expectation for the next year? My question is what should be the recovery in term of being strong or not strong, because if you consider increasing 15% year-over-year and we are considering no growth during the first half, you should be assuming that the recovery could be somewhat strong. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We expected that the economy will grow in the next quarter, more in the second semester. Remember that the economy is more heated in Brazil in the first quarter. This view reflect probably in the figures, in the loan figures. That's our impression. In 2010 it depends on the GDP growth. We expect that GDP will grow around 4%. Consider this GDP growth of 4% we expect that it gradually will grow around 20, 25.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes from Mr. Marcel Thieliant from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, gentlemen. I have a follow-up question on Jorge Kuri's comment on the net interest margin. Actually, two questions on that front. The first one, I noticed that you re-classified the FX gains that you had in the fourth quarter from financial margin with market to financial margin with customers. And since the FX rate was very stable, I mean, March compared to December, I think that -- the fact that you did not -- probably did not have the same amount of FX gains in the first quarter that would eventually explain the reduction in your margins, as you reported from 10.3 to 10%. So I want to understand what was the rationale for you not to consider the FX impact on your margin -- the financial market margin with the market, but with customers? And I want to know if you'd agree with the fact that if you exclude or if you re-classify, if you assume the same classification you had before on the FX gain, that your margins would actually have expanded in the first quarter versus the fourth quarter if you had kept the FX gains classified as financial market &#x2013; financial margin with the market? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our motto today is to operate with our operations, not to assume any position in currency. We are totally hedged. The calculation of this operation in terms of exchange gain or something like that, it's <mark type="inaudible" /> calculation. We decided to improve our model just to report this treasury operations that for us makes sense, because in reality we are operating with our position with our equity, the working capital of the bank invested in treasury position -- treasury bonds. It's for us &#x2013; this is a evolution of how do we report our models. For us, does not make sense to come back to show this because it was <mark type="inaudible" /> gain. It was <mark type="inaudible" /> calculation. For us the model that we report today represent more of the operations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Just one follow-up question on that. Of course it was original gain on your margin, but at the same time you had -- you compensated in your tax, right, because you needed to be over hedged because of the tax deductibility issue. But on the margin you did distort your margin before, is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it correct? I know we're reporting the same way that we report before. You can't see this adjustment in our margin. This quarter it was small because we don't have the movement in the currency. But we reported the same way when you consider the tax impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Our next question comes Mr. John Friedman from Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, gentlemen. I have actually two questions. The first one, within provisions for civil litigations and specifically regarding the provisions for economic plans, do you have the amount that is currently sitting in the balance sheet? In addition, how should we view those provisions going forward? Do you have an estimate of how much you still have provisions for economic plans and how long it should last? And my second question refers to potential client overlapping. Following the merger with Unibanco, I'd appreciate if you could give us some numbers on overlapping, first institutional clients, SME, private bank and credit cards? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This subject is in relation to provision for litigations, we consider only the situation that is best to the judges. That's our accounts procedure. This subject is very, very complicated because it relates in the past with the economic plan. The other thing we have is we have the assets against the cover. We didn't book the assets against the cover. It's a subject that we have to continue to discuss in Brazil. But we will continue to provision our expectations in the letter that we provided.</p>
          <p>In terms of the overlap of customers that we saw, when you compare the customer base of Ita&#xFA; and Unibanco, it's very small compared with our expectations and the expectation of the markets; very, very small. And in fact the customers we have 7%, SME companies around 8%, credit card around 6%. In wholesale we expect 100%, this happened in 100%, this happened in BankBoston. To operate in this segment, it means that we'll have to provide limits. If you have limits, and this bank has a very, very strong capital base, then you can have conditions to assume more risks. The reality, we have opened more limits to the wholesale customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me. Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's question-and-answer session. Mr. Setubal, at this time you may proceed with your closing statements, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your presence here with us in this first quarter conference call. We believe that the numbers that we released are very strong, especially in terms of provisioning for loan losses. Like we said, we expected these numbers to increase because of the situation of international economy and also here in Brazil. But we think that we are in a good place to face all this situation. Synergies will appear of the merge in the coming quarters as long as we go on in the integration. Thank you for your time and we expect your presence again for the second quarter conference call. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That does conclude our Itau Unibanco Holding Earnings conference call for today. Thank you very much for your participation and have all a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>