<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1131987" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-11-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3124</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Pedro Moreira Salles, Chief Executive Officer, Unibanco S.A.</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Alfredo Egydio Setubal, Executive Vice President and Investor Relations Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Geraldo Travaglia Filho, Vice President, Unibanco S.A.</participant>
      <participant id="4">Jason Mollin</participant>
      <participant id="5">Roberto Egydio Setubal</participant>
      <participant id="6">Pedro Moreira Salles</participant>
      <participant id="7">Paul Tucker</participant>
      <participant id="8">Daniel Abut</participant>
      <participant id="9">Juan Partida</participant>
      <participant id="10">Arthur Burns</participant>
      <participant id="11">Victor Galliano</participant>
      <participant id="12">Saul Martinez</participant>
      <participant id="13">Marcelo Telles</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Audio Conference Call of Ita&#xFA; Unibanco S.A. At this time, all lines are in a listen-only mode. Later, there will be a question-and-answer session. Instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. As a reminder, this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>Today with us, we have Mr. Pedro Moreira Salles, CEO of Unibanco-Uniao de Bancos Brasileiros S.A. and of Unibanco Holding S.A; and Mr. Roberto Egydio Setubal, CEO of Banco Ita&#xFA; Holdings Financeira S.A. Also with us are Mr. Geraldo Travaglia and Mr. Alfredo Setubal, Investor Relations Officers of both companies.</p>
          <p>I'd like to mention that a slide presentation is available on the company's Investor Relations website at www.itauir.com at www.ri.unibanco.com.br during this call.</p>
          <p>Future expectations related to this conference call shall consider the risks and uncertainties that involve any activities and transactions and that are beyond the control of the companies pertaining to both conglomerates, including but not limited to political and economic changes, volatility in the exchange and interest rates, technological changes, inflation, financials intermediation, competitive pressure over product and prices, changes in corporate and tax regulation, and also that the corporate restructuring described in this conference call is still subject to the approval of the shareholders meetings of the companies involved and also of the relevant authorities.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to turn the conference over to Mr. Pedro Moreira Salles and to Mr. Roberto Egydio Setubal. Please you may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. This is Pedro Moreira Salles. Thank you very much for coming to this conference call today where we would like to present to you the idea that shape this new company, which we believe will be the largest financial conglomerate in the Southern Hemisphere.</p>
          <p>We have organized this presentation in the following way: Both Mr. Geraldo Travaglia and Mr. Alfredo Setubal will do the presentation on the quarterly results of Unibanco and Ita&#xFA;. And then Mr. Alfredo Setubal will do the presentation on the Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Holding Company. And afterwards, both Roberto and I are at your disposal to answer your questions.</p>
          <p>So we will now start with Mr. Alfredo Setubal who will relate to you the results of Banco Ita&#xFA;'s third quarter results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon to all for you and good morning for those who are in the U.S. We are starting with the results of the Banco Ita&#xFA; Holding that we released today, the final numbers, thus remembering that we anticipated our numbers last week. So we had the approval of the Board of Ita&#xFA; yesterday and we released today the numbers.</p>
          <p>Just to remember, the net income of the third quarter, R$1.848 billion, shareholders' equity of R$31.591 billion. What means a recurrent ROE; annualize it by the average equity of 25.5. BIS ratio, 14.7; we released last week a BIS ratio of 14.9. So the final number is 14.7. Efficiency ratio 47% and non-performing loans ratios 4%, both in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Next slide, loans by type of customer; Ita&#xFA; finished in total loans with R$164.5 billion in credits. The main line in the quarter continues to be car finance, when we &#x2013; our growth was 9.4% in the quarter, finishing with R$39 billion in total, and small and medium-size companies, a 14.7% increase in the quarter, finishing with R$33 billion. Both are the lines that we have been growing more in the last quarters, so we continued in this third quarter in this trend.</p>
          <p>Slide number five, non-performing loans; we finished the quarter with 4% in total, down from 4.3. Both segments' individuals reduced from 6.6 to 6.3 and companies from 1.5 to 1.3. Our coverage ratio increased a little in the quarter and achieved 147%, considering R$100 million that we did of extraordinary provisions on both the regulation of the Central Bank.</p>
          <p>Slide number six, provision for losses and credit portfolio. The total provision in the quarter was R$2.52 billion, and we can see also the ratio of provision for loan losses and credit portfolio continue to reduce and achieve in the quarter 5.8% from 6.2 in the second quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Now I pass over to Geraldo Travaglia that will talk about the Unibanco's third quarter results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
          <p>Well, Unibanco on slide eight is showing a net income of R$704 million as released on October 24, and nine months of this year, we accumulated R$2.2 billion, which represents a 5.5 growth over third quarter 2007 or 16.8 over the nine months of 2007. Our annualized ROE for the third quarter is 23.9% and the accumulated annualized ROE for nine months of 2008 is 24.4, which is perhaps the same 24.5 that we had in the same period of 2007.</p>
          <p>On slide number nine, some highlights of our financial statements. Total assets of almost R$180 billion, loans portfolio reaching R$74 billion, other funding constituted by deposit plus debentures reaching R$73.3 billion, and earnings per share of R$0.25 a share. Our loan portfolio growth has been almost 33% in our 12 months periods and 7.7% on the quarter, reaching R$74.3 billion. The participation of retail was 59% and wholesale 41% which compares to 38% of June 2008, which reflects the appreciation of U.S. dollar currency over the Brazilian real. In the box on the bottom of the slide, you can see the figures of the Brazilian financial system for loans and credits and the only better performance for the same figures and the percent are quite the same.</p>
          <p>On slide number 11, we show some portfolios of our loan book that we mentioned auto loans that still have a very strong demand in the third quarter, reaching 10.2%, accumulating 65% growth in our 12 months periods. And the large corporate loans which showed an almost 15% growth in the quarter, which reflects the depreciation of the Brazilian real over the U.S. dollars.</p>
          <p>I think another figure that is important to mention is in the payroll loans portfolio, the reduction of the acquired portfolio, they were in running off this type of portfolio on September 2008, reaching almost an 11% drop, which means that we were at that time only growing this portfolio through our own sales force. At the end of the slide, we can see individuals growing 2.7 in the quarter, and the corporate loans growing 11.1 in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Slide number 12, which regards to asset quality. The D to H portfolio, which represents the six-day past due loans, reaching 103% of coverage of provisions, which is pretty much similar to June 2008 with 102%. The participation of D to H portfolio is 4.5, which is lower to 4.7 in June '08, and even lower of September '07 with 4.9, which reflects that the quality of the portfolio is increasing in Unibanco.</p>
          <p>The non-performing loans, the coverage is still 118% when compared with the exact figures of a year ago and the participation of non-performing loans over total loans is 3.9, 20 basis points lower than the same figures last year ago.</p>
          <p>Now I'll move on again to Alfredo which got to look over some topic from the transaction recent releases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Geraldo. So we are going to now to pass through the transaction to explain and to clarify the doubt that you may or you can possibly have.</p>
          <p>So with slide 14, three points that we're giving you some attention is the restructuring will cause the migration from the shareholders, current shareholders of Unibanco Holdings and Unibanco to the public listed company to be called Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Holdings, which is currently Banco Ita&#xFA; Holding Financeira, which will be made through a merger of shares.</p>
          <p>Another point that is very important to pay attention is that Unibanco Holdings will have ITA&#xDA;SA and the controlling shareholders of Unibanco Holdings, such control to be exerted by means of a non-financial institution to be incorporated for the purpose of this transaction. So the control of the new bank will be at 50% ITA&#xDA;SA and 50% from the controller shareholders of Unibanco Holding.</p>
          <p>We can see these better if you move on to slide 15. We can see the current structure of Ita&#xFA;. ITA&#xDA;SA is the holding company that has 45.5% of the total capital of Ita&#xFA; Holding. And the free float is 54.5. The current Unibanco's structure is that the controller shareholders of Unibanco at 32.9% of Unibanco Holdings, that has 58.3% of the total capital of Unibanco, and we can see that the free float of Unibanco Holdings is 67.1, and the free float of Unibanco is 41.7.</p>
          <p>So the new conglomerate will have a different position, ITA&#xDA;SA and Unibanco's controllers will create the IU Participation company that is a non-financial company that will held the control of the new bank, the Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Holding Company, as this IU Participation company will have 51% of the voting shares of the new bank. The IU Participation will have 50% of the voting shares controlled by ITA&#xDA;SA, and the controllers of Unibanco will have 50% of the IU Participation.</p>
          <p>So through this IU Participation company, the control of the new bank will be made. ITA&#xDA;SA will remain with 36% of the voting shares of the new bank. That means 18.3% of the total capital of the new bank in the hands of ITA&#xDA;SA. But the control will be made through the IU Participation, shared by ITA&#xDA;SA and the controllers of Unibanco.</p>
          <p>Moving on to page 16, we explain here the number of shares of Unibanco and Unibanco Holdings to be exchanged for each share of Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Holding. The common shares of Unibanco and Unibanco Holdings will be exchanged for both the controlling shareholders and minority shareholders in a relation of 1.1797 shares per shares of the new company. The units you have a little bit different ratio of 1.7391.</p>
          <p>For the preferred shares, the exchange rate was calculated based on the market average price of the units. That means R$7.5460 per unit and the preferred shares of Ita&#xFA;, 26.2468 in the last 45 sessions of the Brazilian Stock Exchange, the Bovespa. So the ratio for the exchange for the shares of Unibanco and Unibanco Holdings, 3.4782 for each shares to be exchanged to receive the shares of the new company. And Unibanco shares 0.17391. So that's the ratios that was released for the exchange; repeating that was 45 sessions &#x2013; the last 45 sessions in the Bovespa.</p>
          <p>On page 17, we can see that after all these transactions; the number of shares of Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Holdings will be increased by 1.120 billion shares, that's the total of shares to be issued by the company to attend the exchange ratio of shares of the shareholders of Unibanco's Group.</p>
          <p>On page 18, we can see a little of our new Corporate Governance. The Board of Directors will have 14 members and six of them will be appointed by the controlling shareholders of ITA&#xDA;SA and Unibanco Holding. The remaining eight will be Independent Directors. The new Chairman of this new company will be Mr. Pedro Moreira Salles and the Chief Executive Officer will be Roberto Egydio Setubal. No changes will happen in the operations and transactions conducted by clients, creditors, and suppliers.</p>
          <p>On slide 19, another relevant aspect of these transactions; the new company will be the largest financial conglomerate in the Southern Hemisphere. Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Holdings will be able to offer the best products and services in the Brazilian market for their millions of corporate and individual clients. The new company will have the largest stockholders' equity in Brazil.</p>
          <p>With this strong position, we'll be able to support the growth of the credit transactions of our clients. We'll have a substantial increase in economic scale gains in all client segments. And of course, we have substantial synergies in area of our business. With this position, we'll be able to expand our credit offerings, cooperate with the government and with other sister-like financial institutions, recognize the work and assure our financial system integrity.</p>
          <p>On slide number 20, we can see the final numbers of the new company considering the data numbers released on the 3rd of September. So the total assets will be R$475 billion; total loans, R$225.3 billion, deposits and debentures issued by the lead companies of both companies will achieve the total deposit and debentures, R$235 billion; assets under management, R$265 billion, and the stockholders' equity, we will achieve at the end 51.7 considering the tax impact. That means that with the new company, we will be among the 12th largest financial companies in the world and we will be the fourth largest company in Latin America.</p>
          <p>On slide 21, we will give you some numbers of the new institution. The total branches and customer side branches, we will achieve more than 4,800. That means 18% market share and the new company will have 14.5 million current account customers, also 18% of the market.</p>
          <p>In terms of credit volume, the new company will represent 19% of the Brazilian system. And in total deposits and assets under management, we will achieve 21%. In terms of insurance, we will hold 17% of the market, and in the case of pension plan, we will have 24%.</p>
          <p>Corporate operations, we will achieve 65 billion with more than 2,000 economic groups, meaning the largest companies in Brazil. Private bank business will be the largest in Latin America, with around R$90 billion in assets of the clients. Credit card position will be very strong, and the operations will include Itaucard, Unicard, Hipercard, and Redecard.</p>
          <p>On slide 22, we can estimate some numbers of the new company. If you take along Ita&#xFA; Holdings on the first part of the slide, we can see the EPS of Ita&#xFA; Holdings of R$2.82 per share. We can see that the new company, considering the profits and the new numbers of shares of the new company. So the total net income just consolidated the Ita&#xFA; and Unibanco, 8 billion and R$400 million.</p>
          <p>The number of stocks, 4.095 billion; that means an EPS of 2.79. So the new company reduced costs and gained synergies of R$142 million, what is very little number compared to the size of the new company. The EPS will return to the same level that Ita&#xFA; Holding has today. So you can see that the scale of the new company is very important and the EPS will probably increase with some synergy gains that probably will be higher than this R$142 million.</p>
          <p>On slide 23, we can see accounting effect that will impact the companies related to this transaction. We can see that considering the capital increase related to the merger of shares, the variation of its equity share and the accounting and tax effects, the positive net effect estimated in the result of Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Holding will be equivalent to R$7.9 billion, and the one of the ITA&#xDA;SA will be R$2.5 billion. The transaction, with all these numbers that I pointed, will be expected &#x2013; is expected to be accretive in 2009.</p>
          <p>The Basel ratio, pro forma of the operation, will be approximately 15.1, that is above the 12% &#x2013; 11% required by the Central Bank as a minimum here in Brazil. Then of course, all this transaction will depend on the approval of the authority, especially the Central Bank of Brazil.</p>
          <p>On page &#x2013; slide 24, you can see the rankings by market capitalization of the most important financial companies. In the world, we can see the new company in R$44.9 billion in the 16th position. In terms of Latin America is the largest company, the largest bank in the region.</p>
          <p>To finalize on slide 25, we can see a number that we released with the material fact that was published yesterday and to give you some more information, the total number of employees of the new company will be 108,000 employees, and the number of ATMs will be almost 30,000 to serve all these large base of clients.</p>
          <p>So now, that's the end of the presentation. And now, Mr. Pedro Moreira Salles and Mr. Roberto Setubal are opened for questions that you can ask. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question comes from Mr. Jason Mollin with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everyone. My question is related to the synergies of the transaction. We know from your prior statements that you are not giving out the exact estimates and it's too early for you to talk about specifics. But given Ita&#xFA; and Unibanco's experience in mergers, is there a minimal amount of combined cost synergies that we should expect? I mean is it just these? You've mentioned some areas that you could cut cost on the processing side or IT side. Is there a minimum number that you'd feel comfortable talking about?</p>
          <p>And secondly, in your presentation, you mentioned the R$7.9 billion positive impact on Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Holding as a result of this from goodwill and other tax implications. Can you explain how we get to this number? And lastly, if you can just comment on tag-along rights, that's something that Unibanco's preferred shareholders hadn't had and Ita&#xFA;'s did. So is that something that shareholders of Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Holding should expect to have going forward? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with &#x2013; it's Roberto. Let me start with the synergies. For sure, we believe that there will be synergies on the roads. We do not have the time to make any calculation on that. We have a strong belief that this will be the case in this transaction. Ita&#xFA; has a good tradition of good implementation on transactions like this one, integrating bank. And we believe that there will be a lot of synergies. We don't have numbers. We are not really enunciating numbers. I could say a number, but I'd rather not mention any number at this moment, because we believe that this will &#x2013; that we will have better calculations. Maybe in two or three weeks we might have some idea of what's possible and how the numbers can work in the future. But like I think the important point here that was mentioned in the presentation is that the transaction was done based on market prices. So it will be accretive next year and this is quite important for all the shareholders.</p>
          <p>And next question, what was that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jason, hi, this is Pedro.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think just to add to what Roberto is saying; again, I mean we mentioned this morning; we are not avoiding the question. But basically this entire transaction was discussed among the two of us. People were not involved. I mean our teams were only brought on Board on Sunday evening as we have said. So really we have a lot of confidence on what we can achieve. Both Ita&#xFA; and Unibanco had integrated a number of banks in the past. We understand what the issues are. This is obviously something of a different size, a different nature. But at the same time, it's a tremendous combination and I think we are going to grow out of this deal not really to look at it only as a cost-cutting exercise.</p>
          <p>As for the tag-along rights that you are asking, the new company is this Ita&#xFA; Unibanco; we have previously the Ita&#xFA; Holding Company. And as you know, they are tag-along rights in that company. And this is a new structure under which we &#x2013; the Unibanco shareholders are moving to. So this will be a new starting point under this new governance of this Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Holding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it clear?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great, that's very helpful. And I don't know if you can make any comments on the R$7.9 billion that I am just not sure how to get to that number that you stated in your presentation and released.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a lot of calculation we can look after Alfredo or Geraldo, and they would give you the numbers. But basically the transaction &#x2013; no, the transaction was done on market numbers. And you have a fiscal effect after the amortization of the goodwill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So is this an expected save like kind of you're going to have a tax shield from the goodwill amortization; is that the idea behind this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hold on a minute. Most of this difference we are talking here, difference comes from the difference between market price and book value, okay? So this is the business difference. There is some fiscal effects, but are minor but still we will be able to give you the numbers if you want.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much and congratulations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Paul Tucker with Egerton Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you very much and congratulations. My questions have all more or less been answered actually. I just maybe could ask one other thing, and I mean to what extent have you been able to approach this with your regulators? And maybe could you give us a sense of how you feel the regulatory environment is, particularly in light of what we've seen around the world with fairly strong encouragement of strengthening of banks within countries? Do you think that gives you maybe an easier passage than you might otherwise expect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Paul, this is Pedro. Basically we took this idea or this deal to the President of the Central Bank on Sunday morning in Brazil; both Roberto and I were there. I think he was very comfortable with the idea. The reaction was very, very positive. Obviously this is a show of confidence and our strength in the country and what we can give. In the afternoon, again both Roberto and I were with President, Lula, in S&#xE3;o Paulo. And I can relate to you that he was also very, very positive on the announcement. And I think he took it very favorably. And yesterday, there were announcement in the press from the Finance Minister, and those were also very positive. So we don't see any reason for the regulatory authorities not to approve this deal. And quite a contrary, I think it's very, very positive deal for the country, particularly at this moment. And we are I think very comfortable that this will pass without any problems.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Pedro. And maybe just one follow-up, could you just give us a sense of what your expected timeline here is for closure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is difficult to say anything, because it depends basically on the authorities. But our experience in the case of BanKBoston, for instance, which was the last transaction that we've made, it took four months and it was a foreign company. So it was probably more difficult because of our regulation. So I would expect to be &#x2013; three to four months would be a reasonable timetable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Daniel Abut with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and kind of a follow-up to the question that Paul asked. If this may take three to four months Roberto, then that means that the shareholder meetings will wait for that to be convened to approve it. So you need <mark type="inaudible" /> first or do you have a timing already for the two shareholder meetings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is the other way around, Daniel. This is Roberto, hello. We will have the shareholder's meeting before we apply to the Central Bank for the approvals. And yesterday, we had a Board meeting already, and we had the approval of our Board to take it to the shareholder's meeting already.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the shareholder meeting will take place likely this year and the approval from the Central Bank and the other authorities will probably not take place until next year, and the company as a consolidated combined company would probably not report combined result on deal sometime next year? Is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hold on a minute, Daniel. We don't have a specific date already, Daniel. But it probably would be in the end of November or beginning of December or something like that, okay? But &#x2013; so we expect to have all these ready to Central Bank approval as soon as possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>From the point of view of the combination, Roberto, have you given any thought when you go line-by-line or business-by-business in what area there may be duplication that will merit the need for some divestitures, when you look at what each of the two bud is bringing to the table?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just coming &#x2013; yeah, I will talk about that also, Daniel. But just coming back to the &#x2013; your prior question, one thing that is very important is that we don't have &#x2013; I mean our deal is already done, okay? It's concluded. We don't have fallbacks. It means that there is no anything like penalty for if one of the parties could go away of the deal. It's a done deal. This is quite important to make sure that everybody understands that.</p>
          <p>Regarding the business, first, I'd like to make it very clear that we don't have plans to close down branches. We believe that we have a great network now and we will keep it even if probably &#x2013; and we will have case where we have door-by-door probably branches. But in those cases, usually today in our case, it's very clear that we need more space in branches. So we don't have ways to accommodate a large amount of clients in our current network. So probably we will really need the branches of both banks in order to serve our clients, okay? This is very important.</p>
          <p>We have not had a chance to really to go business-by-business. We will do this in the next two to three weeks having presentations of both companies to me and to Pedro in all the business lines, so that we can understand what will be possible to do and what are the challenges we have ahead of us. But we are very positive that there will be synergies, there will be opportunities, and that there will be a lot of things to do. We are not considering any &#x2013; we are not considering divesting anything at this point. We believe that we have great subsidiaries, great business in our conglomerates that we intend to keep.</p>
          <p>Maybe Pedro wants to talk something about AIG, which might be of your interest as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Daniel. In the case of the insurance company, and so you know and this has been announced, I mean we have approached the company, actually approached the company before the Tuesday when there was a decision of the U.S. Treasury to bring resources into the company. We had made by then a proposal. This is being looked at. Obviously at the time, the exchange rate was very different from what it is now. And therefore, there needs to be some discussions concerning the valuation of the AIG part within this new context. But I am confident that we will be moving ahead. Obviously, again it depends also on the decision-making process that is now maybe a bit more complex than it was before early-September. But we believe that this is something that will be solved in the near term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our next question comes from Juan Partida with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. I have a question regarding the structure of IU Participa&#xE7;&#xF5;es, the new holding company, particularly, what pertains to the shareholders of the old Unibanco Controlling Group. If I do the calculation of the new shares based on the exchange ratio, I come to a share participation of around 11%. And yet the economic participation seems to be closer to 9%, around 8.7, 8.8%. Can you explain why that there is that difference? Is it because of the way this holding company is structured?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, first of all, as I mentioned, the shares are being exchanged based on the 45 days median price of both companies. And then the controlling shareholders received the shares, and the second step, we created IU Participation &#x2013; Participa&#xE7;&#xF5;es company. And in that company, we had a disagreement that the exchange rate for &#x2013; to exchange levels the shares in that level, but a different one coming because of the agreement among the two controlling groups of both banks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Juan, this is Pedro. Really in order to &#x2013; after the initial exchange is done, there is a negotiation among the new controlling shareholders and for us in order to move into that new company and to have the right to 50% &#x2013; to voting right to 50%, then we agreed on this dilution for the second part, and now we have a company that is exactly 50:50 among the two controlling shareholders. And that company itself has 61% of this new bank, which is Ita&#xFA; Unibanco, and where there will be tag-along rights in the future. So this is the reason that you'd find this difference among the first step and the number of shares that relate to the first step and then the second movement, which is this one and we get into the controlling company and get half the rights of that control.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very clear. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Juan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Arthur Burns with Deltec Asset Management.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Gentlemen, I hesitate to ask this question, but I am going to anyhow. There's been a lot of turmoil in the financial markets and in the whole world, and certainly in Brazil as well. Rumors of corporate problems with the currencies and maybe banking problems with loans to companies that might have those problems that we don't know about yet. You've been talking about this fusion for over a year. All of a sudden, it's a Monday morning announcement to the world. Can you both confirm that there are no issues on the balance sheets of either bank that are problems that we, as shareholders, don't know about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, this is Pedro Moreira Salles. I don't think it's a surprise Monday morning announcement. Any day that it should come it would be a surprise announcement, because it has been dealt with in obviously a very restricted environment, which means that only Roberto and I were talking about this. And this is why there was no leak whatsoever, which I think is quite unique given the size of the company, and the reason for that is that there were very, very few people involved and actually only involved when they were needed to be involved.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You are to be congratulated for that, by the way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. We are very proud of it actually. And the reason that we did this deal is irrespective of the environment. Now I know that there was a lot of turmoil. I think there has been a lot of noise within the system. And we know that there are two companies have got overexposed in this entire derivative issue. Basically that we know of there are two or three that may have gone too far and this is... it doesn't mean that they are 50 or 100 companies.</p>
          <p>Actually, the reason that we in the case of Unibanco pre-announced our results and actual Ita&#xFA; and then doing that two or three days later and other industrial companies also did that. It was basically to clear the issues and to flush out of the system any wrong information that was floating around. And we are, as you know, a very positive company. We are very confident of our numbers. And obviously neither Ita&#xFA; or Unibanco will do this deal if we didn't have a lot of comfort in each other's numbers. So yes, we can confirm to you as a shareholder that the numbers are what we have just announced. And I think this merger is a great, great story.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I appreciate that, sir. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to confirm, yes, from our side we are pretty much confident. There is no problem at all and we are very, very happy to have done this deal that Pedro was describing. We had a long discussion and you can see there is a lot of alignment in this conversation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Victor Galliano with HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi good afternoon. Just a couple of points here; I mean, when do you think we could realistically get a better picture in terms of what the synergy gains might be and what you might be doing in terms of any changes to branch network or potential divestitures. I know at this point that you don't look at any divestitures. But in that point specifically, is there any area in which your market share is maybe seen as potentially too high by the regulatory process, maybe for example on credit cards and someone like that, where clearly Unibanco is very strong, but also Ita&#xFA; is. And just one final question, which is about, I mean are there any potential issues with regard to systems or IT you think that with respect to the &#x2013; with respect to the merger or do you have pretty compatible systems in both banks?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The synergies as we have been talking, we don't have a clear idea of numbers that we can realistically talk about today. We believe that there will be a lot of synergies both on revenues and also on costs. And &#x2013; but we really don't have anything today to give you. Probably in three or four weeks, we might have &#x2013; we might start having some idea of what will be possible, but we know given the experience that we have in other situations that we will know the final number only a long way down the road when everything is really implemented and done and usually, this will take at least in this kind of transaction given the size of this one, statistically, I'd say that we only will have a clear idea in two or three years of all the synergies that have been made possible. But I think that the good news is that given the fact that the deal, the merger was done on market &#x2013; their own market prices, I mean the investors will be the shareholdings will be accretive starting next two years. So, this is very good news.</p>
          <p>Talking about the problems on technology, I don't think that there'll be anything in the future. We believe that we can deal with all the challenges that we have had in technology. It's something that both companies are very strong in and we can deal with the challenges that lies ahead. In terms of market share, we believe that the numbers that we have like around 20% are numbers quite reasonable for the authorities and we do not expect any problems coming from that side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Ms. Klausner Katsu with Oppenheimer Funds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Good afternoon and congratulations on the success on the operations. My question refers to your perspective on credit growth next year. The respective Directors of both companies speaking for each company had commented last week that credit growth was to be expected around 10% for next year. While this contrasts with your earlier commentary of the central scenario of credit growth in the order of 15 to 20% corresponding to your current GDP estimate of 3% growth.</p>
          <p>So, to clarify, is the 15% or 20% credit growth that you were referring earlier today expected for the combined company or were you referring this estimate to the financial system as a whole or put it another way, is the difference with the 10% estimate for each of the Ita&#xFA; and Unibanco companies that was talked about last week having to do with the combined company now? So, basically I am trying to understand what any changes to your central scenario for credit expansion might have happened due to the combined company or is it simply different with estimates referring to different things, sequential systems in contrast with the company since you represent the new companies &#x2013; those represent 20% of the &#x2013; almost 20% of the financial systems? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, the previous numbers that you mentioned &#x2013; numbers that were mentioned on an individual situation, in other words, we have worked on those numbers. Each one of the companies have talked about all those numbers. And you are right, those numbers are entirely different. But basically the idea is, we believe that market will depend a lot on the situation in the U.S. and the Europe. In a reasonable situation, I would expect that we would have &#x2013; the markets here will grow like something between 15 to 20% if &#x2013; this is quite important &#x2013; if U.S. situation goes okay and we have a reasonable year next year. If things get worse internationally. This growth might come down a lot, maybe 10% is a broad number. But again this will depend on a lot of the situation in the U.S., which I personally believe to be quite reasonable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, you are talking about your combined company now or the financial system, the macro number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Macro number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the 15, 20% you mentioned is the macro number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It depends on again just a lot on what will go on in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What kind of sheltering you think can we think of Brazil being a large domestic economy? And you're having those kinds of results and market share on &#x2013; with individuals in Brazil in growing market share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we have not &#x2013; I mean we have to make a more detailed analysis in each one of the markets. We don't have a clear answer for you at this moment. I'd like to really have been mentioning. This year was something that have been carry on with &#x2013; this was along and on this weekend, we have involved with all the people. So we don't have different analysis on numbers and things like that. But I think that we &#x2013; probably, we still have a lot of potential to grow on middle market. On insurance, we have go-to-market that will run the companies really on both &#x2013; in terms of market share. Those are very clear numbers that we are quite strong. We don't have a clear analysis on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's fine, thank you. Just to &#x2013; sorry to insist. So, for now you would maintain the individual company's assessment of 10% credit growth for next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Come again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, not the macro number, but the statement regarding the individual companies 10% &#x2013; about a 10% credit growth expected for Ita&#xFA; loan and Unibanco loan was being &#x2013; we were told last week. So for now, you would maintain that number of 10%, not the financial system, but the Ita&#xFA; Unibanco company as a whole for next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we would expect that &#x2013; I mean &#x2013; again, the number that was mentioned was between 10 and 15%. Unibanco mentioned that number and Ita&#xFA; mentioned something like 15 to 20, and giving the differences on perspective at that time on the situation and international situation. I mean those numbers have to be redefined; I would believe that we probably will follow the market next year, which I would say that 15% probably is a very reasonable number for next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Ian Smith with Natixis Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon and congratulations. I have three questions if that's all right. The first one is on whether you are aware of any significant contracts that might be impacted by the merger; for example, any change of control closes or contradicting exclusivity agreement whether there is any big contracts as it might get affected. The second question is just a follow up on the goodwill creation. And it's just an accounting question whether that's likely to need to be amortized. And also whether that's the creations of goodwill is what's effectively leading to that 15.1% combined capital adequacy ratio.</p>
          <p>And then just the final question, we saw today from Ita&#xFA;'s results that there is a huge growth in time deposits. I think particularly quite long aided time deposits sort over a year plus. I think time deposits grew about 75% Q-on-Q if I'm not mistaken. That would suggest that the company was creating a huge buffer of liquidity for the year ahead. Can you shed any light on the background and what your views are on system liquidity? And how that liquidity on the balance sheet is likely to be deployed going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And well, our numbers shows the increase &#x2013; you are right, the big increase in deposits, time deposits, but also shows some reduction or much lower growth on other types of products that we used to fund the bank. We are using in a much lower level the repos type of instruments at this moment, okay? But basically, we are not &#x2013; we have not done anything different from deposit terms of the overall funding process of the bank. Basically, we have a large cushion of liquidity as we always have had, which is enough to operate the bank. And there's no anything special at this moment. And basically, we are using different instruments giving some changes in regulation <mark type="inaudible" /> of the instruments we use. But there's nothing special on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Pedro. I mean as for the &#x2013; your initial question regarding any major joint venture or contract that could be affected, first of all, there is no change of control in that sense. There is no clause that would trigger &#x2013; there's no event to trigger such a clause. On top of that, as far as we know and have looked at this, there are no major contracts or joint venture that is impacted by the creation of this new holding company, of this new Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Holding.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. And by any chance, can you give me a view on the goodwill that's created whether those amortization on that? And whether that's what's leading to the capital adequacy ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you are right. All the transaction was done on based on the market prices, but there is a difference between market price and book value. The amortization of that creates a fiscal effect. And basically all this together makes the increase in the equity, which increases our BIS ratio as you mentioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And then is that likely to be amortized so that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Over a five-year period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we'll amortize that first.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, excuse me; we only have time for two more questions. Thank you. Our next question comes from Mr. Saul Martinez with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon everybody. I just wanted to follow &#x2013; I have a couple of questions. The first one is just a big picture question and more of a follow-up to Arthur Burn's question for Unibanco. And obviously, your stock has been trading at fairly depressed situation. I mean is there anything about the current market conditions that makes you feel like this was the right time to do the transaction? I know, Pedro, you said that you would do this irrespective of the environment &#x2013; that you think it made sense to do it irrespective of the environment. But is there anything about what's going on today that makes you &#x2013; that made you think this was the right time to pull the trigger, and do the deal?</p>
          <p>And just &#x2013; I guess secondly, can you talk a little bit more about the strategic side of the transaction? And more &#x2013; obviously, there is a lot of overlapping in a lot of your businesses. You guys are in a lot of the same businesses. But can you talk a little about sort of complementary nature of different pieces of your business, whether it be retail banking on the corporate side, the credit card? Can you just talk about how your operations may fit well or not fit so well together?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay Saul, how are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, when you look at the breadth of our shares, yes, they are depressed. They were depressed; they have been going up for the past two or three days. But I think this was the same for Ita&#xFA;, for Bradesco, for Bank of Brazil. If you compare the evolution of the share price, you do it for months, you do it from the beginning of the year, you do it six months, I don't think this will &#x2013; obviously, you can pick into the date. But I don't think there is a lot of fluctuation in terms of what happened percentage wise to all of the financial companies in Brazil.</p>
          <p>As a reflection of what happened above, obviously in the case of Unibanco, because we are more widely held abroad than in Brazil. And there is more float as long as there was deleveraging happening outside of Brazil. People were running for the door, and they were selling whatever shares that were more liquid. And in that sense, we may have paid a little bit more of the price. But then again when we did the deal that was the value at which the company was traded and there's not much we can do about it.</p>
          <p>If we had done the deal four or five months ago, I don't think there would be a significant difference in the actual share transaction that we are announcing. So once Roberto and I were ready and we had gone through all the points that separated us from the start. I mean when once we figured out that okay we were comfortable, then that was the moment to go ahead; and this happened to be now. Could be next week, could be two weeks ago. And it depends on the moment.</p>
          <p>When you talk about the strategic fit, I think it's a huge strategic fit. First of all &#x2013; because I think the cultures match. And I think this is probably the single most important issue when you are talking really about a merger and not about an acquisition. And the fact that we will both be discussing what we want from this company, and what we intend to do with it, and what are the people that we have and the talent that we have. And actually one of the interesting points I think from this transaction is the amount of talent that this company is going to have.</p>
          <p>And the surprising factor I think from a Brazilian point of view is that this is such an evolved industry in Brazil with so much talent. And there's real no multinational &#x2013; Brazilian financial multinational, and we intend to create one. And I think this was one of the drivers when we sat down and began the discussion 15 months ago. The fact that &#x2013; I mean we needed to be bigger, we needed to be more global. We needed to have a really the size in our local markets that would allow us to really to look beyond our borders. And I think now we are ready to do it. And I think this combination of the Ita&#xFA; and Unibanco is a very, very unique combination. And starting out of the number 15, number 16 somewhere around that number, will turn off the world ranking. And being a Brazilian company and controlled by Brazilians, I think is a great start. And I think it's very exciting what we can do ahead.</p>
          <p>And then when you look at the business lines per se, obviously there are overlaps; I mean any two large banks in one market have overlaps. We don't have the geographic differences that U.S. banks have. So we are both national scale Ita&#xFA; being larger, obviously <mark type="inaudible" /> But we don't think that there is a problem with having 4,000 branches or more than 4,000 branches. Actually we're saying that this is great that we are going to be close to 5,000 branches at this point.</p>
          <p>The credit card; we both run very good credit card operations; I think we will run an even better credit card operation going forward. We are very large in consumer finance, and from here we both will maybe start it earlier down this road. But Ita&#xFA; has done also a fair amount in that area. And again joining forces that could be are going to be a more relevant player.</p>
          <p>So going down all the lines, I think this adds up and where there is obviously &#x2013; obvious overlaps we will look at it. And then we will do what needs to be done. But I think this is much more a job done looking at expansion than really looking at cost cutting or synergies. I think it's really an  expansionary load even though the marketplace now imposes more restrictions for that and than it is or have been done, I don't know, 18 months ago. But I think it's great that it's being done now, because we are there made a little bit more prudence and that's always good when you are talking about banks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you for that. Just one quick follow-up into an earlier question; I think an earlier question asked about tried to get you to talk about numbers related to cost savings and you mentioned I think, if I'm not mistaken that you might have a better view of that in two to three weeks. Will you announce it to the market when you have a better view for those cost savings or what the synergies in general might be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't have a plan for that. But one just thing is that in few weeks we might have a better idea of what we have in hand. And I mean conference calls and places that we will be with analysts and investors in the future we might. As we have more clear idea, we will make it public in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fair enough. I understood. Thank you very much and good luck.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our last question comes from the line of Mr. Marcelo Telles with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi good afternoon gentlemen. I have two questions. The first one, in the contract of the transaction, is there any provision that prohibits any sort of counter bids in this transaction? And the second question is a follow-up on my question this morning regarding the acquisition by ITA&#xDA;SA of &#x2013; part of this stake of Unibanco controlling shareholders in Ita&#xFA;, the 90 billion shares. I just want to understand better what was the price paid and how this is going to be paid? I mean I know there's somewhat an impact at this ITA&#xDA;SA level. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer the first part of the question. I'm not sure I really understood the second part of the question. You asked if there was any clause in the agreement that would prevent us from an external bid. Well actually, we never thought of that, because basically the two banks have controlling shareholders. And both banks have agreed &#x2013; both controlling shareholders have agreed that this is the deal that they want to do, and has no bid that can come from east, south, north, or west that would change the decision that has been made. So this is really a merger, and this is what we're trying to go with. And actually I mean it's an interesting question that never crossed my mind. And I think &#x2013; I hope it never crossed Roberto's mind as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I confirm what Pedro has mentioned. It has to be a definite fuel bug. There's no way out, okay? It's a done deal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's question-and-answer session. I would like to invite Mr. Pedro Moreira Salles and Mr. Roberto Egydio Setubal to proceed with their closing statements. Please go ahead, sirs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for coming to this conference call today. I hope that you really got a clear view of what we intend to do going forward and what was the reasons for this merger. I just want to reiterate from an investor point of view, the excitement that we have that we were able to conclude this transaction, and how positive we are on the cost of this company going forward. So I hope we will be able to get in contact with you again in the next conference call, and really to show some of the powerful consequences we feel that we are announcing today.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Roberto. Thank you for all of you that have attended this conference call as well. And we are really very, very enthusiastic about it. We believe that there is a lot of room to grow, a lot of room to put things into view. We are very positive in the view, and this will be &#x2013; it is a really great company. And we will be able to take advantage of &#x2013; having this position; it will be able to take advantage of all the potential growth in Brazil.</p>
          <p>We have a large market. There is a lot of potential to be developed in the financial services. So we are very, very excited with the future of this company in Brazil, and also with the potential that we have to go internationally, to go to other markets in order to have all the perspective in terms of growth. Thank you all and see you next time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That does conclude the Unibanco-Uniao de Bancos Brasileiros S.A., Unibanco Holding S.A., and Banco Ita&#xFA; Holding Financeira S.A. audio conference for today. Thank you very much for your participation, have a good day. And thank you for using Chorus Call, Brazil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>