<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1454766" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>67493</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Director, Executive VP &amp; Head-Investor Relations">Alfredo Egydio Setubal</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Daniel Adrian Abut</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Officer">Caio Ibrahim David</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs do Brasil CTVM SA">Carlos Macedo</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Controllership Director">Rog&#xE9;rio Paulo Calder&#xF3;n Peres</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Saul Martinez</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Officer-Risk Control &amp; Finance">S&#xE9;rgio Ribeiro da Costa Werlang</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Corretora de Valores SA">Mario Pierry</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (Brasil) SA CTVM">Marcelo Telles</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="BTG Pactual CTVM SA">Marcelo Henriques</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Securities USA, Inc.">Victor Galliano</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Morningstar Research">Maclovio Pina</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. We inform you that this conference call is exclusively to discuss the earnings result of Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Holding regarding the second quarter of 2012. Queries related to Redecard's public offering should be addressed to the Investor Relations division of Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Holding. At this time, all lines are in a listen-only mode. Later, there will be a question-and-answer session and instructions to participate will be given at that time.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded and broadcast live on www.Ita&#xFA;-unibanco.com/ir. A slide presentation is also available on the site.</p>
          <p>Before proceeding, let me mention that forward-looking statements are being made under the Safe Harbor of the Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1996. Actual performance could differ materially from those anticipated in any forward-looking comments as a result of macroeconomic conditions, market risks and other factors.</p>
          <p>With us today in this conference call in S&#xE3;o Paulo are Alfredo Egydio Setubal, Executive Vice President and Investor Relations Officer; S&#xE9;rgio Ribeiro da Costa Werlang, Executive Vice President of Risk Control and Finance; Caio Ibrahim David, Chief Financial Officer; and Rog&#xE9;rio Calderon, Corporate Controller and Head of Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>First, Mr. Alfredo Setubal will comment on the second quarter of 2012 results. Afterwards, management will be available for a question-and-answer session. It is now my pleasure to turn the call over to Mr. Setubal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good morning for those in the U.S. and good afternoon for those who are in Europe. It's a pleasure for us to be here again to speak about our second quarter results for 2012. For those who are following through the Internet, we are starting on page two, on the slide number two, highlights. The first highlight is the results, the results &#x2013; recurrent results, recurrent income BRL3.6 billion in the second quarter with means ROE annualized of 19.4%. This means an increase of 8.1% when we compare to the second quarter of 2011. For the full year of 2012, the net income achieved BRL7.1 billion with ROE of 19.7%. This result means an increase of 2.5% when we compare to 2011.</p>
          <p>The second highlight is the loan portfolio that we are going to speak more deeply in the coming slides, but anyway we achieved BRL432 billion in credits here including endorsements, sureties and private securities that we held in treasury of large companies. This means growth including all these, a 3.6% growth when we compare to March 2012 and 15.2% when we compare to June 2011.</p>
          <p>The third highlight is related to our financial margins with clients. The financial margin with client achieved BRL12.3 billion in this quarter. The net interest margin with the clients decreased 30 basis points achieving 10.9%, especially because of the impact of the reduction of the SELIC rate that the central bank is doing in the last Copom meetings during the year since last August when they started to reduce the SELIC rate. The credit spreads remain almost flat with a small reduction of 10 basis points achieving 13.4% and when we look at the risk-adjusted credit spreads, the net spread also increased of 10 basis points achieving 7.5% in this quarter.</p>
          <p>The fourth highlight is related to our banking fees and results from the insurance, pension plans and capitalization business. These operations grew 0.6% in the second quarter when we compare to the first quarter of 2012, achieving BRL5.8 billion in the period.  When we compare to last year, we see an increase in these revenues and results from 11.5%.</p>
          <p>Fifth highlight is related to our non-performing loan ratio and loan losses. Our expenses, net of credit recovery, achieved BRL4.9 billion in the second quarter. The 90-day &#x2013; the total provisions created in this quarter achieved BRL6.0 billion. The 90-day NPL achieved 5.2% in the second quarter with a 10 basis points growth quarter-on-quarter and 70 basis points when we compare to June 2011, and we are going to talk more about this in the coming slides also.</p>
          <p>This sixth highlight is related to our non-interest expenses. The growth in the quarter 3.2% and when we compare 12 months, 5.8% in line what we expected that is a reduction in the pace of growth of expenses during the year.</p>
          <p>Seventh highlight is related to efficiency ratio. Efficiency ratio in this quarter increased 50 basis points. This ratio reached 44.8%, what means up to 280% increase compared to the first half of 2011. In the last 12 months, our efficiency ratio reached 45.9%, which means improvement of 330 basis points also in line or with the expectations that we have for this year. And the last highlight is related to our unrealized gains. We have BRL5.8 billion in unrealized gains and from this BRL1.5 billion is related from our available for sale portfolio of activities.</p>
          <p>Going to the slide number four, we have here our results. The total recurrent net income BRL3.6 billion; net income BRL3.3 billion. The difference is related essentially to the sale of our position, our stake on BPI in Portugal through La Caixa of Barcelona. More details here we can see the operating revenues of BRL20.2 billion, an increase of 1.8% in the quarter and 12.2% when we compare to June of last year.</p>
          <p>We can see here the financial margin with clients that we already talked during the highlights, a decrease in the quarter of 0.1% margin with the market, an increase of 18.4% in the quarter achieving BRL1.1 billion, and an increase of 28.3% in 12 months, here more related to our structural positions and also for a better quarter for the market especially for fixed income.</p>
          <p>We can see also banking fees of BRL5 billion, an increase of 1.5% in the quarter. Results from insurance BRL1.4 billion, an increase of 0.3%, and when we compare 12 months, almost 17%.  Good news came from loan losses and retained claims. Our expenses for loan losses was a little bit lower than in the first quarter. We had a decrease of 0.7% achieving almost BRL6 billion here, what was good because it was in the lower range of the bend that we provided at the end of the first quarter when we announced the expectations for losses for the second and third quarter. So here it was a better number, better for us was a good news also.</p>
          <p>Recovery, a little bit lower also and when we compare to last quarter, 5.6% lower in terms of recovery of credits.  Operating expenses, as I said, we continue to be very focused on controlling the non-interest expenses and the growth of this line when we see 12 months was 5.8% is a good number for this line.</p>
          <p>On slide number five, we can see here more visual some highlights. Operating revenues totaled of BRL40.2 billion, an increase of 12.2% year-over-year. Loan losses provisions expenses, the total for this first semester is BRL12 billion, an increase of 26.7% when we compare to the first quarter &#x2013; for the first semester of 2011. Non-interest expenses, 5.8%, as I mentioned, and recurring net income, BRL7.1 billion, an increase of 2.5% when we compare to the first semester of 2011.</p>
          <p>Page slide six, we can see here the net interest margin with declines, with decreases, as I mentioned, of 50 basis points achieving 11% when we compare 12 months and 30 basis points when we compare to the first quarter of 2012. Banking fees, a increase of 11.5% in the quarter including here the results from the insurance business and our ROE, 19.4% in the quarter, a little bit lower than the 20% of the first quarter of 2010 and 2012 and when we compare 12 months, 19.7% lower than almost 22% that we showed in the first semester of 2011.</p>
          <p>On page seven, we can see the financial margin. As I mentioned in the highlight, a small reduction of 10 basis points in the gross credit spread achieving 13.4%. When we see the dotted line when we can see the risk-adjusted NIM with these clients also a reduction achieving 6.6% of reduction so we continue to see a trend of some reduction here related to the reduction of the SELIC rate and also the spreads.</p>
          <p>On slide number eight, we see some other highlights related to our balance sheet. Assets we have a decrease in this quarter, a decrease of 0.9% especially related this decrease also the reduction of the portfolio of vehicles financing. So, we have this reduction and lower pace of credit growth in this period. Stockholders' equity only by capitalization of profits increased 4.3% achieving 75.6% (sic) [BRL75.6 million]. The loan portfolio here only not including the securities of large corp that we hold on our treasury book. So the number is BRL413 billion, an increase of 3.2% in this quarter compared to the first quarter. And funding, total deposits and AUMs with clients, BRL942 billion an increase of 1.8%.</p>
          <p>On page nine, we can see more details about our loan portfolio, when we see by the type of line and product that we have. So the total BRL413 billion, BRL147 billion is related to individuals.  We see that during this quarter, we had a decrease of 0.2% on the credit related to individuals, mainly because of the reduction that we are doing in our car financing business. During this quarter, we reduced the portfolio of car financing between 4.2% and also a reduction when we see the 12 months, almost 6%. So this is part of our strategy to reduce a little our exposure in the car finance in the local Brazilian market.</p>
          <p>But when we see the other line, the credit cards and personal loans, we see good growth when we compare to the first quarter and mortgage that continues to be strong, almost 8% growth in this quarter and 43% when we compare to last year. So individuals, the main issue here is related to car finance that we are going to give you more details in the coming slides.</p>
          <p>When we see the number related to companies, we can see that we show the growth of 4.3% here. We achieved BRL241 billion. Corporate increased 5.8% in the quarter and here we have an impact of the devaluation of the real against the dollar in our present portfolio denominated in dollar currency.</p>
          <p>When we see this very small, small and middle market, we continue to be selective here since the beginning of last year so we continue to have a small pace of growth when we see this portfolio so in 12 months the growth was only 6.3% and in the quarter 1.9%. We had some growth in the South American countries that we have corporate and retail operations. The growth of the credit portfolio was 14.8% in the quarter, here because we have more activity of corporate business in Chile and also because of the devaluation of the real related to the dollar.</p>
          <p>On slide number 10, we can see more details about our credit ratios. The credit ratio for the total portfolio increased by 10 basis points achieving 5.2%. We can see here a decrease in the NPL over 90 days for companies. We reduced this from 3.7% to 3.5% and we see an increase also in the portfolio of individuals that increased from 6.7% to 7.3%.  Here we have also impact of the increase of the delinquency in car vehicles at the same time that this portfolio is reducing. So we think that this reduction of the portfolio, of course, has an impact in the credit ratio for individuals, the total ratio for individuals in terms of credit.</p>
          <p>Here's a good news on this chart this side when we see 15 to 90-days NPL ratio we can see that both for individuals and for companies, these numbers are much better. What we can expect a lower NPL creation for the coming quarter this trend continues to in the coming quarter. The total balance of the provisions is BRL27.1 billion at the end of this first semester.</p>
          <p>On slide 11, we can see our delinquency for the vehicle car finance portfolio. We can see from long period of time of monthly granting of credit. We can see Ita&#xFA; Unibanco line in red and the market without Ita&#xFA; Unibanco in dark, in black. We can see that we had some periods at the beginning or at the end of 2010 and beginning of 2011 that our numbers were worst than the industry and this is what we are making provisions now in the last quarter, the first and the second quarter of 2012 more specifically but with the measures that we took at the beginning of last year, when we saw this trend, we have now a much better ratios when we compare to the market. So also this give us much confidence that we took the correct measures to avoid worst problems related to this credit portfolio and what we are seeing in this quarters and we will continue to see in the coming quarters is more related to the credits granted in the past when we see this, the credit granted to the end of last year, we can see a much better numbers and positions.</p>
          <p>On slide 12, we can see other numbers related to the measures that we took related to this vehicle portfolio, the reduction in the number of payments that we did. We have now 42 months in terms of payment. And also in the orange line, the average down payment that increased from 28% to 35%.  So as the value of the collateral is much better and now in this situation. We see in the charts below that we reduce very deeply the 60-month term of no down payment.</p>
          <p>And on the chart at the right side, we see what we expected in terms of trend because of this measures and because of these much better numbers that we have in terms of delinquency, what we expect in the coming two quarters for the second semesters in terms of the loan loss provisions for this credit line. So we can see a much better trend in terms of provisions for car financing.</p>
          <p>On slide 13, we can see all the funding and all the proprietary capital and subordinated debt and AUMs that we have. The total is BRL1.2 trillion.</p>
          <p>On page 14, no problems in terms of funding for the growth of the credit portfolio. We have room to continue to grow. Deposit is not an issue here in Brazil of funding the credit portfolio.</p>
          <p>Slide 15, banking fees and insurance results. 12-month growth for 11.5% in line with the numbers that we provided and here we can see also that we had the impact of the Orbitall that we sold so we don't have more revenues from Orbitall in terms of processing service that this company was provided.</p>
          <p>On slide 16, non-interest expenses. As I said, we continue to be very focused on these and we're very optimistic that we will continue to reduce the pace of the growth of these non-interest expenses. In 12 months, the growth was 5.8%; in the quarter, 3.2%. We continue to be very optimistic that we are going to reduce even more this.</p>
          <p>On slide 17, our managerial composition of net income. We can see in the second quarter that the commercial bank was responsible for 32% of our net income; Ita&#xFA; BBA, 17%; insurance, 14%; consumer credit, 8%; and our market activities and corporations is in our, I mean, the use of the excess of capital that we have, 29%.</p>
          <p>In terms of BIS ratio, we have 16.9%. We can see in this chart beside the composition of the reasons of the growth, where did this growth came and also we have the approval of the Central Bank today that of our Tier II ratio of BRL1.7 billion subordinate debt. So our number today is higher than this 17.2% because of this approval that was pending in the Central Bank.</p>
          <p>In terms of on slide 19, our market capitalization that decreased during last year, this year because of the financial crisis in Europe, in Brazil, in the U.S. so the bank's share suffered a lot in all these markets and our market capitalization also achieving BRL127 billion by the end of this semester.  And our shares continues to have more liquidity in the New York Stock Exchange. The total liquidity is BRL751 million. Per day was a good number.</p>
          <p>On slide 20, we have some news expectations for 2012 and the first conference call of the year when we release the results for 2011, we said that our expectation for credit growth was 14% to 17%. Now with the revision that we did and because of the measures that we took and are taking in our credit portfolio, we expected our credit portfolio to grow 10% this year especially because we are decreasing our credit portfolio in car financing from BRL60 billion by the end of 2011 to BRL50 billion to BRL52 billion in this segment. So this impact the growth of our total portfolio. If we don't consider vehicles, we expect a growth of 13% to 15% for the whole year of 2012. So we are reducing our expectations in terms of credit growth.</p>
          <p>In terms of NPL, at the beginning of the year, we expected Ita&#xFA; to be stable. In the conference call the first quarter, we changed to show the loan loss expenses and stable NPL and this also we reducing our expectations of loan loss provision expenses that will be created in the third and fourth quarter. So third quarter now we expected the loan loss provisions to be between BRL6 billion and BRL6.5 billion for the third quarter and BRL5.7 billion and BRL6.2 billion for the fourth quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>In terms of fees and result from insurance, we are keeping our 10% to 12% growth for the year. Non-interest expenses also we are reducing. We expect now the growth to expenses to be between 3.5% and 6.5% for the whole year and even with the difficulties to increase the revenues line especially because we are going to grow less than expected in terms of credit, but anyway, because of the good numbers in terms of expenses, we are maintaining our 200 to 300 basis points reduction improvement in the efficiency ratio.</p>
          <p>The final slide is related to our new JV that we announced with Banco BMG. We are creating a new bank where Ita&#xFA; Unibanco will keep 70% of the shares and Banco BMG that will continue to make its operations will have 30%. The total initial capital for this new venture is BRL1 billion. And with this new venture we will have 70% of the creation of payroll credit that Banco BMG will sell to this new venture. We expected this venture to achieve BRL12 billion in terms of payroll credits in two years.</p>
          <p>So this is in line with the strategy of changing a little the mix of credit of Ita&#xFA; Unibanco, especially related to the credit of individuals. We expected now this payroll business to grow and help us to reduce the dependency in car finance and credit card business are very good, will continue to be good, but of course is more risky and we want to reduce the risk of our credit portfolio in the coming years. So this BMG deal was in line with this strategy that we announced from quarters ago that we are going to go in this direction of changing the mix of our individuals credit portfolio.</p>
          <p>So this finished the first part of our conference call and now, we are all here open to answer your questions about this quarter and the trend for the coming quarter. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, ladies and gentlemen. We will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Ladies and gentlemen, please restrict your questions to two at a time. And our first question comes from Mr. Daniel Abut with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. A couple of questions, Alfredo, in the prior conference call, you did say that even though this year was going to be subpar in terms of earnings growth even with significant increase in provisions that you have seen particularly in the first half but to some extent into the second half as well, but you still expected some low-single-digit earnings growth for the year of the call and so far in the first half you are delivering that. You explained in page five that if we look at the recurring net income for the first half of the year it is showing 2.5% growth compared to the first half of 2011. Do you still feel comfortable that this kind of low-single-digit earnings growth for the year of the call remains a realistic assumption, particularly given the more encouraging trends that you're starting to see on the asset quality side?</p>
          <p>And the second question on the expense growth, given that you have lowered the guidance for expense growth this year and given the progress you are making on your efficiency improvement program, given that that program lasts at least through the end of last year, is this the level of cost growth that we should expect for next year as well or there's something more concentrated in this year in terms of your cost effort that will translate into a way your expense are going to behave next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Daniel. Yes, we expected some low single-digit growth for the year. That's the number, that's the expectation that we have, of course, due to the conditions, especially also because we have continued to have some growth, some good, some big numbers in terms of NPL and expenses creation for loan losses. Of course, we cannot expect big increase in terms of results.  But we still expect some growth for the results. We continue to work well in terms of expenses. We continue to see some growth in terms of credit portfolio. So one by the other we, our budgets and to see some growth in terms of result. But we have to see especially the trend related to our provision for loan loss. I think the biggest driver for this is this line of provisions that we will have, how much we will have to make in this second semester.</p>
          <p>But we don't see big changes in the scenario related to the economy. We expect the economy to be in a better shape by the end of the year and next year. So we don't see unemployment growing, so this scenario that we are seeing is a better scenario. Of course, we have some uncertainties coming especially from Europe. Of course, it is unpredictable what can happen in Europe and what if something bad happens there what will be the real impact in the Brazilian economy? But anyway, for what we can see, we are confident that the results will be in a good line and probably a small growth when we compare to last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can take the second one. Alfredo Egydio speaking, Daniel. You asked about the pace for expense growth next year if the pace we are posting now is sustainable for next year. We have a long-term view in terms of expenses growth. We drive the bank in order to keep expenses grow in line with inflation in order to have all the productivity benefits we have in order to fund the organic growth of the bank.</p>
          <p>So we do believe that we'll be able to keep the same pace of growth in terms of expenses for next year, and we do reaffirm that we have conditions to reach the expectation we have in terms of efficiency ratio. Of course, it's important to remember that the level of top line growth is an additional challenge here, but the bank is going to the right direction in terms of gaining efficiency. So we are going to be, if not at 41%, we are going to be pretty close to 41% as we had established before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This year 3.5% to 6.5% is not the outlier. That kind of a base you think not only next year but longer term you would like to keep as inflation is likely to fall somewhere in between that range and that you still feel comfortable getting close, if not hitting the 41% gross income ratio by the end of next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Daniel.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And now our next question comes from Mr. Carlos Macedo with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. Thank you for the opportunity to ask questions. I have a couple of questions that are a little bit of a follow-up to Daniel's question on efficiency. So I'll go first with the more difficult part of the equation, which is margins. Margins dropped again in the quarter. Of course, the base rates, the SELIC going down isn't impacting your margins.</p>
          <p>The question is, Rog&#xE9;rio, I think in the previous call you mentioned that you still expect margins to increase by something like 12% this year versus last year because of the hedges that you have against the lower rate, is that something &#x2013; is that expectation something that you still have, a 12% increase in net interest income in 2012? If not, given the results of the quarter, I think now year-to-date you're growing at 10%, should we expect that to improve going forward despite rates being lower?</p>
          <p>And the second question was, again, regarding expenses and particularly head count.  The head count dropped below 100,000 for the first time since the merger. Is there more cutting to be done? Will you lower head count further or will additional gains in efficiency from that perspective come from, for instance, shifting back office away from S&#xE3;o Paulo, which is a very expensive location or other things like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Carlos, we have reviewed the expectation for credit growth. We have now an estimate of credit growing around 10% when you include auto loans inside. It's 13% to 15% ex-auto loans, as you know. So we believe that the contraction terms of the spreads is still in a slow movement, but we do see some contraction in the origination particularly because of the mix, particularly because we are driving the bank to a lower risk type of credit and because of that we have an expectation that the top line should grow below 10%, slightly below 10%.</p>
          <p>Regarding your question on expenses, we had an important impact in the second quarter 2012 because of the selling of Orbitall. So a portion of the head count reduction is due to the selling of Orbitall, as well as the cumulative figure includes some reductions of owned partnerships, et cetera that reduced our head count. Looking forward, we do have some perspectives of keeping &#x2013; gaining efficiency taking into consideration the opportunities we have in terms of normal turnover of the bank.</p>
          <p>It's pretty important to highlight this point, particularly at this point of the year because what we are doing is actually capturing benefits out of the normal turnover of the bank. Every time we can keep doing the same level of business without replacing people, we take this advantage and we captured these benefits. We should keep doing this thing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just, you will take out in terms of attrition in order to not hire but just hire selectively, I guess, to replace. Are there other things that you can do, if you could give us some color, in order to achieve this very low inflation rate of pace of growth given that volumes will be growing faster than inflation? What is in the pipeline to be done so that we can at least have some comfort that you will be able to achieve this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So lots of initiatives. We all know the product's efficient. So we have lots of synergies capturing. We have a base effect remember that we have, as you mentioned, we have a lower head count now so we have some &#x2013; we have on one hand &#x2013; we have the new labor agreement to come but, on the other hand, we have a lower level of head count due to the normal attrition, as you mentioned. So we do have in our budget all the conditions to post inside the range we just supplied to you and we are pretty confident that we are going to do so.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Including next year, as you said, around inflation next year, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, long-term view is this the expenses growing in line with the expenses, so every inflation and every additional improvement or increasing in our activities should be funded by the games we have in efficiency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you, Rog&#xE9;rio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Carlos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And now our next question comes from Mr. Saul Martinez with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, guys. I have to say I'm a little bit surprised by the response to the cost question. My understanding was that the target was really to improve the efficiency ratio as opposed to targeting a certain number of &#x2013; a certain percentage cost, i.e., inflation. Has something changed, because it seems, if volumes pick up at some point and you do start to see a bit better top line, wouldn't it be more, wouldn't it be better to invest in your business and try to capture that growth even if cost growth is a little bit higher in environment where revenue growth starts to pick up and hence, you can invest in your business and still grow your cost base a little bit as long as it's grown below inflation, you get the operating leverage. But, it seems the target inflation in an environment or perhaps the economic environment improves and top line improves, I don't know, on the surface it seems to be a little bit shortsighted. Has something changed in terms of how you're thinking about the cost? I always thought it was 200 to 300 basis points, the improvement that you're targeting as opposed to a select percentage growth figure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, nothing changed, Saul. S&#xE9;rgio speaking. Sorry if I gave you a different perspective or a different conclusion out of what you just said. Our long-term perspective is, of course, taking into consideration the normal business, but our preference is, of course, as the investing is growing and of all what we have behind the targets of the bank remain on efficiency, not in cost-cutting, definitely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the inflation figure you gave assumes a certain growth in your top line in the coming years that's similar to what you're growing today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, actually it's expected that the country or the environment should improve and we expect that next year &#x2013; so next year we could be growing in a higher level and the measure I made in terms of inflation is sort of an overall perspective we have in long term but what we are going to do is taking all the opportunity to keep growing. Of course, it's not above here to keep or to prevent from growing because of the targets on cost. What is driving the bank is definitely efficiency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So fair enough. Follow-up question on your expectations for financial margins. I think you addressed it but your NIM from spread-sensitive transactions has been very resilient and we have seen a pretty sharp reduction in lending spreads according to Central Bank data. Can you talk a little bit more in detail about what your expectations are there? You mentioned you expect a little bit of a decline, but why &#x2013; and part of that's mix but why shouldn't we see a broader decline that really compresses your margin if new origination is being done at much lower spreads?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Saul, this is S&#xE9;rgio, I would comment a little bit on the Central Bank data then I'll pass on to Rog&#xE9;rio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The Central Bank has two measures of spreads. One is not very well known and it's published in the Financial Stability Report and it's quite comparable to our net interest margins and it has a much smoother behavior than the other one which is more, let's say, famous and is monthly relieved. The order spreads have been created this other measure, which as you mentioned has shown sharp reductions. It has been created in 1999.</p>
          <p>Now it turns out that the mix of products that the market now has is quite different from the mix of products which is considered under this, under this basis of the Central Bank. Let me give you two examples just to illustrate the point. By then in 1999, real estate loans for individuals were actually at the quite low level in the economy. So it was decided not to be included.</p>
          <p>Another portfolio which was not relaunched was some the MDS loans that are given through the financial sector and which became quite important and these two, they have very, very small spreads and which oscillate quite &#x2013; they have quite small oscillations. What I mean is the following with this introduction. You should not use the big number that is released monthly by the central bank in terms of fall spreads to imagine that this will have an immediate one-to-one impact on the balance sheets of the financial sector as a whole.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, no. That's helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to complement &#x2013; just complementing a little bit. S&#xE9;rgio has mentioned a lot in terms of the average of this spread particularly I just want to add if you look particularly on specific segments, auto loans, for instance, what we have is a reduction &#x2013; first of all, what you see in the data from Central Bank is origination. Remember that we are more selective so we are originating a lower level of risk in our portfolio and as a consequence, of course, the spreads are lower. It does not mean that the final contribution is going to be lower but it does mean that the net or the gross spread is lower at origination. It takes some more time because of the replacement of the portfolio, as you know.</p>
          <p>So the NIM we show in our statements of income is actually a consequence of our stock and not out of our origination, that is, it does reduces but reduces because of mix because of some specific things like in auto loans, again, the commissions to the car dealers has been reduced so at the end of the day, it does not impact the profitability of the bank but it represents a reduction on the spread for the final customer. I also want to remind you that we have made a very important shift in terms of the mix of our personal loans. We are now originating much more payroll discounted type of credit what drives this spread down but does not remove any profitability or much on the contrary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I guess if I look at the spread on credit transaction coming from 2012 and the end of the 2010 to like 11%, 10.9% now, is that the kind of compression that you see a gradual compression of about a percentage point a year will that be a reasonable assumption to kind of use for the rate of compression in your lending spreads?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It's a similar pace. Of course, when we have some acceleration in the credit origination it could accelerate a little bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we don't think is going to be a major change.  We do believe that it will take some years and this from our perspective will give us enough time to reduce the level of provisions we have in relation to the top line. Remember that at now, we have the worse picture because we are moving from higher risk to lower risk but still posting the consequence of the higher risk portfolio originated some time ago so with this time change, we could be benefiting out of this change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Got it. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from Mr. Mario Pierry with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, everybody. Let me ask you two questions. The first one on your NPL ratio, you did do a good job showing to us that the increasing NPLs in the individual segments was primarily related to the auto portfolio and primarily related to the slowdown in the loan book. But I was wondering if you can provide us any color on how your other portfolios are performing, in particular credit cards, and also how comfortable do you feel with the health of your corporate portfolio.  I know that you showed an improvement on your overall corporate portfolio but some of your peers are having some problems. So I was just wondering if you think that the problems that we're seeing the other banks is specific or do you think this could become a concern for the industry as a whole. And then I'll ask you my second question later.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Mario. Rog&#xE9;rio speaking. We have this NPL increasing over 90 days is a consequence of mainly two factors or almost everything coming from this one. We have some increase in the level contributed by personal loans because of the acceleration we did in the past. So this is a mix change and we do have this increase of auto loans, as you mentioned. I just remember that all of this movements are included in our expectation just released positively on our lower level of expenses for that in the coming quarters.</p>
          <p>When looking at the company, we have a decrease of 20 basis points in the portfolio of companies.  This decrease was observed in both lines as more companies and corporates both at the same level. I just, as you mentioned, the peer &#x2013; of course, I'm not going to comment on this but I just want to reaffirm that we look at the SME with a different perspective. We name SMEs here at Ita&#xFA; Unibanco companies with revenues limited to BRL150 million. What is different from some of the other competitors but in both cases we don't have any negative movement. Both are improving at the same level, 20 basis points.</p>
          <p>Two additional data are important to analyze it the future of this NPL particularly on individuals.  We see two very positive indicators, the early delinquency 15 to 90 days is actually in a lower level decelerating from the over 90. This is a consequence of the decisions we took before so more selective. Of course, we are originating better quality of credits and, as time goes on, we have a better performance of the delinquency in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>The other important indicator showing improvements is the NPL creation. So the level of NPL creation has reduced from first quarter to the second quarter and we do believe that this new level reached is the stable level. So we should see a more resilient level of NPL creation in the coming quarters at a lower level than what we showed in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's clear. My second question then is related to the negotiations, your annual negotiations with the labor union. I read here in the local press that the unions asking for a 10% increase in wages this year. Is this a type of increase that you have baked into your forecast when you gave your expense growth of 3.5% to 6.5%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mario, yes, this is all included in our expectation for efficiency ratio and expenses. We do have some expectation that are contemplated in our budget. Let's wait and see.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So but like I would imagine that normally the union asks for a big number and then you eventually are able to reduce this more in line with inflation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. You know our budgets we have a lower level than what they had initially asked for and normally, if you look at the history of all the negotiations, normally the first initiative from the union came in a higher level than the final agreements that we have at the end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from Mr. Marcelo Telles with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Hello, everyone. I have a question regarding your fee guidance. You basically maintain the same 10% to 12% guidance that has provided at the end of last year, but I remember when all these discussions about lower credit spreads started, one of the arguments is that banks and yourselves would be able to increase fees in order to compensate for lower credit spreads and you maintained this 10% to 12%. I want to know what is the reason for that and if you think that maybe next year we can expect some acceleration in fee growth.</p>
          <p>And then after that and then my second question would be still on the margins because looking, if you look at the agreement you guys had with BMG and so on, I believe that your mix it might change in a meaningful way right very high growth in mortgages, high growth in payroll lending and my assessment is that even if you look in terms of your credit spread after provisions, I would imagine that those segments would still be, would still have lower risk-adjusted spreads than other segments. Therefore, we should expect a decline in your margins aside from the impact of low rates, which is easier to predict but how do you respond to that and why are you so confident that the spreads or the margin after provisions will not go down?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Marcelo, we agree with your points on fees and that's exactly why we are not reducing an expectation in terms of fee income despite we have a lower contribution from the auto loans segment and also the selling of Orbitall that reduces our fees on this specific business. So despite we have those reductions since the first moment we launched the guidance on fee income, we are keeping what if you consider everything the same, it would imply actually an increasing expectation in fee income. We are keeping the same despite of these reductions in terms of growth.</p>
          <p>Remember that auto loans represents a very important contribution in terms of fee income and also the investment bank had a lower level of activities than what we had forecasted at the beginning when we launched the guidance. And I think if you add everything in a more negative or lower dynamics in terms of growth beginning from the growth of the Brazilian economy so all included. Just by keeping the fee income perspective, we think we have a positive re-approach of this perspective.</p>
          <p>In terms of margins, as you mentioned, we are moving, we are changing the mix of the portfolio towards lower risk and the margins, the gross margin, the gross or the margin before the bad debt should be impacted over time. It take some time, as I mentioned, in the prior question, but this trend is what we also believe it's going to happen. When looking at the margin after bad debt then it's different because the level of the debt that we have now is pretty high so it tends to reduce as a proportion of the margin so offsetting parts of this pressure. So we don't think that we are going to be pressure down. We don't share the view of this major compression in the margin after the debts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And now our next question comes from Mr. Marcelo Henriques with BTG Pactual.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, guys. I have two questions. One, I want to stretch a little bit the discussion on the NII and margins and trying to separate 2012 and 2013. Looking at your numbers at least from my perspective, when you look at your whole NII even if you include the market, it seems very reasonable to assume that you're going to have very difficulties in increasing this number in absolute terms until the end of the year. If you assume that, as you always said, that margins from the market should be between BRL800 million to BRL900 million and the fact that on the client side, the interest rates will be lower on average in the next two quarters if you compare to the second quarter 2012, and then continue to have a very low loan growth. So it seems unlikely that you can improve this number.</p>
          <p>So on 2012 specifically I'm just wondering how confident you are of reaching a number which is pretty much around 10%. And moving forward to 2013 and it's difficult to see but maybe you have a pickup in volumes as your growth is still very low. But on the margin side, that's my question on the margin side. I understand from your comments that it's very hard to compare the central bank data with the numbers that other banks report. But the reduction was very pronounced and even if you consider like half of what happened in the central bank, what should we expect from margin reduction in 2013 from a client perspective? Would a 40 bps, 50 bps decline would be something that should be reasonable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Marcelo, looking firstly to the coming quarters as you mentioned, we just released our expectation for the credit growth encompassing auto loans. It means that our final portfolio growth at the end of the year is going to reach around 10%.  We believe that the level of contraction that we've seen in the margins are going to be moving at the same pace in the coming quarters so we do believe that the NII growth should be lower than 10%, close to 10%.</p>
          <p>When mentioning our margins with the markets that includes the contribution from trading but it also includes the assets and liability managements of the bank, we believe that we are going to be posing the same perspective that you just mentioned and that we normally announce to the market so around BRL900 million every quarter. So we believe that at the end of the year we are going to be close to 10% but lower than 10% in terms of NII.</p>
          <p>When looking at the next periods 2013 onwards, we believe that we are going to have a contribution from the debt. So despite of this reduction in the margins, we do believe we are going to obtain the benefits of this change because mainly when you look at the data from Central Bank, what we have is the exchange of the mix. So we know that the spreads measured by Central Bank is actually now based on a type of portfolio that is not what we have majorly in our portfolio. It's not &#x2013; as a consequence, is mostly impacting the spreads and the losses on credit. So we believe that we are going to post better figures in terms of the amounts of losses on credit. This is pretty important when you forecast our expectation for margins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But would you agree that it is easier or, let's say, less difficult to keep your margins a little bit more resilient in a sense that you're not growing? You're actually decelerating your loan book and so we can move towards 2013 and if you want to reaccelerate, your margins should compress much further than what happened this year and not to mentioned that the interest rates on average in 2013 at least should be much lower than this year as well. At least, that's what the yield curve is saying. So I'm just wondering &#x2013; I know you're not providing guidance for 2013 but I mean should we expect a much larger compression of margin in 2013 than what you're seeing now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's important &#x2013; you made a good point. Volumes should increase. Remember that we are these movements on spreads moving the credit growth towards lower risk is actually what we have decided to do what we have announced a year ago so we are moving on that direction. We just announced this BTG agreement, the new bank on the payroll BMG agreements &#x2013; the new origination on this payroll-related loan. So this is all related to increasing the volumes of the bank.  So it's probably another good benefits on our margins as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And remember that SELIC is reducing this year but the SELIC expected for next year is different. Some guys in the markets are actually pointing SELIC up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And sorry, just one last question on loan loss provision. If I'm looking right when you report by segment and if I look at the numbers specifically on Ita&#xFA; BBA, your loan loss provision the expense is right increased from, increased almost three times quarter-over-quarter I mean from BRL79 million or BRL80 million, something like this to BRL230 million or BRL220 million and one of your competitors &#x2013; actually two of them is saying that this quarter specifically, they have to increase provisions on a large corporate side. So I'm just wondering if this is related as well because I know that only Ita&#xFA; be based specifically that's where you handed the large corporate. So I'm just wondering if this is related and if you see this continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Marcelo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is all contained in our expectation of the debt expense for the rest of the year, the movements you saw in the second quarter. 40% is related to ForEx impact and all the other movements are related to the mix of the portfolio and maturity, not special case, not specifically anything. The NPL actually improved 20 basis points for large corporate and this is all included in the bad debt expectation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Got it.  Thank you. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Now our next question comes from Mr. Victor Galliano with HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Yeah, just a couple of questions here. One on the NPLs, I'm looking in particular to the vehicle and what you put there on slide, on page 12 which is very interesting. So are you saying that that 2011 quarterly average of provision of BRL607 million, is that kind of a normalized level that you would expect to be kind of heading back to or is there any effect of contamination there, say, in Q3 or Q4 in that provision number? In other words, could this actually &#x2013; could a normalized provision for vehicle loan portfolio be lower than the BRL607 million? That's my first question.</p>
          <p>The second one is what do you disclose, what percentage of your total loan portfolio is fixed rate? And of this, what percentage would mature in the next 180 days? Those are my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm trying to take the figures here to address the second question. Regarding your first question, actually the propositional level of bad debt expenses back to this level we announced here is a good proxy but as the portfolio is now at a lower level, the nominal amount should be even lower than BRL600 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And also, currency is actually mentioned here. Also, there's a mix change in terms of the quality of the origination. So we are originating the credit now at a lower risk if you look at your left-hand side, you'll see the terms are shorter and the level of down payments are higher. So the quality of the portfolio is actually better so it should improve as well as a consequence of the mix.  Fixed rates, it's around 80% and I think maturity, a good guess with not a very refined calculation here is around two years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two years is the average and 80% of your portfolio is fixed rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>80, wow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So just remember that although fixed rate, it has a short duration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, it's actually some lines despite of this fixed rate base, they have a behavior that is similar to a floating rate behavior.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So really fixed rate &#x2013; would it be half of that? Would it be 40% do you think in terms of that would really have a sort of average maturity of two years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have this figure here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are going to study if we can...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And supply this information to the market in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Thank you, Rog&#xE9;rio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a good quality of information. Thank you for the suggestion. We are keeping note of this, Victor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Rog&#xE9;rio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from Mr. Mac Pina with Morningstar Equity Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, guys, and thank you very much for taking my call. But I have a question about your &#x2013; I really appreciate your information on vehicle loans. I was wondering if you can provide some more similar color on your mortgages, and in particular with the credit quality of your newest mortgages your latest vintages. And then, a follow-up on that also on your mortgages, what's the average rate of the new mortgages that you're bringing in the pipeline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The level of &#x2013; well, maybe, Mac, I could start by saying that the mortgage business in Brazil is a low, almost zero risk because the loan to fund the value of the collateral is actually pretty high. The average loan-to-value is around 65%, 70% so the value of the collateral is pretty high. The interest rate we paid is the lowest one in the country. The level of over 90 days is close to zero to give you a good figure on this.  And we keep originating at a very, very high level and we &#x2013; another good example is that we offer terms up to 20, 25 years. The average origination is around 15 years, much lower than what we offer and at the end of the day, we have around eight years in terms of down payment because we have lots of prepayments in this portfolio as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So just to recap you said loan-to-value at between 65% and 70%, right? And your NPLs of 90 plus are close to zero. Is that what I heard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Close to 65% and close to zero, as you mentioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, in NPLs. Okay. Okay. This is very useful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's also interesting to highlight to you, Mac, that we have a constant amortization scheme in Brazil. What gives benefit to the banks as well because their amortization keeps earlier than what normally you see in other parts of the world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, understood. That's very useful. Thank you very much, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's question-and-answer session. Mr. Setubal, at this time, you may proceed with your closing statements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We thank you all for participating with us at this conference call. We continue to be very comfortable with the direction and the production strategy that we have. Thank you and we're waiting for you for the next conference call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That does conclude our Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Holding Earnings Conference for today.  Thank you very much for your participation and you have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>