<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1208305" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-02-26</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3124</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Daniela Ueda, Financial Investor Relations Brazil</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Roberto Egydio Setubal, Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Saul Martinez</participant>
      <participant id="4">Roberto Egydio Setubal</participant>
      <participant id="5">Carlos Firetti</participant>
      <participant id="6">Marcel Thieliant</participant>
      <participant id="7">Daniel Abut</participant>
      <participant id="8">Mario Pierry</participant>
      <participant id="9">Victor Galliano</participant>
      <participant id="10">Pedro Moreira Salles</participant>
      <participant id="11">Geraldo Travaglia Filho</participant>
      <participant id="12">Mario Pierre</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. This is Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Banco M&#xFA;ltiplo Conference Call. At this time all lines are in a listen-only mode. Later there will be a question and answer session and instructions to participate will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. At this time I'd like to turn the conference over to Ms. Daniela Ueda of FIRB, Financial Investor Relations Brazil. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome to Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Banco M&#xFA;ltiplo Conference Call to discuss 2008 earnings results. I would like to remind you that this conference call is being broadcasted live on www.itauir.com. A slide presentation is also available on that site. Let me mention that forward-looking statements are being made under the Safe Harbor of the Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1996. Our performance could differ materially from those anticipated in any forward-looking comments at our results of macro-economic conditions, market risks and other factors. With us today in this conference call in Sao Paulo are Roberto Egydio Setubal, CEO; Alfredo Egydio Setubal, Investor Relations Officer; S&#xED;lvio de Carvalho, Chief Financial Officer; Candido Bracher, <mark type="inaudible" /> CEO; Geraldo Travaglia Filho, Executive Officer and Marco Antunes, Accounting Director. First Mr. Roberto Setubal will comment on the 2008 earnings. Afterwards management will be available for a question-and-answer session. It is now my pleasure to turn the call over to Mr. Roberto Setubal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning for all of you in the U.S. and good afternoon for all of you in Europe. It is a pleasure to be here with you to expose the numbers of Ita&#xFA;. I'd like to start with the highlights for the presentation in the page two for those of you who are in Internet. We had earnings of 2.3 billion recurring earnings, 2.3 billion reais for the quarter and 10.5 billion reais for the year. This represents an ROE of 24.8 for the year. We will explain further on this presentation, the difference between returns and net earnings. One thing that is very important is the provisions that we've made for this new more difficult scenario that we are facing in 2009 and 2010. We have built up a lot of provisions as a result of extraordinary gains that we had after the merger. We've booked 4.6 million reais of additional provision for credit losses. And we will talk more about that, but the idea is that we have a cycle provision, which we plan to use it in 2009 and 2010 as the scenario gets -- if the scenario gets much worse than it is at this moment. But the idea is that we will probably use some of these provisions in this year of 2009.</p>
          <p>Also we had a very strong BIS ratio. We have now above 16% towards increasing basis coming from the previous quarter. We also would like to highlight the unrealized income that we have. We have almost 11 billion reais of earnings not realized, and most of it is regarding our investment in credit cards.</p>
          <p>Our next slide we have the major and more important numbers of the year. If I could highlight that those numbers represent always the addition of Unibanco and Ita&#xFA; for 2007 and for the year of 2008. The numbers, the accounting numbers, of <mark type="inaudible" /> only November on. So we thought that these numbers, adding the two banks for the full year of 2008 and 2007 and the third quarter would represent better the situation of the company and the prospective and potential of this new institution.</p>
          <p>So I would like to show you those numbers, which are on page three. Very strong numbers, as you can see. Our market capitalization now is above US$40 billion. We have been among the top 10 banks in the world in terms of market capitalization as a result of this very strong balance sheet, which has improved even more after those new provisions that we have made in this new balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Our earnings, our ROE has been above 24% for the years of 2007 and 2008. And our efficiency ratio has been below 50%, which puts the company as the most efficient company in Brazil even before the synergies that we have seen, which we are looking forward.</p>
          <p>Total assets of this company has improved more than 20% in the year, more than 10% in the last quarter. Loans have been growing a lot, as you know, in Brazil. We ended the year with 272 billion reais on loans, 34% increase over 2007.</p>
          <p>Shareholders equity has been at the level $43 billion, which is a very strong number in terms of the balance sheet, giving us this BIS ratio of over 16% as I had mentioned before.</p>
          <p>Page four is an important page because we have the relation and explanation for the differences in the net income and the recurring net income.</p>
          <p>We have effects of the merger, which has been positive, especially the fiscal effects of five billion reais, which would be realized over the coming years. This we have made a lot of provisions for the qualification of accounting criteria for the merger expenses. And as I have mentioned before, we have made a big additional provision for loan losses. The number here is different from the previous page because here we are talking about after tax numbers, and there I was mentioning a number before taxes. We have goodwill amortization and other smaller effects for this total non-recurring effects for the quarter represents 468 million reais.</p>
          <p>I would like to remember to remind you that in this quarter we have what I would call the effects of this merger. And we have also goodwill that we have on AIG share of Unibanco's Insurance Company, which we have acquired for our insurance company. The Unibanco insurance companies are fully owned subsidiaries today. We have also acquired 4% of Ita&#xFA; BBA, which was on the hands of <mark type="inaudible" /> Ita&#xFA; BBA. And we have also acquired 70% of the Ita&#xFA; Europa, which was ordered by, held by Ita&#xFA;.</p>
          <p>So all these amortized in this quarter together with the merger effects that we have been explaining. So we have a very clean balance sheet in terms of goodwills looking forward.</p>
          <p>Next page is a pro forma P&amp;L for the quarter, previous quarter, year and previous year of the bank. I would like to mention to you that this bank altogether for the year 2008 had 56.8 billion reais in terms of revenues. By revenues, I am talking about net interest margin plus fees plus insurance revenues. So all this together brings the company above 57 billion reais of income. We have non-interest expenses of 24 billion reais, additional provisions -- here, we are talking about recurrent earnings, so we don't have the additional effect of the 4.3 provision that I mentioned before. So for the company the loan loss provisions, we have 9.7 billion reais, and net income of 10.7 billion reais, which compares to the full year of 2007, by adding Ita&#xFA; and Unibanco, we have an increase of 8% comparing the two years.</p>
          <p>Going ahead for the next slide, we can see the evolution of the loan portfolio, which has increased more on the corporate side and small business, which has increased almost 42% combined, compared to 24% on individual. So this year was a year that we had the increase in <mark type="inaudible" /> and corporate as well, especially in the case of corporate in the last quarter. So for the full year, we had a 34% increase in the loan portfolio, combined, again two companies combined.</p>
          <p>Going forward, we can see the level of non-performing loans and the coverage ratios. The NPL has increased from 4.6 to 4.8, showing the first signs of credit deterioration in the market, which we expect to worsen during this year. Coverage ratio has improved a lot given the, as you know, the provisions that we have made. These are provisions, so we could view that have a very strong provision for the new scenarios that we are facing for 2009 and probably 2010 year. On page eight you can see that our provisions have been increasing. This is regular provisions not including the additional extraordinary provisions that I mentioned at the beginning of this presentation. So this 5.1 provision for the current portfolio does not include the 4.6 billion. <mark type="inaudible" /> higher than eight billion, 8%. The level is 3% almost.</p>
          <p>On slide nine we show you our exposure in the derivatives, <mark type="inaudible" /> derivatives that we had for our balance sheet, when we showed the numbers in October and now we can see that we have a very positive evolution with huge reductions in the exposure of those derivatives. Funding conditions and other types of funds have been improving a lot as you can see on page 10. Basically the bank deposits have been very strong. Have had a very strong growth this year and supports the credit portfolio evolution.</p>
          <p>On page 11 you can see that the bank is well funded by its clients. We do not depend on the market lending. Our position is a very strong one in terms of liquidity <mark type="inaudible" /> in terms of growth on our credit portfolio. Fees revenues have had a quite stable year. We have a different involvement than the one we had the year before. So in terms of asset management we've lost some revenue, because we've lost volume given the evolution that I mentioned, bank deposits and money came out of our money market funds and went to time deposits. Loan operations, we have some changes in the market regulations as we had also account bonuses, which have linked the evolutions on fees for that year.</p>
          <p>In terms of other revenues that we can see here, most of these revenues were related to investment bank and securities, which as we all know, have had a much weaker year when we compare to 2007. But in our expenses, we had an evolution of 12.5% for the year, more concentrated in the last quarter, and this is because we had, as you know, we have an annual negotiation with the union and this was majorly -- in the last quarter, the effect of this negotiation was majorly in the last quarter of the year and this has decreased our personnel expenses in a special way.</p>
          <p>Other expenses also had a big increase. Some of them, given the formality of the expenses like marketing expenses, for instance, they usually they have the higher level of marketing expenses, is on the last quarter. And also we had some influence of the merger, we had a lot of expenses, some expenses at least related to marketing and communications of the merger, which in terms of high volume and things like that have also affected the last quarter. So this explains most of the expenses, the expense increases we have had in the last quarter.</p>
          <p>On the page 14, we can see that even considering this evolution, our efficiency ratio has been improving over the last 12 months. As we mentioned, we had a similarity in this last quarter, in the fourth quarter, and this is pretty much natural for when you analyze the figures in terms of efficiencies. So all together the evolution of the last 12 months have been improving. Finally, I'd like to comment with you the results that we've had since 2008 when we compare Ita&#xFA; Banco with the guidance that we mentioned to you at the end of that year, at the end of 2007.</p>
          <p>So on the page 16 you can see that we have <mark type="inaudible" /> have increased less than we expected. Basically this was due to the fact that the last quarter was much weaker than the previous quarter and this explains why we did not reach the 30% target that we had before. Moving down to business portfolio, we outgrew by far the target that we had for us. We have record 69% growth in 2007. The fees, we are below the target and I had already explained why this happened. Efficiency ratio was pretty much in the target and delinquency ratio was pretty much in the target for us.</p>
          <p>In the case of Unibanco as you can see on page 18, the situation was very similar. Basically the explanations for the shortfall are <mark type="inaudible" /> and pretty much hitting the targets other than those things as we did not. So this is what I had for you, so we are open for questions now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we will now begin the question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question comes from Mr. Saul Martinez with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon gentleman. I have two questions. First on synergies from the transaction. Obviously, you guys feel it's too early to provide any sort of specific guidance on synergies. But in general when should we start to see some of the operating efficiency gains from the merger start to show up in the results? Is that something that should occur in the second half of the year or is that something that we start to see in the results in 2010? Second question is on your expectations for loan loss provisioning levels next year. Obviously, you gave a pretty cautious view in terms of the direction that --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Mr. Martinez, could you please repeat your question please? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. This is Carlos [Bradesco Corretora] but I think Saul Martinez was asking a question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think he lost his connection so we go ahead and we --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. My first question probably has something to do with Saul's question with provisioning and delinquency levels. Given that Ita&#xFA; Unibanco now has such a high level of excess provisions, we know that historically neither Ita&#xFA; nor Unibanco has used these excess provisions to brace from asset quality issues. I was wondering if this year we might see some reversals and Ita&#xFA; Unibanco being more active in the way they manage these excess provisions? And the second question has to do with the fourth quarter. I saw very significant trading gains at Unibanco, significantly above the average for the past few quarters or even years, whereas Ita&#xFA; was a little bit lower. I was wondering if you could give me just the background behind these trading gains given it was such a tough quarter otherwise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, in terms of provisions we do intend to use provisions in this year. We believe that we will have pressures from delinquencies that will be much above the normal levels. And the provisions were made especially for this kind of situation. So we probably will use as we feel that the delinquency level is above the normal levels, we will use some of this provision that we have made, these additional provisions that we have made at the end of the year. We don't have exact number for that, but the idea is that as delinquency level is much above the normal levels, assuming something is normal like last year or something like that, we will use this provision. For this is a <mark type="inaudible" /> provision, which means that will be different from other situations, we really will use this as the scenario asks us for more provision.</p>
          <p>In terms of trading gains in last quarter, I don't have a clear view on that. I am not sure if anybody here in the table has a clear view. I think the results in the bank was really above the target and maybe in the case of Ita&#xFA;, in my mind, it was pretty much in line with other quarters, probably above the average of last year, last quarter. So those are my comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Marcel Thieliant, Banco Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, hello, everyone. My question is regarding your, the expectation of your restructuring charges. I understand from the result that you had a provision about 900 million reais. My question is, if you look back a little more in terms of restructuring expenses to take place throughout the year and how you have been meaning to report those expenses? Do you see them going through this statement or if you would be able to create like a separate amount of provisions in the future related to the integration of Ita&#xFA; and Unibanco? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, this provision is made according to the regulation and it does not account for the full expenses of the integration. It is leaves it to what the regulation allows as provisions ahead of the expenses. We believe that this, we will have provisions that are basically not provisional. We will have expenses that are not provisional during the process of integration, in addition to the regular level. I believe that although we will have provisions, we also will start to see some synergy gains along the process. I can't say how much, what will be the balance of those two different forces, but I think that among the process, which probably will take two to three years, we will end up with lower levels overall expenses than we had last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Daniel Abut with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Roberto. If I look at your loan portfolio now that you reported a combined entity, and I see that in bank loans where Ita&#xFA; stand alone used to have over 20% of the entire portfolio in that category, now by virtue of the growth of it, <mark type="inaudible" /> that this segment did not grow the last quarter, is represented about 17, 17.5%. Is there a level at which you would like to lower that number, given the more challenging environment in order to feel more comfortable about your exposure going forward? Are you consciously trying to reduce that side? What should we expect, that Veco Financial will eventually represent of the whole portfolio with Ita&#xFA;?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would expect in this scenario that loan portfolio, the <mark type="inaudible" /> portfolio will reduce the share of our loan portfolio. This is clearly due to the lower demand of loans for <mark type="inaudible" /> loans at this moment, and so we believe that the loan portfolio will probably reduce it better in our overall portfolio, the Veco portfolio will reduce the presence in our overall portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But how much will it descend?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure, Daniel. Look, this year is a difficult year to forecast growth given the economic environment and also given the merger we have not really fully  <mark type="inaudible" />, we don't have all the numbers on the hand. We believe that the loan portfolio will go something between 10 and 15% and depending on how the economy goes. Probably corporate loans will be one of the major demands that we will have especially given the fact that corporations in Brazil use it to fund themselves out of the, tend to fund themselves inside the market. Also the middle market will keep on growing, we believe that. For vehicles, we do not believe the volume had a very, very weak year. So overall we're losing some share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Roberto. And if I could complement with a second question. Given that you said that although you're not using a specific target for synergies you would expect that by the end of the process in two to three years the combined entity should end up with an expense rate lower than the combined as of 2008. Did I understand that correctly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's what we expect. But you have, I mean, it clearly will depend on also on the overall growth of the economy as we do not expect today. We have in the future a much stronger growth in the next two to three years, it might change a little bit, but at the end what we do really expect is that we will have a much more efficiency ratio in two, three years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Roberto.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Mario Pierry with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. I have I guess two questions. The first one has to do with what you just said about the efficiency ratio should be better. If you could provide us with any guidance, what kind of levels do you expect your efficiency ratio to get to? Also when you guys first presented the merger of Ita&#xFA; and Unibanco you had at the time talked about not having any branch closures. I wanted to know if that is still the case and when should we expect to see the Ita&#xFA; Unibanco branches are fully consolidated or integrated? The other question that I have is related to asset quality. You clearly mentioned that you expect asset quality to deteriorate. Also wondering if you could provide some more color, what areas concern you the most? Is it automobiles, is it credit cards, is it SMEs? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Mario. In terms of efficiency ratio, I think, we don't have a clear number today. But look, Ita&#xFA;, a loan in the past has reached the level of 45%. So I believe this is something that in the future we should be there at least 45% and it should be a number that in the future we have to get back to this level of efficiency ratio.</p>
          <p>In terms of branches, we declared that we don't plan to close down branches. This is still in our minds. We believe that we have a strong brand to attract clients, to pool all the branches that we have, and this volume is something that we will start. The merger itself of the branches will start in the second half of this year and probably will take at least till the end of next year to be completed.</p>
          <p>Your last question was on the credit portfolio. We believe that we have &#x2013; overall the deterioration will take place in all the business lines. This includes consumer, this includes big companies and also this includes middle market companies. Probably we will see first consumers deteriorating, but we believe that the deterioration will be very across the board, especially because this is something that's doubling up because we have really this management in our portfolio, but it's coming basically because of economic deterioration, which will take place in the economy overall. So this will be a more difficult scenario both for consumers, but also for companies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Victor Galliano with HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Yes. A couple of things, I mean most of my questions have been answered, but one I wanted to get a bit more of a feel for. I mean, especially in view of the fact that you've got all these excess provisions, can you give us at least some kind of guidance in terms of a range of what you expect the provisioning levels to be as a percentage of average loans in 2009? That's my first question.</p>
          <p>The second one is on ROE. Industry wide we're seeing the ROEs coming down. Even if you look on a recurring basis, your ROE combined was 21%. Again, can you give us some sort of guidance or a range for what you can anticipate for 2009? And the last question is about tax rate. What sort of effective tax rate should we be assuming for 2009 for the combined entity? That's it. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We don't have a clear number for provisions for the end of 2009. In our mind what we have today, given especially the uncertainties we have for 2009. We have these excess provisions that we believe will be necessary to be used along the year, given the fact that we expect that provision needs for 2009 will be above the 2008 to use some of the provisions. So probably what we will see at the end of the year is a lower level of provision compared to the portfolio, a number that we have shown right now.</p>
          <p>In terms of ROE, we'll give you at this kind of environment above 10% ROE. It's a great number and we think it's a challenge to keep at this level, and at least at this level -- at this kind of environment that we're have facing today. Maybe in the future if the crisis gets better in terms of &#x2013; if the economic situation gets better we can come back to higher levels of ROE. But at this kind of environment we think that this is a good number. In terms of tax rate, I don't have &#x2013; I'm not sure if -- Pedro, please comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think 25 is a figure that we are working on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. Thank you. That includes social contribution or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Okay. Just one last question which is a technical one really. Will you continue to report during 2009 with the level of disclosure that you've given us in the year-end '08 numbers? In other words, Ita&#xFA;'s Unibanco and then the pro forma? Or will this change into just Ita&#xFA; Unibanco pro forma once you merge the shares at the end of the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We won't be able, at least in the year of 2009, to give you the same level of disclosure, because we don't have ways to do this at this moment in Unibanco to combine with the numbers on Ita&#xFA;. But as the situation goes on, we will tend to come back to a more -- a higher level of disclosure. I'm not sure if we'll get there to get back to the same levels of disclosure that we used to have, especially given the fact that our peers or competitors don't use the same levels of disclosure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Understood. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Saul Martinez with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Can you guys hear me this time? Hello? Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You could hear me. Okay. Great. A couple of questions. First of all, a lot of questions on operating efficiency gains and cost energies. I want to follow up with that in terms of timing. When &#x2013; you guys mentioned that 2010 should be lower than '08 and you guys gave some guidance for efficiency ratios, but when should we start to see operating efficiency gains start to show up in the results and in the improvements in the efficiency ratios? Is this something that should start to show up in the second half of the year, or is this more of a 2010-like event?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, more of a question on how you're positioned versus interest rate declines. I think in the past, lower interest rates have generally been &#x2013; generally been more asset sensitive and lower rates have hit your net interest margins, but your balance sheet structure has changed a lot in the last few years with more fixed-rate assets, longer duration assets, more wholesale funding. Lower rates, generally, is that a good thing or a bad thing in terms of your profitability?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. First synergies. I think that synergies might take place this year, it will be minor, and it will happen probably along the second semester of this year. But it will be minor. And I'm not sure if it will be  something that we can read on the numbers, especially given the fact that at the same time we have, as we start using synergies, we will also have additional expenses for the integration. In 2010, yes, we can probably see some of the impact of the synergies and probably the full level synergies will be something more to 2012. In 2011 probably something like maybe 80% of the impact will be in place in 2011. And full impact in 2012. This will be a reasonable number.</p>
          <p>In terms of interest rates impact on the balance sheet, in one hand the lower rates are good, given that it tends to improve the credit condition. In other words when we have lower rates we have a lower level then we can produce, would be a good impact of the lower interest rates. On the other hand some of the lower cost liabilities will not perform in terms of revenues and in terms of the higher level of the <mark type="inaudible" />, so it's a mixed impact. I tend to believe that probably the overall impact, probably will be more to negative on the long term, not necessarily in the short term because you have gradual gains, you have a lot of <mark type="inaudible" /> gains.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just a quick follow up on one of Victor's question, clarification more. Did I understand you when you said that next year, because you're going to use some of your excess reserves, that your credit provisioning level to average loans will be lower than it currently is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Come again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Did I, just a clarification. I thought in your answer to Victor Galliano's question about guidance for credit provision to average loans, that you mentioned that it's going to be lower by year-end next year than it currently is. Is that accurate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What was mentioned was the level of provision on the balance sheet compared to the quarter following will be lower due to the fact that we expect to use some of the excess provisions during the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. What about through the income statement? Thinking about fourth quarter your provisions were about 1.5%, is that a reasonable run rate you think?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we position, the provisions on the P&amp;L also will be higher, not much higher as we plan to use some of the excess provisions to offset the delinquency ratio that we want.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Sibiti Clarey with Raymond James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I had two questions, the first one has been already answered, but I would like if you can clarify, you have just said that further reductions in the selling rate could negatively impact net interest margins in the mid term but have maybe a neutral impact in the short term. My question there is, if you can clarify this is after or before credit loss charges? And the second question if you can give us more color on potential acquisition targets in the region? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I <mark type="inaudible" /> your first question. The idea that I tried to convey is that when interest rates fall you have gains in securities that you hold, you will have gains in treasury overall. So this -- it's a positive impact in the short term. In the long term you lose some revenues coming from lower cost liabilities, but this also is offset by the fact that lower rates gives you a lower level of provisions in terms of delinquency. So overall it's a difficult balance to evaluate. In terms of our international growth, we have, as we have mentioned before, we have declared that we plan in the future to be more international and that we see Latin America as a natural way for Ita&#xFA; Unibanco to go ahead and become an international player. So right now our first priority is integration, and our second priority is also integration. So we are fully concentrated in integration.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Jonathan Prigoff with Equinox Partners .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I just have a &#x2013; I have a question that's motivated by the actual, the audited financials. And so if you look there at the expenses on financial operations, there's a money market line, which increased significantly from &#x2013; on a without Unibanco basis, it looks like it's about three times as big as it was in 2007 and 2008. And that means that if you look at it on a cost of fund basis, your cost of funds actually doubled. So I'm wondering if that's just an accounting thing that I'm not understanding properly, or if there is an actual material change in your cost of funds? And if there was a change, was that motivated by the mix moving to time deposits, or market conditions, or a little bit of both?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I don't have the numbers you have mentioned, but the rationale, my intuitive answer, if I may, it is that the cost of funds has moved into a different mix clearly. We have increased the amount of <mark type="inaudible" />, this probably has changed the way you have described it. But I don't have to give you the numbers you have mentioned to make sure that my answer represents what is the reality. Maybe you can check this afterwards with <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just in general, do you guys have any numbers that you referred? I know normally you talked about the financial margin. Do you have an idea of how much your cost of funds increased? Maybe not on an accounting basis, but just on whatever way you guys think about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm passing on to Filho.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we are forecasting at this moment like we mentioned, when you look, the credit regulation to our source of funding, you see that we have high liquidity, which means that in this moment we are proxy, lower interest rates to GAAP report, which means that during this year probably we'll keep the net interest margin of the operations flat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Ms. Lola Wisner with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Just one question, for the upcoming dividend that you have on or around March 17, I believe. I'm just wondering what is the breakdown between the different Ita&#xFA; and Unibanco share classes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Would you please repeat the question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sure. For the upcoming dividend that you have around mid March, I'm wondering what is the breakdown, like the ratio, between the different Ita&#xFA; and Unibanco share classes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, looking forward, we don't have any differences in the shares, we're the same since November, we have same dividend for Ita&#xFA; and Unibanco shares. Geraldo will make some comments on that. Geraldo is CFO of Unibanco.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. You only have to convert stocks from Unibanco to Ita&#xFA; by the swap ratio that has been released and after this on March 31, the stocks will be all one, the same ticker and the same dividend. The dividends are already provisioned for stockholders of Unibanco will be paid now, in March, we are only waiting the approval of Central Bank. Now if it's everything approved then we will pay it <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Yen Smith with Naska Capital. Mr. Smith, your line is open. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we can hear you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Sorry about that. I have two questions. The first one is on the balance sheet progression during the quarter. It was quite different at Ita&#xFA; versus Unibanco. We saw large sort of asset growth and time deposit growth at Ita&#xFA; and much higher loan growth. While at Unibanco those numbers were much lower. Can you give us an idea of where those differences came from? And whether going forward those differences are going to be more aligned? And then just second question is just clearing up a few queries. The equalization of accounting criteria, I think it's net 1.4 billion reais in the quarter. Can you give us an idea of what that number is? And my sense is that, that probably relates to Unibanco putting through extra loan loss provisions to align themselves with Ita&#xFA;. Is that the case? And then just secondly, second point to clear up, it looks like the shareholders equity level reduced in the quarter. If you just look at the pro rata balance sheet, I think from about 44.5 billion reais to 43.5 billion reais, while we saw positive net income. Can you give us some idea of what that change relates to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. In terms of growth I think we have to look forward if Ita&#xFA; and Unibanco will be one company and I don't think that the growth that we had last quarter is continuing through looking forward for the future. So we believe that the strength in the <mark type="inaudible" /> especially as we have integration going forward <mark type="inaudible" /> will be basically the same so we don't have to concentrate on those differences. In terms of provisions for accounting, we have constant criteria, equalization of our constant criteria. We basically did &#x2013; we used the most conservative criteria, if it came from Unibanco or if it came from Ita&#xFA;. In both cases we have criteria that came from one or the other. So this basically was what was done.</p>
          <p>Well your final question was about why the equity position reduced from the third to the fourth quarter. The merger had a lot of effects, monetary effects. And in addition to the merger effects we had effects coming from dividends, we had effects coming from the amortization of EAG acquisition and other acquisitions that we've made in the quarter. So those basically are the exponential issues that may pay on piece look for seasons we can give you a little more on the stay of them, but basically affect, the company effect coming from those operations then, the dividend that we declared in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Mario Pierre with Deutsche Bank .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me ask you a question with regards to the equity stake the Bank of America has on Ita&#xFA;. As we know the lock-up period is set to expire this year. Bank of America, like other banks in the U.S., is having some financial troubles. Have you had any discussion with managements of Bank of America if they plan on selling their stake? And if they do plan on selling their stake, when will they, they will have the right of first refusal, will Ita&#xFA; then be willing to buy the stake from Bank of America? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Up to this point, Bank of America has not shown any intention of selling their stake on Ita&#xFA;. We have talked to them and they have mentioned that they are not planning to do it. So this is what we have for now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Victor Galliano with HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, a couple of follow-up questions here. One on personnel, I noticed in the quarter if you look at Ita&#xFA;, the employee number came down. You actually seemed to reduce your personnel levels by over 1,000 people in the quarter. In Unibanco it seemed like it increased by about 600, but generally speaking would it be fair to say, and I know that you're not planning to cut branches, et cetera &#x2013; but would it be fair to say that you will be looking to take advantage of those employees who retire, or perhaps retire early, and not replacing them going forward, thereby reducing the personnel levels in that way? That's the first question. The second question, coming back to the excess provisions &#x2013; so I'm just wanting, I want to clarify here &#x2013; are all excess provisions currently included in the capital calculation in the BIS calculation? So if you're going to be drawing down on those, would that effectively reduce your capital position?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Regarding the levels of provisions, I mean the leveling. Let me start with the personnel question. We -- since the merger took place, we have decided not to hire new employees. We basically are not replacing those who are leaving the company, and this was implemented basically in December. We had some, still some people, it was in the backlines hiding profits, but no one &#x2013; since January, we are not replacing those who are leaving the company. So the trend, overall, is that we have people that, overall number of employees reducing among the year. Talking about the excess provisions, it has been part of the capital calculation. And given the new regulation of Central Bank, it represents more or less 1% of the total BIS ratio. So if we do not account for the excess provisions in the calculation, we would have continued growth 15%, which is still a very strong number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes today's question and answer session. Mr. Setubal, at this time, you may proceed with your closing statements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you all for being with us today. It was for us a very special moment to announce the numbers of Ita&#xFA; Unibanco. We are very positive about the future of the company. We believe that this is an extraordinary company that has been combined from one institution from another one. We believe that it's an extraordinary moment for us especially given the very difficult year that lies ahead of us. And probably we are one of the very, very few companies in the world that today has a very positive agenda for the year. And we believe that this, will take place, this transition will take place in a very soft way and I'm very optimistic about the future of this company which will be very, very good. Thank you all for being with us and I hope to be with you again in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The Ita&#xFA; Unibanco Banco M&#xFA;ltiplo 2008 Earnings Conference call is over for today. Thank you very much for your participation and have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>