<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1522756" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-12-12</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7864</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Pablo Isla &#xC1;lvarez de Tejera</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Ignacio Fern&#xE1;ndez</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Capital Markets Director">Marcos L&#xF3;pez Garc&#xED;a</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch International (United Kingdom)">Richard B. Chamberlain</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Andrew W. Hughes</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">Ben L. Spruntulis</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Redburn Partners LLP">Geoff J. Lowery</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd.">Jamie Susan Merriman</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA (Broker)">Anne M. Critchlow</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Geoff F. Ruddell</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Banco Santander SA (London Branch)">Rebecca A. McClellan</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Fraser Ramzan</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Simon W. Irwin</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Warwick R. Okines</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Nmas1 Equities Sociedad de Valores SAU">Francisco Riquel</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the Inditex Conference Call for Interim Nine Months 2012 Results. The presentation will be chaired by Mr. Pablo Isla, Inditex Chairman and CEO. This presentation will be followed by a Q&amp;A session comprising two parts. The first part will be dedicated to the questions received on the telephone and the second part to the questions received through the webcast platform.</p>
          <p>Mr. Isla, please you have the floor. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning to all the participants in this webcast conference call regarding Inditex results for the interim nine months 2012. I am Pablo Isla and here with me today are Ignacio Fern&#xE1;ndez, our CFO; and Marcos L&#xF3;pez, Capital Markets Director.</p>
          <p>The results for the interim nine months 2012 showed that Inditex continues its ongoing global multi-concept growth and a strong execution of the business model. Sales in the interim nine months of 2012 have increased 17%. Our operations have also shown high efficiency and tight operating control over the period. As a result, EBIT has grown 30%. Let me also tell you that in terms of expansion, our store opening plan and online sales rollout for the year is on track. We have opened stores in 54 markets over the nine months of 2012, demonstrating the global reach of Inditex's business model. We have also launched online operations in selected new markets in the period. We continue to see significant growth opportunities for Inditex globally.</p>
          <p>I will now hand over to Ignacio, who will provide some of the detail behind the headline numbers, and I will join you later for the outlook section.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. In the interim nine months of 2012, all <mark type="ph" /> different lines (2:10) from the profit and loss account show significant growth as a result of the operating performance. Inditex has achieved net sales of &#x20AC;11.4 billion, EBITDA of &#x20AC;2.8 billion and net income of &#x20AC;1.7 billion, 27% higher. Gross profit has increased 19% to &#x20AC;6.9 billion. Gross margin on sales has reached 60.5%. Operating expenses are tightly under control. Operating expenses in the interim nine months of 2012 have increased 15%, mainly due to the growth in the space and the variable cost linked to the strong sales performance. Operating expenses include all the startup cost for new openings. Operating working capital remains negative as a consequence of the business model. The working capital evolution is in line with the <mark type="ph" /> tradition (3:17) of fiscal year-end 2011. Inditex continues to show a strong financial condition.</p>
          <p>I will now hand you over to Marcos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of specialization, we are on track. We have opened 360 net stores in the interim nine months 2012 to reach a total of 5,887. Continuing with our global expansion, we have opened stores in 54 different markets over the period. Regarding the performance in the interim nine months 2012, the concepts have continued increasing the sales significantly. The differences reflect mainly the comparable base over the previous years.</p>
          <p>I'm now handing over to Pablo for the outlook section.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>We continue to identify significant opportunities globally. We are expanding our business in a number of markets with attractive long-term returns through our multi-concept and multi-channel strategy. Following on with the online sales rollout, Zara will launch online sales in Canada in spring, summer 2013. We plan to roll out online sales in other selected markets in the near future until we establish a global presence. Inditex is now present in five continents and in all the key markets, showing our global reach. We manage a diversified sales platform in 86 markets. The current base offers huge growth potential for the coming years.</p>
          <p>The store opening program for 2012 is on track. Ordinary capital expenditure will be around &#x20AC;1 billion. Regarding the outlook for the second half of 2012, I would like to add that store sales in local currencies from the 1st of August to the 9th of December have grown 15%.</p>
          <p>Before closing, I would like to cover a number of initiatives carried out by Inditex concepts and some store openings of recent months. Zara has established an online presence in China in September with a very warm reception. Bershka has launched stores in Germany and South Korea, two very attractive markets for its fashion proposition. Massimo Dutti has commenced operations in the United States with the opening of flagship stores at Fifth Avenue, New York and Georgetown in Washington, DC. Pull &amp; Bear has started operations in Austria with the flagship store in Vienna. Stradivarius has launched emblematic stores in Mexico as part of its global rollout. Milan's flagship stores at Corso Vittorio Emanuele and Via Torino now carry Oysho's latest image. Zara Home continues its global expansion with its recent Southern Hemisphere launch in Brazil. Flagship stores have been opened in S&#xE3;o Paulo and Rio de Janeiro. Uterq&#xFC;e was launched in China with very relevant stores at Beijing's The Place and Hong Kong's IFC.</p>
          <p>Last week, Inditex opened its store number 6,000 at Oxford Street in London. Zara's 2,500-square meter flagship at Park House showcases the latest store image. Zara's new flagship store at Champs-&#xC9;lys&#xE9;es will open in the coming days. Zara has opened its largest store in Germany at Munich's most emblematic fashion destination, Neuhauser Strasse. We have opened a very relevant store in Taipei's Q Square. This is our 5th store in Taiwan. We have also opened a flagship store at Busan. This is our 55th store in South Korea. We also continue to grow in Australia with highly prominent stores like Zara Chadstone in Melbourne. We are increasing our presence in South Africa. Zara has opened at Waterfront, the key destination in Cape Town. We have opened our 39th Zara store in Brazil at Avenida Daniel Touche in S&#xE3;o Paulo.</p>
          <p>And finally, regarding our corporate calendar, the full year result for 2012 will be released on the 13th of March, 2013. And this is all from us. We will be pleased now to answer any questions you may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the telephone Q&amp;A session starts now. We remind you that online questions will follow. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Richard Chamberlain from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Good morning, everybody.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning; a question from me please on operating expenses. It came in a little bit higher than I expected, but then so did the sales. So, I guess there's a bit of a relationship there. But I just wondered if you could maybe quantify, talk about the amount of start-up costs that you mentioned that were incurred for new openings in the quarter compared to last year. Why did you decide to mention that? And what was the amount, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, what I would like to tell you is that, as you perfectly know, that the main driver of operating expenses growth is space growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we were saying during the presentation, it also has to do with the evolution of like-for-like sales, because there is a significant part of our costs which are variable and then we also have currency impact, as we have when we talk about sales. It's very similar to the currency impact that we have on sales. Having said that, you know that we always prefer to analyze operating expenses at least on a six months' period, because in any particular quarter there could be different factors; but the main driver is space growth, as it has always been the case. Perhaps, Marcos, about the quarters you would like to add something?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, regarding the evolution over the quarter, you know that we prefer to look at the season six months. But in this particular quarter, there is a technical issue which is the comparable. If you remember, operating expenses grew just 7% in the third quarter 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so it's mainly...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And you have to clarify...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, it's mainly a comparable issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your question because when we talk about, in the presentations, about the operating expenses, this mention about the start-up costs is something that we always say. So, we always say that the operating expenses include all the start-up costs for new openings. So, nothing relevant from that point of view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. I mean I was going to say, it looks like your number of store openings for the first nine months is actually broadly in line with last year. So, I guess it doesn't look like the start-up costs are materially higher than last year. But I guess, linked to that, I mean should we expect store numbers for the full year then to come in at the lower end of your target range or more in the middle?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we can &#x2013; we prefer always to talk about the space growth than the store numbers. And space growth will be totally in line with the 8% to 10% space growth forecast. So, nothing really relevant regarding this topic. I would only like to mention that perhaps, when you see the number of openings, you must have in mind, we mentioned that in the six months' results presentation that there have been several Zara Kids stand-alone stores that have been absorbed into neighboring Zara stores.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So &#x2013; and this is around 15 stores. So, this is something that you must have in mind. But globally is everything very much in line with what we anticipated at the beginning of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we request you that you kindly limit yourself to only one question per turn. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from Andrew Hughes from UBS. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, everybody. It's Andrew Hughes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Just in terms of gross margin, in the past you've guided to a band of down 50% to up 50%. I mean, are we at the point in the year where you think you will do better than the upper end of the range?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you know that we are always very reluctant to talk about the gross margin during the year. We prefer &#x2013; because we don't see ourselves talking about the small basis points, up or down, thinking about the gross margin. Well, what we can say at this stage of the year is that this guidance about the stable gross margin for the full year, now what we could say is stable gross margin for the second half, having in mind what has happened in the first &#x2013; in the third quarter. But having said that, as you know, we prefer not to elaborate very much of what could be the evolution of the gross margin in the &#x2013; in every quarters &#x2013; every quarterly results presentation. But what we would say is a stable gross margin for the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'm sorry, if I could just add one more question on China. You mentioned a warm reception there. Could you elaborate a little bit on what you mean by warm?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well yes, I can elaborate but not in terms of figures, because you know that when we talk about online, we are very focused on the execution. For us online, as we always say, is very relevant from two different point of view. It has to do with the evolution of online sales, but it also has to do with the multi-channel approach. We think it's very relevant that people visiting our web page, seeing the product and then buying in the stores, then everything which has to do with in-store deliveries, in-store returns. So this multi-channel approach, we think, is very strong. And when we were talking about warm reception, we were thinking about the number of orders but we were also thinking about the number of visits, the comments from the people. So this &#x2013; but we prefer not to be more precise about figures. It's too early. It's just a few months and we prefer to continue focused on customer service, execution, showing our image, our product in the best possible way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What would be the big differences with the launch in the U.S. &#x2013; so between China and the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's very difficult to precise what could be the big differences. What I would tell you is that online is much more developed in the U.S. than in China, online sales today. The potential is there of course, but it's much more developed in the U.S. than in China. But in terms of the behavior of our customers, no significant differences.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Ben Spruntulis from Exane. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thanks very much. I've got a question on margins. Consensus is forecasting Inditex will deliver an EBIT margin of around 20% this year. If you achieve further operating leverage in the future, would you be happy to see EBIT margins rise above 20%, or should we expect any additional margin to be reinvested back into the business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you know that this is not the way we analyze our business. I think the evolution of our margins has a lot to do with the very strong like-for-like sales growth that is taking place this year. So, we are not so focused, let us say this way, on the particular evolution of the margins at any given year. It's mainly related with the evolution of like-for-like sales growth because of course, when we have so strong like-for-like sales growth, then it has a positive impact on margins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just to understand that, so if like-for-like sales growth in the future was strong, then we could see EBIT margins rise sustainably above 20%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ben, what I think is relevant is to sustain the fundamentals of the business model and this is what the company has always tried to do. If we achieve very strong like-for-likes, obviously there will be a margin impact. However, what I think is very important is to sustain the speed-to-market, the quality of what we do, and try to focus on execution. If the result of execution is good, this will translate in the EBIT margins, but it's not the other way around.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. Thanks very much, Marcos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Geoff Lowery from Redburn Partners. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi, morning, team. Question around gross margin; if we look in historic context, how low is your level of markdown?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, very similar, not big differences. In terms &#x2013; not big differences from that point of view. I think, as we were saying before, all the different lines of the profit-and-loss account have a lot to do with the evolution of our like-for-like sales, the flexibility of our business model, but not big differences compared to other. You know that during the season, we don't have mark-downs...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In general terms. And then regarding &#x2013; for example, if we think about the spring, summer season and the mark-downs after the &#x2013; at the end of the spring, summer season, not big differences compared to other years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the driver of the improvement is bought-in gross margin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the big driver of your gross margin progress is the bought-in level rather than management mark-down and promotions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I say &#x2013; Mr. Isla has mentioned in the third quarter we tend not to have significant discounts. So the evolution of gross margin is composed of many factors, is the mix, the bought-in, the mark-up, et cetera, et cetera. So, it's basically the execution of the business model which is the main driver in this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Jamie Merriman from Sanford C. Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I actually wanted to turn back to China and your online offer there. I know you're working with a third-party logistics provider. But I was wondering, is it just one? And are there other parts of the online business that you're outsourcing, things like maybe payment processing or anything like that? And how is that working?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in the case of China we have a single logistics provider, so it's the same case in United States and in Japan. And these providers just take care of the last mile, so it's very much like a point that we used to refer the product to our &#x2013; it really operates as a stockroom of any other store, but we tend to focus on just a single provider in each of these markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And is there any other parts of the online business that you're outsourcing, like payment processing, or is that all done internally?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well of course, the payment process is depending on the markets, you rely on the best established players.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But for us, what is relevant is, as Marcos was saying, that we are managing the online store as any other store. This is what is relevant...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...that it could be some technical elements, of course, it could be logistic provider for the &#x2013; it could be something related with payments. But for us, it's exactly as an additional store. Our online store is as any other store in the country from every point of view, from the point of view of the stock management, from the point of view of the deliveries, from our different logistic platforms. So, it's managed as any other store in the country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Anne Critchlow from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, it's Anne Critchlow from SG. You mentioned markup as one of the drivers of gross margin. And I was just wondering if you'd made any notable changes to your price architecture, particularly at Zara, compared to a year ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's like &#x2013; our prices have remained stable in the different markets. And when we talk about the gross margin we always say the same, that we try to isolate one factor, sometimes it could mean to pay a lot of attention to 50 basis points and to forget about 59 points. Not because the exact combination of many, many different factors, in our case it has a lot to do with the flexibility of the business model, it has a lot to do with proximity sourcing as you perfectly know, which is extremely relevant for us; sourcing in Spain, in Portugal, in Morocco, sourcing in Turkey; to have this ability to react during the season. So, it's a combination of many different factors. We would prefer not to isolate any of these factors and particularly when we are talking about quarterly results presentation. But in any case, the gross margin is a global figure with many different elements involved and of course which has &#x2013; it's very much helped when you have a positive like-for-like sales growth evolution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And I think you said your prices have been stable for many quarters now, as far as I can remember back. Does that mean your prices have been stable over, say, a five-year period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They have been stable &#x2013; broadly stable in the last few years, yes, in the different markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Geoff Ruddell from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, morning everybody. Another question I'm afraid on the gross margin. If I've done my math correctly, I think you've reported a gross margin of just over 62% for the third quarter, which I think is the highest &#x2013; I think it's the first time since the IPO that you've actually reported a gross margin of over 62%. My question therefore is, should we just be thinking about as you're having a particularly good year this year or are there any sort of structural reasons that is driving the gross margin higher over time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say again what we have been talking before. I think it's better to wait until the end of the year. It has a lot to do with many different factors. It has a lot to do with like-for-like sales growth and all the different factors involved in the gross margin. I would not extract strong conclusions or consequences of the isolated gross margin of the third quarter of one particular year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And just as a follow-up, your CapEx for &#x2013; of &#x2013; guidance for the year of &#x20AC;1 billion, how much of that is going on new stores roughly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very much in line with what happens always, physically of course it could have &#x2013; it could change a little bit from one year to another, but typically logistics could be around &#x2013; I mean newer stores could be around 75% of the total CapEx. Sometimes it changes little bit one year or another year; then you have refurbishments and then you have IT and logistics to reach the &#x20AC;1 billion figure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Rebecca McClellan from Santander. Please go ahead, madam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. I've got a couple of questions. Firstly, is there any double-costing associated with either &#x2013; the up and coming new headquarters of Massimo Dutti and the new space for Zara?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If there is anything behind that it's...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If there's any double-costing at all, because I think Zara is the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (24:59) the new facility space is almost imminent, isn't it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's totally included in the CapEx, Rebecca.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But there's no double OpEx &#x2013; double-costing in OpEx?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And was there any sort of like noticeable incremental cost associated with the launch of China online?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They're included in the OpEx and they're not material, as you know, because basically the key investments online have been incurred and it's just limited expenses based on their launch in every specific country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just finally a detail, what was the constant currency OpEx for the nine-month period, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very similar to the topline impact, we have mentioned that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Fraser Razman (sic) [Fraser Ramzan] (25:53) from Nomura. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning; just really one question around space growth. Given the very strong improvements in profitability you've seen in recent years, clearly you have an ability to trade in lots of locations and make very good returns. What is your level of confidence on your ability to grow by 8% to 10% per year going forward, and how far forward does it extend? Do you think you'd be able to do this for the next five years or should &#x2013; do you have visibility for two to three?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we think about the next three to five years' period we don't see any reason why space growth should not be between 8% to 10%. You must have in mind that we are present in 86 different markets, and this means a lot of opportunities in the different countries. We were mentioning during the presentation that we have opened the stores in more than 50 countries during this nine months' period. So, we have many opportunities in the different markets, and that is why space growth is 8% to 10%, and we continue seeing this range between 8% to 10% in the coming years. If you ask me in the next three to five years' period, I will tell you that this is the space growth rate that we are seeing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just &#x2013; if I could just add one very short one on the end of that which is around the United States, clearly great to see the Massimo Dutti flagship opening and the new Zara of course. But do you see any sort of significant improvement in the availability of really high quality space in that market for the Zara format?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there are opportunities in the different markets. You were talking about the United States, now we &#x2013; well, with Zara we are present since many years ago, as you know. Now, we have begun our operations with Massimo Dutti in New York and Washington and our idea is to increase step by step our presence with Massimo Dutti in the U.S. market and then with Zara to continue opening stores in the coming years, as we try to do a rework on binding flagship stores with good shopping mall stores. And there are always opportunities, particularly the United States is a very big country with many difference cities and there are always opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much. Thanks for the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Simon Irwin from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen; couple of quick questions for you. Firstly, can you just talk about any trends in terms of geography by sales in terms of which markets are doing relatively better or worse than others? And can you just also just talk about the financials line? Obviously, given your net cash I'd say it's not a significant yield coming off that cash. What other factors go into that net financials lines or hedging impact, et cetera, that we should be aware of, in this quarter in particular?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About geographies, as you know, we prefer not to elaborate very much in the &#x2013; we elaborate about geographies in the first-half results and the full-year results. And about the other question, perhaps, Ignacio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. In relation to the financial income, it is due to the impact of foreign exchange losses related to the conversion of accounts receivables on papers, which is non-cash item. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:30) the first half provided a foreign exchange gain, has been partially reversed as of the 31st of October.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Warwick Okines from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning; question about Brazil, please. Just wondering how many Zara stores you feel you can sustainably open each year. Is it the sort of 5 to 10 range or is it less than that? And also whether you have any plans to launch the other concepts beyond Zara Home and Zara in Brazil. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The 5 to 10 could be a reasonable assumption in the coming years. And about launching other concepts, not in the short term. You know that the Southern Hemisphere needs a specific theme, a different collection. We are with Zara, now we are with Zara Home; it could be in the future but not in the short term.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much. And just quick &#x2013; sort of second question; what proportion of your Zara sales base is now covered by an e-commerce offer globally?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What do you mean? If...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What's &#x2013; more than a percentage of sales would refer to &#x2013; refer, Warwick, to the countries in which Zara is present with online operations, which is 21. And with Canada it will be 22 in the spring, summer season.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We are now finishing the telephone Q&amp;A session to address the questions received through the webcast platform. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. We're now going to go over the questions that have come in through the webcast platform. Some of the questions have been covered already during the conference call regarding our space guidance and expectations for future years, also regarding Massimo Dutti launch in the United States. We had another question about one of our concepts; what do you think is the potential for Zara Home in the Southern Hemisphere?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what I would say is that, of course, there is potential and we will go step by step. It has been very well received in Brazil. We are just at the very beginning and of course there is potential. But it's very difficult for me to be more precise than that at this stage. We are just beginning our operations with Zara Home in the Southern Hemisphere. It's a relevant part of the world. And of course, there is potential.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And I think most of the other questions have been answered. We &#x2013; I suppose the final question referring to a question we received from Francisco Riquel of Nm&#xE1;s1 Securities is regarding online launches.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We've talked about it a little bit; could you give us more color on the expected online launches in future years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we are announcing that we are launching in Canada in the next spring, summer season and we will continue progressively with the online rollout in the different markets. But we prefer to announce things when they are close to happening, not very much in advance. What we can say, as I was saying before, is that we continue very focused on the execution and that we think that this multi-channel approach is very strong from every point of view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Well, that concludes the questions commentary of the webcast platform.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you very much. And in any case, of course, through our Capital Markets Department, we will be ready to answer any additional questions that you may have. Thank you for joining the conference call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>