<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1237769" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-06-10</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7864</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Pablo Isla &#xC1;lvarez de Tejera, First Deputy Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Ignacio Fern&#xE1;ndez, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Marcos L&#xF3;pez, Capital Markets Director</participant>
      <participant id="4">Flora Trindade</participant>
      <participant id="5">Richard Edwards</participant>
      <participant id="6">Luca Solca</participant>
      <participant id="7">Warwick Okines</participant>
      <participant id="8">Anne Critchlow</participant>
      <participant id="9">Nick Hawkins</participant>
      <participant id="10">Fraser Ramzan</participant>
      <participant id="11">Andrew Hughes</participant>
      <participant id="12">Tony Shiret</participant>
      <participant id="13">Paul Smiddy</participant>
      <participant id="14">Robert Miller</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen.  Welcome to the presentation of Inditex's results for the interim three months 2009.  The presentation will be chaired by Mr. Pablo Isla, Deputy Chairman and CEO.</p>
          <p>This presentation will be followed by a Q&amp;A session, compromising two parts.  The first part will be dedicated to questions received on the phone, followed from 10:30 onwards by those questions received through the webcast platform.  Mr. Isla, you have the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning to all the participants in this webcast conference call regarding Inditex's results for the interim three months of 2009.  I am Pablo Isla and here with me today are Ignacio Fern&#xE1;ndez, our CFO, and Marcos L&#xF3;pez, Capital Markets Director.</p>
          <p>I would like to cover a few of the highlights.  First, the results for the first quarter 2009 show that Inditex continues to gain market share globally.  Net sales in local currencies have grown 8%.  In line with the strategic priorities presented to you last March, operating expenses are tightly under control.  Let me also tell you that we have maintained our strict focus on cash-flow generation.  In terms of growth, our space-expansion plans are on track.  These initiatives have been carried out in a challenging period for the retail sector, marked by a difficult trading environment and a slowdown in economic growth in most markets.</p>
          <p>I will now hand over to Ignacio Fern&#xE1;ndez, who will provide some of the details behind the headline numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Before breaking into the headline numbers, let me talk about the background of these quarterly figures.  First, I would like to elaborate on a number of calendar effects.  We are comparing with a leap year in 2008 and Easter has fallen in April in 2009 versus March in 2008.  In 2009, the translation of sales in currencies different to the Euro had deducted around two percentage points for the top sales growth due to the lower exchange-rate basis our reporting currency.</p>
          <p>As you all know, space growth in fiscal 2009 is more weighted to the second half of the year, 75%, than in fiscal 2008, 57%.  And finally, in the first half of 2009, we are trading against a corporate sales like-for-like comparable on a two-year, compound basis.  In this context, Inditex have achieved net sales of &#x20AC;2.3 billion, EBITDA of &#x20AC;395 million.  Let me also highlight that sales in local currencies have grown by 8% in the first quarter of 2009.  In terms of gross profits, this line has increased 4% to &#x20AC;1.3 billion, resulting in a 56.9 gross margin due to the evolution of currencies.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses have grown at 9%, include all the start-up costs for new openings, and are tightly under control.  Operating expenses have grown in the first quarter below space growth.  Our efficiency plans for the year are on track.  The evolution of current account is in line with the performance on the business.  Inditex keeps showing a strong net financial position.</p>
          <p>I will now hand over to Marcos L&#xF3;pez, who will provide some of the detail behind the performance of the Inditex concepts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of space addition we are on track, as we have opened 95 net stores in the quarter to reach a total of 4,359.  We have opened 91 stores in 27 international markets over the quarter.  Let me remind you of the different calendar of store openings in 2009 versus 2008.  As we mentioned to you last March, the space addition in 2009 is weighted to the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Regarding the performance by formats in the interim three months of 2009, Zara and the younger concepts grouped together have performed broadly in line, with some minor differences.  Regarding the younger concepts, Stradivarius and Bershka have performed above the average and Oysho and Zara Home below the average.  I will now hand over to Pablo for the outlook section.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>As we announced to you last March, we expect to add 230,000 square meters to our retail base in 2009.  95% of total new space will be opened in international markets.  The store openings are significantly weighted to the second half of the fiscal year.  Our plan is to invest around &#x20AC;600 million over 2009.  Regarding the outlook for the rest of the first half, I would like to add that the store sales in local currencies from the 1st of May to the 7th of June of 2009 are growing by 9%.</p>
          <p>Before closing let me elaborate briefly on a number of initiatives carried out by Inditex concepts over the quarter and some selected store openings of recent months.  Zara women's wear has launched a new internally designed image in its Trafaluc section, the younger part of its fashion proposition.  This new image is being rolled out in all the new stores.  In men's wear Zara Sport now includes a special MTV theme collection.  Zara children's wear has broadened its collections for zero to 24 months old.  Zara has launched a new website with a stronger visual approach that allows a higher interaction with its clients.</p>
          <p>Additionally, Zara Home on-line sales are progressing satisfactorily due to the constant renewal of the ranges.  We have recently launched Bershka and Pull and Bear in China.  Bershka has opened the stores in the most relevant locations of Beijing, Shanghai, Hong Kong, and Dalian.  Pull and Bear has opened a store in Beijing, Solana shopping mall.</p>
          <p>Both Massimo Dutti and Stradivarius have new store looks.  Massimo Dutti carries this new image in its flagship stores in Berlin and D&#xFC;sseldorf.  Stradivarius' new look has now been rolled out to 90% of its stores.  An important product campaign will take place to celebrate its 15th anniversary.</p>
          <p>Oysho has recently launched a Beachwear collection in all its stores.  Our new accessories format, Uterq&#xFC;e, has entered three new markets, Belgium, Kuwait, and Qatar.  In terms of store openings, Zara has opened a boutique women's wear store at Paris, Faubourg Saint Honor&#xE9;.  The store is located in one of the world's principal fashion streets and showcases Zara's latest women's wear collections.  Inditex has opened its first eco-efficient store at Korai in Athens.  This flagship store of 2,400 square meters has been developed by Zara's teams in conjunction with Spanish universities.  It includes a strong number of features to reduce energy consumption by 30% versus standard Zara stores.  This project will be implemented in all newer stores in the coming years.</p>
          <p>Zara has opened at Mertens House in St. Petersburg, Nevsky Avenue.  This Neoclassical building has been restored to its original features to host a flagship store in the most prominent location of the city.  We have opened an emblematic Zara store in New York City at 15th Avenue (sic) [5th Avenue] on 42nd Street.  It is located in a prominent building next to New York Public Library and Grand Central Terminal.  This is our seventh store in New York City and our third store in 5th Avenue.</p>
          <p>We have recently started operations in Egypt with the launch of four concepts, Zara, Bershka, Pull and Bear, and Massimo Dutti in Cairo.  I would like to close this presentation referring to our expansion in Asia.  Two very relevant stores have been opened in South Korea at Daegu and Bundang.  We continue to see strong potential to expand Zara in Korea over the coming years.  We have also opened a flagship store in Tokyo's most prestigious retail district at Ginza Marronnier.  This is our second store in Ginza and our 43rd in Japan.</p>
          <p>Finally, we continue to expand our presence in China with additional stores.  Zara has opened in the heart of Shanghai at People's Square.  This flagship store has more than 1,500 square meters of retail space over two floors.</p>
          <p>And this is all from us.  We will be pleased now to answer any questions you may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator instructions" />  The first question comes from Mrs. Flora Trindade from BPI [Banco Portugu&#xEA;s de Investimento].  Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Hi.  Good morning.  Firstly, I would like to ask if you could comment on the outlook for the year in terms of like-for-like sales growth because apparently from the figures you gave in the beginning of the second quarter, I know it's just a few weeks, but it seems that the decline in like-for-like sales growth is decelerating.  So, if you could just provide us some insight on the performance in terms of like-for-like per market and how you see this going forward for this full year?</p>
          <p>And also, if you could give us an idea of what do you expect to be the FX impact in top line for the full year?  And finally, just a clarification on whether you have some impact from pricing in the latest quarter because we've seen several retailers speeding up promotions, so if you just comment, could comment on whether you are going through this path or not?  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as you know, when we, I think, talk about like-for-like sales evolution, we always prefer to wait until a six-months period.  So, what we are providing you in this first-quarter results publication is the evolution of store sales in, net sales in local currencies in the first quarter, the evolution in the first five weeks of the second quarter, but we prefer not to talk about like-for-like sales evolution on a quarterly basis, no?</p>
          <p>In any case, and I would say that this answer is applicable to or could be applicable to a lot of things that could be raised during the conference call.  What I mean is that we had our full-year-results conference call two months ago and I would say that 99% of the things we said during the conference call, full-year-results conference call remain the same.  About exchange rates' impact on the top line for the full year, of course it will depend on the evolution of the different currencies during the year.  In any case, what you must always have in mind is that our exposure to foreign exchange movement is relatively limited because 70% of our sales are in Euros, 65% of our purchasing is in Euros, so our exposure is very limited.  About promotions, what I would say is that the trends we are seeing in this season are very similar to those of the last season.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.  Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sorry.  If I just may make a follow-up question on, if you could just comment on the performance of the Spanish markets during this quarter and whether, if you could, give us some idea on market share gains in Spain?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, obviously, as we mentioned in March we believe that we're gaining market share globally.  Obviously, as you can see, most of expansion for the year is going to take place in international markets.  We are growing mainly in Europe and in Asia.  In Europe, both in Eastern Europe and Western Europe and this remains the case, as what we have mentioned in late March.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator instructions" />.  So, the next question comes from Mr. Richard Edwards from Citigroup.  Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  Hi.  A couple of questions.  First one was just on commitment levels going into the second quarter, how do they compare year-on-year?   The other questions were in local currency, what was the cost increase in the first quarter I just want to see if the ForEx effect was different from on the revenue line.  And just thirdly, on Spain itself, can you confirm whether revenue trends were actually positive or not in the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About commitment, what we can say is that it's very much in line with the previous year and this is regarding the first part of your question.  About currency impact on OpEx, is more or less half of the impact on sales and so this is what you could assume.  About Spain, Marcos, anything relevant to comment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't say so.  No, no.  Nothing specific.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We would prefer always to wait until a six-months period to comment on specific markets, specific performance of the different markets.  We think it is much better in order to have a clearer picture, no?</p>
          <p>Particularly having in mind, this quarter, with so many impacts we Ignacioi was saying during that presentation, with all these calendar impacts, the month of the Easter.  But, there's so many impacts during the quarter that we think it is much better to wait until the first half, the first six months of the year to talk about markets, talk about evolution in the different markets.</p>
          <p>In any case, what you can assume is what we said in the presentation, in the full-year results presentation.  More or less, the global trends of the evolution of the different markets, which markets are outperforming, which markets have not, remains the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator instructions" />.  So, the next question comes from Mr. Luca Solca from Sanford Bernstein.  Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  I just wanted to ask you a bit more detail about the various formats and how are they performing.  I remember from last year you were saying that Zara Home and Oysho were experiencing less brilliant results because of space opening, I think.  And I wonder if this is still the case and what are the differences that you are seeing in your formats and how they are faring against the difficult market and competitive pressures?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  It is, it is, it continues being the case.  So, no big differences.  As Marcos was saying during the presentation, Zara Home and Oysho are performing below the average, Stradivarius and Bershka are performing above the average, the younger formats and the rest of the formats are performing in line with the average.  So, the trends remain very similar to those of the second-half of the year 2008, regarding the performance of the different formats.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Warwick Okines from Deutsche Bank.  Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  It's Warwick Okines from Deutsche Bank.  I just wanted to ask about your space expansion plans in Spain.  The slide you put up today suggests around 20 stores planned at the mid-point of your guidance for this year.  At the full-year stage, you were suggesting around 50 stores at the mid-point.  You've opened four net in Q1.  Could you just explain whether that guidance has changed or whether it's just a phasing and timing issue, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It has much more to do with the phasing, no?  What we are planning is, as you know, 95% of the space is going to take place in international markets.  Particularly regarding Zara or other formats, this 95 is more 98%.  So, this remains very much the case.  Yes, you say that in the four quarters, from 95 openings, only four have taken place in Spain, but you should assume because, when you think about the number of openings, we think it's better to think about the space, no?, because of the different size of the different formats.  And in terms of space growth, around 95% of total space added during the year will be in international markets.  So it remains the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Anne Critchlow from Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale.  Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Good morning.  I have a question on the gross margin.  Could you say whether the whole of the 90-basis-point fall was down to markdowns or were there any currency effects in there?   And could you give an idea of what you're expecting for the full year on gross margin, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Regarding the gross margin evolution, the main difference is due to currencies, the vast majority of it, because we have sustained our commercial policies over the quarter.  Regarding what we expect for the year, we always get this question in the first quarter of every fiscal year and we tend to say that for the full year, what we expect is to have a broadly stable gross margin, 50 basis points higher or lower.  So, this quarter we're going to reiterate exactly the same question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.  And then earlier Marcos said that 99% of the factors that you mentioned for the full year still apply when we're talking about, say, consumer confidence and the outlook.  What's changed?  What's the 1% that has changed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's just a way of talking, when I say it's not that I am thinking about 1%, which is changing, no?  What I mean is that, what we said during the full-year-results conference call remains valid and that is what I've, what say.  It is not that I am thinking that there is 1% that has changed.  It is a way of talking, it's a typical expression in Spanish, probably not the best direct translation into English.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Nick Hawkins from Cenkos.  Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's Nick Hawkins from Cenkos.  Good morning.  I've got a question on operating costs, where the performance has improved quite sharply.  Could you give us an idea, please, of how much of that is lower pre-opening costs, since you scaled back your expansion?  And what other factors have contributed to the better cost performance, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This, the main thing is the &#x20AC;75 million plan, saving plan that we announced for the year and this is what is driving this, what I would say, good evolution of operating expenses, which in the quarter are growing below space growth.  In any case of course, what we would like to say about cost evolution, as with many other aspects of our business, is that it's better to wait at least until the first half, and even more until the full year results, to have a global picture, no?</p>
          <p>But this positive evolution of operating costs has to do with all the efforts that we began several years ago and, additionally, with this &#x20AC;75 million saving plan that, if you remember, we were saying that 50% from those savings were going to come from rental expenses savings and the other 50% was going to come from overheads and from procurement, no?  This is the way we approach this &#x20AC;75 million saving plan and it has to do with the implementation of all the measures that are included in the plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see.  So, in this particular quarter, you've managed to achieve rental savings in what areas?  Were you just negotiating more aggressively or?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In line with what we were planning to do at the beginning of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's many things, Nick.  It's nothing of a, it's not just one chapter which is very big, but we are talking about renegotiation of rental expenses.  We are talking about renegotiation of maintenance, freight and cleaning services.  We are talking about using low-energy bulbs in our stores, reducing traveling expenses, keeping a very strict control on overhead.  So, it is micro-management than any big chapter that we're acting on.  And also what you're seeing is also the result of the decision play-efficiency plans put in place over the last years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Okay.  That's good color.  Thank you very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Armstrong from <mark type="inaudible" />.  Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Armstrong just hung up.  So, the next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.  It's Fraser Ramzan from Nomura.  I hadn't understood the pronunciation of my name.  Just one question this morning, it's following on from Nick on the cost saving program.  Do you think, given that you've already delivered a decent amount in the first quarter, there's any chance of you actually exceeding your current plan?   I had expected it to be second-half loaded, so I'm positively surprised by what you've done today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We maintain our plans.  Within that, the &#x20AC;75 million saving plan is very ambitious, as it was the efficiencies that we gained in the previous year, years, and what we can say is that, currently, we feel that we are on track to achieve our target.  But the target, the &#x20AC;75 million target is ambitious itself, so we are, we maintained the plans we had at the beginning of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Jean-Marie from Exane BNP Paribas.  Please, go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everyone.  Actually, it's Laurent <mark type="inaudible" /> at Exane, but my questions have been all answered.  So, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>So, the next question comes from Mr. Simon Owen from Liberal Capital.  Please, go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen.  Could we just go back to the gross margin question.  As I understand it, the first quarter will tend to have a higher proportion of dollar-sourced garments, while the proximity garments will become higher proportion of the mix in the second quarter.  So, is it reasonable to assume that you'd expect less of an FX impact on the gross margin in the second quarter and potentially in the fourth quarter this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not really.  I mean, the proportion of garments that we update over the season is very much the same, so you must not expect a higher or lower impact of FX based on the collection.  It's really depending on the currency evolution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Andrew Hughes from UBS.  Please, go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen.  It's Andrew Hughes from UBS in London.  Just had a question going back to space, where you have opened 95 stores in the first quarter, which looks to me in line with what you expect to open for the full year, around about 400 stores.  How can space still be second-half weighted on that basis?  Are you just going to open very few stores in the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  And you also must have in mind that Zara openings in the quarter which are those that represent bigger space, the figure is low, no?  So, when we talk about space growth, you must assume that in the first half, most of the openings always take place, most of them-of course, not all of them-takes place, take place during April and May.  And when you are talking about the second half, September, October and November, no?</p>
          <p>So, May is also a relevant months in terms of openings.  Then June is very low and July there are no openings, no?, because of the calendar during the years, during the year.  So, it will continue being as we said in the full-year-result presentation more or less, no?, because this figure is never 100% precise, because there could be a delay or an anticipation in a few particular openings always, no?  But, more or less, this year it will be more weighted to the second half that it was the case during the year 2008, that it was nearly even, no?, between the two halves of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mrs. Tony Shiret from Credit Suisse.  Please, go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think that's me.  It's Tony Shiret from Credit Suisse.  I was interested in your comments on the number of stores you've got on 5th Avenue in New York.  I just, looking back over the record of your openings in the U.S., so I just wondered if we're now at the point where you're more prepared to commit to the U.S. opening program, whether this is going to become more meaningful than it has been in past?  Can you comment on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No change, from that point of view.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., we are concentrating our presence in the East coast, particularly in New York-well, the area, New York, Boston, the New Jersey, this area.  In the West coast, Los Angeles, San Francisco, and in Florida, no?  And those are the areas in which we are concentrating our presence  and we are not thinking about a significant change of strategy regarding the U.S.</p>
          <p>We will continue adding every year six, eight, 10 stores, but not a big, we are not thinking about a big expansion in the U.S.  Our priorities from the point of view of expansion are very clear.  We have Asia as a priority and, as we were saying during the presentation, now not only with Zara, but also with other formats, Massimo Dutti, which is already present, and Bershka and Pull and Bear.  And the other priority we have is Europe and we said Europe, always a good balance between Western and Eastern European countries.  And those remain our key priorities regarding expansion.  So, not a change of strategy regarding the U.S..</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Having said that ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This new store that we were referring to in 42nd Street with 5th Avenue is a very, very flagship store from every point of view, no?  So, New York is one of the most relevant cities in the world and we take a lot of care about our presence in New York and about the stores we are opening there.  And we have also a very nice one in the SoHo, very, very, very, very nice store.  So, well, in Manhattan, we have seven stores as we were saying, the seven of them very well located and very, I would say, good looking stores, no?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Paul Smiddy from HSBC.  Please, go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  Can you just clarify why payables are up 21% and also what the drivers are behind the deteriorating interest line?  Are there any one-off charges in there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not really, Paul.  You know that current accounts in the quarter are always difficult to compare, very especially, because in this quarter, there is a, there are three factors, most of them referring to calendar effects.  The first one is the different calendar of dividend payments.  The second one is also a different calendar in fiscal accounts.  And the third one is that something that we have referred extensively over the call, is that the different calendar of store openings results in a different calendar of CapEx and payables for fixed assets.  So, I believe to look at the current accounts over a quarter is very, very difficult.  It's much better to go for the six months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Peter Farrell.  Please, go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning.  I've got one and a half questions, actually, first half being if you could actually confirm the, what amount of cost savings actually came through in Q1 from the 75 million?  And the other one is on the gross margin.  If FX is going to continue to have the same kind of negative impact throughout the year and you're maintaining guidance for a flat margin, does that mean you'll be compensating somewhere?  Is there flexibility to possibly increase prices in H2?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Peter , regarding cost savings, I believe that we've made clear over the call that it's true that in the first quarter operating expenses are growing below space growth and we're happy with that.  But we are committed in full to the &#x20AC;75 million in operating expenses savings that we expect for the year, because it's a very demanding figure, so no change on that part.</p>
          <p>Regarding gross margin, as I say, to look at gross margin over a quarter, in our opinion, is very difficult.  We always get this question in the first-quarter conference call every year.  And, again, we sustain our view that what we have is a broadly stable gross-margin vision for the year.  Because in the gross margin, there are so many impacts, but I believe we have the business model which allows us to look for a broadly stable gross margin over the year, taking account all these factors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Robert Miller from Redburn Partners.  Please, go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning.  I was wondering if, in the current trading number, there are any significant calendar effects that we should consider?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Robert, in this sense, we ... again, there are, there is nothing significant there.  What I would also like to say is that the longer it would be ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />
          </p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>... the better quality.  So it's much better to look at longer periods, a season.  You know, we believe it's much, much more relevant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And can I also ask a slightly sort of random question?  Given that the World Health Organization is about to raise swine flu to pandemic level six, what does your experience in Mexico and previously your experience through the SARS period tell you about any top-line risk through this period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say nothing relevant, nothing relevant, nothing relevant.  In Mexico, stores were closed during two or three days, but nothing relevant in a full-year period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The telephone Q&amp;A session finishes now.  We'll start with the online questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Now, we will address the questions we have just received from line.  So, there is first question.  If you can provide some light regarding the renegotiation of leases, if this has been focused on the Spain or abroad as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, renegotiation of leases is not something that we're doing on a geographical basis.  What we are looking is at performance of given, any given stores and the traffic that we're receiving in these stores.  If for whatever the reason, the traffic is not meeting the initial targets, in any case, in a shopping mall, then this is the reason to act.  So, I would not say that there is a geographic, specific geographic reason in any given store.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there are more questions that I think having already answered regarding like-for-like on <mark type="inaudible" /> the different performance per countries.  And there is a question about the strong cash position at the end of the quarter, if cash conversion of the company is increasing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you know, Inditex has a strong focus on capital efficiency.  We have an on-going evolution of our capital expenditure plan, such as to obtain efficiency in our operating expenses in order to maximize free cash flow.  This process keeps  <mark type="inaudible" /> return on capital employed and shareholder <mark type="inaudible" />.  Inditex is focused on profitable expansion of its business by sustaining higher returns and this remains our objective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, there is a question regarding our expansion in Asia, if it's on a lease or a freehold  basis, which is clearly something on a lease <mark type="inaudible" /> basis, but the question is about, if the breakeven of the stores we are opening in Asia is different, is shorter than you saw?  And the potential number of openings that we must be seeing in the area going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.  Regarding the first part of the question, regarding the breakeven point-not a big difference with other geographies and the potential is huge.  I think this is something that is very evident for us, no?, that the potential in many different markets, but particularly in China, Japan, and Korea, is huge to continue growing with Zara, with the other formats.  The fashion appetite in these countries is very clear and having in mind the size of the countries, the population, the potential is huge.  This is the reason why, for us, it's a key priority right now in terms of expansion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Basically, there are more questions I think we can address from the IR department regarding the top-line <mark type="inaudible" /> and something like that.  And there's a question about the performance of Uterq&#xFC;e, if this has resulted in any special loss in the first quarter?  And the reasons why we are expanding in Belgium, Kuwait and Qatar?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the reasons is because you need to begin somewhere, no?  We are already present in Spain, in Greece, in Lisbon, also in Portugal and we'll continue growing and entering new markets.  And in these first months of the year, we have entered these three markets and we'll continue in the coming months and years, entering new markets.</p>
          <p>About the evolution of Uterq&#xFC;e, nothing relevant.  If you remember, during the full-year-results conference-call presentation, our target is for Uterq&#xFC;e to be profitable this year, the first full year.  This is a very ambitious target and this is what we are trying to do during the year, but not, in this first quarter, no relevant impact coming from Uterq&#xFC;e.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And this is all coming from the online questions, as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, so, thank you very much for all of you, to all of you, in any case.  Of course, we'll continue being ready to answer any question you could have through our Capital Markets department and whatever you could, whatever doubt or question you could have, we would try to answer it.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes our conference call.  Thank you for attending.  Good bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>