<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1142671" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>FY 2007 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-03-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7864</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Pablo Isla &#xC1;lvarez de Tejera, First Deputy Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Antonio Rubio Merino, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Marcos L&#xF3;pez, Capital Markets Director</participant>
      <participant id="4">Luca Cipiccia</participant>
      <participant id="5">Antonio Rubio Merino</participant>
      <participant id="6">Pablo Isla &#xC1;lvarez Tejera</participant>
      <participant id="7">Luca Solca</participant>
      <participant id="8">Claire Kent</participant>
      <participant id="9">Fraser Ramzan</participant>
      <participant id="10">Anne Critchlow</participant>
      <participant id="11">Matthew Taylor</participant>
      <participant id="12">Brevan Howard</participant>
      <participant id="13">Tony Shiret</participant>
      <participant id="14">Robert Miller</participant>
      <participant id="15">Marcos L&#xF3;pez</participant>
      <participant id="16">Richard Chamberlain</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, the Inditex Conference Call will start now. The presentation will be chaired by Mr. Pablo Isla, Inditex's CEO and will be followed by Q&amp;A session during which you will be able to ask your questions. Please you are only allowed to ask one question by turn.</p>
          <p>Thank you. Mr. Isla you have the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I would like to welcome all the participants to this presentation regarding Inditex Results for Fiscal 2007. I am Pablo Isla, Chief Executive Officer of Inditex and here with me are Antonio Rubio, CFO; and Marcos L&#xF3;pez, Capital Markets Director.</p>
          <p>2007 has been another year of strong year growth for Inditex, a reflection of the ongoing expansion of our group. Our result show significant growth in sales and a strong operating performance.</p>
          <p>2007 has also been marked by the satisfactory evolution of gross margins, a significant increase in operating efficiency and a strict cost control. As a result, the group has improved its financial returns, our cash flow keeps growing steadily and our financial condition is stronger.</p>
          <p>Due to these facts and the significant business opportunities to invest profitably, funds from operations have been devoted mainly to the expansion of our business. This growth has taken place through the addition of prime commercial space to our retail base in markets with high potential. Additionally, our financial condition allows us to propose a significant increase in shareholder remuneration for the period.</p>
          <p>I would like to highlight some key points of these results. In 2007, sales grew satisfactorily by 15% to &#x20AC;9.4 billion. Let me remark that Inditex sales in local currencies and constant perimeter increased 17%. In the period we have also achieved comparable sales growth of 5%. Due to this strong sales growth and higher operating efficiency, net income in 2007 increased 25% to &#x20AC;1.25 billion or &#x20AC;2.01 per share.</p>
          <p>Inditex cash flow generation remains strong. Funds from operations increased 18% to &#x20AC;1.8 billion. Return on capital employed has reached 43%. As a result of our performance in 2007, Inditex Board of Directors is proposing a 25% increase in the dividend to be paid in relation to these results.</p>
          <p>Regarding the evolution of like-for-like sales growth in 2007, I would highlight that we have achieved a satisfactory 5% against our 5.5% comparable in the previous year. Our comparable sales performance and the expansion of the group have resulted in solid growth both in Spain and in the international markets were we operate.</p>
          <p>In accordance with our strategy, 85% of the new retail space added over 2007 was located in international markets. As a result we continue to see an increasing share of international sales that now account for 63% of total, versus 60% in 2006. Due to the -- to our ongoing expansion in European markets, the area which shows the highest growth is Europe ex-Spain, reaching 42.4% of total store sales versus 40.6% in 2006.</p>
          <p>I am now handing over to Antonio Rubio, who will provide some of the detail behind the headline numbers, and I will join you later for the outlook section.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning. As you can see in this table, Inditex results for 2007 show significant growth in all the key lines of the profit and loss account and our strong operating performance.</p>
          <p>Starting with sales, let me say that added to our 12% contribution of new selling space, we have delivered a 5% increase in comparable sales. The translation of sales in currency different to the euro and the agreement to franchise our operations in Venezuela at the end of the first half of 2007 have diluted two percentage points from reported sales growth. The perimeter effect we'll analyze at the end of the first half 2008.</p>
          <p>Inditex's commercial space has grown by 15.5% over 2007 and we have added more than 257,000 square meters to our retail park. Space growth on a time-weighted basis has been 14.5% as openings over 2007 had been more biased towards the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Let me remark that 25% of our retail space is still in a maturing phase, as our newer stores generally experience a ramp-up period before achieving full sales densities.</p>
          <p>In terms of gross profit, Inditex's gross margin has performed satisfactorily, reaching 56.7% on sales. Under current circumstances, the group targets a gross margin for fiscal 2008 similar to that of 2007.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses have grown in a very tight manner, up 15%, and include all the start-up costs for new openings. We have made adequate progress in our Reduce 3 efficiency program resulting in a strict control of operating expenses.</p>
          <p>As a result of the sales progression, gross margin evolution, and efficiency plans, we have seen a strong operating performance. Our EBIT margin on sales has reached 17.5%, one percentage point higher than in the previous year.</p>
          <p>Inditex's negative working capital increased at the end of 2007 by 15% over the same point of 2006, reaching &#x20AC;571 million of free cash financing. This inflow was due to our stable working capital fundamentals.</p>
          <p>Funds from operation have increased by 18% in the period to &#x20AC;1.8 billion; due to the improvement in our net working capital, cash from operations increased by 30%.</p>
          <p>As you can see in this table, in addition to the &#x20AC;942 million of capital expenditure, we also increased our dividend payments in 2007 by 25%.</p>
          <p>Finally, the profitability of the group has reach 33% in terms of return on equity and 43% in terms of return on capital employed.</p>
          <p>I'm now handing over to Marcos L&#xF3;pez.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning. I'll go briefly over the evolution of the different concepts. As you can see in this chart, Zara remains at approximately two-thirds of Inditex sales and the younger concepts at one-third.</p>
          <p>In 2007, we have made the decision to coordinate in full the operations of Zara children's wear and Kiddy's Class, integrating their buying functions and managing their retailing operations in a combined manner. Due to this new structure, Kiddy's Class operations are reported back into Zara financials. Zara had a remarkable performance in 2007. Zara sales have grown satisfactorily by 13% to &#x20AC;6.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Let me highlight that in local currencies and constant perimeter Zara sales have grown by 16%. Due to Zara's strong operating evolution EBIT has grown by 23% to &#x20AC;1.1 billion. This is equivalent to 17.8 on sales. Return on capital employed has also increased to 41%.</p>
          <p>The evolution of the younger concepts has also being satisfactory. Sales growth has been very strong across the board. Higher operating efficiencies have been obtained in a majority of them. EBIT growth has been remarkable at Pull and Bear, Massimo Dutti, Bershka and Stradivarius.</p>
          <p>In the case of Pull and Bear, sales have grown by 18% to &#x20AC;614 million and EBIT by 27% to &#x20AC;99 million. Massimo Dutti, sales have grown by 13% to &#x20AC;696 million, EBIT has grown by 31% to &#x20AC;106 million. Bershka, sales have grown by 16% to &#x20AC;925 million and EBIT by 17% to &#x20AC;154 million. Stradivarius sales have grown by 22% to &#x20AC;521 million and EBIT by 22% to &#x20AC;119 million.</p>
          <p>Over 2007 we have taken selected initiatives to accelerate expansion of both Oysho and Zara Home which have grown sales at 30% and 45% respectively. These extraordinary expansion initiatives create the base for further growth and the start up costing curve will be diluted over 2008.</p>
          <p>As I have mentioned, in 2007 Oysho sales have grown strongly by 30% to &#x20AC;213 million. Oysho has opened 89 stores in 2007 versus 47 in 2006. Due to this strong expansion EBIT has grown by 3% to &#x20AC;39 million. Let me point out that Oysho's EBIT margin on sales remains at a remarkable 19%.</p>
          <p>Over 2007, Zara Home sales increased in an outstanding manner, 45% to reach &#x20AC;201 million. In 2007, Zara Home has incurred the start-up cost related to the launch of its e-commerce operations. Due to this reason EBIT grows 1% to &#x20AC;18 million.</p>
          <p>As you can see in this chart, both EBIT margins and return on capital employed for Zara and the younger concepts have remained very strong over 2007.</p>
          <p>I am now handing over to Pablo for the outlook section.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>In this final section of the presentation, I would like to cover four main topics: first, to review our expansion plans both from an international and multi concept point of view; second, our plans to reinforce our unique business model; third, to examine our vision on Inditex's growth drivers for the period 2008-2010; and fourth, the outlook for the rest of 2008.</p>
          <p>Let me talk about the significant expansion plans of Inditex for the coming years. The main focus for our growth is the European market. As you know, we see Europe as our domestic market, an area in which we are expanding all our formats in a selective manner. We are following our focus expansion in Europe combining an accelerated pace in high growth markets with the expansion of all our formats across the region.</p>
          <p>We see significant potential to expand profitably in Europe for many years. In Western Europe, we contemplate a strong growth in markets like Italy and France. We also see significant opportunities in Eastern Europe and the Russian Federation.</p>
          <p>The second priority for Inditex is our expansion in Asia. We are currently operating 58 stores present in the majority of the key Asian capitals. The reception of our proposition in Asia has been very good due to the strong appetite for the latest fashions. Our plans remain to expand retail space in Asia at a rate that more than doubles the average for the group. Over 2007, our commercial surface in Asia grew by 32%.</p>
          <p>We see huge long-term potential for Inditex in Asian markets. Our main expansion markets in Asia are the following, in China our goals are to leverage on our current presence in the key areas of the country.</p>
          <p>Second, we plan to accelerate our expansion in Japan where we have now a consolidated presence and significant experience since we started operations in 1998.</p>
          <p>Third, we are opening our first stores in Korea in April. The expansion in these markets will be combined with selected openings in other Asian countries in which we are present already like Singapore, Thailand, Malaysia, Indonesia and the Philippines.</p>
          <p>And finally, our plans for the Americas are to build on the current presence with a selective expansion.</p>
          <p>Let me elaborate briefly, on some markets with strong growth potential. Our performance in the Italian market where we currently operate all our formats is ahead of expectations. In 2007, we have reached a total of 218 stores. We plan to keep on expanding significantly in Italy with all our concepts over 2008.</p>
          <p>In Russia, we have closed 2007 with 50 stores of 7 concepts. We plan to keep on expanding significantly in Russia over 2008 with 80 stores openings, both in the Moscow and Saint Petersburg areas and in the regional capitals.</p>
          <p>In China, we've closed 2007 with 15 stores in all key capitals, Shanghai, Beijing, Hong Kong, and Macau. Our plans are to leverage on our current presence in these key areas and to expand in other capital cities. We're highly pleased with our performance in the Chinese markets, and we expect a strong expansion in the country over the 2008-2010 period.</p>
          <p>We're also launching Zara in the highly interesting Korea market over 2008. We're opening five Zara stores in key locations of Seoul over the year, with the first store opening taking place in April. We plan to expand Zara significantly in Korea over the coming years.</p>
          <p>Following on our multi-concept growth strategy, a new accessories concept named Uterq&#xFC;e will be launched in the second half of 2008. We see substantial growth potential for Uterq&#xFC;e in a highly fragmented market. Our plan is to open 20 to 30 stores over 2008.</p>
          <p>As you all know, we've started an e-commerce initiative at Zara Home last October. The offer includes around 2,000 references and is available in 14 European countries. We're very pleased with the results of this launch, and we expect to keep on leveraging in our experience in e-commerce over the coming years.</p>
          <p>A key aspect of our strategy is to sustain the flexibility of our business model that combines design, manufacturing, logistics and retailing. Our priorities are to maintain our capacities to react swiftly to changes in demand, reduce lead times and minimize fashion risk. A balanced spilt between proximity sourcing and other origins remains key in this direction.</p>
          <p>Another significant feature of our expansion plans is that our logistic investments for future growth are already in place. Inditex has been making significant logistic investments over the period 2006-2008. The current logistic base is now scalable up to the year 2012.</p>
          <p>Let me now examine Inditex's key growth drivers in the 2008-2010 period. In terms of sales growth we continue to target like-for-like sales of around 4%. Additionally, we plan to increase the selling space by around 15% per annum. 90% of this new space will be added in international markets.</p>
          <p>In terms of use of cash flow, we continue to see capital expenditure to grow by around 7%, a rate which is half that of space growth. As a result, we expect Inditex to operate from a highly diversified sales platform by 2010 both from a geographical and multi concept point of view. Around 70% of our business will be in international markets. In parallel, Zara will be around 63% of sales and the younger concept around 37% of total.</p>
          <p>As you know, the optimization of our operations is a key part of our strategy. The Reduce 3 plan aims at improving the operational efficiency. Currently, some new initiatives are being developed to obtain medium to long-term improvements. Over 2006 and 2007 we have achieved good results in this direction.</p>
          <p>The spread between operating expenses growth and sales growth has been eliminated in the period. This initiative has markedly reduced the risk involved in the structure of our profit and loss account. For this reason 2008 will be the year of the consolidation of the Reduce 3 plan.</p>
          <p>We also want to provide our shareholders with a predictable and attractive remuneration policy. In March 2006, we announced a new shareholder remuneration policy. Since then and taking into account our current proposal, the dividend payment will more than double. In this direction the Board of Directors will propose a dividend for 2007 of 105 cents per share. This represents a 25% increase over 2006 levels.</p>
          <p>Regarding our expansion plans we expect to open 560 to 640 stores over 2008. We plan to launch stores in new markets like Korea, Ukraine, Egypt, and Montenegro over this year. We expect to add around 290,000 square meters to our retail space. I would like highlight that 85% of total space opened over 2008 will be in international markets. Our capital expenditure plans will reach &#x20AC;1 billion.</p>
          <p>Finally, let me tell you that during the beginning of first half 2008, sales performance is according to management expectations. Store sales in local currencies have increased by 17% from 1st of February to 23rd of March, 2008.</p>
          <p>And this is all from us. We are now ready for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> The first question comes from Mr. Luca Cipiccia from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you. Good morning. My first question is about the fourth-quarter growth. If you can explain or let us understand better why the contribution from new stores was so low assuming the, sort of, the like-for-like that you've given for the second half. I struggle to reconcile the overall growth that you've delivered taking out the like-for-like and calculating whereby the contribution to growth from the new stores, so if you could give us some more clarity there.</p>
          <p>And then a second question, if I may, just on the trends since the beginning of February, if you could to some extent quantify the contribution of the Easter calendar with this year to this overall growth. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, Luca. Regarding your first question you know that our mission is that the results should be analyzed on a seasonal basis. I mean it's the whole of the autumn-winter period. In that part of the year, we've delivered 15% sales growth; we had 3% like-for-like. If you look at the space contribution over the whole of the second half, you'll see that it is very much in line with a historical average of 80%. To look at the space contribution over a short period of time, a quarter, we believe is not the right way, but the space contribution, or the way that our stores are contributing to sales, remains very much in line with historical average.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Regarding your second question Luca, what I think is relevant to say because well, first of all, our six weeks or seven weeks periods in this case is just the very beginning of the year. What I think is relevant to say is that this beginning of the year is very much in line with our own expectations. And having in mind all the different calendar impacts in the beginning of the year, we think that this 17% store sales in local currencies reflects reasonably well our underlying performance in this beginning of the year. So we think that the calendar effects compensate each other.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; all right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Luca Solca from Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. Just wanted to ask you a question concerning the reinforcement of the Inditex business model and what actions are you planning to implement as far as to increase the speed of reaction and reduce the fashion risk within the business. What we have been seeing, talking for example to Asian suppliers, is that they are trying to improve their service levels and to reduce lead times. So very much interested to understand how you are going to keep ahead of the game.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We think -- first of all, what I would say is that our business model is unique from the point of view of this proximity production, and as we always say proximity means much more than a pure geographical proximity. It has a lot to do with the way we work with all these manufacturers that are included, with all these suppliers that are included in the concept of proximity production. This idea of flexibility of the business model, of ability to react, is absolutely key in our strategy. This is the reason why we maintain 50% of our production in proximity and of course, at the same time, in the Asian sourcing, we try to increase flexibility; we try to increase -- to improve lead times and everything.</p>
          <p>But the concept of proximity is much more than that. It is very deep integration between our company and all the suppliers that we have in Portugal, Morocco, and Spain. It is a very deep integration that has a lot to do, as I have mentioned several times, with the history of the company. The company was built like that with a very big level of integration with its suppliers, and it's something so, I would say, so intrinsic to the spirit of our company that I really think it is very unique.</p>
          <p>It is much more than reducing lead times. It is a very, very high level of integration with all our suppliers included in the concept of proximity. And as far as this is something which is very relevant for us, we continue working on that, I would say, permanently. And this is the reason why we continue maintaining 50% of our production in what we call proximity production. And when we think about from now in several years, within that we will continue maintaining this around 50% level of proximity production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Shifting gears, if I may. There's another point which I think is very sort of relevant at this stage, which is how you are seeing the Spanish consumer evolving and Spanish demand shaping up in the current month and in the near-term future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. First of all, what we can say that we can talk about our company, not about &#x2013; we prefer to talk about how are things going in our particular case. What we can say is that we are having positive like-for-like sales growth in Spain, which is I think something very relevant. Of course, this like-for-like sales growth is slightly below the average of the group, but that this logical as far as we have a very the long historical presence and a very deep penetration inside the Spanish market. But we have like -- positive like-for-like sales growth.</p>
          <p>And if we think about the market itself, what we can say is that we like very much the Spanish market. The Spanish market is very healthy. We know very well Spain. It is our domestic market, as you perfectly know. It is a market which remains fragmented in which there continue being a lot of opportunities, and we feel very comfortable operating in Spain in different consumption scenarios.</p>
          <p>So we are having positive like-for-like sales growth, and we are operating in Spain in a market which I repeat is a very healthy market for us, and we expect to continue having good performance in the Spanish market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much indeed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mrs. Claire Kent from Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everyone. Could I ask a couple of questions please? The first is with regards to the gross margin that you reported for last year, could you explain the developments between, say markdown, currency, bought in and just generally break it down for us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Claire, you have seen the gross margin evolution in the year has been very positive, 50 basis points to 56.7%. Obviously, to break down these 50 basis points into the different effects I believe is not relevant. What I believe is relevant to say is that the level of markdowns and the management of our inventory have been very similar to the previous year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question is, with regards to the growth you've seen in the first six weeks of the year, could you talk about how the different markets have evolved?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a very short period, and what we can tell you is what Pablo has stressed, that we're seeing good performance with this 17%. We have &#x2013; we believe that with this data we have adjusted all the numbers and it shows the operating performance. It's just the beginning of the year and we don't want to qualify this number further, but I believe it's encouraging.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But -- I mean, is there a big difference between the different regions, would you say?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is not very different; not very different.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the third thing is -- I may have misheard you, but did you say that 50% of production was in proximity markets? I thought that was meant to be 70%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it is -- you have that in the presentation. It's -- 50% is what we call proximity, then we have 15% -- one five, which is other European countries, mainly Turkey today, and then we have 35% which is Asian sourcing. And inside Asia a half of that is China, half of that is other Asian origins.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But basically the Asian part is sort of slowly creeping up by about 5% every year, isn't it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, but it's more or less the same. If you remember last year considering the average for the global figure for the year, in the year 2006 it was 34; this year it's 35. It's around the same levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; thanks for your help.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Fraser Ramzan from Lehman Brothers. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. Just one question, I guess, right now. In terms of your cost growth, just looking at the performance between staff, rents and other, it seems like a large part of the kind of the success of Reduce 3 has been in the other cost areas. I appreciate that costs may be growing at different -- at a different pace in different concepts, but could you give us some kind of assurance that in the more mature concepts, staff costs and rental costs are not growing as aggressively as the total for group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think you can feel very comfortable with the cost growth evolution. I mean, of course, there are three main lines of cost as you know. It's a rental expenses, personnel expenses and other operating expenses and globally there is nothing strange in the evolution of any part of our costs. Of course, it has to do with many different matters, with growth in many different counties. But globally, I think you can feel a quite comfortable with the evolution of cost growth. I don't know Antonio if you want to elaborate a little bit more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our Reduce 3 plan is not only concentrated in a single line of the profit or loss account. One of the reasons why we called it Reduce 3 is that we wanted to focus in the three key lines of profit or loss account about operational cost. We are spreading initiatives not only in Zara, not only in Spain. We are expanding in the plan in all our formats, in all our divisions.</p>
          <p>We are satisfied about the performance of the plan during the last two years, but our target is not only for these next three years, but to change the culture of the company and in all the process from the budget to the final performance, to establish the clear area in the company that the operational cost can not grow above the level of the sales growth. It's related to many small initiatives in some cases about the consolidation of the initiative of the &#x2013; as I suggest before, to expand the initiative from Zara or from Spain to other formats or to other regions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But the do you think you can do more, for example, on staff? Because, I guess staff cost did grow ahead of local currency sales which seems bit of a surprise given that it is all on three lines, as you say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it is not significant, the evolution in relation of sale. In any case, we are increasing the number of initiatives for -- be more efficient in terms of our personnel expenses at the store level, at the logistics level and any new investment in technology in logistics has savings associated to be more efficient about our personnel cost. But the evolution is completely normal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But the medium-term initiatives would be focused on that area, would they?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps, what I would like to say is that what I think is remarkable and we were talking about that in the presentation, is that we have changed the risk profile of our profit and loss account since we implemented the Reduce 3 plan. If you remember costs were growing 300 basis points above sales and we have changed dramatically well, or very significantly the risk profile of our profit and loss account. Three years ago, we were talking about deleverage of our profitability and today we are seeing that our EBIT margins are increasing in a significant manner. I think that is -- and at the same time maintaining a very high rate of expansion. I know it is because we're continue growing our space at a 15% rate. So, I think that is what is remarkable.</p>
          <p>And of course about the initiatives, there are initiatives everywhere. But I think we have always talked about these when we were talking about the Reduce 3 plan that we always &#x2013; we want to think about &#x2013; we have always thought about the Reduce 3 plan much more like efficiency plan than as a pure cost reduction plan. And for us it is very, very relevant to maintain in that principle. And of course, it is very easy to cut costs if you only think about cutting costs, no? But at that the same time, we always have in mind short-term, medium-term, long-term. So, what we are trying to do is to gain efficiency in all the different areas of our activity and to contribute to the long-term evolution of our business, no?</p>
          <p>And of course there are initiatives in the three lines of costs and there will continue being initiatives in the three lines of costs. In the three of them personnel expenses, rental expenses and other operating expenses. We'll continue seeing room to increase the efficiency but what is remarkable is that maintaining a huge rate of expansion. We have been able to eliminate the 300 basis points gap.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mrs. Anne Critchlow from SG. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning. It's Anne Critchlow from SG. I'd just like to ask a question about the gross margin, going back to that. It seems to have been up 19 basis points in Q3 and then down 20 basis points in Q4. Why did it change? What was the swing around? Was it due to pricing or markdowns or input costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, Anne, I believe that the gross margin evolution should be looked upon a six months basis, right? And in that field, you have to also remember that we have a very strong comparable in gross margin coming from the previous year. We have a very strong increase in the fourth quarter gross margin. But again the right way to look at it is over six months because we make decisions all over the &#x2013; all over the decision. What is important to stress is that the level of the markdowns is very similar to last year. No significant changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And could I ask a further question please about logistics? And I think you'd spoke before about a separate logistics platform in Asia, possibly needed from around 2010. Are you still considering this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we have said is that well, first of all what I would like to say is that with our logistic investment plan, that is taking place in the years 2006-2008 with the new logistic platform in Madrid, in Meco, with the enlargement of the Zaragoza one, with a new one in Barcelona for Bershka with a new one in Le&#xF3;n with our -- with this logistic plan that is implemented, developed in the years 2006 to 2008 we have enough logistic capacity until the year 2012 having in mind our growth plans. This is something very relevant to say because we are building for the future.</p>
          <p>And then about the possibility of a logistic platform in Asia, it is something that we do not exclude. That is something that is not going to take place in the short-term and what we have always said is that around the year 2010 is when we should begin to consider seriously that possibility. If I said today that we have enough logistic capacity until the year 2012, if we want to build additional logistic capacity thinking about the year 2012 and the following years, is something we should begin to decide around the year 2010. And it will have a lot to do with the growth of our presence in the Asian markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Isikiro Yamaguchi from UBS. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. Actually it's Matthew Taylor at UBS. I wonder if I can ask a question about the Venezuela subsidiary move to franchise basis. Did you say in the call that this had the effect of reducing sales by 2% or was that just the mix of sales that it affected?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is -- what we were saying in the call is that the combined impact of currency and franchising of the Venezuelan operations represents two points. So, it's more or less one point each of the impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The one point is currency and one point is Venezuela.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that was biased towards the second half, yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, in the second half, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, potentially a 2% effect from Venezuela on the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No one from Venezuela, one from currency.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, so I'm talking about the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it 1% over the full year but weighted to the second half, yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes. That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So when we look at the contribution from new space of 12%, I mean should we bear that in mind?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no. When we think about the contribution of 12% coming from new space, you should have in mind that the average &#x2013; well the space growth has been 16% but having in mind the calendar impact, the average space growth has been 14.5%. So, this translates into a 12% contribution in terms of space contribution.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see. Sorry, so -- it's combined with the currency impact is it then, when you report the breakdown in sales growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you repeat your question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Just looking at the effect of this Venezuela change, is that included in your comments on the currency movement or is it taken out of the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, in the -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...change in local currencies?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...it's in the currency and perimeter impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, got you. All right, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Frederic Danshwa from Brenner Noram. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Brevan Howard. Hello everybody. Just a very quick one for you. You seemed to outperform a lot competition in Spain in the beginning of '08. And according to my calculation, your like-for-like contribution for the group has even increased for the first eight weeks versus the fourth quarter, which is very impressive. So, the question is, do you think there is a increasing polarization between the mega brand like yourself and Hennes &amp; Mauritz in the marketplace and maybe the smaller player? So, how do you explain basically the out-performance of Inditex? So, that's the first question.</p>
          <p>And second question is on stock. It seems that your stock increased a bit faster than sales. And I was wondering if you could also elaborate on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Regarding Spain, is difficult to talk about the facts in such a short period of time. To talk about quarters I believe is not relevant. Over the long-term, we definitely believe that we have the capacity to increase market share in Spain. No doubt due to the fragmentation I've discussed in the case over the last years. So, we prefer not to enter into the quarterly performance because we believe it is not relevant.</p>
          <p>Regarding the stock growth of 22%, you know that our view has always been that the inventory position is not the relevant measure of your commitment, right? And again, our commitment remains very much inline with historical average and still with a lot of a capacity to make changes our decision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand that it's not relevant to look at it on what eight weeks, but still I mean most of your competitors saw a great deterioration in their performance this year basically and if my calculations are right, you are not seeing that at all, which is quite amazing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we are saying is that we have a positive like-for-like in Spain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Congratulations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Nick Farm from SBS Golder. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good day. This is Nick Farm from SEB Enskilda in Stockholm. I'm also going to ask you on the sourcing and inflation in the sourcing chain. Some competitors have actually suggested that there may be falling prices in Asian sourcing in the second half of this year? Could you care to give a comment on that and possible also quantify what you expect will happen to your average input price per item in this year? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Well, first of all what we can say about our sourcing is that in -- I am thinking about potential inflation or deflation in any particular market. Well, first of all that our sourcing platform is very, very diversified. Now, we have this 50% proximity production then we have a little bit more than one-third of our sourcing in Asia. And when we think about our Asian sourcing, we are never trying to find at the cheapest supplier in any particular country. We always try to have long-term relations with our suppliers in order to have quality, in order to have well -- for our suppliers to be in line with our code of conduct. So what we try always is to have long-term relations with our suppliers. So, from that point of view, we have not seen any very relevant change until now. And we are not expecting any relevant change from the point of view of pricing during the year. Of course, there are always adjustments in any particular market, but nothing serious and nothing with an impact in our global profit and loss account.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mrs. (sic) Tony Shiret from Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Mister actually. Good morning. My question is about Reduce 3. I sort of noted your comment in the presentation that you're looking for a year of consolidation in Reduce 3, and I just really wanted to know exactly what you meant by that because you also referred to long-term initiatives. I mean, does that mean that Reduce 3 per se is not going to give any sort of incremental cost savings this year and we are just going to see the build out of previous ones?</p>
          <p>And if you sort of take that analysis and given that your &#x2013; 85% of your openings are in high cost overseas territory, should we expect OpEx to go up at a faster rate than sales growth this year?</p>
          <p>And just as a subtext to that, you also mentioned your long-term like-for-like sales growth rate target of 4%, I mean presumably in 2008, you're expecting that to be somewhat lower. Can you quantify that as well? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. What I would say about the term consolidation is that as far as the Reduce 3 plan from the beginning has been a three years plan, in this year we have not established a new target. So, we are not expecting at all OpEx growth to be higher than sales growth in the year 2008. So, we are not expecting at all a deterioration of our performance from this point of view, but we have not established a new target and we think it is very, very relevant this idea of the consolidation of all the -- I would say of this change in the -- in the profile of our profit and loss account. So, this is what we mean by consolidation. Of course, there are...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You just mean annualization do you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, you mean annualization -- the existing of initiatives you put in previously, is that what you mean by consolidation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't understand very well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no what we mean is that we expect a structural evolution of costs, never above sales growth. This is what we're trying to do and this is what we mean by the consolidation of this policy into our profit and loss account. There are still initiatives to be carried out over 2008, but as Pablo mentioned, we don't expect under any circumstance that operating expenses will grow above sales and this...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In 2008 or ever?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>8 and obviously looking forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, how are you going to do that then, given that 85% of your sales, your space growth is going to be in higher cost territories?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. What we've been able to do is to reduce, to eliminate this 300-basis points gap, that could look very, very difficult from the beginning. So, they...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Well, let's put it another way: why are you so inefficient now then?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why -- sorry, I don't understand your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if you've got so much cost that you can take out now; doesn't that imply that you're very inefficient now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We wouldn't say that we're very inefficient now. What we could say is that, from the moment in which we've focused our company in these efficiencies since the implementation of the Reduce 3 plan, we've been able to continue growing in many different markets, to continue maintaining this 15% space growth and to eliminate this gap between OpEx growth and sales growth. So, and of course, we will always try to continue gaining efficiency in all our activities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay moving on; the like-for-like assumption for 2008?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding that, your second question, what I would say is that, at this stage of the year, we do not see any reason why to think about a different like-for-like target than 4% for the full year 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Robert Miller from Redburn Partners. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Can I ask about the payout ratio which is -- is the same as last year and when I go back to your original discussion about the balance sheet, Pablo you were targeting a -- a four quarter average a neutral balance sheet and I estimate that on a four quarter basis, you've got average net cash of over &#x20AC;700 million. So why are you not increasing the payout ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you are right. The average cash position is around &#x20AC;700 million and we are distributing &#x20AC;652 million. So it is more or less the average of the year. Now, what we think is remarkable is that since we changed our dividend policy, we have more than doubled the dividend. Now in this year, the increase is 25% and what the Board of Directors is proposing to the shareholders meeting is a 25% increase, which is inline with the evolution of the net income and which is very much inline with the average net cash position during the year.</p>
          <p>Thinking about the future, we continue maintaining our policy. Our policy is to have a neutral balance sheet to -- of course, our first priority always is to invest in the long-term expansion of our business. But at the same time, as we were saying during the presentation, we are expecting that CapEx growth will be significantly below space growth in the coming years, as we were saying during the presentation. And we are generating a significant amount of cash and we plan to -- our idea is to maintain this neutrality of our balance sheet, having in mind always the average cash position during the year, not the cash position at one particular moment. We think that this dividend proposal is very much inline with the dividend strategy that we announced two years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How can it be inline when the average net cash position is rising and you were targeting a neutral balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think it's very -- the difference is very small, between &#x2013; you were mentioning &#x20AC;700 million average net cash position, we are distributing 650, it is more or less the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I though the target was a four quarter zero net debt, net cash position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it was a full year. We always have talked about -- we always have talked about the average net cash position during the year, not in one particular quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. But the average is over the four-quarter period is &#x20AC;700 million, you're a long way above that and given your working capital model and the fact your CapEx is rising at half the pace of our space, you're going to be generating a lot more cash in future, so why are you running with an inefficient balance sheet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We think it's not inefficient right now and we are investing &#x20AC;1 billion, we are distributing &#x20AC;650 million in dividends, which is very much inline with the average net cash position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes and Robert, I believe that in your calculation you are probably not taking into account the dividend payment that took place on the 1st of August, right? So don't look just at the reported cash at the end of every quarter. If you look at that and you adjust it by that you will see that the average is very much the same. On the other hand, regarding an inefficient balance sheet, keep in mind that our return on capital employed is 43%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We will talk about that later, Marcos, maybe, but can I also ask on the sales number. Can you just clear one thing up for me? This sales number that you talked about for the current period, is that comparing the same number of trading days or have you benefited in that figure from the 29th of February?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe that we have provided the number which is perfectly reflects the operating performance because it includes obviously, the effect of the one extra day of trading in February, but it also includes the negative impact coming from the obviously, the holidays of Maundy Thursday and Good Friday and Easter. So, you have the positive and the negative, so it's fully comparable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the -- did the year-end stock position suggest that you had a bit more clearance work to do in February than you did last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No; we have already answered that and not at all. The markdown activity has been very similar to last year. And again, the inventory does not reflect the commitment, and the commitment remains the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Richard Chamberlain from JP Morgan. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Hi ,guys. Just got a question on one of the formats. Oysho, the lingerie format: just wondered if you can talk about the outlook for the Spanish lingerie market this year. And why you are choosing to ramp-up the opening so far given that the returns now seem to be under a bit of pressure for that format.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the contrary, what we believe is that Oysho returns are very strong, 39%. And keep in mind that the EBIT margin is still very high, 19%. The expansion is not just in Spain; it's in all relevant markets. We have a lot of trust in Oysho and this why we're speeding up now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In any case, you can say that the openings that we are planning for Oysho, two-thirds of them are international.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. And can you try and quantify the currency impact on operating expenses in the fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you know, we prefer not to get into that on a quarterly basis. You have to look at it on six months. And what we believe is that the way we have managed operating expenses this year is very strong, and as a result EBIT has grown by 100 basis points. In any case, in any case the impact of that is around 1%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; right; okay. And just quickly, just a question on Asia the -- in terms of sort of maturity curve of those stores, are they sort of ramping up as fast as the other openings internationally?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say even more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Even quicker.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes; even quicker.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. So you are sort of -- the reason why your space contribution, I guess, is reverting back to historic average is just -- we have just had a sort of period of super normal growth, have we?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, but you should look to the global figure, no, because it is -- of course, in the question about Asia they are ramping up very, very quickly, you know. But it's always better to look to the global -- I could also tell you that in Russia, they are also ramping up extremely quickly, but it's always a combination of many different countries, many different openings, no?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure; sure; okay. All right; thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Fraser Ramzan from Lehman Brothers. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi again. Sorry; just one quick follow-up. Could you tell me what your average selling prices did in the first and second half last year? And also what you might anticipate for this year currently and for the first half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Stable; in general terms, stable. So like-for-like growth is volume driven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For both the first and second half constant --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, first and second half from beginning of this year. Globally, it's stable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay; thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>&gt;: Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Mr. Michael Kay from Citi. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Can you tell me what the percentage of OpEx is in Spain given that 37% of your revenues are in your local market and all your central costs are in Spain as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously, we don't preferring to enter into this kind of breakdown. What is clear that in Spain, as we have been operating for many years, our operating expenses are tightly under control and growing on a like-for-like basis slightly below the average.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we have last -- we have time for two more questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so the next question comes from Mr. Isikiro Yamaguchi from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry; once again it's Matthew Taylor. Could you just give me &#x2013; were there are any special factors behind the expansion of the Zara EBIT margin, 130 basis points against 40 basis points for the group? Any special factors behind that? I'm especially thinking about t the integration of Kiddy's Class into the numbers there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think what we can say about Zara is that the performance has been extremely good all across the different countries. That is the reason why the EBIT margin growth has been even higher. Globally, if you see the global figures, what is remarkable inside this 100-basis-points EBIT margin growth in the year is that in the case of Zara it is particularly remarkable but also combining the different formats, they also have increased their EBIT margin. I think that is what is remarkable that the increase in the EBIT margin has taken place in Zara and in all the other formats together. In the case of Zara it has to do with a very good operating performance all across the different geographies. There isn't any particular factor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And regarding Kiddy's there is no real impact as we have reported both together -- as Pablo mentioned it's a very much included really it has just performed very much in line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the last question comes from Mr. Robert Miller from Redburn Partners. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, Matthew just asked my question, so you're off the hook guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Okay. So, thank you very much to all of you. And of course, we'll continue being ready to keep in touch with you to clarify any aspect that you would like. Thank you very much for attending this conference call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>This concludes our conference call. Thank you for attending. Good bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>