<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1240179" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>284</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Louise Mehrotra, Vice President, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Dominic J. Caruso, Vice President, Finance and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3">Michael Weinstein</participant>
      <participant id="4">Bruce Nudell</participant>
      <participant id="5">Tao Levy</participant>
      <participant id="6">Larry Biegelsen</participant>
      <participant id="7">Frederick Wise</participant>
      <participant id="8">Matthew Dodds</participant>
      <participant id="9">David Lewis</participant>
      <participant id="10">Matt Miksic</participant>
      <participant id="11">Glenn Novarro</participant>
      <participant id="12">Sara Michelmore</participant>
      <participant id="13">Robert Hopkins</participant>
      <participant id="14">Derrick Sung</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome to the Johnson &amp; Johnson Second Quarter 2009 Earnings Conference Call. All participants will be able to listen only until the question-and-answer session of the conference. This call is being recorded. If anyone has any objections, you may disconnect at this time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference call over to Johnson &amp; Johnson. You may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and welcome. I'm Louise Mehrotra, Vice President of Investor Relations for Johnson &amp; Johnson, and it is my pleasure this morning to review our business results for the second quarter of 2009. Joining me on the call today is Dominic Caruso, Vice President, Finance and Chief Financial Officer.</p>
          <p>A few logistics before we get into the details. This review is being made available to a broader audience via a webcast, accessible through the Investor Relations section of the Johnson &amp; Johnson website. I'll begin by briefly reviewing highlights of the second quarter for the corporation and highlights for our three business segments. Following my remarks, Dominic will provide some additional commentary on the second quarter financial results, an update on the many positive developments in the quarter and guidance for the full year of 2009. We will then open the call to your questions. We expect the call to last approximately one hour.</p>
          <p>Included with the press release that was sent to the investment community earlier this morning is a schedule showing sales for the major products and/or business franchises to facilitate updating your models. These are also available on the Johnson &amp; Johnson website as is the press release.</p>
          <p>Before I get into the results, let me remind you that some of the statements made during this call may be considered forward-looking statements. The 10-K for the fiscal year 2008 identifies certain factors that could cause the company's actual results to differ materially from those projected in any forward-looking statements made this morning. The company does not undertake to update any forward-looking statements as a result of new information or future events or developments. The 10-K is available through the company or online.</p>
          <p>Last item, during the call, non-GAAP financial measures may be used to provide information pertinent to ongoing business performance. These measures are reconciled to the GAAP measures and are available in the press release or on the Johnson &amp; Johnson website.</p>
          <p>Now, I would like to review our results for the second quarter of 2009. If you would refer to your copy of the press release, let's begin with the schedule titled Supplementary Sales Data by Geographic Area. Worldwide sales to customers were $15.2 billion for the second quarter of 2009, down 7.4% as compared to the second quarter of 2008. On an operational basis, sales were down 1.4% and currency had a negative impact of 6%.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., Sales declined 6.7%. Outside the U.S., our operational growth was 3.9%, while the effect of currency exchange rates negatively impacted our reported results by 11.9 points. The Western Hemisphere excluding the U.S. grew 11.7% on an operational basis. The Asia-Pacific Africa region grew by 3.7% operationally, while Europe grew 1.8% operationally.</p>
          <p>If you will now turn to the Consolidated Statement of Earnings, net earnings on a reported basis were $3.2 billion and earnings per share were $1.15. This compares to $3.3 billion and $1.17 in the same period in 2008. Please direct your attention to the box section of the schedule, where we have provided adjusted earnings information.</p>
          <p>As referenced in the footnote, the 2008 results have been adjusted to exclude the after-tax impact of the in-process research and development charge of $40 million. There were no adjustments to the results for the second quarter of 2009. Net earnings on an adjusted basis were down 4.7% and adjusted earnings per share were down 2.5%. I would now like to make some additional comments relative to the components leading to adjusted earnings before we move on to the segment highlights.</p>
          <p>Cost of goods sold at 29.2% of sales was 30 basis points higher than the same period in 2008 due to unfavorable mix in our Pharmaceutical business, partially offset by cost containment initiatives across the businesses. Selling, marketing and administrative expenses at 31.5% of sales were down 200 basis points versus last year, driven by leverage across the businesses. Our investment in research and development as a percent of sales was 10.7%, 80 basis points less than the second quarter of 2008 due to a change in the mix of the businesses and reductions in spending levels.</p>
          <p>Interest expense net of interest income of $85 million compares to $16 million in the second quarter of 2008. The increase in net expense was due primarily to lower interest rates on our cash balances. Other expense net of other income was $6 million in the second quarter of 2009 compared to $135 million of net other income in the same period last year. Dominic will provide more commentary in his remarks.</p>
          <p>Taxes were 24.7% in the second quarter of 2009 versus 23.7% in the second quarter of 2008, reflecting the change in the mix of the businesses.</p>
          <p>Turning now to business segment highlights, please refer to the supplementary sales schedule highlighting major products or business franchises. I'll begin with the Consumer segment. Worldwide Consumer segment sales for the second quarter of 2009 of $3.9 billion decreased 4.5% as compared to the same period last year. On an operational basis, sales increased 3.1% while the impact of currency was negative 7.6 points. U.S. sales were up 0.8% while international sales grew 4.7% on an operational basis.</p>
          <p>For the second quarter of 2009, sales for the over-the-counter Pharmaceuticals and Nutritionals increased 0.3% on an operational basis compared to the same period in 2008 with similar results both in and outside of the U.S. Intensified competitive pressures including private label have impacted the growth in this category.</p>
          <p>Our Skin Care business achieved operational sales growth of 5.9% in the second quarter of 2009 with sales in the U.S. growing at 8.4% and sales outside the U.S. up 3.8% on an operational basis. Growth was driven by AVEENO with the launch of Nourish+ Hair Care line in the U.S., NEUTROGENA and by our Dabao products acquired in the third quarter last year.</p>
          <p>Baby Care products were down 2.2% on an operational basis when compared to the second quarter of 2008. Sales in the U.S. were down 6.3%, primarily due to lower sales for BabyCenter.com. BabyCenter has exited the online retail business and will focus on online content. Sales outside the U.S. were down 1.2% operationally with growth in Hair care and Powder offset by softness in other categories, primarily Lotions and Creams.</p>
          <p>Women's Health achieved operational sales growth of 4.8%. Sales in the U.S. were down 3.8% due to lower sales of napkins and family planning products. Sales outside the U.S. were up on an operational basis by 8.8% due to the acquisition of the Vania products.</p>
          <p>Operational sales growth in the Oral Care franchise was 2.4%. In the U.S., sales were down 5.9% due to softness in the category. Sales outside the U.S. increased 9.5% operationally, driven by strong growth for LISTERINE.</p>
          <p>Sales in the Wound Care/Other category were up 15.7% on an operational basis due to the recent acquisitions in Wellness &amp; Prevention and the Vania acquisition. That completes our review of the Consumer segment, and I'll now review highlights for the Pharmaceutical segment.</p>
          <p>Worldwide net sales for the second quarter of $5.5 billion were down 13.3% versus the same period last year. On an operational basis, sales were down 8.5% with a currency impact of negative 4.8 points. Sales in the U.S. decreased 16.4%, while sales outside the U.S. increased on an operational basis by 3.3%.</p>
          <p>Our results continue to be impacted by generic competition on some of our products namely RISPERDAL Oral, RAZADYNE, and TOPAMAX. The marketing exclusivity for RISPERDAL expired in the U.S. at the end of June, 2008 and there are generic competitors for RISPERDAL in most markets. The marketing exclusivity for TOPAMAX expired at the end of March this year and multiple generics have entered the market while generic competitors for RAZADYNE entered the U.S. market in the latter half of 2008.</p>
          <p>The combined impact of these three products has reduced the second quarter worldwide Pharmaceutical operational growth rate by approximately 17 points, with the U.S. impact estimated at over 25 points and the impact outside the U.S. estimated at 2.5 points. Excluding the impact of generic competition on these products, worldwide operational sales growth was approximately 9%.</p>
          <p>Now reviewing the major products. Sales of REMICADE, a biologic approved for the treatment of a number of immune mediated inflammatory diseases, were up 24.4% when compared to the second quarter of 2008. Sales growth in the U.S. was 12.7% due to strong market growth. Sales to our customers for markets outside the U.S. were up over 60%. As we previously mentioned, the second quarter 2008 sales included a significant inventory reduction due to inventory planning on our customers' part. Excluding the impact of inventory changes in both periods, sales outside the U.S. were estimated to have grown approximately 16%.</p>
          <p>PROCRIT/EPREX declined operationally by 6% during the quarter, as compared to the same quarter last year, with PROCRIT down 4.6% and EPREX down 7.6% operationally. A softening of the market has contributed to the lower sales results for EPREX. PROCRIT results have been impacted by a decline in the market versus the second quarter of 2008, estimated at 9%, partially offset by an increase in overall market share. PROCRIT aggregate share across all markets was approximately 49% in the second quarter of 2009, up five points versus the same period last year.</p>
          <p>Sales of LEVAQUIN, our anti-infective, were up 4.1% on an operational basis when compared to the same period a year ago. The U.S. anti-infective market in terms of scripts is estimated to be flat in the quarter. LEVAQUIN dollar share was up in the quarter on both a sequential basis and versus second quarter 2008.</p>
          <p>RISPERDAL CONSTA, our long-acting injectable formulation, achieved second-quarter sales growth of 12.1% on an operational basis. U.S. sales growth was 9.2% while sales outside the U.S. were up 13.7% operationally driven by increased share.</p>
          <p>CONCERTA, a product for attention deficit hyperactivity disorder, grew 18.7% operationally in the second quarter as compared to the same period last year with sales in the U.S. up 12% due in part to strong market growth. Sales outside the U.S. were up 38% operationally with strong growth seen across the major regions.</p>
          <p>ACIPHEX, as it's known in the U.S. market and PARIET outside the U.S., is a proton pump inhibitor or PPI that we co-market with Eisai. On an operational basis, sales were down 13.3% with U.S. sales down 16.3% and sales outside the U.S. down 10.6% operationally. In the U.S., growth was impacted by the relative strength of the second quarter 2008. Dollar share in the second quarter was the same in both periods. Sales outside the U.S. have been impacted by the market entry in Canada of generic rabeprazole, the active ingredient in PARIET, and reimbursement pressure for the PPI category in Russia.</p>
          <p>VELCADE, a treatment for multiple myeloma, is being co-developed with Millennium Pharmaceuticals. We have commercialization rights in Europe and the rest of the world outside the U.S. Operational sales growth was strong at 26.2%, driven by the additional approval last year for first-line therapy.</p>
          <p>PREZISTA, a protease inhibitor for the treatment of HIV, grew operationally 71% with the U.S. growing 51.2%, and sales outside the U.S. growing 90%. Expanded labeling to include treatment-na&#xEF;ve patients contributed to the continued positive momentum and share.</p>
          <p>INVEGA, our newest atypical antipsychotic, grew operationally 36.6% with the U.S. growing 8.1%. Sales outside the U.S. grew over 160%, driven by steady progress in market share growth.</p>
          <p>Wrapping up the review of the Pharmaceutical segment, as an update on the status of the rivaroxaban complete response, we met with the FDA in June to review our initial proposal to address their questions. Additional meetings with the FDA are planned this summer to agree our next steps to address the points raised in the complete response letter. The outcome of these discussions will be a key determinant in establishing the timeline for the submission of our complete response. Consequently, we do not expect to submit our response until the fourth quarter of this year at the earliest. We plan to provide an update on the progress during the third quarter analyst meeting in October.</p>
          <p>In the quarter, the FDA also approved the supplemental new drug applications for the use of RISPERDAL CONSTA, as both monotherapy and adjunctive therapy in the maintenance treatment of Bipolar I Disorder, and in Japan, the marketing authorization for RISPERDAL CONSTA was granted.</p>
          <p>I'll now review the Medical Devices and Diagnostics segment results. Worldwide Medical Devices and Diagnostics segment sales of $5.9 billion grew 2.9% operationally as compared to the same period in 2008. Currency had a negative impact of six points, resulting in total sales decline of 3.1%. Sales in the U.S. were up 1.9%, while sales outside the U.S. increased on an operational basis by 3.7%. Results have been impacted by lower sales of drug-eluting stents. Sales excluding the impact of lower sales of drug-eluting stents grew nearly 6% operationally.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the franchises, starting with Cordis. Cordis sales were down 12.6% operationally with U.S. down 23.2% and sales outside the U.S. down 5.5% operationally. Cordis results were impacted by lower sales of CYPHER, our sirolimus-eluting stent, partially offset by the solid growth in our Biosense Webster business. CYPHER sales were approximately $235 million, down 38% on an operational basis versus the prior year. Sales in the U.S. of approximately $70 million were down 59%.</p>
          <p>In comparison to the second quarter of 2008, the U.S. drug-eluting stent market growth is estimated at 2%. Penetration rates are estimated at 74%, up from 66% a year ago. The estimated price for CYPHER in the U.S. is down approximately 5% versus the second quarter of 2008. Estimated share in the U.S. of 14% was down one point sequentially and down 23 points from the second quarter of 2008 due to the market entry of two new competitors in 2008.</p>
          <p>Sales outside the U.S. of approximately $165 million declined 23% operationally. The estimated market share in the quarter of 27% was down two points on a sequential basis and down three points from the second quarter of 2008. Increased competition has impacted the share outside the U.S. CYPHER estimated worldwide share for the second quarter was 22%, down one point sequentially and down 11 points from the second quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Biosense Webster, our electrophysiology business, achieved 11% operational growth in the quarter, due to the strong performance of both specialty diagnostic and therapeutic catheters.</p>
          <p>The Neurovascular business, previously reported in our Cordis franchise, and the Codman business that is part of our DePuy franchise have been combined to form a global neuroscience business that is now reported in the DePuy franchise. A schedule of 2008 results by quarter reflecting this structure is available on our website, and the 2009 comparisons reflect the new reporting in both periods.</p>
          <p>Our DePuy franchise had operational growth of 6% when compared to the same period in 2008, with the U.S. growing 5.5% and the business outside the U.S. growing by 6.5% operationally. Pressure on pricing has increased as a result of the economic trends. However positive mix has mitigated much of the impact.</p>
          <p>Hip growth on a worldwide basis was approximately 5% operational with the U.S. growth at approximately 6%, and the growth outside the U.S. at 3% on an operational basis. On an operational basis, worldwide knee growth was approximately 4%, with the U.S. up 5% and outside the U.S., up 2%. Spine achieved strong operational growth of approximately 11%, due to the successful launch of a number of products. Similar results were achieved both in the U.S. and outside the U.S.</p>
          <p>Mitek, our sports medicine business, grew approximately 10% operationally, with the U.S. growth at 11% and growth outside the U.S. at 9%. The Diabetes franchise was down 3.7% operationally in the second quarter of 2009 with the U.S. business down 9.5%. While the market in terms of volume stabilized in the second quarter, pressure on pricing continued. Outside the U.S., sales increased 2.2% operationally.</p>
          <p>Animas, our insulin pump business, grew nearly 30% on an operational basis, due to new product launches and continued development of the international market.</p>
          <p>Ethicon worldwide sales grew operationally by 9.7%, with the U.S. up 20.9% and sales outside the U.S. up 3.2% operationally. The acquisitions of Mentor and Omrix, partially offset by the divestiture of the Professional Wound Care business, added approximately 5.5 points to the worldwide operational growth. Sales in the U.S. for our newly acquired aesthetics products from Mentor were in line with 2008. On a worldwide basis, double-digit growth was achieved in biosurgicals, meshes and women's health.</p>
          <p>Ethicon Endo-Surgery achieved operational growth of 6.3% in the second quarter of 2009, with the U.S. sales growing 1% and sales outside the U.S. growing on an operational basis by 10.7%. HARMONIC technology business achieved strong double-digit operational growth due to the global success of recently launched products and the underlying strength of this platform. Additionally in the U.S., strong growth for the REALIZE Gastric Band and the newly acquired EnSeal products contributed to the results.</p>
          <p>This was partially offset by lower sales in the U.S. for Advanced Sterilization Products, or ASP, which had been impacted by tighter capital budgets in the hospitals. Outside the U.S., in addition to the HARMONIC technology mentioned earlier, strong contributors to growth were endoscopy products and ASP products.</p>
          <p>Ortho Clinical Diagnostics achieved operational growth of 9.2% in the second quarter. Sales growth in the U.S. was 13.6%, while sales outside the U.S. were up 4.2% on an operational basis. The launch of the VITROS 5600 and 3600 made strong contributions to the worldwide results this quarter. Also contributing to the growth in the U.S. were the strong results for donor screening.</p>
          <p>Rounding out the review for the Medical Devices and Diagnostics segment, our Vision Care franchise achieved operational sales growth of 1.9% in the second quarter compared with the same period last year. Sales in the U.S. increased 1.8%. Sales outside the U.S. increased 2% on an operational basis.</p>
          <p>The lens market overall is estimated to be flat to down slightly compared to the same period last year. Estimated worldwide market share was in line with the same period last year and up two points on a sequential basis. Despite the softness in the market, ACUVUE OASYS, 1-Day ACUVUE MOIST, and the ACUVUE OASYS for Astigmatism achieved strong double-digit growth.</p>
          <p>That completes highlights for the Medical Devices and Diagnostics segment and concludes the segment highlights for Johnson &amp; Johnson's second quarter of 2009. I'll now turn the call over to Dominic Caruso. Dominic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Louise and good morning everyone.</p>
          <p>As you know, this was one of the most challenging quarters for year-over-year comparisons in our history, but this was expected and accounted for in our plans. We saw significant impact to our second quarter results from the loss of U.S. market exclusivity for RISPERDAL and TOPAMAX as expected. We are very pleased with our solid operational results this quarter, which were better than expected and reflect the actions we've taken to mitigate the economic and near-term pressures on our business.</p>
          <p>As I have said many times before, the people of Johnson &amp; Johnson always manage the business very well and always rise to any challenge. And this quarter was certainly no exception, as the efforts of our talented and dedicated people are reflected in our results, exceeding even our own expectations. We continue to implement plans to deal with the business and macroeconomic pressures of 2009 and we are making prudent investments that will grow our business for the long-term.</p>
          <p>In my remarks today, I would like to walk you through some additional points about the quarterly results, discuss some of the recent positive developments and investments we have made in the business and provide a few updates to our guidance for full-year 2009.</p>
          <p>When we met with you in January, we outlined several factors that would influence our 2009 business performance and those continue playing out much as we expected. As we have indicated before, the economic environment continues to create tighter consumer spending and increase constraints on some health care spending. This has been reflected in lower sales again this quarter for some of our consumer products where we saw slower growth in certain markets, some increased private label competition and some lower levels of retail inventories.</p>
          <p>Despite those trends, we continue to see solid performances in our skin care products and LISTERINE outside the U.S. The scientific innovations that differentiate our products and the long-standing consumer trust in our brands continue to serve our business well.</p>
          <p>As we expected, we also continued to feel the effects of tighter customer spending in the more consumer-facing parts of our Medical Device businesses, which typically require out-of-pocket expenditures such as contact lenses and diabetes test strips. However, our Medical Device business saw strong growth in orthopaedics and surgery, and excluding the impact of additional competitors in the drug-eluting stent market, the MD&amp;D segment grew nearly 6% operationally for the quarter.</p>
          <p>As Louise pointed out, our pharmaceutical business saw the continued impact of generic competition and excluding that impact, the business grew approximately 9% operationally for the quarter. Overall, excluding the impact of generics and the launch of new drug-eluting stent competitors, the underlying business is growing at approximately 6% operationally despite the general economic slowdown. And normalized for the net impact of acquisitions and divestitures, we saw a slight uptick in the underlying growth of the business as compared to the first quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Meanwhile, our earnings performance in the quarter demonstrated once again our financial discipline and the ability of our business leaders to continue managing costs and improving margins. Our second-quarter results reflect an improvement in our pre-tax operating margin, which we expected for the year when we provided or annual guidance in January.</p>
          <p>Finally, I would like to mention the impact of the recently announced legal settlement with Medtronic. We received a $270 million payment from Medtronic during the quarter to settle a royalty dispute over certain patents. This payment is accounted for in other income and expense, but it was largely offset by several other litigation matters, which were individually smaller in amount as well as asset write-downs and other charges in the quarter, which are also reflected in this line. So on a net basis, the impact of other income in the quarter was not significant.</p>
          <p>This quarter, we continued to experience significant impacts from fluctuating currency exchange rates, which can cause significant volatility in our reported results. The impact of currency translation on sales was approximately negative 6%, and the impact on the earnings per share was approximately negative by $0.06 per share based on an actual average euro rate of $1.35 for the second quarter. Therefore, our second-quarter 2009 EPS of $1.15 reflects approximately $0.03 of operational EPS growth, offset by the approximately $0.06 of the negative currency translation impact versus the second quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Now I would like to turn to a few of the highlights in the quarter that illustrates the progress we're making in advancing our pipelines and where we're headed with some of the long-term investments in the business. On June 4, our pharmaceutical leadership team spoke with you about the strategy, pipeline and future milestones of that business. Based on our recent launches, approvals and filings, as well as the earlier stage compounds we discussed that day, you saw that we have one of the most robust pharmaceutical pipelines in our history and one of the most competitive in the industry.</p>
          <p>This confidence stems from the fact that we have seven compounds with filings pending in the U.S. and Europe, we expect another three filings between now and 2010, and potentially another eight from 2011 to 2013. Since June 4, we have launched NUCYNTA, a new prescription pain medication in the U.S. and SIMPONI, a once monthly subcutaneous treatment for rheumatoid arthritis, psoriatic arthritis, and ankylosing spondylitis, received a positive opinion from the CHMP in Europe.</p>
          <p>In addition to our organic pipeline, we have continued to look for opportunities to add capabilities through acquisitions and partnerships. For example, in July, we announced an agreement with Elan Corporation to acquire substantially all of the assets and rights for the Alzheimer's Immunotherapy program through a newly formed Johnson &amp; Johnson subsidiary. We're excited about the potential new products emanating from this transaction particularly bapineuzumab which has the potential to slow the progression of Alzheimer's disease, a key therapeutic area of focus for our research efforts.</p>
          <p>Additionally with our 18.4% equity investment in Elan, we will benefit on a pro rata basis with other shareholders of Elan from the potential new compounds emerging from a world class neuroscience research team in the treatment or prevention of neurodegenerative conditions.</p>
          <p>Just last week, we completed our acquisition of Cougar Biotechnology which gives us a promising late-stage compound for the treatment of prostate cancer and strengthens our position in global oncology market, another key therapeutic area for our pharmaceutical business.</p>
          <p>We had several other positive developments across the business this quarter. But let me just mention a few for the sake of time. We released important data on the NEVO sirolimus-eluting coronary stent in May. NEVO's unique reservoir or RES Technology reduces contact between the stent's polymer and the vessel wall by 75%, and the polymer is fully biodegradable, leaving behind what is in essence, a bare-metal stent after approximately three months. Based on this accumulating positive data and the unmatched body of clinical evidence on sirolimus, we believe that NEVO will offer a unique combination of safety, efficacy and deliverability that is going to be tough to beat.</p>
          <p>In the surgical space this quarter, an FDA advisory panel recommended approval of our Sedasys system, the first computerized, personalized sedation system, which integrates drug-delivery and patient monitoring. This recommendation covers minimal to moderate propofol sedation during screening and diagnostic procedures for colorectal cancer and the upper gastrointestinal tract.</p>
          <p>We also received FDA approval of our investigational device exemption application to conduct the first study of devices designed for use in Natural Orifice Translumenal Endoscopic Surgery or NOTES, which eliminates the need for external incisions in surgeries. Ethicon Endo-Surgery is the first company to receive an IDE for NOTES procedures.</p>
          <p>So we continue to invest broadly across our base of businesses and feel positive about the progress we are making with these innovations and other potentially new products.</p>
          <p>Now, I'd like to provide some guidance for you to consider as you refine your models for 2009. Let's start with a discussion of cash and interest income and expense. At the end of the second quarter, we had approximately $1.1 billion of net cash. This consists of approximately $14.7 billion of cash and investments and $13.6 billion of debt.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, we used approximately $300 million to repurchase shares of our stock in connection with our $10 billion share repurchase program, which began in 2007. To date, we have purchased approximately $8.9 billion of our stock. We have slowed the pace of our share repurchase due to deployment of cash for the acquisition of Cougar and the agreement with Elan.</p>
          <p>As we stated, when we initiated the share repurchase program, we would always remain flexible should opportunities arise to deploy our cash to build the business. We still expect to complete the remaining $1.1 billion under this repurchase program but at a slower pace than we previously anticipated.</p>
          <p>Our financial position remains strong. We generate strong cash flows and maintain a AAA credit rating, allowing us to continue to have good access to the credit markets for our financing needs at reasonable rates. As always, we will examine the best uses of our financial strength to invest in the long-term growth of our business and to return value to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>For purposes of your models, assuming no major additional acquisitions and the slower pace of completion of the share repurchase program, I suggest you consider modeling net interest expense of between 200 million and $300 million, consistent with our previous guidance.</p>
          <p>Now turning to other income and expense, as a reminder, this is the account where we record royalty income as well as one-time gains and losses arising from such items as litigation, investments by our development corporation, and asset sales or write-offs. This account is difficult to forecast, but assuming no major one-time gains or losses, I would recommend that you consider modeling other income and expense for 2009 as a net gain ranging from approximately $200 million to $300 million, consistent with our previous guidance.</p>
          <p>And now a word on taxes, through the end of the second quarter of 2009, the company's effective tax rate was 24.6%. We suggest that you model our effective tax rate for 2009 in the range of 24% to 25%, consistent with our previous guidance. As always, we will continue to pursue opportunities in this area to improve upon this rate throughout the year.</p>
          <p>Now turning to sales and earnings, it remains very difficult to predict movements in currency exchange rates and their impact on sales and earnings, especially given the ongoing economic volatility and the resulting monetary policy changes that governments around the world are employing to address the situation. As we told you in January, our guidance for 2009 will continue to be based first on a constant currency basis, reflecting our results from operations assuming that average currency rates for 2009 will be the same as they were for 2008. This is the way we manage our business and we believe this provides a good understanding of the underlying operational performance of the business. We will also continue to provide an estimate of our reported sales and EPS results for the year with the impact that currency exchange rates could have, using the euro as an example.</p>
          <p>So turning to sales and taking into consideration the loss of U.S. market exclusivity of both RISPERDAL Oral and TOPAMAX, which have about a 4 to 5% impact on our overall sales growth rate, we would be comfortable with your models reflecting an operational sales change on a constant-currency basis of between negative 1% and positive 1%, consistent with our previous guidance. This would result in sales for 2009 from operations on a constant-currency basis of between 63 billion and 64 billion.</p>
          <p>While we are not predicting the impact of currency movements, to give you an idea of the potential impact, if average currency exchange rates for the reminder of 2009 were to remain where they were as of last week using the euro as an example, this would imply an average rate for the euro of $1.36 for the year, which means our sales growth rate would be negatively impacted by approximately 4% or approximately $2.5 billion. Thus under this scenario, we would expect reported sales to decline to a range between negative 3% and negative 5% for a total expected level of reported sales between 61 and $62 billion, slightly above our previous guidance range, but due solely to the impact of currency movements.</p>
          <p>And now turning to earnings, when I last checked, the recent First Call mean estimate for our EPS for full-year 2009 was $4.51 per share. As a reminder, the recently completed acquisition of Cougar Biotechnology will have a $0.02 to $0.03 dilutive impact on 2009 earnings per share and assuming the closing of the pending transaction with Elan, we would expect an additional estimated dilutive impact of $0.02 to $0.03 on 2009 earnings per share. This transaction could also close in the third quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Due to the overall strength of our operating results and taking into account the dilutive impact of these transactions, which aggregate to $0.04 to $0.06 per share in the second half of this year, we are maintaining our full-year operational EPS guidance excluding special items. Therefore, I suggest you consider full-year 2009 EPS estimates excluding the impact of special items of between $4.60 and $4.70 per share on an operational basis. That is assuming the same average exchange rates for 2009 as we saw in 2008. This represents an operational growth rate of 1 to 3%, consistent with our previous guidance.</p>
          <p>While we are not predicting the impact of currency movements, to give you an idea of the potential impact on EPS, if currency exchange rates for the remainder of 2009 were to remain where they were as of last week with the average euro for the year at a rate of $1.36, then our EPS growth rate would be negatively impacted by approximately 3% or approximately $0.15 per share. Although currency rates have fluctuated, this is the same estimated impact we provided back in January. Therefore, we would be comfortable with your models reflecting full-year reported EPS, excluding special items, around the midpoint between $4.45 and $4.55 per share consistent with our previous guidance.</p>
          <p>As you update your models, please consider that TOPAMAX in the third quarter of 2008 was stronger than in the second quarter of 2008. Therefore generic erosion of TOPAMAX will continue to significantly impact our third quarter 2009 results as well.</p>
          <p>Finally, as a reminder when updating your models, please consider the dilutive impact of the two transactions I mentioned previously of $0.04 to $0.06 per share. Since the Cougar transaction closed last week and the Elan transaction could also close in the third quarter, a portion of that impact could reasonably be reflected in our third quarter results.</p>
          <p>Now, Louise, back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Dominic. Elizabeth, could you please provide the instructions for the Q&amp;A session?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from Mike Weinstein with J.P. Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you hear me okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We can, Mike. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Good morning, Dominic. Just a couple of items if you wouldn't mind, first the commentary on the XARELTO timing, if you could provide any additional insight to your conversations with the FDA. Do you have visibility at this point as to what the FDA would like to see prior to a resubmission? Is it just the complete outlook data that you presented at the panel or is it additional data that you like to see from the subsequent trials?</p>
          <p>And then if you could comment as well to the degree which you can, on the dispute with Schering relative to the anti-TNF rights and just help us a little bit with the process from here with regard to that dispute? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, I will &#x2013; and Louise you can help me with this, XARELTO's timing. Louise mentioned the timing would be not before later in the year, fourth quarter, as we're going to continue to meet with the FDA through the summer months.</p>
          <p>I would characterize the request this way: no new additional clinical data was requested. The FDA did request to see the data from the ongoing clinical trials of XARELTO in other indications. And of course this involves the involvement of the committees that review those ongoing clinical trials, so that's one aspect of the request. And the other aspect of the request relates to additional information on some of the study sites in the trial.</p>
          <p>With respect to the Schering-Plough dispute, we're not going to comment on that matter Mike. I can give you the current status however is that we, as you know, we filed to commence the arbitration proceedings, so we're awaiting that commencement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me just ask this one follow-up and I'll let some others jump-in. Dominic, there was a commentary in the prepared remarks about the orthopaedic business and pressure on pricing has increased but that is being offset at this point by mix. Could you just add a little bit more to what the business is seeing out there relative to pricing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Well, just as an overall comment, the overall market for orthopaedics was growing in the prior years at roughly eight or 9% and now our estimates and many of the published estimates indicate about four to 5% in terms of overall market growth. We're seeing hospitals basically putting some pressure on the price for the products that they are willing to buy from us. And that of course has been offset by some newer products that we have launched which is the mix comment that Louise made earlier. So I would say a little bit softer in terms of the ability to gain price with current market conditions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Bruce Nudell with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning Bruce. Hello?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, sorry, Bruce Nudell here. To follow-up on Mike's question, it looks like the market is in your business around four to 5%. Is that principally volume, is that &#x2013; can I just confirm that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We haven't seen much price at all in the orthopaedics market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So basically is the four to 5% that you're seeing principally volume?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So in the second quarter on a worldwide basis the price for DePuy not with mix in there, just price, was down about half a point and in the U.S., it was down about 1.5 points. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, and thank you. And then I had a question about the Elan transaction. Clearly it's going to be a huge therapeutic category, but bapineuzumab also had kind of a mixed trial result. Could you comment on the extent to which the investment really reflects full belief in bapineuzumab as opposed to gaining a seat or a footprint in what's going to be an exciting therapeutic category?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, well, obviously when we did the investment, which is twofold is, we considered not only the Alzheimer's immunotherapy program, but also an investment in Elan Corporation, a very talented group of researchers in neurodegenerative diseases. So there are two aspects of the transaction I just want to remind you about. In terms of the Alzheimer's immunotherapy program, you are referring to the Phase II trials, which showed some mixed results. We of course, did significant due diligence prior to entering the transaction with Elan.</p>
          <p>We saw some of the very positive results in the sub-group analysis, which I think some of you are aware of especially with the non-carriers of the APO-4 gene, which those results were remarkable. And of course, the Alzheimer's immunotherapy program includes not only bapineuzumab, but also includes backup compounds, that particular compound and also a vaccine for Alzheimer's, which is in early development. So hopefully that summarizes the level of interest that we had in the overall arrangement with Elan, Bruce.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Spoken like a biotech guy. Thanks, Dominic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Bruce.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Tao Levy with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Tao.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thanks. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was wondering if maybe you could comment just briefly on your expectations for Tylenol through the course of the year, maybe next year, obviously there has been a lot of media attention. Do you expect pressure on that business? I didn't hear you call it out in the prepared remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, thanks. Well, a couple of things. I'm sure you've all followed the FDA advisory panel proceedings. Just a couple of comments on that. One, we've been very clear that we strongly disagree with the committee's recommendation. We have made a number of recommendations to the FDA for their consideration. Of course, the FDA will have to consider these recommendations along with the committee's findings and recommendations and then proceed in a drafting process and a finalization process that will likely be ongoing, discussions with the FDA. I can't give you any timing per se, but this will &#x2013; I think will take some time to sort out. And we basically look forward to working with the FDA as they consider both the recommendations of the panel as well as our recommendations to make sure the products are safe and effective as prescribed and taken as directed, which we feel pretty strongly about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And in terms of your guidance overall that incorporates things just staying status quo?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, our overall guidance, we won't comment on any particular product, but we take everything into consideration in providing the guidance. But I think it will take some time to work through these issues with the FDA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just lastly on the other line, do you suggest the back half, is it evenly split Q3, Q4, are there any specific events that might happen in Q3 versus Q4 in terms of modeling purposes for that other line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I can't &#x2013; well, Tao, we don't really want to give particular quarterly guidance. I think the 200 to 300 overall number for the year for you're talking about other income and expense...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, exactly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...is a good number. I can't think of anything that's going to be material that will pop out in either one of those quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Larry Biegelsen with Wells Fargo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thanks for taking my question. First, Dominic, can you please confirm that the operational EPS guidance that's still 4.60 to 4.70, that includes the two deals, the Elan and the Cougar deal. So you're essentially absorbing the dilution from that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct, Larry. The 4.60 to 4.70, which was the same guidance we provided before now includes the dilutive impact of $0.04 to $0.06 on the two deals.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And second, we've seen two industries already strike specific deals with the government to reduce healthcare costs, I think pharmaceuticals and hospitals. And there's reports that the insurance industry is next. But devices are not reimbursed directly by payers. So, how should investors view this? Do you think device manufacturers, do you think they are immune from these deals or do you think at some point there'll have to be some kind of compromise with the government? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Yeah, it's a great question, Larry. One of the things to keep in mind is that we're going to work closely with AvaMed, which is the industry association that represents the medical device manufacturers. It would be fair to assume that the Medical Device businesses in the U.S. would probably feel some impact from the current deal that's been struck &#x2013; I'm going to call it a deal with quotes &#x2013; with the current "deal" that's been struck with the hospital associations, right? So you remember that I think last week sometime, there was an announcement of about $155 billion deal over 10 years, with the hospital association. We would expect that the medical device manufacturers would be contributing to that, obviously indirectly through pressures that the hospitals may face.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Rick Wise with Leerink Swann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, Dominic. Good morning, Louise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Rick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me turn to REMICADE. In the first quarter, there was a lot of concern based on some of the reported numbers that higher priced biologics like REMICADE were being hurt by the economy. But you were up in the U.S. now 75 million sequentially, what's the read through here? Is market growth rebounding, you guys are doing better, less pushback, and maybe I was wondering you can update us on the launch of SIMPONI and how that's going?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Just a couple of comments from my end and I'll ask Louise to comment. We did see market growth that Louise mentioned in the quarter. And I think our overall growth rate was consistent with the market growth in the U.S. Secondly, just as a reminder, REMICADE is an infusion therapy compared to the other products on the market, which are subcu including our own SIMPONI, but that's obviously not on the market yet. And I would say that we haven't seen as much pushback as was touted in the industry just a couple of months ago with REMICADE. So we'll leave at that and may be Louise, you can comment on SIMPONI's early results?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're excited about the access that SIMPONI has received in the U.S. and it's very, very early on, but at this point good signs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just a couple of follow-ups, just one more on DePuy, I just want to make sure I understood what you're all saying, clearly some more price, your U.S. numbers were sequentially lower by just a couple of million, are you seeing stable, slowing procedure growth just any perspective and any look ahead for the second half, are you concerned that we'd see further slowing on the procedure side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Louise, you had some data on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So in terms of the market, Rick, we're the first one out. So I can just give you first quarter market data that we have. But in the U.S., we believe the hips market was up about 6% on a worldwide basis, in constant currency up about 4%. And the knee market we think is up both U.S. and worldwide on about a 4% basis. That's slightly lower than last year, but it's still growing nicely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just last quick one, Ethicon Endo was up 1%, Ethicon was much stronger and I realize again there's Mentor in there and everything. But again are you seeing procedures slow, is this market share loss? Just any perspective would be welcome. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think, we've continued to see the elective procedures in surgery continue to slow versus prior year. So that was a continuation that we saw early in the year. And I would say another little bit newer phenomenon that we saw was more pressure from hospital on capital purchases and within our Ethicon Endo business is our advanced sterilization products business which has a portion of their business, which is capital purchases. So we did see some slower capital purchases by hospitals in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks so much, Dominic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Matthew Dodds with Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning. A couple of questions. First Dominic, on the Western Hemisphere, which jumped in the second quarter, is that where the REMICADE comparisons are really easy or is there something else going on there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So in the Western Hemisphere excluding the U.S., basically the markets are Brazil and Venezuela are the biggest markets there. And I wouldn't say that that was &#x2013; that had anything to do with REMICADE.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The OUS REMICADE, it wasn't in Canada or in one of the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Louise has that data, just a minute Matthew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so just a reminder on the OUS REMICADE. So last year at this time, we talked about the inventory management on our customer's part, so Schering Plough's part and this year we're having favorable inventory comparisons. So if you take out the two inventory builds in both periods for REMICADE OUS, as I said in my remarks, it's up about 16%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So there is nothing large or one-time that caused that jump in the Western Hemisphere. Just that market accelerated?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's right. I think once you take out the inventory build, you still had about, what Louise said about 16% growth in the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Dominic, I was talking the broader, the whole Western Hemisphere market, not just REMICADE.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I don't think there is anything significant in there. We have a broad base of businesses across the Western Hemisphere. So I wouldn't single out anything in particular, Matt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on Tylenol, can you at least give us some breakdown of how large the business is now in OTC, in &#x2013; either worldwide or in the U.S., just to know what kind of size we're talking about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So Tylenol, in the U.S. is about $1 billion product.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the adult.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the adult Tylenol, it's about $1 billion product. And so that excludes the pediatric business and of that $1 billion product, about 50% or so is this Extra-Strength version, the 500-milligram adult Tylenol. So hopefully that sizes up the business for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it does. All right, thank you, Dominic. Thanks, Louise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from David Lewis with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Dominic, just one quick question on margins. It seemed like in this quarter it was pretty encouraging. You saw gross margin benefit, you saw that falling down to the EBIT line. So I wonder, given the expected top line acceleration in your business, specifically pharmaceuticals, given the pipeline, and the previous cost controls you've talked about, how should we be thinking about leverage going forward in the business? Historically, it's been a pretty predictable ratio, I wonder if we think that ratio should be better or worse or the same than we've seen historically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, great question, David. So over long periods of time, we've grown our earnings faster than sales, which of course is a reflection of margin expansion. This quarter, just to correct you a little bit before I make my comment, this quarter, we did see gross margin deterioration a bit, right? Because losing products such as RISPERDAL and TOPAMAX to generic competition has a significant impact. I think our businesses did a great job of offsetting some of that, but you still saw some gross margin deterioration in this quarter.</p>
          <p>We had great progress as you saw in SG&amp;A cost and R&amp;D as we said many times will trend lower to the level of comparable &#x2013; to industry norms, because we're a bit higher than that. So it's hard to predict, I can't give you the exact number. But I'd say that we would still grow earnings faster than sales, but given some gross margin pressure in the business until the new products start ramping up, maybe not at the rate that you saw over like a 10 or a 20-year period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, if historically you were growing &#x2013; I'm sorry; I was referring to gross margin versus our number, which is what I'm more focused on, of course. But in terms of the ratio, I think Dominic, it's really kind of 1.4, 1.5 type of ratio, so you grow the bottom line 1.5 times faster than the top. Is that the kind of ratio we should be thinking about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think, David, that has to do with two things. Number one, if the markets we compete in on the top line are growing faster, then obviously we should be able to grow faster than those markets and then our earnings will grow faster than that. So it all depends on what your prediction is for the rate of growth in the market. So to the extent that the market growth would be slower than it's been historically, I would say that our overall ratio would be lower than historic norms.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then one other question here related to Bruce's question on bapineuzumab, but just taking a broader sense, looking at your pipeline, you are at the cusp of significant re-acceleration in your organic pharmaceutical pipeline. And at the cusp of that, you're still taking risks with Elan and with Cougar, so is this sort of a shift in J&amp;J's philosophy or are you seeing more opportunities? Are you trying to say something inherently about your organic pipeline or are you saying something more about just the returns you're getting on your cash?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I don't think there is anything new in what we've done. I think historically, we've had a good mix of organic R&amp;D investment supplemented by partnerships. As you know, the current robust pipeline that we have is probably equally composed of partnered products and organically developed products. And then finally supplementing all of that with selective acquisitions in areas that we think we can gain access to exciting either compounds or technologies. So I wouldn't read much into this in terms of a major shift, it's always been a mix of organic, licensing and partnerships and then selective acquisitions along the way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Matt Miksic with Piper Jaffray.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. Thanks for taking the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just one clarification if I could, on something you said earlier, Dominic. And then I just had two quick questions here. So one was, on this question of healthcare reform and sort of the agreement that was struck with pharma, the one that was struck here with hospitals, it sounds like you would expect from what we know today and it seems like you have pretty good exposure to the discussion that pricing objectives throughout this reform process would be achieved indirectly kind of through the agreement that was struck with the hospitals. Is that &#x2013; I'm speaking of pricing objectives with respect to devices. Is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. My comment referred to the fact that although no specific arrangement was reached with the medical device industry, that the hospital arrangement, it would be safe to assume that some contribution from the medical device industry would be required in order to make those numbers from the hospital industry come to life. So I think it's just reasonable to assume that any pressure that the hospitals feel going forward would be reflected indirectly in the medical device industry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And then just two quick ones here, one on price. In orthopaedics, you talked, Louise, about this 1.5% negative price approximately in the U.S. Just based on what you're seeing from hospitals and the current reform environment in mind and what we just discussed, can you help us understand how you see pricing playing out going forward? In other words, should we dial in something like this for the level of pressure, absent the mix or is this something where this could get potentially worse, is there some rationale for why this is an adjustment during this period that can converge back to something slightly negative? Any color there you could provide would be helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So we're not going to get into predicting price going forward for the DuPuy or the orthopaedics industry. But within the quarter, there is no anomalies within the quarter. So this type of pricing could play out for the year. And then price net of mix, we're expecting to be in the very modest potentially negative area for the remainder of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, just Louise, just to push on that just a bit, I mean if you compare orthopaedics to, I mean, there's other businesses where you live with something like a minus three or minus 5% price per annum going forward and almost in perpetuity, it's just a way of doing business. Is there anything about orthopaedics that you could speak to that would make it different or the same to some of these other markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're seeing just more pressure from the hospitals in terms of pricing. And if you look at historically, the last few years in the orthopaedic industry, it was modestly positive price and now it would be modestly negative price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. And then one last on just the M&amp;A front, Dominic. So the &#x2013; in light of some of the investments that you've made, a couple of device transactions, visible transactions and a couple on the Pharma side, could you &#x2013; as you look at the general field of opportunities across Consumer, Pharma, Devices, do you see the risk profile or richness of targets sort of rising or falling in any of those areas, given the stage we're in with respect to the consumer downturn at this point or the reform environment? Anything that's making one or another of these areas potentially more or less attractive, just from the standpoint of risk?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Matt, great question. I would say that given the uncertainty over the whole healthcare reform impact in the U.S. as well as outside the U.S. in terms of pressure on healthcare spending and given the fact that the depth and length of the recession is still uncertain and the type of rebound we would get is still uncertain. I would say generally speaking, when looking at acquisition candidates, we would consider the risk profile a bit higher now than it has been in the past. Now, having said that, we're interested in growing our business, we're interested in adding capabilities to our business, we're interested in doing or acquiring assets or technologies where we think in our hands, we can do much better than the current market valuations indicate. So we're always looking. But I would say generally speaking, the risk profile because of the uncertainty is a bit higher than it has been.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks for taking the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Glenn Novarro with RBC Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thank you. Just a couple of Pharma questions. One, on what's happening at the wholesaler distributor level. Is it fair to say that wholesalers and distributors destocked in the first quarter and now here in the second quarter, they're restocking or at least going back to normal buying patterns? That's question number one.</p>
          <p>Two, very quickly, were there any major price increases on any of the Pharmaceutical products in the quarter?</p>
          <p>And then lastly, just any update you can give us STELARA and paliperidone palmitate? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. So let's see, do you have the data handy on the distributor inventories, Louise?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I have second quarter versus &#x2013; '09 versus '08. So if you took out what I had spoken about in terms of REMICADE OUS, the change in the inventories is pretty much the same as what we saw last year. So there is nothing specific in terms of inventory changes going on with the exception of REMICADE OUS in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And then on pricing, obviously we have selected pricing throughout the businesses and on selected products. But our pricing overall has always been very modest and actually in the second quarter on an overall basis, it was less than 0.1. It was basically flat overall in pricing.</p>
          <p>And then on STELARA, Louise, the most recent update on STELARA we have is we responded back to the FDA with some additional information. They indicated another review would take another three months to review that data. So we're expecting to hear back from the FDA in the October timeframe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct. And paliperidone palmitate, the PDUFA is August 3.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So just in general, just what's happening on the distributor level? For J&amp;J and industry wide, it's back to more normalized levels because when you look at the first quarter, many of the drug companies experienced a lot of destocking at the wholesale level. So I'm just trying to get a sense of, are things back to normal here in the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I think some of that had to do with the anti-TNF category and REMICADE is a different model than the others in the industry. I think that's what you're probably referring to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Sara Michelmore with Cowen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...taking the question. Dominic, just back on the gross margin discussion, obviously we know what the negative dynamics in terms of mix during the quarter but it was a fairly strong performance. And I'm just wondering specifically what the positive offsets where and I'm just trying to get a sense of what was adjust for this quarter and what's sustainable there in terms of the underlying trend as you exit the RISPERDAL generic comparisons in Q3? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. It's a great question. Thanks for noting the strong performance. I think our people did an excellent job in managing the business, quite frankly, and keeping a rein on cost and being judicious about where we can make investments and where we can otherwise operate more efficiently. An interesting factor is that if you look at the impact of RISPERDAL and TOPAMAX alone in the second quarter that's about $1 billion of lost sales compared to the second quarter of '08. That's pretty significant in any business. And if you look at our overall EPS performance, I mentioned in my remarks that currency had about $0.06 negative impact to our EPS.</p>
          <p>So our EPS of 1.15 would have been 1.21, right on a constant-currency basis compared to last year's 1.18. So the fact that our business leaders are able to manage costs and manage the business in a way that generates positive EPS growth in light of this pretty significant impact to the top line is remarkable and it speaks to the resiliency of our people and the fact that they are committed to managing the business well as they always do. So I would say general cost control was a major factor in the business during the quarter. Now, going forward, I'd say that some of that is obviously sustainable because we want to &#x2013; we don't basically cut costs, we try to develop ways of doing business better or smarter or more efficiently. So some of it is sustainable.</p>
          <p>But as we launch new products and we get opportunities to invest in the future, we're going to take those opportunities and we'll obviously be clear with you all about when we see some uptick in those spending levels, which obviously we think will be the prudent thing to do for the business. So I wouldn't extrapolate necessarily this quarter to all future quarters. I mean that will be on a case-by-case basis as we see the opportunities unfold.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's helpful. And then on the R&amp;D line, I know that the pharmaceutical spending, you guys have been targeting a much lower percent of sales, trying to get more in line with the industry. Is that the main driver of the reduction of that percent on sales for R&amp;D or are there other parts of the business where you're getting some leverage as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think that that is one main driver. The other driver is the mix of the business, right. Because as the &#x2013; as consumer sales become a larger portion of the total, obviously that part of the business has a relatively lower R&amp;D spend than the overall rest of the business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just one last one big picture. What's your latest thinking on corporate tax reform, Dominic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, I would say that I'm generally more encouraged than I was a month or so ago. I visited in Washington recently and I would say that the general consensus coming away was that the impact to deferral or the elimination or reduction of deferral of U.S. tax on international operations is most best handled in an overall tax reform discussion and not as a single pay for in Healthcare reform. That's what the current thinking seems to be. We're very supportive of that kind of thinking and I'm encouraged by that kind of thinking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks so much for taking the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. So with respect to everybody's time, we'll take two more questions. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Bob Hopkins with Banc of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you. Can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just a couple of quick follow-ups. Dominic, first of all just to clarify your position on healthcare reform and some of the deals that have been cut. Is it your opinion that we should not expect the medical device industry to cut a deal similar to what we've seen with hospitals and with pharmaceuticals or is that still a possibility?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I would say it would be premature for me to offer an opinion on that. I think the dialogue is still ongoing but I think the dialogue would have to consider the impact of &#x2013; to the medical device industry of the hospital deal. That's what I meant by that. So &#x2013; but I can't predict whether there will be a deal or not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you for that. And then another clarification on the Ethicon Endo U.S. sales growth of 1%. Is it possible to quantify the negative impact from advanced sterilization capital equipment drag and what the rest of Ethicon Endo grew excluding that? Do you have a sense for that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have it handy. We can give you generally what the impact was. We don't break out ASP sales but Louise; you have a general indication of the impact there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so if you took out the impact of ASP, it would grow about the 3% range in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, just one other color on Medical Device business I'd like is are we still talking about the same sort of timing on NEVO that you guys have articulated previously?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Bob. It's on track.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks. That's all I had. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Last question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your last question comes from Derrick Sung with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks for squeezing me in. Could you elaborate on the hospital spending &#x2013; hospital capital spending comment that you made? Are you seeing sort of incremental, on a quarter-to-quarter basis, incremental pressure on hospital capital spending or is that same as it was last quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we saw slightly more incremental pressure in hospital capital spending in the most recent quarter than we had seen earlier. And just a reminder, our business is not heavily dependent upon that but we did it see it in certain pockets of our business where we do have capital spending as a major component of those specific businesses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. And a similar type question regarding too the economic sensitivities in you Consumer business, OTC, and also in your Med-tech businesses like vision and diabetes. Are you seeing incremental economic sensitivities there on a quarterly basis or is it about the same as it was last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Louise that &#x2013; we're just looking at the data right here to make sure we give you an accurate assessment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I can give you a couple of data points. For consumer, if you look at a 52-week rolling average of growth in the category, at the end of 2008, it was about 4% growth. If you took a look at the March-April timeframe, which is the latest period we have, it's down about half a point. And you'll see the same type of trend if you look at eight-week periods as well, down about half a point. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then in my commentary I provided some growth rates on Vision Care and on &#x2013; in terms of Diabetes Care, we're actually seeing some pricing pressure, more pricing pressure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, Derrick.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. So that will end the Q&amp;A session. We'll now have some final remarks by Dominic.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Louise. Well, in closing, I would like to offer these final thoughts. We continue to see that the underlying growth of our business is solid and improving as I mentioned earlier. And while we recognize there are challenging factors in today's economic environment, such as currency volatility and uncertainty surrounding the depth and length of the current recession, we remain financially strong and well positioned for long-term profitable growth.</p>
          <p>We are launching new products, advancing our pipelines and making prudent investments that will strengthen our business. Thanks to the dedication and focus of the talented people across the Johnson &amp; Johnson family of companies I am confident in our ability to innovate and execute our growth opportunities, while managing our business in a way that will make us an even stronger, more competitive leader in the global healthcare industry. I look forward to updating you on our progress throughout the year and we'll see you in October, where we will provide an update on our MD&amp;D segment, in addition to reporting on our quarterly results. Thanks and have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This concludes today's Johnson &amp; Johnson second quarter 2009 earnings conference call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>