<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1358559" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-01-14</date>
    <companies>
      <company>288</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Douglas L. Braunstein, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">James Dimon, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">John McDonald</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Betsy Graseck</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Guy Moszkowski</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Glenn Schorr</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Mike Mayo</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Moshe Orenbuch</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Jason Goldberg</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Paul Miller</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Matthew O'Connor</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Matthew Burnell</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Edward Najarian</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">David Konrad</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst">David Hilder</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst">Chris Kotowski</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst">Richard Bove</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst">Jeff Harte</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="analyst">Carole Berger</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. Welcome to JPMorgan Chase's fourth quarter 2010earnings call. This call is being recorded. Your lines will be muted for the duration of the call.</p>
          <p>We will now go live to the presentation, please stand by. At this time, I would like to turn the call over to JPMorgan Chase's Chairman and CEO, Jamie Dimon; and Chief Financial Officer, Doug Braunstein. Mr. Braunstein, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, operator. I'm going to take everybody through the earnings presentation. It's available on the website, as you know, and we'll take questions after the presentation. And finally, take a note of the slide in the back of the presentation regarding forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>With that, let me start on page one. We generated $4.8 billion of net income in the quarter, $1.12 per share. That's on revenues of $26.7 billion. For the full year, you see we generated $17.4 billion in net income. That's up 48% over last year, $3.96 per share, and revenues slightly under 105 billion. Our full-year return on tangible common equity was 15%.</p>
          <p>We're highlighting a number of significant items in the quarter. It is not every action in the quarter, but I just want to walk through these quickly and make sure we have clarity around them. The first is we added a net increase in RFS to loan loss allowances of what equates to $0.14 a share reduction in earnings. And just quickly, that $930 million pre-tax does not include a one-time adjustment. I'll talk about it when we get to home lending of $632 million release of reserves. That corresponds to an increase of net charge-offs which is basically a wash, but I'll get into more detail later on that.</p>
          <p>Card, we reduced our loan loss allowances by what equates to $0.30 a share increase in earnings. We also took an increase in litigation reserve, predominantly mortgage related. That reduced earnings $0.22 a share. And additionally, at the end we recognized a $1.2 billion pre-tax or $0.18 a share after-tax gain in corporate, and that's largely related to the repositioning of our securities portfolio. And in addition, that's going to have a negative impact on NII in successive quarters. Broadly speaking, very solid performance across most of the businesses, but I will talk about each of those in turn.</p>
          <p>And then finally, just a note on our common ratios; Tier 1 common ended the year at $115 billion. We had very strong Basel I Tier 1 common ratio of 9.8%. And you see here our estimated Basel III ratio of 7%, which, as you know, is the minimum requirement for Jan. 1, 2019.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Jamie. I want to interrupt for one second. So Doug, I just want to reiterate. A lot of you have raised the question that reserves came down by $2 billion. On this page, you see them coming down by approximately 1 billion. And the difference is the $600 million, which we have accelerated charge-offs which are already recognized in reserves and reserves taken down. And then there's another $400 million, which is all various wholesale related type stuff. There's a little confusion out there about where that came from, but the $600 million obviously is a timing difference. It didn't affect income. Charge-offs were accelerated; reserves were taken down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So with that, I think we've covered most of page two and three, so let me dive into the Investment Bank on page four. You see circled net income of $1.5 billion. That's on revenues of $6.2 billion in the quarter. IB fees of $1.8 billion; we continue to be ranked number one in fees, but it is an increasingly competitive market, and you see that in results.</p>
          <p>The results also reflect a record in debt underwriting for the quarter as well as for full-year 2010, and also record Investment Banking fees in Asia for 2010. The league table results you'll see are on page 20 in the back. Revenue of $4 billion in fixed income and equities; that's up 8% year over year. It's down modestly quarter on quarter, and that's largely based on continued solid client flows and normalized trading spreads.</p>
          <p>One quick note on DVA, which was effectively flat for the quarter; fixed income markets excluding DVA would have been down $377 million quarter on quarter, essentially flat year over year. Equity markets excluding DVA would have been down $141 million quarter on quarter, flat year over year. And that really reflects the negative impact of DVA to revenues in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Credit costs here, a benefit of $271 million, so that's part of that $2 billion allowance that you saw in total. That largely reflects a reduction in loan loss allowance related to net repayments and loan sales. Expenses in the quarter of $4.2 billion, that's up significantly year over year. That's primarily due to higher performance-based compensation year over year. The comp-to-revenue ratio for the quarter is 30%. And there's also an increase in our non-comp expense, and that includes litigation reserves taken in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Full year, if you looked at comp-to-revenue ratio, it's 35% excluding the UK bonus tax. And that's largely consistent with our prior guidance of 35% to 40%. It's up from 33% in full-year 2009, in part because of higher head count. And going forward, we really expect full-year comp-to-revenue ratios to continue to be in that range of 35% to 40%.</p>
          <p>Final number circled here on the bottom of the page, end-of-period loans of $56.9 billion; that's up 6% quarter on quarter. And we're beginning to see that new business activity build; and as a result of that, some increasing demand in loans as the market for credit and the economy generally pick up.</p>
          <p>Page five, Retail Banking; this is the consolidated results for the fourth quarter, $708 million of net income on $8.5 billion of revenue, and I'm going to review each of the segments in detail on the following pages.</p>
          <p>So if you turn to page six, you see, you see Retail Banking net income of $954 million. That's on revenues of $4.4 billion. Revenues are down 2% year over year, and that largely reflects lower deposit related fees, full-year impact of NSF OD fee changes. And that's offset by our continuing build-out of the retail branch footprint. Deposit growth was 3%. Year-over-year checking accounts were up 6%. Year-over-year investment sales up 4% year over year. And as you know, we built 154 new branches; 70% of those branches are in California and Florida. You'll note here, by the way, credit costs here include a loan loss allowance reserve release of $100 million in Business Banking, again, part of that $2 billion number.</p>
          <p>Mortgage Banking and other consumer lending, you see circled net income of 577 million. That's on $2.8 billion of total revenue. Revenue here reflects strong mortgage banking origination revenues, higher production volumes, almost $51 billion in the quarter, $56 billion in total originations. And you also had improved margins year over year.</p>
          <p>We're separating out now repurchase expense. You see that number of $349 million. And remember, that's a contra-revenue item. The number is down $300 million year over year. It's down $1 billion quarter on quarter. And that's largely the absence of reserve builds, but we end the year in RFS with a total repurchase reserve of $3 billion.</p>
          <p>Expenses in the quarter of $1.7 billion, that's up almost $400 million quarter on quarter, $600 million year on year. And that largely reflects higher default related costs, but it includes an impact of the estimated cost over time associated with the foreclosure delays from the affidavit issues. We took that cost in the fourth quarter. Credit costs in this segment also benefited from an allowance release in auto finance of $150 million as the trends there improved.</p>
          <p>The real estate portfolio on page seven, this is the consolidated result. Lower revenues here of $1.3 billion, that's largely based on continued loan runoff. Our balances declined year over year $29 billion as we continue to run off the Washington Mutual portfolio, losses in the portfolio for the quarter of $823 million. And the total credit cost number of $2.3 billion; I think it is helpful if we cover that in detail on page eight, so I'll turn to that now.</p>
          <p>So there's a lot going on here. I'm going to take a little bit of time here on this page. Home lending net charge-offs as reported is $1.750 billion, and you see that on the left. Now that includes that $632 million adjustment that I referenced at the beginning Jamie talked about. That's related to the timing of when we take charge-offs on delinquent loans. And so what we've effectively done is accelerate our net charge-offs for delinquent loans, and we've correspondingly released the $632 million number in our reserves. So it's essentially a shift in geography from reserves to charge-offs, but this doesn't have an impact on our results for the quarter, but that $632 million is picked up as part of our total company allowance release.</p>
          <p>If you really look at the underlying fundamental picture, absent the changes in accounting for the fourth quarter, you see the circled number of $1.15 billion, which is basically flat to modestly improved over the third quarter. And it's largely in line with the delinquency trends we've seen over the second and the third quarter. You see in the specifics, home equity losses are flat and the mortgage portfolios are showing some modest improvement, and you can see more detail of those trends on page 18 in the appendix.</p>
          <p>So given the reductions quarter on quarter in the losses and the fact that delinquencies are basically flat to slightly improved, we've taken a reserve release in the home lending portfolios of $950 million in the quarter, and you see that as the last bullet on the right.</p>
          <p>We're also, as a result of the last three quarters, changing our outlook. You see our outlook, quarterly net charge-offs of $1.2 billion plus or minus, and that's really based on current delinquencies and the severity outlook that we see today.</p>
          <p>The last change on this page, you look at the PCI [Purchased Credit Impaired] performance on the bottom right. And remember, for PCI we're using lifetime loss estimates for the portfolio. And as we've previously told you in our third quarter call, the estimates assume an improvement in delinquencies and I think given our last several quarters of actual experience. As a result of that, we've increased our estimates on remaining lifetime losses for the portfolios. And the result is we're taking a $2.1 billion incremental impairment in PCI, and that is predominantly related to home equity.</p>
          <p>So with all those actions, we thought it would be helpful to just summarize the reserve positions around mortgages in general, and so we're doing that on page nine. And maybe I can try and give you the key takeaways from our perspective going into 2011. The first is on the agency side. Between the $5.6 billion that we've taken in both expense and reserves and $1.2 billion plus or minus guidance that we have for 2011, we believe we've got a pretty good chance here of being done on the agency repurchase side. And this is certainly consistent with the analysis that Charlie presented to you all in the fall.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>And that they do.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>And it is certainly consistent. In fact, a number of you think that we're more than well reserved on that topic.</p>
          <p>On the private label side, based on our current circumstances, we have significant reserves. And you have to remember, private label exposure, there are very significant differences in the nature of the reps, the warranties, the quorum rules than for the GSEs. So to give you some perspective on what we think that means, if you're in the range of the private label repurchase exposure that have been recently published by a number of analysts on this call and you follow what we've taken in mortgage related litigation reserves during the past year, you should feel pretty comfortable with where we are going forward into 2011.</p>
          <p>On the real estate portfolio side, $9.7 billion in reserves in real estate portfolios excluding PCI; basically we have more than two years of coverage based on our annualized fourth quarter net charge-off rate. And through the year, we've also added $3.2 billion to our purchase credit-impaired reserves. So based on those current conditions, we believe we're really well reserved going into 2011.</p>
          <p>Page 10 is just an update on the foreclosure process. I'll give you three key takeaways. First to remember, we really continue to work very hard on avoiding foreclosures. It is not good for us or the borrower or the economy. And there are a number of facts here, and I'd just highlight we prevented more than two times the number of foreclosed assets during the course of the last 24 months. When we do foreclosures, obviously, those mortgages are very often delinquent for many months at the time of foreclosure. The homes are often vacant. They're not owner-occupied. And oftentimes, owners there don't qualify for modification.</p>
          <p>Having said all that, as you know, we suspended our foreclosures in September and October. And since then, we've really enhanced our process. We've retrained personnel. We've revised our processes and added additional quality controls. And as a result of that, we have been resuming our foreclosure proceedings across the country.</p>
          <p>Page 11, we'll turn to Card Services for the quarter; net income of $1.3 billion on revenues of $4.2 billion. This is really the first quarter since the first quarter of 2009 that we're breakeven. We made $61 million on a pre-tax pre-loan loss reserve income basis.</p>
          <p>Credit costs are, again, the big story in this quarter. They're down significantly to $671 million. You see the two circled numbers at the bottom of the page. Our charge-off rate was 7.08% for the Chase portfolios excluding WaMu. That's an improvement of 100 basis points quarter on quarter. It's also lower than our prior guidance of 7.50% plus or minus, and that's largely due to continued improvement on credit as well as the improvement in the economic environment.</p>
          <p>Thirty-day delinquencies declined to 3.66%. That's down almost 50 basis points quarter on quarter. And based on that decline in delinquencies, we're taking a $2 billion pre-tax reduction on our loan loss reserves because of the lower estimate for future losses.</p>
          <p>Just a quick moment on outlook for charge-offs; Chase and WaMu, both those portfolios, we expect to see charge-offs improve in the first quarter. And losses for the Chase portfolio we expect to see below 7% in Q1 '11.</p>
          <p>$4.2 billion worth of revenue, quickly, that's flat quarter on quarter, down year on year. That's largely down on lower outstandings. 100% impact this quarter in the run rate for the CARD Act, and that has been offset by positive sales volume, excluding WaMu up 10% year over year, 8% quarter on quarter. And note here, we really believe we've outpaced the industry growth, and as a function of that are really improving our market share as more people take their Chase cards out of their wallets at the store.</p>
          <p>On the balance side, we're reiterating the balance guidance I gave you in the third quarter. That's $120 billion plus or minus by year end for the Chase portfolio.</p>
          <p>Page 12, the Commercial Bank, just a quick moment on full-year comments for this business, not on the page. We had record revenue of $6 billion for this business this year and record net income of $2.1 billion. On the page, you see circled net income of $530 million. That's on record revenues for the quarter of $1.6 billion. That's largely better spreads, higher Investment Banking fees, actually record Investment Banking fees for this quarter for this client set. And that has been offset by lower average balances quarter on quarter, year over year.</p>
          <p>Credit costs of $152 million; that reflects trend of continued charge-offs in our Commercial Real Estate segment. And that has been offset by improving strength in our C&amp;I portfolio; 60% of the net charge-offs in the quarter are real estate related. And if you look down at the bottom of the page, one other credit statistic to highlight, NPLs are down significantly to $2 billion, down almost $900 million quarter on quarter.</p>
          <p>Last number circled here, loan balances of $98.9 billion. That's up modestly again in this quarter after last quarter's improvement as well. We do continue to see some positive signs of activity in the middle market. Balances are up 11% year on year, and some of that is driven by demand, some by new client growth for the year. We added 1,600 clients approximately in the middle market, 400 new clients in the quarter. But a word of caution, utilization rates across the Commercial Bank continue to remain flat through the last quarter of the year, in the low 30s.</p>
          <p>Page 13, Treasury &amp; Securities Services, you see circled net income of $257 million in the quarter. That's up year on year slightly and quarter on quarter. Revenues of $1.9 billion, same story on revenues; we're continuing to see pressure from a lower rate environment. And that has been offset by growth in our assets under custody. They ended year at $16.1 trillion. That's up almost $1 trillion year over year; as well as we saw an increase in our trade loan balances as we continue to build out our international footprint. Expenses in the quarter are up $79 million or 6%, and that's largely reflecting the same theme of that ongoing investment primarily related to the international expansion.</p>
          <p>Asset Management on page 14, again, a little full-year commentary; it was record revenues for the year of $9 billion. That was based on record long-term flows of $69 billion. And that was really a function of very solid investment performance across the complex. For the fourth quarter, you see circled net income of $507 million in the quarter. That's up year on year, up quarter on quarter. And net income is actually at its highest level since the fourth quarter of 2007.</p>
          <p>Asset Management had record revenues in the quarter, $2.6 billion. That's up almost 20% year on year and quarter on quarter. That's based on strong net inflows into those products with higher margins. We did have outflows in liquidity products of $25 billion in the quarter, but that was offset by $23 billion in long-term product inflows. That, by the way, is the seventh consecutive positive quarter of long-term inflows in AM. We also had positive effects obviously from a higher market as well as strong fourth quarter performance fees.</p>
          <p>We also had a significant increase in our mortgage production business. We did $7.8 billion in mortgage production in Asset Management this year, $3.4 billion in production in the fourth quarter. You see expense growth higher; that reflects higher head count, performance-based comp, and some continuing investments in technology across the platform.</p>
          <p>One last comment on the head count side, we've added 500 people to our front office across the globe in Asset Management, a little under 40% of that internationally during the course of the year.</p>
          <p>On page 15, you see Corporate Private Equities, private equity gains of $178 million in net income. Remember, that's going to vary quarter on quarter, realizations and market value for the portfolio, but it was a solid quarter for Private Equity.</p>
          <p>Corporate loss of $149 million in net income, that's really three factors at work. The first is NII is down quarter on quarter. It's down year on year, and that has largely the repositioning of the portfolio that we've been talking about through the course of the year. Second is we did have security gains as a function of that repositioning of $1.2 billion pre-tax. But again, that's going to pressure NII going forward. And then the third is we took that $1.5 billion pre-tax increase to litigation reserves predominantly related to mortgage matters in this quarter.</p>
          <p>One quick note on guidance here is excluding Private Equity and excluding non-recurring items, we still believe that net income for Corporate should be $300 million plus or minus on a go-forward basis each quarter.</p>
          <p>Page 16, fortress balance sheet; I really covered the top of the page. The one comment that I would add is that given the expected growth in our capital positions both through 2010 and forward, we remain hopeful that we're going to be able to return capital to our shareholders both through an increase in the dividend as well as share repurchases when appropriate. And we obviously wait on the results of the FCCP process to get back to you on that. We've addressed all the guidance issues in each of the lines of business.</p>
          <p>So with that, operator, why don't you open up for questions for Jamie and I? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from the line of John McDonald from Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Good morning; Doug, a question on net interest income. The run rate looks like about $12 billion this quarter, $48 billion annually. What are the puts and takes for 2011 when we think about the net interest margin and NII at the top of the house?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So NIM is down about 13 basis points quarter on quarter. That has been a function of the repositioning we talked about, a little less positive effect from dollar roll financing. We expect NIM to be flat to minus five basis points in the first quarter of this year.</p>
          <p>The broader question on NII in general, you're going to have offsets between &#x2013; what we've shared with you is runoff in our portfolios in RFS and Card. And those are things that we've been &#x2013; that's WaMu related in large part, and we planned to do that. And that's offset by what we see as beginning trends in growth in our loan portfolio across wholesale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The corporate NIM will be down quite a bit, the dollar amount, but we've given you the guidance in that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Card will be down $500 million or $600 million as it runs off. And the home equity &#x2013; the runoff from mortgage is about $700 million. Those will be disappearing next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it your hope that new growth will offset the runoff and you can have the balance sheet or earning assets be flattish or even up this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't really know yet because it's hard to tell. But Card, what we said is it will start to grow maybe late in the year because most of the runoff will be gone. But the mortgage stuff will be running off for years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then a question on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We may or may not replace it, and corporate is completely discretionary. We've decided to reduce the exposures in some of the portfolios there, reducing corporate net interest income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, the one other comment I'd make, as we run off these portfolios, it's also going to be liberating capital for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's the other thing to keep in mind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. Yes, you've been pretty clear about that. I guess on the put-backs, Doug, when you say that you have a good shot at being done on the GSE side, does that mean that you'll likely use the reserve to absorb future realized losses, or do you just mean that you probably won't do any more reserve building?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think early in the year, we'll be probably be charging and expensing that stuff. But a lot of you have done your own numbers showing that we're probably fully reserved. So once it's really determined that we're fully reserved, we'll probably be hitting that against the reserve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just one quickie on the private label, the litigation reserve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What he means is we'll still probably give and take a little bit. Obviously, there's a little bit to play out here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's fair. A quick question on the private label; are you able to add to the reserves for private label even if the claims haven't come in yet based on your own estimates, or are you only going to add litigation expense based on what you currently see as claims coming in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's got nothing to do with claims coming in per se. We can make our own judgments about how we're going to go about handling it. Most of the securities litigation &#x2013; you all, again, have done your own estimates in that, and those range from for us $3 billion to $10 billion or</p>
          <p>$12 billion or something like that.</p>
          <p>I think the way to look at it is we and maybe uniquely have put up litigation reserves for it. And we don't know what the ultimate number can be. We can be higher or lower. We're not saying we're done, but it's going to be years before this plays out. And this litigation is going to be fought almost securitization by securitization. There's almost no other way to do it. Very high &#x2013; you've got causality. The reps and warranties are low. You've got to do it loan by loan. This could be a long, ugly mess. The important thing is it's not going to be life threatening to JPMorgan, and it will be years before we know the ultimate outcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Betsy Graseck with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Betsy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, a couple quickies and a couple of just strategic questions. So on the mortgage originations, you obviously had a nice pickup Q-on-Q as the applications closed this past quarter. Could you give us a sense of how far through that pipeline you're and what the outlook is for mortgage originations over the next quarter or two?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Betsy, I did not check. They have to come down because the originations have come down, and I just didn't look at the pipeline. I'd be surprised if there were $50 billion of closed loans this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so you think you got through most of what the spike in apps you had?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would think so, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Usually it's like 60 days, and the last month was pretty low.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On loan demand, I know it's hard to predict what's going to happen over the course of the next year. But could you give us a sense as to how loans came in relative to expectations in 4Q, and was there any incremental change throughout the quarter? One of the reasons I'm asking the question is because obviously you had the long end of the curve move up. Does that incent people to get into C&amp;I in any material way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you referring to any particular segment here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Card and Commercial.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so the Commercial Bank loans have been up. Middle market, other loans, remember, we also bought a portfolio. But the middle market has been up every quarter the last three or four quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not because of utilization, just more loans, and we think that's a very good thing. It could be a little bit of market share, but I anecdotally hear from other people that there's loan growth there too. So our early indicators are that we will continue to see loan growth this year. And early indicators are people requesting it and industrial production and inventory numbers and all the things that can drive loan demand.</p>
          <p>In Credit Card, yes, there's going to be a seasonal drop in the first quarter, and I've got the number. That's going to be 4% &#x2013; 5%. Plus, for us you can add $3 billion in runoff, so the driver can be something like $10 billion in the first quarter, so the runoff is a couple billion dollars a quarter after that. But underlying that, we're actually seeing some growth now. So you might actually see net growth by the fourth quarter in Credit Card.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then separately on regulation, rule writing is obviously in process. And I just wanted to see how you're thinking about protecting your revenue and profit in the derivatives business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The rules haven't all been finished yet, but we are obviously preparing. We're going to be a great derivative house, okay, so if you want to go to us and go through a clearing house, we will be prepared, and it's possible volumes will go up. We gave a number like a $1 billion loss of potential revenue, but we don't really know. We've seen a lot of things that go to clearing houses and volumes go up. Spreads can change a little bit, but it might be a net plus. So you can assume that we are building rapidly to make sure we are the best out there in the new world.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's just because one of the questions on your business is that you're benefiting from a credit spread, relative credit spread benefit because your rating is higher. So how do you protect for that in an environment where you go to an exchange and the rating isn't worth as much?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's a very good point, which is one of the reasons there are issues about exchanges where in effect you socialize the credit. You socialize both credits. You socialize the credit of the company that might have been providing credit and the credit of the company getting credit. So that is why we look &#x2013; that piece will be a possible small negative. But we don't know how it's all going to sort out. We're not quite sure what the margin rules will be for end-user exemptions, and we'll see. Remember, a lot of the end-user exemptions, the reason they wanted to do business with JPMorgan is we would give them the benefit of their credit and they get the benefit of our credit as opposed to an exchange, where neither happens.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. And then last on the Durbin piece, Durbin obviously came in, in the last quarter. Does it change how you're thinking about your deposit pricing changes that are underway? Is there anywhere else you think you can make it up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just make a statement about Durbin that part of what happened in Durbin was this notion that retailers pay zero for cash and zero for checks and they were paying 70 or 80 basis points for debit card. But the fact is that cash costs retailers &#x2013; and there have been a lot of studies done on this &#x2013; 30 to 70 basis points. They've got to process it, handle it, move it, insure it, bank it. They need registers, and there's a lot of defalcation &#x2013; what's that called? Checks cost also 70 basis points for all the same basic reasons. As a matter of fact, the guaranteed check, which is the equivalent to a debit, like you get your money right away and it's guaranteed and you're not taking the fraud or credit risk, is $1.20, 1.2%, if you want to go guarantee a check. So that was a false premise.</p>
          <p>The other false premise is that somehow in a fixed cost business, you can price to variable cost and survive. No business in the world can price to variable cost and survive. And so this debit thing has enormous benefit for consumers. Even for retailers, it was faster. And how this happened is completely beyond us. We have to figure it out. You can't price your products at variable cost and survive as a business. So we're going to have to figure out a way, and we want to do it that's consumer friendly and fair. But of course, the consumer has got to pay, and they weren't paying for debit before.</p>
          <p>So we don't exactly know. We're going to test a whole bunch of things. Remember, we might not just charge for checking. You might charge for debit. You might just have higher deposit balances. And you're right, you might keep a little bit more spread. So that's all going to sort out both in the competitive sense and a legal sense as we figure out how to deal with it. Our biggest concern right now is to do it in a way that's as consumer friendly as possible. We also think it will have the adverse consequences of making a portion of current bank clients unbanked. You will not be able to profitably serve them. And, my current estimate it has to be about 5%, and I'm not sure that was a good public policy issue either.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>5% of your customer base?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the general banking customer base may be pushed out of the banking system.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your any comes from the line of Guy Moszkowski from Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Guy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Guy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, just a comment; that outlook page that you used to do was actually pretty useful, even though yes, you do go through of the different units, so I'd be a fan of putting it back in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A question, first of all, on the litigation reserve; is it fair for to us assume that that $1.5 billion that went through Corporate is largely for private label mortgage, or is there some expectation of foreclosure settlement in there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's largely for private label mortgage and mortgage related type of stuff. And foreclosure settlement, we don't have any more foreclosure settlement, but there was hundreds of millions of dollars of higher cost that we either expensed or accrued for the delay in foreclosures because of the affidavit issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's in the mortgage business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's within RFS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And separately, within the Investment Bank, there was about a $700 million or so swing in the non-personnel expense from the third quarter to the fourth. Reading the press release, it sounds like maybe a lot of that is litigation reserve building as well, or did I misinterpret that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You read it right, and that number obviously will normalize and go back to &#x2013; the non-comp number will go back to a more normalized $1.6 billion or $1.7 billion quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and should we assume that a fair amount of that is for mortgage stuff as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, the whole budget stuff, the detritus of the storm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And also speaking of swings in the Investment Bank, there was about an $800 million swing in credit portfolio revenue versus the third quarter. That probably doesn't have any provision impacts, right, because it's just a revenue number. So I was just wondering if you could help us understand that swing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So remember, the credit portfolio is a hard one. On a normalized basis, it should earn about $200 million or $300 million a quarter, and think of it as NII. But in addition to that, there's hedging and hedges and up or down, so it swings all over the place. We try to manage that economically, not for steady GAAP revenues.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's fair. The fixed income VAR had a notable decline in the quarter. And again, that really continued a trend, so it's down quite a bit for the year. Is that just a decline in volatility of some instruments? Is it that you've actually reduced risk? And is that reduction mostly in rates or credit or where?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're right. Most of that &#x2013; I think the largest part of that is just dropping, more volatile quarters from last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that number is coming down for no reason other than you're changing the data set that goes in the calculation, which is one of the reasons I personally never paid that much attention to it because it changes without any good reason. There was no conscious effort to take down risk, et cetera. That's done by desk, and I don't think there was any particular area where it was dramatically different than others. There are a couple that are coming down, but it's usually the traders making decisions on that particular book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and the final question I have for you is just looking at the AOCI. It had a negative $2 billion swing in the quarter. I wouldn't make a big deal out of it, I guess, because it's still more than it was a year ago. But is that mostly due to what happened in the treasury market in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and we also realized $1 billion of gains.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you realize gains, it reduces AOCI because that would have been there. Remember, we did that early, and we're doing that to protect &#x2013; not just to protect AOCI, but if you look at our interest rate exposure where causally, if long rates go up, it will help us; and if short rates go up, it will help us a teeny bit. So we positioned the company for raising rates and I think we did it a little bit early, saving...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You were talking about it a year ago or more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Glenn Schorr with Nomura.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey there. So I think we all are now in agreement that you're pretty well reserved on the agency side. I'm curious. It might be a moot point, but I'm curious. Is the waiting on the WaMu decision in the way of a potential settlement and just putting it behind you on Fannie and Freddie?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we had settled most the GSE stuff. The GSE put-back rep and warranty issue had already been settled regarding WaMu. That had been done sometime a year ago or something.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, then I'll rephrase. Is it of any interest to proceed the settlement route or a moot point given your reserve position?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a moot point. But if they wanted to settle all at once, it would be fine with us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's getting more and more developed. The loss curves are getting more developed. They know their own numbers. We know their numbers. Look, both Fannie and Freddie are working with us. They're giving us files. We look at the files, return them back. We're just trying to get it all behind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And we should hear any day based on who is on the hook for WaMu?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the bankruptcy settlement...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Who is on the hook for WaMu for what?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the private label potential liability going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We think they are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So do I, but we're waiting on a judge, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a different issue. There's a whole bunch of stuff going on with WaMu to settle and finalize all this stuff. Then there's the private label. WaMu is about a third the private label. We think that they're responsible for that piece. Again, the analysts, you all have done estimates on this. And between our reserves and even some of your estimates, I guess it's going to take a long time to resolve. And so my opinion is it's going to be resolved. It may be more. It may be less, but it's not going to be terrible for us, whether or not WaMu takes their one-third.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I agree. Jamie, I wanted to ask you this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We want to put it behind us, but the big piece is now it's going to go on for years. I don't think this stuff will be &#x2013; we'll be talking about this every quarter for the next three years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I hope we have better things to talk about, but I hear you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I hope that people get more and more comfortable that while we're talking about it, it isn't going to be something that's going to change the future of JPMorgan. It's just going to be a few adjustments and a few quarters up or down when this is all resolved.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. The second question is related to the stress tests and the capital plan that you just put forward. I'm curious on the stress test that both you just performed and the one that's being performed now versus the last stress test, if you can articulate what the major differences might be. In other words, last time, I think they took a very harsh look on trading. It didn't pan out that way. How do you see the adjustments this stress test versus last?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say it's similar, and higher unemployment and home prices going down. And we do this ourselves anyway, by the way, and stress testing, market results, and stuff like that, but a lot more detail, a tremendous amount more detail. In any event, even under highly stressed environments, JPMorgan has been retaining an awful lot of capital. We are looking for ways to use that capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think your comments were over the next three years of $40 billion to $50 billion versus $30 billion in the highly, highly stressed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and whether they come up with similar numbers or not, I don't know. But the fact is we're going to have plenty of capital. And we also think that 7% Basel III is plenty of capital. In fact, I think the stress test will confirm that, not just on us, but all the banks. That's what capital is for, to deal with stress. And for the most part, I think banks will be able to deal with a lot of stress at 7% Basel III. We're starting to add capital on top of capital at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I hear you. All right, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I remind you that 7% Basel III is more akin to 11% Basel I. The first stress test on Basel I was 4%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>By the way, before I let you go, do you feel like you're making progress with Washington on that front specifically? Because I feel like initially other companies might have said it's 7% and there might be a buffer on top and you add a little bit on the edge on this one, and I think a lot of people agree with you; but just curious if you made some progress.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, no. I think the regulators will look at the issues, and this is a world, global issue because a lot of regulators overseas think it should be a lot more. Some think it's sufficient. I hope America takes a rational position and a leadership position. That's what I hope. We don't have to do what everyone overseas thinks should be done. We need to take a leadership position in the United States that we think is appropriate. And personally, I think 7% is plenty. I think you could make many arguments why some of the big companies were stabilizers in this storm as opposed to systemic risks in the storm.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you both.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Mike Mayo with CLSA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Mike.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What are you doing to manage your exposures in Europe in light of what's taking place there? And what impact did Europe have on your current quarter results? I see that EMEA revenues were down 7% in the Investment Bank linked quarter. But just more generally, what's the impact and what are you doing to protect yourself or maybe to potentially capitalize?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so we disclosed at one point that our net exposures were $20 billion in the gypsy countries. That number is down substantially now. But the important part is that we also continue to do business there with sovereigns, with corporates, with governments, with institutions because we have a lot of clients. And so we're letting the client side do that. And obviously, those exposures could come back and haunt us at one point, but we're not going to stop doing business in those countries. The business is just down a little bit. I don't think there's any mystery to it. And are there opportunities to get from it? Yes, I think the opportunities come from continuing to service our clients, not running. That's the real opportunity; that people know you're there for the client in good times and bad times.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what about acquisitions? What's your general appetite and what would be your appetite in Europe if there was a Bear Stearns or a WaMu type situation there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't count on something like that. We believe the highest use that we can ever do is organic growth. And if something came up that really made a tremendous amount of sense, then our obligation is to go look about it and think about it, but I'm not sure that will happen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You seem sanguine about Europe or you don't seem too alarmed by what's taking place there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you talking about for us or for the system?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Talk about both then. It seems like what could happen to the system will impact you, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are going to continue to do business in all those countries. We have clients in all those countries that rely on us. We want to be there for them. We're not a fair weather friend. Could we lose money from that? Absolutely, we could be making a mistake, but that will be okay. Okay, a bank is supposed &#x2013; we're supposed to be there for them in good times and bad times.</p>
          <p>I personally think that Europe will muddle through this situation. They have demonstrated, and I think the regulators and the leaders have demonstrated that they are going to fix this. It's a little bit of fits and stop-and-starts. Obviously, there are some disagreements, but you've seen a lot of very strong statements that they're going to get through this, and I would bet on that. I think that's the likely outcome. And we're not betting the company, but I do think that's the likely outcome. I do think over time, they've got some serious structure issues that they have to fix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then lastly, what was the impact of Europe on TSS this quarter, and can you just elaborate on why TSS had such good linked-quarter growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think Europe had any effect on TSS at all. I know we did much better in trade finance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We did better in trade finance. Linked quarter, we get a little bit of an impact from the ADR business, which is up quarter on quarter, and a little better impact from assets under custody, but I'm not sure. We can get back to you on the specifics for Europe. But in general, that's the quarter-over-quarter change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Moshe Orenbuch with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. I guess, as you've mentioned, Jamie, the litigation on the private label is years away. And you pretty much &#x2013; you had that $1.5 billion was plus or minus the level that you had in every quarter this year. Is that something that we should be looking forward to in 2011, or do you feel good about where that is right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I feel pretty good about where it is right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've got to react to circumstances. But more likely than not, you'll see nothing next year for that category.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We like to keep our balance sheet clean and just move on, and so we've moved on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And secondly, you probably are going to be the only one that can truly say that they're at the 2019 capital levels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I just want to make a comment about litigation because I did mention before about the detritus of the storm. I think it's also reasonable that after we've had a storm like this that the litigation follows years later, so I'm not saying there won't be other litigation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>My experience has been that things will &#x2013; and you've seen tons of it. Some of it is completely frivolous, but some may not be. I can't say that there won't be any litigation expenses next year of size.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But not at the $1.5 billion quarterly level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I hope not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Secondly, you're, saying that you're at the 2019 Basel requirements already and you've still got runoff portfolios there. And yet you talked about pulling down some discretionary parts of your balance sheet. What could cause you, particularly now with a somewhat steeper yield curve, to start rebuilding that? How should we think about that in 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess we're going to have normal business growth in 2011, which will use some the balance sheet. And we're still waiting for final guidance from the regulators on what the capital requirements are going to be, et cetera. Listen, we can build the balance sheet much quicker if and when we feel it's appropriate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I will add, Moshe, there are some things. There are components of our balance sheet that we plan on running off that were part and parcel of some of the mitigating actions as the impact of Basel III takes place. So there are going to be some assets that we will change over time because they're very high utilizers of RWA on a Basel III basis. And those will come off balance sheet regardless of whether we're building other components of the balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, I wasn't referring to those. I was referring more to WaMu runoff portfolios and other pieces of your mortgage business that are still in the rundown mode.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can always make a portfolio decision to put assets on the balance sheet to create more NII. That's why I always talk about excess capital as earnings in store. You can use it whenever you want, just use it wisely and use it at the right time. We don't want to do that and have huge unrealized losses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're actually trying to protect ourselves from that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As a follow-up to that, obviously, a few things have to happen even after the Fed makes pronouncements on dividends with respect to stock buyback. Could you just talk about your thoughts as to the regulators and stock buyback at this stage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They have said that when they finish all this work, which will be on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Late March, March 21.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...late March that they will be giving companies guidance on capital, so that capital to me is dividends and stock buyback. At that point in time, if we have a little more guidance on the ultimate outcome of what the capital needs to be, like it's going to be more than 7%, our board will take the appropriate action. I'm hopeful to be able to do the dividend right away.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jason Goldberg with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. In the Investment Bank, it looks like non-performing assets were up a little over $1 billion linked quarter, any in terms of color in terms of what's driving that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's just too large an asset to move to non-performing. And remember, non-performing has specific reserves against it, so we're not worried about that at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then I guess secondly, and I know it has been talked about on the call, but in the last several years we've seen a drop-off in trading in the fourth quarter and then a nice rebound into the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we noticed that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously we're only two weeks into the first quarter of this year. But can you just give us any sense of in terms of how you're thinking about the thick line, near term, just given the volatility in those types of earnings?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you mean how trading is doing so far this month? Is that what you're saying?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That and just your near-term expectations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know. You guys can guess as much as we can. So far, the year started off pretty good. And look, your can have a very good year in trading and Investment Banking this year. But your guess is as good as my guess, so use your own.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Paul Miller with FBR Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Hey, Jamie, on the dividend, a lot of people expect you &#x2013; you've been talking about raising your dividend. But how aggressive do you think you can be? I know the Fed is talking about a 30% payout ratio. Do you think you can get to that quickly, or will that take a couple quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't we just wait and get the guidance from the Fed about what it's going to be? What we have spoken about is that we would like to get eventually back to 35% of normalized earnings. If the Fed gives guidance that they want it to be at 30% of normalized earnings, then we have to limit it to 30% of normalized earnings. They are our regulators. Remember, me, I don't care if we pay dividends at all so we can use it for some other purpose down the road.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the other issue is that there's a lot of discussion and there are a couple articles out there about dropping servicing fees to zero and restructure the mortgage industry along with it. What is your thoughts on that, if you have any?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I would defer that. The Treasury is putting out some guidance on the GSEs. If you change servicing, that changes how you price mortgages and how you account for mortgages, so it's not going to change the mortgage business per se. You're still going to originate and service mortgages. It will just change the asset on the balance sheet and accounting. So I'm not worried about it. I would just prefer to wait to see all the guidance that comes out from the government and how it all sorts out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Wouldn't that help you guys out, though, on your Basel capital rules? Because if something like that went down the road that MSR would be a lot lower than it is today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but it's still under the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It doesn't have a big impact on our Basel III capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Because it counts up to 10 or...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>10% and 15% in total for a number of items, and we're not very far off that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Basically, we would probably restrict MSR to 10% of the balance sheet if that were the case unless it was really, really profitable, in which case we'll take the capital charge and put it back on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just one other tidbit question on the HELOCs. On the $600 million acceleration, was that all &#x2013; was that more referring to WaMu, or was that across the board?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was across the board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Across the board, okay. Thank you very much, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Matt O'Connor with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If I could just look at expenses at the top of the company, if I back out the $1.5 billion litigation in Corporate and then several hundred million of mortgage, foreclosure, all that stuff in RFS, and I think several hundred million also in the Investment Bank, you basically get a run rate of expenses in the $55 billion range. How are you thinking about that level going forward outside of the Investment Bank? I'm asking because you've been investing heavily in a lot of your businesses. And I was trying to get a sense of how much more investment spend is needed and how that might track going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think it's investment spend. I think the way you should look at these expenses will grow with our businesses over time. It's not like we have massive additional expenses that we have in addition to that. There are a lot of expenses which will eventually go away. You mentioned there was a little over 300 million from the affidavit in this quarter. There's 300 million of foreclosure expense. Obviously, a lot of the mortgage charge-offs will reduce dramatically over time &#x2013; that's not through expense. And there was obviously the litigation stuff which hopefully won't be reoccurring. I look at it by business. It's very hard for me to look at the aggregate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then just separately, you went into some detail on the balance sheet repositioning of the securities book. I guess one thing that's interesting is if I look at the size of your securities portfolio and guess at where the yield is going to be, it's a fairly low yield. And if I compare it to your long-term debt, you're not really making any money on it. And I know that's not a perfect way of looking at it, but it's probably the only bank I cover that would scream like that. I guess the question is, are all these securities that you have on the balance sheet, are they needed for liquidity? Or over time, can we start seeing more efficiency to the balance sheet, which it might be smaller but higher NIM and free up some capital?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So some of that was moved to what I would call spread product, which has the exact effect of what you're saying, but it protects you in a rising rate environment, which we thought was a wise thing to do. That portfolio is used to both reinvest excess deposits and to balance all the asset/liability management in the company. And right now, we're asset sensitive, and we just think that's the right place to be. Can we change it, reduce the size of that portfolio? Absolutely, those are big portfolio decisions, which we try to make at the appropriate time. You really can't look at it relating to the long-term debt. I think long-term debt is &#x2013; a lot of it is swapped and a lot of assets are also swapped.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess I'm looking at the debt, and you're growing a lot of your core funding quite nicely. The balance sheet is not growing all that much, and there are still pretty big chunks of long-term debt that over time I would assume run off. And I don't know what the plans are on reissuance there would be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have almost $20 billion to $30 billion of maturities each year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we'll be in that zip code of plus or minus $30 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now, we're playing for good organic growth. We don't know the capital rules. It is possible when that comes out, we won't issue all that debt. It is possible that we'll do other things with the balance sheet and figure out how to &#x2013; but all of it was done to protect the company and to make good money for the shareholder.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Matt Burnell with Wells Fargo Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, two quick questions for you, first a bigger picture question. I'm just curious if you have any thoughts about the implications for the industry from last week's decision in the Massachusetts Supreme Court on the Ibanez ruling and how quickly that whole foreclosure issue might get decided in Washington, if there's any momentum in DC to mitigate that risk going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'm not going to give you a specific legal. I'm just going to say that every state is different. And the facts, the way we see things, are different. And we said right from the beginning that you're going to see a lot of state differences, local differences, court differences, and we've built that into our thinking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But you don't think that there's a push in DC to have a more broad or a more comprehensive way of thinking about that going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There might be, but I hope if &#x2013; but it's going to be the same kind of thing as how did you finish and properly process foreclosures. And I don't think this one thing changes the mess. It's a big mess. It has cost us a lot of money. I personally think we're all along the way or more through this whole thing. And unfortunately, the only way to do it right is name by name by name. There is almost no other way to do it properly. Person by person, home by home, are they occupied? Did they lie on their forms? Are they entitled to a HAMP? Are they entitled to a modification? We do as many as we can.</p>
          <p>There's a lot of paperwork. The paperwork is different in every single state. There are mistakes made. And I remind people that the affidavit process is not the foreclosure process. There are multiple checks and balances. And there may be mistakes made in the foreclosure process, but they're very few. And boy, we find them and we try to make up for them right away. And obviously, this issue has been heavily politicized. And in some cases, mistakes were made and they're being pointed out and they should be fixed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, and then a quick administrative question. I notice that U.S. non-interest bearing deposits were up about 10% quarter over quarter. Is that largely corporate deposits coming in, or is that also consumers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>U.S., I missed it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go through that one more time. What was that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm looking in terms of &#x2013; on page 39 of the supplement, you have U.S. offices non-interest bearing deposits up about 10% from September 30th at 242 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll get back to you on that one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Ed Najarian with ISI Group.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you give us a quick update on what your opt-in success has been so far and how much percentage you think you might recover of lost overdraft charges related to Reg. E? And then quickly, any other comments on what you might be doing in 2011 from a mitigation standpoint around the deposit side?</p>
          <p>And then I know you said you wanted to test a lot of things related to Durbin. Is there any &#x2013; in your mind just right now, and I know there's a lot to learn, but is there any real way to make up much of that lost Durbin revenue, or do you expect that most of that will just be lost? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know the opt-in percentage. I'll just give approximate. Approximate, for those who used it before, approximately more than 50% opted in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, and the full run rate effect of that is already in the numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we told you that's $700 million in net income, and that was full run rate in 3Q and now 4Q.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. And then on the Durbin, you can't run your business where you're charging things at variable cost. In some ways, you're going to have to look at ways of repricing the business, and that may not come from the price you see. It may just come from higher &#x2013; you have to keep higher deposits on balance to have reduced fees. It may come from checking account fees. You've already seen a lot of people around the country eliminate free checking. But I think ultimately, most of it will get repriced into the business. It's very hard to run a business where you can't charge for your products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you do think that you've got a good shot of getting a good chunk of that revenue back through your pricing strategy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and we're very conscious of doing it right, like design the right products for the right people. I think I said before, it may drive some clients out of the business into the non-banks because there may be no way to reprice those clients because you can't collect the fees because the accounts are too small. And remember, for a whole bunch of clients, it may not matter that much at all. They already have high balances; they're already quite profitable. So we'll have to figure it out. We're doing a lot of thinking and a lot of testing. Remember, it's effective...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>July.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...July, so we still have a little time to figure it all out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then in terms of overdrafts, should we think about 3Q and 4Q as the trough and maybe a reasonable growth rate off of the 4Q number as you get more impact from customers opting in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I would think of it more as just the run rate going forward</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Run rate is normal. Customers are going to get careful how they do things. We're not looking for it as a growth item, but just another item in the income statement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I just want to go back on that. Our first two quarters next year because the phase-in was over time will be down quarter over quarter because of the impact, the full-year impact of the overdraft.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of David Konrad with KBW.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All my questions have really been asked. But just to follow up on the material decline in NPLs in Commercial Banking, just any color there regarding is it CRE, multi-family, or more business lending?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Some of it we sold and got rid of and reduced. I don't know if there was any &#x2013; it wasn't real estate particularly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The balance of the NPLs is more balanced toward real estate. So as we brought it down, it was predominantly real estate, but it was across the board.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How much was due to selling NPLs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't remember.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do it to keep it clean and move on. I would say when we've been doing it, it has been economic to do so. So in large part, the reduction in NPLs we either reserved for or actually got some recoveries as a result of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are economic analysts. We don't do that to show lower numbers. We do that because it's the right thing to do manage our credit portfolio economically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of David Hilder with Susquehanna.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Sorry, my questions have been all asked and answered. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from the line of Chris Kotowski with Oppenheimer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, just if we could go back to the trading environment a bit. This is the third quarter in a row of sluggish trading revenues industry-wide, and I wondered. Do you think &#x2013; is it just the lingering impact of concern about Europe and so on, or is there something structurally different in the world? That is things like less mortgage-backed, less non-agency mortgage securities out there, so less trading opportunity there, and less CDS writers and therefore, less opportunity there, is it something structural or it is the overhang of euro concerns?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think it's structural, and I don't think it's an overhang of euro concerns either. I think it's the ebbs and flows of trading. Rate was very strong earlier in the year and I know came down a little bit. The last couple weeks in December are almost always low. Credit has been very strong all year and I think it was a little slower this quarter. It's just going to &#x2013; trading changes. That's the way it is. I don't think it's either structural or Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So far this year, it started off pretty good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. That's all for me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Richard Bove with Rochdale Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I apologize for my voice. On page 20 of the handout, you show a pretty sizable decline in market share and rank in each one of quite a number of your Investment Banking positions. I'm just wondering what happened there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the first answer is that I think we had &#x2013; I'm not going to call it artificial, but we had a bump up in '09, which I think we've told our shareholders we expected to come down a little bit in 2010 because the competition has come back full force, which I think is a good thing, Dick. We knew it was going to happen, but it happened. So I think that's part of it. Over time, we gained share. And then in some other areas, equity, a lot more done in China, A-shares, which we can't do, though we just got a license to do it. M&amp;A, a couple of deals we had didn't happen. We're comfortable with our franchise. We think we have a fabulous Investment Banking franchise, and we will defend it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The other question is on the balance sheet. If you take a look at Citigroup or Bank of America's cash position and their net Fed funds position, they seem to be overloaded with cash. Whereas on your balance sheet, if I net out the Fed funds position against your cash position, you don't seem to have as a goal driving up the liquidity on the balance sheet, so I'm wondering. What is the difference in philosophy between the two companies of the two groups of companies?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, we feel like we have a lot of liquidity. I know everyone is showing their liquidity ratios, these new liquidity numbers, but I'm not sure they're all equally done, nor are all businesses the same. So if you had a big retail business, you may not feel the need for that. If you're in a big wholesale funded business, you might feel the need for a lot more of that. So we feel fine where we are. If we wanted to drive the number up, we can easily do that at no cost to the company, but I'm not sure why that would help us.</p>
          <p>The other thing I look at, which is important, is if you look at our balance sheet, there's a $300 billion portfolio, mostly very high quality stuff. There's a lot of short-term assets in repo. And we have, what is it, $1 trillion of deposits and $700 billion of loans. We look at that as a very stable funding source. That's true in almost every single business that deposits are in excess of loans. That's even true in middle market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I hope you convince these people in the regulatory area that the industry now does have an excessive amount of capital relative to any time in its history, and it's just a ridiculous position. But thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I just saw your report that came out. And between capital and these LCR ratios, the LCR hasn't all been issued. It isn't finished all either, but there are some serious issues about how they look at certain types of deposits and certain types of revolvers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jeff Harte with Sandler O'Neill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of follow-up questions; one, on the fixed-trading side, it's easy to talk about fixed income trading has been soft the last couple of quarters. But if we compare your fixed income trading revenues the last couple of quarters to pre-2009, they've been really, really good. How do you think about more of a secular outlook as far as fixed income trading, where it was for JPMorgan, and where it's going for JPMorgan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the way you should think of it, we built a world-class trading business. And I think you can go back several years ago. That wasn't completely true. We had extremely volatile results. We weren't strong in a lot of areas. Now we're strong in a lot of different areas. We've always had some historical strengths. We're still building the commodities side, which we're going to continue to build. If you look at shares, if you look at Greenwich reports and other people who report shares, our shares have gone up dramatically in trading. I'm talking about over years now. I'm not talking about over quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The last thing I'd remind everybody too is in '09, which was record revenues, that's in part because spreads blew out quite significantly. And so we're looking at aggregate numbers here where volumes are up, spreads have normalized, and revenues on a historical basis are pretty solid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Does that answer your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And then secondly, you mentioned the selling of non-performing loans. Is maybe an acceleration of that activity or more sales more a function of finding better bids or deciding to sell at lower prices?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, we are purely economic, so we're not going to sell something just to sell it. Sometimes you think it's worth X. The buyer think it's worth a little bit more than X. Sometimes they're better able to handle it. They're more local. They're more capable, et cetera. So I wouldn't read anything into that other than it's the normal pruning of what we do and how we look at our exposures, and I don't think it had any material effect on the numbers this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. In fact, it was net positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, but not materially.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But not material.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I think as much from an environmental standpoint if there's risk appetite, there are more aggressive bids out there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think there's a little bit more risk appetite. As the year progressed, there was more risk appetite for people to take on things like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your final question comes from the line of Carole Berger with Soleil.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, just one technical because Glenn asked my questions, of course, but why the change in the timing for the net charge-offs? Did you move towards industry standards? Are you leading the industry towards faster charge-offs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Carole, the $632 million, I think it was largely just based on our own observations and experience relative to the delinquent loan portfolio in home lending. It was nothing more than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Jamie, would you like to give us a preview or a plug for your Analyst Day in February?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, our folks are working hard. If you have questions and stuff you want answered, just send them into Lauren. But you're going to hear from every business, and we're going to talk about the future, the growth opportunities, obviously balance sheet, returns, targets. We're going to try to cover the whole shebang for you.</p>
          <p>We feel great about the company. If you look at the underlying results here, we're growing. We've got a lot of businesses. They're all doing quite well. They've done well through this crisis. We never stopped making money. We never stopped investing. We never stopped marketing. We never stopped helping clients around the world. So this company is, I think the future is extremely bright in spite of all the headwinds. I think if you're an owner of bank stocks, you can make a long, long list of all kinds of things hanging over banks, regulatory, Basel. And I think there's some truth to that. But also during the course, some of these things will be resolved and we'll go on. They may have a negative effect, positive effect. There are always unintended consequences, but there's a chance some of those will be positive, too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Folks, thank you very much for spending time with us, and we will be talking to you soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's conference call. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>