<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1355916" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-04-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>296</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Paul Alexander</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Senior Vice President">Mark A. Buthman</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Thomas J. Falk</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co., Inc.">Ali Dibadj</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Christopher Ferrara</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities LLC">Gail S. Glazerman</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Wendy C. Nicholson</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (United States)">Chip A. Dillon</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Lauren R. Lieberman</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Bill Schmitz</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies &amp; Co., Inc.">Douglas M. Lane CFA, MBA</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Morningstar Research">Erin Lash</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Janney Montgomery Scott LLC">John P. San Marco</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Weeden &amp; Co. LP">Javier Escalante MBA</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Caris &amp; Co., Inc.">Linda Bolton Weiser</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">John Faucher</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Buckingham Research Group, Inc.">Alice Beebe Longley</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">Jason M. Gere</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your patience in holding. We now have your speakers in conference. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>It is now my pleasure to introduce Mr. Paul Alexander.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David, and good morning, everyone. Welcome to our first quarter earnings conference call. Here with me in Dallas are Tom Falk, Chairman and CEO; Mark Buthman, Senior VP and CFO; and Mike Azbell, Vice President and Controller.</p>
          <p>Here's the agenda for the call. Mark will begin with a review of our first quarter results, followed by a brief overview of our full-year outlook. Then Tom will then provide his perspective, and we'll finish with Q&amp;A. As usual, we have a presentation of today's materials in the Investors section of our website, which is www.Kimberly-Clark.com.</p>
          <p>Before we begin, let me remind you; we'll be making forward-looking statements during the call. There can be no assurance that future events will occur as anticipated or that our results will be as estimated. And I'd refer you to the Risk Factors section of our latest Annual Report on Form 10-K for a further discussion of forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>I'd also like to point out that we will be referring to adjusted results and outlook. For 2010, adjusted results exclude a loss related to the move to highly inflationary accounting in Venezuela. For 2011, adjusted results and outlook exclude costs for the pulp and tissue restructuring and a non-deductible business tax charge in the first quarter related to a law change in Colombia. For further information and reconciliations to comparable financial measures determined in accordance with GAAP, please see today's news release and additional information on our website.</p>
          <p>And now, I'll turn it over to Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Paul, and good morning.</p>
          <p>Let me start with three key headlines for the quarter. First, we delivered organic sales growth of more than 2%, and we made good progress with our targeted growth initiatives. Second, we returned a significant amount of capital to shareholders. And third, while cost inflation is weighing on our near-term profitability, we're taking a number of actions to ensure we deliver on our commitments for the year.</p>
          <p>Now let's cover the details of the quarter. Overall sales increased 4% to $5 billion. Organic sales rose more than 2%, on track with our full-year plan. Sales volumes improved 2%, while the combined impact of changes in net selling prices and product mix was slightly positive.</p>
          <p>Volumes benefited from innovation and targeted growth initiatives. On the other hand, we experienced lower volumes in Venezuela, and category demand remained soft in parts of North America.</p>
          <p>First quarter adjusted operating profit fell 14%, with an operating margin of 13.1%. Benefits from top line growth and $60 million of FORCE [Focused on Reducing Costs Everywhere] cost savings were more than offset by input cost inflation of $195 million. First quarter adjusted earnings per share were $1.09 compared to $1.14 last year, and included benefits from a decline in the tax rate and a lower share count.</p>
          <p>Cash provided by operations for the quarter was $250 million compared to $464 million in the prior year. Looking forward, I expect our cash generation to build throughout the year as earnings grow and we complete nearly all of our pension plan contributions in the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>First quarter capital spending was $234 million compared to $184 million last year. We're off to a strong start supporting our growth, innovation, and cost reduction programs.</p>
          <p>We repurchased 13.1 million shares of KMB stock at a cost of about $850 million in the quarter. And we're on track to execute our $1.5 billion <mark type="audio gap" /> (3:50 &#x2013; 4:10)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we apologize for the inconvenience. It is now my pleasure to reintroduce Mr. Paul Alexander.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, David, and we apologize. We had some technical challenges with the conference call. So just for the sake of full transparency, we will re-begin with Mark Buthman's conference call remarks, and then we'll turn it over to Tom Falk. So with that, I'd like to hand it over to Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Paul, and good morning, again.</p>
          <p>Let me recap the three key headlines for the quarter. First, we delivered organic sales growth of more than 2%, and made good progress on our targeted growth initiatives. Second, we returned a significant amount of capital to shareholders. And third, while cost inflation is weighing on our near-term profitability, we're taking a number of actions to ensure we deliver on our commitments for the year.</p>
          <p>Now, let's cover the details of the quarter. Overall sales increased 4% to $5 billion. Organic sales rose more than 2%, which is on track with our full-year plan. Sales volumes improved 2%, while the combined impact of changes in net selling prices and product mix was slightly positive.</p>
          <p>Volumes benefited from innovation and targeted growth initiatives. On the other hand, we experienced lower volumes in Venezuela, and category demand remained soft in parts of North America.</p>
          <p>First quarter adjusted operating profit fell 14%, with an operating margin of 13.1%. Benefits from top line growth and $60 million of FORCE cost savings were more than offset by input cost inflation of $195 million in the quarter. First quarter adjusted earnings per share were $1.09 compared with $1.14 last year, and included benefits from a decline in the tax rate and a lower share count.</p>
          <p>Cash provided by operations for the quarter was $250 million compared to $464 million in the prior year. Looking forward, I expect our cash generation to build throughout the year as earnings grow and we complete nearly all of our pension plan contributions in the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>First quarter capital spending was $234 million. That's compared to $184 million last year. We're off to a strong start supporting our growth, innovation, and cost reduction programs.</p>
          <p>We repurchased 13.1 million shares of KMB stock at a cost of about $850 million in the quarter. We're on track to execute our $1.5 billion share repurchase plan for 2011. In total, we allocated more than $1.1 billion to share repurchases and dividends in the first quarter as we continue to allocate capital in shareholder friendly ways.</p>
          <p>Now I'll highlight a few areas of our segment results for the quarter. And as usual, further details are in this morning's news release. In Personal Care, organic sales were even with last year. Sales volumes improved 2%, offset by changes in net selling prices and product mix. In North America, we delivered double-digit volume growth in Feminine Care for the fifth consecutive quarter, and high single-digit growth in Adult Care.</p>
          <p>Momentum also remained strong in our targeted growth initiatives across K-C International. On the other hand, volumes fell significantly in Venezuela. And the Baby and Child Care categories in North America remain relatively soft.</p>
          <p>Personal Care operating margins of 17.8% were impacted by cost inflation, primarily for oil-based materials and a higher level of promotional activity in North America. There were also a few smaller items, including some machine startups and supply chain disruptions, which I wouldn't expect to recur going forward.</p>
          <p>Now turning to consumer tissue, organic sales grew 3%. Net selling prices were up 2%, led by cost driven price increases in K-C International in Europe. Changes in product mix improved sales 1%. Sales volumes were even with last year, as gains in bathroom tissue and Kleenex facial tissue in North America were offset by declines elsewhere. Operating margins of 9% were below prior-year levels, as higher net selling prices and cost savings were more than offset by cost inflation, mostly fiber costs.</p>
          <p>Moving to K-C Professional and other, organic sales increased 4%. Sales volumes grew 3%, including double-digit growth in our Safety business in North America and a mid-single-digit gain overall in K-C International. On the other hand, relatively soft market demand continued to impact our washroom sales in North America. Operating margins of 13.5% were down slightly but remained solid despite the challenging environment.</p>
          <p>And lastly, Health Care organic sales were up 5%, driven by higher sales volumes of 6%. Volumes of high margin medical devices were up high single digits, paced by I-Flow and our airway management business. Supply volumes grew mid-single digits and benefited from a modest improvement in category demand in the North American market. Operating margins were down somewhat compared to last year, and it's mostly due to cost inflation and ongoing litigation expenses related to the I-Flow acquisition.</p>
          <p>So that wraps up the review of the quarter. Before I hand it over to Tom, I'd like to briefly comment on the updated outlook that was provided in this morning's news release. We've widened our estimate for 2011 adjusted earnings per share, which we now expect to be between $4.80 and $5.05 a share. There has been no change to the top end of our previous guidance range, but we've lowered the bottom end by $0.10 a share. The wider range reflects a significantly higher cost inflation assumption of $450 million to $550 million for the year. That's more than double our previous assumption, and represents an incremental headwind of more than $0.45 per share compared to our previous plan.</p>
          <p>We're responding to the significant pickup in cost inflation in three primary ways. First, we're raising selling prices across a number of our businesses. Second, we're accelerating or implementing additional FORCE cost savings programs. And third, we're focused on managing our overhead spending aggressively. Now, Tom will talk more about our specific plans in each of these areas. All in all, we expect these actions, along with other modest changes to our plan, to offset most, if not all, of the incremental inflationary headwinds we're now anticipating compared to our previous plan.</p>
          <p>So that wraps up my review. To recap, we achieved top line growth in line with our plan for the year, with further progress on targeted growth initiatives. We delivered on our commitment to return significant capital to shareholders. And we're taking actions to combat the inflationary headwinds facing our business.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn it over to Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark, and good morning, everyone. I'll share my perspectives on the state of our business after the first three months of 2011; and more importantly, what we're doing to overcome the headwinds we face, and then we'll get to your questions. In short, we're executing our global business plan strategies and we're taking aggressive actions in a challenging near-term environment.</p>
          <p>Looking at our organic sales growth and our market positions, we're on track with our plan in the first quarter. Our volume growth was the best we've delivered since 2009. And as you heard from Mark, we continue to make good progress with our targeted growth initiatives, particularly in K-C International, our K-C Professional Safety business, and our Health Care Medical Device business. We're also getting good returns on our innovation and marketing investments. This is especially true in Feminine Care and Adult Care in North America, where the initiatives we began last year on U by Kotex, Poise, and Depend continued to deliver volume and share growth.</p>
          <p>And looking more broadly at our share positions, we held or increased market share in seven of our eight key consumer categories in the U.S. That included share gains of four points in Feminine Care, three points in Adult Care, two points in baby wipes, and one point in both Child Care and facial tissue. And we're growing ahead of category rates in a number of markets in K-C International, such as Brazil.</p>
          <p>In terms of overall market demand, portions of the North American market are still relatively soft, but there are early signs that conditions are starting to improve. And most importantly, we have a number of innovations coming to market in the next few quarters to further improve our brands. We're launching an improved Huggies diaper in North America in the second quarter, and Jeans Diapers will be hitting the store shelves in the near future. We'll also be introducing an exciting Huggies diaper line extension later this summer.</p>
          <p>Outside diapers, we'll be launching improved PULL-UPS training pants, new and improved U by Kotex and Poise products, some upgraded Cottonelle bathroom tissue offerings, and new Kleenex facial tissue offerings. And we have plenty of innovation coming in K-C International as well.</p>
          <p>So our innovation pipeline is healthy. We're executing strong marketing programs, and we're continuing do what's right for the long-term success and health of our brands.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the cost environment and what we're doing to improve our profitability, clearly the environment is much more challenging since we talked to you last at the beginning of this year. Market pulp costs did not fall in the first quarter like we and most others had assumed. Instead, costs rose in March, and over the next few months are likely to hit or potentially even exceed the peak levels that occurred last summer.</p>
          <p>In addition, as we all know, oil prices have risen rapidly to over $100 a barrel. This is well above what we planned for, and it has caused prices for many of our oil based cost inputs to increase considerably. For example, polymer costs are up about 20% both year over year and sequentially from the fourth quarter of 2010. Similarly, super-absorbent costs are up 15%, and costs for both of these key materials are expected to increase further in the near term.</p>
          <p>Now it's our job to manage through these headwinds, and that's what we're working very hard to do. As Mark mentioned, we're focused on increasing net realized revenue, implementing additional FORCE cost savings programs, and reducing overhead spending compared to our previous plans.</p>
          <p>Let me share some more details on each of these areas. First on the revenue front, many of our businesses are increasing selling prices. Last month, we announced increases for most of our North American consumer products businesses that will go into effect over the summer. We're also in the process of raising prices in many areas of K-C International, particularly in Latin America. And our B-to-B businesses are also taking pricing action, including a North American K-C Professional price increase that we announced last week. So as a result, we now anticipate that price and mix improvements will deliver one to two points of revenue growth in 2011. That's up from our original assumption of about 1%.</p>
          <p>Second, we're aggressively identifying and implementing incremental FORCE cost savings programs. Our global procurement organization and our Lean Continuous Improvement capabilities will help us deliver even more savings in the current environment. So all together, we now expect FORCE cost savings of $250 million to $300 million in 2011, and that's $50 million more than our original planning assumption.</p>
          <p>And third, we'll be reducing overhead spending compared to our original plans. We're using Lean Continuous Improvement to reduce the costs of our back office operations, and we're closely managing our spending on discretionary items. As a result of our control of SG&amp;A spending, we're now targeting for total between-the-lines expenses to grow in line with or potentially slower than the rate of sales growth in 2011.</p>
          <p>So all in all, the benefits from our actions to improve revenue realization and reduce costs will be more visible in our results in the back half of the year. I also expect our innovation and growth initiatives to build momentum as the year progresses. All of these actions require strong focus and discipline, and I'm confident in our team's ability to execute these plans while we continue to build an even brighter future for our company.</p>
          <p>So to summarize, we're continuing to execute our global business plan strategies for the long-term success of Kimberly-Clark. We are aggressively managing those factors we can control to deliver solid results in the near term. And we're firmly convinced that successful execution of our global business plan will improve shareholder value over time.</p>
          <p>So that wraps up our prepared remarks, and now we'll begin to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Ali Dibadj with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Ali.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pretty good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. I just had a question. If you could, talk a little bit about what's different this time versus last time from a commodity increase &#x2013; the environment and commodity increases. If you look at Personal Care, for example, the last time in 7/08, the margins held in pretty well. This time, it sounded like Mark had mentioned there were some one-off things. But subsequent to that, your operating margins were, as far as I can tell, the worst you've seen in &#x2013; gosh, it looks like a decade in the model. What's different now versus last time on that metric in that segment along a number of dimensions, whether it be competitive environment, whether it be just these one-time really driving that, et cetera?</p>
          <p>And then on consumer tissue similarly, I guess high single digits one would expect at these levels. How do you describe that environment right now as well from a competitive environment, and what's different versus last time?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'd say the reasons why the commodity costs are higher are different, so I think that's part of it. But we had a pretty big hit on margins on tissue when pulp spiked to over $1,000 [per ton] the last time as well. So I'd say yes, we're a little below where our low watermark was for Personal Care margins, and some of that that was the one-time. Some of it was the pricing environment globally was a little bit more aggressive, so we had a little bit bigger trade spend in the first quarter, so that's probably part of it. So timing and promotion activity is part of it. We certainly expect our margins to improve from where they are over the back half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I would say also the makeup of cost inflation is probably &#x2013; if you think about it as two-thirds oil and oil related costs, one-third fiber, that's a little different mix than we've experienced in the past. And oil and oil related costs tend to impact Personal Care a little bit more than you'd see in tissue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I also think some of the underlying commodities are adjusting quicker now that than they may be used to; so polymers are reacting a little more quickly as well as super-absorbent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And by the same token, you are, it sounds like, trying to react more quickly as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. In that context, I guess, how do we think about your guidance? How much confidence do you have in your guidance? Why should we believe in your guidance in a sense? And it was that you went through the incremental tier and $75 million in commodities roughly and how that breaks out in terms of pricing and FORCE and overhead. But could you put a few more numbers behind some of that and let us know your confidence in each one of them, particularly around the competitive environment going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ali, I think you know us well enough. We try to tell you how we really think it's going to turn out every time we do this call. So our confidence level around guidance is always pretty high, or we wouldn't guide it to this level. And so we're not always right, and sometimes things happen that we didn't expect. So certainly, based on the assumptions that are in there that we shared with you in terms of input costs and cost savings, we're pretty confident we can deliver in all those areas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And last one is something you talked about that you do have control over is buybacks. Can you give us a sense of the pace of that as you go forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. As we said in the January call, and Mark can give a little more color, but we expect to have most of our planned buybacks done for the year in the first half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think that's fair to say. We'll have some to do in the back half, but we've got a significant amount out in the first quarter. We'll take that pace down just a little bit in the second quarter, but the majority will be done by the time we finish with June.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And nothing incremental planned at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We already had a pretty big step up in this year's planned buyback activity, so we'll see how cash flow looks later in the year. But at this point, we're pretty comfortable with the plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ali.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Chris Ferrara with Bank of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, guys. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pretty good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So I guess I wanted to follow on a little more specifically on that first line of questioning. I guess the specifics are, consumer tissue North America, Personal Care globally, it seems that pricing is a little bit more challenged. You have deeper levels of promotional spending in Personal Care. Yet, you're turning around today and saying that pricing realization is going to be a little bit better, and your volume assumptions aren't changing much, I guess. So what gives you the confidence that volume won't drop off more, particularly in Personal Care? I guess now that the competitive environment is already difficult, now you're going to price on top of that difficult competitive environment, and you don't see a lot of volume fall-off? Or maybe you do and it's just embedded in a bigger number. I guess if you can give a little color around that, it would be very helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. On tissue in particular, last year in the first quarter, we were on allocation on Scott tissue. So we had constrained promotional spending somewhat, and it returned to more normal levels late in the year. So it's not as big of a jump if you look at the average for 2010 versus where we spent in the first quarter. So we'd say part of it is the comparison &#x2013; a different set of issues, but a similar story on Personal Care, where last year's first quarter was a little lighter promotional calendar. We had Jeans Diaper come in the second quarter and spent a little more aggressively on that, and so we had a little bit more promotion.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter, we also had some competitive activity in the first quarter that we were matching up to that ramped up in the latter part of last year, particularly in K-C International. So from that standpoint, some of it's in the quarterly comparison. It was probably the toughest in the first quarter. If you looked at it versus the year average, it wouldn't be up by as much.</p>
          <p>And then to the second question about demand, on Baby Care, it's really more of a function of the birth rate than consumers deciding to constrain purchases of diapers. And so we've seen a relatively depressed birth rate really since the economic downturn began in 2008 &#x2013; 2009, and have actually seen probably a 5% decline in the total number of annual live births over that cumulative period. So we're expecting that to start to pick up in the second half of the year and to level off in the first half.</p>
          <p>And so we'll see how the data progresses, but we don't think industry price changes will have a big impact on that. We'll obviously watch private label share and pricing gaps to see what happens in that standpoint to see if there is any category down-trade. But with all the innovation we have coming, with an improved Huggies diaper that starts to ship; with Jeans Diapers in the second quarter, we've got some exciting news on Huggies that we'll be talking about later this year, all those factors we feel pretty good about our innovation plan for the year.</p>
          <p>In tissue, you see a similar story. We've got pretty good momentum going on Cottonelle. And as we see the pricing take hold in the market, we don't expect to see a big hit there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it sounds like, if I can characterize it right, you're saying that the higher levels of promo that you guys cited and the fact that pricing &#x2013; I think in North America, pricing decelerated sequentially in a couple of the categories. Are you saying that the comp issue, you don't feel like the competitive environment is particularly more heated right now that it was over the last six months? Is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, with the caveats that in some markets where we've talked about principal competitors, in Baby and Child Care in particular that heated up last year, that has abated somewhat, but not substantially, but not as much in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's helpful. And then just I guess on pricing geographically, North America, obviously, you've already made the big announcement. Can you just talk a little bit about elsewhere? We haven't heard anything on Europe. And in China, is there any chance of taking &#x2013; or in Asia in general, is there any chance of taking pricing, and in Europe, I guess, also?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think what you want to look for is where you've had very strong currencies, you're probably not going to see much opportunity for price because you're not going to actually have the same impact on their local currency cost structure. So in markets like Latin America, we'll probably be getting more price, where their currencies haven't appreciated that much relative to the dollar. So we'll be aggressive there. In other markets like Australia, which has had a very strong move against the U.S. dollar, probably not a big move on price there because it's not really going to be justified in the local currency market. In other markets like Vietnam, they have had very high inflation, so you see pretty high price realization there. In China, there is a lot of launch activity going on, so it is a pretty competitive market, so probably not as much of an opportunity to gain pricing in China, but that's one we'll continue to watch and try to drive mix and innovation there to get revenue realization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot for the time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Gail Glazerman with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Gail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Can you talk a little bit more about the Personal Care volume in international markets? I know you said Venezuela was a big impact on that. Perhaps if you could quantify, and are you seeing any sense of pressure and resistance to price increases in this market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think Venezuela was &#x2013; Paul, what was it, a couple points of drag in the Personal Care numbers overall?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Correct, it took about 0.5 point out of our total consolidated volumes. And it more skewed to Personal Care, obviously.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we saw broadly good results across most of the international markets, probably not as rapidly growing as in prior quarters. It was a little slower for us in Eastern Europe. We still had double-digit gains in China and high single-digit growth across Latin America ex-Venezuela.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And is it possible to break out and quantify some of the operating and one-off costs that you had in Personal Care in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we had several startups, and some of them didn't go as well as planned, and so it wasn't any one thing that was as big of a deal. The bigger factor driving the margin was cost inflation and higher trade spending.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Tom, you had mentioned, I guess, some early signs of economic recovery. Is that something you can elaborate on? Where are you seeing it? Is it change in buying patterns? Is it in K-C Professional?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple of areas; obviously, we expect the birth rate to stabilize and start to pick up in the U.S. in the back half of the year, and we look at lots of long-range forecasts on that. A lot of it is related to consumer confidence and so forth. So we're seeing small positive signs there.</p>
          <p>In our KCP business, we had double-digit volume growth in Safety in the quarter, which is good. Manufacturing related stuff is starting to move again. On the other hand, office vacancies are still bumping along the bottom, so not a lot of improvement in that segment. Lodging as well is at near historic lows. So it's a mixed bag, but in some of the manufacturing segments, we're starting to see decent growth. We actually had decent volume growth in KCP in Europe. Germany is heating up and recovering nicely. And then in the emerging markets, we saw still pretty solid volume growth in KCP.</p>
          <p>Health Care as well had decent volume growth this quarter, which has been a pretty stable performer. So we're past the H1N1 comps and are back to more normal growth in Health Care, which was positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just my last question, you've touched on some of this. But in terms of the price increases that you have announced, mainly in the North American market, can you give us any sense of color to both the competitive and the customer response to that, and any areas hat you'd be particularly concerned about risk of trade down? Markets like paper towels seem to be still pretty weak for you. Are you concerned that this will just make that issue &#x2013; aggravate that issue, I guess?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think our announced price increases were in bathroom tissue, diapers, baby wipes. And so I think there has been some competitive announcement on paper towels that we'll obviously be evaluating. But I think that like anything else in these things, you announce your price increase. I don't think I've ever seen a customer yet that said thank you for that, and so just as we've dealt with our suppliers hand us cost increases. So it's a competitive environment, and we'll see what happens in the marketplace. I think recently, we had confirmation that one of our principal competitors was going to follow. On the KCP front, actually a couple of other competitors led price increases that we recently followed. So I think it's not surprising when you look almost across every category out there, you're seeing the impact of higher commodity costs show up in higher selling prices for everything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Wendy Nicholson with Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Wendy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, two questions. First, I know you don't like to give specific quarterly guidance. But I wanted to get a feel &#x2013; I hope I didn't miss it &#x2013; for any of the moving pieces in the second quarter. If most of the pricing isn't going to go into effect until the summer months, I assume the second quarter is going to feel more gross margin pressure, but maybe you're going to get a volume bump as some retailers take inventory in prior to the price increase. Can you comment on that generally?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't give any quarterly color on that, but I'd say you're thinking about the right variables. So in the second quarter, we'll not have much benefit from any selling price moves, at least certainly not in North America. And we do try to manage the amount that customers forward buy on pricing because it just screws up everybody's supply chain. So I wouldn't be looking for too big of a volume move there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Wendy, the other thing I would add is in the near term, costs are going up sequentially. Although with the amount of shares that we bought back in the first quarter, that should start to benefit the bottom line number more going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But fair to say most of the FORCE savings will probably be back-half loaded as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we're pretty steady implementers of those programs, so I think you should start to see those build as the quarters go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fine. And then on currency, I know you shifted the expectation there of a one point benefit to a two point benefit on the top line. But I'm surprised you didn't call that out in terms of something that was going to insulate your earnings maybe a little bit more than expected? And can you remind us what the translation is or if there's a multiplier effect in terms of if currency is going to benefit the top line by two points, what's the impact on your operating margin or your operating profit? Is it the same two points, or is it a little bit more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's roughly about that. It always depends on what currencies are moving. But essentially, the change from the one point benefit to two points of benefit on the top line, translation to the bottom line is about $25 million or $30 million of operating profit. So it is one of those other items that is a bit better than we had planned originally.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect, okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Wendy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Chip Dillon with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yes, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Chip.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First question is to dive a little bit into the higher costs, it looks like the midpoint of your expectations are up about $275 million, but FORCE will offset $50 million of that, so I get $225 million. And I hate to go so fast with the math, but that looks like about $0.35 to $0.40 a share after tax. And I suppose you'll get also some benefit from currency. But all added in, it looks like to offset that, you need about 2% higher average pricing over the second half of the year, which certainly seems reasonable given your announcements, if you can get them. Am I on the right track there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're a little high on the price front. So basically, our cost inflation, we went up from $200 million to $250 million to around $450 million, I think. And so it was about a couple hundred million move. If you get an average of about 0.5 point more price, that's $100 million. Some additional FORCE cost saving is another $50 million, and, then, some benefits from currency and between-the-line spending and those kinds of things is roughly how you'd get there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'm sorry. I meant 2% for the half, so that would be about 1% for the year. I see. And of course, currency helps you as well. Since you've come out both in the U.S. market on disposable diapers and on retail tissue, have you seen anything in the marketplace, any movement from other competitors so far?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe that one of our principal competitors has confirmed that they're going up on diaper pricing and on roll tissue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. Okay, got you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You'll be able to ask them questions later this week.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you, that's pretty good. So for one, it actually does answer your questions. That's good to know. And, the last question, this is more for Mark, not to put you on the spot. I just wanted to get an update on the, this is Note 2 from the K. But when you look at the timber notes you all got back years and years ago, I think you've been carrying about $615 million give or take on your balance sheet, which overstates your debt and your assets. Is that number still about right, and do you see that changing much in the next year or two?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think we've got &#x2013; I think the disclosure speaks for itself. We've got financing out there that is secured financing around the timber that we sold. And...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's more a tax planning strategy, Chip, so nothing is really changed on that. It remains in force, and we haven't had to pay the tax yet based on how it has been structured.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are two notes in there, Chip, and we paid one of those off. That may be the movement that you're seeing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, so is it now below $617 million?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's about $400 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And was that paid off in the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it was last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Last year, got you. And last question, again, I understand how...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chip, you're really getting into the 10-K. That's good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We try to do our homework. Listen, the last question is I know that a lot of these structures allow you to &#x2013; obviously, the longer you can push this out, the better it is. Is this something that you believe you can keep pushing out say for more than five years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we're going to go there on this one, Chip.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're pretty deep in the dirt here. So I think the disclosure stands for itself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you, I totally understand. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Lauren Lieberman with Barclays.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Lauren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning. I just wanted to ask a question or two about marketing spending because there was no specific mention in the press release and I know coming into the year, the plan was for strategic marketing to increase faster than sales. Is that still the plan, or should we think about it as being more of an in line with sales kind of year or even below?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I would expect to see absolute spending go up this year, but probably by about the same or slightly less than sales. And so we're getting pretty good returns on our innovation spend. We've got a lot of innovation coming, and we're also getting some efficiency in how we spend the money. So we think we're adequately funding the innovation, which is our near-term strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on paper towels, I know you, notably, did not initiate pricing there in North America. But as we think through the fact that the volumes have been challenged for quite a while now, both category and your shares, what is the plan? Is there innovation coming in towels? Is there efforts to regain some shelf space for Scott towels? How are you guys thinking about the strategic outlook for that business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We continue to drive innovation and gain distribution back on both Viva and Scott towels. We're back on air with Viva this year with Mike Rowe, our celebrity spokesperson for Viva. So we've actually &#x2013; that's out and the team is making some headway with that. And so I expect to see us continue to support both those brands.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then finally just on curtailment, so there was some curtailment expense in the quarter. Where did that leave you at the end of the quarter? Is there an expectation of further curtailment in tissue in Q2 or Q3, or do you think you're pretty clean from here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the way you should think about it is that we're really focusing on managing two variables. It's customer service levels and days inventory outstanding. And so we're taking curtailment, as we need to, to hit those variables. And so I think part of the comparison to last year is that because we ran allocation, our customer service wasn't where we wanted it to be, so we ran everything we had in tissue particularly flat out in the first quarter of last year. And this one was probably more normal sequentially to where we were in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lauren, so for the full year, curtailment really shouldn't be a positive or a negative. It should be pretty neutral.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I'm sorry, so the $25 million in this quarter, does that work its way through the system, so it actually ends up being a positive from here, or is it just that there's no further impact?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It could be a small positive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. I'll leave it there, thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Lauren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Bill Schmitz with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A couple things, one is housekeeping. But if you look at your cost of goods sold breakdown, and you disclose pulp and polypropylene and some other things, that's only about a third of your total cost of goods sold. So what's going on with the other two-thirds that we really can't track as closely?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That should be more than two-thirds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our costs are going up, Bill, on packaging, materials, adhesives. Really, just about everything that's going into our products are going up. Individually, they may be smaller, so we don't disclose them, but they all add up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and so you assume similar inflation to some of the oil based stuff and the pulp?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Basically, if you look at everything from polymer, packaging material, adhesives, super-absorbent, they all use the petroleum molecule in some fashion, and so they're related to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, that's really helpful. And, then, again, I know Wendy asked a question about the second quarter. But if I look at some of the variances, like I think last year you had $105 million of FORCE savings in the quarter, you had a big restructuring benefit. How do you lap all that stuff?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, we're more focused on hitting the full-year guidance at this point, and so, than trying to manage any one individual quarter to have a quarterly comparison that's favorable or unfavorable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and last year FORCE was pretty consistent across the year. So the big restructuring benefit we got was in the third quarter of '09. So year on year, we don't have the same comparison issue maybe that we wrestled with in the third quarter of last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I've got you. And then what was I saying? In terms of elasticity on some of this pricing, are you seeing historical trends prevailing, or has it gotten worse? How has it been trending?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The other thing, if you look out there at every category, you're seeing this kind of pricing popping up. So it's certainly happening in food. It's happening in other non-food categories. It's happening at the gas pump. And so I suspect what you're seeing is the consumer potentially is less sensitive. I think we're also getting more sophisticated in our pricing ability in terms of targeting price points and understanding consumer shopper behavior. So where we're doing it with count versus list is more sophisticated as well. So we're intentionally trying to avoid having big elasticity challenges.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Doug Lane with Jefferies.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Doug.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just looking at the gross margin trend the last year, you saw all of the commodities went up. You saw sequential deterioration in the second quarter and the third quarter. And then in the fourth quarter, it really evened out. And frankly, if I remember right, it was pretty substantially better than what I was looking for. And then, it looks like that has reversed in the first quarter, so I wonder, what is the main difference in the gross margin landscape, which looked like it was, at least from a margin improving in the December quarter, and now it looks like it's going the other way in the March quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sequentially, our gross margin was down about 170 basis points from Q4. A lot of that is going to be pulp and polymer, in particular, are up year on year. But I don't know if I have any color on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Doug, the two main factors are first, as Tom mentioned, inflation, especially in the oil based materials. They moved up quickly in Q1. And then the other thing is promotion activity. We had more trade promotion in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So are we going to see that promotional give-and-take as prices go up, so that we really won't get the full benefit of the price increase maybe adjusted for promotions until we get really into the third or even fourth quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think we've got some activity in K-C International that you'll start to see in Q2. But the reality is the big price increase in North America doesn't start to go into effect until the end of Q2.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Doug.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Erin Lash with Morningstar.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, thanks for taking my question. Obviously, cost pressures aren't unique to Kimberly-Clark. But I was wondering if you could discuss or provide some additional details on your conversations with retailers, both domestically and abroad, in terms of the cost pressures and the pricing action that you've been taking.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think retailers certainly understand what's going on because they're hearing it from every supplier. So whether you're selling Corn Flakes or Kleenex, you're seeing the impact of higher commodity costs show up in pricing discussions. And so retailers understand it, but they also want to understand how you're going to help them drive their business overall and how you're going to make it relevant to the consumer and handle it in the shopping environment. So I think every one of those discussions goes a little differently, but that's basically the nature of it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And switching gears, beyond your share repurchase program that you've already announced, could you talk about your priorities for cash use and what your appetite for potential acquisitions are in this environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, sure. We continue &#x2013; the dividend is important. We've increased our dividend at a rate faster than earnings for the last several years, and had a top-tier dividend payout, so that's important to us. And then, obviously, providing enough capital to invest in our business to continue the innovation growth and top line growth in emerging markets that we've seen, so we'll spend close to $1 billion on capital spending this year; and so that's, obviously, a key priority. And then where we see tuck-in M&amp;A opportunities, we would, obviously, look for those. We're disciplined and approach it in that fashion. But I don't see anything substantial that's on the horizon at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from John San Marco with Janney.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you drill down into the quarter's K-C International volume growth? Specifically, did it disappoint you at all? And I know there's both inelasticity and some Venezuela issues in those numbers. But presumably, neither of those are going away. So I'm looking for a reason to believe we'll get a recovery there as the year progresses and get something back to normal volume-wise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say you've seen a little bit slower category growth, China, for example, we've been growing last year in the 25% to 30% range in Personal Care. We were double digit this quarter, but lower double digit. We've got a lot of aggressive expansion going on there and expect that to continue. But these are all competitive environments as well. And so if the Chinese economy slows a bit, you could see a little slower rate of category penetration in some of these markets.</p>
          <p>Latin America continued to be pretty solid. So ex-Venezuela, we had volume growth in Personal Care that was high single digits. That's pretty consistent with where it has been, with good category penetration.</p>
          <p>Eastern Europe is probably the one that has been more of a challenge for us. And some of that is just that it's in a more competitive environment and more competitive pricing pressure. And so that market actually dipped in volume in the quarter, and we would expect that to turn around and return to growth with some of the activity that we have planned there for the balance of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. So you were pricing ahead of your category in Eastern Europe, I take it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was more competitive activity was pricing below us, and we were probably a little slow to come down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and just one last question. You commented I think in your prepared remarks that you're expecting live birth growth starting in the second half of this year from what has been a pretty severe decline. I guess my first question is, is that a global expectation, and how does that add up geographically? And then secondly, can you share what data you're basing that expectation on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that was really related to the U.S. market. And we look at various consumer confidence surveys to get a projection on that, and use the same types of sources. And we can get you the specific details, if you're interested.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd love to. Thank you very much for taking my questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome, John, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Javier Escalante with Weeden &amp; Company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Javier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, how are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very well, it's good to hear your voice again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, a long time; a couple of questions, actually. One is a clarification, if you could please revisit what's happening with North America diapers. Huggies prices were down in the first quarter, I understand, because of trade spending. And now you expect to put a price increase in place in the 3% to 7% range in the third quarter. But does this change in pricing have to do with pre-existing promotional plans you had in place, meaning that it was self-inflicted? Or was it a response to consumer trade-down to Luvs, to the mid-tier pricing from Procter &amp; Gamble?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think two things. One is that a principal competitor had made a count change to an effective bonus pack to add some diapers to the pack. Rather than do that, we decided to match on a price per diaper basis through higher trade spend, and so you saw that impact in the first quarter. Probably the other impact was looking at it versus first quarter last year. We had relatively fewer events scheduled as we were getting ready for the Jeans Diaper launch that happened in the second quarter of last year. So there was more of a normal event calendar in the first quarter of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I see because my question is related to the price increase that Procter is announcing to the retailers. My understanding is it limits only to Pampers, not to Luvs. So the fact that the price increase is only in Pampers, does it in any way change the attainability of the price increase for Huggies in the summertime?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think a couple of things. First of all, we announced what we're going to do on price, and then we see what shakes out in the marketplace. And so I think the information on competition is emerging at this point in time, and we'll see what happens in the marketplace; obviously, what private label does or other competitors do.</p>
          <p>And the second thing is we've got a very strong innovation plan coming with improved mainline Huggies that's beginning to roll out as we speak, Jeans Diaper coming in the second quarter, and then some strong Infant Care category innovation in the last half of the year. And so I think when you're coupling pricing moves with better innovation, that typically has a smaller impact on the category.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood, and finally, more a strategic. In terms of your global pricing strategy, by raising prices in North America but less so in Europe, which is understandable because of the strength of private label there, you have a disadvantaged market share position. Wouldn't you be pushing growth by leaving prices flat in Europe? Wouldn't you be pushing growth in a business that is lower margin at the expense of the North America business and therefore hurting shareholder value? Is this like &#x2013; North America certainly is higher pricing. You have a better competitive position. But at the same time, if you can revisit the whole European strategy there because in the end, if there is no growth in North America, there is even less growth in Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So is there a question in there, Javier, somewhere?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, there is a question. The question basically is why don't you just exit Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's a different question than I thought you were going to ask. No, I think the way that pricing strategies play out is that in every individual market, you look at the dynamics of cost and competition, and you try to get as much net revenue realization as you can, and you do that through a multiple of ways. Some involve innovation. Some involve list price. Some involve promotional strategy. So we did some price realization in the UK on Andrex last year, where we have a very strong brand, really by just adjusting our promotional depth and frequency and didn't do anything with list price. And we were able to improve our revenue realization by reducing the depth and reducing the frequency. And so every one of our teams around the world is trying to improve their margins as much as they can by using all the tools that they have available to them.</p>
          <p>And so a separate question long term is where is Europe from an attractiveness standpoint. Overall, Europe generates a substantial of cash. They delivered on their plan fully in 2010, and we know they're working hard to deliver on their commitments in 2011 as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But you understand that what I'm saying is that basically you are subsidizing Europe by taking prices in North America and leaving Europe prices flat. And therefore, you are basically pushing growth in a market that has lower operating margins, and therefore you are basically destroying shareholder value by doing that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, you need to really look at it market by market. So we're taking price in the U.S. because of the innovation strength, the competitive advantage, and the cost dynamics. In some markets in Europe where we can get price, we'll take price there as well. But it's really more about optimizing each individual market as opposed to a global pricing strategy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Linda Bolton Weiser with Caris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Linda.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, how are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pretty good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Listen, just a big picture question about you've had commodity cost pressures pretty on and off for several years now. And you've been really good about finding cost savings and increasing your cost savings, and you're talking about more overhead cost reductions now. How does that affect your employees and morale? They're just constantly in a cost cutting &#x2013; cut this, cut that type of environment. Can you just address that question about morale and the idea &#x2013; giving them the idea that there's growth and not just cutting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, absolutely, Linda. And I'll be going from this call into a call with our top 1,000 leaders. And we're going to talk about our innovation plans for the back half of the year and the exciting things that we have coming in Huggies and U by Kotex and Poise and Depends and the great opportunity we have to continue to drive our KCP Wiper and Safety business and all the exciting things coming in Health Care and how rapidly we're growing in international markets.</p>
          <p>So it's not about cutting for the sake of cost cutting. It's managing those things that we can control so that we can invest in the long-term future growth options for our business. And we're also telling, hey, we're not going to be victims here. This is the way the world is everywhere. Everybody has got to be good &#x2013; sharp on costs. We've got to be good at pricing. We've got to be good at innovation. And so we're going to make those tough tradeoffs to do the most important things, and the nice-to-have stuff isn't going to get done. So you see, you got a little warm-up of my speech that's going to come to the employees in a few minutes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Linda.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from John Faucher with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, thanks. So I want to talk &#x2013; I know you talked a little bit about potentially the prices of the inputs continuing to move up a little bit sequentially from here. And it has been mentioned before on the call that the gross margin performance year over year last year was a little bit volatile. So my math would say you guys had roughly 6% cost of goods sold per unit inflation, basically taking the 10% COGS inflation, subtracting out unit growth, subtracting out FX. Should we assume a similar level for the second quarter? And then, since the comps change year over year in the back half to a lesser level of COGS per unit inflation in the back half on an FX-neutral basis, if that makes sense?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think directionally, without doing all the math in my head, that sounds right. But if you look at &#x2013; pulp is likely to go up again in April. Polymer is going up in April from where it was in the first quarter. So I think we'll probably have relatively more cost pressure in the second quarter than we &#x2013; and the comps get a little easier in the back half of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Especially on pulp.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Okay, great. And then not to pick at this, but I thought it was interesting that you guys simply lowered the bottom end of the range of the guidance. And given the level of pessimism surrounding the numbers today, can you talk a little bit about if you were to hit the midpoint or above from that standpoint, what do you think would need to go right in order to have a more positive outlook relative towards getting closer to the higher end of your guidance?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Part of the reason for widening the range was when you think about it, just our cost estimate alone swung by $0.45 a share from our last guidance to you and today. We were operating with a $0.15 annual guidance range, so widening it seemed appropriate.</p>
          <p>So how would you get to the top end of the range? If costs wind up being a little bit more positive in the back half of the year, if things settle down in the Middle East, and oil &#x2013; it wasn't that long ago it was $85 a barrel. We're not predicting that. But if you saw some break in commodity costs in the second half, that would be a plus. Obviously, full realization of price and innovation, and particularly in the back half of the year, would get you north of the top end of the range, and then delivering the cost savings and SG&amp;A that we talked about. And so we're aimed at doing all that, at least on the things that we can control. And I think we've still got a shot at the guidance range this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Alice Longley with Buckingham Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Alice.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I have some follow-up questions on the promotional activity for diapers in the U.S. and bath tissue in the U.S. I think those were highlighted in your press release too. Your net selling prices in the U.S. or North America were a negative 3%, and net selling negative 2% for bath tissue. Was that about in line with the industry, or would you say that that net selling number in both cases was a deeper negative than the industry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think because of the factors that I talked a little bit about, it's probably a little worse for us from a comp standpoint. On the tissue front, as I said, in some areas we had some supply challenges in the first quarter of last year, so we had basically pulled back on promotions. And so now that we're back to more of a normal promotion environment in tissue, that's a bigger negative for us than it would be for some other competitors.</p>
          <p>On the diaper front, part of our increase in trade was, again, getting back to a more normal &#x2013; a more robust promotional calendar, so that's probably going to be more our issue. And then we're matching up with some competitive activity with trade spending versus with other tools. In the U.S., when you put a bonus pack in, that shows up as a different &#x2013; that shows up as volume growth, not as higher trade spend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. But on a price per unit basis, would you say that in diaper Child Care, if you were to look at the numbers that way, would net selling prices have gone similarly throughout the industry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I think because of the timing of promotions, we're probably going to be a little higher drag than the industry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You'd see competitive pricing on shelf, so it's more of a comparison issue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And then should we expect the same sorts of numbers in both cases in the second quarter because the price increases won't come through yet?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think in the case of tissue, our supply issues were stabilized by the second quarter of last year, so it shouldn't be as big of a drag.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But in Child Care, it might be similar?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say because we were launching the Jeans Diaper last year or will be doing that again this year. So again, the comparisons should be a little easier in the second quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then once we get to the second half and we get these price increases, but maybe you'll also have incremental trade spend more than you did a year ago? Are we going to see those price increases you set actually come through in the net selling prices that we see, or are the announced price increases going to be offset with incremental trade spending?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Obviously, our focus is to make sure that those announced list price increases do translate into higher net realized revenue in the back half of the year. If you take your list up and spend it all back, you won't have accomplished anything, and so we'll see what happens in the marketplace. But we certainly believe that pricing is justified based on the costs. And if you look at other categories, it's happening in lots of other categories around the grocery store.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then the final piece to that is just to circle back to a former question, you are not assuming much elasticity, so you're going to take this pricing and you don't think volume is going to be hurt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, you can see some short-term volume impacts, particularly if there's some consumer loading ahead of the price change or trade loading ahead of the price change. You can see some volume swings, but we're not assuming any major volume drag at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So the only volume impact would be retailers loading up or not, not the consumer responding?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At this stage, that's our expectation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, super. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alice.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Jason Gere with RBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I beat the clock, just a couple of questions. I guess the first one, just talking about Fem Care and Adult Care, so while the diaper business &#x2013; I hate saying this &#x2013; has been sagging, and I know you're starting to lap some of the innovation, how come there hasn't really been any pricing here? Can you talk about that, and just your expectations in North America for volume growth, that is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pricing in Adult, in some cases, the U by Kotex stuff was already premium priced. And so as we've seen our share grow, we've been getting the benefit of mix on Feminine Care and really have seen some good momentum. And again, with much higher gross margin categories, the cost impacts have a lower relative impact on the overall cost structure. So we're really focused on driving our growth and return based on our innovation there.</p>
          <p>Adult Care, a similar story with both Poise and Depends; the categories are growing rapidly. That's probably our most sensitive consumer from a price elasticity standpoint. The primary competitor is private label, where we know that there will be a lag on pricing. And so we've got strong innovation and mix, accretive innovation coming, and are really going to get our net realized revenue improvements there through mix and volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just I guess going back to one of the earlier questions, just on the cost inflation assumptions, I know you guys have confidence with what you're forecasting. But can you just lay out the worst-case scenario? What if pulp goes much higher than what you're anticipating? Similar to what happened a few years ago, will you be more aggressive again, leading the charge, taking more price? Can you lean more on FORCE this year, or are you borrowing from next year's FORCE savings? I'm just wondering if you could lay out hypothetically a worst-case scenario for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pricing is always set based on expectations, so we're looking at the forwards for oil. We're looking at all the industry forecast for pulp. And if we saw that there was a much bigger spike coming, we wouldn't be shy about taking pricing where we need to, to recover that. I think the challenge has been that the commodity costs have not performed as forecasted. No one expected the Middle East to melt down here in the first quarter, which has driven oil up at a much more rapid pace. And so I think we're looking at all the same forecasts that we have in the past and that most of our principal competitors are. And as we see those expectations changing, we won't be shy about adjusting price going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just the last question, I know you guys have given all your color on volumes staying intact and wanted to not seeing consumers responding. I'm just wondering just on the KCP side. Obviously, it seems like it's doing better than maybe what we anticipated. So I was just wondering how much of the volume is better expectations just on the B-to-B business to help out along the way; Health Care obviously lapping from H1N1. Can you just put a little context around that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Certainly, both B-to-B businesses were strong volume performers in the quarter. We probably have easier comps because of both the economic downturn impact on KCP last year and then the H1N1 impact on Health Care last year. So that will help, I think, our overall volume performance. And I do think that you're seeing signs in some segments of the economy that things are starting to get marginally better, so we'll look for that to be a volume boost for us this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great, thanks. Good luck, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Chip Dillon with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chip. Did you find something else in the 10-K you want to talk about, or do you have another question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>We've done enough 10-Ks for one morning. But on the detailed tissue side, we've seen a lot of activity from your competitors, your two big ones, and even private label on adding basically newer variants of Through Air Dried [TAD] technology. I was just wondering if there is something you can &#x2013; give us some insight in terms of how you think about that and what maybe Kimberly might be doing going forward especially as you realign your tissue retail footprint?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, there's more TAD capacity out there, but it's also a lot more difficult to make a high quality premium Through Air Dried sheet than just buying a machine and starting it up. So I would say both us and P&amp;G have substantial experience in both the fabrics on those machines as well as the chemistry to deliver an advantaged base sheet performance. And you can expect to see some improvements in Cottonelle that we think will be a step change in performance improvement on Cottonelle, which will continue to make it be the premium product that deserves the market pricing that we're going to have on it this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you think you have enough capacity to handle growth for the next, say, two or three years, or will you need to address that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think in the near term, we're getting productivity growth through our Lean Continuous Improvement. And so certainly for North America, we should be in pretty good shape from a capacity standpoint.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chip.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time, we have no further questioners in the queue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks, David. We'll turn it back to Tom for a closing comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Once again, it's a challenging environment, but we've laid out a plan that we think is aggressive but will help us stay on track with our global business plan. Thank you for your support of Kimberly-Clark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>