<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1447869" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2013-01-25</date>
    <companies>
      <company>296</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Paul J. Alexander</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Senior Vice President">Mark A. Buthman</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Thomas J. Falk</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co. LLC">Ali Dibadj</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Chris Ferrara</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Agricole Securities (USA), Inc.">Caroline Shan Levy</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="BMO Capital Markets (United States)">Constance M. Maneaty</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">Jason M. Gere</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Lauren Rae Lieberman</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Vertical Research Partners LLC">James H. Armstrong</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Bill G. Schmitz</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Consumer Edge Research LLC">Javier Escalante</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">John A. Faucher</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Caris &amp; Co., Inc.">Linda Bolton Weiser</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your patience in holding. We now have your speakers in conference. Please be aware each of your lines is in a listen-only mode. At the conclusion of today's presentation, we will open the floor for your questions. At that time, instructions will be given as to the procedure to follow if you would like to ask a question.</p>
          <p>It is now my pleasure to introduce today's first presenter, Mr. Paul Alexander.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, David, and good morning, everyone. Welcome to our Year End Earnings Conference Call. Here with us today are Tom Falk, Chairman and CEO; Mark Buthman, Senior VP and CFO; and Mike Azbell, Vice President and Controller. Here's the agenda for our call. Mark will begin with a review of fourth quarter results. Tom will then provide his perspectives on our full year results and also our 2013 outlook. We'll finish with Q&amp;A.</p>
          <p>There is a presentation of today's materials including our key planning assumptions for 2013 in the Investor section of our website. As a reminder, we will be making forward-looking statements today. Please see the Risk Factors section of our latest annual report on Form 10-K for further discussion of forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>We will also be referring to adjusted results and outlook today. Both exclude certain items described in this morning's news release. The news release has further information on these adjustments and also reconciliations to comparable GAAP financial measures.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll turn it over to Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Paul, and good morning. Let's start with the headlines. First, we achieved organic sales growth of 5% highlighted by 9% growth in K-C International. Second, we delivered adjusted earnings per share of $1.37, that's a 7% increase compared to the prior year. And third, we generated an all-time quarterly record $1.1 billion in cash from operations. Now, let's cover the details of the quarter.</p>
          <p>Fourth quarter sales were $5.3 billion, up 3% versus last year. Underlying organic sales rose 5%, driven by increased volumes of 3% and higher net selling prices of 2%. Unfavorable currency rates and lost sales in conjunction with our pulp and tissue restructuring further reduced sales by 1% each. Fourth quarter adjusted gross margin was 34.3%, that's up 170 basis points from last year. The increase was driven by organic sales growth and $80 million of FORCE cost savings. For the full year, FORCE savings were $295 million, that's well above our original target for savings of $150 million to $200 million for the year. We also surpassed our three-year savings target of $400 million to $500 million after just two years. We're making great progress leveraging our global procurement organization and deploying LEAN continuous improvement throughout our company and I expect that momentum to continue in 2013.</p>
          <p>So moving down the P&amp;L, adjusted operating profit rose 5% with an operating margin of 15%, that's up 30 basis points compared to last year. We continued investment between the lines including higher administrative and research spending to build capabilities and support future growth, particularly in K-C International. In addition, strategic marketing rose $10 million in the quarter.</p>
          <p>The fourth quarter adjusted effective tax rate was 30.6%, as in line with our full year target of 30% to 32%. All in all, fourth quarter adjusted earnings per share were $1.37, that's up 7% versus last year. As I said before, cash provided by operations in the fourth quarter was an all-time quarterly record of $1.1 billion. That's more than double our year-ago performance driven by improved working capital and lower pension contributions. Cash provided by operations for the full year was $3.3 billion, that's up $1 billion compared to the prior year. Our working capital cash conversion cycle improved two days in 2012 to a record low 45 days for the year, and we expect to make further progress in 2013.</p>
          <p>During the fourth quarter, we repurchased 3.8 million shares of KMB stock at a cost of $320 million. For the year, we repurchased 16.4 million shares at a cost of $1.3 billion. Altogether, we allocated $2.5 billion of cash to share repurchases and dividends in 2012.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll highlight a few areas from our segment results for the quarter. In Personal Care, organic sales rose 9% with volume growth of 6% and net selling prices up 3%. K-C International had another strong quarter with organic sales up 12%. Our key growth initiatives continue to perform very well. In fact, in the diaper category, volumes in China grew 50%, volumes in Russia rose 15% and volumes in Brazil were up 10%. Elsewhere in Personal Care, volumes were up mid-single digits in Europe and low single digits in North America. Fourth quarter Personal Care operating margins of 17.6% rose 220 basis points, driven by the organic sales growth and our cost savings.</p>
          <p>Now moving to Consumer Tissue, organic sales were up 1% driven by higher net selling prices and volumes. Volume gains in North America were mostly offset by modest declines in Europe and in K-C International. Consumer Tissue operating margins were down 30 basis points compared to a strong year ago, although they were up 50 basis points sequentially versus the third quarter. During the quarter, we also completed our pulp and tissue restructuring charges on schedule and in line with our expectations. Our Consumer Tissue team did a terrific job executing a multi-year plan. I'm pleased with the operating profit margin benefits we've generated so far from these restructuring actions, and I expect benefits will continue to build over the next two years.</p>
          <p>Turning to K-C Professional, organic sales were up 3%, driven by improved volumes and pricing. Organic volumes were up high single digits in K-C International, down slightly elsewhere. Operating margins of 16.7% were up 120 basis points, driven by organic sales growth, cost savings and input cost deflation</p>
          <p>And lastly, Health Care organic sales were down 2%, driven by slightly lower volumes and pricing. Operating margins of 14.9% were up 60 basis points, driven by lower input costs and between the lines spending.</p>
          <p>So that wraps up my comments on the quarter. To recap, we achieved excellent organic sales growth led by K-C International. We delivered improved margins and earnings per share, and we generated terrific cash flow.</p>
          <p>Now, I'll turn it over to Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Mark, and good morning, everyone. Since Mark has reviewed our fourth quarter results, I'll focus my comments on the full year and then I'll talk about our outlook for 2013.</p>
          <p>So starting with 2012, overall results were very strong. We had a great year. On the top-line, we delivered organic sales growth of 5%. Just to put that in perspective, that's our best top-line performance since 2008, and it was driven by targeted growth initiatives, innovation and improved net realized revenue.</p>
          <p>In terms of targeted growth initiatives, our K-C International team had an excellent year. They had organic sales growth of 10% and a double-digit increase in operating profit.</p>
          <p>KCI delivered strong Personal Care volume gains in key growth markets. For example, our diaper volumes increased 45% in China, 20% in Russia and 15% in Brazil. Results in all three countries benefited from product innovation.</p>
          <p>In addition, our Huggies business in China has now expanded into 80 cities, that's up from about 70 at the end of 2011. And we're targeting to be in at least 90 cities by the end of this year. We also made good progress making our adult care and baby wipes businesses truly global. For the year, K-C International grew volumes in both of these categories at double-digit rates.</p>
          <p>Elsewhere in KCI, our K-C Professional business grew organic sales high single digits in 2012, as we've been making strategic investments for industrialization and economic development are occurring. In total across all our businesses, K-C International now represents about 37% of our total company sales, and we continue to be very optimistic about KCI's plans to deliver strong growth going forward.</p>
          <p>Product innovation around the world was also a key contributor to our organic growth in 2012. We introduced several innovations in North America, including super-premium Depend briefs, new U by Kotex tampons and pads and a number of new products in K-C Professional. We also launched a number of innovations in K-C International. That included the introduction of diaper-pants, premium feminine care products and adult care offerings in several markets.</p>
          <p>We supported our innovation and growth initiatives with a $115 million increase in strategic marketing. Our spending there rose at a double-digit rate.</p>
          <p>We also increased research and development spending double digits as we continue to make investments for future growth. Our success with targeted growth initiatives and innovation helped mitigate the impact of soft category demand in infant and childcare in the U.S. and in Europe overall. Nonetheless, our European team executed well and delivered a solid increase in operating profit and margin in 2012. They also initiated and are moving quickly to implement the strategic changes we announced last quarter.</p>
          <p>Our market positions remain solid overall. In the U.S. we improved or maintained market share in six of our eight consumer categories. And in K-C International, we're growing faster than the category in a number of markets.</p>
          <p>In terms of profitability, we increased gross margin by 230 basis points and we increased our operating margin by 90 basis points. Our FORCE cost savings program was a big reason for these improvements. I'm also pleased that all four of our business segment delivered operating profit growth and improved their margins in 2012.</p>
          <p>On the bottom-line, earnings per share for the year were $5.25, that's up 9% year-on-year, at the high-end of our long-term objective. It was also nicely above our original 2012 guidance for the year of $5 to $5.15.</p>
          <p>Finally, as you heard from Mark, our balance sheet and cash generation remains strong. We continue to allocate capital in shareholder-friendly ways as we returned $2.5 billion to our shareholders through dividends and share repurchases. So overall, we had a very good financial performance and I'm encouraged by the progress we made in 2012.</p>
          <p>Now, let me turn to the outlook. In 2013, we'll continue to pursue targeted growth initiatives. We'll introduce new and improved products and we'll support our brands with increased levels of strategic marketing. We have several innovations launching in K-C International particularly in the infant care, feminine care and adult care categories. We've also got some &#x2013; a number of new innovations coming in North America, including new Depend products for men, the best ever Pull-Ups training pants and improved Scott Extra Soft bath tissue and as the year progresses, we'll have more product news on many of our other brands.</p>
          <p>We also expect to deliver strong cost savings again this year of $250 million to $300 million. That will help us fund our brand investments and overcome moderate cost inflation, which we currently expect to be in the range of $150 million to $250 million. Overall, we're targeting to grow organic sales by 3% to 5% and to increase adjusted earnings per share by 5% to 8%. This latter earnings guidance assumes an approximate 1 point drag from Venezuela and we're not sure exactly what the operating environment will be in Venezuela in 2013, so we thought it made sense to build some of that potential impact into our plan.</p>
          <p>And finally, we'll continue to focus on generating strong cash flow and allocating capital in shareholder-friendly ways. We expect to raise the dividend at a high single-digit rate and that will be our 41st consecutive annual increase in the dividend. We also plan to repurchase about $1 billion to $1.2 billion worth of Kimberly-Clark stock. Together, dividends and share repurchases should total more than $2 billion for the third consecutive year.</p>
          <p>So to summarize, we're encouraged by our performance in 2012, we're optimistic about our plans for 2013 and beyond, and we remain convinced that our global business plan will continue to deliver value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>That wraps up our prepared remarks, and we'll now begin to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, at this time, the floor is now open for your questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Ali Dibadj with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. A couple of questions. One is really around the very strong KCI growth this year, 10% organic, as you mentioned, but kind of doing some algebra, the rest of the business being a little bit more subdued. So if you think about the 3% to 5% organic sales growth target for this year, for 2013, can you help us with the composition of that by geography and by segment? And maybe in answering that can you give us some sense about the distribution gain that you might continue to get? You mentioned one example of that in your prepared remarks, but a distribution gain you might be able to get on a continuous fashion? How much more runway there is for that? And do you need that to get to your KCI current numbers? That's the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let's say, Ali, the growth is again going to be heavily focused on K-C International, and within that, more focused on Personal Care as it was this year, where you saw, I think, in KCI Personal Care organic volume was up 9% for the year. Part of that was distribution gain in China, certainly it was also increasing our participation in the category as we moved into the mid-tier segment of the category. But in markets like Brazil, we're moving more aggressively into the northeastern part of Brazil, so that's a big opportunity for us where we're there but we're not really fully represented. So we've got additional capacity starting up there.</p>
          <p>In Russia and Eastern Europe, we've had a good presence in Moscow. We're moving out into broader distribution reach across Russia and some of the other Eastern European countries, and so that's an opportunity for us. And so it's going to be a combination of innovation and a little bit of distribution gain and good execution to make that happen. In North America, it's a &#x2013; the diaper category has kind of flattened out, so the birth rate's low, we expect diapers to be down about a point year-on-year. Childcare, which was down 5% this year, may only be down 1% next year from a category standpoint. We got a lot of innovation coming, so I think we'll have less of a drag from North America in 2013 than we had in 2012, and we still have good momentum in Personal &#x2013; in adult care, in fem care in North America that should carry over into 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me ask just the KCI question slightly differently, specifically on the 10% organic sales growth. Can you help us figure out how much of that is comp store growth versus how much of it is distribution growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say the analytics are probably not as precise there as you'd like to think, as you know, because some of the Nielsen data doesn't get you that. I'd say the bigger factor is broader participation in the category. So in China, for example, going into the mid-tier of the diaper segment across the geography that we're already in, but going from 70 to 80 cities you can do the math. Now they don't all start up and contribute at the full level of your existing base and you're in the big cities to start, and you're going to the next tier down, so they're not &#x2013; each incremental city is not as big of a pop as what you originally got. So I'd say the more of it is from the expansion of our participation in the category and the innovation that we're driving and that the additional geography is a relatively smaller part of the boost.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So second piece is just about the incremental strategic spending, $10 million, which seems lower than it's been all year. Can you comment a little bit about that? Is it launch timing, seasonality? And how should we expect that to trend going forward for the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No it's probably launch timing, but I also would say if you look back, we're ramping it up, and so we've kind of hit more of a stable state. So you'll see it go up as a &#x2013; faster than sales in 2013, but it won't go up as much. We were probably up more than double our rate of organic sales growth this year; it won't be as big of a delta in 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And my last question, and you've been kind with your time, is just around competition broadly. So what are you seeing? And maybe make more specific, U.S., but also &#x2013; and in the U.S., have you, for example, in the Consumer Tissue business, tried to in your guidance take into account a new entrant in the U.S. with TAD technology and private label? And then in China, we keep hearing from local competitors there that they're going to get more aggressive. They're not just going to give up their turf to folks like you who are coming into their cities. Can you comment on that as well? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah sure. We have lots of tough competition everywhere. And so in the Personal Care space, obviously we've got P&amp;G most places but we're seeing Unicharm increasingly show up in markets around the world. They're obviously strong in Asia. They're now talking about expansion in Brazil and Mexico. So they make very good products and we run into them in large markets around the world. Some of the local Chinese players, they hang on and those folks tend to be at the lower end of the product spectrum, but they're trying to move their mix up. And so there's a &#x2013; you got to be &#x2013; execute well and have great innovation and great marketing to be successful in these markets, and so that's what we're aiming at.</p>
          <p>In the U.S. the private label, if you look at private label shares in tissue and bath, it was up a point or two year-over-year and towels is up about a point. But our shares were pretty stable. And so &#x2013; and actually we've got a pretty good innovation agenda for Cottonelle and Kleenex, and so I think we feel cautiously optimistic about our tissue business going into 2013, particularly in North America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the TAD technology entering in private label doesn't concern you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It &#x2013; not at this stage. I mean I think there's good quality private label around, but we think that the branded products still are differentiated and offer consumers an attractive value, and our Cottonelle business is showing that. I mean we had pretty strong share results in the fourth quarter, and we're feeling good about that business going into 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ali.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Chris Ferrara with Bank of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey good morning, guys. So I wanted to try to better understand, now that I guess you probably had a better look at it, the P&amp;L impact of the stranded overhead on the European exits, right? So I understand you're committed to clearing that out, right, and still delivering obviously now 5% to 8% growth.</p>
          <p>But I guess can you talk about what you think the gross drag will be from that stranded overhead? Because I mean, you have to be finding offsets, right? It's not that you're going to be able to clear all those expenses out at the same rate that the sales are going away, right? So I just kind of want to understand the gross impact, if possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No I mean &#x2013; Chris really we are aiming to cut our overhead in Europe by at least as much as the sales, right? And, so, Kim Underhill and her team and Robert Abernathy were working on this for a good part of last year. Mark Buthman's team was leaning on it as well and in terms of the back-office things and maybe Mark can chime in on that. But we're aggressively going after the European structure, and so we had probably overbuilt that a bit to expecting Europe to grow and to be a bigger business, and so we've gone in and stripped a lot of the overhead out. They've gone through the consultation process with most of the countries and most of our team in Europe now knows whether they have a permanent role, they have a temporary role, or they're going to be &#x2013; their role has been eliminated and so I don't know. Mark, you've sat in on those calls lately, so I'll let you add some color to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Chris. For us, it's &#x2013; if you think about it as an enterprise, it's a great opportunity for us to kind of paint a picture of what our overhead structure might look even more broadly across the world. And they've got a real compelling business case to do it. And so we have &#x2013; it's on the top of our management agenda and we're watching it closely. A high degree of difficulty but a high degree of confidence in the plans they put together.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we know we have to execute it and we'll be transparent about how we're doing on that as the quarters progress in 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. That's helpful. And I guess moving over to KCI, obviously the growth has been there. Can you try to dimensionalize where you think sort of long-term margin improvement comes from? Do think the KC margins will progress at a rate faster than the overall company margins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the KCI team is aiming at being the most attractive investment opportunity for Kimberly-Clark. And so they know they've got to grow top-line and they've got to grow bottom-line. And so one of the things that was really pleasing about their results it 2012 is they had double-digit top-line but they also had more strong double-digit operating profit growth too. And so &#x2013; and as you see cities and markets get to scale, the gross margin structure is pretty attractive. And we've still got work to do and we can do better in lots of places but they've got an aggressive program to continue to take out costs, to get more effective with our marketing investment and our trade spend investments, and as we do that, that should help our margins improve. And we have individual markets in KCI that have got gross margins that are strongly accretive to the corporation so we know it's possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then just one last follow-up on margins, I guess when you benchmark yourself versus peers and I guess normalizing for product mix, and you look at that 34% gross margin that you guys are at right now, what do think the opportunity is there for that gross over the long-term? Because obviously, you've accelerated your top-line, KCI has accelerated, but what's the opportunity on gross margin when you think longer-term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean we've been higher in our own history. And so as you go back before some of the commodity run-up, we were in high 30s and we're talking about scaring a 40% gross margin so that's certainly kind of a near-term goal that we're aiming at, and I think we made a strong move toward it in 2012, and we'll have commodity challenges from time-to-time that'll afford our progress there. But we're certainly aiming at improving gross margin, being able to invest more than strategic marketing and then delivering a part of that to the bottom-line in operating margin improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Caroline Levy with CLSA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Carolyn.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Hi. Good morning. I was wondering if you could help us put some numbers and maybe this is a longer-term question but around the adult diaper opportunity? Because again, it may not be a huge contributor to earnings right now, but as you model out your company 5 and 10 years, how big do you think this can get? And what do you see as your major opportunities just given the number of older people in China and Japan, for example?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well &#x2013; and it's exciting. Even in North America, our adult care business grew volume 6% last year and so we had strong innovation behind Poise and Depend and had &#x2013; and saw that even as an income consumer that's maybe more sensitive to price change, they were still willing to invest in a better quality product and so we still got lots of growth in the U.S. and your developed markets. In the emerging markets, the businesses are small but they're growing fast and we're putting more resource against it in many markets, and we've had &#x2013; we had multiple launches in 2012. We've got more coming in 2013, and so we think that Poise and Depend will someday be strong $1 billion businesses for us and each of those has the potential to be a $1 billion brand and that's what we're aiming at.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And is that margin diluted as you grow adult versus other parts of the business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I mean our adult care margins within Personal Care are competitive with the segment averages and in some markets even a little bit better. Obviously, as you launch in a market, you'll be investing to build the brands. So in that particular market, it'll be a little dilutive, but the gross margin structure is quite attractive.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And then just moving to the growth of your market, did &#x2013; do you believe that you took mark &#x2013; that you outgrew the market not just in China, for example, but overall? And what do you think the market growth rate will be in 2013, your market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, broadly in the emerging markets, we would say you're probably looking at mid-single digit growth and we grew high single, so we would say we probably took share in a number of places. Obviously, some of the Nielsen data is a little tougher to get at because there are so many points of distribution that aren't covered really well by Nielsen, and it's getting better and &#x2013; but we still got some room to grow there. So if you look at our global business, we'd say the categories are growing 3% to 4% much faster than that probably mid-singles in emerging markets, slower than that in the developed markets. And so our 3% to 5% top-line if we just hold share, we should be in the 3% to 4% range. If we drive some innovation and a little bit more share growth, we can get to the high-end of that range as we did in 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And then just lastly, is January off to a good start, the year off to a good start?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so far. I mean I have nothing to complain about yet. We haven't closed the month yet, so we want to see the results, but &#x2013; yeah, but nothing unusual that we're seeing in the data so far.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Cold and flu is...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're benefiting both probably in Health Care and facial tissue. It was pretty flat in December but it's kind of picked up pace in January.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's a good point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'm sort of sorry but happy to hear that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good for us. Bad for...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're here for you if you need us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Connie Maneaty with BMO Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Connie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning. Just two questions. What do you think the impact will be on retail prices in the U.S. from all the new tissue capacity that's coming on? And do you think the branded companies would have to roll back prices to maintain an appropriate gap?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know, Connie, I am not as worried about the U.S. market from the additional capacities. There's a lot of capacity that's gone out of the U.S. market, and so as we shutdown Everett and Chester, there has been some other &#x2013; or some of the capacity that came out of Chester. The U.S. market operating rate is probably in the high 80% range. And actually, we're fully loaded and are running our capacity pretty full up in 2012 and heading into 2013. So probably more of it is what's going to drive tissue pricing is whatever happens to pulp and we're calling pulp to be up slightly in 2013, so that should put a little bit of a positive spin on pricing. So we had a little bit softer pricing in the third quarter, came back a little bit in the fourth quarter. That had more to do with timing of promotions year-over-year, so there is nothing big happening on that front, so we'll have to wait and see. But overall, again, we feel better about the &#x2013; about our branded tissue business position going into 2013.</p>
          <p>I think the big place in the world you commented on tissue capacity expansion was more in China, and we don't have a big Chinese tissue business. We have a facial tissue business, so we don't do much in roll products in China.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. And my second question is what's included in your Venezuela impact? You said you're starting to build in some of a potential impact. So is it the effect of 50% devaluation? Or the impact of continued price controls in the face of inflation? So what's included in your &#x2013; what have you already assumed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and this has been a tough one to call because it's difficult to predict from day-to-day what's going to happen. So we have not included any of the balance sheet re &#x2013; devaluation that would flow through the income statement. So none of the financial asset translation of the new rate is in our guidance, so that would be a one-time thing that we'd have to call out. And we really looked at it and said it was a very low single-digit percent of sales and operating profit in 2012 but something's probably going to happen, either there will be a deval, which will have a translation impact. We didn't model it probably as deep as 50% but we assumed there will be some reduction, or you could have a scenario where there's no deval but it's tough to get foreign exchange and so we wind up constraining our supply because we can't get dollars to pay our bills. So you wind up with a drop in demand and a shrink in the size of the business. And so it was very difficult to predict which of those would happen but we said probably something's going to happen, so let's be a little bit conservative on that number going into the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Connie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Jason Gere with RBC Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, just a couple of questions. One, as you think about 2013 with all the changes going on with Europe and the tissue restructuring, is there going to &#x2013; is it going to be pretty smooth across the quarters or should we see that maybe back half a little stronger than the front half? I was just wondering if you could provide a little bit of the cadence there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, in all the charges for the Consumer Tissue, the North American tissue restructuring have flown through the P&amp;L now, so those are behind us. So we took a good chunk of the European restructuring hit in the fourth quarter. If you look at the sequencing of the year, I'd expect actually a pretty consistent growth rate over the quarters year-on-year which would say that the back half is probably going to be a little better than the front half because that was the way it shaped up in 2012. And so you get some things that will help the first quarter and like we might have a little bit lower effective tax rate because of the way the tax bill that got passed. But, but all in all, I would say the growth rate is going to trend pretty close to a consistent year-on-year across the quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then just the next question. I know that I think one of the earlier questions broke down the organic sales by geography but I was &#x2013; and I hope you can provide some color in terms of &#x2013; about the segments, Tissue versus Personal Care versus kind of the B2B segment, and how you're looking at those trends, where you may see any tip of acceleration versus deceleration versus 2012 with &#x2013; getting in within that 3% to 5% range?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, if you kind of go through Personal Care, you'd hope that North America will be a little better year-on-year because the categories are not going to be down as much. And so we should have &#x2013; I think for the year in infant care, we were down 5% and flat on childcare. Wipes was down a little bit, so those should be better year-on-year. In fem and adult, we're high singles for &#x2013; in total for those. I mean &#x2013; I think feminine was up 6% and adult was up 10%. So I'd say you'd expect to see those collectively be in the high singles in 2013, and K-C International is 9%. That was a terrific result. We probably won't keep that 45% growth rate in China, but we still expect to have a strong growth rate in China in 2013, so maybe a little slower in KCI.</p>
          <p>In Consumer Tissue, that's one that is playing more of a grow margin role for us. So we had relatively light volume growth. In North America it was flat. Overall, Europe was down a little. Even KCI was down a percent. So I don't see huge growth coming in Consumer Tissue. In K-C Professional, our washroom business was up a couple of percent. We think we actually grew a little bit more than the category in washroom in 2012. We got a lot of innovation coming in 2013 and if we get a little bit of economic improvement, you could see a little bit better growth in KCP. In KCP in emerging markets, we were up 6% on the organic volume line and we've got actually lots of growth coming there. So I'd expect to see at least that in 2013.</p>
          <p>Health Care, our supplies were up a couple percent. Devices were up 3% and probably expect supplies to be a little flatter and devices to be a little better in 2013. We've got some more innovation coming to market and a little bit better push on some things in the device front in 2013. So I thought that's helpful for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you very much for all the color. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Lauren Lieberman with Barclays.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Lauren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Thanks. Good morning. So actually the comment you just made about Consumer Tissue playing more of a grow margin role for you guys is exactly what I want to ask about because in this quarter, margins were actually down in that business, which is rare to see when there's deflation. And thinking that the majority of your kind of incremental investments and strategic marketing would be more oriented towards Personal Care than Tissue, I just was curious if you could talk a little bit about margin performance in that business this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean we were up 50 sequentially &#x2013; up 50 basis points sequentially. And so &#x2013; and for the year, we were up 220 basis points in that business. So there are some costs startup issues and a couple of things in the quarter that were a little bit more noise versus fourth quarter last year. I think Europe also had a much stronger fourth quarter in 2011 that didn't repeat in 2012 and so that was a part of it as well. So &#x2013; but overall, I would say, the trends in Consumer Tissue we are happy with. It's back in 13.6% for the year, 14% for the quarter and that's getting close to where we need it to be from it being an investable business standpoint.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. What &#x2013; can you just explain, Tom, sorry, the startup issues? Is that downtime or what is that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, downtime, overall, was a little better for the company year-on-year. We had some &#x2013; broader in the fourth quarter broadly across a number of the segments. We had a little bit more startup activity on new assets and some &#x2013; and when you have a startup, typically you are writing off the old assets. So you had some higher startups and write-offs. So of it &#x2013; so probably more of it was in Personal Care but Consumer Tissue had a little bit of it as well.</p>
          <p>We also had some higher distribution expense, and particularly in K-C International as you are seeing carrier rates are up across the board around the world and Consumer Tissue probably feels that a little bit more than the other segments because freight's a bigger percent of cost of sales.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's really helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from James Armstrong with Vertical Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First question is on the pulp and tissue restructuring benefits. You said that you're currently on a $60 million run rate in operating profit in the fourth quarter and expect $75 million in 2013 and more than $100 million in 2014. Just to make sure, those are not incremental numbers, right? So the &#x2013; in 2013 from the Q4 run rate, it will be more like $15 million?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Each of those numbers was cumulative, so I think we had $20 million in 2011, we had $40 million in 2012 which gets you to $60 million cumulative and there'll be another $15 million in 2013 which gets you to $75 million and so forth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And how is that weighted in 2012? Should we see a little bit more than that $15 million number in 2012? Or I mean in 2013 just because of the timing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I mean I think that's &#x2013; we'll obviously keep the cumulative $60 million that we've already got and the big chunk of that was the shutdown of the Everett mill, and that's done and behind us. And so the &#x2013; some of the additional things we decided to do at Chester, Pennsylvania, will &#x2013; started to benefit late 2012 and will carry forward into 2013 and 2014.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect. And then switching gears just a bit, with the recent innovation in child care, have you seen any things that have worked, any products that have worked in certain regions that you're really starting to expand in the other regions? And could you just give us few examples?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we've been very happy with the Pull-Ups nighttime launch and that's gone well. We've also got a terrific GoodNites business that's in our child care segment and they actually had &#x2013; introduced a line extension of bed mats last year that was a big success in North America.</p>
          <p>In terms of the ideas that are working well around the world, our whole diaper pant approach is going very well. We're going aggressive at both a value tier and a premium tier in many markets around the world. That's gone well. Our U by Kotex Stylista feminine care positioning is one that we're launching in multiple markets around the world. And then our upgraded Depend products, our adult care offering, we're offering that in many markets around the world. So these are things that we're focused on and have got great solutions. I think another example would be baby wipes. We've done baby wipes in North America and Europe.</p>
          <p>We really haven't been fully reflected and penetrated in other markets around the world and so &#x2013; and now we're trying to figure out what would it take if we could sell one wipe for every diaper we sell around the world. If we could do that, we'd have a $1 billion baby wipe business. So there is a big opportunity there for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That helps a lot. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Bill Schmitz with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, guys. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Are you guys willing to call a bottom to the baby bust because it seems like you're a little bit more upbeat on...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That sounds like a quote, Bill, bottom to the baby bust. I like it. No, I think the birth rate has flattened out. We expect it to be basically flat in 2013. The categories will probably still be down a percent on diapers in North America. And I'd say, for us as we've modeled it, the three drivers that are more predictive are male unemployment, or new home purchase or household formation and consumer confidence. And I think as you see those things stabilize, you'd say, yes, all right. That kind of make sense, but the birth rate would be flattening out. It hasn't turned up yet, but I would say you haven't seen any of those three indicators really make a major positive move lately either.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. And then was there not an impact from the flu season? Because I know when you talked about the North American Consumer Tissue business, there's really no mention of facial tissue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, there wasn't much in the fourth quarter. We're seeing it more in the start of the year. And we're pretty good at looking at flu index data almost by zip code. And so are our retail partners, and so they're very nimble about getting flu displays up as the flu moves into a particular part of the country. And so both our Health Care business has been selling a lot of face masks and exam gloves in January. And we've been selling a lot more facial tissue for cold and flu in January. So we'll see how that progresses through the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. And then, are you concerned at all about the &#x2013; if you look at the business segments, three of the four had declined in sequential margins, I mean was it that third quarter was kind of an anomaly and everything was so good?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say to the point we made earlier on the other cost of sales, we probably had a little bit more startups in the fourth quarter and some asset write-offs that were -affected us versus the third quarter, and we &#x2013; then distribution expense started to tick up in a couple of markets, and so we're digging into that. And, but I'd say, I'm pretty happy with the progress for the year. We were up in all four segments year-on-year, and that's really what we're aiming to do consistently over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah I mean, is there a way to say it was like the third quarter the anomaly or was the fourth quarter the anomaly? Or is it not that simple?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't &#x2013; I mean I don't think, it's &#x2013; I could be that precise with you. If I'd say, you look at Personal Care and we had said coming into the year that if we could be flat with 2011 we'd be happy, and we ended the year 60 basis points higher. So we probably were a little ahead in third quarter of where we expected, and it normalized a bit in the fourth quarter, but broadly for the year, we're pleased with the progress we're making.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks. And then just one last one. Did you say what the sales impact of the distribution sale for the mid-tier diapers in China was? Was it material to the top line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No we didn't spell that out. And so I mean the mid-tier in China is the biggest part of the category. So going into that was a plus. Now we started that in mid-2011, so it wasn't a full year benefit, but that was certainly part of the growth that we saw in China this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We also picked up a couple of share points in China this year, which in a market that size is substantial from a sales standpoint.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. And maybe I missed this, but can you talk about your country penetration in mid-tier? I mean, your &#x2013; sorry, your regional penetration in China? Like is it done or is there still &#x2013; I think you said there's still some room to grow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. No we were in 70 cities at the beginning of 2012. We were in 80 by the end of 2012. We hope to be in 90 by the end of 2013. And so, as you know, there's many more cities with at least a million people in that we're really not present in yet, so we've got a ways to go to really be fully penetrated.</p>
          <p>And there's other geographies as well. I mean we're moving more aggressively in the Northeastern part of Brazil. We've been present but not really fully leveraging the opportunity there and so we're putting capacity up there and a little bit more dedicated sales effort, so that will help.</p>
          <p>In Russia same kind of a thing where we had a strong presence in the Moscow region, but we're moving into some of the other former Soviet republics and the Central Asian countries and other Eastern European countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. And then I promise one last one. Do you think that advertising spending is going to track pulp costs? Because it seems like that's the way it sort of played out this year, where it went like 45, 35, and then 25, and then 10. So is that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No I think it more tracks our innovation pipeline. We had more innovation that was front-end loaded this year and we're going to spend behind good ideas and saw more of that than trying to drive pulp. I mean a good chunk of the increased A&amp;P is in Personal Care and in emerging markets where we were driving launch activity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks so much, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Javier Escalante with Consumer Edge Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just would like to go back to your forecast for the year and the commentary that the diaper category, you expect to go down about 1% and that your expectation is, is that the birth rate are &#x2013; may improve. We had done some analysis and we see basically the sales of newborn diapers being down 1% to 2% on top of minus 4% last year.</p>
          <p>So we thought that that would be a leading indicator of whether newborns were picking up and we don't see that in the data. And the contra part of that is that your business is more exposed to late stage diapering, training pants. So how that pan out in terms of your better outlook in the U.S., if number one, we don't see that in the data yet, number two, you are &#x2013; actually your business depends on later stage diapering.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, I guess, I'd say, Javier, we're looking at, from predictive model for the birth rate, so we're looking at male unemployment and consumer confidence and household formation as more of a leading indicator of where it's going. And as we've back tested it, that has been the best fit model, and so that model would say &#x2013; been predicting that the birth rate would get less negative all year. That's pretty much what's happened. It's predicting for 2013 that the birth rate flattens out where it is now.</p>
          <p>And so when we talk about the diaper category being down about 1%, it is more that effect that as the babies haven't been born in the last two years are not in the category now. And so they won't be there in 2013 either. And certainly that affects our &#x2013; affected our child care business more significantly this year as you had three or four years of birth rate decline that have totaled 8% to 9%. That's been showing up in our training pant business. But we expect most of that is behind us and I expect a little bit better or less negative category environment in 2013 than we had in 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That is good. And my second question also has to do with what is your view what's happening in Consumer Tissue business also in the U.S.? I mean here bath tissue and paper towels. You mentioned that private label picked up 1 to 2 points and a lot of it has come in from the competition, from your main competitor, which has been innovating in the category, both in paper towels and bath tissue. And they are losing share. You guys don't seem to be losing share.</p>
          <p>Could you help us understand how you see the consumer dynamic and why you are not being as pressured by private label as your competitors have been? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah I mean &#x2013; and we've had more innovation. So if you look at the fourth quarter, our Kleenex volumes were up 1%, Cottonelle was up 8%, Scott bath was up 1%, our Viva towel business was down a couple percent, and Scott towels was up 11%.</p>
          <p>But &#x2013; so some of it was promotional timing, some of it we've had good innovation on Cottonelle and it's a terrific product. And so I think we just continue to try to make sure we get quality promotion, we're doing great marketing, we keep bring innovation to the category and that makes it tougher for the private labels to fight against that. So it's pretty &#x2013; it's a pretty simple formula.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from John Faucher with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey guys. Just wanted to follow up a little bit on Chris's question but sort of thinking about the margin structure in Europe longer-term. How should we think about where you guys can go as you get through some of the stranded overhead issues? What do you think is sort of the long-term structural upside to margins there? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'd say, medium-term, we'd say double-digit operating margin is a reasonable goal, which would be a good improvement from where we've been. But then as we also &#x2013; as Kim and the team look at that, they'd say long-term, they would like Europe to be at least equal to the corporate average, and so that &#x2013; they've got some work to do to get there, they don't have all the answers to figure that out. But we've got good businesses in categories that are growing in Europe, and the whole point of this restructuring effort is to free up that team to focus on driving our baby wipes business where we've got good accretive margins and driving our child care and DryNites businesses, where we've got strong margin opportunities; and making our Kleenex and Andrex and Scottex businesses successful in Europe.</p>
          <p>And there are already great brands with great market positions, but we've got to put more innovation and investment behind them to make them produce the kind of returns that we're looking for. And so, I think we've got to execute the plan in front of us and get to a stable, consistent place and then look how we can grow that from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And so, just a follow-up on that, it sounds as though you feel like you guys &#x2013; there's nothing structural to the categories themselves in Europe that would limit that, it's a question just you're being able to go out and execute that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think in Europe the big thing you worry about particularly in tissue is private label, so the private label structure in Europe is very different from anywhere else in the world where you're seeing bath tissue in some markets shares north of 70% for private label. So, you've got to &#x2013; you've got to be much &#x2013; probably a little bit more cost conscious and your innovation's got to pop a little bit more to break through that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Linda Bolton Weiser with Caris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Linda.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I was just wondering if on your projections for $150 million to $250 million of input cost inflation, is there any way to split it up roughly between like second half and first half? I would think quite a bit more in the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, about two-thirds of it is pulp and recycled fiber and you're probably right that in the first part of the year, at least the first quarter that doesn't look like there's going to be as much of that showing up so far, so that's probably a fair comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's actually all I had. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time, we have no other questioners in the queue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you, David. We will wrap up with our closing comment from Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, once again, we had a strong performance in 2012 and we're looking forward to keeping the momentum going in 2013. And thank you for your support of Kimberly-Clark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that concludes today's presentation. You may disconnect your phone lines and have a wonderful weekend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>