<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1355914" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-10-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>296</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Paul J. Alexander</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Senior Vice President">Mark A. Buthman</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Thomas J. Falk</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities LLC">Gail S. Glazerman</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co., Inc.">Ali Dibadj</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Agricole Securities (USA), Inc.">Caroline Shan Levy</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">Jason M. Gere</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Christopher Ferrara</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Bill Schmitz</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">John Faucher</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Vertical Research Partners">Chip A. Dillon</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Lauren Rae Lieberman</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Consumer Edge Research LLC">Javier Escalante</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="BMO Capital Markets (United States)">Constance M. Maneaty</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Federated Investment Management Co.">Karen Ann Lamark</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your patience and holding. We now have your speakers in conference. Please be aware that each of your lines is in a listen-only mode. At the conclusion of today's presentation, we will open the floor for your questions. At that time instructions will be given as to the procedure to follow if you'd like to ask a question. It is now my pleasure to introduce Mr. Paul Alexander.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, David, and good morning, everyone. Welcome to Kimberly-Clark's third quarter earnings conference call. Here with me in Dallas today are Tom Falk, Chairman and CEO; Mark Buthman, Senior VP and CFO; and Mike Azbell, Vice President and Controller.</p>
          <p>Here is the agenda for the call. Mark will begin with a review of our third quarter results. Tom will then provide his perspective on our results and also the full year outlook. We'll finish with Q&amp;A. As usual, we have a presentation of today's materials in the Investors section of our website, which is www.kimberly-clark.com.</p>
          <p>Before we begin, let me remind you we'll be making forward-looking statements today. There can be no assurance that future events will occur as anticipated or that our results will be as estimated. Please see the Risk Factors section of our latest Annual Report on Form 10-K for a further discussion of forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>We'll also be referring to adjusted results and outlook today, both of which exclude certain items described in this morning's news release. For further information on these adjustments and reconciliations to comparable financial measures determined in accordance with GAAP, please see today's news release and additional information on our website.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn it over to Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Paul, and good morning. Let's start with the headlines. First, we delivered organic sales growth of 4% highlighted by 11% growth in K-C International. Second, adjusted earnings per share were $1.26, an 11% increase compared to last year. And third, cash flow remained strong as we've generated approximately $0.75 billion in cash provided by operations.</p>
          <p>Now let's cover the details of the quarter. Overall sales increased 8% to an all-time record $5.4 billion. Organic sales rose 4% driven by higher net selling prices of 3%. Product mix and sales volumes each improved slightly. Volumes benefited from product innovation and targeted growth initiatives. However, soft demand in portions of North America and Europe largely offset these gains.</p>
          <p>Third quarter adjusted operating profit rose 8% with an operating margin of 14.1%. Benefits from top line growth and $90 million of FORCE cost savings more than offset cost inflation of $150 million and higher than expected production curtailment to manage inventory levels. As expected, FORCE savings picked up nicely from the first half of the year and our teams continue to push aggressively to maximize savings. Nonetheless, with year-to-date savings of $195 million, we could fall somewhat short of our target range of $300 million to $350 million of savings for the year.</p>
          <p>Third quarter adjusted earnings per share were $1.26 compared to $1.14 last year. The improvement was driven by higher operating profit along with a lower share count and a lower effective tax rate. Given our year-to-date adjusted tax rate of 30.1%, we now expect the full-year rate to be toward the low end of our target for the year of 30% to 32%. Cash provided by operations increased slightly to $750 million in the third quarter. I'm encouraged by our cash generation and expect a strong finish to the year.</p>
          <p>We repurchased 0.6 million shares of KMB stock in the quarter at a cost of $40 million. As mentioned in our news release, we've decided to accelerate an additional $260 million of pension contributions into 2011 and reduce our full-year share repurchase target by the same amount. This will improve our pension funded status nicely from current levels, and it will allow us to make much more modest contributions next year while setting us up for a strong year of share repurchases in 2012.</p>
          <p>Now I'll highlight a few areas from our segment results for the quarter. As usual further details are in our news release. In Personal Care, organic sales rose 5% with volumes and net selling prices each advancing about 3%. K-C International had a terrific quarter with 15% organic growth led by strong performance in Latin America, China and South Korea.</p>
          <p>In North America, we continue to generate high single-digit to low double-digit volume growth in adult care, feminine care and baby wipes. On the other hand, volumes were down in infant and child care. The volume softness reflects category declines, competitive promotional activity, reductions in customer inventory levels in diapers and some consumer trade down in the child care category.</p>
          <p>Personal Care operating margins of 16.6% remain below prior year. Input cost inflation, production curtailment and higher between-the-lines spending were partially offset by benefits from top line growth and cost savings.</p>
          <p>Now turning to Consumer Tissue. Organic sales were off 1%. Net selling prices rose 4% in response to cost inflation, and product mix was favorable by 1%. On the other hand, volumes fell 6% reflecting sheet count reductions in North America, our focus on revenue realization and strong promotion support for Cottonelle Bath Tissue in the third quarter last year. Consumer Tissue operating margins improved to 12%. It's our best performance in two years. That was driven by sales growth, cost savings and lower between-the-lines spending.</p>
          <p>Moving to K-C Professional &amp; Other. Organic sales rose 5%. The increase was due to improved volumes of 3% and higher net selling prices of 2%. Volumes were up mid-to-high single-digits in K-C International in Europe. On the other hand, volumes were even with year-ago levels in North America as high unemployment and office vacancy levels continue to impact market demand. Operating margins of 14.7% were similar to last year.</p>
          <p>And lastly Health Care organic sales were up 8% driven by higher sales volumes. Medical supply volumes rose double digits led by growth in surgical products and exam gloves reflecting improved North American demand. In addition, global medical device volumes increased high single digits including strong growth in Europe and Asia. Operating margins of 13.8% were somewhat above last year driven by sales growth and cost savings.</p>
          <p>So that wraps up the review of the quarter. To recap, we achieved solid organic sales growth led by K-C International. We delivered strong growth in adjusted earnings per share, and we continued to generate significant cash flow.</p>
          <p>Now I'll turn it over to Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark, and good morning, everyone. I'll share my perspectives on our third quarter results and our full year outlook and then we'll get to your questions as usual.</p>
          <p>So starting with the third quarter, I'm encouraged that we were able to deliver 4% growth in organic sales and deliver double-digit growth in adjusted earnings per share. We overcame significant cost inflation and also softer than expected demand in parts of the developed markets. Some of the keys to this performance was our focus on our targeted growth initiatives, our focus on revenue realization and our focus on delivering cost reduction. Let me share a few of the highlights with you in each of these three areas.</p>
          <p>First, we made excellent progress with our targeted growth initiatives. In North America that's particularly true in our Adult Care, feminine care and baby wipes businesses. Our global Health Care medical device business also achieved solid volume growth in the quarter and K-C International delivered outstanding results led by our teams in China, South Korea and Latin America.</p>
          <p>Turning to revenue realization. We delivered three points of favorable net selling price in the third quarter. That's up nicely from the 1% benefit we realized in the first half of this year. Our progress in the third quarter was highlighted by success in K-C International, K-C Professional and in our North American Consumer Tissue business. So overall our pricing initiatives are on track with our expectations for the year.</p>
          <p>In terms of cost reduction, in addition to the FORCE savings that Mark already mentioned, we continue to make good progress controlling our overhead spending. For the first nine months our total between-the-lines spending is up 2% while our sales are up 7%. So we're on track to achieve our target to grow spending slower than sales this year in this category.</p>
          <p>Let me give you now a brief update on our market positions which remain solid overall. In the U.S. our third quarter market shares were ahead of or even with the year-ago period in about half of our consumer businesses. On a year-to-date basis we can make the same statement for six of eight of our consumer businesses. Third quarter private label market shares were stable overall versus last year although they did pick up modestly from second quarter levels in some categories and while we believe this reflects the generally cautious consumer and in some cases we have had branded price increases that occurred ahead of private label.</p>
          <p>Outside the U.S. we continue to grow ahead of category rates in a number of markets in K-C International, including China and Latin America. In Europe our market shares are flat to down slightly as the environment worsened modestly there over the last three months.</p>
          <p>Before moving to the outlook let me touch on a few of the innovations we launched in the third quarter. Our Huggies Little Movers Slip-On Diapers are off to a solid start in North America. Our distribution levels continue to build and Slip-On achieved four points of market share in the most recent four-week time period. This innovation is also performing well in a number of markets in K-C International.</p>
          <p>Our new Poise Hourglass Shape Pads are also performing well, and they achieved three points of market share in the quarter in the light end of the U.S. Adult Care category. And we're excited about the prospects for Kleenex Cool Touch facial tissue which started shipping toward the end of the quarter.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to the outlook. We expect our momentum with revenue realization and targeted growth initiatives to continue led by K-C International while also continuing to operate with financial discipline focusing on cost savings, control of overhead spending and cash generation. Key changes to our full year planning assumptions are included in this morning's news release, but here are the highlights.</p>
          <p>In terms of sales, we're taking our volume growth assumption to the low end of our 1% to 2% target range. This reflects somewhat lower expectations for portions of the developed markets, particularly in the North American Infant and child care categories.</p>
          <p>In addition, as a result of the recent strengthening of the U.S. dollar, we expect less benefit from changes in currency rates than our previous plan. The weaker Mexican peso has also caused us to lower our expectations from our equity income from K-C de Mexico. On the other hand because commodity costs have moderated some from the peak levels that we experienced this summer, we now expect about $100 million less cost inflation in 2011 than we previously estimated.</p>
          <p>So putting it all together, we're now targeting our 2011 adjusted earnings per share to be in the range of $4.80 to $4.90 per share, and that's essentially consistent with our previous guidance in July which was that earnings were more likely to be in the lower half of our target range of $4.80 to $5.05 per share.</p>
          <p>So to summarize, despite the challenging near-term environment, our businesses continue to be fundamentally strong. We're continuing to deploy our strategies for the long-term success of Kimberly-Clark, and while we're not on track with all of our goals this year, we are convinced that our Global Business Plan will improve shareholder value.</p>
          <p>So that wraps up our prepared remarks, we'll now be happy to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, at this time, the floor is now open for your questions. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Gail Glazerman with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Gail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. Can you talk a little bit about &#x2013; just around demand environment? Was some of the weakness you saw in the quarter in developed markets more weighted towards inventory de-stocking that might have played out? Or, are you seeing changes in overall consumption pattern?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I wouldn't say consumption pattern. You see, we're still seeing it derive from the birthrate, so the diaper and training pant category is where we saw the biggest category decline relative to our expectations and so it's partly the &#x2013; yes, birthrate has been down for three years. That's starting to flow into the child care category as you've got three years of low birth rate now in toilet training so that one probably had the biggest volume hit relative to expectations. A little bit of &#x2013; inventory destocking was a part of I,  and I think that's just customers trying to run their working capital tight as you'd expect in this environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, can you talk a little bit about the improvement you saw in U.S. paper towels? Is that basically back to where you think it should be or is there incremental recovery yet to come?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we're executing better. We got some of the distribution back, and both Viva and Scott towels had decent volume growth there, so I think &#x2013; we're overall happy with the progress we're seeing and bouncing back from what were historic low share periods for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And, just on inflation, your resin costs, have those flattened out sequentially or would you like to see some relief in the fourth quarter? Or, are they still increasing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we think they peaked in the &#x2013; early third quarter so we'd expect to see a little bit of benefit in the fourth quarter but I will say that they are stickier coming down, it seems, than you would expect given how oil has performed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, Gail, this is Paul. I would just add, even though they are coming down sequentially, they still will be up year-on-year in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Gail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Ali Dibadj with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Ali.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, how are you? Just a couple things; one, you start to answer the question I think last &#x2013; but you were struck by how volumes were really quite, quite tough, particularly in the developed markets and of course there are some birth rate issues and sheet reduction and inventory reduction, et cetera. But there does seem to be this &#x2013; intentional or not I don't know but a little more subdued view of demand in the release and I'm just trying to get a sense from you about &#x2013; are you seeing that flatten, get worse, see things getting a little bit better? And I ask that question &#x2013; I ask that question also in the context of you raising prices relatively significantly if there's any risk to some of those price increases as you go forward given the volume response?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, a couple things. We took the overall volume number in our guidance down to the low end of the range. So we said we were 1% to 2%; it's going to be closer to 1% for the year, which is really where we think it's playing out. I'd say that the de-sheeting effect, we expected; that's &#x2013; our shares are fine in bath tissue which is where most of the de-sheeting occurred, and trends in facial tissue are positive there so that one is playing out about as we would have expected. I'd say the diaper and training pant category is one that just continues to be a little softer. Our insight is that we're not seeing it in terms of diaper usage per day; it's really just, in some cases, moms delaying toilet training or even training out of diapers as the child care category. The low birth rate continues to be lower than was forecast early in the year, and so you're just not having as many new moms enter the category.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What about the second part of the question in terms of are you still comfortable with taking the pricing you're taking or you're planning to take &#x2013; have taken given the volume response that you've seen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in the diaper category, there really hasn't been any pricing in the category. In fact, pricing was negative in the quarter. So I would say that &#x2013; the weakness in the category is not related to price change. And, in Consumer Tissue, the pricing is beginning to be put in place in the marketplace and I think the volume response is about what you'd expect. So.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But, In PC you'd planned to take pricing. It got pushed off, pushed off. Now, it's supposed to be October. Is that happening?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It is happening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes and a lot of it's by count so the count changes will start to roll to the shelf in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, maybe more volume hit on that business or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that potentially you'll see some volume softness just because customers typically order a consistent number of cases and if there's a &#x2013; with a count change, you're going to have fewer diapers per case, so you typically have a little bit of an inventory impact when a count change goes into the marketplace. The category tends to be a little softer than we're expecting and that's factored into our adjusted guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And, one question that's sort of a recurring theme, zeroing in on Europe and Consumer Tissue specifically, can you talk a little bit about that business and how it strategically fits in your portfolio at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's &#x2013; we've got leading brand shares in Europe in bath tissue. We've got a strong facial tissue business in Europe as well. It's got margins that are probably a little below the segment average but consistently profitable, and the challenge in Europe has been the growth in private label and actually encouragingly our shares were relatively stable this quarter and private label was stable as well. I think the challenge has been getting any real price recovery there with the run up in fiber cost has not been easy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ali.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Caroline Levy with CLSA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I was wondering if you could take a longer-term view on what this decline in birthrates means in the western countries as you look out to 2012 through 2015. How much do you know about the volume impact just from pure demographics? And I guess there's a flip side of it in countries like &#x2013; throughout Latin America or Asia. How much do you know again about the tailwind from birthrates?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'd say a couple of things. If you look at a global trend, birthrates have been coming down for a while. I mean Europe has probably been the lowest. But even in China with the golden baby policies there, you had a fairly low birthrate in Korea. Probably some of the highest birthrates in the world would tend to be in Africa and in parts of Latin America. And so obviously our business in Latin America has benefited from that.</p>
          <p>In the U.S., we'd say the things that typically are going to drive birthrate are household formation, employment, those kinds of things. And obviously with the weaker economy in the near term, I'd say the category is probably going to be a little softer in 2012 than our prior long-range forecast would have indicated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And are there ways to counter that? I mean, how much innovation are you looking at that can target that? Does it come with lower-priced product? Does it come with breakthrough products? How are you thinking about that decline in global rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, I mean, absolutely. As you go into emerging markets, you're still seeing huge category penetration. And so you saw that in our K-C International growth this year. So for example, where we're today selling diapers but we don't have a very well-developed wipes business. We don't have a very well-developed Little Swimmers business. We still got opportunities to launch diaper pants or training pants to move the category up mix. Those are all things that we're looking at as those consumer incomes develop that they want the best for their baby and they'll buy a broader range of those products.</p>
          <p>Those categories are more fully penetrated in North America, so it's looking for what are other things that we can do like launch Huggies Slip-On Diapers that we did in the third quarter to, again, move Mom to a better mix and a better performing product.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. So if you think about &#x2013; I think you said China, Latin America and Korea were the highlights internationally? Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what happened in Mexico though? That seems a little different from the rest of LatAm?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Mexico &#x2013; had I think mid single-digit volume growth stable shares. Really, they got hit more with commodity cost and some foreign exchange issues as their U.S. dollar payables &#x2013; they suffered a loss on that as the peso devalued at the end of the quarter. But their fundamental volumes and shares are solid in Mexico.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Caroline.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Jason Gere with RBC Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Jason.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Hey. Good morning. Just a question on the growth in KCI. So I mean, it look like a good chunk of that was on the pricing side. And regards to the Personal Care business, the pricing that you took. How much of that was for commodity? How much for currency? And just with some of the major currencies such as the peso and the real, obviously starting to turn. Just your comfort level as you go into 2012 that that pricing can kind of hold?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, I think each of our countries has a strategy to maximize their local currency net income. So they're looking at their business from a perspective of a local currency point of view. So if their commodity costs and local currency terms are going up, they're going to look at pricing to pass that through. They're not necessarily trying to deliver a dollar result, but they take pricing because of translation. So as you think about it, really most of the pricing was a result of commodity input going up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's good. And then just thinking about gross margin, I guess it's a two-part question. One, obviously it's good to see the inflation, especially on the pulp side coming down. I guess the first question is as you exit the year, do you expect to see any gross margins to be kind of flat? I mean, obviously, I think the curtailment &#x2013; production curtailment had a bigger impact in the third quarter that kind of weighed down on your prior guidance. But I guess the first part is, as you look for a nice modest increase in gross margins exiting the year?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, when you think about 2012, it kind of has the same dynamics as 2009, where FX has kind of turned the other way, commodities are improving, pension is going to be a little bit of a headwind, and you have some good cost savings. The magnitude that you saw back in '09 was tremendous, but of course pulp was down 20% plus year-over-year. I guess I was just wondering if you kind of give a little bit of color about 2012 and how you see just the gross margin progression going fourth quarter and maybe into next year? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good questions. If you think about the sequential changes in gross margin in the fourth quarter, pricing should be a positive because we'll get more pricing flowing through from our North American Baby Child Care businesses. Commodities should be a positive sequentially. Still be pressure year-on-year in many areas. Currency will be a drag because you'll have some exchange rates that have gone the wrong direction. And downtime sequentially should be similar to slightly positive. So I think that one we'll have to see where the volumes actually come out. So on balance, I'd say should be more positives than negatives moving from third quarter to fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>As I look at 2012 and we're still &#x2013; there's a lot of moving parts, it seems like more than ever, looking at what's the trade-off of currency headwinds versus commodity tailwinds and how's that going to play out but we'll give you more color in January but our goal is to deliver a 2012 plan that achieves our global business plan goals and has the kind of top line and operating improvement and earnings per share improvement that we're looking for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But directionally, am I on the right path in terms that you should see gross margins start to sequentially improve in 2012? I'm not talking about &#x2013; I mean at this point, yeah, you're right, I think it's a little premature to talk about the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think it would be the '09 kind of a windfall though. I think &#x2013; but yes, directionally it should improve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay. And then just one last question, I was just wondering &#x2013; just on FORCE and just thinking about that you're saying it's going to be shy of the $300 million to $350 million. I mean &#x2013; so does that mean it's going to be below $300 million? Or it's going to be the low end? And I guess the question is last quarter you guys raised it so what kind of delayed some of those savings that you thought you would have gotten this year? Or is this just a plan to have more in store for next year and just not rush it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not like FORCE is a bank account that we can take it out as easily but I think this really has more to do with &#x2013; there's a little bit more downtime than we thought. When you're not running your process as full, you can't push as many cost savings through that pipe that go along with that. So that's probably the biggest single effect. And so I think we got $195 million in the bank through three quarters so we'd need an all-time record fourth quarter to get to the low end of the range so there's a risk that we'll be below the low end of the range. But we'd certainly expect to keep our foot on the gas of delivering as many cost savings because when we deliver those, usually you've got benefits that spill into 2012 as well. So our team is focused on delivering as much as they can this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks for answering the questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Chris Ferrara with Bank of America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. The FX translation for next year, for 2012 or even Q4, can you just talk about what you expect the impact to be on the bottom line relative to the top line, right? Obviously you guys have transaction drag in some markets but can you just talk about what that effect might be, right? If you see a couple of points on the top line, what would the bottom line coincident effect be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, from a translation standpoint, it's fairly linear so that you'll see that same kind of a drag on the bottom line. Transactions were partially hedged. We usually hedge about half of our transaction exposure so there's more of a lag before that flows through earnings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you would &#x2013; but you would expect the bottom-line impact to be bigger than the top line impact, right? When you put it altogether not just translation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And any order of magnitude that you can talk about? I know we've seen in the past it's been pretty variable, right? Is there any kind of a relationship that you guys can talk to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I mean it's such a complicated question because it really depends on where the exchange rate happens and you've seen such wild swings in the last four weeks of the quarter, I think we'll give you a better outlook when we get to 2012. Typically the big currencies for us, the euro is important, the Mexican peso is important, the A dollar is important, the Korean won is important, the Brazilian real is becoming increasingly important. Most of those have weakened at least mid-single-digits to double digits in the last four weeks, and we'll see what happens between now and the end of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thanks. And, look, on marketing research, general and administrative, right, I mean, I know you guys have talked about cutting costs out of there, and it's been a little bit volatile the last couple of years as a percentage of sales. But can you just talk a little bit about what you think that relationship should be like going forward or what the year-on-year change can be as you think about next year? Are we going to see leverage to the SG&amp;A line essentially as you move into 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, as you look at how we think about it, we want to be able to invest more in strategic marketing to fund innovation. And so you're going to see that part of it with upward pressure and us wanting to invest more where we can to go faster and deliver more growth to the market. In our KCP and Health Care business, the selling line is their advertising promotion lever, so we're going to be investing more sellers and driving our safety business, driving our medical device business. The G&amp;A line is where we're trying to get efficiency, and so we're trying to run that and grow that at a slower rate than sales. So if you looked at just SG&amp;A and not include strategic marketing, our goal would be for that overall to grow a little slower than sales, but you'd have more upward pressure on sales and downward pressure on G&amp;A, if that makes sense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It does. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Bill Schmitz with Kimberley-Clark (sic) [Deutsche Bank].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't work for Kimberly-Clark. I mean, I wish. I meant to say I wish I did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I've admired you for years, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just in the Personal Care margin front. Can you just disaggregate what's, I mean what's driving that? How much of it is the slowdown in the training pants business, which is much higher margin? And much of how much of that is just like the geographic business mix where some of the lower-margin markets are growing faster?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I'd say, it's a couple things. A, we are still seeing higher commodity costs, so Personal Care took more of the brunt of inflation this quarter as really pulp was actually slightly positive for the family care segment and all of the fiber cost increase in the quarter fell in K-C Professional which is really secondary fiber. And so Personal Care had the brunt of the inflation this quarter and really had no positive price to speak of in the developed markets. We got some in the emerging markets but not as much in the developed markets and then, the weaker volume in North American diapers and training pants was obviously higher than segment average, so that was a drag on the margins as well in the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So it sounds like one kind of temporary and one is just contingent on what volume growth does. Is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, I think we will start to get price in the fourth quarter, so that will help. You get a little bit of commodity improvement sequentially in the fourth quarter, which will help. And then obviously you need to look for stronger volume growth in those categories over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then how correlated are FORCE savings to commodity costs? I mean, that like when commodities are higher is FORCE easier to generate than when commodities are rolling over?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say we look at our procurement team, for example, looks at savings in four buckets. They look at year-on-year cost savings, they look at cost avoidance where everyone else in the industry got an increase and we didn't, they look at working capital savings and then savings on capital spending. And so, in rising price environments you tend to find more cost avoidance and a little bit less year-on-year. And so in falling price environments or neutral price environments you tend to find more year-on-year cost savings. But I think that's &#x2013; at the margin you're still looking for lots of year-on-year cost savings from that team. I think for us for this year we've got more FORCE out of our lean activity where we're driving waste and efficiency and productivity growth, and that's been a positive for us as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. And then one last one if I could. You said that there was some trade de-stocking on the Personal Care side. It's kind of unusual to see de-stocking ahead of a price increase. So can you just give us a little bit more color on what's going on there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, the price increase is by account. I think you're just finding at the end of every month retailers are managing their balance sheet. Everybody has got working capital objectives just like we do, and you're seeing a little tighter working capital phenomena from a couple of key retailers and we saw that more pronounced this quarter than we've seen in a while.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But is it a category thing or is it a brand thing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we saw it more in Personal Care this particular quarter than we did in Tissue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But is it the Personal Care category or is it Huggies versus Pampers? I mean, what &#x2013; it wasn't distinct to Kimberly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, it was the category.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Well, thanks very much for your time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Gilly Faucher (sic) [John Faucher] with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm assuming that's me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'd say that's you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So thanks. And just a quick question, obviously you said this isn't 2009 and we're not looking at the type of sequential fall off in commodity costs that we saw back then. But there is always a question of okay, when does the sequential fall off in commodities turn into risk to pricing? And so can you talk a little bit about that conceptually in terms of the rational behavior in the category, how you see the competitors thinking about things? And where does it get to the point where we should say, okay, the sequential fall off could lead to higher levels of discounting in terms of people looking to get some of that back?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good questions. If you go back six months which is about where we were when we made a lot of the pricing announcements, commodities have run up quite a ways past where we were then. And so I think as we would look at it we'd say, yes commodities have come back a little bit but they're still at higher levels than they were when we announced the price increases. So we would say the price increases in the marketplace that we've announced are still appropriate and justified by the commodity input costs. We'll still have year-on-year cost increases in the fourth quarter for example and we'd play that through. So I assume our other competitors in the marketplace are seeing the same things and so at this point we'll see how it plays out in the marketplace and whether private label moves and all those kinds of things.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So it sounds like we almost probably need to look at this in terms of the rationality of pricing not just on a sequential or even a year-over-year basis but more of like a peak to trough.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that makes sense.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...level. Is that the right way to look at it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, yes. I think at this point based on what we see it's hard to imagine commodities falling enough that you'd have an impact on market pricing but it's- there is a pretty volatile world we live in some days.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Chip Dillon with Vertical Research Partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Good morning, guys. Hey, first question is on the pension situation. Could you just let us know &#x2013; you're upping the amount you're putting into it &#x2013; how much of the $680 million to $760 million have you done through the nine months? And is there, shall we expect a share &#x2013; it looks like you're not going to buy back stock in the fourth quarter, would you have an early look as to how you think about that next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, what we &#x2013; what &#x2013; our thinking on that &#x2013; and maybe Mark can add a little color to it &#x2013; the big issue on the pension plan for us is more as you look at what's happened to the discount rate. We've made actually good progress this year. We've put a little over $400 million in the plans already. We've actually had better than our benchmark performance. But when you compare that to what's happened to the liability because of the drop in long-term interest rates, we've basically gone backwards on our funded status. And so we've got some internal goals that we want to hit in terms of funding status and so we made the call that we would go ahead and accelerate some of our 2012 pension contribution into this year and we'll probably then do a little bit heavier than normal stock buyback next year and kind of flip-flop those, but, Mark, I don't know if you want to add anything to that, but --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, no. I think directionally that's right. We knew coming into this year we're going to be heavier on share repurchases maybe than we had typically been. They were going to be more front end loaded. We've accomplished that. We're generating plenty of cash flow and which gives us some options. And just given where pension funded status was relative to our target decided to shift that a little bit. You should think about it as an acceleration of next year's and that just frees up cash to buy back shares in 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well, one of the downsides of low interest rates is that everybody's pension plan sprung a leak so it's got to be filled up with more cash.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. And let's say rates stay roughly where they are and your assets stay where they are, now in the plans, do you think &#x2013; I know last year you ended the year about $1.1 billion in your plans underfunded. Would you be in that neighborhood with this or might you improve on that? And secondly I know in 2010 your pension expense &#x2013; I'm not sure what it's been this year &#x2013; was $133 million looking at your K. Did you see a big change from '11 to '12 given that you're putting this funding in?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I would guess that when putting this additional funding in our funded status would improve slightly in the plan so --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's about &#x2013; think of this $260 million relative to that $1.1 billion, Chip, that's about 25% of our global GAAP.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so while our funded status has fallen off this will top that up. And then some &#x2013; and then as you &#x2013; as &#x2013; one of the things that we did by freezing our DB plan, we're less sensitive now to volatility in our pension expense going forward because we'll be amortizing any actuarial gains and losses over the remaining physical life of employees, not their service life. So there's some &#x2013; so we'll see less volatility next year. We'll give you more color on what our pension expense assumptions are in 2012 but I don't think it's going to be as big a swing as you might have seen in prior years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then a couple small items. One is it looks like you talked about your ad spend going up this quarter. Can you just give us a flavor as to will this level sort of be maintained? And then on a different note, if you just would talk a little bit about the other income line, $17 million positive, is certainly bigger than normal. Is that something that's new or was it the one-time just puts and takes happened to end up there and it should go back more or less to zero in the future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah in the ad spend we're up a little bit year-over-year but as a percent of sales we're not &#x2013; we're down. So our expectation is that over long term I think you'd still want to see us growing that line a little faster than sales growth. And so that's still an opportunity area for us as you look at 2012 and longer forecasting. We tend to want to invest more there if we could. So I'd say, yeah, that one's got more upward pressure.</p>
          <p>On the other income and expense, we had currencies, some small currency transaction gains this time versus losses last year and then we had a sale of a small asset in South America that had a gain on it. That was the other factor. But that would not be something that you'd repeat so --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then lastly, the FORCE issue this year being a challenge and it looks like it picked up a bit, at least in the third quarter from the first half pace. But would you say that's mostly due to the volume challenges and you can't run as well? Or was it that you just didn't &#x2013; you don't feel you'll be able to tackle all the programs you might have had earlier in the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think it's more the former. But as &#x2013; you take curtailment and you're not running your process as much, you don't get the benefits of the cost savings that were inherent in the cost savings program. So our team is aggressively looking at delivering another very solid year from a FORCE standpoint but because of the weaker volume we're not going to get quite as much through the pipe as we would have thought.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, guys. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chip.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Lauren Lieberman with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Lauren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. Just about Consumer Tissue, the &#x2013; I think you mentioned a couple of times that the de-sheeting, you would expect &#x2013; the volume decline seem sort in line. So when we look from here though, can you just remind me how long the lag is to where kind of volume or normal consumption catches up with that kind of de-sheeting activity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lauren, I mean, I think that until you annualize the de-sheeting activity you'll have a volume drag from de-sheeting relative to your comps. So we look at dollar share and we'd say on a dollar share basis we're essentially on track with where we thought we'd be. We're probably watching more competitive promotion pricing across multiple outlets and it's a little choppy right now. Some places it's moved up, some places it hasn't. So that's probably the biggest thing we're watching in the marketplace right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because the 4 points of pricing was a 6 point volume drag does actually seem a lot more severe in terms of volume impact than was the case at any time in the last 6, 7 years when you price. So, should pricing accelerate from here and the volume &#x2013; is your expectation the volume remains similarly challenged and pricing accelerates? Or does it in fact feel like the elasticity is worse than it was at this time around three years ago?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think in some cases the de-sheeting was a little bigger than maybe we've done in prior years in part because of some of the commodity cost run-up. But I think we've got most of the price in the marketplace as we speak on Consumer Tissue. There maybe a little bit more that comes internationally but there's not going to be any more planned at this point in time in North America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So it feels like maybe the missing piece of the puzzle then is adding in the margin improvement, that it's not just about the top line, it's the profitability of every roll sold is that much better right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on the inventory &#x2013; actually, I'm sorry &#x2013; on curtailment. Is there a way for you guys to manage curtailment better, I mean, with better forecasting? Because it doesn't sound like &#x2013; it's tissue demand in Europe, but if North America birth rate challenges continue, should that really be much of a surprise at this point that we're still looking at curtailment being a 50 basis point drag in a given quarter? It just feels like to me it's maybe something where you should be adjusting your production well in advance of needing to make this kind of adjustment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I guess I would interpret it &#x2013; we're more disciplined about hitting target inventory levels and not running up inventory. So inventory historically is the slack variable and if you missed your sales forecast, you just ran your inventory up. We're more disciplined now by taking the downtime in the quarter. As you realize you are off-track from a sales forecast, you shut the process and don't build the inventory. And so as a result, you're seeing more real-time impact from curtailment than maybe we would have seen several years ago. And I think you're seeing that throughout the extended supply chain. I think you're seeing retailers adjust inventory levels quicker if they are not seeing foot traffic than they would. And so &#x2013; and the reality is in most cases you own the asset at this point, so you can't do anything else other than curtail it, if you've got a demand shortfall.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But is there room as you look over the next 12 to 24 months to be more anticipatory in terms of demand levels in child care and infant care in North America?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, we haven't added a diaper machine or a training pant machine in North America in a long time. So we have kind of what we have and we think we will need it as we drive innovation and continue to grow the business. What probably had a bigger impact on us is as we move internationally and have had more productivity growth, we've been able to actually sequence our capital better and probably do a better job of planning our international production capacity to a larger extent than we've maybe done previously.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Because the margins in Personal Care, I know you've walked through &#x2013; the Personal Care feeling the brunt of the cost inflation this quarter and the timing on pricing. But the margin performance in that business this year has been pretty notable, right? And going back to the first quarter, you guys talked about some one-time items in the quarter in addition to lack of pricing, commodity cost inflation and expecting to get better as the year progressed. So, is there anything else? It just &#x2013; it feels a little bit like something's missing to be looking at 16.5% margins in a business that typically runs 20% to 21%. This has had a very sudden change in profitability profile in the last nine months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no. I mean, there's no question. When you say notable, we've noticed it as well. And so no, no one is satisfied with where the Personal Care margins are. And so we are going to get more price in North America in the fourth quarter, that will help. We should see some sequential commodity improvement that will help. And in the meantime, we're going to keep the innovation coming to continue to drive the business forward. So, we have had good success in lots of areas like adult care, feminine care that are positives, but we've got to show what's growth and margin over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The Slip-On Diaper, I'm guessing, do we &#x2013; how far does that need to go in terms of share for it to be a mix positive strong enough to offset some of the &#x2013; sorry, the negative mix dynamics from child care? And the child care is such a big business that that's probably going to win for a while.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, I think that the drag on the child care category is going to be a bigger impact than Slip-On can overcome, that's for sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Lauren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Javier Escalante with Consumer Edge Research.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. I'm fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Javier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. How are you guys?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that the question probably would be better for Mark. It has to do with the gross margin progression that you are guiding to for the fourth quarter versus the lack of improvement in gross margin in the third quarter. What I see is that we didn't see a sequential improvement in the third quarter in spite that commodities improved, right? You have 150 pressure versus 180 in the last quarter. You have 3 points of pricing in the third quarter versus 1 point of pricing in the second quarter. And you have $90 million in FORCE savings in the third quarter versus $50 million in the second quarter. So all these three items should add up to margin progression to see some improvement in gross margin and yet, something held back these improvements. So could you tell us what held back the gross margin progression in the third quarter that is going to be changing in the fourth quarter so we will see these items benefiting the gross margin line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, I'll start and then I'll let Mark give you kind of the color commentary. If you look at sequentially you'd say, okay, pricing is going to be better in fourth quarter versus third quarter. Commodity costs will be a little bit better fourth quarter versus third quarter. Still higher than last year but should be sequentially better. Currency will be a drag. And so that'll partially offset those. And then downtime, at this point our guidance would say that it should be slightly positive. So not as negative as third quarter and then part that was last year's fourth quarter had a bigger drag from downtime so we'll be lapping that from a comp standpoint. But, Mark, if you want to give him any other color to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, Javier, I think third quarter volumes were a little lighter than we expected. Other than that, Tom's review of the bidding is about right. Better pricing, slightly better commodities, currency will go the other way, downtime will be about the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just to clarify, right, we had all those improvements already in the third quarter relative to the second quarter. So basically we didn't see the margin improvement. So my understanding then is that the swing factor for us to see the margin improvement that you are guiding to, either volume either curtailment or whatever have you is going to be better than it was in the third quarter. That is going to make the difference for us to see the sequential improvement that you're guiding to.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess I'd say, Javier, in some cases commodity costs peaked in the third quarter. So for example secondary fiber was at its peak in the third quarter and the Personal Care pricing and Baby Child Care is going to come in the fourth quarter, so we'll have more price in the fourth quarter than third from some of those businesses. So I do think that the story for the fourth quarter is a little different than the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, but if you &#x2013; and just not to beat this horse to death, but you have $30 million lower commodities, you have around $100 million better in revenues because of pricing, and you have $40 million better in FORCE savings in the third quarter and yet gross margins were similar to what we saw in the second quarter. So the question is what is holding back the improvement in the third quarter relative to the second quarter that is going to change in the fourth quarter relative to the third quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and I think, Javier, we've tried to explain the key moving pieces both in the news release and in the remarks and Tom's color about the fourth quarter of the key changes sequentially are just what he said, which is commodity costs coming down somewhat, a bit more pricing and a fair amount of those two things are offset by currency. So we do believe that sequentially that our gross margins will pick up from third quarter levels, and we'll come back to you at the end of the year and tell you how we did.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And of the $100 million lower raw material cost that you are forecasting for 2011, how much of it was already accretive in the third quarter? And if you can tell us what kind of pulp prices are you are assuming for the Q4? And that will be my last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, most of the $100 million change in inflation will come in the fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And in terms of pulp pricing for the fourth quarter, we are assuming between $935 and $950 for northern softwood.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Connie Maneaty with BMO Capital Markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Morning, Connie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I just have a few questions and thank you for giving such complete answers on the call. Given the downtime and the curtailment you've taken and slowing birthrates almost worldwide, what is your capacity utilization in diapers and training pants? And do you think that your plants and your production lines are in the right locations as you look three to five years out for where growth is slowing and for where it's really picking up?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as you saw in the quarter from K-C International, we've still got a huge growth story. So you got a great category penetration opportunity in the international markets that's far outweighing the impact of a slow birthrate. And so it's taking a mom from using one diaper per day to using five diapers a day as they would in developed markets is a big, big deal. And so we're still adding capacity for both diapers and pants as well as Fem Care as well as Adult Care in our international markets consistently. And so that trend will play out for a number of years to come.</p>
          <p>In North America I'd say we've got some additional capacity but we've also got a pretty aggressive innovation agenda and so I think we've got some slight additional capacity but nothing that I would say that I'm particularly worried about at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. What's the outlook for the Santa diaper and how would you compare it to the blue jean diaper?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think fashion is something we continue to believe is a big idea. Being first, being innovative, being different, being relevant is key. So we're excited about it and we'll see what mom feels about it when it gets into the marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's it for me. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Connie.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Karen Lamark with Federated Investors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I just want to follow up on Lauren's questions about the production curtailment and the first thing I wanted to know is how much of it is a function of your own forecasting versus, say, retailer actions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, they're sort of related. So we can certainly do a better job of forecasting and so that's a &#x2013; that's part of it but it's also sometimes when a retailer decides they're going to bring inventories down at the end of a quarter, you can only react to that. So you wish you knew about it earlier; you could've planned better, you would've forecasted better but I think that's a challenge for our teams is that we can do a better job of forecasting the business so that we can run our supply chain as efficiently with as low inventory as possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the good news is we've got better capabilities to do that than we ever have before and what you're seeing is inventories continued across the enterprise to come down and faster reaction time on our part when we do miss a demand plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And, then also are the curtailments meaningful beyond the baby, Personal Care category? Are there any other categories that are showing signs of &#x2013; the need for some production cuts? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I'd say it was predominantly concentrated in Personal Care and Consumer Tissue. Basically, Health Care and K-C Professional, there wasn't much curtailment in the quarter and so we were a little light on Scott tissue relative to expectations and took some time out of the schedule from that standpoint but nothing out of the ordinary from how we'd run it quarter to quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Ali Dibadj with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Ali.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Thanks for taking the follow-up. Just a question about how we should be thinking about marketing investment in CT in particular. It looks like obviously in this quarter it was down. Obviously, we've even on this call have had debates about the ROI on marketing investments in Consumer Tissue. Specifically, have your &#x2013; has your thought process changed at all about that, the ROI you're getting by marketing spend there in this environment or even broader longer term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we continue to get better at measuring ROI and allocating spend, and I'd tell you actually some of our highest ROI events in the company have been in Kleenex facial tissue. So we measure it. We look at it across the portfolio and look to see what's the right vehicle. We're doing a better job of being creative and channel agnostic in terms of how we bring those to market, but we'd say particularly for the premium end of the category, things that we've done with the micro campaign on Viva has responded positively to the sales growth you've seen in our Towel business. Our Kleenex facial tissue activities that we've had going have had a high return, and Cottonelle is a pretty high-margin category so there's some responsiveness there. So we do track it and make intelligent investment decisions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But, we should expect on CT, in particular, marketing spending to continue to go up as a percent of sales?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I would say yes but we'd look probably for more opportunities to drive adult care, drive fem care, drive baby child care around the world. If you look at the big picture, Consumer Tissue is probably going to be more a North American story. I think, the other markets around the world, it's going to be a little bit spottier in terms of where those opportunities are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, given that though and the kind of beneficial ROI you're getting, shouldn't we be concerned that it was down this quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that it's more a function of what your cycle of investment is and so the fact that we launched Cool Touch at the end of the quarter, you're going to see a little heavier push on that in the fourth quarter. As we were going through a pricing cycle, you tend to wind up not as much on promotion with some retailers until you get your new prices established. And so &#x2013; so you often want to couple strategic investment with trade execution, and if you're not going to get the trade execution, you pull back a little bit. So, I wouldn't read too much into it. It's more a function of timing, of innovation than anything else.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Chip Dillon with Vertical Research Partners.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, yes. Just a quick follow-up; as you all have grown overseas, I just wanted to get an update on your exposure to two raw materials, one would be waste paper and the other one to pulp. The last I had was, like, 2.5 million for pulp and 900,000 for waste paper annually.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the pulp number is pretty close. The wastepaper number is more like a million too so....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, basically all you're buying would be the pulp substitute type grades, the bleached collections?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you're looking for a higher-quality wastepaper if there &#x2013; if that's not an oxymoron but &#x2013; it's a office waste kind of a grade as opposed to the really cheap stuff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got you. And, then just another quick one; on the charge in the fourth quarter &#x2013; sorry, the third quarter, for the pulp and tissue, I would assume about $80 million of it was for &#x2013; was in depreciation. I don't know if you gave that somewhere but is that about right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know that we gave that level of detail but the team is looking through that. It's basically that thing is tracking with our plans. They're giving me smiley faces so it sounds like you're in the ballpark with the $80 million so....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I like smiley faces. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks, Chip.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time, we have no further questions in the queue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thanks, David. We appreciate the questions, and we'll just finish with our closing comment from Tom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Well, once again, we're tracking and executing our Global Business Plan. We're pleased with the progress we made in the quarter but not satisfied, and we appreciate your support of Kimberly-Clark. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen that concludes today's presentation. You may disconnect at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>