<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1225613" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-04-15</date>
    <companies>
      <company>842</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Richard D. Kinder, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">C. Park Shaper, President</participant>
      <participant id="3">Darren Horowitz</participant>
      <participant id="4">Richard Kinder</participant>
      <participant id="5">R. Tim Bradley</participant>
      <participant id="6">Steven Kean</participant>
      <participant id="7">Noah Lerner</participant>
      <participant id="8">Kimberly Allen Dang</participant>
      <participant id="9">C. Park Shaper</participant>
      <participant id="10">Brian Zarahn</participant>
      <participant id="11">Xin Liu</participant>
      <participant id="12">John Edwards</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Welcome and I would like to thank you all for holding and inform you that your lines are in a listen-only mode during today's conference until the question-and-answer session. Today's call is also being recorded. If you have any objections, you may disconnect at this time.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to turn the call over to Rich Kinder. Sir, you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ed, and welcome everybody to the First Quarter Kinder Morgan Energy Partners Conference Call. As usual, we're likely to make statements within the meaning of the Securities Act of 1933 and the Securities Exchange Act of 1934.</p>
          <p>Also as usual, I'll give a overview of our first quarter performance and our strategic outlook for the year, and then turn it over to Park Shaper, our President, who will go through all the financials. And then we'll throw open the line for any questions that you may have.</p>
          <p>Let me start by focusing on what I would call the view from 30,000 feet and then get down to tree top level for a more detailed look at our performance and the outlook for the rest of 2009 on a business segment-by-business segment basis.</p>
          <p>First, let me say while the year-to-year comparisons for the first quarter don't look very good, we're actually very pleased with what we've accomplished and with the way the rest of 2009 looks to be shaping up. And I'll go into that in some detail.</p>
          <p>If you go back to our Investor Conference in January, we said then that we faced a number of headwinds toward &#x2013; as burdens toward achieving our budget target of $4.20 in distributions per unit for 2009. And we said that those headwinds included lower than anticipated oil prices, potential for lower Products Pipeline throughput as a result of the recession, and lower volumes at some of our bulk terminals particularly those that handle steel.</p>
          <p>Those have all come to roost I think, but the good news is we've overcome the great bulk of any potential shortfall in distributable cash flow. And I'll go into some kind of &#x2013; into more detail of that as we go forward. So we're making good progress on overcoming the headwinds, and we look forward to certainly meeting our distribution target of $4.20 per unit.</p>
          <p>Now let me just go into a little more detail, again from the overall corporate standpoint. In our budget, we assumed that WTI price of $68 per barrel. That didn't look too unreasonable back in September and October of 2008 when we put our budget together. But we realized by the beginning of the year that that was probably too high. So rather than change the budget, we just told you that the sensitivity in our CO2 segment was $6 million for every $1 variance.</p>
          <p>Today, as we look at our full year strip, including what we have received and actually realized for the first quarter, we expect the number to be in the low 50s versus 68 in the budget.</p>
          <p>So you'd think we would be confronted with a headwind or a shortfall of $100 million give or take from a commodity price differential alone. And you add to that the fact that we're also experiencing lower throughput in our Products Pipeline and lower steel volumes in our Terminal segment, as I referenced earlier, and you'd think we would face a pretty big shortfall for the year.</p>
          <p>In fact, we've been able to mitigate the great bulk of that shortfall, and under our current forecast, we're looking a lot better than these negative factors would imply.</p>
          <p>How we've been able to do that? First of all, we are experiencing lower interest rates on our floating rate debt. At today's forward curve, we expect interest expense to be significantly below our plan for full year 2009.</p>
          <p>Secondly, we've begun to achieve some significant improvements in operating expenses. To give you one example, we expect our O&amp;M costs in our CO2 segment to be lower than plan by at least $35 million. Now that contrasted with a lower number that we targeted at the time of our Investor Conference. We've been able to improve on that, and I think there may be more in that segment between now and year-end.</p>
          <p>We've also been able to achieve additional reductions in operating costs in our other business segments, although not at that same level. And we've been able to lower our capital expenditure costs, particularly in our CO2 segment</p>
          <p>The next positive factor offsetting the headwinds is we've been able to reduce our compensation and benefit costs by over $15 million. And we've done that by deferring salary increases and freezing certain benefits for 2009.</p>
          <p>The next positive factor that we're beginning to see is strong performance in our Natural Gas Pipeline segment. And then finally and perhaps most importantly, we now expect better than budgeted production at both SACROC and Yates for fiscal year 2009.</p>
          <p>As we've shown you in our numbers attached to our release, in the first quarter we averaged 30,000 barrels per day &#x2013; put that in perspective, that's up from 27,300 barrels per day in the first quarter of 2008, and it's up from 29,000 barrels per day that we had in our plan. If you want to go a step further, during March and April to date, we've been averaging a shade over 31,000 barrels per day.</p>
          <p>Now, why is it significant? Because as we've told you in our sensitivity chart at our Investor Conference, every 1,000 barrels per day difference at SACROC is worth $27 million in bottom line benefit. Now let me qualify that by saying that obviously that $27 million was based on the budgeted prices. So it'd be somewhat less than that. But it's still very significant and frankly, the most important moving part in our CO2 earnings and cash flow generation picture.</p>
          <p>So those are five positives that have gone a long way toward offsetting the headwinds that we faced. So we're feeling a lot better about the year.</p>
          <p>Now while we are early in the year and there are lots of moving parts, we think that again, as we've said all along, the great bulk of the $2.1 billion that it takes to distribute $4.20 per unit is very secure. We did face these headwinds and we'll continue to face them. But even if you look at them realistically and look at our current forecast through the light of the present circumstances, we're feeling a lot better about our ability to distribute $4.20, which we certainly expect and intend to do.</p>
          <p>Now obviously, we expect to generate that. If we fall a little short of actually generating the $4.20, I'll remind you of course that we have accumulated excess coverage that would occur for us this year which gives us even more confidence in the ability to sustain and actually make the distribution of our target of $4.20 per unit.</p>
          <p>Now let me talk about results and outlook on a business-by-business view. Starting with our Products Pipeline, we expect healthy growth in earnings before DD&amp;A in 2009 versus 2008, and we saw some of that in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>We had good performance from our West Coast Terminals, and we'll be helped by the inflation escalator that goes into effect on July 1.</p>
          <p>We're still experiencing weak throughput on our refi0ned products pipelines, as you can see from our attachments to our earnings release. Our refined products volumes were down about 5% in the first quarter being shipped on our Cochin line, which moves NGLs from Canada down into the U.S. Midwest. Overall mixing and matching all of these factors on our Products Pipeline, we expect to come out modestly below plan for full year 2009.</p>
          <p>Natural Gas Pipelines were well above 2008 in the first quarter as you can see. And we expect that positive difference to continue and actually to strengthen throughout the full year 2009 as we're helped by our new pipelines that are coming online later in the year.</p>
          <p>We're also helped by continued good performance at our Texas Intrastate. With regard to our Natural Gas Pipelines segment, we expect to be approximately on plan for the year in earnings before DD&amp;A and modestly above plan in terms of distributable cash flow as our sustaining CapEx in this particular segment is running a little lower than expected.</p>
          <p>In our Terminal segment, we're experiencing good results in our liquids terminals and in practically most of our bulk facilities. But we are seeing weaknesses in the terminals which handle steel products, which is obviously a leading indicator, at least in my view, of the weak economy that we are experiencing in this country.</p>
          <p>Now on the other side of it, we are helped by lower prices of diesel fuel than we had in our budget. As you recall with all the machinery we operate at these terminals, we spend an awful lot of money on diesel fuel. And we are also helped by our ability to make significant reductions in variable costs, particularly on a terminal-by-terminal basis at those terminals like the steel terminals that are handling less throughput than we were in 2008.</p>
          <p>So the combination of these savings and frankly through some acquisitions that we believe will be made within the next quarter, we believe that the performance of Terminals will look pretty good for the year. We are anticipating now that we'll probably be modestly under plan for the year in terms of earnings before DD&amp;A, but about on target or maybe even a few million dollars above in terms of segment distributable cash flow.</p>
          <p>In our CO2 segment, I think I've pretty well covered it in my earlier remarks on the whole company. But it is interesting to note that while we expect to run below both plan and last year for the full year, we do expect to run pretty close to plan for the remaining three quarters given the anticipated kicking in of the cost savings that we have. And the higher volumes in our oil production platforms at SACROC and Yates. So that's where we stand on the CO2.</p>
          <p>And again on a lot of these cost savings, we negotiated them during the first quarter. Most of the impact will really come to the fore in quarters two through four.</p>
          <p>Our fifth business segment of course is our Canadian operations. And there as you can see, we're well above 2008 for the first quarter, we expect to be well above 2008 for the full year. That's as a result of the Trans Mountain expansion which was completed in the fall of 2008, and also having a full year of Express at the KMP level. Both of those helped our results when you compare them to 2008.</p>
          <p>When you start talking about comparison to plan, the main potential negative or risk is the Canadian dollar and its strength or weakness against the U.S. dollar. It's right now running a little weaker than it was last fall, and obviously that's a negative with regard to achieving plan.</p>
          <p>We also have a non-cash accounting change relating to book taxes which get zeroed out at the corporate level because we always differentiate for you cash taxes from book taxes. But in terms of segment earnings before DD&amp;A, that will also have an impact.</p>
          <p>Zeroing out those two factors, which I think is the right way to judge the performance of the segment itself, we expect the Canadian segment to be on plan for full year 2009.</p>
          <p>Now as we look at the year, aside from achieving our financial and our operational and safety goals, our other major objective is to complete the sizeable expansion projects that are under construction, particularly our three large Natural Gas Pipeline projects.</p>
          <p>Let me give you an update on our progress. First, let me say that outside of these three major projects in the Natural Gas group, virtually all of our other, admittedly smaller, capital projects are running on budget and on time. So we don't have any problems other than in these three big projects.</p>
          <p>Now with regard to those three projects, let me start with the bad news. We've continued to see project costs move up, and we've experienced some additional delays as we reported. The culprits really remain the same and they are &#x2013; weather, regulatory restrictions, and time and material contracts, and unfortunately those factors kind of work together. In other words, if you have rain, this triggers additional environmental requirements and slows down construction. And the costs of the slowing down of construction and the additional environmental requirements are passed on to the project. That's the negative.</p>
          <p>On the brighter side, we're in a better position than we've been for a long time on the construction that remains to be done. Why is that? We've secured unit price contracts versus time and material contracts for the final leg on MEP and the final leg on REX.</p>
          <p>Now in MEP, that's the part of the pipeline that runs from Delhi &#x2013; we expect to be to Delhi by the end of this month. From Delhi on across Mississippi to the Transco Station just on the Alabama side of the border, we have unit contracts on that leg. We also have unit contracts on the REX project from Lebanon on out to Clarington. That's the construction that will start next month. During the month of May those contractors will be turned loose. We have all of our notices to proceed on that as we do on Midcontinent Express.</p>
          <p>So we have a better price environment in terms of the type of contracts we have for the rest of these two major pipelines. And we have a cost cap on the relatively small remaining amount of work that needs to be done on Kinder Morgan Louisiana.</p>
          <p>We've also been able to finish much more of the upfront regulatory work. So we'll have a relatively clean start on the construction for these final legs. And this year, that is the fact that we have notices to proceed for the balance of both of those projects.</p>
          <p>On our Fayetteville Express project, we expect to benefit even more from the improved cost environment there. And we're taking full advantage of the time we have to be well prepared when construction begins later on the project that will not be in operation until late 2010 or early 2011.</p>
          <p>And we're almost finished. We'll end the year with all three of our current projects fully in service and with a much more manageable slate for 2010 and beyond.</p>
          <p>So hope that gives you an update of what's going on. And with that, I'll turn it over to Park to get into the financial details. Park?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Well thanks, Rich. So it's the first quarter, so everybody's nap time &#x2013; while I go through these numbers &#x2013; will be a little bit shorter. But turning to the first page of the numbers behind the press release, you'll see the face of the income statement. Really just comment there towards the bottom, you'll see the declared distribution per unit of $1.05. So the Board today did declare $1.05 as the distribution for the first quarter, consistent with our budgeted distribution of $4.20.</p>
          <p>If you go to the second page, again towards the bottom of that page, it's the second line from the bottom above the footnotes. The DCF per unit before certain items is $0.97 for the quarter. So we don't quite cover the $1.05 distribution and we're a little bit under our budget. And I'll go through why in just a minute although Rich has already covered a lot of it.</p>
          <p>But first, just from a broader perspective, I mean that negative coverage, the gap between the distribution and what we're generating in terms of cash flow is about $23 million.</p>
          <p>As we currently look at our forecast, we expect that we will have a gap in coverage in the second quarter and the third quarters, and then have pretty significant excess coverage in the fourth quarter. And as we look our forecast, and this is what Rich was alluding to, we have dropped in essentially the forward curve for oil prices. We have reduced our expectations in terms of product volumes. We have reduced our expectations in terms of steel volumes. So in essence, we've included the impact of these headwinds that we have felt.</p>
          <p>And then we've also incorporated the cost savings that Rich mentioned, the higher SACROC volumes that we are seeing. And what is very encouraging for us today relative to where we were three months ago, is that as we look forward the gap between our expected distribution and the cash that we are going to generate is a whole lot narrower than those headwinds would imply.</p>
          <p>And so Rich totaled up &#x2013; again just on the CO2 &#x2013; oil prices, you can get to $100 million. And you add the impact of the other items on top of that, and you get above $100 million. We have narrowed that gap to a fraction of that number. And so as we look forward for the rest of the year, we still have work to do, but we're very encouraged by what we've been able to accomplish in the last three months.</p>
          <p>And so focusing a little bit more on the first quarter, and I'll talk as Richard's already done about some of the outlook as well. If you move up from the DCF per unit, the line right above that is the net income per unit &#x2013; $0.22 before certain items relative to about $0.64 a year ago. We talked about a lot of this back in January as a function of how reserve tend to be marked at the end of the year, how our depreciation has gone up considerably. And so that depreciation is impacting this net income number.</p>
          <p>In addition, I mean, clearly the crude prices that we experienced in the first quarter were significantly below our budget. And so that also impacted this number. Ultimately as we say every quarter, we don't think the net income per unit is the overly relevant number, it includes that non-cash depreciation charge. We think that the DCF per unit is a much more meaningful number.</p>
          <p>Continuing to move up, DCF before certain items &#x2013; $260 million, down from where we were a year ago of about 280, almost $281 million. Again the impact of oil prices alone or really as commodity prices on our CO2 segment was $50 million in the quarter. And so you can see that we did a good job in the quarter of overcoming the majority of that impact.</p>
          <p>Above that, sustaining capital expenditures &#x2013; essentially flat with last year. As we look forward for 2009, we actually think that we'll come in a little bit under our budget. You may recall our budget is $202 million, we think that we'll see some savings in sustaining CapEx on the Terminal side and on the Natural Gas side, and a little bit on the CO2 side. So again we expect the sustaining CapEx for the year will be a little bit under our budget.</p>
          <p>There is a variety of reasons for that. One is just lower costs. To get the same work done, again, costs have come down. Some is &#x2013; certain projects that moved to operating expense. And so they show up in expense rather than in sustaining capital expenditures. Some projects that have been deferred to future years, and then some things that with lower volumes, and this is especially true on the Terminal side, just don't need to be done. And so certain maintenance, as you move less product through your facility, then that maintenance does not need to be done until a later date when more volume moves through.</p>
          <p>The Express contribution is a little bit above budget for the quarter, and will be a little bit above budget for the year. The book cash tax differences &#x2013; essentially where we expected to be for the quarter. And then above that you'll see the DD&amp;A is $56 million from where it was a year ago, 45 of that is coming at the CO2 segment. And so that's what is driving that.</p>
          <p>And so those are the components that again get from net income to distributable cash flow.</p>
          <p>Why don't we talk about the segments at the top of the page? Rich has already covered a lot of this. Product Pipelines is up about $5 million from where it was a year ago. It is a little bit below its budget. The entire miss relative to budget comes from Cochin. If you look at all of the other assets other than Cochin, we did experience lower volumes on those assets. But that impact was offset by lower costs, and then some nice performance at the West Coast Terminals. And so the entire downfall relative to budget came from Cochin.</p>
          <p>On Cochin, we did see fewer volumes available at the origin of the pipeline in Canada to transport down that pipeline. And that drove that shortfall. We actually expect to see a shortfall at Cochin for the entire year. And so, in truth, we expect right now that the entire year will be analogous to the first quarter.</p>
          <p>All of our shortfall relative to plan will be from Cochin. And all of the other assets in the aggregate &#x2013; and of course there are some things that will be up and some things that will be down. But if you look at all of the other assets in the aggregate, we expect them to be on plan even with lower volumes than our plan forecasted.</p>
          <p>Natural Gas Pipelines up about $14 million from a year ago &#x2013; dead-on its plan for the quarter. As Rich mentioned, for the year there are some ins and outs. The project delays hurt us a little bit in terms for earnings before DD&amp;A. KMIGT is performing very well, which helps to offset that. We expect that we will be right about our earnings before DD&amp;A plan. And as I mentioned, we expect sustaining CapEx for this segment to be slightly lower. So on a DCF basis, the Natural Gas Pipelines segment will be above its budget.</p>
          <p>CO2 is down about $32 million from a year ago. I mentioned a minute ago that the impact of price was $50 million. So you can see again clawing some of that back. It was down also from its budget, although again not down as much from its budget as price would imply. And as Rich mentioned, what's going on here is we're experiencing the lower prices. We're offsetting that with cost savings. And truthfully, the majority of the cost savings will be felt as we go into the second, third and fourth quarters. And then of course, with strong volumes coming out of SACROC and on budget volumes at Yates.</p>
          <p>On the Terminals segment, up about $9 million for the quarter. We expect them to be just a hair below their earnings before DD&amp;A budget for the year, although again here we're getting a little bit of sustaining CapEx savings. So on a DCF basis, we think that the Terminals will be a little bit ahead of their budget, and that is overcoming the weakness in steel volumes, which impact our revenues. A little bit of weakness on the fertilizer side as well, but it's significantly smaller than the steel volumes.</p>
          <p>And again I'll remind you, as we talk about the forecast we have incorporated into the future quarters, the lower volume expectations on steel, lower volume expectations on the Products Pipelines and the forward curve for crude oil prices.</p>
          <p>Kinder Morgan Canada is up from last year by about $4 million. It's actually a little bit under its plan in terms of segment earnings before DD&amp;A. But as Rich mentioned, that's driven by two factors that are not operational. One is a book tax accrual that's a function of an accounting change. And the other is a change in FX which impacted us in the quarter as well. Absent those two items, Kinder Morgan Canada was on budget for the quarter. And again absent those two items, we expect them to be on budget for the full year.</p>
          <p>Now the book tax change &#x2013; that again is a non-cash item and does get that back down below when we reconcile to cash taxes, that change will recur every quarter this year. So we're going to continue to talk about that as a variance relative to budget. But I'll remind you it is non-cash &#x2013; it is reversed out when we get to distributable cash flow. You'll see total segment earnings before DD&amp;A essentially flat with where we were a year ago.</p>
          <p>With that, I'm going to drop down &#x2013; drop below the DD&amp;A and then the segment earnings contributions from the segments. And you'll see G&amp;A down there about $84 million. It is an increase in expense of about $8.5 million from where we were in the first quarter &#x2013; relative to 2008, that's essentially all timing. It's timing on taxes, it's timing on some capitalization, it's timing on benefit. We expect that to sort itself out relative to 2008 over the course of the year. And the really important factor is that our forecast for the year currently is about $10 million under our budget. And so primarily for the reasons that Rich mentioned, the savings that we expect to see, we expect that G&amp;A will come in under our budget for the year.</p>
          <p>Interest below that, you'll see it is up about $7 million from where we were a year ago. It is a little bit over our quarterly budget. But when we look at it for the year, we expect that interest will be under our budget, and will provide a nice savings relative to that budget. Now it's up from a year ago because balance has gone up as a function of the expansion CapEx and acquisitions that we've done, our average rate is down about 50 basis points.</p>
          <p>We do have a few certain items in the quarter. They don't amount to a whole lot. There is one that makes up the vast majority of the total. It's about $15 million, and it again is related to this accounting change on Kinder Morgan Canada. There are the tax adjustments that is also non-cash. This part is one-time. This will not recur &#x2013; of about $15 million. And so again, it is non-cash. It is non-recurring. We have it down here in certain items.</p>
          <p>And in the other items are similar items that we have in a number of quarters, the allocated non-cash long-term compensation. To remind you, this is compensation expense that we have to recognize for accounting purposes, but it is something that KMP will never have to pay for. KMP will not have to pay cash, KMP will not have to pay equity, KMP will never pay anything for this expense. But for accounting purposes, we have to recognize it. We pull it out here as a certain item.</p>
          <p>The mark-to-market of certain upstream hedges, this really goes back to what we discussed in the second quarter of last year. And we have some amounts that moved in and out here as a function of marking those hedges to market. The ultimate value of the hedges ends up in the segment as those transactions occur.</p>
          <p>So the total for certain items &#x2013; about $18 million for the quarter. Again, when we look at the distributable cash flow and the DCF per unit, we are backing those items out.</p>
          <p>There really is not anything else to focus on, on the first page &#x2013; on the GAAP income statement. I will point out that accounting has now changed; minority interest to be called non-controlling interest and it has reorganized a little bit where it shows up. But it doesn't have any change in our bottom line &#x2013; what you call bottom line.</p>
          <p>Net income now is before minority interest or before non-controlling interest. But you'll see the net income attributable to KMP, that is what was previously labeled net income. But again all it is, is  change in labels. It doesn't affect any numbers.</p>
          <p>With that and you'll have the volumes page there, and Rich covered a number of those. And then behind that, you have the balance sheet. And I'll go over that briefly.</p>
          <p>Cash is basically unchanged. Other current assets is down about $300 million and that's all accounts receivable. PP&amp;E is up about $100 million, a little over, that's capital expenditures offset by depreciation in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Investments is up almost $150 million. That's contribution to our joint venture pipelines. And then, of course, you have earnings from those pipelines offset by distributions from those pipelines. But the primary reason why it's up are contributions to those joint ventures.</p>
          <p>Deferred charges and other assets of almost $275 million. That's our hedge portfolio flowing through the balance sheet. Total assets &#x2013; $17.6 billion.</p>
          <p>On the liabilities' side, notes payable and current maturities. I'll talk about that when I talk about total debt in just a minute. Other current liability is down almost $440 million, A/P is a huge piece of that. And then we have some other accruals that normally are reversed in the first quarter &#x2013; that's accrued interest, some deferred revenue which isn't necessarily a recurring item, and then some accrued bonus which gets paid out in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Long-term debt, I'll talk about that in a minute. The value of the interest rate swaps changes a little bit with the function of the forward interest rate curve. Other is basically unchanged. Accumulated other comprehensive loss moves as a function again of our hedged portfolio. Other partners' capital is up because we did issue some equity during the quarter. So that's really the liabilities and partners' capital.</p>
          <p>If you look at total debt, it's a hair under $8.7 billion. It's up from about $8.5 billion at the beginning of the year. That's an increase of $176 million. I'll talk about what caused that increase in just a minute.</p>
          <p>First, we'll look at the debt-to-EBITDA. You will see it now rounds to about 3.5 times. If you take it out another decimal point, it's 3.48 times. At the beginning of the year, it was 3.42 times. And so, barely has changed consistent with our expectations for this year.</p>
          <p>On the change in debt. Our debt increased $176 million. We had expansion capital in the quarter of $316 million, and then contributions to our joint ventures of $174 million. Those are the primary uses of cash.</p>
          <p>We raised equity in the quarter of almost $290 million; so, right at $290 million. We also got $98 million back in an arrangement that we have with a customer on the Texas Intrastate. So that was a source of cash of $98 million.</p>
          <p>We unwound a swap in January. And we really talked about this at the last earnings call, and at the January conference, because it occurred before then. But that is a source of cash of $144 million.</p>
          <p>We had a change in CapEx timing. It's really related to accruals. That was a use of cash of about $74 million in the quarter. We had distributions from equity investments that exceeded earnings of $18 million. So that's a source of cash of $18 million.</p>
          <p>And in working capital and other items were a use of cash of about $160 million. And what's driving that is &#x2013; difference between A/R and A/P was about $36 million; accrued interest was a use of cash of about $87 million. You may recall that our large interest payments just happen to fall in the first quarter and the third quarters. And so we have uses of cash for interest in those quarters.</p>
          <p>Accrued liabilities were a use of cash of about $57 million. About $30 million of that was bonus, about $15 million was deferred revenues. And so, essentially, some cash that we had pre-collected at the beginning of the quarter.</p>
          <p>And then accrued taxes were a source of cash of about $16 million. Again those things total to approximately $160 million use of cash for working capital and other items. And again that's fairly typical for the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Now I mentioned that expansion CapEx for the quarter &#x2013; little over $300 million. I can give you a sense as to where that was spent. On the Product Pipelines, I'd say about $27 million; continued ethanol expansions at our Southeast terminals, adding some tanks at Carson and various other smaller projects.</p>
          <p>On the Natural Gas Pipelines segment, we spent a little over $100 million, about 90 of that was in Kinder Morgan Louisiana Pipeline, and then some smaller storage and other pipeline expansion projects.</p>
          <p>On the CO2 side, we spent a little over $110 million. SACROC was a big piece of that, Yates a smaller piece.</p>
          <p>On the Terminals side, we spent about $70 million, ongoing expansions at Vancouver Wharves and at Pasadena and Galena Park were the biggest pieces of that.</p>
          <p>And then, in addition, I talked about the contributions to joint ventures totaled about $174 million, little over $50 million of that went to Rockies Express, little over 110 went to MEP, and a little under $10 million went to FEP.</p>
          <p>And that is my summary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And with that, we'll take any questions that you might have. Ed, you want to come back on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. First question comes from Darren Horowitz [Raymond James]. Your line is open. State your company name, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, guys. Raymond James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Darren, how are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Pretty good, Rich. First question for you is on the CO2 side, specifically SACROC. Can you give us a little bit more insight as to volumetrically why the increase? And more importantly as you look out over the course of this year, how do you think that that volume pace is going to be sustainable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I've got Tim Bradley right here. And I'll have him answer that, Head of our CO2 segment. Tim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rich. We are seeing positive response ahead of plan in two areas of the field. And our early analysis of that suggests that it's driven by two fundamental features. One, our injection rates are running a little bit higher than planned in those areas. But secondly, taking that into consideration it looks as though these two areas might be resulting in a higher recovery efficiency, meaning more oil is going to come out of the ground than we had originally expected.</p>
          <p>It's too early to declare victory and to present a new number on our expectations there. But it's certainly well above plan and it has not yet started to decline. That would be a more definitive signal as to what the ultimate would be from these two areas. But we're seeing some very encouraging results from the southwest center line and the south platform area of the fields. And we hope that that continues, and we are betting that to some extent it will for the remainder of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim, do you see anything from an injection rate or recovery efficiency standpoint at Yates, or even when you look at the reservoir dynamics, that think you might be able to get the same result as we progress throughout this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Probably not at Yates. It's too early to say, but we are looking at the west side of the Yates field where we have spent no time and no investment pursuing. There is still a large remaining oil target there and we're developing projects that might exploit that. That would be a different activity, not in improvement in recovery from the existing operations which I think the short answer would be that that would remain unchanged. But there are additional opportunities out there that we're starting to evaluate and we may be able to bring some projects forward later this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Have there been any changes to the drilling plan versus what you guys detailed at the Analyst Day?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to SACROC, I think I introduced the fact that we might shift the planned budgeted pattern development program there are little bit to the east. We are prosecuting that. We will drill fewer wells this year. We will add fewer patterns this year. But these are more lucrative patterns. These are patterns with more oil in place, more targets to go after. So we expect that with less capital, the same oil. And in fact, this is a more resilient business plan at today's oil prices than we had planned on late last year at a budget price of $68 a barrel. Other than that, there is no change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I appreciate it. And then, just one quick one for you, Rich. On the REX-West expansion by about 200 MMcfe a day, can you give us a little bit of insight as to qualitatively what that entails, and any sort of quantitative reference would be helpful too?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Steve Kean is right here. Steve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It's a compression expansion on REX-West. It is fully subscribed with an existing shipper on the REX project. We're in the certificate process. What I can you tell quantitatively it's a good return for that incremental capital investment. So it's something we're very satisfied with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks, guys. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Noah Lerner [Hartz Capital]. Your line is open. State your company please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hartz Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. How are you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, good. Thanks, guys. I was just wondering, Rich, if you and Park, if anybody else can comment on &#x2013; what you think the impact might be in the likelihood of passage of some of those provisions of Mr. Obama's budget plan where they are talking about possibly getting rid of the deduction for tertiary recovery, and IDCs &#x2013; all of those things? What kind of impact do you think it might do to the company if they're passed and also to the industry as a whole?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think on those particular things, very little impact to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the tertiary oil recovery, you have to be at certain prices, lower prices in order to get that deduction. And it phases out as soon as I think you start going into the 50s. The number two thing about all these deductions is these aren't deductions &#x2013; we don't pay corporate income tax at KMP. And so these are deductions that then get passed on to our unitholders. So they are not going to &#x2013; any change in these won't impact KMP, it could impact slightly the coverage or the deferral of the income for some unitholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it won't impact our cash flow but it could impact tax consequences for our unitholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you have the tax return on the unitholders instead?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, although again I would emphasize we expect them to have very little impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think the bigger deduction that most unitholders get is the depreciation deduction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Which these don't have any impact on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Brian Zarahn [Barclays Capital]. Your line is open. State your company please, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Brian, how are you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, Rich, how are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Looking at your Products Pipelines segment, can you comment on how Pacific did in the quarter and how they expected to do this year &#x2013; in line with plan or ..?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, actually that's &#x2013; as Park said, that while the volumes were down on Pacific through a combination of cost cuts, tighter operation, we've actually been able to keep it on plan. And we expect to be on plan for the year on Pacific. In fact, again notwithstanding in that I think is should get a bit of creditability from this statement, not withstanding the fact that we are experiencing overall what I consider to be a pretty significant decline in volumes, about 5%. Now if you want to get technical and take out the leap year, it's a little less than that. If you want to exclude Plantation, which you probably should, it's a little more than that. But anyway, just picking the 5% is probably as a good number as any.</p>
          <p>Notwithstanding the fact that we were down that much in refined products volumes, actually all of our Products Pipelines except for Cochin, we expect to be on plan. They are on plan for the quarter, and we expect they'll be on plan for the year.</p>
          <p>And Cochin, again which is propane, there just was not propane available at least at good decent prices that could be shipped out of the port up in Canada down to the upper Midwest. So it was really not a &#x2013; ironically we had a pretty cold winter where our terminals are located in Iowa and in other parts of the Midwest. But we just &#x2013; there just wasn't enough supply to accommodate all the demand.</p>
          <p>So that's really ironically the shortfall and that's the way we expect the year to go. We expect to be on plan for the Pacific.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. In the press release you mentioned that you're continuing to pursue acquisitions and you hinted at Terminals in the call earlier. Can you comment a little more on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think we will have some acquisitions &#x2013; we've discussed those with the Board. And we would anticipate that we will have one or more announcements before the end of the second quarter on acquisitions.</p>
          <p>Again nothing is &#x2013; or it is not in the crowd till you get it there. But we do think that and particularly in our Terminals area that we will have some opportunity to make acquisitions. And we think in our Products Pipeline area, we will have some opportunities to make some relatively smaller acquisitions there.</p>
          <p>So we feel pretty encouraged that we will spend at least as much as we have in the budget &#x2013; in the original budget &#x2013; and possibly a little more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay but in the market, are you seeing bid/ask spreads narrowing &#x2013; M&amp;A?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it depends on what type of asset you're looking at. I think we have seen some expectations of sellers or potential sellers come to ground. Others are still pretty proud of their assets. So I think it's kind of a mixed bag.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question will come from Xin Liu [JPMorgan]. Your line is open, ma'am. State your company please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, how are you today?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. How are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So on CO2 you mentioned you expect some cost saving there. Can you quantify it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we expect for the full year cost savings of $35 million or a little better. And that's based on what we've currently been able to do with our vendors, and include some power cost savings too. And I would hope that as the year goes on, we may be able to add to that, although I think that we've probably got the bulk of what we're going to see for the year.</p>
          <p>But again, as Park said, very little of that actually hit in the first quarter. The deals have been negotiated. In other words, you have lower rig rates or lower payment for whatever kind of services. But most of those were negotiated in February and March. So it didn't have much impact on the CO2 segment's results in the first quarter, but will throughout the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>And we'll continue to look for additional opportunities. But that's the quantification, and that's on the O&amp;M side. And as Tim said earlier, we've also had some reductions in our expansion CapEx in CO2 also.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And on REX, you were able to revise the firm ending drop down rates on the Western leg because of cost inflation. Is that in the budget, and how much benefit do you expect to get from the new rates?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Still, we don't have anything in the budget assuming the higher rates or in our forecast really, assuming the higher rates now. In the longer term, the project is really fully subscribed, or just nearly fully subscribed.</p>
          <p>The impact is going to be more on really in two ways. One is, when those contracts expire. Secondly is, potentially on expansions. And then third, to the extent we're able to squeeze out bits and pieces of capacity here and there which we've been able to do some up to-date, and to the extent the market spreads support it, we would be able to pick up some additional revenue that way. So it's definitely worth doing, definitely worth getting the higher rates in place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to make sure that that's clear. On the capacity that is subscribed, we have contracted rates that don't change for the term of that contract. Now we have filed for higher rates as an assumption of the higher costs. And so our recourse rate &#x2013; the maximum rate that we can charge to other shippers is higher. But for the existing shippers who have contracted for long-term capacity, those tariffs don't change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Ed, do you have any more questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from John Edwards [Morgan Keegan]. Your line is open. State your company, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Morgan Keegan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, John. How are you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, pretty well. Just on the remaining spending then this year on REX, Kinder Morgan Louisiana and MEP, what do you have left for '09 on each of those?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Park?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I am not sure that I necessarily have the remaining '09 spend. Okay, I guess I do. And so for &#x2013; and these are '08 numbers. It is around 1.5 billion on Rockies Express. And it's a little bit less than $800 million on MEP, is what remains to be spent on those two pipelines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then on Kinder Morgan Louisiana?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have Louisiana in front of me. I don't know ...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>200 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Less.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Or less, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Couple of hundred million dollars or less.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just following up on the volumes on SACROC. You've had this big bump up and you've answered a little bit on the sustainability. What's &#x2013; in terms of the risks to that sustainability &#x2013; do you see it being risks to the upside, or do you see it as, you know, risks to the downside?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, and then I'll let Tim answer that. First of all, I want to be clear that as we said, our overall volumes for the first quarter were 30,000 barrels a day. We've been doing better than that &#x2013; that the trend has been up. But we haven't baked in any big upward trend in this. We're waiting to see how it develops. Tim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that that's the short answer. Specifically, in March, we've averaged over 31,000 barrels a day, well above plan. April month-to-date, we're right at 31,000 barrels a day. Our annual plan number was in 28,500 or so barrels a day. We're forecasting for the rest of the year, based on what we're seeing today, approximately 30,000 barrels a day or a little bit below where we were last month and where we are month-to-date.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So it's too early to tell what the &#x2013; whether it will trend --?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey John, the number on Louisiana line is 170.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>170. Okay, great. Okay. That's all I had. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Yves Siegel. Your line is open. State your company, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Arroyo Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Yves . How are you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you. Quick question, just off of something you said before, Rich. I think you said that in the Terminal business, steel was down, and was a leading indicator you felt. Can you give any sort of insight in terms of what your crystal ball would suggest going forward as it relates to leading indicators? And as you think about the volumes on the Products Pipeline, do you think we're seeing some deceleration in the declines in volumes there? Any sort of insight that you might have on the economy if you will, going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I'm afraid I don't have much. I would say that, so far, we have not seen a turn in the steel. Now again, both Park and I, I think alluded to this. If there is a silver lining there, it's with the steel, any bulk terminal you're able to &#x2013; you have a lot of variable costs, and you're able to cut your variable costs pretty fast in response to a downturn in volume. But we have not seen a turnaround in steel yet. One would think that as they exhaust inventories, you will see some turnaround, but I don't know when that will be.</p>
          <p>On the Products Pipeline, it varies. We're still seeing weakness on volumes in Las Vegas and Arizona, although in the month of April, we've had a little bit of an uptick in Arizona. But nothing, I don't think, to get too excited about. Surprisingly, gasoline volumes in Florida have held up pretty well for us, if you add back in the switch to ethanol and everything. But jet fuel volumes are down across the board as the numbers indicate by &#x2013; oh, between 9 to 10% across the board and at all the airports.</p>
          <p>So I think it's too early to say that it's turned around. Now again, I think the good news is we've been able to offset a lot of it and we are prepared to live with it as it is. And you got to believe that in the end, at some point in time, particularly with reasonable gasoline prices that people are going to be driving more of it. But so far we have not seen a turnaround. It's not getting any worse, but we have not seen a turnaround.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then finally, as it relates to Intrastate Natural Gas, do you sense that the decline in the rig count is going to impact the business there in any way?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, certainly any time you have a decline in the rig count, at some point in time you're going to have less gas. But again I think you have to look at that on a regional basis. And what we're finding right now, Yves , is that there is a tremendous build-up of production in the Barnett in Texas and that's really looking for a home. In fact, all of East Texas looks pretty good from the standpoint of volume still coming online and wanting to move. I think South Texas, we're seeing somewhat of a decline in production.</p>
          <p>But it's sort of regionalized and there is a lot of gas moving around Texas and wanting to get certainly to the Houston Ship Channel in Beaumont where we have the best connectivity. And then wanting to get into the interstates and get out of Texas and move further north or further east. And again our pipelines are pretty well positioned for all of that too.</p>
          <p>We have a lot of interconnections between out intrastate lines and NGPL, for example, and other interstates. And obviously, MEP, I think we neglected to say at least orally that we actually ramped up the first segment of NGPL, which &#x2013; excuse me, of MEP, Midcontinent Express, which connected the NGPL and we immediately had movement on that. I guess we connected last Saturday, is that right or --?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Actually a little earlier, it's Thursday or Friday.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thursday or Friday of last week. So that's &#x2013; to a little place called Atlanta, not Georgia, but Texas. And so we actually started that and immediately had some demand on it just from people wanting to move their gas, in this case into NGPL and get it further away from the producing areas.</p>
          <p>So we're still seeing that. And the Fayetteville is still very strong in production. And the Haynesville, to the extent that they can get out, there is pretty good production there too. So in those producing areas we're still seeing strong production. We are seeing some downturns in South Texas, and we're seeing downturns in Western Colorado as the rig count has declined there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time, I show no further question, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, thank you all very much for listening in. And if you have any further questions, give Kim Dang or David Kinder a call. And they'll be able to answer it much more thoroughly than we have.</p>
          <p>Thank you, and have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time, that will conclude today's conference. You may disconnect. Thank you for your --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>