<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1170617" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-16</date>
    <companies>
      <company>842</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Richard D. Kinder, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">C. Park Shaper, President</participant>
      <participant id="3">Ross Payne</participant>
      <participant id="4">Richard Kinder</participant>
      <participant id="5">Park Shaper</participant>
      <participant id="6">Steven Kean</participant>
      <participant id="7">Darren Horowitz</participant>
      <participant id="8">John Edwards</participant>
      <participant id="9">Dan Jenkins</participant>
      <participant id="10">Sharon Lui</participant>
      <participant id="11">Barrett Blaschke</participant>
      <participant id="12">Becca Followill</participant>
      <participant id="13">Yves Siegel</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Excuse me, this is the conference coordinator. I would like to thank you all for holding for the quarterly earnings conference call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> I'd like to turn the call to Rich Kinder. Sir you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Ed, and welcome to the Kinder Morgan Quarterly Investor Call. As usual, we'll be making statements that may fall under the Securities Act of 1933 and the Securities Exchange Act of 1934. Also, as usual, I'll give of an overview of the quarter, and some of our strategic projects, and then our President, Park Shaper, will give you all the financial details, and then we'll we take any questions that you may have.</p>
          <p>Let me start with a slightly different approach than we normally do. We had a tremendous second quarter, as you know, if you've read the release. We had distributable cash flow per unit of $1.14, we raised the distribution to $0.99, which is up about 16% ahead of where we were in the second quarter a year ago, but it think it might be well to start out in this kind of stressful economic times, it might be helpful to just start to reiterate and talk through the Kinder Morgan strategy again.</p>
          <p>As most of you know, we are investors in the midstream energy business, and we have a very long-term investing horizon. I think the right way to think of us is really as a toll road, where most of our customers agree to pay fixed tolls for a long period of time at the time we build the toll road. And that's true of our natural gas pipelines, our CO2 pipelines, and most of our terminals. Now in our Products Pipelines, the amount of use of the toll road can vary, but in that scenario, we do have inflation escalators, and the ability to true up our tolls if the volumes decline or increase precipitously.</p>
          <p>So, while I would analogize us to a toll road, we do have some exposure to commodity prices, some of that exposure is positive, and some of it is negative. Most of the positive exposure is over in our CO2 segment, where, if you have higher WTI prices, this results in higher prices under a lot of our CO2 contracts with third parties. In other words, under those contracts, we have a floor price, and then we have some of sharing upside with our customers, if WTI prices go higher. We also get a benefit in our CO2 segment on the price we get for our NGLs, because they are not hedged. And then on the relatively small amount of our crude production that's not hedged, we get a slight benefit from higher WTI prices, but that's relatively minimal.</p>
          <p>If you look at the negative side of the equation, the segment that's hit the most is our Products Pipeline group and there, when you have higher product prices that result in less demand and therefore, less throughput through our Products Pipeline, the volume decreases. We also have a negative impact in the fact that we use vast quantities of diesel fuel. In our Terminals group alone, we use about a 1 million gallons a month of diesel to the fuel our heavy equipment. And so, that is a negative impact from higher prices. And then, of course, we power our pipelines with natural gas and electricity to the extent that those prices increase, that's a negative.</p>
          <p>I think if you look at the whole enterprise, in general, the positives outweigh the negatives, although it's hard to quantify, but I think we generally benefit somewhat from higher oil and gas prices. But, as we will talk to in a little bit, while we're well above plan, very nicely above plan for the quarter and year-to-date expecting to end the year that way, we'd be above plan even if the prices were the same as we had in our original budget numbers that we came up with prior to the January conference.</p>
          <p>Now, beyond this kind of quantitative assessment I've given, higher prices also benefit us by increasing the, I guess you could say, the desire of our producers to get their production to market as quickly as possible, particularly if they have aggressive drilling programs. And I think this is particularly true in the natural gas field, where we're seeing and feeling a lot of producer push to build new pipelines, and to take large amounts of capacity on those new pipelines at fixed rates for an extended period of time.</p>
          <p>So that's sort of the impact of commodity prices on what's essentially a commodity-neutral organization like ours. And if you then look at what our business segments are really all about, we have a lot of critical mass. We own the largest independent products pipeline system in America. We are the largest owner-operator of bulk and liquids terminals. We are the largest transporter and marketer of CO2, and we're certainly one of the largest natural gas systems in the country. If you look at these, this group of assets, which we think are pretty world-class, it gives us a tremendous amount of diversity, which I think allows us to do just what we did this quarter, which is to prosper even under widely varying economic scenarios.</p>
          <p>Now let me talk about the second quarter. As I said, we upped the quarterly cash distribution to 99 cents, that's 3.96 on an annualized basis, up from $0.96 in the prior quarter, and a year ago, we were distributing $0.85 or 3.40 annualized. So, that's a 16% &#x2013; actually a little over 16% increase, since the comparable quarter of 2007, very consistent with what our plan is for the year. As you know, we anticipate a 16% increase in distributions in our plan versus full year '07. We've now indicated we expect to exceed that plan.</p>
          <p>KMP had quarterly distributable cash flow before certain items &#x2013; and the certain items were basically meaningless in the quarter &#x2013; of about $294 million. That's 43% above the second quarter a year ago, and then distributable cash flow per unit, which we believe is the best way of measuring our performance, was $1.14 this quarter. That's up 31% from the $0.87 per unit that we had for the comparable period last year.</p>
          <p>If you look at the first six months, our distributable cash flow was $574 million, that's 46% above the same six month period last year. And I think another thing to note, and Park will take you through all this in more detail, is that the excess of distributable cash flow above the declared distributions for the first two quarters of 2008 is approximately $79 million, so we had a lot of excess cash above our distributions.</p>
          <p>Now if you look at on a segment-by-segment basis, we had really outstanding performance I think from all of our business segments with the exception of Products Pipeline. And we had good performance there, almost up to plan, but certainly, we have been impacted by lower throughput on our products pipeline as a result of high prices, particularly for gasoline.</p>
          <p>I think the quarter was particularly strong as we said in our release, when you consider this lower gasoline demand, a pretty sluggish economy and pretty wholesome increases in construction and fuel costs that do impact our operations.</p>
          <p>So, looking first at our Products Pipeline segment &#x2013; we and of course, we judge this as earnings before DD&amp;A is the way we report &#x2013; earnings before DD&amp;A was about $137 million, that's down 8% from the same period a year ago. If you exclude the North System, which was in the numbers in the second quarter of 2007, but we sold it in the fourth quarter of '07, then the earnings before DD&amp;A were down only about 3%. Through the first two quarters, Products is down 5% from the plan and we expect it to fall modestly short of its annual budget growth target of 5%.</p>
          <p>The segment's refined products revenues were still above last year, but the volumes have clearly been impacted by reductions in demand, driven by high crude and product prices. We've often been asked, when does the elasticity begin, and I think we found it at $4 gasoline. To put that in perspective, total refined products revenues for the quarter were up about 2%, but the volumes were down about 8% compared to a year ago. Now, that's greater than the EIA numbers for example. However, you have to remember that EIA includes ethanol in its numbers. We don't obviously &#x2013; we do not include ethanol in our numbers, because we're not shipping ethanol across the pipelines, even though we do benefit from ethanol, particularly in a lot of our terminal operations both in Florida, the Southeast, and also, in California.</p>
          <p>The NGL volumes were actually up about 4.6% for the quarter and for the first six months of 2008, the Products revenues were up 2.7%, volumes were down about 6.8%, or about 5% if you exclude Plantation. So, that's the story on the Products Pipeline.</p>
          <p>If you look at our Natural Gas Pipeline business, we had earnings before DD&amp;A in the second quarter of about 183 million. That's 26% above the second quarter of 2007, and we now expect to exceed our published annual budget growth of 18% year-over-year for the full year. These results were led by contributions from REX, the Rockies Express Pipeline, which the West segment is now complete, and that accounted for about 75% of the growth in the segment. But we also had strong performances, as we have over the past several quarters, in our Texas Intrastate Group and also, in our TransColorado pipelines.</p>
          <p>Our Intrastate's growth was attributable to really good, increasing transportation revenue from a lot of long term contracts. We were able to secure higher sales margins and we realized greater processing volumes and margins. To put it in perspective, our Texas Intrastate group generated almost half of the segment's earnings before DD&amp;A, and was 40% above its budget for the quarter. Transport volumes were up 27% in the second quarter of 2007. That's not really surprising because most of that is attributable to startup of REX-West and the sales volumes were up 8%, and virtually all of that &#x2013; or all of it really is in the Texas Intrastate.</p>
          <p>Our third segment is our CO2 business, and there we had second quarter earnings before DD&amp;A of &#x2013; just shy of $217 million. That's up 68% from the same period last year, and we are on track to substantially exceed our annual budget target, which was to grow earnings before DD&amp;A by 40%. I think CO2 had an outstanding quarter in virtually every respect. We had stronger than expected oil production at Yates. We had increased CO2 sales and transport volumes, as some of our facilities in Southwest Colorado are now beginning to come online. As you know, we have a major expansion there. We had higher hedge prices. We had higher oil and CO2 prices in general.</p>
          <p>For the quarter, average oil production at Yates was 28,100 barrels per day. That's up 4% compared to the second quarter of '07 and above our budget. At SACROC, the average oil production for the quarter was 27,500 per day, and that's down about 2% from the same period a year ago, but on budget for the quarter. Our CO2 delivery volumes were up 14%, compared to the same quarter a year ago due to those expansion projects that I talked about.</p>
          <p>Turning to our Terminals segment, we have reported second quarter segment earnings before DD&amp;A of a little over $140 million. That's up 28% from the second quarter a year ago and just right on our budget for the second quarter, growing at about 24% growth, which is what we have projected for the full year. We think our Terminals group will come in at or slightly below budget for the full year.</p>
          <p>And of all of this growth, this roughly $30 million in growth in the second quarter, slightly more than half of the growth came from organic opportunities, and the remainder was attributable to acquisitions, primarily the Marine Terminals acquisition, which we made in September of '07. and from the Vancouver Wharves operation, which we picked up in May of 2007.</p>
          <p>Some other statistics I think are kind of interesting in the Terminals Group: our segment liquids leasable capacity is now up to about 52.5 million barrels, up from about 43.5 million barrels a year ago. And that's due to all of these numerous expansion projects that we have been doing on the liquid side, again, doing them only after we have fairly long-term contracts with users of those facilities. As you would expect, liquids throughput increased about 15%, compared to a year ago, growing to a record for us, almost 161 million barrels that we handled. And we set all-time records at our big complex here on the Houston Ship Channel.</p>
          <p>Overall on the Bulk side, the highlight was really that our coal handling increased by 22% in the second quarter, we handled about &#x2013; a little short of 9 million tons in the quarter. And there, we benefited from record coal throughput of 1.1 million tons in June alone at our Pier IX Terminal in Newport News, Virginia.</p>
          <p>Our fifth, and by far the smallest business segment is our Trans Mountain Pipeline up in Canada. And that produced second quarter segment earnings of 33.4 million. That's up by over 60% from a year-ago. But, it's not really apples-to-apples, because we had a full three months of earnings for the second quarter of '08. Last year, we had only two months of earnings from Trans Mountain. The results, compared to plan, were below plan due to lower revenues, caused primarily by a delay in the approval of increased tariffs for 2008. Those tariffs are now in effect. They went into effect on June 1st and we now expect that this segment to meet or slightly exceed its budget for the full year.</p>
          <p>Now if you look at the full year on a company-wide basis, as you know, we &#x2013; our target for the year on the budget &#x2013; under the budget we published and discussed with you in January, was to declare cash distributions for the full year of $4.02. We now expect to exceed that target for the year.</p>
          <p>Now let me talk about some of the strategic developments that occurred during the second quarter. I think one of the great challenges we and other pipeline builders and operators face today is obviously, rising construction and material costs, and these continue to create a challenging business environment for our whole industry. We're really focused on managing those increases, trying to identify ways to offset them where we can and bring in our projects as close to being on time and on budget as possible. And so, we, each quarter true those up with the prior quarters and go back to our analysts' conference in January, where we discussed all these projects in a lot of detail. So, let me do just that.</p>
          <p>Right now, our total forecast to CapEx on our major projects have increased by a little less than 10% from the projection we made at our January investment conference. Most of the increase during the last quarter has been on our Natural Gas Pipeline major project. There, we have faced market conditions &#x2013; have driven higher prices for consumables, for labor and construction equipment, and then &#x2013; specific to our REX project, we did have certain provisions in the final EIS, the environmental impact statement, that have resulted in substantial increased costs on that project.</p>
          <p>While we'd rather obviously not see these increases, we remain confident that REX, and all of our other projects, will still deliver attractive returns to our investors. And I think it's important to remember that when we evaluate these projects, in order to make capital investment decisions, we conservatively estimate the cash flows, which leads us to opportunities to outperform rather than just wrestle with that kind of wordy gobbledygook, let me give you an example.</p>
          <p>On REX, what we built into our EBITDA structure was that we would get the demand payments which are fully contracted for a period of 10 years on the REX project. But as we have put REX in service, we're already providing ancillary services to our shippers, which generates revenues for us in excess of the contractual revenues on which we based our expected return.</p>
          <p>Another example is that on our CO2 improvements in Southwest Colorado and on the pipeline running from Colorado over to the Permian Basin in Texas, while our costs have increased, we're realizing much higher prices on our CO2 under these contracts I discussed earlier. So actually, our return there is substantially higher in terms of the return on invested capital than what we originally projected.</p>
          <p>Now, our Board has approved about $8 billion in capital projects at KMP. And projects representing about $3 billion out of that $8 billion have been completed, and are in service, and most of those came in pretty close to the budget for capital expenditures that we set for. The remainder of the projects are in various stages of construction, and I would like to spend just a couple of minutes reviewing with you progress on some of the most important of those projects.</p>
          <p>I'll start again with Rockies Express, we call REX. What we call REX-West, which is the part of the system that runs from the Cheyenne Hub in Weld County, Colorado over into Audrain County, Missouri is now completely finished. We went into service to Eastern Kansas on January 12, and then completed the last spread over to Audrain County, Missouri and put that in service in May of this year. The capacity of the pipeline is now 1.5 billion cubic feet per day, and it is operating at or near full capacity.</p>
          <p>The next phase of the REX project is from Audrain County, Missouri on over to Clarington, Ohio, which is essentially on the Ohio-Pennsylvania border. We now have started construction on that. That's about 640 miles of pipeline. We expect to be in service to Lebanon, Ohio, by year-end, with full operations to Clarington, in the third quarter of 2009. When the whole thing is completed, it's a roughly 1700-mile pipeline with a capacity of about 1.8 billion cubic feet per day. I remind you that we have binding firm commitments from credit-worthy shippers for all of that capacity. And we are overseeing construction of project, we own 50%, Sempra and Conoco own the rest. Our current estimate of total construction costs on REX, which includes the bids we now have on the construction of this last segment, is about $5.6 billion in total.</p>
          <p>Our second major project, which is a great success story, I think, is our Midcontinent Express. That's the project that runs from Southeast Oklahoma across Northeast Texas, Northern Louisiana, Central Mississippi and interconnects with the Transco Pipeline near Butler, Alabama. Initial design capacity was 1.5 Bcf a day. That's now been fully subscribed with long-term binding commitments. We've just completed a successful open season and we now expect to increase the main segment to 1.8 Bcf per day. This project is a 50/50 joint venture of KMP and Energy Transfer, and we expect to start construction on that pending regulatory approvals within the next month or so.</p>
          <p>Construction continues on our approximately 595 million Kinder Morgan Louisiana Pipeline. Now, that's a 133-mile, 42-inch diameter line that moves natural gas across multiple pipeline interconnects from the Cheniere Sabine Pass LNG facility. All of the approximately 3.2 Bcf per day of capacity on that line has been subscribed by Chevron and Total, and we expect to have that operational sometime in the first quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Now, over in the CO2 segment, a major project that we have going is drilling new wells and adding compression in our McElmo Dome area located near Cortez, Colorado. We began commercial production from those facilities in June, and we're now producing over 100 million cubic feet per day of CO2. Our share of this project is about $140 million. That includes our share of the Cortez pipeline also. And the project will continue to ramp up as these wells are added, and we expect it to be producing an additional 200 million cubic feet per day from McElmo Dome, when we complete all the construction in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Now, we have a number of other projects either underway or just completed and the details on that are in three or four pages of our earnings release. But, what I've given you is an outline of the major projects. And I might add, we're in active discussions on other major opportunities with our customers. So, we see this as a very fertile opportunity for an extended period of time to continue to grow our pipeline of terminal network around North America.</p>
          <p>So, I think if you look at it from a strategic perspective, we've had a great first six months of 2008. We're on track to exceed our budget for all of 2008, which was a growth in distributions of 16%. We continue to make good progress on our expansion projects, which are certainly a big part of the foundation for our future success, and growth in distributable cash flow per unit.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll turn it over to Park.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks Rich. And I'll go through the numbers, as I usually do. Hopefully, everyone has the press release. I'll start on the first numbered page following the press release, but just spend a brief time there.</p>
          <p>You'll see at the bottom of the page the declared distribution, $0.99, is what the Board declared today. That's up 16.5% from the $0.85 that was declared for the second quarter of 2007. And that that means we will distribute $1.95 for the first half of the year, also up 16% from where we were in the first half of what we distributed for the first half of 2007.</p>
          <p>Now with that, I'll turn to the second page, and that's where you can really see the sources of the growth. Let me start in about the middle of the page, right above weighted average units outstanding, you'll see DCF per unit before certain items, Rich mentioned this, $1.14, up 31% from the $0.87 a year ago. It's tremendous growth in DCF per unit and for the six months, 2.26, up 34% from the $1.69 of a year ago. And not only has the DCF per unit grown &#x2013; or really, the truth is &#x2013; not only have we grown our distributions at 16%, but our actual cash flow has grown more rapidly, again, as you see from the DCF per unit, so that our coverage has expanded.</p>
          <p>Our coverage, as Rich mentioned, is $79 million through the first half of the year. Now, our budget grew the first half of the year with essentially no coverage. You'll remember our budget for the total year was about 10 to $12 million of excess coverage. We talked in January about the fact that historically, we had budgeted coverage to be fairly tight and typically, we have outperformed that. We certainly believe that we will have excess coverage in 2008 that is well beyond our budget of 10 to $12 million. And again as I said, we're already at $79 million so far. We do expect our distribution will exceed our budget, but we also expect that we will cover our distribution in each of the next two quarters, so that our excess coverage is likely to grow as we continue throughout the year.</p>
          <p>Moving up from there, you can see the actual cash DCF before certain items, $294 million, up about 44%, $574 million for the six months, up 46%. The components of that, immediately above that, sustaining CapEx is up about $10.5 million from where it was a year ago. It's up almost $14 million for the six months. Now it is on track, or we still expect to have sustaining CapEx of around 196, $197 million for the year, consistent with our budget.</p>
          <p>Above that, you will see that we actually had a hurt from book/cash tax difference during the quarter. We did actually expect in our budget that we would have a little bit of a help. And so, actually I'm sorry, in the quarter we expected that there would be a little bit of a hurt. For the year, we expected that we would have a little bit of a help from that. We now do not expect that to be the case. We expect that actually the book/cash tax difference will be a slight negative for us for the year.</p>
          <p>But clearly, we are overcoming that and it's largely driven by what we talked about in the first quarter, which are additional taxes related to premiums on our Westridge dock facility that's part of the Trans Mountain System, and those cash taxes we expect to get back in future years.</p>
          <p>You'll see depreciation is up largely driven by increased depreciation at CO2, and then also, increased depreciation at the terminals where we've put on additional facilities, and having a full quarter and six months of Trans Mountain. You'll recall that a year ago, Trans Mountain was only in the second quarter for two months, because that transaction closed at the end of April, and so for the six-month period, we had an incremental four months and for the quarter, we have an incremental one month for this year. And above that, you get to the net income numbers although again, we believe that the DCF numbers are much more meaningful.</p>
          <p>And so with that, I'll jump to the top and talk about the segments. Rich has already covered a lot of this. You'll see Products is actually down for the quarter, it's down for the year-to-date. Now, to have a true apples-to-apples comparison, you need to adjust Products for the North System, which was sold at the end of the third quarter beginning in the fourth quarter, 2007. Now, if you did that &#x2013; it would still we down a little bit compared to last year for the quarter, it would be above where it was last year for the six-month. Rich talked about the impact of the product volumes, basically, the decline in volumes, driven by higher fuel prices and by weak economic conditions.</p>
          <p>Now as he mentioned, that of course, is offset, in part by our ethanol revenues. We do blend a lot of ethanol at our terminal facilities, and we earn revenues because of that. And then also, we do have inflation adjustments on our tariffs on a lot of our refined product lines. And so, in truth, our refined products revenues are above where they were a year ago, even though our volumes are down driven by those two factors. But bottom line, product is under our budget, we expect it will be under our budget for the year.</p>
          <p>Natural Gas Pipeline's way above last year, it's up about 26% for the quarter, it's up about 32% compared to 2007 year-to-date, driven by Rockies Express. Clearly, the addition of that is having a big impact on the growth year-to-year. And then also, the Intrastate pipelines, which are having a tremendous year once again are both above last year and nicely above their budget for both the quarter and the year-to-date.</p>
          <p>CO2, way above last year, it's up about 68% for the quarter, so about 64% year to-date. As Rich mentioned, for crude volumes, SACROC is slightly below last year, but right on our plan, Yates is above both last year and our plan. Our SMP business &#x2013; the CO2 transportation business &#x2013; volumes are actually above our plan, and way above last year, because of the addition of the new facilities in Southwest Colorado and the Cortez pipeline.</p>
          <p>NGL volumes are slightly below last year, and below our plan, and that's being hurt by the pipeline pro-rationing issue that's discussed in the press release. We hope that that will be resolved in the very near future.</p>
          <p>And then of course, the CO2 segment is getting helped by the price, which largely impacts realized CO2 prices and NGL prices, and has a little bit of an impact on the unhedged crude volumes. Overall, again, we expect CO2 to finish the year well above its budget.</p>
          <p>On the Terminals side, nice growth from last year, it's up about $30 million or almost 28% for the quarter, the same, about 28% year to-date driven by a lot of the expansion capital projects. Now, it is a little bit under its budget, most of that occurred in the first quarter. We discussed it at that time, driven a lot by some projects that came on a little bit later than expected, but are on now, and then of course, by the fuel prices, as Rich mentioned, are a little bit of a headwind for the Terminals segment. We expect Terminals to come in just a little bit under its budget, and hopefully, they can make that back up and hit their budget for the year.</p>
          <p>Trans Mountain once again, we did have a full three months this quarter, only two months in '07. For the year to-date, we have a full six months this year, as opposed to just two months a year ago, and so that drives nice growth. We do hope that Trans Mountain will be on its budget for the year.</p>
          <p>You will see then that total segment earnings before DD&amp;A, up $710 million, up 28% from a year-ago. For the six months, almost 1.4 billion, up 32% from the 1056 a year-ago. You may recall that our annual budget for segment earnings before DD&amp;A is just a hair under $2.8 billion. We now expect that we'll be nicely over $2.8 billion, so we expect good outperformance from our segments this year. And of course, that's growth over $2.2 billion in 2007, so very nice growth coming out of the segments.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll drop-down and talk about G&amp;A. If you go through the DD&amp;A and down through the segment earnings contribution and underneath that, you will see the G&amp;A, up about $10 million, so that's a negative variance, '08 second quarter versus '07 second quarter. Year-to-date, we are off about $23 million or put in other words, G&amp;A is up about $23 million.</p>
          <p>Now, some of that was expected, although our G&amp;A is running a little bit above, both for the budget and year-to-date. The reasons are incremental legal expenses, higher G&amp;A at Trans Mountain, which is driven primarily by increased insurance costs above our budget, and then some cash reserves that show up in G&amp;A.</p>
          <p>Interest below that, you will see up slightly from a year-ago for the quarter, up about $9 million from a year-ago for the six months, but well under our budget, and under our budget largely as a result of lower rate. We do have 50% of floating rate debt, 50% fixed, on our floating rate debt. We are realizing interest rates that are below our budget, and realizing some benefits from that. Minority interest, essentially unchanged. And so that basically what's driving the distributable cash flow before certain items.</p>
          <p>To talk briefly about the certain items, you can see they net to essentially just $1 million for the quarter and up $3 million for the six months. Now, in 2007, there were bigger amounts. A couple of them related to Trans Mountain events prior to the drop down, again, those were 2007 amounts. Some of them relate to non-cash compensation that for accounting purposes, have to show up on KMP's income statement, but KMP has no responsibility for that compensation.</p>
          <p>KMP won't be charged in cash. It doesn't have to issue any equity, has absolutely no obligation related to this compensation, and never will have to pay anything related to the compensation, but that's not sufficient for the accounting folks. They deem that it still has to show up here on the income statement.</p>
          <p>Loss on debt retirement was an '07 item, as were the environmental reserves. A gain on sale, you'll see a positive in the second quarter of 2008, largely related to the sale of our 25% interest in Thunder Creek. A little bit of residual North System gain flows through in both the second quarter of '08 and the first quarter of '08.</p>
          <p>You will see a negative amount, about $13 million mark-to-market of certain upstream hedges, because of the divergence in NGL prices and crude prices that has gone on over the last three to six months. Some of our NGL hedges in our upstream business, which is part of our Natural Gas Pipeline segment, have been deemed to be ineffective from an accounting perspective. What that means is we run this amount here through the income statement, but it is purely a timing item. It has no impact over what we reflect in the segment, because what we always reflect in the segment is the actual physical sale, plus or minus any impact from our hedge. And so that will still show up in the segment when the physical sale happens.</p>
          <p>So, really what you are going to see, you have this $13 million negative here in this quarter. You're going to see $13 million come back &#x2013; we'll pull it out as a certain item down in the certain items over the next three quarters or four quarters, and what you will see in the segment is exactly what you always see, which is the actual cash that we receive from these transactions. Other is de minimis.</p>
          <p>So again, those are the certain items, I think, really in 2008. There have not been really any certain items of any substance. Now, again, that's what gets us to DCF per unit of $1.14, again, nicely covering the distribution of $0.99.</p>
          <p>Flipping back to the first stage, which is the face of the income statement, it does not make a lot of sense to go through this in detail, because we don't believe that this gives you a fair representation of what's going on at KMP. And in an effort to highlight that, and then also, maybe to demonstrate that we are trying to be fair in this analysis that we show on the second page, as opposed to just skew things in our favor.</p>
          <p>I want to draw your attention to the G&amp;A line that's on the face of the income statement. You'll see there, for the quarter, it has G&amp;A of about 73 million compared to last year of about 89 million, which indicates that G&amp;A is down by $17 million. Now, you may recall a couple of minutes ago, I told you that G&amp;A is actually up $10 million quarter-over-quarter. And if you look at the second page, that is what we show. And that's what we believe to be true.</p>
          <p>When you strip out these certain items, and the one impact that &#x2013; the one piece that especially has an impact there, is this item that's called allocated non-cash long-term compensation &#x2013; when you strip out those items and look at what we believe KMP is really responsible for, and what will occur going forward, that is what shows up on the second page. And that indicates that G&amp;A has gone up by $10 million, as opposed to, if you just looked at the face of the income statement, you'd say, oh great, G&amp;A is down by $17 million. Again. I just highlight that, because hopefully, it will help convince people that what we're trying to do is make a fair representation on the second page.</p>
          <p>With that, I will go to the balance sheet, which should be the last page of your press release, and run through that quickly. Cash and cash equivalents, up a little bit. We actually have no commercial paper outstanding. At the end of the second quarter, we have a little bit higher cash balance than we would have otherwise. Other current assets is up significantly. Restricted deposits related to hedges are up, AR is up. And those are the two main items increasing that.</p>
          <p>PP&amp;E, you will see up by over $900 million, that's a function of CapEx, which for the six months totals about $1.25 billion less depreciation during those six months. Investments is up by about $227 million. That is the net impact for the contributions to Rockies Express, and then some cash that was returned from Midcontinent Express, when we put in place our credit facility at Midcontinent Express. And then also a reduction due to the sale of the 25% interest in Thunder Creek.</p>
          <p>Deferred charges and other assets, that is essentially flat. Total assets, about $17 billion, up about $2 billion from where we were at the end of '07. Notes payable and current maturities, I mentioned that we really don't have any commercial paper outstanding. We do have a piece of long term debt that comes up in the first half of 2009 that now shows up as a current maturity. So, that's essentially what's on that line.</p>
          <p>Other current liabilities, you will see up almost $1.1 billion. AP is up a fair amount. And then the mark-to-market of the hedges again, for the most part, we have hedge accounting, which means we do value the hedges on a current market basis, but we only do it on the balance sheet. And a fair amount of that shows up here in the current liabilities section.</p>
          <p>Long term debt, you will see is up about 1.3 billion.. We've issued a significant amount of long term debt, termed up a fair amount of debt in the first half of the year. And then we had the one maturity that rolled out of long term debt into a current maturity, so basically, it went the other way. The value of interest rate swaps just fluctuates with the forward interest rate curve.</p>
          <p>Other is up about 1.1 billion &#x2013; over 1.1 billion. That again is the hedge values being adjusted there. Minority interest, down a touch. You will see an accumulated other comprehensive loss. Again that's the hedge value being adjusted there. Primarily, it's a function of our crude hedges, so you'll say, well wow, that's a big negative, almost $1.7 billion. But of course, the value of all of the crude that we have in the ground is going up, on an equivalent basis, but that's not reflected on the balance sheet. Other partners' capital, up about $400 million, and that's a function of primarily equity issuance and a little bit of the excess cash flow.</p>
          <p>So, where that gets us in terms of total debt, you will see a little under $8 billion for the quarter, that's up from $7 billion at the end of 2007. And at the end of the first quarter, we were about $7.6 billion. Now, so &#x2013; in terms of measuring the strength of the balance sheet, we like to look at our debt-to-EBITDA ratio, and you will see it shows up as 3.4, basically unchanged. Now, if you took that out another decimal point, which all of you can do, just by running the calculation, you'll see at the end of 2007, it was 3.43, and at the end of June 2008, it's 3.37. So, it does still round to 3.4, although there has been improvement in that measure. And we believe, given the stability of the assets that we own and operate, that is a very strong balance sheet, with debt just 3.4 times our EBITDA.</p>
          <p>And while we're on debt and talking about the capital issues, clearly, capital markets have been a little sketchy really, for the last 12 months. Again, I think based upon on the strength of the diversified portfolio of stable assets that we own and operate, we have not had any issues accessing capital. And to demonstrate that to you, just this year, so, in the first six months of 2008, we have termed up $1.6 billion of debt. So we've issued new debt of $1.6 billion. And this is just to KMP, and we've issued equity of $384 million. If you go back another six months from that, so if we look in the last 12 months, we have issued $2.1 billion of debt, and we've issued equity of $727 million.</p>
          <p>Now, if you add on to that the KMR distribution, which are effectively an equity issuance, built-in equity issuance, you would add on another $275 million of equity. And you'd be at KMP, in the last 12 months, issuing $2.1 billion of debt, and $1 billion of equity. And even on top of that, we've had some requirements for our pipeline joint ventures. At MEP, in the first quarter of this year, we put in place a $1.4 billion credit facility. So, access to new capital of $1.4 billion. And then last month, at Rockies Express, we termed up $1.3 billion of debt there, which we used to pay down commercial paper that we had outstanding.</p>
          <p>If you add all of that up in the last 12-months, we've raised $4.8 billion of debt, and $1 billion of equity. And so, again, in the last 12-months, in rather tumultuous capital markets, we've raised $4.8 billion of debt for KMP and for its pipeline joint ventures. And for KMP, we've raised $1 billion of equity, granted, that's including the KMR distribution. But it is a $1 billion of equity that we have to invest. So again, I think that demonstrates the strength of the assets that we own and operate.</p>
          <p>Now, as I usually do, let's talk about the change in debt. For the quarter, it's up a little under $400 million, about $389 million. And for the first half of the year, it's up a little under a billion, about $970 million. And so, what's driving that? Well, CapEx, not including sustaining, for the quarter is about $550 million, and for the first half, is about $1.17 billion.</p>
          <p>And then on top of that in the first half, we had a contribution to Rockies Express of about $300 million. So, that's additional cash going out. Now, we did raise about $50 million in the quarter and the first half through divestitures, largely &#x2013; or exclusively the sale of Thunder Creek. And so that was a source of cash of about $50 million for the quarter and the first half.</p>
          <p>We did have equity issuance in the first half of $384 million. Again, all that occurred in the first quarter. We did retain cash due to KMR distributions of about $70 million for the quarter and $138 million in the first half. We also received from Midcontinent Express $63 million in the first quarter, so that only applies to the first half. Margin deposits have increased, again, a posting margin related to hedges by $108 million in the quarter, and about $207 million in the first half.</p>
          <p>And then offsetting that, a source of cash we had that excess cash flow as we mentioned, of about $40 million in the quarter, and about $79 million in the first half. And what that means where &#x2013; what we end up with is working capital and other items have been essentially flat for the first half. It's actually been a source of about $120 million in the first quarter, I mean, in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>So, if you look at what's going on in the second quarter, AR and AP was a little bit of a use of cash. Other current assets and other current liabilities was a source of cash of about $173 million. That is driven primarily by prepayments that we have collected from customers.</p>
          <p>And then, we have a little bit of change in our bank accounts, relative to what's in the bank versus what checks have been written and sent and thus show up on the book. And various other items that totaled up again there a few negatives, which are the AR and AP, the change in the overdrafts, and the other items that offset the $173 million source from other current assets and current liabilities. They get you to about the $123 million positive that we're seeing from working capital in the quarter.</p>
          <p>And again, when you sum up all those items, that gets you to a change in debt, about $390 million for the quarter, about $970 million for the first half. Again, most of it's going to CapEx and the contributions to REX offset by the fundraising that we are doing, primarily on the equity side.</p>
          <p>So, we have had a significant amount of CapEx. Products continues to work on the project it has underway. It spent about $55 million in the first quarter, about &#x2013; a little under $100 million in the first half across the variety of project, finishing up the El Paso to Phoenix expansion, a little bit on the ethanol project down at Central Florida, some on the Miramar tanks, and then various other tank projects and pipeline expansions that are going on.</p>
          <p>Natural Gas and CapEx was about $220 million in the quarter, right about $400 million in the first half. The biggest piece of that was the Louisiana Pipeline, about $150 million in the quarter and almost $300 million in the first half. CO2 CapEx was about $116 million in the quarter, almost $260 million year-to-date, a lot of that going on at SACROC, and of course, continuing the Southwest Colorado expansion, and then a little bit at Yates.</p>
          <p>Terminals continued to have a lot of expansion projects going on there. About $83 million of CapEx in the quarter, or a little over $200 million in the first half. A lot of that at Pasadena and Galena Park, finishing up the North 40 project in Edmonton, and then a whole slew of other projects. And then in Trans Mountain, we spent about $71 million in the quarter, about $216 million in the first half. The vast majority of that's going to the Anchor Loop project, a little bit on finishing the pump station expansion.</p>
          <p>And that is all that I have. I will hand it back to Rich.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And Ed, we will take any and all questions people may have now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> First question comes from Ross Payne. Your line is open. State your affiliation, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Ross Payne with Wachovia. Good quarter, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Ross.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Couple of questions here. Number one, how much was unhedged on the CO2 business. Second of all in that regard, OXY came out talking about a new CO2 extraction plant they are going to build. What kind of the impact do you guys see from that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Unhedged, you have on the oil side, essentially almost all of our oil production was hedged. So, very little, as I said, very little of the oil production was unhedged. Now, we got a big increase, as you know, which was in our plan from the fact that, one set of hedges obviously rolled-off, another set of hedges came on and they were substantially higher prices all that we described to you in January. Where we did benefit was in two areas in CO2 from price and that was that our NGLs are unhedged, I think our net NGL production was around 9100 barrels or thereabouts. That's unhedged, we put all our hedges against the crude oil. So, to the extent that NGL prices are higher, we benefited there, and they obviously have some relationship with crude, not as easy to determine as it has been in the past.</p>
          <p>And then the second thing, second area where we benefit is a lot of our CO2 contracts with third parties are based on a floor price, but they have escalators based on the price of oil, if it gets above a certain level, and those are trued up every quarter. So, we've already trued up now for the third quarter, for example. So, that was a significant benefit of higher prices on our CO2 results.</p>
          <p>Now with regard to the OXY situation, there is tremendous increased demand by OXY and by a lot of other players in the Permian. And in fact, OXY and others are looking to us to supply additional CO2 for them in the out years. We have nothing else we can give them in the short term, but as we have some other contracts fall off, we do have some room in the portfolio a few years out. And they are looking to expand their tanks from us.</p>
          <p>So, our view and I think OXY's view is they see a big increase in the amount of CO2 that they want to use in the Permian Basin to increase their oil production, as do others. And so, we don't see it as having any impact on the demand for our CO2 that we move each day down the line from Southwest Colorado.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just switching gears to REX real quick, and then I'll step off here. Can you let us know roughly what the contribution for REX was, EBITDA was for the Natural Gas group? What's your pro rata share of the REX that currently is? And last of all, obviously, the project has increased in price, is there a maximum debt to EBITDA level that you guys are comfortable with at REX that you are going to keep it up? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Park?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I don't think we've disclosed our pro rata share of the EBITDA. We haven't talked about the REX EBITDA separately. Our pro rata share of the debt right now -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's 2.5 billion in total, sales -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So our end is half of that. And in terms of the debt overall, the debt is not expected to go above $3 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Permanent number, that's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so, we do not expect that REX will have debt beyond $3 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, that's it from me, guys. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ross.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from <mark type="inaudible" />. Your line is open. State your affiliation <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, that's <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good quarter, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now, could you talk a little bit &#x2013; when we think about the '08 distribution, when that's above budget, how much you think that's going to be above, and in light of the crude forecast, think above where you guys are at?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we've said &#x2013; and it's always work in progress, we start out the year saying we are going to distribute a certain amount, in this case 4.02. I think at the end of the first quarter, we said we would meet or exceed that, now we're saying we will exceed that. We will see how the results turn out these last two quarters. There're a lot of moving pieces, we're highly confident, or we wouldn't say it that we are going to have the firepower to exceed the 4.02, but we'll make the determination by how much as the succeeding quarters go by.</p>
          <p>And obviously, we are delighted to have a lot of excess coverage. I think that's good in a number of respects, and one thing is, nobody knows where crude prices are going. We are again &#x2013; we would still be above our plan even without &#x2013; if crude prices were just on our plan numbers, which I think were down in the 90s for WTI.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>82.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>82 for WTI. But, given that we are not certain where crude prices are going, I think it would be irresponsible to try to distribute every last penny that you are getting from higher crude prices in a given year where they're that far above budget. So, we're looking at all these factors, we are confident we will beat our $4.02. We're on track to do that, but I wouldn't want to specify anymore than that at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah <mark type="inaudible" />. The only thing I will add is our distribution is going up by 16% this year, and we're now confident it's going to go up by more than what we said originally. And again, originally it was increasing by 16%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. And just to switch gears, on the $8 billion of total CapEx that you spoke about, how much is locked down and protected from cost inflation versus additional costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me start with the fact that I said, and these are approximate numbers that we have completed about $3 billion of it and put it in service. And that's our share of these various projects, just like 8 billion is not, does not include 8 eighths of REX, it includes 50% of REX.</p>
          <p>So, 3 billion or three-eighths of this is all locked, put away, done. And then the remaining roughly $5 billion is our current best estimate. I don't know that I could estimate &#x2013; Steve Kean maybe could &#x2013; but exactly what part of that. A high proportion of it is obviously locked in because on REX for example, all of our pipe is bought, all of our compression is bought. The only thing left on REX is obviously these, as we've explained last time in gory detail, these were time and material contracts now.</p>
          <p>So, we have prices that our contractors believe where they will come in, but there is upside or downside off of those prices. We think it's fairly modest, but there are no guarantees in life. And, so it's relatively, if you add the 3 billion to pipe and compression that's locked in on these projects, certainly well over half is locked and put away, as you said. And about the only exposure is on these time and materials contracts, at least on the major pipeline projects. Steve, anything you want to add to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can say in general, with the projects when we get our customers get to the point where we have customer on contracts and that sort of thing. In general, our projects are going out and trying to lock in the costs that they can at that point of time, so the costs are becoming clearer at the same time that the economics are coming together on the project's approval.</p>
          <p>But you can't do that with everything, and some of the contracts &#x2013; specifically, time and materials contracts, as Rich mentioned, will fluctuate over time. But, again, in general we're trying to lock it in as soon as we can. And I think that that's evidenced by the fact that the cost increases that you're seeing in these projects, in the cost environment we can say are not as up as much in general costs are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, just to pick one number for you, I think the cost of pipe on some of our earlier projects where we ordered the pipe upfront was in the $1,200 per ton range. Today, a same pipe is going for in the range of $2,500 per ton. So, by locking in early, we save enormous amounts of money and of course, we did lock in on REX, Kinder Morgan Louisiana, and Midcontinent Express.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. And lastly, with 3.4 times leverage, you guys are well below your peers. Do you think that for additional CapEx, it can be debt financed rather than equity financed?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Park?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we'll continue to look at all of our investments at kind of a 50% equity, 50% debt mix. And my expectation is that that will probably keep us in the low 3s in terms of debt to EBITDA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, all right, thanks guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question will from Darren Horowitz. Your line is open, state your affiliation, please Darren?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Darren Horowitz of Raymond James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Darren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Again to echo everybody's earlier comments, Rich, great quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My first question is on the Louisiana Pipeline, it seems now that the in-service date is going to be April 1, and if memory serves correct, I think last quarter you had mentioned it was going to be about three months early, which would have pegged it around the beginning of the first quarter of '09. Can you give us a little bit more color as to any changes or nuances that are different there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we could have brought this in earlier, but clearly, this is very consistent with what I've said in prior calls, clearly, there is no great demand &#x2013; all this &#x2013; let me back up.</p>
          <p>All this transportation capacity is underwritten for 20-year periods of time by Chevron and Total. But, in point of fact, there is no LNG, virtually no LNG going through Cheniere. So, they really have no need and no obligation to ship this before the April 1st date. So, we could probably incur some additional expense, and bring it in, in that January timeframe that we originally talked about. But, we've decided to just not spend any additional cost, and bring it in on time, and therefore, as close to budget as we can. Now, we have had some cost overruns. But, that's the main reason.</p>
          <p>We're making good progress. The tough part of the construction there is laying the pipe through the lake, and Steve, I think we're about 75% finished that part of it. And then we go through some swamps. And then &#x2013; and I can say this, because my wife is from Louisiana, they call it then the uplands portion. I am not sure I equate that section of Louisiana with uplands. But, anyway, we're getting out of the lake, we are making good progress through the swamp, and we will soon be in the fertile uplands. And but, we have elected not to have an all-out push like we might on REX or other projects where there is a lot of pent-up demand for that capacity right off the bat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I appreciate the color. So, it sounds like you're taking a bit more prudent approach to costs, specifically in that area?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Switching gears, Rich, over to the CO2 division, I just want to address a point that Ross initially asked, and you answered when you were discussing additional room in your portfolio to expand your CO2 presence in the Permian. Can you give us a little bit more color on the nine new production wells at the McElmo Dome ramping up to 200 Mcf a day?</p>
          <p>Your target is the fourth quarter, but can you give us a little bit more color as to the timing and maybe any expectations for CO2 production into the first half of '09, because it seems like demand would underscore more production.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'd be happy to. The Southwest Colorado expansion really has three parts to it. One part is to expand the production at McElmo Dome, that's our historic production area that churns out about a billion cubic feet a day today that goes down Cortez, that's point one, to expand that by 200 million cubic feet a day.</p>
          <p>The second part is to expand Doe Canyon, which is a new production field a few miles away from McElmo Dome and that we own about 80-plus percent of, is to develop that to produce 100 million cubic feet a day, and then to expand the Cortez pipeline by 200 million cubic feet a day.</p>
          <p>So, we are going to have, when everything is finished in the fourth quarter, 200 million additional cubic feet per day coming down to the Permian Basin, the other 100 million cubic feet we've sold to a producer over in Southern Utah who's going to take it, so coming the other way out of Southwest Colorado. So, that's where the 300 is going.</p>
          <p>We have drilled the wells at Doe Canyon and put the plant in there. Those wells have come on better than expected. We are now producing 100 million cubic feet a day, we thought it would take five or six wells to do that. We are now doing it on &#x2013; have got two or three wells &#x2013; two wells, Park says &#x2013; doing that with just two wells, that's how prolific those wells are. So, that 100 million is done.</p>
          <p>On McElmo Dome, we originally intended to drill nine wells that &#x2013; to produce an additional 200 million cubic feet a day. We've completed most of those wells. We've had &#x2013; the only hang-up is, we've had some problems getting permission to drill some of the horizontal wells that &#x2013; they're not sited on the national monument out there, but the horizontal portion of the well is actually &#x2013; intrudes on the sub-surface of the monument. So, that's very difficult to get permitted. It's taking longer than we thought. But, the wells we've drilled have been better than we thought. So, we may actually only drill seven or eight wells instead of the full nine.</p>
          <p>Now the other thing that has to be done is we have to ramp up the compression on Cortez in order to get that additional 200 million down the line. We've got &#x2013; we are up to being able to move about 100 million additional &#x2013; but we have &#x2013; one of the points where we're adding compression that has not been fully permitted in the State of New Mexico. And we're actually now going to move generators on to work that until we get the final permits for that, which could swap over into early '09. Therefore, we're adding some generators to actually bring it up online in the fourth quarter, we'll be able move the full 200 million.</p>
          <p>So, I guess we're dancing as fast as we can on this. But, there are a lot of permitting issues particularly when there is anything close to the monument area out there in Southwest Colorado.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I appreciate it. And then one final question, switching back to the Natural Gas Pipelines for a minute. When you're looking at MEP, can you give us a sense of the current pulse of regulatory approval on the line?</p>
          <p>And the second question is, any opportunity to either expand zone one capacity further or additional expansions given the geographic footprint? It could probably use more capacity, as &#x2013; certainly as the hands will kind of ramp up over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no question, and let me &#x2013; between what I said and what's in the earnings release, let me repeat that. We started out with planned capacity of 1.5 Bcf a day. That is now completely subscribed to. Then we went out with a binding open season, which was just completed last week, on an additional 300 million cubic feet a day, which can be done just by adding power. That was fully subscribed in a binding open season. So, we now have commitments for extended periods from creditworthy shippers for 1.8 Bcf a day. And that will include the expansion that we're talking about for the last 300 of it.</p>
          <p>And beyond that, we certainly think there is opportunity, we're in the drawing board process right now. The next expandability will not be as cheap, and it will be incremental in terms of rate making, we think. So, we're now planning that, and we will be going out to our customers, who didn't make the cut in the binding open season to work with them. And I think there's a very good likelihood, nothing certain, but a very good likelihood, that we will further expand that system.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you give us an idea to the magnitude, Rich?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Too early to tell. We are just going to look at that and see what our producers want. And usually Darren, in these expansions, there's kind of a sweet spot, where, gee, we can expand this much by adding X amount of pipe of this size, and then leaving room for still additional compression on the new pipe, and it will cost Y, or we can do or we can do a little less or a little more.</p>
          <p>And that takes some engineering work, which we're in the process of doing right now. We hope to complete that, then go back to the other shippers who didn't get the capacity they wanted in the open season, and be able to say okay, for X, we're willing to build an additional whether it's 200, 300, 400 million cubic feet a day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rich. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question will come from <mark type="inaudible" />. Your line is open. State your affiliation, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, congratulations on the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the cost inflation on the organic growth projects, the Midcontinent Express had a large increase from your last estimate. Is there further risk to the cost estimate for Midcontinent Express?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we think not. We took our Board through that today. Our Natural Gas group came in and went through line-by-line exactly what drove that price increase. And we still have a fair amount of contingency left in it. But again, there are no guarantees, and I've been in this business almost 30 years, and just as I've never seen it as good in terms of producer demand for signing up long-term capacity on natural gas pipelines, I've never seen the cost environment in terms of pressure and in terms of frankly, issues on quality, and workforce, and that kind of thing that we have now in the pipeline space. We think we've nailed it all, and we think that any increases will be none or minimal, but again, there are no guarantees.</p>
          <p>Now it's a very good project from a return standpoint, particularly including this very effective expansion that we now have subscribed. So, it's very good. But we are going to do everything we can to hold it where it is, and virtually everything is locked in, but we still have these time and materials contracts, which, if you had a real rainy period, those could increase. They are just some moving parts. I don't know, Steve, our Chief Operating Officer, anything you want to add to that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you covered it and there is, as you mentioned, beginning a good amount of contingency. And that contingency is there for a reason, as construction costs do tend to vary. But we hope that will help insulate us from further increases here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have most of the right-of-way already locked up. And again, this runs across &#x2013; unlike the Kinder Morgan Louisiana, and unlike parts of REX &#x2013; Midcontinent Express doesn't run across a lot of scenic riverways, or environmental crossings, and a lot of it parallels other pipeline right-of-ways. That's all the plus for the project. So, I feel pretty good about it, but all I can say is, we watch these things like hawk, and we think we're doing a good job of managing it.</p>
          <p>It's just that some increases have been unavoidable. We think we've nailed all those, but again, there aren't any guarantees, and we could have some additional price creep on one of these projects. We don't expect it, and if we did have additional price creep, we think it'd be fairly small.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of operating expenses, you were describing that &#x2013; and that's probably high commodity prices are positive at Kinder, but in terms of operating expenses, which segments are more exposed to higher electricity costs and fuel costs?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on diesel fuel costs, our Terminals is the most exposed. As I said, we use &#x2013; a million gallons a month in our terminals and to the extent that diesel prices are up, if they are up $1, that's $1 million a month, if they are up $2, that's $2 million a month. Now, we are able to go back and collect some of that. We have some contracts where we are able to extract fuel surcharge, some we're not. So, that's where the most pressure is on the diesel side.</p>
          <p>On the natural gas and electric power side, we have varying mixes in our pipelines. Some are more fueled by natural gas, some more by electricity. Now, we do, on a lot of our pipelines of course, have pass-through clauses there, where we actually are able pass through the costs of that as part of our tariff.</p>
          <p>So, it's sort of a mixed bag. Probably the most direct impact of higher commodity prices on the whole business is in the Products Pipeline, where, as we've had lower demand, we have lower throughput, and on the Terminals side, where we are experiencing substantially higher diesel prices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next, Ed?.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next one comes from John Edwards, your line is open. State your affiliation, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi everybody, John Edwards with Morgan Keegan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, how are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh good, how are you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just, at the analyst meeting at the beginning of the year, you were talking about, there was &#x2013; 83% of the oil was unhedged for '08. And I think it was 73% for '09, and I'm just wondering where you were at on that -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, you said unhedged. You meant hedged.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I meant &#x2013; I'm sorry, hedged.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I meant &#x2013; 17% was unhedged, right. I'm just wondering where you stand now, and is there continued opportunity to go above your $82 per barrel budget?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, yes, those hedges are essentially what's on for the year. And so that's the right way to think about what is hedged for this year. Now, the number &#x2013; the chart that you are specifically referring to is a BOE chart, and so that includes NGLs in it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's why we say, John, basically we allocate all our hedges to the crude oil side. So, as a practical matter, virtually 100% of the crude oil is hedged, and all of the NGLs are unhedged. And that's where we &#x2013; aside from the CO2 contracts, that's the second significant upside from pricing on the CO2 segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so that's essentially what your &#x2013; like Park to your point, you were saying it's barrels of oil equivalent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And so &#x2013; now it includes in the NGLs, it does not include an approximation for CO2, which just gets into a very difficult calculation, because of the floors that Rich mentioned, and how exactly you translate that back, but it does include the NGL barrels.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then have you locked up additional on 2009 and 2010, since the beginning of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We've put on some additional hedges, but they've been in out years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then could you &#x2013; in the past you had talked about submersible pump issues out at CO2, and &#x2013; you didn't mentioned at this time, is that largely resolved at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I'm happy to say it is &#x2013; where's the wood &#x2013; I'm happy to say it is. Our failure rate on the pumps has gone down dramatically. We have a new vendor out there &#x2013; I'd say new, it's now been with us since last fall, I guess &#x2013; and they've done a better job and our failure rate is now down to our target level. So, we're doing a lot better on that.</p>
          <p>Actually, I would just say as we've talked about before, SACROC is an enormously complicated unit and again, things are going very well there in terms of performance. And I think we've had some, we've corrected a lot of the problems. You're never 100% complete, but I think we've gone a long way, submersible pumps are doing a lot better. We're hitting our targets. We've &#x2013; I think doing better on our power supply, although I would say in that part of West Texas, you still have windstorms or storms come across a couple of times a month that, we end up losing part of the field for six hours or something. But, I think we've made a lot of improvements there. It's a pretty wild and wooly country in terms of weather.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So, you're expecting it to stay at this 27,500 production level for SACROC, and a little over 28 for Yates, for the bulk &#x2013; for the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We expect to be on budget for Sac Tock, which I believe is 27.7 for the full-year average. And then at Yates, our current expectation is that we'd be on to maybe slightly above our budget for the full year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. That's all I had, thanks. Good quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, John, thanks. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Dan Jenkins. Your line is open. State your affiliation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, State of Wisconsin Investment Board, and congratulations on a nice quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Dan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>First, just a couple of operational things, I was wondering on the PP, the Product Pipelines, you've talked about how they're impacted by the demand destruction from higher prices. I was wondering if you could give us a sense of how a change in volumes would impact the revenues that you're seeing on those &#x2013; like with a 1% decline or 2% decline in volume, how would that translate into the revenues?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, again, what we said is for the quarter, we were down around 8%, year-to-date, down about 6%. And that's impacted the revenues. We said we are now &#x2013; I think Park said we are now running about 5% below plan. And that's &#x2013; and our Products Pipeline people have put into their current estimate what they expect the volumes to be for the rest of the year, which is essentially where they are, maybe a little bit of an uptick in fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>But, essentially, pretty low volumes for the year, and that's where we come out. We expect to be, as I think Park said, kind of consistent in terms of earnings before DD&amp;A with where we are today, around 5% below plan, which would translate to be $30 million or a little more based on a plan, as you know, of a little north of $600 million. I don't have any sensitivity on what each 1% is, but that kind of gives you an idea.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, if you're just talking about revenues, then clearly, our revenue is just the volume times the tariff. And everything else being held equal, if you lose 1% volume, then you'll lose 1% revenue. Now, if you take that to the bottom line, clearly, when you have less volume going through, you require less power, and so it doesn't all fall to the bottom line, there's a little bit of variable cost there. And then the other issue is, it's not, everything is not equal. The tariff does change as a function of inflation.</p>
          <p>And if you're talking about 1% of volume, that has gone away, because it's been replaced with ethanol, well in all likelihood, we're receiving that ethanol at our terminal at the end of the pipe. And we're storing it, and then we're blending it into the fuel stream, and then we're sending it out over our rack, and we're getting paid to do that. And so, when you start to get into dynamics like that, it gets very difficult to try to assess the impact of a specific percent change in volume.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I was wondering on the NGLs, you mentioned that there has been a problem. I was wondering if you give a little more color there on what that is and when you expect that to be solved, as far as getting those -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we've been prorated by &#x2013; the pipeline moves NGLs from West Texas down to the ship channel. And it was because I think of some fuel issues, contamination issues, and the mix of product being shipped through pipeline. This is a third-party pipeline, not ours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the contamination didn't come from us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the contamination didn't come from us, yeah. And they've now indicated that they think they're closer to getting it solved, in which case the prorationing should end, but we don't have a specific date on that yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then on &#x2013; I think I saw in your release that the volumes were down on Trans Mountain, and given that you increased the capacity this year versus the last year and that people expect production to be going up from those areas, I was wondering if you could give a little more color on what might be behind that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. In the second quarter, there were a number of production issues with the oil sands production, and with some of the upgraders, and then there was a refinery fire and a shutdown. So, a whole bunch of sort of discrete things combined to just &#x2013; there was just less throughput available to go through the pipeline. Now, we do have &#x2013; our tariff allows us to recapture some of that. It's not a strict dollar-for-dollar decline, but our volumes were down in the quarter because of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the last thing I was wondering is on the financing plan. You mentioned you've issued 384 million of equity so far, and I think about 900 million of debt. And I think in your plan, you had talked about a billion of equity if you give out any &#x2013; when the timing we'd see those additional units, and would we expect more equity than debt in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Park?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the actual amounts for the year-to-date are 1.6 billion of debt, and almost $400 million of equity. And I think the actual equity that we are going to issue is little bit less than that, and you have to take off the KMR issuance of which &#x2013; which is included in there, and is actual equity that we will raise. So, I expect that going forward, we'll continue to try to finance our expansions and acquisitions, 50% debt and 50% equity. And when the timing's right, then we'll issue some of both as appropriate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question will come from Sharon Lui. Your line is open. State your affiliation, Sharon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sharon Lui, Wachovia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Sharon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. Rich, I was wondering if you could just comment on the hydrostatic test that's planned on REX-West for September, and if the disruption may impact your cash flow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have announcements &#x2013; it's really all posted on the REX website, that we are going to hydrostatically test a section of the REX line, generally from September 3rd to about September 26, I really think all the information is there. We will have &#x2013; that will have some modest impact on our revenues in September. That's all in our current forecast.</p>
          <p>But we are hydrotesting, we are in compliance with DOT regulations now. But ultimately, as we finish the project, the pipeline will need to operate at a higher pressure, and we need to test it in order to get that design level in compliance at the higher pressure level. And that's what we are doing. We're working with our customers on that. But right now, we have it scheduled for that time period in September. We'll obviously do it as quickly as we can, if we can do it a little more quickly than that, we can.</p>
          <p>But the details &#x2013; and that &#x2013; it's not a &#x2013; obviously not a full curtailment of all the capacities, just again on the area from Eastern Kansas over into Missouri that needs to be hydrotested. So, again, a lot of the capacity on KMI and Northern Natural Gas and NGPL will still be there.</p>
          <p>So, it's a curtailment of a part of the 1.5 billion we're shipping today. Obviously, we wanted to give our customers advance notice. Some of them may be able to find other outlets, and then we'll get it back in service as quickly as we can. It's relatively minimal in terms of reduced cash flow for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Also, do you have an update, I guess, on Northeast Express?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, really not much to report. We continue to work with some customers there to extend the line from Clarington on East over to Princeton, New Jersey and perhaps on north to Linden. We are not going to do that, as we said, unless and until we get throughput signed up.</p>
          <p>We have some meetings with some of the shippers early next week, and we'll just see how it goes. Again if we could get &#x2013; I think I said last time I would think it's about 50/50, there are other competing proposals. And we'll just see whether we can get customers to sign up for throughput.</p>
          <p>And I will say, as I said real briefly at the end of what I said in the prepared remarks, we have a number of pipeline projects that we're working on, a lot of them close to our present lines, including an expansion of MTB, but several other major potential projects, none of which we're at all prepared to announce today, because we don't have shipper agreements signed yet. We continue to work on them. Some, I think we will get, and some we won't and that's the category I put Northeast Express in.</p>
          <p>Again, as I've said a million times, we do not believe in the old movie title, the old Field of Dreams' build it and they will come, we believe in signing up your throughput, and then building it. And so, if we can get throughput agreements signed, we will build these pipelines. If we can't, we won't, that's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, terrific. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question will come from Barrett Blaschke. Your line is open. State your affiliation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's Barrett Blaschke with RBC. Great quarter, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a couple of questions over on the refined side. Where do the &#x2013; Rich, you mentioned kind of the elasticity point seems to have finally been found here. What do you think we need to back down to, in terms of commodity pricing to see this go a little more inelastic again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know, clearly, we look at this very closely, Barrett, and clearly, there was a difference between the first quarter and second quarter. The second quarter was more of a deterioration. And so, that would I guess say that on gasoline, some place between 3.75 and $4, $4 seems to have some magic impact. And there is some variation around the country, but certainly, the trend line pretty well across the board was down for the first quarter and the second quarter.</p>
          <p>And so I've got to believe, and I don't know, but I've got to believe that at $4, people are cutting back, maybe at 3.75 they cut back less, but I am not here to predict that. We'll just roll with the punches, whatever they are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>With prices the way they are, is this kind of a disincentive to go do additional refines &#x2013; products pipelines and focus more on other areas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, I think it makes you look very carefully at your growth numbers, but we'll still continue to look at expansion opportunities when that expansion is needed to serve a market and try to look at the long-term. But it will just make us look very carefully at our growth assumptions, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question will come from Becca Followill. Your line is open, state your affiliation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Tudor Pickering Holt, good afternoon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Becca.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, the follow-up question I have on the REX hydrostatic testing &#x2013; any chance of moving that later in the year, when it wouldn't have so much impact on basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've discussed that with our customers. Right now, it's still scheduled for September. We are working to see what the most appropriate date, but right now, the schedule posted on the website is still September.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>To move the date, would you have to get DOT approval, or what would you have to do to move that date?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we would not need DOT approval.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, it's just at your discretion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah &#x2013; working with our customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just to clarify why &#x2013; I know you said you needed to do the hydrostatic testing to increase the pressures, but why not do it before the lines went in service? Why now, why at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the lines were hydrostatically tested before they went into service. All the lines were. But, in this particular case, in order to be able to allow us to operate at a higher percentage of the maximum allowable operating pressure, we needed to hydro test to a higher &#x2013; actually I think hold a spike test for a longer period of time. And it's that part of the test, Becca, we need to do again.</p>
          <p>And clearly, it would've been preferable to do before the pipe went into service, but we're going to get it taken care of as quickly as we can. And in the meantime, of course, we're moving <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Becca.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from John Edwards, your line is open. State your affiliation, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, John.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, follow up, Morgan Keegan. Just &#x2013; I forgot to ask you, are you &#x2013; with the weak economy in other areas, are you seeing &#x2013; I mean from your comments it didn't sound that way &#x2013; but are you seeing any beginnings of relief on the cost side on your major construction projects?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we're frankly not, John. I think that there is so much building going on in our area, our industry, that I think still, the pressure is pretty great. Now, you know we &#x2013; there's some anecdotal evidence. We talk to contractors who say they are having the capability to do more spreads. They're training more welders. All those things are steps in the right direction. But so far, we haven't seen the corner being turned. So, I think that the pipelines and similar construction is still pretty hot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then I've forgot to ask you the &#x2013; with all the inclement weather earlier this year, did that impact your REX-East schedule at all? I know you hadn't really started construction with most of the heavy rains, but did that impact you at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, not on REX-East. On REX-West, with the construction's finished, but we're still restoring the right-of-way. Certainly that's had some impact. It's hard to plant new grass seed when you're under two feet of water, unless you want rice.</p>
          <p>But, so at any rate, it's had some impact there, but not on REX-East. Now if we have rain later in the fall, in Illinois and Indiana, then that would have an impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from Yves Siegel. Your line is open. State your affiliation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Wachovia Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Yves, how are you doing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good, thank you. Good evening. Just a quick follow-up on the potential growth projects going forward. With &#x2013; given the cost escalations of getting the projects done, for new projects, will the tariffs be sufficient enough, so that you can still get the same sort of returns that historically you've gotten, number one?</p>
          <p>And so, the second part of that is, given the &#x2013; as you discussed, the tightness in the market, how much lead time do you need to be able to procure a pipe, and get contractors to even contemplate new projects?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, your first question is certainly &#x2013; tariffs, I think in general will be higher, I'm not speaking just for Kinder Morgan. Tariffs in general will be higher than they have been on the prior projects.</p>
          <p>If you had to replicate REX today, at today's steel prices, today's compression prices, no telling what the tariff would be, but it would sure be a way of a lot higher than the roughly $1.10 across the whole system that is our present part of tariff. So, yeah, tariffs are going to get higher, in general to reflect the higher cost construction.</p>
          <p>That said, I think that Kinder Morgan and other companies of this size may actually have an advantage, because we're using a lot of the major contractors, particularly when you get to 42-inch pipe, there are very few contractors who could really do this. We have good relationships; we know who is good and who's not. So, I think we may have more insight into it than most.</p>
          <p>So, to the extent we can land new projects, we will make as certain as we possibly can that we have built in the current costs at that time of doing that project, including labor escalations and, including pipe cost. And the pipe costs are fairly easy to lock down and most of these &#x2013; they may not be at prices you would like, but you can ascertain what the prices are. And of course, you do have some lead time in terms of getting in line at the mill, because the permitting process on any of these projects is the most significant time consumer in the projects.</p>
          <p>So, you may take 18 months to permit, and nine months to build, in a hypothetical example. So, you can lock in the price, and you don't have to ask the bill to deliver today or tomorrow. That's where you really get scalped. You can set a price, agreed with them obviously, for delivery 18 or 20 months out.</p>
          <p>So, we're, we would be happy to build more pipelines, but only obviously, if we can get a good return on those that we build.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, guys. Have a good night.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Yves. All right, Ed , is that it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time, I show no further questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you all for spending the time with us. We're delighted with our quarter, and we'll talk to you again. If you have any questions call Kim, and she will be happy to answer them for you. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time, that would conclude today's conference. You may disconnect. And thank you for your attendance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>