<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1386283" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-04-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3057</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o Guti&#xE9;rrez, Chief Financial and Administrative Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst">Lauren Torres</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o Guti&#xE9;rrez</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Gustavo Oliveira</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Robert Ford</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Lore Serra</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Margaret Kalvar</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Antonio Gonzalez</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Jos&#xE9; Yord&#xE1;n</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Alan Alanis</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Celso S&#xE1;nchez</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and welcome to Coca-Cola FEMSA's First Quarter 2011 Earnings Results Conference Call. As a reminder, today's conference is being recorded and all participants are in a listen-only mode. At the request of the company, we will open up the conference for question-and-answers after the presentation.</p>
          <p>During the conference call, management may discuss certain forward-looking statements concerning Coca-Cola FEMSA's future performance, and should be considered as good faith estimates made by the company. These forward-looking statements reflect management expectations and are based upon currently available data. Actual results are subject to future events and uncertainties, which can materially impact the company's actual performance.</p>
          <p>At this time, I would now turn the conference over to Mr. H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o, Coca-Cola FEMSA's CFO. Please go ahead, Mr. Trevi&#xF1;o.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us today. In the first quarter of 2011, our company delivered strong top and bottom line results, supported by our successful strategy to selectively increase prices on our wide portfolio of various alternatives over the past 12 months combined with our operations discipline to adapt our business to particular market conditions. Our Mercosur and Latincentro divisions were the main drivers of our positive performance for the quarter demonstrating again the benefits of our geographically diversified portfolio of franchise territories, which enable us to compensate for a slow start of the year in our Latincentro division.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter, our consolidated revenues reached 25.8 billion pesos, up close to 10% from the first quarter of 2010, despite the effect of a strike we faced in our Venezuelan subsidiary at the beginning of the year. On a currency neutral basis, our consolidated total revenues grew approximately 11%.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter, our consolidated sales volume rose 2.6%. This increase was driven mainly by the strong performance of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (2:27) in our Mexico division and the solid performance of our sparkling and the still beverages portfolio across our Mercosur division. Our consolidated gross profit increase close to 10% in the first quarter of 2010; cost of goods sold increased as a result of PET and sweetener cost across our operations which were partially offset by the appreciation of our main operations local currencies as applied to our U.S. dollar-denominated raw material costs. Consequently, our gross margin expanded 20 basis points compared with the first quarter of 2010. Our consolidated operating income improved more than 10%, reaching 3.9 billion Mexican pesos in the first quarter; supported by double-digit operating growth generated by our Mexico and Mercosur divisions.</p>
          <p>Operating leverage achieved through higher consolidated revenues combined with stable year-over-year operating expenses in our Latincentro division compensated for higher labor cost in Venezuela and higher labor and freight cost in Argentina. As a result, our operating margin expanded 10 basis points, reaching 15% for the quarter.</p>
          <p>On a currency neutral basis, our consolidated operating income grew approximately 11%. Our consolidated EBITDA increased 11%, reaching 5 billion pesos during the first quarter of this year. Our net consolidated interest income increased 6% to 2.2 billion Mexican pesos. This increase mainly resulted from higher operating income recorded during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Now let me expand on our operations. In the first quarter of 2011, our Mexican operations delivered strong top and bottom-line results, driven by operating leverage we achieved by strong volume growth and pricing ahead of year-over-year inflation. 10% volume growth of brand Coca-Cola in multi and single-serve presentations, combined with an 8% volume growth in flavored sparkling beverages enabled our sparkling beverage portfolio to achieve high-single digit volume growth for the quarter. Our bottled water portfolio grew 10%, supported by both our bottled water business and our single-serve water percentages.</p>
          <p>Moreover, our still beverage category grew 14%, driven mainly by Valle Frut, our orangeade and our Jugos del Valle line of business. Powerade, our isotonic beverage, grew more than 30% and Nestea grew more than 50% as compared with the first quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Our average price per unit case increased more than 4% as compared with the first quarter of 2010. This increase was driven mainly by the selective price increases that we have implemented across our portfolio over the past several months coupled with higher volumes of brand Coca-Cola.</p>
          <p>As a result of these factors, our Mexican operations' total revenues increased more than 14% to 1.5 billion pesos. With regard to our profitability, the impact of higher PET costs was partially offset by the appreciation of the Mexican pesos applied to our U.S. dollar-denominated raw material costs.</p>
          <p>Compared with the first quarter of 2010, our gross profit increased more than 13% to 4.5 billion Mexican pesos and our gross margin declined 30 basis points to 47.9%. Our operating income increased more than 23% to 1.4 billion pesos. Operating leverage achieved through higher revenues produced an operating margin expansion of 100 basis points, reaching 14.4%. Our EBITDA grew more than 15% to 1.8 billion Mexican pesos compared with the first quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>During the first quarter of 2011, our Mexican operations delivered strong results, achieving the highest volumes ever recorded for a first quarter. All of our beverage categories grew at a healthy pace. Brand Coca-Cola continued its growth, thanks to its strong brand preference and our operators' relentless effort to design segmented growing portfolio that allows to capture additional industry <mark type="ph" /> volumes (7:53).</p>
          <p>Our strategy to selectively increase our prices has proven successful as we outpaced increase year-over-year levels of inflation. This strategy has enabled us to partially compensate for raw material cost pressure such as the higher prices of PET resin in our Mexican operations.</p>
          <p>On the sugar front, we have seen a more stable cost environment, which combined with the appreciation of the Mexican peso, as applied to our U.S. dollar-denominated raw material costs, is also helping us to mitigate the raising cost pressures.</p>
          <p>The investments we have made over the past 18 months in the marketplace to enhance our execution of the point of sale, foster the availability of our turnover presentations, increase our <mark type="indiscernible" /> (8:51) and support our still beverage categories are enabling us to increase our market share year-over-year. We are confident that our clear focus on satisfying our consumers with our wide <mark type="indiscernible" /> (9:06) portfolio of beverage combined with the precise execution of our marketplace initiatives will continue to drive our performance for the year and help our Mexican operations to outperform our industry.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to our Latincentro division. Our Latincentro division posted a 14% volume decline in the first quarter. This decline mainly resulted from the strike we faced in our Valencia production and distribution facilities in Venezuela at the beginning of the quarter, which resulted in a 29% volume decline in this franchise territory and a slow start to the year is in our Colombian operations. In Colombia we recorded an 8% volume decline in the first quarter, mainly due to continued bad weather conditions that affected the whole of our industry. However, we have maintained our market share in this market. It is important to note that in the first quarter of last year, our Colombian franchise territory recorded double-digit volume growth presenting a tough year-over-year comparison.</p>
          <p>Our Central American operations recorded a 2% decline in sales volume compared with the first quarter of 2010, cycling a 12% volume growth. Volume growth in our water portfolio and our still beverages category was outpaced by a mid-single digit decline in our sparkling beverages volume.</p>
          <p>Our Latincentro division total revenues declined 5% reaching 7 billion Mexican pesos. Higher average price per unit case across the division was offset by lower volumes. On a currency neutral basis, our Latincentro division total revenues declined 2%. With regard to our profitability, our Latincentro division's gross profit declined 2% to 3.3 billion Mexican pesos. Higher PET and sweetener costs were offset by 1) a benefit recorded in Venezuela resulting from having PET inventories from 2010, which were registered at a lower exchange rate as compared to the same quarter of last year and second, the effect of the appreciation of the Colombia peso as applied to our U.S. dollars-denominated raw material cost.</p>
          <p>Operating leverage achieved through higher average price per unit case in local currency produced a gross margin expansion of 150 basis points to 47.3% compared with the first quarter of 2010. Our operating income decreased close to 9% to 1.1 billion Mexican pesos. Higher operating expenses were driven mainly by higher labor costs in Venezuela, which were partially offset by lower operating expenses in Colombia and Central America. As a result, our operating margin declined 60 basis points to 16.1%, compared with the first quarter of 2010. Our EBITDA declined close to 5% to 1.5 billion Mexican pesos compared with the first quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>During this first quarter, our Latincentro operations faced several challenges, from a 26 days strike at our most important facility in Venezuela to continued bad weather conditions in Colombia. In the face of these challenges, our operators demonstrated their flexibility to adapt our business to the prevailing conditions and minimize the impact on our profitability. Despite a 14% volume decline across the division, our profitability decreased by less than 5%, mainly due to our operations ability to implement selective price increases, innovate with different packaging alternatives and effectively adjust our business to this aggressive environment.</p>
          <p>Importantly, our wide portfolio products continues to enjoy the strong preference among our consumers as demonstrated by our gains in market share across the divisions. Furthermore, consistent with our commitment to stimulate and satisfy our consumer taste with additional high-quality products, we reinforced our non-carbonated beverage platform. Through the acquisition of Grupo Industrias Lacteas in Panama with our partner, The Coca-Cola Company, we ventured together in a promising beverage segment.</p>
          <p>Among other benefits, this transaction will give us the opportunity to learn about the dairy category and develop new capabilities to manage equal distribution system, leveraging our skills to segment the market and refine the pricing architecture of this important product portfolio, while we incorporate a talented team of professionals into our company who will leverage our mutual strengths. As of April 2011, we will start reflecting the profitability of our share of this business in our financial results through the equity method.</p>
          <p>Now, let's talk about Mercosur division. In the first quarter of 2011, our Mercosur division's total revenues grew more than 18% to 9.3 billion Mexican pesos. Excluding beer, which accounted for 877 million Mexican pesos, our total revenues reached 8.5 billion Mexico pesos. An increase in the average price per unit case accounted for approximately 65% of incremental total revenues and volume growth represented the balance.</p>
          <p>Volume growth in our Mercosur division was up almost 7% in the first quarter of 2011. Our Brazilian operations recorded close to 4% volume growth, successfully building on more than 14% volume growth in the same period of last year and despite bad weather conditions presented during the quarter. This increase was driven mainly by brand Coca-Cola in single and multi-serve presentations and the continuous strong performance of our non-carbonated beverage <mark type="indiscernible" /> (16:17), which grew more than 40%, supported by the Jugos del Valle line of products and the incorporation of different line extensions of the Matte Leao portfolio.</p>
          <p>In Argentina, our volumes grew 14%, mainly due to the strong performance of brand Coca-Cola, which grew 18% and the solid performance of our still beverage category, which grew 17%, mainly driven by our flavored water brand Aquarius, and our Cepita juice brand.</p>
          <p>With regard to our profitability, our Mercosur division's gross profit increased 18% to 3.9 billion Mexican pesos. Increased sweetener and resin costs across the division were partially offset by the appreciation of the Brazilian real as applied to the U.S. dollar-denominated raw material costs. Consequently, our gross margin decreased 20 basis points to 41.9%.</p>
          <p>Our operating income grew 18% to 1.4 billion Mexican pesos. Operating margin was 14.9% in the first quarter, remaining flat as compared with last year. Our EBITDA grew more than 23%, reaching 1.7 billion Mexican pesos. During this first quarter of 2011 our Mercosur division delivered positive results. Our portfolio of products demonstrated its preference from among customers building on significant volume growth in the first quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>Our operators successfully their &#x2013; the liability of packaging alternatives in the sparkling beverages category, especially brand Coca-Cola in <mark type="ph" /> return to our (18:22) presentations. Moreover, the still beverages category continued its momentum supported by the Jugos del Valle line of beverages and now we are <mark type="indiscernible" /> (18:33) portfolio Matte Leao <mark type="ph" /> food products in Brazil (18:35). As well as our Cepita juice brand and Aquarius flavored water in Argentina.</p>
          <p>Our operators execution capabilities combined with the innovation we have developed across all of our various categories enabled us to grow at a faster pace and lead our bottling system. The selective prices strategy we have implemented over the past several months allows to compensate for increased raw material costs.</p>
          <p>Now, let me walk you through our financial performance for the quarter. This quarter the balanced profile of our franchised territories underscore the value of our company, diversifies source of profitability. Despite a slow start to the year in our Latincentro division, the strong performance of our Mexico and Mercosur divisions enabled us to increase our profitability. This performance highlights our robust defensive profile, which protects our consolidated cash flow from particular economic, geographic or weather-related events we may face in our business.</p>
          <p>As of March 31st, 2011, we had a cash balance of 13.5 billion Mexican pesos and our total debt was 17 billion Mexican pesos. Our last 12 months net debt-to-EBITDA ratio and our EBITDA-to-net interest ratio were 0.2 and 15 times respectively. As you may already know, in March 2011, Coca-Cola FEMSA held its Annual Ordinary Shareholders Meeting in which our shareholders approved a cash dividend in the amount of approximately 4.4 billion Mexican pesos, to be paid actually today, April 27, 2011. This dividend is approximately 70% higher than the amount we distribute to our shareholders last year and it's more than three times the dividend we paid during 2009.</p>
          <p>On April 18, we successfully issued 2.5 billion pesos in five years Certificados Burs&#xE1;tiles of peso bonds at a yield of 28-day TIIE plus 13 basis points and 2.5 billion pesos in 10-year at a fixed coupon rate of 8.27%. We will mainly use the proceeds from this issuance to pay down the maturity for our 3 billion peso bonds that matures at the beginning of next year. This issuance will not only extend our maturity profile, but also replace our cash balances after the dividends we have distributed to our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Our operations posted a positive start to the year. The strong brand equity of our portfolio beverages, our fine execution capabilities and the innovative mix of product and packaging alternative we have developed to suit our consumers' particular needs enable us to reinforce our business position in the beverage industry. We remain confident in our ability to generate increased value for our shareholders and position our company ahead of the curve.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your continued trust and support. And now I would like to open the call for any questions that you may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And your first question comes from the line of Lauren Torres with HSBC. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. H&#xE9;ctor, you mentioned this in your prepared remarks, but I was curious if you could elaborate a bit on your commodity costs outlook for the remainder of the year? You obviously talked about pressures PET and sweetener costs trending up and we've heard this from other bottlers for the year, curious about your offsets, I know you've taken pricing, is there more room for pricing or are you comfortable with your current pricing offsetting these costs increases? And also any details with respect to hedging, how do we think about you managing the costs potentially if they're still going up for the remainder of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Lauren. I guess that the environment with raw materials is not only an issue with our industry. I've seen many different companies also are commenting on this issue of pressure on raw materials. In general, I will say that the environment that we are seeing and as you perfectly know this, the two prices &#x2013; the two raw materials that we have on exposure and that are important is sweeteners and PET or packaging materials, mainly PET. Last year we saw her a lot on this <mark type="ph" /> generic (24:30) front. We believe that for 2011 sweetener costs will not present a big issue although we are seeing prices are stable, we are seeing in some markets prices slightly above last year or slightly below last year, but not a big issue with sweeteners.</p>
          <p>As we have expressed, we have basically agree with our suppliers on certain amounts of sweeteners at a certain price range that basically sets the price for, especially for <mark type="indiscernible" /> (25:16) in Mexico, around, as we mentioned last quarter, around 3% to 5% of our &#x2013; the costs we had last year. Since <mark type="indiscernible" /> (25:30) is dollar-denominated, the effect of the foreign exchange is helping us to compensate a little bit that, let's say, 5% increase in the cost of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (25:40).</p>
          <p>In the other markets, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (25:45) down the map, in Colombia and Venezuela we are seeing slightly above what we had last year. In Brazil, we are seeing prices in the marketplace similar to what we found last year, but last year we had the benefit of a very successful hedging strategy on the sweetener costs. So, therefore, when we look at our numbers, we will suffer a little bit on Brazil slightly but it is not something to worry &#x2013; I would say that sweeteners will increase a little bit higher than Mexico, than the 5% that I mentioned in Mexico because &#x2013; obviously because of the volatility and the <mark type="ph" /> moment (26:28) that we did the hedging in 2009 <mark type="indiscernible" /> (26:30) 2010. We have continued to hedge some of the sweetener costs in Brazil, but as the prices have been more stable, we don't see the benefit that we had last year of having this important element in our P&amp;L.</p>
          <p>The issue to worry this year is <mark type="ph" /> PET. PET (27:00) is increasingly important in dollar terms in most of our markets. If my memory <mark type="ph" /> has often failed to me (27:07) &#x2013; we're probably 30% to 35% above what we had by the third quarter of last year. So, it's a very important increase in <mark type="ph" /> PET (27:20) costs. That has obviously put a lot of pressure to the industry in terms of trying to pass those price increases to the consumers. And, we have seen some mixed reactions from our competitors.</p>
          <p>We have, as we &#x2013; as I mentioned during the prepared remarks, we have <mark type="ph" /> electively (27:44) increased prices in some of our portfolio, some of our presentations. And, for example, in Mexico, very importantly, after, I'd say, probably six to eight years that <mark type="ph" /> Jarritos (28:04) was with flat prices of 10 pesos for two litres, for the first time in, I believe it's close to eight years, they increased prices to 11 pesos.</p>
          <p>I think that that has to do to two factors, one that we increased prices also of our products because of the pressure on raw materials, but also that they are also being &#x2013; that they're also facing this pressure from especially <mark type="ph" /> PET (28:34). So, I think that that's a positive <mark type="ph" /> mostly (28:38) in Mexico that one of the competitors, especially in the Valley of Mexico area is moving their prices when they haven't &#x2013; they have been very reluctant to increase prices, as I've mentioned for many years.</p>
          <p>One element that is important for you to consider, Lauren, is that in the <mark type="ph" /> PET (28:59) front, remember that we have a very important mix of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:05) presentations. That's not very common in our competitors. There are some, like <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:14) in Brazil that has some <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:16) in the portfolio, but it's not very common. Most of our competitors are 100% <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:22) approach and that &#x2013; I think that that also give us certain advantage in this environment where we're seeing a lot of pressure on packaging materials.</p>
          <p>Our technicians continue to do a lot of analysis and improvements in <mark type="ph" /> light-weighting (29:48) our packages, which is a lot of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:50) they were facing. But, at the end of the day, there is &#x2013; you're put in the &#x2013; the common &#x2013; the important element is our ability to increase prices to compensate for all of these materials. We believe that we have some flexibility, as in the case of Mexico where we are seeing this improvement, improvement in the pricing and the competitors following with those price increases. <mark type="ph" /> The PepsiCo deal (30:22), we believe that, on a temporary basis, some reductions on some of the pricing in <mark type="ph" /> PET (30:30) presentation, which is going to even the pressure on <mark type="ph" /> pricings (30:35). But, we believe that in general the environment in Mexico, and I'd say the same for Venezuela, Central America and Argentina, is positive on the pricing front.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, we're seeing some pricing activity <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:51) packages that we believe are temporary and are more related to the introduction of new presentations. And, in Colombia, as we have expressed, we have a very tough competitor on flavor markets &#x2013; on the flavor segment that &#x2013; it appears that they are very concerned with the pricing strategy of Big Cola and they have been reluctant to increase prices so I'll have some question marks on Colombia in terms of our ability to increase prices, although clearly one of the signals that the operators there have is to &#x2013; are clear for us as leaders of the industry, we should be leading the way in the pricing architecture in the industry. So, we're focusing a lot on Colombia and have to improve the performance <mark type="ph" /> overall (31:52).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And, if I could just quickly follow-up on Mexico with respect to pricing, be it that you and your competitors are being rational here, are you seeing general consumer acceptance? I know you've had some good hot weather in the quarter, so curious though with respect to the health of the consumer if you think these price increases are being basically well taken?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Lauren, I think that that in general we have seen a very positive environment on the consumer in Mexico. I think that in general these price increases are <mark type="ph" /> sticking in (32:29) very well. My concern in that front is <mark type="ph" /> a little bit (32:34) again with Colombia where we believe it has to do a lot with the weather-related issues.</p>
          <p>And, as we mentioned, even though we reduced our volumes 8% for the quarter, our market share is stable or gaining a few basis points. So, it is an industry trend that we need to understand and to follow very important. Venezuela, given the fact that we have increased the price importantly because of the devaluation of the Bolivar and the increases in salaries and raw materials that we have faced there because of the macroeconomic environment, we're seeing the consumer a little bit less reluctant to accept the price increases as in Venezuela.</p>
          <p>And, in Argentina and Brazil, we &#x2013; similar to Mexico, we &#x2013; I mean, in general the industry is moving, as I mentioned, with the little exception of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:37) presentation but other than that activity &#x2013; pricing activity, we're seeing a positive environment and the consumer accepting price increases in Venezuela &#x2013; excuse me, in Brazil and Argentina.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Gustavo Oliveira with UBS. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, H&#xE9;ctor. Good morning. I have a question with respect to your operating leverage, both in Mercosur and also in Mexico. When you compare the first quarter numbers of 2011 to the first quarter of 2010, obviously I think the comparison was relatively easy because the volumes were weak in first quarter 2010. Could you please comment what you think you could see going forward in terms of operating leverage in Mexico since you've been investing a lot in your commercial model and I think perhaps this is mostly done, I don't know whether perhaps you could clarify that? And also, I think in the last call you highlighted that the focus in the Mercosur division for this year would be in trying to achieve some operating leverage from the model, obviously we saw that in the first quarter, but I think that the comparison <mark type="ph" /> base (35:07) was relatively easy, so what we could expect going forward from here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="audio gap" /> (35:12) Hi, Gustavo. As I mentioned, and you correctly pointed out, a lot of the focus of the company for 2011, a lot of the strategies and the initiatives that we are following have to do with running a more efficient company with respect to the SG&amp;A. We have, as you know, moved our strategies in terms how we go to the market importantly. We don't <mark type="ph" /> do (36:05) strategies that we have implemented in the go-to-market strategies. We're rolling out a lot of these initiatives.</p>
          <p>And, I think that in general, in Mexico &#x2013; you're pointing out correctly that maybe last year first quarter was an easy comp for Mexico and Brazil but never the less we're seeing improvements especially in Mexico with respect to the way we measure fixed costs structure and we are seeing that because of that you're starting to see a little bit more operating leverage going through to our P&amp;L. We're following every month, line by line, the fixed costs structure of our operators, and they know that they are being measured importantly this year on that front.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned last quarter, we need to focus a lot in Mercosur, in that area. In Brazil, we're facing, and I guess &#x2013; my guess is that it has to do with the whole country, we're facing a slightly higher inflationary environment than we have in the rest of the countries, that is being reflected also in salaries in Brazil. That is pushing a little bit on some of the costs and related issues in Brazil, including freight and salaries. And, in Brazil, we have one particular element which is &#x2013; and that's why we &#x2013; because &#x2013; that's the reason why we are focusing a lot in Brazil.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, we are running &#x2013; we've been growing the &#x2013; our volumes and our company importantly over the last months and the last years. And we're getting to a level where we are facing capacity constraints. We just finished the &#x2013; a few months ago the installation of two new production lines. As we have expressed, we are thinking of building a new production plant in Brazil next year. We will start working on that this year, and looking at that for 2011.</p>
          <p>And, all of that activity, when you are running close to 100% capacity, it's difficult to &#x2013; for you to get &#x2013; to trickle down all the revenue growth all the way to the bottom of the P&amp;L because you have to increase capacity. We are building the warehouses; as I mentioned, we have two new production lines; and we're starting to work and obviously carry the expenses related to all the planning and engineering of our new production plant in the state of Minas Gerais.</p>
          <p>It's true we will have some tax benefits on that &#x2013; <mark type="ph" /> some facilities (39:14), that is also one of the reasons we're building that. But the main reason is that the plant &#x2013; existing plant that we have in Belo Horizonte is no longer good for our needs there and we are paying much higher freight costs because we are <mark type="ph" /> producing 100% of (39:29) &#x2013; we are <mark type="ph" /> selling (39:30) more than 100% of our capacity in that production plant. So, clearly we feel we have the reason that we need to follow.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned, we're following month by month. We know that we are &#x2013; <mark type="ph" /> that they are dong (39:37) the effort. We state that the second half of the year we will start seeing a reflection of that as we lower our head count and reduce some of the freight cost expenses et cetera as we bettered and we grew our logistic network. And that's an effort that we need to follow.</p>
          <p>The good news is that the company continues to grow top line importantly. And although we are not improving the profitability of the wait, we should be improving, in other words, we should be improving profitability higher rate than the growth of the top line. Now those margins are staying flat compared to last year even though we are growing volumes and revenues importantly. I think that the good thing is that we shall be top line and we are working in fixing the issues that I have described, so that by the second quarter of this year, we should be improving the profitability in Brazil.</p>
          <p>I think that in general also Brazil with a slightly below 4% volume growth, clearly was a tough comparison versus last year, but slightly less than 4% growth was a little bit behind of what we were anticipating. So I think that we have some room to go back a little bit of head count et cetera because the volume was not what we were anticipating because obviously we were going through several months where volumes were growing important. So I think that there is a lot of work to do in Brazil. But I think that the main issue which is top line growth is there and we will bring the feedbacks of that in the second part of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just a follow-up on that, these additional <mark type="indiscernible" /> (41:46) in production lines and production facilities, were already done contemplated in your initial CapEx for the year? And if you could remind us of your CapEx? And if they were not contemplated, what would be the incremental CapEx that we're talking about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Last year, we were &#x2013; let me give you a picture of the CapEx moving on. If you take a look at what we had spent last year, it was around &#x2013; I'd say around $500 to $520 million last year. As we mentioned during the last quarter conference call, the numbers that we were anticipating for this year was a little bit higher probably closer to $550 million to $580 million. Now, in the last Board meeting that we have few weeks ago &#x2013; two weeks ago we presented this new production plant in <mark type="indiscernible" /> (42:42), we presented to our Board of Directors the plan for this new production plant in Brazil and also for one in Colombia. So that would probably increase our CapEx number by around $50 million to $60 million over this year probably what we carry in our plans.</p>
          <p>So in general I would say that somewhere around $600 million, $620 million will be a good number for 2011, which is higher a good $100 million above what we had last year. That's part of the reasons why we decided, given the interest rate environment that we have to issue these bonds, we have this very important dividend payment being done today. We have the maturity of these bonds at the beginning of 2012, but also we have an important CapEx story that we need to finance and given the &#x2013; what we see in this very good interest rate environment we decided to do this financing, which may be was a little bit surprising given our cash balances that we have now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Gustavo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Robert Ford with Bank of America. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey. Thank you and good afternoon everybody. Hi H&#xE9;ctor. I know it's very difficult, but in Mexico it was just a great performance and I know weather helped, but when you look at the macroeconomic aggregates, right, employment is growing very well, particularly for low income consumers and salary mass, growth is there and nominal wages are up 5% to 6% right, so I imagine this is growing low double-digits right now in Mexico. And one would think that in addition to the weather benefit, you're seeing some trade up, particularly as beer brands raise prices you mentioned, right, the first time that probably those has in many, many years and '10 is kind of a magic number, right, when it comes to the relevance of that price point. And I was curious if you could, how would you allocate your volume gains and you also have the impact of a shift in Easter, I know it affects your different territories differently, but there's a lot of moving parts. And this quarter suggests that you do have considerable pricing power, and I was wondering if you could address your expectations in terms of maybe a consumer trade-up, the strength and pricing and the ability to fully offset the additional increases you are likely to have in terms of PET please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Robert. I think that in general, your comments are correct, I mean, in Mexico we have seen a consumer that is showing us a move <mark type="indiscernible" /> (45:52) the salaries are increasing, the employment is increasing. I think that the perspective for &#x2013; every economist in Mexico is increasing their expectation of GDP growth for the year from what we have before. So I think that in general the consumer sentiment in Mexico is good. I think that we have the positive moves so the brands also increasing price, because of the pressure they are receiving.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned, Pepsi was a little surprising with a reduction in their full year Pepsi-Cola pricing, right now they are pricing below us with brand Pepsi-Cola, which is <mark type="indiscernible" /> (46:37) that's the case right now with the volume of Mexico and that we hope that is a temporary thing. So we think that in general I will say that we feel very confident with the pricing facility we have with brand Coca-Cola, with some of our juices and nectars, Vita Food &#x2013; Vita Food we have increased importantly our prices over the last &#x2013; since the introduction. And we introduce their prices 4 pesos and we are selling that for 6 pesos. It is a very substantial price increase for percentage wise, so it's certainly an important element. We think we have flexibility in some other area. Flavors, I'm a little bit worried, but given the size of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (47:26) follow with some of the price increases that we've used. I think that we're okay also in that front and as you know &#x2013; you might have noticed in the past, in the sparkling category, we always have healthy growth in brand Coco-Cola, we were struggling a little bit with flavors. So the last six months we have growth in flavors and so we need to protect and foster &#x2013; continue fostering the growth of flavors so that we don't lose momentum there. And I think that in general we will be a little bit more cautious in increasing prices in flavors. But in general, I'll say that we have a positive environment in Mexico with the consumer sentiment and the possibility of them trading up to better alternatives. For example, very successful, I'm speaking about market prices 400 milliliters of brand Coca-Cola at 5 pesos has very importantly helped in our growth in brand Coca-Cola and that's very good for our Company as we continue to increase volumes in single-serve presentations. So in general, I think that the explanations we presented is correct and that's how we are seeing the environment, the consumer environment in Mexico, Robert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And when it comes to that opening price point strategy that you have H&#xE9;ctor, whether it is the 400 milliliters or returnable glass, do you see other opportunities to kind of drive the core business in Mexico and other marketplaces with additions on the low-end?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, well I think that &#x2013; I mean, if I understand correctly your question with &#x2013; we are seeing opportunities in the single serve presentations, I mean, in Colombia and Brazil, we're doing important, I would not say introduction because these products have been there for a few months, but important inroads on revenues that were in volume growth through for example in Brazil with 250 milliliter presentation that are very important price point, which is one real, which is like a market price again. So in Colombia we're doing a little bit the same strategy. So we do think that although we're not seeing in the numbers of the first quarter because multi-serves continue to outpace single service in growth, both categories are growing but we do see that there is this possibility of us improving the pricing mix of our company by moving a little bit more volume for our single serve presentation and the consumer sentiment and the consumer focusing tools.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Robert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Lore Serra with Morgan Stanley. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just a couple of quick things. First in Mexico, the funds on the revenue line was really great. But following up on the earlier question, it looks to me like the operating expenses weren't maybe as tight as they could have been, especially since it looks like depreciation came down. So is the first quarter just an anomaly? I take your point about putting more focus on the SG&amp;A line. But how should we think about the way in which SG&amp;A in Mexico would grow this year? What's the kind of right metric to think about it?</p>
          <p>And then in Latincentro the 150 basis-point gross margin increase, I suppose a lot of that's what you referred to about taking pricing in Venezuela and cutting older raw material cost. So can you help us understand in the coming quarters what is the sort of downside risk in Latincentro because it sounds like the pricing is getting maybe a little more tough in Venezuela and maybe the raw materials will be a bit more difficult. So can you help us understand what to expect there that would be very helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Lore. Let me address first the question with what to expect. I think, I mean, we've seen some improvement in Mexico as we mentioned on the operating expenses. I think that there is still room to improve there. When you look at, for example, marketing is increasing in &#x2013; when you compare the absolute number versus last year, but in terms of &#x2013; as a percentage of revenue since it's more or less the same number. So in a way marketing is behaving like a viable expense on this quarter. You know that sometimes when we see a lot of pressure on the results we start reducing our EBITDA where marketing, this has not been the case in this quarter because we have seen positive numbers. And we are investing on some of these programs as we have done in the last 18 months to &#x2013; and what we call the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (53:23). So there is room for improvement there. When you look at these specific lines of expenses are totally fixed, we are seeing those staying fixed and not moving as we improve the volume. So that's positive when we look at what had happened in other quarters in the past, when we were growing our volumes and because of the capacity constraints, again, we were increasing some of our work force and all of that. So, the positive signal is that we are seeing that benefit, I think that there is still room to improve in Mexico in that front. In Venezuela, and Latincentro in general, I think that it is important that we comment on the serving, this was probably an atypical quarter in the sense that as you correctly pointed out, we increased 150 basis points our gross margin and that has to do a lot with the fact that in Venezuela we have the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (54:39) that was bought at a control exchange rate when at the beginning of the last year we were buying in the parallel market at substantially higher rate. That's not going to stay going forward because obviously those historic performance &#x2013; we are going to get starting this coming second quarter to a more comparable exchange rate in &#x2013; as we applied to raw materials in the second quarter versus the second quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>So, clearly that's going to put some pressure on the margins in Latincentro. The other area of worry to me is that as I mentioned during one of the comments and you also correctly pointed out this during the question. We are seeing some, let me use the word, softness in the response to &#x2013; of the consumer to price increases in Venezuela. I am not sure, still if it is fully there but we are starting to see that the prices &#x2013; that the consumer is not necessarily buying at the same pace that they were buying before because we had increased prices importantly. Also salaries have increased importantly in terms of the valuation of the bolivar and all of that and we probably <mark type="indiscernible" /> (56:05) saying that minimum wages will increase around 26% this year. So salaries have increased but prices have also increased and the consumer is little more hesitant to continue buying our product, so we need to be very careful with price increases in Venezuela going forward.</p>
          <p>In Colombia I think that the name of the game is how do we regain growth for the industry and for the country. Again I'd like to point out this issue. We are maintaining and in some categories even increasing slightly our market share numbers but volumes are down 8% versus last year. Taken that last year we had double-digit growth and all of that but &#x2013; and considering that the volume is not there and we need to focus a lot of our attention on the basic indicators and basic strategies in Colombia it has to do with per capita, as we have mentioned in many quarters, it's very low compared to other markets. It is half of what we have in Venezuela, which is a neighboring country and we haven't been able to increase the consumption per capita. So as I mentioned that the focus in Mercosur and Mexico is to continue controlling SG&amp;A, the same is true for Latincentro in Colombia, which we have the additional task of how do we take leadership in an industry where our competitors are strong in flavors. We need to take pricing leadership and start growing volumes in Colombia. So when you take into consideration all these issues, the whole environment for Latincentro for the rest of the year is a little bit tough. We'll have a tougher comparison with raw materials in Venezuela, which have the effect of salary increases, the effect of the devaluation of the bolivar, in Colombia a very soft volume that we need to continue growing so that we start seeing this operating leverage to function. Central America, we're okay. It is small but we are okay. We are improving there little by little.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, and just very quickly in Brazil, obviously the year got off to a slower start volume wise because of the weather issues. Can you give us an outlook for what you're expecting for volumes for the full year please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In general I will say that, given the competitive environment and all of that Lore, we should be seeing growth in the volume similar to GDP. I mean if you look at the consensus economies, they are looking at 5% to 6% GDP growth, we should be growing around that rate. This year, especially during carnival, which is an important season in our industry in Brazil, the weather didn't help a lot and it took everybody by surprise with some let me use the word, overcapacity in our system to tackle a larger volume that was not there because of the weather in our geographic area. But in general, I continue to see Brazil for the full year growing around 5%, 6% volume wise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>[Operator Instruction] And your next question comes from the line of Margaret Kalvar with Harding Loevner. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Yes. Good afternoon. I have a question about the cost issue in terms of the translation rate in Venezuelan currency that you were allowed to use. We'd spoken before and you had said that that was going to impact your margins in Venezuela as you had to buy at a less advantageous Venezuelan exchange rate. Was there evidence of this this quarter and if so how much or is this something that we will see in the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning, Margaret. Yes. In raw materials, I think that went through several phases in Venezuela. One, at the beginning probably the first half of last year when we &#x2013; we didn't have full access to the so-called controlled exchange rate that last year was around 2.6, that was the control rate. But since we didn't have full access to that some of the raw materials we were buying in the pilot market at close to 6 bolivars or 7 bolivars per dollar.</p>
          <p>Then we had the devaluation of the bolivar and the control rate move from 2.6 to 4.3 and we were buying &#x2013; but we have plenty of availability of dollars to buy at that exchange rate, the 4.3. So this first quarter we are basically comparing raw materials that we have bought at around 4.3 bolivars per dollar versus raw materials we're buying at around 6 bolivars or 7 bolivars per dollar in the pilot market.</p>
          <p>So that's why we say second quarter we'll see a little bit more pressure on the cost of raw materials because the comparison will not be as favorable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So the reality was that last year first quarter despite the officially better rate since you couldn't get it all at the good rate you ended up buying at a much less advantageous rate then you were able to this year, but from now on we should see more of an impact?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That's correct, Margaret.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's exactly correct. What you are saying is correct. We were buying even though the official exchange was lower, we didn't have access for 100% of our raw materials at that rate and we were buying &#x2013; it's not a black market it's what's called the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (62:58) market, it's official but with very high exchange rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But in order to continue rolling our <mark type="indiscernible" /> (63:05) &#x2013; we were forced to buy that or otherwise we have to stop production <mark type="indiscernible" /> (63:12) raw materials.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Margaret.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next was income from the line of Antonio Gonzalez with Credit Suisse. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, H&#xE9;ctor. Thanks for taking my question. I just want to make a follow-up on Brazil and I wanted to see if you can focus on the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (63:35) 5% to 6% growth in volume that you are expecting for the rest of the year, does incorporate scenario of higher taxes? And if you can give us an update on whether you would try to pass through any higher taxes to the final customer or you would try to eventually absorb some of that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Antonio. It's a good question. I mean, we have probably &#x2013; we should have mentioned that also in the remarks, we had in this first quarter an official increase on the Value Added Taxes that was very impressive, taxes on consumption. That basically had an impact in our business so that in order to fully compensate that tax increase so that it's neutral for us we had to increase prices around 3% to 4% &#x2013; 3.5%. And then we'll take the profitability of our business to the same level that we had. We have already done that increase and the industry has done that increase. So in general, that also had a slight impact on &#x2013; in addition to the weather &#x2013; to the soft volume that we saw during the first quarter, because the industry in general was passing this price increase &#x2013; this tax increase was passed to the consumer as a price increase. So that everyone has this number in mind. Basically, in order to fully compensate for tax &#x2013; this tax increase that we have, it's equivalent to around 3.5% increases on prices. And we have already done that in our products, as well as our competitors. So going forward, we still believe that we can reach the 5%, 6% volume growth for the year. Obviously, that assumes that there are no more surprises on the taxing front, which is always a question in <mark type="indiscernible" /> (65:56).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, perfect. Thank you, H&#xE9;ctor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Antonio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jos&#xE9; Yord&#xE1;n with Deutsche Bank. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. Just a quick question more about the long-term about the M&amp;A et cetera. I mean, I guess you could argue that &#x2013; that some of the costs pressures in the last year or two have been the catalyst for M&amp;A, maybe <mark type="indiscernible" /> (66:24) that's what brought them together finally. And how do you think about this &#x2013; is this something that's continuing to bring sellers to the negotiating table with you?</p>
          <p>The strong dollar is not going to last forever and maybe these pressures will continue over the next couple of years. So how is this making it more or less likely that we'll have M&amp;A, significant M&amp;A in the next year or two? And does the spike in CapEx in 2011 have any bearing on whatever you're doing on the M&amp;A side? And for that matter on the dividend policy for next year, should we expect flat dividends next year as a result of the &#x2013; of this spike in CapEx this year? But more interested in the trade off between this and the M&amp;A plans.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. It was a good question. I think that it's very difficult to know what really triggered the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (67:27) consolidation. But one thing is for certain, I think that my perception is that in Mexico and in general in Latin America, everyone is looking at that transaction and doing an internal analysis and reviewing the <mark type="ph" /> bio-reserves (67:45) you have mentioned, the cost pressures that you have, the strong currencies that we have in some of these markets that in theory will help compare a larger dollar amount in a transaction value.</p>
          <p>So in general, I'll say that because of the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (68:10) transaction, I think that we will see a new wave of at least some curiosity from some of the owners to look at a potential transaction that will be positive for the mentioned environment. Second, I don't think that given our financial position, the heavier capital expenditure program we have this year would have any impact on the M&amp;A front. I think that we have plenty of financing capacity to do large transactions and it's important to point out also that if the <mark type="ph" /> Arca contal (69:00) transaction serves as an indicator it's probably &#x2013; it's a problem that some of these transaction would also be driven &#x2013; will be done more as mergers more than an outright purchases of the owner and maybe they would require some cash element there but that's also <mark type="indiscernible" /> (69:26).</p>
          <p>And I think that, obviously for the shareholders to approve next year that after improving our dividend payout ratio importantly as we mentioned during my remarks we basically have increased dividend compared to a couple of years ago like 3.2 times, so that's a very large increase. We feel that now we are paying a dividend yield of around 2.5%, which is pretty much comparable to a lot of the deals but on the other hand we have a capital structure that is inefficient because we &#x2013; as we also reflected in the remarks and in the press releases, we are getting very close to zero debt situation in our company.</p>
          <p>So the recommendation of management to our Board of Directors will continue to be that if we don't have a &#x2013; indicate we don't have a specific M&amp;A transaction in the short or medium-term then we should continue to increase the dividend so that we pay the capital structure of the companies for some more effective &#x2013; more efficient capital structure where we'll be putting some leverage there and also <mark type="indiscernible" /> (71:00) at the end of the day that would be my recommendation, I think that our CEO is more or less in the same page and at the end of the day it will be the Board of Directors to approve and obviously the shareholders for final approval though.</p>
          <p>But in general, my message is, I'll say, if we have any M&amp;A transactions, we broadly stay with dividends of the year, if we don't have M&amp;A transactions in the medium-term or in the short-term, we should be looking at our increases in the dividend payout ratio broadly not at the pace that we have seen with dollar in last year and now increasing 70%, was continued to increase little by little on the yield that we are paying now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's great. But it sounds like a bit like, a few months ago maybe six months ago when you were looking at Ecuador, that seemed like you had a couple of things in the short-term analysis, under analysis and that for a while then the sort of plate became empty. It sounds like its &#x2013; like it would beginning to be more active in that area at this point. It sounds like there's more people accepting to meet with you guys et cetera in Mexico, hopefully and perhaps elsewhere. Am I reading you correctly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we'll say that &#x2013; we don't have a strategic thing right now in the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (72:39) this is my interpretation of the situation in Latin America. As you say, it was &#x2013; the exchange rate being favorable, cost pressures in some of the &#x2013; for this is one thing that I'd like to point out is that we have been very active in the M&amp;A front constantly. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (73:05) could have been many years ago, but then three years ago <mark type="indiscernible" /> (73:10) business in Colombia, we increased <mark type="indiscernible" /> (73:17) our neighbor to look at a couple of years ago <mark type="indiscernible" /> (73:21) with reagard our company two years ago, we just closed last month the acquisition of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (73:28) Panama. So we have been very active <mark type="indiscernible" /> (73:32) are not very large. I think that we will need a specific financing or leverage in the company because of that. But my projection is that we will continue to be active. And I think that there is a positive environment in the minds of the owners. That's my projection. If I were there, I would be looking at <mark type="indiscernible" /> (74:00) the example of the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (74:02) and that's creating, in my opinion, everyone should be now looking at their own internal numbers and see if that, is this the right moment to merge or to sell or do something.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, that's great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question come from the line of Alan Alanis with JPMorgan. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much. Hi, H&#xE9;ctor, thanks for taking the question. It's regarding Mercosur, I don't know you've commented in the prepared remarks or if I missed it, but did you comment anything regarding the surge in the D&amp;A, the increase in D&amp;A in Mercosur, because if we isolate that increase the margins of Mercosur where the EBITDA margin would have been stable. So I was wondering number one, what is it &#x2013; what's causing this and how should we think about modeling the appreciation and amortization for the remaining of the year. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, please stand by. Your conference called will resume shortly.</p>
          <p>H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o, you may proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry for the inconvenience. We have cut off I don't what technical difficulty we had. Alan, are you still there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's why I am here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry about that. I just want to say I don't know where we lost you but then we noticed that the line was cut off. In Brazil, in Mercosur in general, we have &#x2013; but especially Brazil, we have two production lines that I mentioned that we introduced because of the capacity constraints, because of the growth that we had experienced in the past. It is a good product to have but it also generates CapEx and therefore depreciation and amortization. This program that we call <mark type="indiscernible" /> (77:31). It's a very important coolers program that we have introduced at a very fast pace with heavy investments in tens of millions of dollars in coolers that is also producing some increase in depreciation and amortization. And also the other element as you knows that has been very successful for us even for anoptional of returnable package. As you know the presentation that we introduced into the turnover packages help us a lot to grow brand Coca-Cola and to gain importantly market share. But obviously we are suffering a little bit from that &#x2013; from the effect of amortization of these packaging materials. But I will say those are the three main elements that are there. In general, I will say that the 2009 we had the normal amortization as <mark type="indiscernible" /> (78:36) that. I mentioned that we're going to invest in a new production facility in Brazil that will create some additional depreciation and amortization there for next year.</p>
          <p>The coolers, I think that we are now more in a more normalized investment in cooler program out of this spice that we had last year for this strategy. And the turnovers in general we are seeing a more stable replenishing the bottleneck that we have, so we are not seeing important increases in introduction in turnover presentation, now that we have got up to an appropriate level there. Those are the three main elements that is causing this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That is very clear. So basically it is we should think about a new level of DNA for Mercosur. Thank you. One last question, regarding market share in Brazil going forward, and I know that the objective is always to maintain or increase market share while you are increasing profitability but as you roll out new returnable presentations, your main competitor in Brazil is doing the same.</p>
          <p>We're also seeing the entrance of new <mark type="ph" /> B brands (79:54). What should be the thinking? And what you mentioned regarding the 5% to 6% volume growth for Brazil in 2011, what's the thinking internally regarding the balance if needed going forward regarding giving a little bit of market share in search of maintaining or expanding the profitability of the margins in Brazil specifically but in all of Mercosur verses saying you know what we are expecting capacity, we've brought in new two lines into service, we must use them and we're going to defend that market share and we might see some weakness in pricing in Mercosur going forward.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="audio gap" /> (80:40).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think that it is a tough question because it's something that we need to be judging basically day-by-day. Now it is a tough balance, obviously, as you correctly pointed out it's the general objective is to maintain or to slightly increase our markets, we don't want to be &#x2013; to create a very adverse reaction for our competitors as we start to increase market share is important. So as a general strategy, maintaining the market share is important.</p>
          <p>If that starts to create a conflict with profitability, our general vision as a general statement is, we'll sacrifice a little bit of market share in order to increase our profitability. But that also has a limit because then we will start to enroll &#x2013; if you lose a lot of market share just start to enroll your staying power in the future. It's important that you stay with the exact preference on the market share that you've got, which is a very tough question that I hope that I have answered with those two general comments.</p>
          <p>As a general principle, maintaining market share or increase it slightly is desirable. But if that starts to be conflict with profitability, we'll sacrifice a little bit on that in order to get profitability but also to a certain element. So <mark type="indiscernible" /> (82:24).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Now the answer is certainly helps. Thank you so much H&#xE9;ctor. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your last question comes from the line of Celso S&#xE1;nchez with Citi. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi. So I'll try to keep this brief, I know the calls has went long, just with some of the news that we're hearing again about the potential movement in ownership of <mark type="indiscernible" /> (82:47) in Brazil. Can you remind us what your view is on the role of beer in your business? And whether you think, obviously one of the names being thrown around is potentially is still &#x2013; is Heineken being interested if &#x2013; would you rather have more access to beer and if it's market share became available through your partner?</p>
          <p>And would that help your business or was there a scarce chance to reconsider that all the progress you've made on return ability in the portfolio, evolution and the magic price point and so forth, would there be a chance to maybe consider focusing more on soft drinks. I guess the question is net-net is more beer better or is there a chance to actually focus more on soft drinks if your partner goes that route?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, Celso. It's again a tough question as the previous one, it's very difficult to judge from without having all the elements of a certain moment and without &#x2013; looking at the environment at that precise moment if beer would help or not, in your strategy going forward.</p>
          <p>So far on this stage, I'll tell you that since FEMSA <mark type="indiscernible" /> (84:08) was the owner of <mark type="ph" /> Kaiser (84:11), and now will kindly keep <mark type="indiscernible" /> (84:13) general, the comments of all the bottlers, the Coca-Cola bottlers in Brazil including <mark type="indiscernible" /> (84:22) is that the margins for distributing those products is not very good. There are lot of conversations in terms of the owner with respect to changing our relatice commercial relationship between the beer company and the soft drink company as to change our EBITDA the margin of this <mark type="indiscernible" /> (84:48) and this conversations continue <mark type="indiscernible" /> (84:50).</p>
          <p>It's an important element because our competitor has a very important position &#x2013; market position with our competitor, meaning, our soft drink competitor, it's a very important beer player in Brazil. So, it's also that's what creates a lot of difficulty in sharing a very precise answer.</p>
          <p>Beer strategy in Brazil is important to where &#x2013; totally because the competitor, it's very important in beer. But so far for the last two or three years, in general the complain from the bottler sees that the margin that we get for distributing beer. It's reliable and we need to improve that relationship.</p>
          <p>How that will turn out into future is <mark type="indiscernible" /> (85:48) will play a role &#x2013; it's really complex for to try to answer at this moment, because I don't have the answer like not that I don't want to share with you. But we look at those strategies and from our perspective &#x2013; from FEMSA perspective is lot of those beers brings to the table for us in terms of market strength in terms of serving better our clients, which are the retailers.</p>
          <p>And does this bring to table, these our competitors that is very strong in the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (86:28) and if we have or not have a weakness, because our presence &#x2013; larger presence or low presence in there.</p>
          <p>So those are the variable that we need to look everyday basically <mark type="indiscernible" /> (86:48). It's a very important competitive element. We cannot still discuss the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (86:58) and we need to look at ways of improving our profits from selling beer no.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think we all have always been under the assumption that beer is very important but your results in soft drinks relative to your competitors results in soft drinks seem to suggest that even with a portfolio that is not as strong perhaps as theirs on the beer side, you seem to be doing so well. So I was just wondering if perhaps, you have an opportunity to reevaluate that, does your contract allow you &#x2013; is there any stipulation in the contract that allows you to reconsider before certain point of time, if you can remind us how long the contract with Heineken is for and how often are you usually to renew or alter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's an important point because I don't remember exactly but we have filed like 16 &#x2013; 15 or 16 years more of a contract that we have to sell beer and in the other hand, Heineken will have to sell through the Coca-Cola system for the next 15 year or 17, I don't remember exactly the years unless if both parties agree. You are correct, we are doing great a job in soft drinks. I think that some of that moment that our competitor is doing in terms of return ability and all of that is precisely because we are being very successful in soft drinks, even though we have not as strong portfolio of beers compared to our competitors. So you can argue that we don't need the beer but so far we have tied up with these agreements at least for the next 15 years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and there is no --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Unless both parties agreed all the ways long.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>There is not specific of event clause that their ownership of your broadens or something or there is a transaction, there is no changes, I guess it would be change of control here, but there is no &#x2013; nothing obvious that would relate to the potential acquisition of another brewer as would be case <mark type="indiscernible" /> (89:05) that would allow you to reevaluate the contract, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I will come to you. I don't remember if there is any change of control, especially <mark type="indiscernible" /> (89:13) but I will review on that one and if there is any specific opportunity there we will certainly share with you but I don't think that there is any &#x2013; there is no easy way out of doing these and don't get me wrong, it is not that we want to get out, it is we'd like to improve the profitability of selling beer, and its an important element, it is an important number in our revenues, our profit but we have seen that given the effort we have and these are these what we make in terms of profits in solving, I think that we should improve the profitability in here, in our operation and that's the negotiation that we need to continue carrying out with Heineken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time, we have no further questions, I would like to turn the call back over to Mr. H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o for any closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you all of you for your interest in the company. We now stay a little bit longer and obviously to say, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (90:21) will be available to answer any questions that you might have in the coming weeks and days. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>