<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1264396" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-10-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3057</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o Gutierrez, Chief Financial and Administrative Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst">Lauren Torres</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Robert Ford</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Lore Serra</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Alfredo Fern&#xE1;ndez</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Alex Robarts</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Jose Yordan</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and welcome to Coca-Cola FEMSA's Third Quarter 2009 Earnings Results Conference Call. As a reminder, today's conference is being recorded. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /></p>
          <p>During this conference call, management may discuss certain forward-looking statements concerning Coca-Cola FEMSA's future performance, and should be considered as good faith estimates made by the company. These forward-looking statements reflect management expectations and are based upon currently available data. Actual results are subject to future events and uncertainties, which can materially impact the company's actual performance.</p>
          <p>At this time I will now turn the conference over to Mr. H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o, Coca-Cola FEMSA's CFO. Please go ahead, Mr. Trevi&#xF1;o.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone and thank you for joining us today. Our strong Jugos del Valle portfolio brands in a wide array of presentations, the continued growth of with new line of business across Latin America and the price increases that we have implemented in our territories produced another quarter of strong top and bottom line results for our company under still difficult consumer and economic environment.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated revenues reached more than Ps. 26 billion, up more than 30% from the third quarter of 2008. Organic growth, driven by the higher volumes and pricing accounted for more than 55% of our incremental revenues. The effect of a positive exchange rate translation resulting from the depreciation of the Mexican peso against our operations' local currencies contribute more than 40% of our incremental revenues and the consolidation of Brisa in Colombia represented less than 5% of our incremental revenues.</p>
          <p>Excluding acquisition of Brisa and on a currency neutral basis our company is achieving more than 17% organic revenue growth in the recessionary economic environment.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated sales volume rose more than 7% year-over-year. Excluding Brisa, our consolidated sales volume increased more than 5% during the quarter. This increase was mainly driven by the growth of sparkling beverages in Mexico and the still beverage portfolio in all of our divisions.</p>
          <p>Our gross profit increased more than 28% in the third quarter of 2009. Higher revenues partially compensated for our higher costs of goods sold which resulted mainly from one, the effect of the devaluation of our local currencies as applied to our U.S. dollar denominated raw material cost; and two, higher year-over-year sweetener cost across our operations; and third, the third and final stage of the scheduled Coca-Cola Company increase in concentrate prices in Mexico.</p>
          <p>The lower cost of resin partially compensated for all these factors. Our gross margin declined 110 basis points during the third quarter of 2009. Our consolidated operating income improved 24% to Ps. 4 billion in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>Revenue growth partially compensated for higher operating expenses mainly due to higher marketing investments in our Mexico and Latincentro divisions combined with higher labor cost in Venezuela and Argentina. The effect of our positive currency translation resulting from the depreciation of the Mexican peso against our operational local currencies provided approximately 45% of our incremental operating income and the consolidation of Brisa in Colombia accounted for approximately 10% of our incremental operating income for this quarter. Excluding the acquisition of Brisa and on a currency neutral basis our consolidated operating income would have grown more than 10%.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated operating margin declined 100 basis points year-over-year to 15.2% for the quarter. Our consolidated EBITDA rose 24%, reaching Ps. 5 billion in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, our net consolidated income increased more than 70% to Ps. 2.1 billion, mainly due to high operating income recorded in the third quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Now let me expand on our operations. Our Mexico division delivered close to double digit volume growth in the third quarter of 2009, successfully improving the volume growth we presented in the second quarter of 2009 which was the highest growth recorded by our Mexico division in more than three years.</p>
          <p>Our sales volume of sparkling beverages grew 8% driven by a double digit volume increase in brand Coca-Cola. In both multi-serve and single serve presentations, that more than compensated for a low single digit decline in our flavored sparkling beverage sales volume.</p>
          <p>Distilled beverage category, mainly driven by the Jugos del Valle beverage portfolio, grew more than 80% during the quarter, reaching more than 60 million unit cases. Our successful Valle Frut product line accounted for more than 90% of the incremental growth in this category and have help us to consolidate our leadership position in the orangeade segment in Mexico in a short period of time.</p>
          <p>Our water business grew close to 5% during the quarter. Our single serve water segment increased more than 8% and our bottled water segment grew 4%, driven by the expansion of our jug water business in the body of Mexico.</p>
          <p>Our average price per unit case increased 2.6% during the quarter. This increase was mainly driven by higher volumes of brand Coca-Cola in both multi-serve and single serve presentations, combined with the average price increases implemented last year in our Coca-Cola portfolio. These increases was partially offset by higher volumes of jug water and the Valle Frut orangeade products which carry a lower average price per unit case.</p>
          <p>Our Mexican operations total revenue increased more than 12%. Incremental volumes accounted for close to 75 of our total incremental revenues. On the profitability front higher cost of goods sold was mainly driven by the devaluation of the Mexican peso as applied to our dollar denominated raw material cost. And the third and final stage of the annual increase in concentrate prices agreed upon with our partner, the Coca-Cola Company in 2006. Lower year-over-year resin prices partially compensated for these increases.</p>
          <p>Our gross profit reached Ps. 4.7 million, growing close to 7% as compared to third quarter of 2008. Our gross margin in Mexico decreased 260 basis points. Our operating income remained flat at Ps. 1.7 million. Our operating margin declined 220 basis points reaching 17.7% mainly due to gross margin pressures. Our EBITDA grew 1% compared with the third quarter of last year, reaching Ps. 2.1 million.</p>
          <p>Our Mexican product portfolio is one of our industry's most complete beverage offering in the world. We are able to target all consumption locations successfully with our different various categories and presentations and at the same time outperform in an adverse economic environment.</p>
          <p>Over the past months, we have bolstered our marketplace initiatives. We have increased the availability of our sparkling beverage in returnable multi and single serve presentations. We have enhanced our execution across the Mexico division, increasing our cooler covers, and during the third quarter, we successfully re-launched Coca-Cola Zero. These initiatives supported our solid growth for the quarter, especially in the sparkling beverage category.</p>
          <p>At the same time, we have been investing to capture future growth opportunities in our industry, relying heavily on our novelty still beverage portfolio to accelerate growth. We will continue analyzing the pricing architecture of our portfolio, considering the economic conditions and competitive dynamics to evaluate making potential price increases in the coming months to offset expected local inflation.</p>
          <p>Our Latincentro division post double digit volume growth. This increase was driven by the integration of our recently acquired Brisa bottled water business in Colombia, the continued strong performance of our still beverage portfolio Colombia and Central America and the growth of sparkling beverages in Central America and Colombia.</p>
          <p>In Venezuela, price increases implemented over the past 12 months designed to compensate for local inflation produced a low single-digit decline in volumes. In Colombia the still beverage category continued to post significant growth, reaching more than four million unit cases in the third quarter. This growth was driven by the Jugos del Valle line of beverages. Sparkling beverages recorded a low single-digit volume growth despite important price increases implemented in this territory over the past 12 months.</p>
          <p>In Central America, we recorded sales volume growth of more than 6% compared with the third quarter of 2008. This increase was mainly driven by the mid single-digit volume growth in sparkling beverages and more than 30% growth in our still beverage portfolio.</p>
          <p>Our Latincentro division's total revenues grew more than 70% year-over-year, reaching Ps. 9.8 million. Our organic revenue growth driven by higher volumes and average price per unit case accounted for approximately 50% of our incremental revenues. A positive currency translation resulting from the depreciation of the Mexican peso against our operation's local currencies representing approximately &#x2013; represented approximately 45% of our incremental revenues and the integration of Brisa accounted for the balance.</p>
          <p>On a currency neutral basis and excluding the acquisition of Brisa, our Latincentro division revenues would have increased approximately 35%. On the profitability front the Latincentro division's gross profit increased more than 70% to Ps. 4.5 million. The lower cost of resin partially compensated for the higher cost of sweetener across the division. Our gross margin reached 45.4%, an expansion of 30 basis points compared with the third quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Our operating income grew 70% reaching Ps. 1.3 billion. Higher revenues compensated for increased operating expenses which were mainly driven by marketing investments to support our growing still beverage platform and the Brisa water brand combined with higher label cost in Venezuela. The effect of a positive currency translation resulting from the depreciation of the Mexican peso against our operational local currencies accounted for close to 40% of our incremental operating income, and Brisa accounted for approximately 15% of our incremental operating income for the quarter. Excluding the acquisition of Brisa and on a currency neutral basis, our operating income grew more than 30%.</p>
          <p>Our operating margin expanded to 20 basis points to 13.2% as compared with the third quarter of 2008. Our EBITDA grew more than 60% to Ps. 1.6 million.</p>
          <p>Our Latincentro division is an important driver of our company's growth. Over the past 12 months we have expanded various categories in which we'll participate and reinforce our position in the water segment through the acquisition of Brisa. Our sparkling beverage portfolio has continued to grow despite increased pricing which shall help us to compensate for local inflation.</p>
          <p>Our Mercosur division total revenues grew more than 20% to Ps. 6.6 billion in the third quarter of 2009. Excluding beer which accounted for Ps. 642 million our total revenues reached Ps. 5.9 billion. Organic growth mainly driven by higher average prices per unit case represented more than 35% of our incremental revenues and the effect of a positive currency translation resulting from the depreciation of the Mexican peso against our operation's local currencies provided by this.</p>
          <p>Volume growth in our Mercosur division was up close to 1% in the third quarter of 2009. Our sales volume of still beverages across the division compensated for a slight decline in the sparkling beverages.</p>
          <p>Our Mercosur division's volume grew despite high single digit price increases implemented over the past 12 months in Brazil and Argentina and bad weather conditions during the quarter. Growth in the still beverage category was mainly driven by the integration of Jugos del Valle line of products in Brazil and the continued strong performance of our Aquarius, our flavored water brand in Argentina. The division's volume of still beverage grew more than 50%.</p>
          <p>On the profitability front, our Mercosur division's gross profit increased 21% to Ps. 2.9 billion. Our cost of goods sold increased as a result of higher cost of sweetener in Brazil and the devaluation of the local currencies as applied to our U.S. dollar denominated raw material costs. The lower cost of resin partially compensated for all these factors.</p>
          <p>Our gross margin increased 20 basis points to 43.8% in the third quarter of 2009. Our operating income increased 28% to Ps. 959 million. Operating leverage driven by higher revenues more than compensated for our increased cost of goods sold and higher labor and freight cost in Argentina.</p>
          <p>The effect of a positive currency translation during &#x2013; resulting from the depreciation of the Mexican peso against our operations' local currencies accounted for more than 55% of our incremental operating income. On a currency neutral basis, operating income would have grown more than 12%. Our operating margin increased 90 basis points year-over-year to 14.6%.</p>
          <p>Our EBITDA grew more than 30% to Ps. 1.2 billion. In our Mercosur division, we are strengthening our efforts to build our total beverage portfolio, taking advantage of the opportunities we see in the underdeveloped still beverage category through the Jugos del Valle platform. In the sparkling beverage categories, we have been able to implement important price increases in our markets' local currencies and further develop our returnable base.</p>
          <p>As economic conditions gradually improve, we believe that our consumer will be able to balance their disposable income and increase their spending on our products.</p>
          <p>Now let's talk about our financial performance for the quarter. During the first nine months of the year, we have witnessed difficult macroeconomic conditions. Under these circumstances, our company has been able to deliver strong cash flow generation. As of September 30, 2009, we had a cash balance of Ps. 8.9 billion, an increase of Ps. 2.7 billion compared with year-end 2008.</p>
          <p>Our gross debt decreased Ps. 2.9 billion compared with year-end 2009. Considering the proceeds of the bond issuance made at the beginning of the year in the amount of Ps. 2 billion, we have been able to decrease our gross debt, mainly driven by our July payment of a dollar denominated Yankee bond in the amount of $265 million and a Mexican pesos bond in the amount of Ps. 500 million and our September pre-payment of local currency debt in Colombia for an amount equivalent to $170 million. As a result of these factors, our net debt decreased by Ps. 5.6 billion in the first nine months of the year.</p>
          <p>The strong cash flow generation that we have achieved during the year have enabled us to invest $46 million to finance our share of the Brisa water business acquisition in February, pay dividends to our shareholders in the amount of Ps. 1.3 million in April, meet the previously mentioned debt maturities and yield stronger cash position. As of September 30, our last 12 months net debt-to-EBITDA coverage ratio was below 0.4 times, underscoring our strong financial position. Our net debt as of September 30, 2009 was Ps. 6.7 billion.</p>
          <p>This quarter, our company demonstrated once again its ability to deliver solid top and bottom line results based on our balanced geographic platform of franchise territories across Latin America, the strong brand equity from our products, the benefit of our acquisition and new avenues of growth, and our talented team of professionals.</p>
          <p>We positively see that our product portfolio behaves in a very defensive fashion and continues to post important volume growth in the working markets despite the lack of economic growth lower. As we enter the final part of the year, our company is in a very strong operating and financial position to capture the opportunities that we foresee in our industry in the coming years, relying on our proven ability to manage our business under difficult circumstances and at the same time take advantage of the economic turnaround whenever it comes.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your continued trust and support and now I would like to open the call for any questions that you may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from the line of Antonio Gonzalez with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Good morning everyone. I have two questions if I may. My first question is on Argentina and this potential increase in excise taxes. Could you please give us some color on how likely do you think this increase is to materialize? And what kind of impact would this have on your cash flows generated in that country? And do you think any potential tax hike could be eventually passed on to final consumers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Antonio , good morning. Well, at every end of the year we have a little bit of this history now that when every government in the country that we operate are looking to their budgets for next year. In the case of Argentina, there have been some conversations about potential excise taxes. Remember that we had that situation in the past. It was reduced substantially a few years ago and the idea is that in Argentina, given the difficulties we have to increase prices because of the intention of the government to control the inflation and the authorization that we need to get for any price increases. We believe that if we have some tax increases, we will have the perfect excuse to ask the authorities for authorization to price increase. We believe that the industry is in the same page, so we don't think that we will have a competitive problem. But &#x2013; and again I believe that the whole industry will be looking to the authorities to try to pass this increase to the consumer. By the same token, we don't have clarity still of which way this potential tax increase might go, it is still kind of in the air.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And secondly I'd like to ask you on this increased collaboration or integration you've got with FEMSA Cerveza lately. Could you give us an update on where you are right now? You've talked in the past, I think, about sharing marketing intelligence, best ways to serve your clients and so forth. Could you quantify some of these results achieved lately? And how do you expect this project to evolve in the future, especially in light of this potential consolidation that we're seeing for FEMSA Cerveza?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Antonio . What we have &#x2013; what we have seen in Mexico is where we are a bunch, you know that Brazil we have a natural collaboration of beer and soft drinks because that's the way it has been since we arrived to Brazil. And Brazil is a separate animal.</p>
          <p>Let me refer you a bit to what we have been doing in Mexico. Over the years we have been trying to do a lot of integration of back offices and procurement and I think that those stories have been successfully implemented in the past in terms of doing some of the easy things that you can do together with different industries like sharing all of these back offices' activities. The main focus on the marketplace has been some pilot tests that we have been doing in the state of Michoac&#xE1;n in Mexico, where we have been integrating a few routes. But these are very, very minor pilot project.</p>
          <p>In total, we have around seven pre-sellers in the city of Michoac&#xE1;n that are doing sales effort for beer and soft drinks. And those seven pre-sellers have the &#x2013; are being served by three distribution routes that are attending these clients together. As you can imagine, because of the presence of soft drinks in the marketplace in Mexico, not all of the clients that we serve with soft drinks are necessarily clients for beer. As a matter of fact, it's a very small number of clients, it's probably close to 20, 25% of the clients we serve in these specific territories that we are been doing these pilot tests.</p>
          <p>And so far I think that the numbers are not conclusive, but you see some optimization of the routes, because you gain scale and you get a little more of presence for good products and all of that. It's important that I clarify that this is a pilot test that we are doing in the state of Michoac&#xE1;n and the idea is that we should continue with this testing now.</p>
          <p>With respect to the press release that FEMSA did a few weeks ago, I know that they have their conference call tomorrow and it's appropriate for them to answer any question related to this situation tomorrow. From our perspective, we will continue with these tests and continue to sharing these results with the guys from FEMSA Cerveza as they come about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. That's very helpful. And congratulations on your results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Lauren Torres with HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everyone. H&#xE9;ctor, in your press release you mentioned that the economic environment has improved recently, and I was just curious to get your thoughts across your markets, where you're seeing these improvements? And as it relates to the consumer environment, how things have changed, I guess, for the better of the last quarter or two? And I guess as we kind of round out this year and think about next year, how you're thinking about sentiment and how you're thinking about potentially stronger growth coming from your markets?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Lauren, good morning. We had a lot of debate internally, we should stress something like that in the press release. But I guess the general conclusion was that we are starting to see some turnaround. It varies market by market. I'm &#x2013; I've been more concerned on the turnaround in Mexico, and direct with the markets we are seeing a little bit more improvement in some of the economic indicators.</p>
          <p>But in general, in Mexico we feel that given the proximity to the U.S. markets and the importance of the U.S. market to Mexico and some of the preliminary &#x2013; some of the data that we have seen in the U.S., we believe that next year we'll start to seeing some growth. But it was a difficult quarter. In general, we believe that the consumer in Mexico, that we have benefited from the fact that the consumer stopped spending a lot of &#x2013; on durable goods and that helped the consumer to have a little bit more disposable income for products like us, for consumer goods like our business.</p>
          <p>And our hypothesis is that it is the reverse case in Brazil where there was a lot of stimulus going into durable goods, and the consumer started to take a little more debt and spending on cars and a little domestics. And because of that and maybe a little bit because of the weather, we saw volumes basically very flattish in Brazil. We have seen some statistics where you see this correlation of durable goods versus consumer goods under this trend where you see in Brazil a bit more spending on these durable goods and less on the consumer goods. I think that that's basically the general perception that we are seeing in our markets.</p>
          <p>Colombia, we are seeing good economic activity. Venezuela as always is our &#x2013; as always obviously our focus is continue working all of our supply chain without the problems we have and surprises that we have every day. And Central America, after two very difficult quarters, we finally are seeing a third quarter that is improving in general. I think that Central America suffered a lot from remittances much more than what happens in countries like Mexico.</p>
          <p>The big question in Mexico is what is going to happen with all this tax package that is still being debated? And I think that that would be a &#x2013; once we have that we'll have a clearer picture of how fast are we going to get out of this situation in Mexico.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I could just ask you to clarify, as far as Brazil's concerned, seeing that flat volume or flattish volume in the quarter, do you feel that was more reflective of the pricing actions you took? Or you are seeing some change in consumer behavior there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's a little bit of both, Lauren. We took some pricing, but we definitely believe and that's why we mentioned that's an hypothesis that we have more, because we don't have necessarily all the proof here still, that the consumer dedicated a big amount of resources to durable goods because of the support that the government was giving to cars on a domestic investment to &#x2013; so that &#x2013; as a way of avoiding the major heat on those industries. So I think that that is a combination of things that we, having a pricing activity, an important pricing activity both in Argentina and Brazil, but especially in Brazil because of these subsidies that went to cars on the domestic side we believe that the consumers refocus some of their resources to this industry as opposed to ours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right. That's helpful, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Robert Ford with Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good day everybody and thank you for taking my call, H&#xE9;ctor. I had a question with respect to your comments on Morelia, and you seemed very tentative and you were very careful to say this is just three distribution routes and seven pre-sellers. But when I read the comment on the first page attributed to Carlos Salazar, he seems to be excited about the development of and deployment of new go-to-market models which will enable you to maximize your clients' revenue potential. And I'm curious, I mean, is it really that tentative in terms of Mexico, in terms of is the improvement in terms of traction and profitability just marginal? Or are you excited about it? Because I would suspect that if you have an opportunity to do this anywhere, it's Mexico where you have the &#x2013; potentially the biggest gains in terms of what you can do for the point of sale, what you can do in terms of investments in the point of sale, what you've can do in terms of synergies particularly with the market shares distributed across the country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think that there are two elements here, Robert. And one is related to this what I explained, this final test in Morelia which as I mentioned is small in scale, because it's only these three distribution routes and seven pre-sellers. But what we are referring here is as we understood that the industry what's moving to a much larger number of SKU within the soft drink industry, and that we understood and tested in the past that the industry was also moving to healthier alternatives and the importance of water. And then the next stage was juices and still drinks, and you see how important these other categories have contribute to growth.</p>
          <p>All our sales and distribution efforts start getting a lot of complexity without taking any merit to the production facilities that are also very complex because of the numbers of SKUs and how you work inefficiencies. Now when you look at the numbers of Coca-Cola FEMSA for many years, you see that we have been broadly benchmarking types of execution in several areas. In production efficiencies, and when you look at the number of unique cases that we produce for any production plant, and you see when we acquired Panamco, how we immediately started closing a number of facilities and reducing &#x2013; I don't even remember, but we went from like from 50 closed plants to 30, that's the number of plants that we have.</p>
          <p>So in terms of efficiency in manufacturing and production, I think that we have shown tremendous advances. In terms of how we spent our CapEx and the number of cases that we produce, the new cases that we can produce and distribute for any new dollar of investment that we do, we cut those numbers and we have become very, very efficient on that. In the way we handle our procurement, I think that we also have because of our scale, we have very, very good prices that when we do benchmark around the world, we have &#x2013; we are happy with our results.</p>
          <p>And one of the areas where you have commented, all of you, the investment community in the past, where we are &#x2013; were lacking some of the efficiencies that you should gain when the scale is, when you go to sales and distribution. Because a lot of our structure, if you have a pre-seller and a distributor. A distributor meaning the truck that does the distribution, that handles or that carries basically a very important part of the salary on available basis, then all your distribution and sales becomes viable. And then you have all these comments that you have a lot of growth in the top line and then when you get to SG&amp;A, you don't see the efficiency that you are achieving.</p>
          <p>Well, one of the main areas obvious in production is basically to comment that one of the areas of focus for this organization in the last year, year-and-a-half and that is going to be very important in the years to come is how do we address the complexity that is generated by this proliferation of SKUs? And how do we achieve the efficiencies that we need in order for every dollar that we &#x2013; additional dollar that we get in &#x2013; at the top line, for that dollar to trickle down to the bottom line. And that's what we are referring in that comment with Carlos Salazar is how we go to market? How we classify our clients? How we look at our clients and the revenue that they generate toward their own &#x2013; for their own profit.</p>
          <p>And that for us is how do we capture this revenue potential? You can argue that one additional SKUs could be beer. And that's correct, I mean, we are preparing this organization to not only distribute soft drinks, but also water and also juices and the still beverage on an efficient way.</p>
          <p>Another product could be beer or another beverage product that could be delivered and sold through our workforce. And that's what we're referring to that comment with Carlos. I don't want to play down this pilot test that we are doing in Michoac&#xE1;n with this route for beer, but that's the reality. It's a small test that we are doing. And so far, results are positive, but it's not conclusive because of the fact that, of the pilot, we need to advance further in order to conclude on that as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much, H&#xE9;ctor. And just as a follow-up, when do you envision kind of expanding the size of the pilot or trying it out in the different region?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that it was also related to one of the questions before, I mean, the fact that &#x2013; the comment that FEMSA leadership weeks ago certainly puts some question marks on this. But at the end of the day, we are doing that in Brazil. We learn from that and we are experimenting with that. And we think that we should continue regardless of a potential transaction or not.</p>
          <p>So I think that probably, not by year-end certainly because we are basically there. But I'll say that mid-next year we'll have a clearer picture of we should improve or not. Which will &#x2013; not improve, increase the size of this pilot play or not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much H&#xE9;ctor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Lore Serra with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I also wanted to ask a couple of questions in Mexico. As you mentioned in your opening comments the volume growth in Mexico was really impressive, the strongest in many years. And I wonder if you could give us a bit more color on what you think drove the growth. You mentioned the re-launch of Coke Zero, how much of the growth came from that versus other factors? And I'm wondering if you could reconcile that very, very strong volume growth with your somewhat more cautious comments at the beginning of the call on evaluating pricing in Mexico. If volumes are that strong why not take pricing up importantly in Mexico given the fact that your pricing's really lagged inflation the last couple of years? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Lore, good morning. Volume growth in Mexico has certainly been a kind of a surprise for everyone here. It's not, I mean, obviously under a decent scenario where you see other industries not necessarily growing, for us being &#x2013; posting record levels of volume. As a matter of fact July was the highest volume ever in a month in Coca-Cola FEMSA in Mexico, reaching basically 112 million unit case. Usually the month of May was the largest month of the year. But this time around May was a record and then July was even larger than May. And it probably had to do a little bit with very favorable conditions that we have in the Valley of Mexico with respect to rain and all of that.</p>
          <p>Now having said that, it's important -- several elements here. One is that we are focusing on a lot of our marketing expenses to the Valley of Mexico. And we have what we call the Valley of Mexico plan, which is basically aimed at regaining share in this market that, as we have commented in the past, have been the focus of attack from B brand producers. And we have mentioned in several conference calls in the past, that Jarritos and Red Kola have been causing a lot of noise here in the marketplace in terms of the activity that they have and their share.</p>
          <p>So with that Valley of Mexico plan, we will refocused a lot of our marketing dollars that had to do with investment in coolers, with investment in return on our presentations, and trying to take advantage of the return that we have. And we're foreseeing that because of the economic crisis where turnover presentations should be again important. And that was an element of this fall.</p>
          <p>So we have weather, we have the value of Mexico plan. And now we have two products that have grown very importantly. One is Coca-Cola Zero. That, we compared that versus last year is growing around 80% versus what we have last year. But remember that we have like three different cycles for Coca-Cola Zero.</p>
          <p>We launched it 2007. It was a big success. We have all this negative Internet campaign, came down very importantly. Then we try again with the same formula, saying that isn't containing cyclamate. Didn't do a lot of volume. It didn't perform well. Now with a totally new resource, design, image, new campaign in the TV and media, I think that we are in a very good track. So far, even though we grew 80% versus last year, we are still below the levels that we presented in 2007. We are probably 90% of the way, so we are 10% below the peak that we had in 2007. So Coca-Cola Zero, very important engine of growth.</p>
          <p>And the other is this product in the line of Jugos del Valle, which is this orangeade with low juice content. That is having a lot of traction especially during the morning hours for the consumer. It's a way of something to share with breakfast. Remember that we were not present there. We had our initial steps in this category last year. That category is also growing very importantly. It's &#x2013; the growth, it coincides basically with the growth Coca-Cola Zero. It is growing around 80%, those volumes. And I have mentioned how the volumes of orangeade is very important.</p>
          <p>Now broadly two trends here that are important to mention, and that are of concern to us and that we need to focus. One is that we are achieving this leadership in the orange category that we were looking for. If we take the territory that we cover in Mexico, we are the number one. We are still the second player in the Valley of Mexico on this category, and we need to work hard.</p>
          <p>But that category, it's in a way probably cannibalizing a little bit the sparkling flavored drinks. So if a guy is drinking an orangeade from Valle Frut, he is probably not drinking the Fanta product or a Sprite. And that's why we see volumes of Coca-Cola brand, including Coca-Cola Zero and Coca-Cola Light and the Red Cola, growing more than 10%, double digit growth. That probably is the biggest surprise of all when you look at the trends all around the world, where you see sparkling beverages coming down. And you have flavors with a mid single digit or low single digits, around 3% reduction in volume in flavors, but I believe it's been in a way cannibalized by Valle Frut.</p>
          <p>Important activity on the pricing front as we are increasing prices on some of the cola products. And we are &#x2013; most importantly, we are increasing prices of the orangeade by an important amount. We were selling those products in the Valley of Mexico, the 600 ML, around four pesos. We are moving that to five. So it's basically a 25% increase in the orangeade price. And in the two liter presentation, we are moving from 10 to 11.</p>
          <p>There are some other areas in the country where the orangeade is being sold at seven pesos, the 600 ML. So we still have room, but certainly the most competitive market for the orangeade is the Valley of Mexico. And we need to measure the consumer dynamics.</p>
          <p>So if I summarize a little bit here, I'm trying to summarize the answer. We have tailwinds with respect to weather. We have very good performance of Coca-Cola Zero and the orangeade. And we are, as you correctly pointed out, we are looking at the pricing equation on some of the products. And we are refocusing some of the investments to marketing and especially what has to do with return on our products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Then just a follow-up, I mean I understand that &#x2013; some of the dynamics in orangeade, but if you look at just the core CSD portfolio, you've had pricing below inflation for awhile, right? And you've got some really strong volume trends in the sector.</p>
          <p>So realistically, is something changing in terms of your price gaps or the competitive behavior or the consumer behavior that makes you more optimistic that if we look forward to 2010, you can have pricing closer to inflation? Because it hasn't been that way. Or is this just the weather was warm, but the underlying dynamics on the consumer or the competitive side remain similar?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, we have said that in consumer -- that competitor dynamics continues to be a concern obviously, because some of our competitors have not moved prices for many years, as I was speaking about Jarritos and Red Kola. And some of the other competitors have moved the prices, so price gaps have continued to widen.</p>
          <p>We believe that because of the strength of the brand, in brand Coca-Cola, we have space. That's why we are increasing prices as we speak. We believe that in orangeade, there is room to increase and that's why we are increasing. And especially if the orangeade is cannibalizing some of the sparkling beverage, we need to increase the margins of these products, and that's where we are moving.</p>
          <p>We believe that if we sell &#x2013; I mean assuming that these prices that I are mentioning -- these prices stick -- we will be getting very close to the profitability of multi-syrups and flavors with these orangeade products. They are still below sparkling beverages, but we are getting closer and closer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And just &#x2013; I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I was going to say is, if you think of the way we manage the businesses -- we see opportunities to increase prices, we'll take it. Our objective is to be equal to inflation or slightly ahead to inflation if we can.</p>
          <p>And sometimes when you look at the pricing equation on a global basis for the results, you will see that we are not getting necessarily &#x2013; that we are not getting inflation, as you say. But when you look at specifically at for example colas or water or flavors, we are probably a little bit softer on flavors. Water, we have been able to increase prices. Cola, we have been able &#x2013; when you look at the mix of products that we are selling, the total mix, it certainly brings the average price up. But it's important that we distinguish the pricing activity in this category.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And just two quick follow-ups. Could you give us what you think the weighted average increase in CSD pricing is that you're putting through currently?</p>
          <p>And then just quickly, in Mexico, we're seeing the sugar prices spike, and that was clearly one of the sources of the gross margin pressure in the second quarter. Do your current costs of sweetener in Mexico, and I know you use high fructose as well as sugar, reflect the current market prices? Or as we move to the fourth quarter and the first quarter, should we see higher sweetener pressure than what we saw reflected in your third quarter figures?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Lore, with respect to prices, basically the prices that we have been implementing is probably around that 2% average, because we are not increasing all of the &#x2013; all of our presentations. We are taking the real pricing in the two and a half return our presentations. And I believe on the 600 ML, that was taken during the third quarter but is going to affect the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>And sugar prices, we see &#x2013; let's just say it's a complicated environment. We are probably going to use a little bit more fructose as we move to next year because we have a price -- or a cost advantage -- when using a little bit more high fructose versus refined sugar. And that would probably help us a little bit on the equation. But I'll say that it's safe to assume that what we have in terms of pricing for sweeteners in the third quarter is what we are going to expect fourth quarter and first quarter of next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to clarify, Lore -- this is Alfredo Fern&#xE1;ndez. The price increases that we have taken so far in the month of October have been mainly on multi-serve presentation of colas and in the orangeade of Valle Frut.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Alex Robarts with Santander.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks very much. I want to go back to the Mexican sweetener issue. I'm trying to understand here -- I can see that we have had some clear pressure from COGS.</p>
          <p>But as I understand it, most of the sugar or sweetener that came through in the third quarter really has been purchased under contract in prior quarters, and that the spike that we've seen year-to-year -- I guess it's been 80% sugar and 30% in high fructose. But I mean is &#x2013; as we &#x2013; I understand you're doing some purchases now such that we will see likely a step up in the sweetener, starting at the end of the year and early next year. If you could confirm that, and talk to what type of magnitudes could we be looking at?</p>
          <p>And the second question is really more of a strategic one, which is going back to this Michoac&#xE1;n pilot. I mean, is it safe to assume, I mean obviously the complexities that your distribution system is going through now as you've launched into multi-category, which you kind of unveiled for us last year. Is it safe to assume that that's really the priority as opposed to beer? I mean, I guess with a 25% hit rate on three routes in Michoac&#xE1;n for beer, probably I can see how it can't or it might not be that conclusive, the impact. And in the end that decision to say that we've got through this multi-category phase and now let's look at beer more seriously, I mean, to what extent can the Coca-Cola Company just basically balk on that. I mean and basically gives thumbs down. I mean is that a risk? I mean, do they hold some power in that final shift?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alex, good morning. In general what we have, especially in Mexico and that's where we have a little bit more volatility in the sugar markets. And let me briefly touch on some of the other countries. Brazil very similar to international prices, although as you know we have some &#x2013; in Brazil we have the opportunity to hedge some of the exposure on the sugar because it tracks very closely international market. So in general, we have half of our sugar in Brazil with a contract that has been negotiated for many months before.</p>
          <p>Venezuela, there is a lot of scarcity of sugar. Sugar has increased more than any other country in Venezuela, because there is no sugar and we have low inventories. And it's a very difficult market to operate. And the important thing there is that our plans have sugar at any cost so that we can continue producing. And if you add the third quarter versus last year's third quarter, sugar increased around 40, 45% in Venezuela.</p>
          <p>Colombia, it's also a market that is important for us. But in general, it has behaved a little bit closer to what we've seen in Mexico.</p>
          <p>In Mexico, when you look at the prices of the third quarter, we basically have increases, I'd say around 25%, which is much lower than the international prices. And that's because we have been able to work with the different mixes of using either cane sugar or high fructose. When you look at the price of high fructose, that has come down in dollar terms. The impact that we have is that variation, which is a mid single digit reduction in dollar terms in high fructose in Mexico, and you have a 20 something percent devaluation of the Mexican peso, then the cost of sweeteners in general have increased around 20, 25% in Mexico. And I believe that those &#x2013; this kind of cost pressure is going to be very similar to what we had in the fourth quarter and then on the first quarter of next year.</p>
          <p>In some cases in Mexico, when we have some stability, we have the opportunity to negotiate with the sugar price producers and the corn -- the high fructose corn syrup producers -- with some months in advance, and have compromises of supply and demand and certain pricing formula with a number of months in advance. When the volatility is like similar to what we have, you see a lot of reluctance from the suppliers to get into long-term agreements.</p>
          <p>So we will have to play it by ear and see how the market is evolving. But our feeling is that, for the next six months we'll have similar cost pressure on sugar to what we had during the third quarter. That's what we are presenting.</p>
          <p>Now with respect to beer and this test pilot, again I don't want to play it down. We believe -- we firmly believe that Coca-Cola FEMSA should be ready with all the production, distribution, and sales to work in an industry that is more diversified, and we have a great number of SKUs. And that's regardless of beer -- is we have -- when we look -- you know that I've been here in this company for 16 years. And the number of SKUs that we had in '93 was less than 15. And it was basically Coca-Cola returnable glass medium, small, and large size, and that was basically all of &#x2013; the majority of the SKUs.</p>
          <p>The SKU proliferation has brought a lot of complexity to this industry. It's in production because of the cleaning process and the retooling processes that you have. And as I mentioned in the beginning, I think that we have been very, very successful in working in all the production and manufacturing.</p>
          <p>And distribution is also a very complex animal, because you have to have union's negotiations to introduce new SKUs or to introduce different way of compensating for different SKUs that may have either lower or a substantially higher margin than soft drinks. And then negotiations with Jugos are very complex. You need have to the systems and the platforms to &#x2013; and decide how to go to market. And that's what we have had been focused in the last year and a half, and we will continue to focus into the next years. We have to work with our client &#x2013; with different clients and the complexity of this distribution with this tremendous number of SKUs.</p>
          <p>Beer is another product. I mean, if it's successful, this is going to be in our trucks. If it's not successful, it will not be. We have to finalize this pilot test that we are doing in Michoac&#xE1;n. So far, it looks fine, but it's not conclusive yet. And obviously if &#x2013; as we have &#x2013; as we are different companies, similar to what we have in Brazil. For Coca-Cola FEMSA to sell a beer from Kaiser and the rest of the Coca-Cola bottlers in Brazil, you have a margin for distribution and you have to judge if it's a good business for you to use your capacity to sell a beer product in Brazil vis-&#xE0;-vis the cost that you have for distribution and the commissions that you have to sell. And vis-&#xE0;-vis the space that it's taking in your truck versus maybe a product that is &#x2013; that your family's not producing directly.</p>
          <p>And that &#x2013; so it's a simple equation, Alex. But we need to test and see if it's worthwhile for us to sell beer in the future or not. And that's where we are, no? At the end of the day, we are testing that. As you have different shareholders, it's important that you understand the economics for both parties. For FEMSA Cerveza or for Kaiser in Brazil, it has to make business sense to use a distribution vehicle that is cheaper than what it costs for FEMSA Cerveza or for Kaiser in Brazil. For us, it's important that the margin we get doing that pays for the cost of doing that and the space that it's taking from our own products. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from the line of Sean Glickenhaus with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. We were wondering what opportunities you could share with us regarding Valle and still beverage expansion in Brazil? Should we be thinking about it similarly to the success you had in Mexico in further rolling products out to additional points of sale? Perhaps that there's a percentage that hasn't been covered? And also what the timeframe associated with that would be? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Sean . Brazil, it's a &#x2013; it has been a difficult story, and it shouldn't be. We have a situation similar to Mexico where we have different &#x2013; a number of bottlers that are different in the countries, not like Central America or Colombia, where we basically operate the whole country and we have been very fast in introducing some of the markets. So you have to get into agreement with a larger number of stakeholders and <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>So it's important to remember that in Brazil, we have had Jugos del Valle for a few years. And that has, in a certain way, taken up part of the volume on the still beverages or juices and nectars in Brazil. So in a way, we didn't start with Jugos del Valle from scratch in Brazil as we were doing in Mexico. So that's why the incremental volume that you see in Brazil is not as important as what we have in some of the other territories.</p>
          <p>But certainly, Brazil is &#x2013; we believe that it is substantially under-developed. The volumes &#x2013; the capital that you see in juices and nectars and low juice content beverages -- it's very small compared to Mexico or Colombia. And we feel that there will be opportunities there that we need to capture. It's important also that we have in mind that, again, it's 16 different bottlers throughout the Coca-Cola Company as shareholder in this joint venture. And it takes a little bit more effort to get everyone with the same idea to try the market. But you're right, I mean there are opportunities there, and our work is to go out and capture them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And regarding the bottlers, who -- I assume most of the bottlers and Coke recognizing the importance of the incremental growth that you get from these products and that we've seen you do elsewhere. It's less a directional issue and more of a how-to, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's more &#x2013; as you say &#x2013; you are correct. It's &#x2013; we have been debating how to deal with the two brands, and we finally got to this agreement that it's going to be under the umbrella of a local Jugos del Valle <mark type="inaudible" /> so that we have the two brands. And some cannibalization when you introduce Jugos del Valle because the same products were also with <mark type="inaudible" />. And that kind of effort for everyone is in the same page, I believe on the opportunities that we have going forward. And obviously, after doing this business, everyone wants to get the highest return on that investment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from line of Jose Yordan with Deutsche Bank Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon everyone. I do have just one question. Your cash obviously continues to grow at a pretty good clip ahead of schedule, and so the question of acquisitions and what're you going to do with that cash comes again. And I guess my question would be, what are the chances in terms of your pipeline that we'll see a substantial acquisition of another Coke franchise, let's say within the next 12 months? And if there is one or more, is one of those likely to be outside of Latin America as you have been, let's say, advertising for awhile that you're sort of authorized to step outside of Lat-Am? Would that next opportunity over the next 12 months include something outside of Lat-Am or would it stay inside of Latin America?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Certainly the level of cash flow generation and therefore the amount of &#x2013; or let me put it this way, the capital structure that we have, it's getting to be very inefficient. And obviously the &#x2013; immediately the question in mind is what do we do with the excess cash and how do we get into, again into a financial structure that is efficient and appropriate for our company at this time. We continue to look at opportunities. We have been looking to both opportunities within Latin America and outside of Latin America.</p>
          <p>I think that with respect to the timing it's a little bit complex to say, I would not like to venture to saying that we will have something during the next 12 months. Because at the end of the day, it's not only your financial structure and your willingness to do a transaction, you need to find a good opportunity and do something that is rational also in terms of the prices that you're paying and everything else. So I would not be scared that we do something in the medium term, could be outside of Latin America or within Latin America. Because I think that's what I can say right now. But certainly the financial structure is in the top of mind of our board of directors, know that we need to address.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And next question comes from the line of Alain Alaini with JP Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good day, everyone. Most of my questions have been answered, but let me expand or have specific questions regarding this beer and soft drinks issue. H&#xE9;ctor, I mean, Modelo has been distributing the number one bottled water in Mexico now for I think over two years, if I remember correctly. They have claimed that their volume growth has been consistently double-digit. You're reporting this quarter single-serve volume water growing at around 8%. Could you comment if you're losing market share in single serve water versus Nestl&#xE9; versus Modelo in the quarter and how do you see this bottled water evolving because I guess the sub-question to that would be we're also seeing Big Cola being more aggressive with their water product at a aggressive discount and how &#x2013; yeah, those will be the two questions? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alain , I think that there are some, I guess, misconceptions on this. I mean we have been tracking obviously what Modelo has been doing with the Nestl&#xE9; brand, Santa Mar&#xED;a. I think that you probably can argue that in single-serve presentations they have had some traction in some of their on-premise clients.</p>
          <p>But at the end of the day, Santa Mar&#xED;a continues to be very far away from all the water brands in terms of -- I don't know if it's the fourth brand or the fifth brand. This is not the number one brand. I don't know how they are measuring that. Maybe they look at restaurants in Mexico City or whatever maybe they get to an interesting number, but I haven't seen those numbers yet.</p>
          <p>What we have in terms of information is that we have lost a few share points -- and when I say this, fractions of 1% -- in water. It probably would compare to last year. We are close to 1% market share erosion. But the one that continues to create a lot of problem for us is Bonafont. It doesn't have anything to do with the model of distribution. Bonafont continues to grow and it is the leader and is the one that is a little more active, the more aggressive in pricing, the more aggressive in marketing in the TV and media and all of that. And that continues to be the leaders in brand.</p>
          <p>We have started, and that's part of the regional marketing expenses that we have during the quarter. It is not only Coca-Cola Zero. We are re-launching Ciel with a new image. We have covered big hops for the brand to see if we get some traction from that. I think that what we have done with Ciel, from non-existent a few years ago to where we are, is remarkable in terms of the volumes that we are getting. I think that in Jaguar we are doing good improvements. As a matter of fact, the price of Jaguar even though it's the lower of all the products that we have when you look at price per unit case, is improving importantly because we are doing a little more in the Valley of Mexico where we have a better pricing formula than in the rest of the country.</p>
          <p>And so I think that water is a story that hasn't end yet. And again, the leader is Bonafont. And we &#x2013; that's the area of focus.</p>
          <p>Your question is a little bit more related to this &#x2013; to the effect that you have when you integrate with beer these products, and I hear that they are getting some traction on the volume. As I mentioned, some of the comprendes accounts, but we haven't seen anything significantly with the brand Santa Mar&#xED;a, which is owned by Nestl&#xE9;. And our feeling and the rumor in the market is that neither Normalelo nor Nestl&#xE9; are happy necessarily with the arrangement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is a follow-up question from the line of Lore Serra with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks for taking the follow-up. I know this is a sensitive issue and maybe it's appropriate or not to ask, but Coke said very clearly on the conference call last week that they believe in the back-end integration of beer and soft drinks and not the front end. And clearly what you're doing is -- this final test involves both the front end and the back end.</p>
          <p>So when you think about this sort of situation, how do we reconcile those two different points of view?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Lore, that if I read correctly the conversations that I have had with the Coca-Cola Company in the past, I think that you have a situation where the Coca-Cola Company has a large scale in the operations that we have in Latin American and probably on a worldwide basis. And although they recognize that, and if I focus in Latin America, which is the area that I know better, you have competitors, especially Pepsi, that has been doing work together with a beer company, or doing the distribution and everything together, or even the ownership is in the hands of a beer company.</p>
          <p>But when you look at some of the numbers, you can argue that, yes, Brazil, you have some profitability that is good for some of the products, but when you are &#x2013; if you were in the shoes of PepsiCo, are you really getting the benefit or the volume traction because of having your product being sold and distributed together with a beer product or because you're talking distributing a beer product?</p>
          <p>And I think that the argument that the Coca-Cola Company is trying to present is that you're going to have a much lower scale in this market, and therefore they probably needed the benefit of getting additional scale by getting together with other products. And their argument is that in the case of the Coca-Cola Company, they haven't seen the benefit for PepsiCo on that relationship.</p>
          <p>From our perspective, again -- and when I say our, meaning Coke FEMSA -- is we have a distribution force and a sales force that is very potent, probably one of the largest in Latin America and I don't know if it's the largest or not, but it's very, very large, very complex, very efficient. And as probably and maybe do a little comparison with a retailer, I mean a retailer has the space and the question is what else can I do with this space that I have to start getting additional revenue? From our perspective as we have the distribution force, we have the sales force, can we do other products that will bring some scale or efficiency or margins just because of getting distribution margin in that and that's where we need to analyze. And it's probably difficult to reconciliate, but that's where we are right now, Lore. I don't know if I'm answering your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And this concludes our question-and-answer session. Ladies and gentlemen, I would now like to turn the call back over to Mr. H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your interest in our company and Alfredo Fernandez will be available to answer any remaining questions that you might have or clarifying questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes your presentation and you may now disconnect. Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>