<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1327269" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-07-23</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3057</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o Gutierrez, Chief Financial and Administrative Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst">Lauren Torres</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Robert Ford</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Gustavo Oliveira</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Antonio Gonzalez</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Alan Alanis</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Celso Sanchez</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and welcome to Coca-Cola FEMSA's Second Quarter 2010 Earnings Results Conference Call. As a reminder, today's conference is being recorded and all participants are in a listen-only mode. At the request of the company we'll open the conference up for questions-and-answers after the presentation.</p>
          <p>During this conference call, management may discuss certain forward-looking statements concerning Coca-Cola FEMSA's future performance and should be considered as good safe estimates made by the company. These forward-looking statements reflect management's expectations and are based upon currently available data. Actual results are subject to future events and uncertainties, which can materially impact the company's actual performance.</p>
          <p>At this time, I will now turn the conference over to Mr. H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o, Coca-Cola FEMSA's CFO. Please go ahead, Mr. Trevi&#xF1;o.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us today. Despite recent global economic volatility in second quarter of 2010, our company delivered solid top and bottom line results. Strong preference for brand Coca-Cola among our consumers, the growing scale of our still beverage platform and our ability to selectively increase prices across our wide portfolio approach were the main drives of our performance for the quarter.</p>
          <p>As a point of reference, in our last conference call we explained the devaluation of the bolivar in Venezuelan and its effects on our results. For your benefit we will briefly review the conclusion that we drew during the call. We have decided to use the exchange rate of 4.30 bolivars per U.S. dollar compared to 2.15 bolivars per U.S. dollar that we used last year 2008 the financial statements from our Venezuela subsidiary to our reporting currency, the Mexican peso.</p>
          <p>In second quarter, our consolidated revenues reached more than MXN25 billion, up 4% from the second quarter of 2009, despite the devaluation of the bolivar in Venezuela bolivar. On a currency neutral basis and excluding the acquisition of Brisa in Colombia, our consolidated total revenues grew 16% for the quarter, driven by selective prices increases and volume growth.</p>
          <p>In second quarter, our consolidated sales volume rose more than 4%. Excluding Brisa, our consolidated sales volume increased more than 3%. This increase was driven mainly by the strong preference of brand Coca-Cola, which grew 6% and the double-digit growth of our still beverage category supported by the Jugos del Valle of products.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated gross profit increased 2% in the second quarter of 2010. Cost of goods sold increased mainly due to higher sweetener cost across our territories. This was partially mitigated by the appreciation of the local currencies of our main operations as applied to our U.S. dollar denominated raw material costs. Consequently, our gross margin declined 100 basis points compared with the second quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated operating income improved more than 11% reaching MXN4.1 billion in the second quarter, supported by the operating income growth achieved in all our divisions. Operating leverage achieved through higher revenues in local currency compensated for gross margin pressures. As a result, our operating margin improved by 100 basis points reaching 16.2%. On a currency neutral basis and excluding the acquisition of Brisa in Colombia, our consolidated operating income grew approximately 24%.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated EBITDA increased by double-digits to MXN5 billion in the second quarter. Our net controlling interest income reached MXN2.5 billion, an increase of close to 15%. This increase mainly resulted from our higher operating income.</p>
          <p>Now let me expand on the performance of our operations. Our Mexican operations successfully built under a strong volume base from last year, delivering more than 4% volume growth. During the quarter, the sparkling beverage category significantly contributed to our incremental volumes, mainly driven by the 5% volume growth of brand Coca-Cola in both multi and single-serve presentations, this combined with the low single-digit volume growth of flavored sparkling beverage.</p>
          <p>Our still beverage category supported by the Jugos del Valle line of products post double-digit volume growth, while the volumes from our water portfolio remained almost flat year-over-year and drove an important sequential recovery from the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>Our average price per unit case increased 5.4% in the second quarter. This increase was driven by several factors. One, higher volumes of brand Coco-Coal, which carries a higher average price per unit case; two, a positive shift in our product mix to single-serve presentations resulting from last year's low on-premise channel consumption driven by the effect of swine flu in May of 2009, in combination with increased on-premise consumption during June of 2010 generated by the FIFA World Cup soccer event.</p>
          <p>Three, selective price increases implemented in our portfolio during the quarter. And four, lower volumes in our bottled water portfolio, which as you know carries a lower average price per unit case. As a result of increased volumes and prices, our Mexican operation's total revenue grew 9.3% to MXN10.7 billion.</p>
          <p>On the profitability front, higher sweetener costs were partially offset by the appreciation of the Mexican peso as applied to the U.S. dollar denominated raw material costs. Compared with the second quarter of 2009, our gross profit increased by almost 8% to MXN5.3 billion, and our gross margin declined 60 basis points to 49.5%.</p>
          <p>Our operating income grew 3% to MXN2 billion. Increased operating expenses were mainly driven by the resources deployed across our Mexico division to support our growing still beverage platform, enhance our execution at the point of sale, bolster our returnable base and improve our cooler coverage.</p>
          <p>Our operating margin decreased 110 basis points to 18.4%. Our EBITDA grew 5% to MXN2.4 billion compared to the same quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>In summary, our Mexican operations recovered from a slow start of the year to deliver solid results this quarter. Our main challenge for the year remains the higher cost of sugar. As you may know, international sugar prices started to decline significantly at the beginning of the year, but we have not seen yet this decline in local sugar prices. Accordingly, we will continue to leverage our ability to use high-fructose corn syrup to mitigate this cost pressure.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn our attention to our Latincentro division. Our Latincentro division recorded 1% volume growth in the second quarter. This increase was driven by the integration of the Brisa bottled water business in Colombia; excluding Brisa, the division's volume declined 4%.</p>
          <p>In Colombia, volume grew 10% during the quarter, mainly driven by the integration of the Brisa water business and the performance of brand Coca-Cola. Bad weather conditions in the month of May and June affected the volume growth of our sparkling and still beverage portfolio. Including our water segment, our Colombian operations volume grew 1%.</p>
          <p>In Venezuela, our volume decreased 7%, driven by lower disposable income of our consumer base, especially during the month of June. Our Central American operation sales volume declined slightly, mainly due to bad weather conditions experienced at the beginning of the quarter. High single-digit volume growth in the still beverage category was offset by a 2% decline in the sparkling beverage portfolio.</p>
          <p>Our Latincentro division's total revenues declined 15% to MXN7.4 billion. This decline resulted mainly from the devaluation of the bolivar in Venezuela. On a currency neutral basis and excluding the acquisition of Brisa, our Latincentro division's total revenues grew 23%, driven by higher average prices per unit case across our territories.</p>
          <p>On the profitability front, our Latincentro division's gross profit declined 16% to MXN3.4 billion as a result of the devaluation of the bolivar in Venezuela. Higher sweetener costs across the region were partially offset by the effect of the appreciation of the Columbian peso as applied to our U.S. dollar denominated raw material costs. Compared with the second quarter of 2009, our growth margin declined 70 basis points to 46.5%.</p>
          <p>Our operating income grew 19% to MXN1.2 billion. Operating leverage achieved through higher revenues in local currencies and higher operating expenses recorded in the second quarter of last year resulted in an operating margin expansion of 470 basis points to 16.7%. Our EBITDA grew 16% to MXN1.6 billion compared with the second quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Our Latincentro division delivered stable results when compared to the first quarter of 2010, despite the devaluation of the bolivar in Venezuela and the unusually bad weather conditions experienced in Colombia and Central America.</p>
          <p>In local currency terms, our operations continue to post solid top line growth, mainly driven by selective price increases implemented over the past months designed to compensate for local inflation and higher sweetener costs.</p>
          <p>Now let me talk about Mercosur. In the second quarter of 2010, our Mercosur division's total revenues grew 24% to MXN7.2 billion. Excluding beer, which accounted for MXN745 million, our total revenues reached MXN6.4 billion.</p>
          <p>Organic growth driven by higher average prices per unit case and increased volumes, represented approximately 75% of our incremental revenues. The effect of a positive currency translation resulting from the depreciation of the Mexican peso against the Brazilian real provided the balance.</p>
          <p>Volume growth in our Mercosur division was up close to 9% in the second quarter of 2010. Our Brazilian operations recorded more than 13% volume growth, mainly driven by brand Coca-Cola combined with the continued strong performance of the Jugos del Valle line of beverages.</p>
          <p>In Argentina, our volumes declined 2%. The solid performance of our still beverage category driven by Aquarius, our flavored water brand, was offset by a low single-digit decline in the sparkling beverages.</p>
          <p>On the profitability front, our Mercosur division's gross profit increased 21% to MXN3 billion. Increased sweetener cost across the division combined with higher PET cost in Argentina were partially mitigated by the appreciation of the Brazilian real as applied to our U.S. dollar denominated raw material cost.</p>
          <p>Our gross margin decreased 100 basis points to 41.4% for the second quarter of 2010. Our operating income grew 21% to MXN895 million. Operating leverage achieved through higher revenues in Brazil were partially affected by higher labor cost and trade cost in Argentina. As a result, operating margins declined 30 basis points to 12.5% in the second quarter. Our EBITDA grew more than 15% to MXN1.1 billion.</p>
          <p>In summary, our Mercosur division delivered positive results in the second quarter of 2010. In Brazil, our portfolio of products continue to perform strongly, especially brand Coca-Cola. The preference among our consumers for this brand is driving higher demand across our portfolio. Our strategy of building a wide array of products and presentation to satisfy our consumers' needs is proving successful.</p>
          <p>Additionally, the still beverage category continues to build momentum growing at superior rate, supported by the integration of Jugos del Valle line of beverages in Brazil. Over the past few years, our Brazilian franchise has become an important driver of our company's growth. Going forward, we have ample opportunities to continue developing our portfolio, enlarging our beverage offerings to satisfy the dynamic market and capitalize on the opportunity to increase per capita consumption.</p>
          <p>Now let me walk you through our financial performance for the quarter. This quarter our operations produced strong results, with all of our divisions contributing to profitability. Our geographically balanced portfolio of franchise territories is helping us to deliver sustainable cash flow generation, and to compensate for seasonality or weather related events.</p>
          <p>As of June 30, 2010, we had a cash balance of MXN9.4 billion, a decrease of MXN572 million compared with end year 2009, mainly as a result of debt and dividend payments we made during the first half of 2010 and net of the cash generated by our operations during the year.</p>
          <p>Our total debt decreased MXN103 million compared with year-end 2009. By using part of the proceeds from our $500 million Yankee Bond issued during February, on April 16, 2010 we fully paid the maturity of our Mexico Peso bond in the amount of MXN1 billion, and also during the year we prepaid $202 million of bilateral loans.</p>
          <p>Our net debt increased by MXN469 million, mainly as a result of the MXN2.6 billion dividend we paid during April 2010, and obviously net of the cash generated during the year.</p>
          <p>As of March 31, 2010, our net debt to EBITDA coverage ratio was 0.3 times, and our EBITDA to net interest coverage ratio was more than 15 times; highlighting our financial flexibility and the strength of our products.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, our operations delivered positive results for the quarter. The performance of our Mexico division improved significantly compared to the first quarter of the year. And the rest of our operations across Latin America continue to deliver profitable growth. We are pleased to serve a growing base of consumers with our broad portfolio of high quality products and presentations in one of the best markets in the world to serve &#x2013; to sell beverages.</p>
          <p>As we enter the second half of the year <mark type="inaudible" /> increased global economic volatility. Nonetheless, we are confident that the brand equity of our products, the operating capabilities that we have developed and the financial strength that we have achieved will help us to continue outperforming our industry. Despite the prevailing challenging economic conditions, we remain focused on our goal of delivering solid results for all of our stakeholders.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your continued trust and support. And now I would like to open up the call for any questions that you may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from the line of Lauren Torres with HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In the first half of the year you have these higher costs, but you are able to get operating margin based on better operating expense leverage. So curious if you feel that, directionally that's what we should still see in the second half. I guess I'm just looking for some comments on some of your COGS &#x2013; your COGS outlook for the second half, and then also the offsets that you see in the operating expense line, if those initiatives sustainable?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Lauren. Yes, I think that as I mentioned during my speech, in general terms we see very stable cost of the raw &#x2013; of our raw materials. The challenge remains sweetener cost in most of our areas, and then we go to some other geographies. In Mexico, as we mentioned during the Mexico part, we saw an increase. We saw a faster pace of increase than when we saw last year in the international markets. And now that the international prices have come down, in Mexico prices have come down slightly, but not at the pace of the decline in international prices. So in other words, the gap of the Mexican sugar price compared to international prices have widened substantially as international prices have declined. What we anticipate &#x2013; but nonetheless, we see a little by little reduction in sugar prices.</p>
          <p>Our expectation is that we will continue to see some small declines in sugar prices in Mexico. We are a little bit concerned of &#x2013; on high-fructose corn syrup. We might &#x2013; we are expecting some increases in corn syrup. So when you factor in those two elements, we are expecting stable sweetener prices at these current level of the second quarter, current levels for the rest of the year, which will put some pressure on our margins.</p>
          <p>If we go to other markets like Brazil, prices went up last year importantly and then came down importantly, because they follow very closely the international price. So I don't see an issue there in Brazil. We have some hedges there, as we have explained in the past, because of that proximity of the local prices to the international prices we are able to hedge some of the cost. We basically have a growth around 0.155 to $0.16 per pound on our hedges, and that's a good number given where the prices are right now. And so Brazil I don't see a problem.</p>
          <p>We have seen some pressure in Argentina with the high-fructose consumer prices, and the same in Columbia with sugar prices we have seen pressures. In Central America, it's similar to in a way between Mexico and some of the other markets. It's not as closely related to the international prices, but it is not as high as in Mexico on that front. And lastly Venezuela, it's more an issue of availability and because of the scarcity some of the prices, we have very large volatility on the prices because of the scarcity of sugar in Venezuela.</p>
          <p>Other than that we see PET prices very stable, as we are not expecting any initial prices there, although obviously that depends a lot on oil prices. And the other big component is obviously the concentrate prices, where we see stable environment as we have discussed in the past. We don't see any surprises there. So that's in general what I can basically share with you, Lauren, with respect to our cost of goods sold.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So with that &#x2013; so when you think about managing the operating expense line, do you think there is advantages there or we should see some of that spend maybe ramp up in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. In the operating expenses we have &#x2013; as we have mentioned in the last few quarters, big effort following all of our fixed cost structure. We will continue to push in that respect and we have seen some improvement in some of the territories, especially in Mexico. We still have to do some of our homework in Brazil and Argentina. In Colombia, the numbers are good in that respect. And as we mentioned where we see a lot of volatility in salaries is in Argentina and Venezuela, because of the negotiation with unions are complicated in those &#x2013; especially complex in those two countries.</p>
          <p>We do have also in some markets additional activity on the marketing front. In Mexico, as I mentioned during my Brisa speech, we have been spending regional resources in marketing, not only because of the World Cup that was more I guess across the globe during this season, every country is spending a little bit more because of all the promotional activity, and the Coca-Cola company being the biggest sponsor on that big event. So you always hear every four years that increase because of the World Cup. But in Mexico especially because of the campaign that we have for returnability and introduction of coolers, <mark type="inaudible" /> our marketing expenses.</p>
          <p>So when you look at the marketing expense in Mexico, that we normally say it's around 3.5 to 4%, last year was around 3.8; this year the second quarter was around half a percentage point higher than what we have. So you see that &#x2013; we have seen that increase in marketing expense. In Brazil, we have also taken a very strong campaign, I think a very successful campaign of going to returnable presentations. Returnables are still a very low percentage of our mix, it's around 15%. But a lot of this volume, this tremendous volume growth that you see in that country has to do with introduction of waters and cases that are also reflected in our marketing expenses. So I think that in general and in summary I'll say, you will see this campaign for returnability increasing in our territories, but to compensate for that you will see as a big trend a push from corporate to lower fixed cost structure of our operations. So I'll see a stable operating expenses going forward, Lauren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. That helps. Thanks <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Robert Ford from Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, thank you and good day, H&#xE9;ctor. I had a question with respect to Venezuela, but also a follow-up on Mexico too. In Venezuela, what percentage of EBITDA from the Central American region or Latincentro came from Venezuela? And what access did you have to dollar FX for inputs and remits? As my understanding is that all corporate now are capped at $350,000 a month when it comes to remittances, but you may have better access at preferential rates for some of your inputs.</p>
          <p>And then with respect to Mexico and returnability, you're doing a lot to drive single-serves, and I was wondering if you could give us some little bit of an update in terms of your efforts to promote those single-serve presentations and simultaneously drive more returnability. And if there are any specific learnings that you can perhaps transfer to other markets, like Brazil or Argentina?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Bob. Let me give you some general figures on these questions. In Venezuela, even though we have registered a very strong devaluation of the Venezuelan bolivar and as we translate that into Mexican pesos, Venezuela represents around &#x2013; I'll tell you around 10% of the total EBITDA of the company. If you remember, last year we were saying that it was around 12% of that, and we were expecting for those numbers to reduce substantially basically to have, given the strong devaluation of the Mexican peso. But given the performance of their operation, that has to do a lot with on the volume decline we have, important adjustment to some of the prices and also mix change and a strong reduction in some of the operating expenses, because we basically were not spending marketing dollars in there, given the capacity constraints that we have with energy <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>At the end of the day the EBITDA continues to grow in local currency. So right now Venezuela represents I'll say around 10, 11% of our consolidated EBITDA and it represents 9% of our volume. So it's pretty much in line. I don't think that that number is <mark type="inaudible" /> sustainable, given the fact that we are translating that into pesos at a higher exchange rate. But it will depend on our ability to control costs and pass along prices as we have a high inflation environment in that territory.</p>
          <p>Mexico, we continue &#x2013; there are two effects on this single-serve pools that we have. Obviously, we are happy to see that increase. The mix of single-serve increased around 60 basis points in our mix. As I mentioned, it has to do with the fact that last year a lot of the on-premise consumption was reduced substantially because of the swine flu, and this year we have the other effect of having many people in restaurants during the some of the matches, that helped a little bit on that front. But we continue to launch new and innovative packages. And as a matter of fact I also wanted to share that we have in the market for the first time a 200-milliliter PET bottle, one-way bottle. That to my understanding is the lightest PET bottle for that size in the world. It's only 10 gram. It's incredible what our technical guys have developed here in our operations. Obviously, working very close hand-on-hand with the Coca-Cola company, because of all the &#x2013; to be sure that the growth is &#x2013; that the quality of the growth is very good.</p>
          <p>We are anticipating it will success, because with that very light bottle, with very low PET content at the end of the day we can afford to have a very low price for the consumer as an entry package. And that we are just waiting to see the results of this production in Mexico, because we think that as a presentation that will be very much successful in other geographies and we are starting to do some planning for launching of that package to other markets.</p>
          <p>So in returnables, so in a way we have these two big pushes. One is try to get these two packages, innovative packages, the small cans, the slim cans, and to have entry price points for the consumer that are attractive in single-serve presentations. And we have worked with both returnables and one-way, but mainly one-way because of the size of the presentations, although we have been &#x2013; we have done some experiments with small returnable glass bottles.</p>
          <p>But on the other hand, we also want to have special income areas of the <mark type="inaudible" /> with lower income areas. We want to have, therefore, the ability of returnable products and we are working also on that &#x2013; second hand on large packages and the liter <mark type="inaudible" /> liter both in plastic and glass in different geographies.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, as I mentioned, it's been a tremendous success basically from non-existing returnable approach, with returnables are now 15% and that has to do a lot with the growth that we are seeing in that market.</p>
          <p>And the last part of the question with respect to the Venezuelan availability of dollars, the way it works is that for raw materials that are in certain least, you have access to &#x2013; let me qualify that. You have slow access to those dollars, but we have been receiving dollars. I was reviewing the figures for our Board meeting, and basically we have purchased around $50 million of &#x2013; $50 million for raw materials that are in those list at 2.6 exchange rate and we have access to this small basket, which is as you correctly pointed out $300,000 per month, but that is only for products or goods that are not on those list. So that's basically for some services and things, and that is around 5.3 bolivars per dollar rate approximately.</p>
          <p>So in general, we are still getting some dollars at the controlled exchange rate, although we are seeing a reduction of the flow, and that's part of the complications of doing business in Venezuela. You have to negotiate with suppliers for them to be patient, so that we're able to get the dollars out of the system and those are tough negotiations, because sometimes the periods are for &#x2013; to get those dollars are long, now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Gustavo Oliveira with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. It's a follow-up question on your returnable strategy in Brazil. The country has not been on a returnable market in soft drinks for a long time or the presence has been very small. Can you expand on that? What is the target? You can move this 15% penetration that you have in your territory up to what number? That's the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question is, is this a Coca-Cola Company initiative or it's a Coca-Cola FEMSA initiative only in your territories and it's something that can be expanded to the other territories, even the ones that you don't have in the country? The third question is on whether your focus is on-premise or off-premise consumption for the returnable packages and how could that mix evolve over the long run? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Gustavo. Yes, as you correctly pointed out, Brazil was not used to these returnable presentations, although the beer industry uses that a lot, but it's a little bit different. In our case it's an initiative that we wanted to test. Obviously, we have to have very long conversation with the Coca-Cola Company. To be honest, I'm not sure if this has been applied to other territories outside of our operations, but I assume that if it's successful some other bottlers will follow. The investment behind the bottles and cases are high, but it's an important element to grow volumes.</p>
          <p>Our main target is to focus to the low and, let's say, medium-low classes of the population. It's a two-liter presentation. It's basically for off-premise, for home consumption. And one of the main areas that we want to attract is that &#x2013; and I have mentioned this in the past what is an important element for you to have in mind. Once you have the consumer used to carry an empty bottle to the mom-and-pop or to the supermarket to buy a returnable package, once he's used to that, it's like a virtuous circle, because the consumer takes the decision what product he is going to buy when he is leaving his house. Before he goes to the mom-and-pop, he takes the bottle and he already knows &#x2013; or he or she already knows that they will buy a Coca-Cola product.</p>
          <p>So they will go the store and they will not start comparing our product with some other competitor products or whatever, because they already took the decision of what are they going to buy, let me give you the expression at the <mark type="inaudible" />. They might look at some of our competitor products, but the price point of that presentation which is attractive and that's how we can maintain these price gaps that we see across all of our territories where we have substantially premium in comparable presentations, and when I say comparable it's comparing one-liter presentation versus one-liter presentations. But for the consumer that prefers our product but wants to be a little bit more &#x2013; to spend a little bit more less money, they just have to carry this empty container, which is not a large inconvenience at the end of the day. And that has proven to be successful in other markets and we think that in Brazil it's also going to be the case.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And on &#x2013; since it's an off-premise initiative, I think the two follow-up questions is; first, what do you think it could be a target you have in terms of percentage of contribution in volumes? And the second is, since it's an off-premise initiative are you already having the buying in from the large retailers or for now you're targeting mostly the smaller mom-and-pops?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the second part. It's basically targeted for mom-and-pops, because some of the big retailers do not necessarily like the hassle of having &#x2013; and the space to have the empty containers and <mark type="inaudible" /> when the consumer enters the supermarket. But so far it's more a mom-and-pop as a target.</p>
          <p>And in terms of the how far it can go, it's a complicated question, Gustavo. I think that you have &#x2013; I think that if we get to know &#x2013; if we get a chance to be successful, although we are not targeting that right now, if we get to get successful to introduce this to some of the small food places. As you see beer, where a consumer shares for lunch a liter presentation or a 600-milliliter of beer returnable glass, we might have a chance to introduce that into some of these cafeterias or <mark type="inaudible" />. But we haven't started to do that. As a reference I will tell you that in Mexico returnables are as high as 30%. It's too early to say that &#x2013; for me to give a guidance that we'll get that level. I think it's not going to be 30% in the short term, but I think it's going to grow from the present level. But I would not like to give a target figure, because I honestly don't have a specific figure. And we think that we have to push that product and if it grows, welcome, and if it stays at a lower level, we don't mind. It's already on a high that makes a profitable package for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Antonio Gonzalez from Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, H&#xE9;ctor. I also wanted to talk about Brazil and I wanted to see if you could expand on the operating leverage that you're getting in the country. I mean, year-to-date already volumes have been quite strong and it's somewhat difficult to understand where are you in terms of profitability, for instance, maybe if you can talk vis-&#xE0;-vis Mexico and what upside do you think is still left to be realized?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Antonio. Brazil is a market that is growing fast, and as I mentioned a little bit earlier, it's a country where we need to work a bit better on all the fixed cost control, and that's one of the areas of focus for us in this year and going forward. We have this tremendous volume growth, we have expansion of operating income and EBITDA, but it's a little bit affected by &#x2013; especially when you look at the first half, by some of the &#x2013; although the prices follow international prices, they were high compared to the previous year. So we have a little bit the effect of sugar prices there. We have little bit of the prices. And when you look at the Mercosur numbers, certainly the Brazil numbers are contaminated a little bit by the performance of Argentina, that obviously will &#x2013; as I mentioned, will &#x2013; volumes that were not as successful. As a matter of fact, they are negative versus last year in Argentina, with pressure on labor cost and pressure on some of the cost because of the higher inflation rate that we are seeing in this country and pressures on high-fructose because of the increasing prices we have, of course, in Argentina, but let me use the word contaminated with the performance of Brazil. So Brazil is a profitable market. It's improving. The profitability is still behind Mexico in terms of margins, but improving. And my feeling is that once we control a little bit better the SG&amp;A figures, especially on the fixed cost part of that, we will have better numbers.</p>
          <p>Also it's important to remember that in the case of Brazil, the joint venture that we have for the Jugos del Valle products, it's an arrangement where all the bottlers are partners. It's basically the same that in Mexico. But different than Mexico, we have a structure of a JV that stays with all the profitability of the &#x2013; because there are important tax benefits because of the location of the production plant and all of that. And then in our case, we report that more as a &#x2013; it is not shown in our operating income, no, it's just below the operating income line, although we've registered the volumes because we're selling those products. And also in other words, our Brazilian operations sell the Jugos del Valle product basically with zero profit. The profit stays in the JV and then we share dividend from that JV. So that issue also distorts a little bit the profitability of Brazil, but economically either if it's below the operating profit line or below that, economically is from a financial point of view we are receiving the benefit of the Jugos del Valle investment, although it's below the operating line as a dividend or as other income.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. This is very helpful. And if I may just quickly on Venezuela. Do you think you'll be able to maintain current prices, given the low volumes? I understand there has been broad based deceleration in consumer dynamics in the country. So I just wanted to understand if you feel comfortable with the current prices or you'll have to adjust a bit downwards maybe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll have to place higher <mark type="inaudible" /> at the end of the day. Yes, you're correct. There is a big deceleration on the feeling of the consumer in Venezuela what we are feeling there, especially during June we saw big deceleration. And most of the companies, I think we have to comply with 20% less use of energy as compared to last year, are struggling to keep up with that regulation. We're giving preference to brand Coca-Cola obviously in some of our production runs, so we are suffering a little bit in flavor because we do not necessarily have all the flavors available as we give preference to brand Coca-Cola. So it's a challenge I think to work in that country, we have to work with prices. Our preference is not to move prices down, because obviously we have high pressure from inflation and salaries. So our first choice will be not to move prices and we haven't been moving prices up to this moment.</p>
          <p>You have the challenge of increasing labor cost, increasing raw materials, availability of dollars to pay your suppliers, so it's a challenge to work in the country. But I've think that so far our team there has done a tremendous job of, even though the circumstances they continue to increase very importantly the profitability of the business in terms of absolute numbers in local currency. So when you translate that into pesos, even though it's half of what it was last year, still an important number in our numbers. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Alan Alanis with J.P. Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Hi, H&#xE9;ctor. My question has to do with Brazil also. Remember &#x2013; when was the last time the Coca-Cola Company did a concentrate increase? And now that the country's profitability for Coke is increasing so fast, what's the likelihood of getting another concentrate increase from Coke there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alan, I hope that nobody in the Coca-Cola Company is listening to your question, <mark type="inaudible" /> don't give bad ideas. Now let me tell you, we received a concentrate increase in 2005 &#x2013; 2005 or 2006, I don't remember, at the same time that we announced the Mexico price increase. It was a price increase in three steps in Mexico and there was this increase in Brazil. The difference was that, because Brazil was going through a very difficult time during the early 2000, during &#x2013; if you remember when we were buying Panamco, it was a very &#x2013; operation that was not probably dollar all and it was negative at EBITDA figures. The Coca-Cola Company did a concentrate reduction to all the bottlers, in that prior to Coke FEMSA being there. So either &#x2013; I don't remember it was 2005, 2006. Now that the profitability was back to the industry, they decided to take it back to the level it was before the reduction. So it was &#x2013; that's why it was an accepted movement by all the bottlers, because in a way everyone recognize that the Coca-Cola Company to share the pain or the situation in Brazil, sacrifice a little bit the concentrate price for a few years. So everyone was in agreement to take back that price increase. And that's what we &#x2013; that's the only movement we have seen in this <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>As far as what is the likelihood of them increasing, I don't know. I mean, they can do it. You know that contractually they can do it in other markets, and obviously you know that as we do the other raw materials increase, we have some volatility on some raw material, we try to compensate either with marketing or prices or whatever. We always look at ways to try to maintain our profitability. But so far I think that the main focus &#x2013; and I think that two companies are in sync in that respect is how do we continue growing the size of the pie rather than splitting the pie in a different way. And I think that that is pretty much the dialog that we have together with the Coca-Cola Company in our conversation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very useful. Thanks. Now if I may ask just quickly two more questions. One has to do with the competitive environment in Mexico. Have you seen &#x2013; what are the kind of changes that you've seen now that the <mark type="inaudible" /> has been run by Pepsi for a while there in the market? And my last question will have to do with cash deployment going forward. Any news regarding your previously mentioned potential expansion plans for both in the Americas and outside of the Americas, of course?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alan, with respect to the competition environment in Mexico, we have seen some positive trends. When I said positive is that we are seeing less aggressiveness on regard of Pepsi in terms of some of the products. For example, they have placed the three-liter presentation at 14 pesos, so which is basically at parity with our returnable 2.5-liter, before that it was 13 pesos. So the fact that they are increasing the price point of some of the products I think that that is a positive trend for the industry. And for them also to separate a little bit from the big brands, that you remember that <mark type="inaudible" /> time they were being &#x2013; they were pricing the products very, very close to big brands.</p>
          <p>With respect to cash deployments, we basically are on the same page. I mean, as we mentioned few quarters ago, we will be looking for opportunities to grow in this industry that we feel that we can manage very well, and obviously with a lot of caution and a lot of thoroughness in our analysis. And as we mentioned, we don't see opportunities in the short term. We'll probably increase a little bit our dividend next year as we did last year, remember that basically double the amount in peso terms of the dividend payment this year. And as we mentioned in some of the press release, basically this is our seventh straight year that we have been increasing dividend. So if we see that there are opportunities, but they are not very close from our timeline perspective or we don't see any opportunities, we certainly need to look back at the current dividend payment ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you so much, H&#xE9;ctor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your last question comes from the line of Celso Sanchez from Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. I've been pretty impressed by this continued strength of brand Coca-Cola, not just in Mexico, given they're already high per capital consumption, but also relative to flavors in that market and more recently &#x2013; or more obviously this quarter at least in the Mercosur division. Can you speak a little bit to &#x2013; it does seem like this is a bit of a structural thing. Certainly brand Coca-Cola for yourselves and other bottlers has been growing quite strong in several regions, in Latin America for a while. Is it something we should think about that maybe there is a structural reallocation of marketing resources that is pushing more towards the Cola rather than the flavors given competitive environments in different markets? And also or &#x2013; is there also an element of flavor support that used to be there for the sparkling side is now being slightly moved to the Jugos del Valle still &#x2013; how should we think about this, because it does seem like there is a trend here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Celso. I think that there are several elements as normal in this &#x2013; for instance, it's very difficult to explain with a single fact here. But let me share with you some trends. Brand Coca-Cola, as you said, is &#x2013; continues to grow strongly, and especially when you compare to some other flavors. Flavors, the good news is, for example, that in Mexico we saw for the first time an increase, around 3% increase in flavors versus last year, which was a switch in the trend that we were seeing in flavors. But flavors, you're right, they have been affected by the production of different products of the Jugos del Valle line of business. We introduce flavored waters, like Aquarius  in Argentina; we introduced Valle Frut <mark type="inaudible" />, which is a low juice product in &#x2013; with no carbonation in Mexico or Colombia or Brazil with some small content with no carbonation. Those products basically eat away a little bit of the flavor or the core flavor markets, and for me that's a very important trend. But the consumer is moving in that direction and if we don't have those products, someone else will do it, then we will suffer in our core flavor products anyhow. When you offer a consumer a product that has a little bit of juice, that  has vitamins and that has a good flavor and maybe no carbonation, I think that is an attractive combination for the consumer vis-&#xE0;-vis as a Sprite or a Fanta or Lift, for example, in Mexico.</p>
          <p>But again I think that I'm very happy to see that the trend for flavors that we have seen a decline in Mexico especially it's starting apparently to change for the first time with a 3% increase. On the other hand, on colas you have all these initiatives of, for example, marketing dollar because of the World Cup. The name that you saw in lot of the shirts and on a lot of the stadiums is Coca-Cola or POWERade, there were also lot of marketing dollars behind POWER. But you don't see Sprite or Fanta or Aquarius; you see brand Coca-Cola and you see POWERade, <mark type="inaudible" /> sport drink, so there were some more marketing dollars behind that. And especially I say also that because of the size and the scale that brand Coca-Cola has, that's where you can afford the returnable bottles and cases. In the product that it has an &#x2013; not a high volume for example, let's say that you want to do Fanta or Simba in Brazil turnover, it's very hard to do it, because flavors you have different proprietary shapes for every flavor and different labels and all that, so it's &#x2013; and brand Coca-Cola, it's one bottle, one product with matching the scale and then you can afford &#x2013; the economics of the returnability are easier to achieve when you have that scale of &#x2013; or that massive volume it has, like behind brand Coca-Cola. So I think there are combination all of these factors, and it's very difficult to give a strategic weight to each of them, but a combination of those factors is what is happening behind brand Coca-Cola, Celso.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. And I know it's a long call, but if I could just ask one follow-up; I joined a little bit late and so I heard the end of the PET returnable discussion. I think it was PET, but returnable discussion for Brazil. You mentioned <mark type="inaudible" /> there has ne potential avenue for growth for that, but one of the examples I know you've talked about in the past was Argentina where the mom-and-pops initially had the returnables in term of glass in that case I suppose, and then the supermarkets actually asked for it. Now I know this was in the time for crisis, I know it was a bit different. But is that not something that you think could develop in Brazil or is it really specific to that situation the economic hardships in Argentina and that's why you'll be looking at <mark type="inaudible" /> has potential to be a follow-on rather than supermarkets. And the second part of that is, if you do push a larger size returnables, how does that square with your single-serve initiatives in Brazil? Does it potentially cannibalize some of those opportunities for single-serves in places like <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, let me just go over there. Returnables in Brazil, we started with a two-liter returnable plastic bottle. It has been successful with the mom-and-pops. We have been doing some activation in the <mark type="inaudible" />, mainly because of rather than we continue to sell beer in our <mark type="inaudible" /> and we see how the returnable beer bottles, how the consumer woks with that very well at launch and what they serve with friends in one of these places, <mark type="inaudible" /> or caf&#xE9;s or whatever. So we are doing some activation and that's why we want to follow that direction, because we see that in Brazil there is this &#x2013; the consumer is used to sharing a glass from the same bottle when they are with friends, and that's the main driver behind pushing the <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>If &#x2013; you are correct, in Argentina during the time of crisis the supermarkets were asking for the returnable products, again it was very important for the consumer. At that time I think we did a good job in trying to segment the market. We had a different packages to supermarkets than to mom-and-pops so that we avoid any cannibalization of one channel to the other. And seeing that if the supermarkets in Brazil starts &#x2013; if they start to ask for this product, we certainly have to look at that maybe with a different package, Celso, not necessarily with the same two-liter presentation as we have done in some other markets. Until then you get into a very complicated structure where the &#x2013; it's important that the mom-and-pop has a different package than supermarket, because then you don't have this contamination with this mom-and-pop goes and buys from a supermarket, because it's cheaper. We prefer some promotional activity as compared to <mark type="inaudible" />. But we are open to those strengths and I think that we have the knowledge to manage the different trends also, Celso.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes your question-and-answer session for today's conference. I would like to hand the call over to Mr. Trevino H&#xE9;ctor for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you everyone for your interest in our company, and obviously Jose and his team are available to answer any remaining questions. And if you reach Mexico, please give us a call and I will be there to help you understand better our business. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for you participation in today's conference. This concludes your presentation. And you may now disconnect. Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>