<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1288977" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-02-12</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3057</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o Gutierrez, Chief Financial and Administrative Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst">Lauren Torres</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Robert Ford</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Lore Serra</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Sohail Ahmer</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Jos&#xE9; Yord&#xE1;n</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Alan Alanis</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Celso S&#xE1;nchez</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and welcome to Coca-Cola FEMSA's Fourth Quarter 2009 Results Conference Call. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. At the request of the company, we'll open the conference up for questions and answers after the presentation.</p>
          <p>During this conference call, management may discuss certain forward-looking statements concerning Coca-Cola FEMSA's future performance and should be considered as good faith estimates made by the company. These forward-looking statements reflect management expectations and are based upon currently available data. Actual results are subject to future events and uncertainties, which can materially impact the company's actual performance.</p>
          <p>At this time, I will now turn the conference over to Mr. H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o, Coca-Cola FEMSA's CFO. Please go ahead, Mr. Trevi&#xF1;o.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us today. Last year, we experienced increased challenges in one of the most difficult global economic environments witnessed in recent history. Under these circumstances, our company managed to prove its defensive profile and deliver solid on bottom line results, extending its strong track record of growth.</p>
          <p>Our broad portfolio of products, the wide array of value alternatives that we offer our consumers, and the innovation we developed in new categories were the main pillars for our solid performance during the year, driving double-digit top and bottom line organic growth.</p>
          <p>In the fourth quarter, our consolidated revenues reached Ps. 29 billion, up 28% from the fourth quarter of 2008. Organic revenue growth was driven by increased prices and volumes, which accounted for more than 70% of incremental revenues. A positive exchange rate translation effect represented less than 25% of incremental revenues and the consolidation of Brisa, the water brand in Colombia provided the balance.</p>
          <p>For the full year, our consolidated revenues reached Ps. 103 billion, growing 24%. In the fourth quarter, core consolidated sales volume rose 8.7% year-over-year. Excluding Brisa, our consolidated sales volume increased more than 6%, driven mainly by double-digit growth of brand Coca-Cola in our Mexico and Latincentro divisions and more than 30% growth of the still beverage category across our territories. For the full year, our consolidated organic sales volume grew 5%.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated gross profit increased more than 28% in the fourth quarter. Higher revenues compensated for higher cost of goods sold producing a gross margin expansion of 20 basis points as compared with the fourth quarter of 2008. Consolidated operating income improved 19% to Ps. 4.8 billion in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Revenue growth partially offset the high operating expenses, which resulted from higher labor cost in Venezuela and increased marketing investments in our Mexico and Latincentro regions. The effect of a positive currency translation resulting from the depreciation of the Mexican peso against our operations' local currencies provided more than 40% of our incremental operating income and the consolidation of Brisa in Colombia accounting for more than 5% of our incremental operating income for the quarter. Excluding the acquisition of Brisa and on a currency neutral basis, our consolidated operating income would have grown 10%.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated operating margin declined 120 basis points year-over-year to 16.6% for the quarter. Our consolidated EBITDA grew close to 17% to Ps. 5.8 billion in the quarter. For the full year, EBITDA grew 15% to Ps. 20 billion.</p>
          <p>In the fourth quarter, our net controlling interest income reached Ps. 2.8 billion, mainly as a result of higher operating income combined with a more favorable comprehensive financial result recorded during the fourth quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Let me expand on our operations. Our Mexico division delivered 7.6% volume growth for the quarter. Incremental volumes were driven mainly by double-digit volume growth of brand Coca-Cola combined with growth in the still beverage category due to the innovation generated by the cola-combined platform.</p>
          <p>In the fourth quarter of 2009, our still beverage category grew more than 25%, driven mainly by increased volumes of our orangeade, ValleFrut. During the quarter, the sales volume of <mark type="inaudible" />, which we introduced in the market less than two years ago, reached more than eight million unit cases, becoming one of our top five selling brands in Mexico.</p>
          <p>Our water business, excluding bulk water, recorded double-digit volume growth. This growth was driven by the new image of our Ciel water brand, which we launched during the second half of last year.</p>
          <p>Our average price per unit case increased 2.7% during the quarter. This increase was driven mainly by the higher volumes of brand Coca-Cola and the selective price increases that we implemented during the quarter. Our Mexican operations total revenues &#x2013; more than 10% to Ps. 9.3 billion. Increased volumes accounted for 75% of our total incremental revenues, and a higher average price per unit case represented the balance.</p>
          <p>On the profitability front, higher revenues combined with the lower cost of resins year-over-year helped to mitigate for increased sweetener cost and the third and final stage of the scheduled Coca-Cola company concentrate price increase announced back in 2006. Our gross profit grew more than 10% to Ps. 4.7 billion as compared with the fourth quarter of 2008. Our gross margin in Mexico remained almost flat at 50.6% as compared with the fourth quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Operating income grew 4% to Ps. 1.9 billion. Higher operating expenses were driven mainly by normalized marketing investments during 2009. As you may remember, during the fourth quarter of 2008, we rationalized marketing expenses to adapt our business to the global economic environment.</p>
          <p>The investments made during 2009 were intended to support our growing still beverage platform as well as to deploy resources in the Valley of Mexico to enhance our execution at the point of sale, bolster our returnable base, and improve our cooler coverage. In addition, during the second half of 2009, we supported the launch of Coca-Cola Zero and the new image of our water brand Ciel. As a result, operating margin decreased 130 basis points to 20.5%.</p>
          <p>Our EBITDA remained flat compared with the same quarter of last year, reaching Ps. 2.3 billion. For the full year, our Mexican operations EBITDA reached Ps. 8.5 billion.</p>
          <p>In 2009, the severe global economic crisis produced an important devaluation of the Mexican peso versus the U.S. dollar that affected our dollar denominated raw materials. This effect was the main factor that drove the gross margin pressures reported last year in our Mexican operations. Despite the Mexican GDP contraction in 2009, our Mexican operations delivered volume growth of almost 7% during this difficult year.</p>
          <p>For 2010, we foresee an important challenge that we must confront. Global sugar prices will remain volatile. However, our ability to use fructose in Mexico, combined with an expected more favorable exchange rate of the Mexican peso versus the U.S. dollar, applied towards U.S. dollar denominated raw materials, should help us mitigate higher sugar prices.</p>
          <p>All of our strategies remained focused on our primary goal to provide our consumers with the most valuable alternatives to satisfy their diverse mix. From our brand Coca-Cola approach in returnable packages to products such as ValleFrut our orangeade. This successful launch exemplifies that we have learned to develop novelty products in a short period of time and to manage a wide offering of packages in almost every category, making our portfolio an attractive vehicle to offer value for our consumers. We will continue to evaluate the competitive environment throughout the year to implement selective price increases in our portfolio to compensate for higher sugar prices and increased inflation.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to our Latincentro division. Our Latincentro division falls at 19% volume growth in the fourth quarter. This increase was driven by, one, double-digit growth in the sparkling beverage across the division. Two, the integration of the Brisa bottled water business in Colombia. And three, the strong performance of our still beverage portfolio in Colombia and Central America. Excluding Brisa, the division volume grew close to 10%. For the full year, the division organic volume grew more than 5%.</p>
          <p>In Colombia, volumes increased more than 25% in the fourth quarter, driven mainly by the integration of Brisa and growth in the still beverage category. Over the past 12 months, sparkling beverages sales volume grew despite important price increases implemented in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>In Venezuela, we recorded a 20% volume growth driven by the strong performance of our sparkling beverage category and a low year-over-year comparison resulting from operating distractions that we faced during the fourth quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Our Central America operations recorded sales volume growth of close to 7% as compared to the fourth quarter of 2008. This increase was driven mainly by a mid-single digit volume growth in our sparkling beverage category, and more than 25% growth in our still beverage portfolio.</p>
          <p>Our Latincentro division's total revenues grew 43% to Ps. 10.8 billion. Organic revenue growth, driven by higher volumes and higher average prices per unit case, accounted for more than 90% of our incremental revenues. The integration of Brisa in Colombia represented approximately 5% of our incremental revenues, while a positive currency translation resulting from the depreciation of the Mexican peso against some of our operational local currencies accounting for the balance. On a currency neutral basis and excluding the acquisition of Brisa, our Latincentro division revenues would have been approximately 40%.</p>
          <p>On the profitability front, our Latincentro division gross profit increased 58% to Ps. 4.9 billion. Higher revenues combined with lower cost of resin and the appreciation of the Colombian peso as applied to U.S. dollar denominated raw material cost compensated for the higher cost of sweeteners across the division. Our gross margin reached 45.5%, an expansion of 420 basis points compared with the fourth quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Our operating income grew 32% to Ps. 1.3 billion. Higher operating expenses were driven mainly by higher labor costs in Venezuela, increased marketing investments to support our growing still beverage platform in Colombia and Central America, and the integration of the Brisa water brand in Colombia. As a result, operating margin decreased 100 basis points reaching 12% as compared with the fourth quarter of 2008.</p>
          <p>Thanks to the positive currency translation resulting from the depreciation of the Mexican peso against some of our operations' local currencies accounted for close to 20% of our incremental operating income, and the acquisition of Brisa represented approximately 15% of our incremental operating income for the quarter. Excluding Brisa and on a currency neutral translation, our operating income grew more than 20%. Our EBITDA grew 33% to Ps. 1.7 billion as compared with the fourth quarter of 2008. For the full year, our Latincentro division's EBITDA reached Ps. 6.2 billion.</p>
          <p>In 2009, our Latincentro division delivered strong results. In the past 12 months, we have advanced our strategy to build a comprehensive portfolio amplifying the beverage categories in which we participate. At the same time, we reinforced our position in the Water segment through the acquisition of Brisa. The sparkling beverage portfolio demonstrated its defensive strength by growing mid-single digits year-over-year across the division despite increased pricing designed to compensate for local inflation and higher food costs.</p>
          <p>Now let me talk about our Mercosur division. In the fourth quarter of 2009, our Mercosur division total revenues grew to 32% reaching almost Ps. 9 billion. Excluding beer, which accounted for Ps. 990 million, our total revenues reached Ps. eight billion. Organic growth, driven mainly by higher average prices per unit case, represented more than 35% of our incremental revenues. The effect of a positive currency translation resulting from the depreciation of the Mexican peso against the Brazilian real provide the balance.</p>
          <p>Volume growth in our Mercosur division was up 2.3% in the fourth quarter of 2009. Our Brazilian operations recorded mid-single digit volume growth, driven mainly by brand Coca-Cola in multi-serve presentations, and the continued strong performance of the Jugos del Valle line of beverages. In Argentina, however, volume declined mid-single digits, mainly due to the prevailing tough economic environment and the bad weather we experienced in the city of Buenos Aires.</p>
          <p>On the profitability front, our Mercosur division gross profit increased more than 23% to Ps. 3.8 billion. Higher revenues combined with the lower cost of resin across the division and the appreciation of the Brazilian real partially compensated for the increased cost of sweetener across the division and the year-over-year devaluation of the Argentine peso as applies to our U.S. dollar denominated raw material costs.</p>
          <p>Our gross profit margins decreased 290 basis points to 42.4% for the fourth quarter of 2009. During the fourth quarter of 2008, we recorded a one-time operational tax benefit in Brazil equivalent to approximately Ps. 180 million. Excluding these effects, our Mercosur division gross margins during the fourth quarter of 2009 would have remained flat.</p>
          <p>Our operating income grew 31% to Ps. 1.6 billion. Operating leverage achieved through our higher revenues and control of operating expenses compensated for gross margin pressures. Our operating margin remained almost flat at 18.1% in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>The effect of a positive currency translation resulting from the depreciation of the Mexican peso against the Brazilian real accounted for approximately 70% of our incremental operating income. On a currency neutral basis, our Mercosur division operating income grew close to 10% in the fourth quarter of 2009. Our EBITDA grew more than 31% to Ps. 1.8 billion. For the full year, our Mercosur division's EBITDA grew more than 27%, reaching Ps. 5 billion.</p>
          <p>In 2009, our Mercosur division delivered positive results <mark type="inaudible" /> expansion of our beverage categories. Our still beverage products base is growing faster due to the integration of Jugos del Valle line of beverage in Brazil, helping us to amplify the current array of juice-based beverage offerings and to accelerate our novelty capabilities in the market.</p>
          <p>Now let me walk you through our financial performance for the quarter and the full year. At the beginning of 2009, adverse global economic conditions presented many challenges for both companies and consumers. Under these conditions, our balanced and diversified portfolio of assets delivered strong results peaking our free cash flow generation.</p>
          <p>Today, more than ever, our company is in strong operating and financial position to continue growing, investing in our business, and ultimately delivering an attractive return to our investors. As of December 31, 2009, we have a cash balance of Ps. 9.7 billion, an increase of Ps. 3.5 billion compared with year-end 2008. Our total debt decreased Ps. 2.6 billion compared with year-end 2009. This decrease was driven mainly by the maturity of our Yankee Bond in the amount of $265 million and the maturity of our peso bond in the amount of Ps. 500 million for July of 2009.</p>
          <p>As a result of the above-mentioned factors, our net debt balance decreased by Ps. 6.2 billion at year-end 2009. On December 31, 2009, our net debt to EBITDA coverage ratio was 0.3 times, and our EBITDA to net interest coverage was above 12 times, highlighting the strength of our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>On February 5, 2010, we successfully issued a 10-year Yankee Bond in the amount of $500 million at a deal of 4.689% with a coupon of 4.625%. This transaction marked our first return to the U.S. capital markets since 1996, underscoring our company's fundamental investment grade credit rating and the ability to access international markets at very attractive rates. We intend to use the net proceeds from this issuance to refinance certain maturities and for general corporate purposes. We are very pleased with this successful transaction.</p>
          <p>As you may already know, on January 11 of this year, 2010, the Venezuelan government authorities announced a devaluation of their currency, the bolivar, and the establishment of a multiple exchange rate system. According to accounting practices, this event will not have an effect on our 2009 financial results and balance sheet. For 2010, we expect this devaluation will increase our operating cost as a result of the exchange rate movement applied to our U.S. dollar denominated raw material costs and reduce our Venezuelan operations financial statements when translated into our reporting currency, the Mexican peso. According to accounting practices, the exchange rate that will be used as of January 2010 for translation purposes in our financial statements will be the one at which we can remit dividends. We are still awaiting a resolution on this matter.</p>
          <p>2009 was a difficult year for all of us. Our company's strong results came from our firm conviction to maximize the value potential of our multi-national portfolio of assets with fancy guard view of our industry, the strong brand equity of our products, and our new line of businesses, and the innovation we always pursue across all of our processes were key factors to achieve these strong results.</p>
          <p>Once again, this year represents opportunities and challenges for us. Our operating and financial flexibility positions our business to continue growing in one of the more dynamic and attractive regions in the world to sell beverages, Latin America. We never stop learning. These lessons we have acquired over the past years will strengthen our ability to continue outperforming in our industry. Our team of talented professionals is our most valuable asset. They are continuously developing the operational experience and innovation capabilities to expand our company's track record of solid results for our stakeholders and investors. Thank you for your continued trust.</p>
          <p>Now before I open up the call for questions, I would also like to announce an important change in my team. Alfredo Fern&#xE1;ndez who has been working with me as Head of Investor Relations for Coca-Cola FEMSA since 2001 has been invited by our Mexican operations to continue his career path with our company. Alfredo has worked well relentlessly to position our story as a benchmark in the global beverage industry. Alfredo, thank you very much for all your support. We wish you the best with your new assignments.</p>
          <p>As new Head of Investor Relations, we have appointed Jose Castro. Jose has been part of the corporate finance team of Coca-Cola FEMSA since 2003. I'm sure that Jose will extend Alfredo's successful track record. And through his experience, he will help our analysts and investors in the coming years. Welcome, Jose.</p>
          <p>Now I would like to open up the call for any questions that you may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from the line of Lauren Torres with HSBS (sic) [HSBC] .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Actually first I want to congratulate Alfredo. And secondly, if I could ask about expansion opportunities this year, it seems like you along with FEMSA have been somewhat vocal about investment opportunities this year, and I was just curious to get a sense of where you see these opportunities? You've spoken about building out your business in and outside of Latin America. So any more comments on that would be helpful. And also with respect to brands, as you've been acquiring brands, if you feel that there's more opportunities on that front?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Lauren. Let me just address some of these issues then.</p>
          <p>Growing in this industry has proven to be difficult by acquisitions. I mean we have been successful with some of these acquisitions in the past, but if you look at our track record, we did the Buenos Aires transaction, then with a small piece of Mexico in the Tapachula region, then the big acquisition of Panamco that took us some time to digest and integrate. And then we just have several transactions that helped us to diversify our portfolio approach like Jugos del Valle transaction or Brisa or the acquisition of Agua de Los Angeles in Mexico, another water plant.</p>
          <p>As you know, we are totally committed to work together with the Coca-Cola company in this front with respect to the brands that you mentioned in your question. Any transaction that we might do in the future, if it's a different category of a different brand, we'll be always together with the Coca-Cola Company.</p>
          <p>And with respect to geographic expansions, we continue to look at some alternatives and to have our eyes open. Just as an information, because I think that there were some rumors in the past, the owners of the franchise in Ecuador were in a process to entertain proposals. We were there, present, and the process had to stop. We need to wait for the clarification of what are the intentions of the owners of that brand, but that was probably the closest thing that we have in our radar screen.</p>
          <p>And just continuing to answer your questions, we will see opportunities to expand outside of Latin America. As we mentioned in the last few months, we believe that we have a Coca-Cola Company's door open for us to look at some of those alternatives. Right now, we don't have anything in our radar screen in that sense, and that's basically where we're expanding those.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if I could also ask one other question with respect to your initial thoughts on the deal with Heineken and how you see that working SKU benefits and how are you going to go about working with them now in a closer capacity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For us, Lauren, it really doesn't have any specific implication. I know that they are working very closely with the guys from FEMSA Cerveza to &#x2013; just to close the transaction and start taking over the operations.</p>
          <p>We continue selling Kaiser beer in our trucks in Brazil, because we have that contract. We have continued with this very, very small pilot more as a learning process for Coca-Cola FEMSA to &#x2013; just to be ready in case there are changes in the marketplace in Mexico that we are not foreseeing presently. But also, as we mentioned during the last quarter conference call, I think that the most important element of this is continue to learn from managing multiple categories.</p>
          <p>So far, I don't think that there is any specific implication for us, Lauren, with respect to this Heineken and FEMSA Cerveza transaction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Robert Ford with Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, everybody, and congratulations on the quarter, H&#xE9;ctor. I had a question with respect to Venezuela. And of the Ps. 10.8 billion that you have in revenue from Latincentro, how much is coming from Venezuela in revenue, as well as the 1.7 billion in EBITDA?</p>
          <p>And I know you are &#x2013; going forward, you're going to use the FX rate to translate &#x2013; the same FX rate at which you remit, and I was curious, when was the last time you actually were able to access the remittance rate for dividends in Venezuela?</p>
          <p>And I do understand that some industries are able to access that preferred lower FX rate of 260 for critical inputs, and I understand that you maybe one of those companies, which could suggest that, at least in a bad environment, you're still doing fairly well. And I was curious how much difficulty you're having accessing that preferred FX rate of 260 right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Bob. I think that this is a very important question for us at this time of the year. And we just had our board meeting, and obviously all &#x2013; a very important part of the board meeting was dedicated to the issues of Venezuela. Let me give you some flavor of what we are seeing.</p>
          <p>First of all, we will look at the 2009 figures. We have very long conversations with auditors, and we analyzed several options, and we concluded, together with the auditors, and that was in our understanding what other companies are doing, is that since this devaluation of the bolivar happened in January 2010, we should not affect 2009 figures. That's first point. 2009 stays as it's been reported.</p>
          <p>However, let me give you some flavor of where the numbers can go going forward. There are two main effects. One is the impact of this new exchange rates on raw materials. In there, we think that we feel very comfortable with &#x2013; that we will have access in a big portion of our raw materials to the 2.6 exchange rate, which is basically a 20% devaluation from 215 to 2.6.</p>
          <p>The rules are that in order for you to access this preferred exchange rate, you have to have what is called the certificate of non-local production. It's called CNP for the acronym. And we have that CNP for this full year for PET &#x2013; for resin and for sugar, in case we need to import sugar because remember that we buy it local. But sometimes there have been some deficits in the sugar industry in Venezuela, and we need to import that. And we have that CNP because we needed that to have access to the 215 exchange rate during 2009. So on PET and sugar, we feel very comfortable that we will have the smaller impact of all the impacts available in Venezuela, which is this 20% devaluation.</p>
          <p>Cans, we haven't had the CNP for 2009 and we don't have it for 2010. We buy locally, but the supplier has not been able to buy aluminum at the lower exchange rate. So cans during all 2009 were acquired at the parallel market, and we were suffering that cost during 2009. And I believe that's going to be the impact that we'll have on cans during 2010. So that's basically one leg of the equation, which is the effect that we have on dollar-denominated cost in the operation.</p>
          <p>Now the second leg of the equation is how do we translate those numbers into Mexican peso, which is our reporting currency? And as we mentioned, we need to define &#x2013; the accounting rule says that generally that we can remit dividends, we should use that. We have the declared a dividend in Venezuela recently &#x2013; last week &#x2013; and we are in the process of requesting the dollar access to just to pay us that position. However, in the past, we have asked for dividends and we have been denied the authorization, so I don't mistake that in the short term we'll have a larger to fix dividend request.</p>
          <p>If we look at the 2009 figures as an example, and we were to use the 430 exchange rates, so that you have an idea of the size of the impact that we might have, Venezuela during 2009 represented around 20% of revenues and around 12% of EBITDA. If we reduce the 430 exchange rates, those numbers will go down to around 10% of revenues and around 6% of EBITDA. I do believe that 6% for EBITDA, it's a more reasonable number when you compare that to the importance that Venezuela has in our portfolio since the acquisition of Panamco 2003. It started around 4% of EBITDA. And where we have improved a lot the operation and the profitability of the Venezuelan operation. So it has grown in importance, but certainly 12% of EBITDA was a large number and was affected basically by this exchange rate translation effects.</p>
          <p>So in summary, Bob, I will say that we will have an impact on some of the raw materials, but the majority of the raw materials that we have which is PET, sugar, are &#x2013; we have this certificate of non-local production that will give us access to 60 bolivars per dollar. We have to buy cans at the 430 and then the translation, we are thinking and discussing with the auditors that if we don't have an answer in the short term, we should be using the 430 exchange rate that is basically 100% devaluation of &#x2013; in that translation effect. And that would basically devise our own cash, the numbers that I just mentioned. So Venezuela during 2010 should be representing around 6% of EBITDA on a consolidated basis. There will be some uncertainty, because obviously we will start using the 430 and then we have access to dividends, we might need to change the currency. But we will fully disclose that to you guys when I can fully understand what we are doing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Lore Serra with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. I actually want to just go back to Venezuela for a second. When you mentioned, Hector, that you were buying at the parallel rate in cans this year, does that mean you're buying at the effective whatever it was, five or six rate, instead of the official rate? That's one question.</p>
          <p>And then I want to understand, do you have pricing flexibility in Venezuela? So I understand the translation effect is what it is, I'm just trying to understand do you expect to be EBITDA margin positive in Venezuela in '10? Or do you expect to lose money on an EBITDA basis in Venezuela this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Lore, good morning. The first question, yes, parallel market is around six, and during last year we were buying cans and sometimes other raw materials like caps and labels at that parallel market around six bolivars per dollar.</p>
          <p>With respect to the profitability and pricing flexibility of this year, those are certainly risks that we need to confront us, as we have experienced in other countries in the past. Every time that a country goes through a difficult situation like the one that Venezuela is going right now, we do have less pricing flexibility because there are concerns about inflation and pressures to try to manage inflation. That's one risk that we have, and this is very recently and we have not had any pressures so far, but it's certainly a risk.</p>
          <p>One other element of the risk, which is important to mention, that is &#x2013; to mention and even though it's probably &#x2013; so that you come into the radar screen, it's pressures on sellers. Venezuela and we have mentioned several times between conference calls that Venezuela has very high labor costs and very difficult process for the negotiation of those contracts. We don't know at this moment if this valuation of the bolivar will put extra pressure on some of these dollars. And so far if we look at our budget for Venezuela, I think that we basically believe that we can be EBITDA positive. I don't think that we will get to a negative number in the EBITDA, but with the caveat that obviously we have a lot of volatility in the country.</p>
          <p>And as I mentioned, those are some of the main risks that we have noted. We have pricing flexibility or not to pass along some of the cost increases of raw materials. Pressure from labor in terms of extraordinary increases because of the remuneration and obviously the environment in Venezuela that has been difficult for several years in terms of the operations disruption or something like that. But with our preliminary assumptions we believe that Venezuela will be profitable this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. Thanks very much. And can you just remind me what percentage of costs are resin, sugar and aluminum in Venezuela?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. If you split sugar and PET are between 20 to 25% each. Then you have a more important percentage, which is the concentrate that since we are in an incident base level, we don't have a foreign exchange problem there. And with those three you basically get very close to 80% of our costs of goods sold and aluminum cans is very small because it's not as important, but it should be around 5% aluminum.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Sohail Ahmer with Lusight.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I have a few questions on sweetener costs in general. Not just the cost but in terms of availability. So I just want to confirm if you have availability in each of your markets? What sweetener you need? And also in, 2009 was a tough year, so it was harder to push through any cost increments in this, in the last year but I'm wondering if you're going to make up for that in this year? And perhaps is there a likelihood of seeing higher margins quarter on quarter on a seasonally adjusted basis?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. As far as availability, we don't see any problem. The only place where we have some problems with availability in the past and we might see that in the future is Venezuela because of all the very complex process to import goods whenever you have that need. Venezuela produces a lot of sugar, but it's deficitary in that and the equal process in the past have been very complex by the suppliers, and during 2009 we have some scary moments where we were very close to not having sugar in our production facilities. So I think that Venezuela, that's the only case that will worry me in 2010. The rest, it's more an issue of the price rather than of availability of sugar, and as we mentioned during this conference call, we do have some flexibility to use some alternative sweeteners like high fructose corn syrup and some other corns.</p>
          <p>With respect to margins, I think that in general year-end, the very strong decline in growth in the economy where we operate we basically have approximately 7% reduction in GDP in Mexico. In Brazil, obviously, behaved better with a flat GDP growth versus 2008. But in general most of our &#x2013; the countries where we operate had a very negative macroeconomic environment, so it was very difficult to increase prices. We were successful in some increase, some of the packing on the large formats in Mexico. We were able to increase prices importantly in Columbia because the competitors were also moving, and in some cases we were following, sometimes we increased prices beforehand and some of the competitors then were following us in Columbia, but we did have some price &#x2013; a lot of pricing flexibility in Columbia.</p>
          <p>So market by market, I feel comfortable that we were very close to having either flat pricing, prices in real term, or slightly negative, that given the fact that we were with this deceleration in the economies, I feel very comfortable. I think that going forward one of the elements that will play in our favor is the effect of the FX translation in some of the raw material costs, with the exception of Venezuela, as I explained, the previous question. Mexico was &#x2013; Mexican peso was clearly the worst performing currency last year. We don't expect that to continue this year given the fact that we think that it's now a little bit under-valued. So given that we see a little bit more stability on the currencies we feel that some of the cost pressure will not necessarily be there.</p>
          <p>But going forward, 2010, obviously we will again try to keep prices with inflation and to maintain or slightly improve our margins leaving all the variables, no higher sugar price, a better FX environment and that's basically what we are seeing for 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Do you have a consolidated figure for the percentage of your costs that are denominated in U.S. dollars?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. On a consolidated basis, it's around 30% of cost of goods sold.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jos&#xE9; Yord&#xE1;n with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning, Hector and everyone. My question on Venezuela was answered already, but just a question on the dividend. I saw that you doubled the dividend, but given that you're saying that there's no potential acquisitions of any size and even if you are able to turnaround Ecuador, you probably can finance that with a couple of weeks cash flow. Why still hoarding cash? I mean you should be able to quadruple at least the dividend without really any impact on your financial position. I would still be conservative. So why you are still holding cash to a certain extent even though letting go of a little bit is a good start? I would have expected something more aggressive at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, Jose. Generally that's &#x2013; if I should give some priorities to the two issues that were discussed the most during the Board meeting that we had a couple of days ago and in the finance committee, one was Venezuela and on the reporting things as I mentioned and the other one was the capital structure of Coke FEMSA, and given the fact that we're basically reaching the level where we might have on the net debt position basically, went to zero very fast.</p>
          <p>The message that we received from the &#x2013; and it's a probably a bit conservative &#x2013; is that rather than giving a very large numbers in dividends and then maybe be confronted with an opportunity to grow by acquisitions and then reduce that dividend, that they felt that it was better to increase the dividend double the size right now. We are still below some of our peers in terms of our yield on that, and you look at the dividend yield &#x2013; our dividend yield, and just to continue to increase little by little as opposed to having reductions in the dividends going forward.</p>
          <p>The one element that is still there, which I think is important, that I want to mention is that even though we don't have any specific transaction on our radar screen, it really doesn't mean that we are not looking for opportunities. So we will continue to look for opportunities strongly. Always with a very &#x2013; let me use the word &#x2013; with a very wise approach of doing some transactions that make sense for our investors and shareholders in terms of value and &#x2013; vis a vis the opportunities to grow and all of that. But we still believe that &#x2013; whether we can continue to grow.</p>
          <p>So it's important that we don't go to a situation where we totally pay all the excess cash and start just having like very small cash balances or very high debt levels in this structure. So the debt structure of the company is an issue because it's not efficient but we feel that we still have opportunities. If we don't see those opportunities the answer from our Directors is we don't see those opportunities we will continue to incur dividends. But we think right now that we will have some opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it, I know you guys always do a dividend once a year, is it possible that if come October, let's say, you have not turned anything up &#x2013; to turn up with any adequate acquisition opportunities etcetera that you would pay a second dividend, an extraordinary dividend, such as what Arca does for example and then several other companies in Mexico? Is that even possible or likely under Coke FEMSA's by-laws or not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Under the by-laws is it possible. To be very honest I think that from Q2 October it's going to be a short period of time to change our mind in terms of the opportunities to grow. But I mean what is certain is that we will continue to review every Board meeting what is present to us in terms of opportunities, probabilities of those to happen. And if we are at a stage where we feel that we don't have the need to start accumulating those cash balances, you're right, we might decide to pay some extra dividends. I don't think that October, I mean I think that October is too close to change our minds in terms of the acquisition opportunities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Alan Alanis with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Congratulations, Alfredo and best of lucks with Jose. Welcome. Actually the question is going to sound a little bit bizarre knowing that Jose is now coming to take over IR. But in the line of Jose Yordan's question, could you remind us toward the merits of keeping Coca-Cola FEMSA listed. I mean you decided, I mean the Board decided to increase the dividend to x amount, but it's not &#x2013; I mean you could like it was said previously it could have been much, much higher than that. And to a levered buy-out you can easily take out the float and still be easily under two times, if not much less than two times net debt-to-EBITDA. So I think it's a good opportunity to remind us, all of us what are the merits of having the Coca-Cola FEMSA listed, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I appreciate your comments Alan and obviously we have very aptly discussed this with Jose also if he's joining. That's certainly a possibility. I mean I know you read every other press release or every other research report that that possibility.</p>
          <p>Let me give you what is our philosophy here. We do believe still that having Coca-Cola FEMSA listed help us in several niches. One is the visibility that we have with some of our peers. Clearly, they follow our reports. They see the track record that we have and you can argue that they can follow that if they look at the FEMSA report or whatever, but it's important from a perspective of the dialog that we have with our peers are very often. But the most important element is that we still have not conclude on the issue of the Coca-Cola FEMSA shares a currency that is attractive for acquisition or not. At some point in time we're thinking that in theory FEMSA could do an acquisition and use FEMSA shares as a currency, which is a more liquid share and all of that. And that's still a viable alternative. I'm not sure what the impact of this Heineken transaction letter &#x2013; transaction will have in terms of the implications for FEMSA shares of the currency.</p>
          <p>We still believe, Alan, and &#x2013; that the sort of dialog that we have had with some of the bottlers that some of them do not want to exit the business. In the words of some of these bottlers, especially in Mexico, that I have heard is that the best business they know in the world is a well-run Coca-Cola bottling operation and the second best business that they know is a bad-run Coca-Cola operation in Mexico. So we are still facing with this question, but we don't have an answer yet, if Coca-Cola shares is an attractive currency for acquisition. But some of these bottlers might not be interested in exiting the business, but we believe that without Coke FEMSA as a public company, we might attract some of these investors that are interested in the Coca-Cola operation alone, not beer nor us nor cash to invest in software companies or whatever.</p>
          <p>If we get to the conclusion that this is not the case and I have to recognize that this has not been the case in the last 16, 17 years that I've been CFO of this company, then certainly taking Coca-Cola FEMSA parallely supporting it, and as you said it's very well within the reach of Coke FEMSA to do that. So far we have analyzed that.</p>
          <p>We haven't basically concluded, we are in the process of reviewing that again and again and I had the opportunity to listen to some of the comments that friends have made during the road show when they were explaining the Heineken transaction and they said that they were open to analyzing either doing a larger float for Coke FEMSA or taking Coca-Cola FEMSA private.</p>
          <p>So it's in the top of mind of the management, but we, as of February of 2010, we haven't concluded that we don't need FEMSA shares to attract some potential targets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, I hear you. Thank you, H&#xE9;ctor. That was useful now. In terms of just going into the operations, the trend of the operating expenses, particularly in Latincentro and Mexico, are quite concerning in the fourth quarter. Could you comment going forward how this should look in your view in 2010? And I have a similar question regarding CapEx. If you could isolate there how much of the CapEx in the fourth quarter was regarding any acquisition and what CapEx guidance could you provide for 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Alan. Let me go first to the operating expenses line. I think that this quarter we have like a very &#x2013; a lot of variations on those lines. The main impact that we have is in Mexico. Last year we were very much concerned with the well being of the business and we stopped during the fourth quarter a lot of the marketing projects that we have. If you look at the marketing expense as a percentage of revenues in Mexico during the fourth quarter, was basically around 1.3% of revenues and you know that we basically are around three, 4%, sometimes 4.5% of revenues depending on some marketing activities. So if you look at fourth quarter versus 2009 versus 2008, marketing expenses were basically double as a percentage of revenue. We ended up with a 2.6, 2.7 marketing expense as part of revenues during the fourth quarter. If you look at the full year 2008 versus 2009 you still see some differences in the marketing expenses. 2008 we ended up with around 3.2, 3.3% of revenues while 2009 we ended up around 3.8% marketing expenses to revenue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that marketing is matched by Coca-Cola, correct? So this is also...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sorry. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's matched by Coca-Cola, yes. It's 50 and 50, and that's the way it has been always, no?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In Latincentro, we have all this additional expenses with respect to marketing with a new campaign for Brisa in Columbia. We did spend a little bit more resources in marketing because we were increasing prices in Columbia, importantly. So it was again a little bit more on the marketing expense.</p>
          <p>There are many initiatives now within the company to try to control better all this fixed cost structure. We have in Latincentro the effect of labor that will be reflected in SG&amp;A in Venezuela. We spent some time on a previous question about that and the pressure that it will receive, so the recent initiatives what we are trying to isolate, Alan, is that there are many expenses that traditionally you would think that are fixed that has to go along with the distribution and sales force. But when you start dissecting and drilling down on those expenses, some of them I would not say that our fixed are quasi &#x2013; quasi fixed, but there are quasi-variable also. You have variable compensation to some of the sales personnel and you have the depreciation expense on trucks and forklifts and warehouses space and all of that. That, as you continue to grow volumes, or as you continue to increase the number of SKUs, you immediately see an impact on those expenses or costs that you felt that were, that traditionally you would think that are fixed, no? So there's a big effort on the companies to try to better understand that situation and to better manage these expenses. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes that was useful. Thanks. And in terms of CapEx, just quickly CapEx going forward, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. CapEx for next year will be a bit higher than 2009. The budget that was presented to us, we were calling for around $500 million. My personal gut feeling is that if every year we have a request for a special amount of CapEx and then projects get a little delay, and even you start on time, you will not expand on the results because of the velocity of the investments and the transportation of equipment or building warehouses and all of that, so my gut feeling is that it's going to be somewhere around 420 to 450 for 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Celso S&#xE1;nchez with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. I just wondered if you could update us a little bit on the Brazil still beverage opportunities? And if you could just remind us how the Jugos del Valle and Matte Le&#xE3;o integration is going, in terms of fitting it into the existing business, how the coverage is going, if it's where you want it to be. Sort of where we are in that process? I know it took a little bit longer there obviously than it did in Mexico but clearly it's a compelling opportunity. So if you could update us on that, please. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Celso, good morning. Let me give you some flavor there in Brazil. I mean you are totally right. It took a little bit longer. It was already an existing operation with Jugos and Matte Le&#xE3;o, and I would have thought that just integrating Jugos del Valle into the same platform was going to be easier. We have some issues with integration. I think that the most important change that we have made are the two important changes. One is that actually the mails, which was a few years ago the marketing guy for Coca-Cola FEMSA in the operations in Mexico, he was appointed as the CEO of Jugos del Valle in Mexico. He was there for two years and now, as of January, he has started as the CEO of the JV in Brazil.</p>
          <p>I think that that's going to be a positive change for the operations in Brazil. The previous CEO that we had was the same that Jugos del Valle had that has had a very successful experience of starting Jugos del Valle from zero to the number one juice company in Brazil was under the helm of the three previous owners. But at the end of the day dealing with 16 different bottlers and the CEO and et cetera was not working out, so we decided to this change and I think it's an important change. Even though I'm saying that the volumes are growing very fast. I mean <mark type="inaudible" /> around one million unit cases last year and now we're selling around three million unit cases. So it's basically tripling the volumes of the operation. Now those are numbers for the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Now with respect to Matte Le&#xE3;o, that company was acquired by the Coca-Cola company. It went through a long process with CADE, which is the Antitrust Commission in Brazil. It finally got approval somewhere last year. They requested that Nestea be dropped or suspended from the -from our trucks, and starting either this week or the following week we are starting to sell Matte Le&#xE3;o on a ready-to-drink presentation, and we are stopping the process of selling Nestea and this is happening as we speak. I believe it's next week when we start <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>That's the way the operation for the ready-to-drink tea is going to work. We have finalized together with the Coca-Cola Company and the 16 bottlers how &#x2013; the process to integrate that into Jugos del Valle. The price that we have to pay the Coca-Cola Company for that acquisition, which is basically the costs that they have plus some current costs and some other expenses that they have when they <mark type="inaudible" /> manage these operations so I think it was a pressure value.</p>
          <p>We split the &#x2013; half of the price and so this is on the 50/50 joint venture umbrella. We split between the 16 bottlers what has to be paid by who among ourselves. So all that process is behind us and now we are ready to yet to go forward and use Matte Le&#xE3;o as the new platform.</p>
          <p>On the dry part, and by dry I mean the tea bags that is also part of the business, we continue to be managed by the Matte Le&#xE3;o personnel because it's a different product that it's not necessarily as appropriate to go in our process as the case of ready-to-drink tea. But everyone is owner in their own participation according to how they want to split. So the Coca-Cola Company owns 50% of the dry tea of these tea bags and the bottlers we own the other half, and we will benefit from profits on that. But in the meantime, during this year the decision was that we should continue to be handled by the people that were doing this process in Matte Le&#xE3;o. A year from now, we will review and see there is a different alternative to handle the tea bags industry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Should we think about the profitability of the business in terms of what trickles down to the bottlers sort of like it's been in Mexico where it gets reinvested in the brands? Or do we &#x2013; should we see some profit enhancement on the bottler and as you consolidate these operations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think that at the beginning with respect to Matte Le&#xE3;o, we are going to continue to invest behind the brand because we are just taking over that and it's important that we invest there. And from our perspective, we will have a price at which this product is sold to all by the manufacturing facilities and we have a distribution margin. We're saying that we're having basically in Jugos del Valle in Mexico, no? It's not the full margin that we have when we compare to the carbonated soft drink market, but this arrangement that we have explained to you guys before, which is, where the others will be we have a distribution margin on whatever profits that remain in the operation, we split half and half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is a follow-up question from the line of Lore Serra with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks for taking the follow-up. I just wanted to go back to Mexico real quickly. You have had really strong volume growth the last couple of quarters in Mexico, yet the pricing seems to be lagging and I know you took some price increases recently, but it didn't look like as much of them stuck into the fourth quarter as I would have guessed. And I know there's probably a lot of mixed issues, so can you talk a little bit about the pricing outlook in Mexico for '10? You know, why can't you get pricing more in line with inflation? Why is pricing up only 1.5% year-on-year? I suppose there's a lot of mix effects, but we would like your perspective on that please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Lore, good ones. Yes, you're right, the main impact of this is a mix change. We have, in the numbers that you see, we have an important growth as you mentioned in brand Coca-Cola that help us a little bit vis-&#xE0;-vis water products or even some of the juice products like the orangeade that have a lower price per unit case. Orangeades continue to grow very fast and that pushes the equation a little to the other side. Just so that you have an idea, in Mexico, for a product that was not existent a year and a half ago, two years ago, where Mexico as a country sold a little bit more than 50 million unit cases of ValleFrut product. In our case, in Coca-Cola FEMSA territories was in Mexico 30 million unit cases. And that obviously pulls a little bit the price down, because of the pricing equation on that.</p>
          <p>The other big trend is, as we enter a very difficult macroeconomic environment, consumers no question moved to larger packages, and larger packages obviously as you are well aware, it will carry a lower price per unit case. We have several initiatives to try to bolster or to foster the consumption of single-serves and we think we see very promising things in terms of developing new packages and things like that into single serve categories that we expect will help us with the pricing equation. But the main impact of not having this, of not passing &#x2013; not fully passing inflation in our prices has to do with mix changes. In every category we try to increase it to the level that is appropriate always taking in consideration the rounding figures that when you have a low price product going from Ps. five to Ps. six, it is a very large increment and you need to manage that. But it's again in summary the main impact is mix change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you just...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe that &#x2013; sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I'm sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just analyze this. I think that 2010, I'm hopeful that we will see a little more of economic growth in our economies and we will have a little bit more pricing flexibility.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I'm sorry. Thanks for that. And then just a follow-up. If you strip out orangeade and you strip out water and you just look at sparkling and specifically brand Coke, are you seeing any evidence of downgrading to the larger sized bottles is starting to slow down? Are you still seeing that trend as strong in the fourth quarter as it was, I don't know, two or three quarters ago?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. If we strip the orangeades and the water, certain gallon at which price. But even if we just look at, let's say, <mark type="inaudible" /> or even just brand Coca-Cola for 2009 we saw, as we mentioned, <mark type="inaudible" /> almost flat but basically had to do with chief stores the large packages that are worth mentioning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes our question-and-answer session. I would now like to hand the call over to management for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, everyone, for your attention to this conference call and the interest in the company. And I know that Jos&#xE9; will take over Alfredo's job with a lot of strength. And Gonzalo and Roland will continue to work with Jos&#xE9; and we are here to answer any questions that you might have. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation in today's conference. This concludes the presentation and you may now disconnect. Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>