<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1370061" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-02-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3057</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o Gutierrez, Chief Financial and Administrative Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst">Lauren Torres</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Alan Alanis</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Lore Serra</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Jose Yordan</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Celso S&#xE1;nchez</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and welcome to Coca-Cola FEMSA's Fourth Quarter 2010 Earnings Results Conference Call. As a reminder, today's conference is being recorded and all participants are in a listen-only mode. At the request of the company we will open up the conference for question and answers after the presentation.</p>
          <p>During the conference call, management may discuss their forward-looking statements concerning Coca-Cola FEMSA's future performance, and should be considered as good faith estimates made by the company. These forward-looking statements reflect management expectations and are based upon currently available data. Actual results are subject to future events and uncertainties, which can materially impact the company's actual performance.</p>
          <p>At this time, I would now turn the conference over to Mr. H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o, Coca-Cola FEMSA's CFO. Please go ahead, Mr. Trevi&#xF1;o.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us today. Last year our company continued to extend its track record of profitable growth despite the unusually bad weather conditions across our Mexico and Latincentro divisions during that and most of the part of the year, and the effects of our Venezuelan bolivar <mark type="inaudible" />. The strength of our <mark type="inaudible" /> business profile and our operator's disciplined ability to adapt our company through a complex market environment enabled us to deliver solid growth, resulting in double-digit growth in volume per share <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>In the fourth quarter, our consolidated revenues were $38 billion pesos, down 3.6% from the fourth quarter of 2009, mainly due to devaluation of the Venezuelan bolivar. On a currency neutral basis, our consolidated total revenues grew 12% for the quarter driven by volume growth <mark type="inaudible" /> Mexico divisions, and the pricing initiatives implemented across our territories. For the full year, our consolidated revenues grew 1% year-over-year to 103 billion Mexican pesos. In the fourth quarter, our consolidated cash volume rose 1% year-over-year, despite the usually bad weather conditions in our Latincentro division.</p>
          <p>Our increased sales volume resulted mainly from the strong performance of <mark type="inaudible" /> division and volume growth in our sparkling beverages in our Mexico division. For the full year, our consolidated sales volume grew 3%. Our consolidated gross profit declined 3% in the fourth quarter 2010. Higher sweetener  <mark type="inaudible" /> were offset by leverage from higher revenues in local currencies in our Latincentro division, combined with the appreciation of our main operation local currencies as applied to our U.S. dollars in <mark type="inaudible" />. Also currently, our gross margin expanded <mark type="inaudible" /> as compared with the fourth quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Consolidated operating income improved 5% to 5 billion pesos in the fourth quarter, as a result of double digit operating income growth in our Latincentro divisions. Operating strength in local currency increased mainly as a result of higher label and trade costs in Argentina, continued marketing investments in our Mexico division and higher label cost in Venezuela.</p>
          <p>On a currency neutral basis operating income grew 24% and our consolidated operating margins increased by 150 basis points year-over-year to 18.1%.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated EBITDA grew 5% to 6.1 billion pesos in the fourth quarter. For the full year consolidated EBITDA grew close to 7%.</p>
          <p>In the fourth quarter, our net consolidated income rose 7% to 3 billion pesos, mainly as a result of higher operating income. For the full year, net consolidated income increased 15% reaching close to 10 billion pesos or the equivalent of 5.31 pesos for each <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>Now let me expand on our operations. Our Mexico division delivered close to 3% volume growth for the quarter. Incremental volumes were driven mainly by our sparkling <mark type="inaudible" /> supported by brand Coca-Cola, combined with mid-single digit volume growth in the <mark type="inaudible" /> categories, mainly due to the <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>Our average price per unit case increased 3.7% in the fourth quarter. This increase was mainly driven by higher volumes of brand Coca-Cola and the selective price increases that we implemented during the year.</p>
          <p>Our Mexican operations total revenues increased 7%, reaching almost 10 billion pesos. Higher average prices per unit case accounted for 60% of the total incremental revenues and volume growth represented the balance. <mark type="inaudible" /> with the impact of higher sweetener and PET cost was partially offset by our higher average price per unit case and the appreciation of the Mexican peso as applied to our U.S. dollar denominated <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>Compared with the fourth quarter of 2009, gross profit increased approximately 4% to 4.9 billion Mexican pesos. And our gross margin declined 130 basis points to 49.3%. Our operating income decreased 3% to 1.9 billion Mexican pesos.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses grew as a result of the investments that we made at our Mexico division to support the growing <mark type="inaudible" />, enhance our execution of the point of sale, bolster our turnover base and improve our cooler coverage approach <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>Operating margin increased 190 basis points to 18.7%. Our EBITDA declined 2% in the fourth quarter to 2.3 billion Mexican pesos. For the full year, our Mexican operations EBITDA reached 8.3 billion pesos.</p>
          <p>2010 proved to be a very challenging year for our Mexico division. We faced high volatility in international commodity markets that significantly affected local sugar prices and consequently our profitability. Accordingly, during an important part of the year, we experienced bad weather conditions that not only negatively affected consumption across the country but also caused substantial disruption to our distribution network.</p>
          <p>Despite the circumstances, our operators demonstrated their ability to adapt our business to successfully meet these challenges. Underscoring our distribution capabilities, our company contributed with 90% of the Coca-Cola system's incremental volume <mark type="inaudible" /> during the year. Additionally, the implementation of selective price increases that matched inflation levels combined with the efficiencies achieved from the value chain enabled us to offset most of the global margin pressure that we're expecting at the beginning of 2010.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> the market place, which enhanced our execution of the point of sale, supported our growing beverage portfolio, and better positioned our business for an improved consumer environment.</p>
          <p>For 2011, we continue to anticipate volatility in the international commodity markets and the important challenges that we must face is increased price of the <mark type="inaudible" />. Nevertheless, we feel confident that a more favorable economic environment and the expected appreciation of the Mexican pesos combined with more targeted marketplace investments should help us mitigate these pressures.</p>
          <p>We will closely guard the economic and consumer environment throughout the year <mark type="inaudible" /> the implementation selective price increases across our portfolio. This will help us to prepare the profitability of the business and to compensate for potential commodity pressures and increased inflation. At the same time, we will take advantage of our powerful innovation pipeline to provide our consumers with product <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>Now, let me turn to our Latincentro division; our Latincentro division are close to 9% decline in volume during the fourth quarter. This decrease was mainly driven by the continued condition &#x2013; the bad weather conditions that we experienced across our franchise base throughout the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>In Colombia, total volume declined 8% during the quarter. Our water portfolio <mark type="inaudible" /> declined 4%. However, consumer preference for our portfolio with sparkling beverage has remained strong, allowing us to maintain market share year-over-year.</p>
          <p>In Venezuela, we incurred a 14% volume decline for the quarter, driven mainly by a double-digit decline in the sparkling beverages portfolio. Resulting from the very adverse weather conditions for the quarter, across our franchise territories.</p>
          <p>Our Central American operations sales volume declined 1%, compared with the fourth quarter of 2009. Prior volumes in the <mark type="inaudible" /> were outpaced by declining volumes from our sparkling beverages competitors <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>Our Latincentro division's total revenues decreased 26% to 8 billion Mexican pesos. This decrease resulted mainly from the effect of the devaluation of the bolivar in Venezuela. On a currency neutral basis, our Latincentro division's total revenues grew 12% driven by high average prices per unit case implemented across our operations.</p>
          <p>With regard to our profitability for the quarter our Latincentro division gross profit declined 23% to 3.8 billion Mexican pesos, as a result again of the devaluation of the bolivar in Venezuela.</p>
          <p>The impact of higher sweetener cost across the division was offset by higher average prices per unit case in local currencies over the last 12 months.</p>
          <p> Lower U.S. dollar-denominated cost of goods sold in Venezuela resulted from a more favorably exchange rate with our access during the quarter, and the appreciation of the Columbia peso as applied to our U.S. dollar-denominated raw material costs.</p>
          <p>Compared to the fourth quarter of 2009, our gross margin expanded 180 basis points to 47.3%. Our operating income increased 24% to 1.6 billion Mexican pesos. Operating leverage achieved through higher revenues in local currencies combined with lower marketing expenses in Colombia and Venezuela and then more further exchange rates as applied to our dollar-denominated operating expenses, compensated for higher labor costs in Venezuela, resulting in an operating margin expansion of <mark type="inaudible" /> basis points reaching 20.1%.</p>
          <p>Our EBITDA grew 16% in the fourth quarter to 2 billion Mexican pesos. For the full year, our net income to the division grew 11%. Latincentro division's EBITDA grew 11% reaching 6.9 billion Mexican pesos.</p>
          <p>In 2010, our Latincentro division faced a very complex operational environment. Our operations were affected by several factors from adverse weather conditions across our <mark type="inaudible" /> 2010, <mark type="inaudible" /> disruption of our distribution network <mark type="inaudible" /> devaluation of the bolivar in Venezuela.</p>
          <p>Despite these dynamics, distribution continues to improve the capability and deliver solid response, due to the strong <mark type="inaudible" /> for our portfolio of sparkling beverages, combined with our strategy to reinforce our non-carbonated beverage portfolio <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>As we mentioned in our last conference call, in October 2010, we signed a preliminary agreement to acquire Grupo Industrias L&#xE1;cteas in Panama. This company enjoys an important presence in <mark type="inaudible" /> value-added dairy and juice contents in that country.</p>
          <p>Negotiations continue to take place in an orderly fashion. As a matter of fact, we recently received approval from the local <mark type="inaudible" /> authorities. And we expect to successfully <mark type="inaudible" /> consumption during the first quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>This acquisition represents a conformational step for our company to develop significant capabilities to manage <mark type="inaudible" /> distribution system. Additionally this transaction will allows us to quantify perspective synergies with our <mark type="inaudible" /> distribution system, and to leverage the full potential in business portfolio all across the value chain to our extensive cooler coverage <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>In 2011, our Latincentro division of operators will continue different challenges. Nevertheless, the <mark type="inaudible" /> ability to successfully back our business to complex operating environment. As we continue to stay within our portfolio <mark type="inaudible" /> protect the division's profitability.</p>
          <p>Now, let's talk about our Mercosur division. In the fourth quarter of 2010, our Mercosur division total revenues grew 13% to 10 billion Mexican pesos. Excluding beer, which accounted for close to 1 billion Mexican pesos, total revenues reached 9.1 billion Mexican pesos. Volume growth and higher average prices per unit case were partially offset by the effect of a negative currency translation resulting from the appreciation of the Mexican peso against the Brazilian real and the Argentinean peso. On a currency neutral basis, our Mercosur division's total revenues increased 18%.</p>
          <p>Our Mercosur division generated 8% volume growth in the fourth quarter of 2010. This growth was driven by strong performance of Jugos del Valle line of business in Brazil and by solid performance of brand Coca-Cola and Aquarius our flavored water brand <mark type="inaudible" /> in Argentina. The strong performance of our sparkling beverage portfolio has allowed us to gain market shares in this portfolio in 2010.</p>
          <p>With regard to our profitability, our Mercosur division's gross profit increased more than 14% to 14.3 billion Mexican pesos. Higher sweetener costs of Mercosur division combined with increased PET costs in Argentina were offset by our higher revenues in local currencies resulted from the implemented price increases implemented over the past several months and then the appreciation over the Brazilian real as applied to our U.S. dollar-denominator raw material costs.</p>
          <p>Our gross margin expanded 30 basis points to 42.7% for the fourth quarter of 2010. Our operating income remains flat at 1.6 billion Mexican pesos despite increased labor and freight cost in Argentina. Our operating margin declined 207 basis points to 16% in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Our EBITDA grew 4% in the fourth quarter to 1.9 billion Mexican pesos. For the full year, our Mercosur division EBITDA grew more than 15% to 5.8 billion Mexican pesos.</p>
          <p>In 2010, our Mercosur division represented an important value for our company's growth. Our Brazilian franchise reported strong volumes leveraging its strong consumer and economic environment, and with a selective price increases that allow us to compensate for higher levels of inflation and increased raw material costs.</p>
          <p>In Argentina, we saw an important sequential decline in our volumes, driven by a more favorable consumer environment and various weather conditions.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> advanced significantly <mark type="inaudible" /> to increase our footprint in this high growth potential <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>During the fourth quarter, the ready-to-drink category grew close to 40%, when compared to the fourth quarter of 2009. In sparkling beverage category we significantly grew our <mark type="inaudible" /> and through our <mark type="inaudible" /> offering <mark type="inaudible" /> in search of more consumers.</p>
          <p> To report on our execution at the point of sale we substantially extended our cooler coverage. In the <mark type="inaudible" /> operations in only one day we sold more than 5,000 coolers establishing a benchmark for the Coca-Cola bottling system. For 2011, our Mercosur division will extend <mark type="inaudible" /> of growth, supported by our operator, disciplined and to find the the ability to serve one of the world's most dynamic and diverse markets.</p>
          <p>Now, let me walk you through to our financial performance for the year. Despite the challenges we confronted in 2010, we continue to improve our financial position based on the strength of our defensive business profile on our balance diversified <mark type="inaudible" /> free cash flow generation.</p>
          <p>As of December 31, 2010 we had a cash balance of 12.5 billion Mexican pesos and our total debt was 17.4 billion Mexican pesos. Our net debt to EBITDA coverage ratio was 0.2 times, and our EBITDA to net interest coverage ratio was about 14 times.</p>
          <p>On February 18, it was proposed to our Board of Directors a dividend payment of approximately 4.4 billion pesos, subject to approval of the Annual Shareholders Meeting to be held during March of this year. The proposed dividend is approximately 60% higher compared to the dividend paid in 2010.</p>
          <p>This dividend proportion does not change our strategic vision to continue growth through acquisitions. At Coca-Cola FEMSA we have debate, a strategic <mark type="inaudible" /> which clearly lays the foundation for our future business growth. With these strategic <mark type="inaudible" /> we continue <mark type="inaudible" /> to grow our business in the direction both organically and through acquisitions. We <mark type="inaudible" /> in our strong new products pipeline of innovation. This has enabled us to significantly enhance the company's financial position providing us with the possibility to participate with the consolidation of our industry with discipline necessary to ensure the value creation for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, our operations delivered positive results for 2010, despite the weather-related events that affected our volumes and the increased sweetener cost that affected our <mark type="inaudible" />. We delivered improved results thanks to the strong continued preference for our growth and our balanced portfolio profit.</p>
          <p>Our operators have the ability to capitalize on the <mark type="inaudible" /> which had gained over the past several years; it's an important competitive advantage, which will lead our company well into the future. 2011 results challenging and the possibility to forward growth . The position we had achieved in the various industries is the result of our daily effort to transform concept, challenges into opportunities to deliver increased value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>We thank you for your continuous growth and support.  And now, I would like to open the call for any questions that you may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from the line of Lauren Torres with HSBC. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. H&#xE9;ctor, you mentioned obviously that commodity costs and the impact of higher costs this year will affect you, but you also mentioned that you feel somewhat comfortable offsetting these costs. Just first, if you give us a sense of where you are as far as exposure to cost, whether it would be sweetener costs and/or packaging costs this year? And then secondly about your confidence in offsetting the &#x2013; you talked about selective price increases, just curious if you feel that's the main offset here at this point, and I guess I asked that question with consumer still being somewhat weak if you feel comfortable that taking pricing at this point make sense? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Lauren. <mark type="inaudible" /> 2010 was a very tough year in terms of cost prices on some of our raw materials. Some <mark type="inaudible" /> internally. We have to say <mark type="inaudible" /> bad debt regarding 2009. <mark type="inaudible" /> very much improved in refined sugar prices and cane sugar prices basically drive a new around $120 million on our P&amp;L. And we <mark type="inaudible" /> around <mark type="inaudible" /> by using different <mark type="inaudible" /> of sweeteners in our <mark type="inaudible" /> and drive the other $80 million impact on our <mark type="inaudible" /> , which through <mark type="inaudible" /> pricing initiatives looking some value to the <mark type="inaudible" /> in our valuation and therefore when you look at the results of <mark type="inaudible" /> in this past year and carrying an operating income that <mark type="inaudible" /> to increase a little bit more than 7%, I think that <mark type="inaudible" /> in our &#x2013; from our operations <mark type="inaudible" /> in our strategies and value <mark type="inaudible" /> of $120 million <mark type="inaudible" /> cost which has implied that without that our operating income <mark type="inaudible" /> closer to 14% or 15% as opposed to 7% <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>It's also fair to say that during the first half of this year, we benefit from the appreciation of some of the currencies versus some of the dollar-denominated raw material cost and therefore some of the averaging material were benefiting and that was also helping us to offset the value impact.</p>
          <p>During the fourth quarter, we started to receive <mark type="inaudible" />, so the fourth quarter was affected by both high <mark type="inaudible" /> price and higher PET price. And going forward <mark type="inaudible" /> we have to be very careful <mark type="inaudible" /> that we totally will have during 2011. And certainly that was during the first quarter of 2011.</p>
          <p>If you look at some of the future prices of some of these commodities, <mark type="inaudible" /> sugar prices to come down as we are balancing the year. <mark type="inaudible" /> crystal ball here. So it's very important our operators work <mark type="inaudible" /> fixed cost structure which <mark type="inaudible" /> in several conference calls, especially in the last year of our <mark type="inaudible" /> procession a lot of pension in terms of the SG&amp;A and how we <mark type="inaudible" /> in a more efficient manner. I assume that both Mexico and <mark type="inaudible" /> made some important <mark type="inaudible" /> because of the growth that we have in Brazil and <mark type="inaudible" /> in Argentina <mark type="inaudible" /> successful in that <mark type="inaudible" /> in that area.</p>
          <p>And addressing your question more specifically, we have worked <mark type="inaudible" /> in trying to fix some of the <mark type="inaudible" /> continued prices. We basically have <mark type="inaudible" /> some of the suppliers to <mark type="inaudible" /> that will basically mean that we have enough <mark type="inaudible" /> 2011 for <mark type="inaudible" /> at the prices that are around 5% <mark type="inaudible" /> what we have during 2010. Given the prices of <mark type="inaudible" /> that we've seen our 2010 levels are good <mark type="inaudible" /> we have seen that we have &#x2013; we grew <mark type="inaudible" /> additional prices.</p>
          <p>So the big question is <mark type="inaudible" /> be able to pass the long-term prices as we're balancing the year. We believe the answer is yes, although we have to recognize that we have a very large gap versus our competitor in <mark type="inaudible" /> presentations. You know that we're very innovative and very creative <mark type="inaudible" /> in these markets <mark type="inaudible" /> that we have and the knowledge that we have in market allow us to <mark type="inaudible" /> different cycles <mark type="inaudible" /> different SKUs to different consumer locations or different geographic areas that allow us to better compete.</p>
          <p>So just to give you an idea, if you look at today's prices in Mexico and you compare <mark type="inaudible" /> in some areas of 13 pesos, in some areas of 14 pesos, we are thinking around <mark type="inaudible" /> price gap. We will <mark type="inaudible" /> convenient factor <mark type="inaudible" /> our presentation.</p>
          <p>If you compare <mark type="inaudible" /> versus our Coca-Cola products in two years the gap is close to 45%, 47%. So our anticipation is that some of our competitors will also feel the pressures in terms of margins because of the raw materials and that they would start increasing some of these prices and regardless of what our competitors will do we will continue as ever looking for opportunities to find price points at which we can <mark type="inaudible" /> price mix and still maintain our market share.</p>
          <p>So, it's a very tough environment, but I assume that we have <mark type="inaudible" /> that we have somewhat additional pressure on sugar prices and <mark type="inaudible" /> diminishing prices towards the end of the year, we have some &#x2013; <mark type="inaudible" /> looking some of the prices in <mark type="inaudible" />. We're seeing that we have pressure in PET <mark type="inaudible" /> pressure in the first half of the year &#x2013; last year and we are starting to see pressures in the fourth quarter of 2010 and first quarter of 2011 in PET prices. <mark type="inaudible" /> to compensate that in savings throughout the value chain and in our cost structure and some pricing activity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's helpful <mark type="inaudible" />. I was just trying to get a sense of is pricing was one of your main offsets? There seems like in addition to everything else you have been doing to offset those cost increases you really still have the ability to do that in addition to pricing <mark type="inaudible" /> opportunities, I guess that's a correct statement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I assume <mark type="inaudible" /> pricing is a very important element in <mark type="inaudible" />, but we continue to look through innovation in terms of having lighter packages, having different <mark type="inaudible" /> and we look at <mark type="inaudible" /> opportunity toward the value chain <mark type="inaudible" /> we try to compensate <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line Alan Alanis with JPMorgan. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning, H&#xE9;ctor. First a clarifying question regarding the operating expenses in Mercosur, H&#xE9;ctor. If all the increase is only coming from labor interest for patient, I think some very back of the envelope numbers here. I mean around one-fourth to one-third of your Mercosur revenues are coming from Argentina. So if all of this spike is coming only from Argentina, that means that you almost doubled the total SG&amp;A or close to 70% plus the growth in SG&amp;A in that region. So that &#x2013; I guess the first question is could you quantify a bit this a bit more and what else is there besides the labor and transportation cost in Argentina?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Alan. trend, when you look at Mercosur, we got two different environments. The volume in Brazil as you probably know that was very important growth in volumes and in consumer safety maintain et cetera and very favorable for the development of our growth in our area.</p>
          <p>On Argentina where we're having this very strong construction with some of the main cost and some areas labor costs that especially with freight. <mark type="inaudible" /> in Argentina I think that we actually made up most of the distribution done through to Paris  again the smaller penetration that have <mark type="inaudible" /> are supposed to be what we have <mark type="inaudible" /> in Argentina most of the industries were global.</p>
          <p>But the impact that we have had in the trade cost in Argentina <mark type="inaudible" /> has increased close to 70% that's what we found out, salaries have increase around 32% <mark type="inaudible" /> 35% depending on the fixed promotion of some warehouse operators (37:445). So that G&amp;A numbers in Argentina, compared to losses in Argentina compared to last year, last year in the middle of the crisis, and it was free from most of our operations at the end of 2009. We still have very strong growth in marketing expenses in most of our operations. In general, marketing expenses this year <mark type="inaudible" /> pesos increases versus what we saw in 2009. Especially when we compare fourth quarter, this is fourth quarter, the numbers are a little bit more dramatic and this is the case in Argentina also. In the fourth quarter of last year we didn't go to <mark type="inaudible" /> very close to zero marketing expenses in the fourth quarter because more volumes were very difficult environment as you remember last year during a very difficult year.</p>
          <p>The decrease in Argentina is that I feel that or we feel that the consumer sentinel is improving during the fourth quarter. We grew values in Argentina around 7% <mark type="inaudible" /> but if you look at the month of December, December grew around 16% volumes and that &#x2013; and general and shareholders are running at seven digit growth rates in Argentina. So, I believe that with this flexibility that we have in terms of how we apply <mark type="inaudible" /> marketing expenses on the environment and the (3938) consumers 70%, it's very less and we will now <mark type="inaudible" /> now in fourth quarter in addition to the very strong focus and the very strong salary increases, we book out specialty good in marketing expenses, but we believe they now produce what the volume that we've actually in Argentina.</p>
          <p>Again in marketing expense, even if you spend a little bit compared to Brazil that we have in the fourth quarter, it's an important increase.</p>
          <p>So I feel that when you isolate Argentina <mark type="inaudible" />  a little bit more stable during the past, nice growth in volume, nice growth in prices, and you got revenues and profits growing at double-digits. I very clearly understand your concerns <mark type="inaudible" />  when you look at the fourth quarter numbers that it combines for Argentina and Brazil <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So there is nothing else &#x2013; I mean those are the key. So I just want to quickly ask a more &#x2013; more strategic question regarding the use of cash and regarding M&amp;A. I mean you've seen the transaction obviously <mark type="inaudible" /> transaction what happened with <mark type="inaudible" /> and my question goes more in sense of we're entering an environment of inflation. We're already in food inflation. That's trickling down into other categories. And what this means is that the interest rates are going up. I mean I don't think that anyone would push to say that they will stay this low for a long period of time.</p>
          <p>The specific question for you H&#xE9;ctor, what's the sense of urgency? I mean knowing that the cost of capital is going to go up, and that it's likely any acquisition that you made during the future is becoming more expensive from the financing standpoint as time passes by. How does the consultants action changes your view regarding senses of urgency regarding how you should approach M&amp;A in the future? And what's the optimal use of cash for the company after all these events?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think that you raise a good point and I think it's important to clarify.</p>
          <p>I mean when you look at our robust Coca-Cola trends, you know that we have been active in conversations with every single bottler in Latin America and <mark type="inaudible" />. We acquired some assets in 2003 we entered into a phase of devaluation our balance sheet because of the <mark type="inaudible" /> 2003 where if you look what we have done or what we have accomplished after that, it's basically in the last three or four years. Every single year we've had an important transaction.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> and you know that we did that transaction for the whole season in <mark type="inaudible" /> we acquired Brisa <mark type="inaudible" /> water business of our <mark type="inaudible" /> we acquired <mark type="inaudible" /> we acquired Brisa in Colombia together with Coca-Cola company we entered a transaction of Matte Leao. We are doing this laboratory in Panama which I think has tremendous <mark type="inaudible" /> look at these numbers <mark type="inaudible" /> of water and <mark type="inaudible" /> and we have <mark type="inaudible" />. We're leaders in the 20/20 vision that Mr. Trevi&#xF1;o proposed for the future and we are firm believers of that. There is no question that we have to go <mark type="inaudible" /> especially value added <mark type="inaudible" /> in order to be able to accomplish that.</p>
          <p>So when you look at the transactions we have accomplished in the past <mark type="inaudible" /> we were afraid of investment bankers <mark type="inaudible" /> on the transaction amounts.</p>
          <p>I feel that the <mark type="inaudible" /> transactions are very positive one for the system <mark type="inaudible" /> that we have been expecting for a long time and then we have disclosed openly the revenue <mark type="inaudible" /> that everyone in Mexico is independent <mark type="inaudible" /> independent meaning there's <mark type="inaudible" /> bottlers are thinking &#x2013; I'm sure that they are thinking now should I stay independent <mark type="inaudible" /> what will be.</p>
          <p>I think that the fact that the owners of <mark type="inaudible" /> this transaction also signals against the new environment and we're dealing with in Mexico in terms of generation changes and differing needs of different stakeholders you can argue <mark type="inaudible" /> security issues in Mexico playing the role you know. I think the fact that Coke FEMSA represented 90% &#x2013; and let me repeat that &#x2013; 90% of the additional cases that <mark type="inaudible" /> Mexico. I think that <mark type="inaudible" /> clearly important local trends have in the growth of this industry, and I think that it will be also an important element for whoever wants to join forces with different bottlers to consider in terms of who should they be approaching.</p>
          <p>Another idea that if you take a position to no longer control a <mark type="inaudible" /> business but to approach strong one, we should approach <mark type="inaudible" /> in terms of the reputation, going to Brazil and Argentina and Colombia and have been <mark type="inaudible" /> but I think right now that you consider <mark type="inaudible" /> even in bad situation that we have in Venezuela and the difficult situation we have in Argentina, and see that <mark type="inaudible" /> at the end of the day. And I feel that story is very difficult to replicate by other alternatives.</p>
          <p>So, regarding cost of capital, I feel that you are right. We are of the view that <mark type="inaudible" />. In our recent board meeting that we have last Friday, the finance committee approved this additional <mark type="inaudible" /> growth in dividend payment because it is a dialogue that we have had with you guys, with investors saying we are approaching <mark type="inaudible" /> capital structure when you have close to zero debt in our balance sheet. Together with that decision was approval of our finance committee to see if we can <mark type="inaudible" /> or try to look for <mark type="inaudible" /> financing and taking advantage of the lower interest rate in anticipation of <mark type="inaudible" /> we can prepay. That's the worst case scenario that we've gone on to this one and paid in March of last year. But we can also use that as part of our controlling the capital structure to a more reasonable capital structure for our company, and if we have an acquisition in the <mark type="inaudible" /> forecast, then we shall <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>I think that <mark type="inaudible" /> also signal an important element <mark type="inaudible" /> in terms of prices that some stakeholders are willing to join forces. I think that signals also or it confirms our belief that we have been disclosing with investor community for many years, that the Mexican bottlers are momentarily here to sell, and then just go out with a big pile of cash to look for alternatives.</p>
          <p>It confirms that investors in Mexico <mark type="inaudible" /> system, they want to continue to be part of the system. And in that respect, your concern with the interest rates <mark type="inaudible" /> because it would be more of a merger of <mark type="inaudible" /> as opposed to trying to finance through the capital markets looking for <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, understood <mark type="inaudible" />. Thank you so much, H&#xE9;ctor. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your next question comes from the line of Lore Serra with Morgan Stanley. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, H&#xE9;ctor. I just wanted to go back and look at sort of maybe the year as a whole, and first look back and then look forward.</p>
          <p>So, I mean I think your goal is &#x2013; if you would tell me that cost margin would go up a 110 basis points with declines in Mexican Mercosur and a big increase in Latincentro, I'm not sure I would have believed it. So can you walk us through why you have so much margin increase in Central America?</p>
          <p>And then as we look forward to this year, there are lots of moving parts. I think the certainty here is Venezuela is going to be under pressure, given what's happening with the bolivar, with probably the strike, and the fact that I think your input costs are going to be more difficult. So I assume the margins are going to be under pressure in Latincentro. And you've talked about pricing and costs but there's lots of moving parts.</p>
          <p>So can you just kind of give us a sense of &#x2013; is this a year where you're going to be hoping for margin stability because of all these factors, and you're going to really have to be tight on operating expenses to get there? Or is this a year where you think there's some potential for margins to recover in Mexico and Brazil and sort of pull out from the problem areas?</p>
          <p>So if I look at a consolidated basis, is the margins going up or down this year? I guess some direction would be helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Lore. I think that you raised a very important point. I mean when you look at it on a consolidated basis, our margins, you see clearly the effect of Latincentro. It's 800 basis expansion in the operating margin in Latincentro. It's got a lot of noise in there because of Venezuela and because of the foreign exchange translation.</p>
          <p>What was very positive in Venezuela this year that significantly affected our margins were basically the factors that as we have access to some other important raw materials on a consolidated &#x2013; translated to around 2.6 bolivar per dollar, versus what we have in 2009 that we were buying some of these raw materials in the open market of close to 6 bolivar per dollar, in some cases a little bit more than that.</p>
          <p>That created a lot of, let me say, additional margins in Venezuela, but I don't see for next year, because of <mark type="inaudible" /> 2.6 market <mark type="inaudible" /> to unify the <mark type="inaudible" /> one is 2.6 and one 4.3 <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>We have the <mark type="inaudible" /> dollar denominated expenses but we're also affected by that conversion. Again in 2009, we paid with very high exchange rate because we didn't have access to control market. And in 2010, we <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>So when you look at &#x2013; I think what's very positive in Venezuela is the pricing levels when you <mark type="inaudible" /> strong inflation. You have more flexibility in moving prices and increasing prices in real terms in an important manner in Venezuela. That I think is the pricing level we still have.</p>
          <p>I think that similar to what we have in Colombia and &#x2013; both in Colombia and Venezuela, still maintain a very important role in Latincentro. We have very strong bad weather conditions that disrupted a lot of our availability of products in the marketplace. And with that we basically stopped a lot of our marketing efforts. Not necessarily the advertisements on TV. The day-to-day marketing activity in the street.</p>
          <p>You have <mark type="inaudible" /> facilities or in the warehouses because of the disruptions in the logistics that you simply stop buying marketing activity. And therefore Colombia and Venezuela, the two of them have a lower marketing level of expenses that that would &#x2013; that I will anticipate in a normalized way.</p>
          <p>When you look at, especially Venezuela, on a sequential basis, <mark type="inaudible" /> operating income to sales ratio around 15%, more or less, each of the first three quarters. And then we jumped during the fourth quarter to 20% because of <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
          <p>I think that because of this pressure on the bolivar that will target a higher exchange rate for some of the raw materials. And some other things that I have mentioned. I think that a more normalized level is going to be around 15% to 16%. So certainly we'll have pressure this year for 2011 on the margins in Venezuela.</p>
          <p>On top of that, you have some pressure on raw material <mark type="inaudible" /> raw materials will play a role. My anticipation is that we have pressure from <mark type="inaudible" /> at the end of the year. So there's a lot of uncertainty there, no? So all of these I mentioned is clearly to send the same signal.</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> in the last year. I think that we will have a more normalized minimal profits in the result on 2011.</p>
          <p>I think that Mexico and Brazil, on the other side, I'm positive on  those two countries. Mexico is showing very strong growth in the first two months of the year in terms of volume, and that <mark type="inaudible" /> during the year in terms of Mexico. And I think that Brazil and <mark type="inaudible" /> on those was very, very strong volume wise in 2010, we'll expect a more moderate growth in 2011 in terms of volume.</p>
          <p>Where I'm expecting them to deliver on &#x2013; our operators to deliver on the scaling cost control as I mention during this conference call. I still advice that the Mexico and Latincentro in some of the cost containment. I think that Brazil has some <mark type="inaudible" /> and we think that because of those efforts, we're expecting to see some improvement in profitability for Brazil.</p>
          <p>So in summary, I see Mexico and Brazil with potential to increase the margins during 2011, I see a are very complicated Venezuela because of the exchange rate now moving from a comparative rate a little bit higher 4.3 that would make it very difficult for us in terms of comparison, because we have access to potentially through &#x2013; in fact to the year. I see Argentina <mark type="inaudible" /> question that Alan raised, and obviously those increases are you know going to stay for 2011, and I think that Colombia it's also an area where we should see improvement in margins. In Central America that we also see stable or increasing margins in Central America. I hope that this answers your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Just I'm sorry &#x2013; just to clarify. So you're saying that overall that you'd expect margins to come up this year as those franchises compensate? And then just secondly, can you just give us an idea what the CapEx budget for this year is, I think it was about 500 last year if I remember correctly, what is that for this year, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Lore, I didn't hear very well, you are speaking about CapEx for this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. What is the CapEx budget for this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We have a similar CapEx budget to what we had. But the big question that what we have in 2010 and a little bit more than $500 million. The big question that we have is if we start a new plant in Colombia that we're looking at that project and we're analyzing the possibility of replacing the production facility that we have in <mark type="inaudible" />. You will move in that direction and I think that we have good chances of moving in that direction in next year, there is a slight increase barely reaching $550 million as opposed to $500 million that we have this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Jose Yordan with Deutsche Bank. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning H&#xE9;ctor and everyone. My question is about the working capital, I mean the working capital investment for the year is 6 billion pesos, it's pretty &#x2013; it's lot higher than what've you had in the past. I mean I &#x2013; a two-part question, is there any specific one-time reason for this or is this the way we should think about working capital investments in the future?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jose, good morning. I think that when you look at the cash flow statement that we have in the press release and we've had discussions going on the &#x2013; with our auditing committee which think the 17 that cash flow statement specifically in the press release it's a little bit convoluted (06) in the sense that it has some effects of information because of  &#x2013; I'm sorry, <mark type="inaudible" /> effects of some other country that we participate, not only the conference <mark type="inaudible" /> inflationary accounting but its consolidated.</p>
          <p>The tranquility I'd like to give this I think that clarifies our specific numbers that is going I would ask you to wait and look at the numbers. Working capital distinguisher is not very complex because there are &#x2013; and this, very large number, negative number as we in this statement. We've very few accounts that has grades in every conference very, very minimal and we have some <mark type="inaudible" /> supplies. At the end of the day it's never been a problem for our company to be more lowering our tertiary area to finance <mark type="inaudible" /> in working capital.</p>
          <p>And <mark type="inaudible" /> to reduce specifically the complications that are involved in that cash flow statement, but I like to give you <mark type="inaudible" /> quality that from a working capital point of view, we don't have any strategic mix that we should be certainly worried to <mark type="inaudible" /> at this moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, <mark type="inaudible" /> I'll take it offline with him and just a clarification to Lore's question, was it your answer in the end that on a consolidated basis you expect flat margins for the year notwithstanding a six point decline or so in the &#x2013; in Laticentro?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I tried to go to Laticentro that I frankly referred to the opportunity of two improving margins in different regions. I think that when you look at a consolidated basis, it <mark type="inaudible" /> mix with everything that they might see Brazil and Mexico and Columbia with good possibility of retreating margins. Actually Argentina and Venezuela we have good possibility of diminishing margins because of the pressures of that they have and I feel more neutral of Central America.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll work it out from that. Thanks a lot. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your final question comes from line of Celso Sanchez with Citigroup. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi good morning. I just want to ask really about innovation in Mexico on two different levels, or two related levels I suppose. One, on the process side and by that I'm speaking just look about the commercial model like as I said just to see what update you can give us in color on that process. Especially, I think you mentioned some of the execution initiatives you are working on the quarter as affecting operating expenses. So, it would be helpful to know kind of where things stand there, how you see that having evolved and is it in line with your targets at this point, is it ahead of schedule or behind schedule? And then secondly on the portfolio side, this bill beverage growth in Mexico was I think throughout the year a bit lower than I would have thought at this stage of the game not very much higher than the sparkling side, and so I just wonder is that a low end growth or is it really a category? Is that year for competitive reasons or overall pricing reasons should not be expected to grow that much above sparkling, which to me there should be a material that have its growth rate the benefit of still? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, good morning, Celso. If you look <mark type="inaudible" /> which is innovation and in part competitive innovation, innovation which one will be very important pillars that we have in our client process in Coca-Cola <mark type="inaudible" /> for those years and I think that some of these elements that have <mark type="inaudible" /> recent innovation and have <mark type="inaudible" /> importantly in terms of volume growth in the past. <mark type="inaudible" /> was an example of that some marketing we started <mark type="inaudible" /> very importantly in volume wise last year. And if you remember I mean, it's very important in Mexico division and you remember Mexico, we mentioned during some of the conference last year that we record level volume growth in 11 months out of 12 months of last year when the economy in Mexico was suffering and GDP was coming down around 6%, we were increasing our volumes around 6%. <mark type="inaudible" /> what the economy was doing and the level that has to do with innovation and <mark type="inaudible" /> 2010 very difficult year to grow. I feel that you are very correct in pointing out that the growth of the <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
          <p>Part of that has to do again with the <mark type="inaudible" /> 2009 on very difficult terms. Part of that is that we have not been able to grow importantly the base of the business that we acquire which is due to some metrics. We have been able to grow on some terms. There are around due to some metrics, we didn't have a lot of <mark type="inaudible" /> to do due to <mark type="inaudible" /> competitor.</p>
          <p>I feel that we are gaining &#x2013; actually we are achieving &#x2013; we are gaining market share, but we feel that we've got a lot of opportunities and we should capture those opportunities going forward. I think that growths like <mark type="inaudible" /> are growing at a fantastic pace <mark type="inaudible" /> from a small base. So I feel that if this approach continues to grow, we will start to see more traction in volumes of non-carbonate approach. Growth like power in Mexico region everyday new milestones, as a matter of fact in our territories and confidential territories probably we have reached market share in beverage of around 26%, 27% from basically nothing that we have few years ago. It's a very strong scene along of the World Cup we are doing <mark type="inaudible" /> in Mexico. When you think about this trend that the <mark type="inaudible" /> in these territories. If you ask me a few years ago, I had a dream of carving a longer territory of that amount of market share points and it was very difficult to believe.</p>
          <p>I think we have to work a lot on the profitability on power because obviously it has <mark type="inaudible" /> in the pricing environment, and so these are our competitor there. We have to improve profitability because we get traction. Some of the marketing expenses that are high compared to the volume that <mark type="inaudible" />. We will start to distribute that marketing expenses on that lower volume base. So far as pricing and marketing expenses <mark type="inaudible" /> specific growth. We are just speaking that we have taken away the many markets that belong from our competitor when especially when our competitor is deriving most of the profitability from that growth.</p>
          <p>I think that is very important success stories for our company. But if you are right <mark type="inaudible" /> being the focus of divestment and then <mark type="inaudible" /> value that we should have a better growth story in non-carbonated products. We have worked with <mark type="inaudible" /> in some of the coffee initiative in Mexico under the Coca-Cola brand name Black. We have placed 5,000 equipments at the end of 2010 in the Valley of Mexico. We are targeting to increase that to 8,000 through addition of 1,000 equipments in future, and it's a very specific consumption occasions targeting <mark type="inaudible" /> from the concerns relating to pirating. The involvement of providing a new category that the <mark type="inaudible" /> to also to our guidance. And it's proving to be an important element that that once we promise better rates here <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
          <p>We have a large in a place called Mercosur which is <mark type="inaudible" /> with the Coca-Cola company. It's a thing that provides 50% on the profit <mark type="inaudible" /> by a few starting with the ones targeted here in Mexico and some of the other counties, especially counties like <mark type="inaudible" /> where nutrition is an important element in development of the key scenario that we would like to help with us.</p>
          <p>And lastly that you mentioned about our <mark type="inaudible" /> of our route, probably to assign the route to market. It's also an important element in terms of how we target our plans on how we segment our brand it would be impossible for us. It would be impossible for us to dream of presenting to our clients <mark type="inaudible" /> if we don't have the tools that are around what we call <mark type="inaudible" />. We target the clients and it's important <mark type="inaudible" /> and then we define <mark type="inaudible" /> then we will targeted to this different lines. Again it will be impossible to develop success story with so many different attributes that we just launched every year <mark type="inaudible" /> plan in the universal plan. <mark type="inaudible" /> It's important to focus and to target specifically with clients. So I feel that all those efforts that our innovations are very important for the future growth and that's why innovation is one of the important pillars in our planning force. And <mark type="inaudible" /> the answer for the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, that's great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And at this time, we have no more questions. I would now like to turn the conference back to management for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much for your attention into the conference call and feel free to call us for any additional questions you might have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's conference. Thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect. Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>