<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1245842" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-07-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3057</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o Gutierrez, Chief Financial and Administrative Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2">Lauren Torres</participant>
      <participant id="3">Robert Ford</participant>
      <participant id="4">Alan Alanis</participant>
      <participant id="5">Alex Robarts</participant>
      <participant id="6">Jose Yordan</participant>
      <participant id="7">Lore Serra</participant>
      <participant id="8">Celso Sanchez</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and welcome to the Coca-Cola FEMSA's Second Quarter 2009 Earnings Results Conference Call.  As a reminder, today's conference is being recorded and all participants are in a listen-only mode. At the request of the Company, we'll open the conference up for questions and answers after the presentation.</p>
          <p>During this conference call, management may discuss certain forward-looking statements concerning Coca-Cola FEMSA's future performance, and should be considered as good faith estimates made by the Company.  These forward-looking statements reflect management expectations and are based upon currently available data.  Actual results are subject to future events and uncertainties, which can materially impact the Company's actual performance.</p>
          <p>At this time I will now turn the conference over to Mr. H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o, Coca-Cola FEMSA's CFO. Please go ahead, Mr. Trevi&#xF1;o.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us today.  Our Company's diversified portfolio of products, the strength of our core brands, along with our execution across Latin America, effectively drove our continued growth under one of the toughest economic environments that we've seen to date.</p>
          <p>During the second quarter, our consolidated revenues reached more than Ps. 24 billion, over 30% from the second quarter 2008.  Organic growth, driven by the increased volumes and pricing, accounted for more than 50% of our incremental revenues.  The consolidation of REMIL in Brazil, Brisa in Columbia and Agua De Los Angeles in Mexico represented less than 20% of our incremental revenues.  And the effect of a positive exchange rate translation contributed less than 30% of our incremental revenues.</p>
          <p>Excluding acquisitions and the positive effect of the exchange rate translation, our Company is achieving more than 16% revenue growth in a recessionary environment.  Our consolidated sales volume rose close to 10% year-over-year, excluding REMIL, Brisa and Agua de Los Angeles, our consolidated sales volume increased close to 6% during the quarter.  This increase was mainly driven by the growth of the Sparkling Beverages in all of our divisions and our Still brands portfolio in Mexico and Latincentro.</p>
          <p>Our gross profit increased close to 28% in the second quarter 2009.  Higher revenues partially compensated for our higher cost of goods sold, which resulted from higher year-over-year sweetener costs across our operations, the effect of the devaluation of local currencies as applied to our U.S. dollar-denominated raw material cost and the integration of REMIL.  The lower cost of resin partially compensated for all these factors.</p>
          <p>Our gross margin declined 90 basis points through the second quarter of 2009.  Consolidated operating income improved 16% to Ps. 3.7 billion in the second quarter.  Revenue growth compensated for higher labor cost, mainly in Venezuela and Argentina.</p>
          <p>The effect of a positive currency translation provided 30% of our incremental operating income.  Our consolidated operating margin declined 190 basis points year-over-year to 15.2% in the quarter.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated EBITDA rose more than 16% to reach Ps. 4.5 billion.  During the second quarter, our majority net income increased more than 17% to Ps.2.2 billion. This increase was mainly due to our higher operating income and our lower net interest expense in the second quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>Now let me expand on our operations.  Our Mexico division delivered almost 7% volume growth for the second quarter of 2009, recording the highest volume growth in our Mexico division in more than three years.  Our sales volume of Sparkling Beverages grew close to 3%, mainly driven by brand Coca-Cola in multiserve presentations.</p>
          <p>The Coca-Cola category increased volumes by close to 5%, which more than compensated for the slight decline in our flavored Sparkling Beverages the first quarter.  In the Still Beverage category, Jugos del Valle beverages portfolio continued to provide important incremental growth, reaching almost 40 million unit cases of this product for the quarter, almost three times the volume we sold in the second quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Our incursion into different beverage categories, such as the Valle Frut product line, has provided an important growth driver.  12 months after we started to participate in this line of business we were able to gain leadership in the orangeade category in Mexico.  An important part of our organic growth is being driven by innovation in the Still Beverage category.</p>
          <p>Still Beverages, excluding Water, have gained importance in our portfolio over the past year representing now more than 5% of our total beverage portfolio in Mexico.  Still Beverages including Water in personal presentations represent almost 11%.</p>
          <p>Our Water business grew close to 7% during the quarter.  The slight decline in single-serve Water was compensated by a 10% growth in our jug Water segment, driven by the acquisition of Agua de Los Angeles and the expansion of jug Water business in the valley of Mexico.</p>
          <p>Our average-price-per-unit case increased 0.7% during the quarter.  This increase was mainly driven by the average price increases implemented last year in our Coca-Cola portfolio combined with higher average-price-per-unit case in the Jugos del Valle line of beverages.  These increases were partially offset by higher volumes of our Sparkling Beverage multiserve portfolio, jug Water and the Valle Frut orangeade products, which carry a lower average-price-per-unit case.</p>
          <p>Our Mexican operation's total revenues increased 7.8%.  Incremental volumes accounted for the majority of our total incremental revenues.</p>
          <p>On the profitability front, our higher cost of goods sold was mainly driven by the third and final stage of the yearly increase in concentrate prices that we reported in our filings of the Coca-Cola Company in 2006, increased year-over-year sweetener cost and the devaluation of the Mexican peso as applied to our dollar-denominated raw material cost.   Lower year-over-year resin prices compensated for these increases.</p>
          <p>Our gross profit reached Ps.4.9 billion, growing 5% as compared to second quarter of last year.  Our gross margin in Mexico decreased 140 basis points.  Operating income grew more than 2%, reaching Ps. 1.9 billion.</p>
          <p>Our operating margin declined 100 basis points to 19.5%, mainly due to gross margin pressures. Our EBITDA grew close to 1% compared with the second quarter of last year, reaching Ps. 2.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Our Mexican business continues to produce positive results.  This quarter we reached a long-time high sales volume in Mexico, despite one of the most adverse economic environments in more than 15 years and the effects of the swine flu outbreak that took place at the end of April in Mexico City.</p>
          <p>Brand Coca-Cola and our slow initial growth allow us to continue outperforming economic trends in Mexico.  To reinforce our growth in the Sparkling Beverage category, we will rely on several new strategies in the market place.  We will continue driving the availability route on our packages, especially single-serve presentations, and proliferation of market channels to improve our price mix, offer additional alternatives for personal consumption in this category and bolster single-serve transactions.</p>
          <p>We will leverage the strong equity of our core brands, our wide array of product offerings at different price points and enhance execution at the point of sale to fuel our growth as we enter the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>In July, our Mexican operation's volumes are off to a very good start for the third quarter.  Sparkling Beverages continue growing, driven by brand Coca-Cola and the re-launch of Coca-Cola Zero.  Innovation in our Still Beverages category continues to post double-digit growth and good weather conditions in our Mexican territories are helping a lot, allowing us to generate double-digit volume growth for the month so far.</p>
          <p>Our Latincentro division posts double-digit volume growth.  This increase was driven by sparking beverages in Venezuela, the integration of Brisa in Colombia as of June 1, and Still Beverages in Colombia and Central America.</p>
          <p>In Venezuela we had a low year-over-year comparison due to the operating disruption that we faced in the second quarter of 2008.  In Colombia the Still Beverage category continued to grow reaching more than four million unit cases driven by the Jugos del Valle line of beverages.</p>
          <p>Despite price increases implemented in May, Sparkling Beverages in Columbia remained almost flat for the quarter.  In Central America, we recorded sales volumes growth of more than 2%, mainly driven by Still Beverages.  Sparkling Beverages remained flat as compared to the second quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Our Latincentro division's total revenues grew more than 60% year-over-year, reaching Ps. 8.7 billion.  Our high average-price-per-unit case and volume growth accounted for more than 55% of our incremental revenues.  And a positive currency translation represented the balance.</p>
          <p>On the profitability front, our Latincentro division's gross profit increased more than 68% to Ps. 4.1 billion. Higher revenues combined with lower cost of resin compensated for the higher cost of sweeteners across the division and the devaluation of the Colombian peso as applied to our dollar-denominated packaging costs.</p>
          <p>Our gross margin reached 47.2%, an expansion of 120 basis points compared with the second quarter of 2009.  Our operating income grew close to 40%, reaching Ps. 1 billion. Higher labor costs in Venezuela and maintenance expenses in Colombia offset the operating leverage that we achieved through our higher revenues.</p>
          <p>The effect of a positive currency translation accounted for approximately 50% of our incremental operating income. Excluding this currency translation effect, our operating income grew close to 20%.</p>
          <p>Our operating margin declined to 110 basis points to 12% as compared to the second quarter of 2008.  Our EBITDA grew more than 40% to Ps. 1.3 million.</p>
          <p>In our Latincentro division, we continued to expand our product portfolio during the quarter.  As of June 1, we started to distribute the Brisa brand Water portfolio, adding close to three million unit cases to our existing portfolio of Water brands in Colombia and Guatemala.  Also at the beginning of May, we started to produce the Jugos del Valle line of beverages in our Bogot&#xE1; plant.  These new production lines will give us the opportunity to increase our progress of the development of juice beverage alternatives for our consumers, and complement our still fruit offerings in Columbia.</p>
          <p>Last let's talk about our Mercosur division.  Our Mercosur division's net revenues grew close to 37%, reaching Ps. 5.7 billion in the second quarter of 2009.  Excluding beer, which accounted for Ps. 614 million, we increased our net revenues by close to 35%, reaching Ps. 5 billion.</p>
          <p>REMIL accounted for approximately 65% of this growth.  Organic growth driven by higher average-price-per-unit case and higher volumes, represented close to 30%, and the effect of our positive currency translations provided the balance.</p>
          <p>Volume growth in our Mercosur division was up more than 18% in the second quarter of 2009.  Our sales volume, excluding REMIL and beer, increased 3.4%, driven by low-single digit volume growth in Brazil and the mid-single digit volume growth in Argentina.  In Brazil our sparking beverage volume post low-single digit growth despite unusually cold weather in <mark type="inaudible" /> in May and price increases implemented at the beginning of the year.</p>
          <p>Growth in the Still Beverage category was mainly driven by the integration of Jugos del Valle line of products, which helped us to grow our volumes approximately 50% in this category year-over-year from a low base.  We have decided to integrate the Suco Mais juice brand into Jugos del Valle line of business in Brazil.  We expect the combined strength of these two brands will provide the innovation platform to develop new beverage alternatives for our consumers.</p>
          <p>In Argentina our sales volume increased more than 5%. Sparkling Beverages, mainly driven by the brand Coca-Cola, grew low-single digits, providing approximately 50% of our incremental volumes. The Still Beverage category, driven by the successful performance of Aquarius, our flavored Water brand, represented the balance.</p>
          <p>On the profitability front, our Mercosur division's gross profit increased close to 32%, reaching Ps. 2.4 billion.  Our cost of goods sold increased as a result of the integration of REMIL in Brazil and higher cost of sweeteners and the significant devaluation of local currencies as applied to our U.S. dollar-denominated raw material costs. The lower cost of resin partially compensated for all of these factors.</p>
          <p>Our gross margin decreased 170 basis points to 42.4% in the second quarter of 2009.  Our operating income increased 31%, reaching sales of Ps.39 million.  Our operating levels driven by higher revenues more than compensated for higher labels and trade cost in Argentina. The effect of a positive margins are mentioned accounted for later of our incremental operating income.</p>
          <p>Our operating margin declined 60 basis points year-over-year, to 12.8% in the second quarter. Our EBITDA grew more than 32% to Ps. 923 million.  As we enter in the second half of the year, we will further develop our turnover base, both in multiserve and single-serve presentations to offer our consumers viable alternatives for their consumption.  To reinforce our presence in the core channels, we will increase our cooler coverage in the market place to improve single-serve transactions.</p>
          <p>Now let's talk about our financial performance for the quarter.  For the first six months of the year, it has proven to be very difficult to everyone.  However our Company has been able to successfully adapt to current lowered economic conditions, making cash flow generations above our expectations.</p>
          <p>As of June 30, 2009 we have a cash balance of Ps.11.4 billion, an increase of more than Ps. 5 billion with year end 2008.  This increase, near of $46 million that we paid to finance our share of the Brisa Water business acquisition, and the clearance of Ps. 1.3 billion that we paid in April came from cash generation in the last six months and the proceeds of our January 2009 bond issuance in the amount of Ps. 2 billion.</p>
          <p>Our gross debt increased Ps. 2.2 billion compared with year end 2008, mainly driven by the previously mentioned bond offer.  As a result of these factors, our net debt decreased by close to Ps. 3 billion in the first half of the year.  As of June 30, 2009, our short-term bank debt was Ps. 10.1 billion.  Our long-term debt was Ps. 10.7 billion.</p>
          <p>As we mentioned on our last conference call, we have maturities coming in during the beginning of July.  Of these we already paid down a dollar-denominated Yankee bond to the amount of $265 million and a Mexican pesos bond to the amount of Ps. 500 million.  The majority of our remaining debt matures from 2012 onwards.</p>
          <p>As of July 23, 2009, we had the equivalent of approximately $590 million in our cash balance, net of the above-mentioned maturities that we paid.  These funds are more than sufficient to meet our operating needs for the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>As of June 30, 2009, our last 12 months net debt-to-EBITDA coverage ratio was 0.5, underscoring our solid financial position. Our net debt as of June 30 was Ps. 9.4 billion. Our ability &#x2013; our liability structure considering the maturities that we paid in the beginning of July, is comprised of a balanced mix of currency. Approximately 30% of our debt is dollar-denominated and the remainder is comprised of local currency-denominated debt, mainly Mexican peso.</p>
          <p>As we mentioned in our last conference call, as part of the Brisa water business acquisition that we closed in February 2009, with <mark type="inaudible" />. On June 1, we started direct <mark type="inaudible" /> distribution at <mark type="inaudible" /> to consolidate this operation into our Colombian business. We included one month of Brisa in our Colombian and Latin Central operation.</p>
          <p>This quarter's results represent another great achievement for our company. We pushed volume growth in key markets under unusually challenging difficult starts. Our sparkling beverages portfolio plus our division has contributed importantly to this growth.</p>
          <p>Our acquisitions have provided us with avenues growth and innovation capabilities that would have taken us years to develop on our own. These are core capabilities, especially in the Still Beverages, combined with our in-house development and execution toward and our learnings from managing the wild service portfolio in these markets are amplifying this defensiveness to our business and providing our company with sustainable growth.</p>
          <p>As we enter the second half of the year, we continue to focus our efforts on delivering positive results for our shareholders, based on our proven ability to manage our company for the long run and under continuously changing and challenging conditions. Thank you for your continued strength and support. And now, I'd like to open the call for any questions that you will have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from the line of Lauren Torres with HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. I was hoping you could talk a little bit more about the consumer environment in Mexico, and in particular, expectations for the second half of the year? Obviously, you had a great first half managing a lot of these pressures very well. But I was curious, as we think about the second half and I don't even know if you want to start talking about next year, if you feel that your initiatives, be it from a package standpoint a or pricing standpoint, will keep the momentum that you have going, or do you need to be a bit more aggressive with some of your actions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, Lauren. Let me give you some of the main trends that we are seeing here in Mexico. And then we can compare it a little bit with some of the other operations.</p>
          <p>One of the phenomenons that we have seen in Mexico that is different from what we are seeing, for example, in Brazil, is that in some of the other countries in South, the authorities have reduced or fostered the consumption of durable goods like automobiles and household appliances and things like that, by lowering taxes. And because of that reason, in areas for example like Brazil, we are seeing a boarding starting to be more flattish compared to last year, and the same is true for Argentina.</p>
          <p>In Mexico, we believe that one of the phenomenons that we are seeing is that, as people started to spend less of their disposable income on these kinds of products and durable goods, they have some extra cash for these small kind of luxuries like our products. So we are seeing very important growth that has, in a way, surprised us, especially in the last two months. And as I mentioned during this conference call, including July with very positive numbers.</p>
          <p>We are relying a lot on the innovation of these products that I have mentioned, this idea of <mark type="inaudible" />, which is an orangeade that we launched basically 12 months ago, that we now have leadership in the category, continue to grow. We are trying to take control of those new categories, as we do all this innovation <mark type="inaudible" />. And once we take control of the category, we try to increase prices and start improving the profitability.</p>
          <p>We have recently increased the price of this product importantly, close to 20%, because obviously as we have expressed in other conference calls, the profitability for this category is not the same as what we have, in some cases, lower than what we have in soda. So our strategy is to capture this consumption of pesos from the Mexican consumer or Latin American consumers. And as we see an opportunity, starting to improve in the profitability.</p>
          <p>In general, it's a tough question, what can we expect for the second quarter? We think that the government is facing a lot of pressure with the revenues and tax revenues are other revenues. They will probably reduce, and that they actually announced today that they are going to reduce some of their expenses.</p>
          <p>And so it's a little tough to predict what is going to happen in the second quarter. The big trend that we have, that I was trying to explain is, as the consumer is just having a little bit more disposable income, as they are moving away from durable goods, it seems that they are spending more and more on these kind of products, like our products.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And with respect to your competition in Mexico, are they following along your actions, or is there any unusual behavior going on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what we have seen so far is that in Mexico, the usual suspects, some of our competitors increased &#x2013; they have increased prices. Abel Cola and Revipa so far have stayed with the same prices that they have. In De Cola, that is a competitor and these oranges, orange category have increased prices also.</p>
          <p>And Pepsi-Cola has also followed some other price increases as we have mentioned. We believe that because of the cost pressure that we have, this again, one of these big movements that we have this year is, the affect of imported raw materials on our costs. We believe that the competitor will follow with all these increases that we have done.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Robert Ford with Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody, and congratulations on the quarter, H&#xE9;ctor. I had a question with respect to your franchises. You have several that, where the agreements have expired or about to expire, and you've been negotiating some of these for quite some time.</p>
          <p>And I was curious as to whether or not you've gotten to a point where you feel comfortable saying that it's unlikely we're going to see a material change in the concentrate pricing. And I was curious as to what is taking so long to resolve these agreements? And I was also hoping you could break out Venezuela, given how high the inflation is, Venezuela in terms of the value, incremental value and volume in <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Bob. The agreements, let me &#x2013; I guess, that we can try to summarize the issue with the agreements. It is not &#x2013; the situation where we have agreements that are coming due and that we are not renewing or not signing is, there is <mark type="inaudible" /> Coca-Cola FEMSA or Coca-Cola.</p>
          <p>We both know, and we have been very open, that there are some clauses in the -- let me use the word, the so-called international, the new international bottles agreement, there are some issues that we are not in agreement, which they know. And they see what we have been doing is renewing this on a very short-time basis and sometimes on a quarter-by-quarter basis. But also the agreement that we have in the two companies is that we don't need an <mark type="inaudible" /> agreement between the two companies to continue our relations, the negotiations that we have had with the top senior management in Latincentro.</p>
          <p>And with our CEO basically reached upon what we said, well, I cannot move on this, on these few chapters of the agreement, and the other side can also &#x2013; doesn't have the authority to move, because they are trying to implement a standard international agreement for all the rest of North America or the world. And if we have been out of our radar screens for a few years. At some point in time, we need to sit down and finalize these negotiations, but it will then take more involvement of Atlanta also on this issue.</p>
          <p>The issue where we have this agreement, it doesn't have anything to do with pricing as constantly. It has to do more with role of the Coca-Cola Company in the operation of the business, and I think that everyone has a very clear definition of the roles, that we do day-to-day operations in the marketplace and they do all the branded advertising.</p>
          <p>If you remember in 2006, when we had this announcement of the concentrated price increase, we mentioned that we got assurances from the CEO of the company in Atlanta that we will not &#x2013; that they will not revisit this issue for a long time. And we are still confident that, that's the case.</p>
          <p>With respect to Venezuela, it's a tough environment that also we are dealing now. We have very important inflation rates. In our estimates, it's between 25, 30%. That has a lot of implications. We have to move your pricing restructure, how do you try to work more efficiently?</p>
          <p>We have the new issue or the more recent issue that the availability of dollars to pay for raw materials is getting very, very complicated. So far, up to the second quarter of this year, we have been able to get dollars at the official rate for most of the raw materials. There is a new regulation that is kind of quite new for these two months, is where you, in order to &#x2013; for you to get dollars at the official rate, you need to get what is called a certificate of non-local production.</p>
          <p>We have to work through that process for all of our raw materials, including concentrate, including the &#x2013; including sugar. And obviously, we do have some of our services that are also saving dollars, including services that are paid to Mexico to cover <mark type="inaudible" /> Mexico.</p>
          <p>We believe that the environment to get these dollars has officially generated getting more and more complex. There have been talks by the authorities that they will provide more liquidity to this in the future, probably to a higher level, through a dual exchange rate mechanism, where they will lead and officially generate for things that are more basic and probably the <mark type="inaudible" /> stuff. And that will certainly put some pressure on the way we translate the bolivars into Mexican pesos as well as the numbers of Bolivars that are spent to buy some raw materials.</p>
          <p>Right now, the Bolivar exchange rate is basically three times the official rate. So you can imagine the impact that that will have into costs. And as a matter of fact, if you look at some of the SG&amp;A figures that will carry that incentive are already affected by that, because we have some services that are charged by our headquarters in Mexico that haven't been paid, because the official rates has not been authorized. And we have to register the effect of paying for those services at the parallel exchange rate, which is basically as I've mentioned, free fold besides that.</p>
          <p>So Venezuela, in summary, is a very complex environment. Volumes are growing, prices are growing. And again, the complex environment is to do with the uncertainty of having raw materials, the uncertainty of having dollars to pay for some of the foreign raw materials, and that creates a lot of pressure on the day-to-day operation in Venezuela. And I think that's a good summary for Venezuela, Rob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, H&#xE9;ctor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Alan Alanis with JP Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, everyone and H&#xE9;ctor. I had a question regarding your results in Brazil. You are showing there organic growth for, if I'm calculating it correctly, of around mid single-digits, around 5 to 6%. What kind of trends are you seeing in beer, and what would explain the difference of the beer performance over there in Brazil, H&#xE9;ctor?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alan, I know that in beer, I know that we have a good performance in Sao Paulo, growing our volumes, as we mentioned.</p>
          <p>And I know that for the total number for the countries, that they are going through flattish of forward slightly negative volumes. But I don't have the details. And I'm sure that the guys from FEMSA <mark type="inaudible" /> will answer this. They've got the strategic answers for the questions, I believe on Monday is when they have the conference call. What I can tell you is that I know that some of the areas are growing, some are coming down. In general, I think that the volumes are flat or slightly negative and Sao Paulo is growing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Now if I may ask just a different question, regarding non-carbonated soft drinks in Mexico, specifically. Jugos del Valle is the number two player in juices, or it was, up until last year. How &#x2013; with the kind of growth that you're achieving in Jugos del Valle, how far are you from for taking over Jumex. And if can you update us in terms of the kind of market share that you have in Mexico, specifically in juices and in general, in non-carbonated soft drinks, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Alan, I don't have specifically the numbers of market share with Jumex. But what I know is that they are not participating in the oranges categories so far.</p>
          <p>They have some groves, but they are not very strong on that area. And that's an area that we have grown important. For us, if you look at what we acquired last year, which is what we called the juices and nectars, we are still trailing Jumex in market share, not for longer than &#x2013; you can probably, I don't know four or five percentage points differential in market share, Jumex having about 40% and we slightly below 40%. If we add all the innovation that we have created over last year, I'm sure that we have surpassed by far the volume that they have. But again, it's a little bit difficult and it is not how the numbers are being measured in the marketplace now.</p>
          <p>For example in oranges, we are competing mainly against De Cola and some of the milk producers in Mexico that we're very strong on that. Antivasa is a growing brand. So just to summarize, in juices and nectars, which is the area that we bought, we are still trailing Jumex with that kind of margins that I mentioned, or four, five percentage points for actual market share. But we have grown very importantly, more than doubling our volume without these innovations where Jumex <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Alex Robarts with Santander.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi everybody, thanks. I wanted to go into the OpEx in Mexico. I mean it was a higher than expected increase for me and kind of looking at it, it has been slightly outpacing your volume growth first quarter and then again in the second quarter. But somehow the year-on-year increase, almost 7% there, is the strongest increase in four quarters. And I'm just wondering if this is a reflection just simply of weak CST demand and what has to be spent in the marketplace to support volumes? Or could it be something maybe perhaps associated with as non-carbs become a bigger piece of the sales mix, I mean, are they necessarily carrying that much more OpEx per case and is this something that we could see going forward, or I mean, I guess could this just be kind of a Coke reimbursement issue vis-&#xE0;-vis that selling and marketing expense? If you could help us get a better understanding on that going forward, that would be great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, Alex. I think that when you look at the operating expenses in Mexico, you have several issues that are maybe difficult to explain, given the fact that that is a number that summarizes a lot of expenses. But let me start with the areas that are extraordinary this year. We have added important routes to market because of all the non-carbonated products. And we are continuing to cover these, all these volumes that I was explaining in the previous question.</p>
          <p>Obviously that implies, in some cases, specialized routes and you can argue that some of these routes were already present, because Jugos del Valle started our operations in February. We started selling Jugos del Valle in February of last year, but we have continued to increase <mark type="inaudible" /> volumes continued to increase. We have continued to spend again something that is ordinary is the inclusion of 400 people and we took over Agua de Los Angeles, just to distribute this jug water business into the valley of Mexico.</p>
          <p>And we have increased, in addition to that, as we continue to foster this sector of selling jug water to home deliveries and office deliveries. So that has created some additional &#x2013; so I'll say that those are the two main things that were not last year, that are now present.</p>
          <p>Now you go to other lines, you have marketing expenses that we expect &#x2013; remember that last year, we had at the end &#x2013; for the full year, we ended up with a fourth quarter that was adjusted to a lower schedule of work, protecting the company for this very difficult financial situation, that we would use our marketing expense. This year, we were not yet focus for the sale, on the activity that we have in Jugos del Valle. With this approach, we believe that marketing expenses are going to be a little bit higher than what we had for the full year last year and we are providing for that quarter-by-quarter.</p>
          <p>We have a very, very strong program to introduce coolers in the marketplace. We believe that, that's a very strong tool for promotion of our products in the marketplace. Again we have mentioned trying to promote single consumption to these coolers program and that obviously brings also the sales expenses to this line.</p>
          <p>So in general, Alex, I think that when you look at the number, it continues to come down as a percentage of revenue, which I think is important, because that's single-driver margin is improving a little bit. But I agree with you that when you look at the growth of OpEx and compare that to just the growth of volumes, not the growth of by revenues, just the growth of volumes, we have similar numbers. And again there, I think those things is what explains this trend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very helpful, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jose Yordan with Deutsche Bank (sic) [UBS Warburg].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi good morning everyone.  A couple of questions, one on the on your gross margin outlook, as sugar continues to increase in international markets as well as creeping up in Mexico, and potentially resin prices are &#x2013; may begin to inch up as well, now that the world is out of crisis mode and economies are beginning to improve. The oil price is rebounding significantly, so how are you protecting yourself against this now? Are you taking any new hedges or what's your strategy to face this environment over the next year?</p>
          <p>And if you could comment on &#x2013; or clarify what's happening in the Mexican Congress regarding excise taxes as it pertains to soft drinks, because we've heard some rumblings about that as the government tries to find new revenues for next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jose. Gross margin, well, obviously that's an area where we don't have certainly a lot of control over that to try to move &#x2013; try to leverage. And but we think that we have been quite &#x2013; I will say, quite successful in implementing all across our operations price increases that seemed like very risky while we were taking those price increases. But that even the drive that the majority have followed this price increases, we believe that has proven to be the right strategy. Right now, I'd say that basically &#x2013; and then we start with Mexico, because we are a little bit different from the rest of the countries.</p>
          <p>Sugar prices have increased, as you correctly pointed out. We have pressures on some of the cost of sweeteners here in Mexico. In the past, that was also &#x2013; in a way we were compensating that by using high fructose corn syrup in some of our products. You remember, we used at some point in time a 50-50 mix of high fructose and sugar, because we were kind of managing the cost impact of sugar price increases in Mexico through that process. Unfortunately, this last year, we also had the effect of a very strong movement of the exchange rate and high fructose is quoted in dollars.</p>
          <p>So even though the price in dollars of high fructose has helped us a little bit versus when you compare it to the cost that we had in dollars last year, the effect of the exchange rate is not helping at all despite of this part of the year. So we have lowered our mix to basically 70% local sugar versus 30% high fructose. The 70% part of the equation is growing probably around 4 or 5% versus last year and we have basically been flat second quarter versus first quarter.</p>
          <p>We do see pressures on this for the second half of the year and the idea is that obviously, we will need to try to see if, now that we have a more stable exchange rate, we can try to offset that effect using more high fructose. Or at the end of the day, we'll try to find the right mix of sweetness for our operation in Mexico.</p>
          <p>And that has been basically compensated during this year, because of the reduction in BP prices. But again, because of the exchange rate has not been as large, we have raising prices in U.S. dollars probably around 25, in some cases, 30% below last year in dollars.</p>
          <p>But because of our fluctuation, the exchange rate along those levels, we basically have flattish or slightly negative resin prices in pesos. If we assume that the exchange rate stays more or less where we are, we will isolate the effect of CapEx and start playing a little bit more directly, the dollar movement of the <mark type="inaudible" />.</p>
          <p>What I was saying is that Mexico is different than the rest of the countries because, especially on the issue of RevPar.  In other big countries, Brazil, sugar is very linked to the international prices. I mean there, we do have some hedges and again, the sugar price. If we were to do like an exercise to do a mark-to-market of the hedges that we have in Brazil, the value of the mark-to-market of that is around, say around $20 million positive, because we have contracts, some of them expiring October, some of them expiring next year. And we even have some small contracts that go all the way to 2011. We are continuously evaluating, specifically the case in Brazil, because that's the only one that we see that is more like a perfect hedge vis-&#xE0;-vis the international price. Well, that's more or less the environment on this.</p>
          <p>With respect to Congress, we have heard the same rumors that you hear. This is an issue that is &#x2013; every year is present at the table. That is, we always see taxes on cigarettes, beer, sometimes liquor, although they have very large excise taxes right now and on soft drinks, too.</p>
          <p>So it's kind of early to know. They announced that &#x2013; If I remember correctly, by October they will have a new budget presented to Congress. And we will see from there, because this is tough. But every year, we are in the limelight with these taxes. It's a variable that is very easy to have access to this industry for revenues, for tax revenues when the situation is tough and what has been in the history in the past there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but no concrete action yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We haven't received any specific either proposal or action or comment from the authorities. Remember that we just had elections less than a month ago, and half of the congress was new there. So, my belief is that we will start receiving some news about that. We are there or not in those plans, not by history.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jose.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from the line of Lore Serra with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, a couple of things. Let me just firstly follow-up on Venezuela. H&#xE9;ctor, if you were forced to run the market rate on the Bolivar three-year results today, would you still be profitable in Venezuela?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Lore, I think that &#x2013; yes, the answer is, yes. We will have to move everything there. We'll probably have an increase, I'd say around 30% of our &#x2013; in cost of goods sold. That would be basically the impact of moving everything to the Bolivar exchange rate.</p>
          <p>And the other place where we -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am sorry, what percent of your COGS are imported versus materials in Venezuela?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's basically aluminum and resin. And that's around 20% of our COGS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your final question comes from the line of Celso Sanchez of Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning. On the Jugos del Valle discussion earlier, you mentioned that, I think I heard you correctly that prices were pushed up 20%. We had heard in some other parts of Mexico that they had been pushed up substantially more than that, and that volumes seemed, at least initially, to still be growing despite the price increase.</p>
          <p>So I guess, could you give us some color in terms of kind of when you did the price increase, and what kind of volume performance you have seen since then? And in that context, if you think there is more room to maybe move prices a little bit more in the months ahead, given you will presumably have resilient volume?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Celso, good morning. You're right. I mean, this product is probably the area that has more competition is in the valley of Mexico. We basically added our price, a Ps. 5 price point in Mexico City, and that was taken during July, during this month. So it's also in the works for the second quarter. The effect of that will be reflected in the second quarter. We have a Ps. 4 price point, and we moved it up to five.</p>
          <p>There are some cities in the North, for example, in Monterrey where this sales growth has been solid at Ps. 7. So I do believe that there is still room for price increases. But I have to recognize that the toughest market in that specific category is being fought in Mexico City.</p>
          <p>It's important that we have this pricing flexibility or that we can improve this pricing, because obviously, as you can imagine, when you have a largest part of the border is to license some other flavors and assortments. So it's important that you get to very close to even more than the profitability that you have in your flavor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks. And maybe could you characterize, I know it's very early, but one would normally expect a price increase to be accompanied by a volume decline. Is that the case here in the early stages, or was there even potentially low volume growth despite the price increase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We continued to see growth in the category still, in our volumes. That's for doing is. <mark type="inaudible" /> the price increase was at the beginning of July. But so far, we continue to see growth in our volumes, despite the price increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just on Jugos del Valle more broadly, can you talk a little bit about the coverage in your territories, how much of an opportunity still do you see expanded coverage of points of sale, or is it really more just the existing points of sale that are pretty well covered, rolling out a broader SKU portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's more the latter. Celso, I mean, since we have been working with this brand basically for a year, we believe that most of these our client base is covered. A lot of them are buying the product, because <mark type="inaudible" /> in terms of the size of the store or whatever. But we are present in basically all of our clients right now.</p>
          <p>So we believe that  innovation is one of the big goals in launching new packages, new sizes, etc, <mark type="inaudible" /> should be. The usual activity that we have in the marketplace, where we've tried to move early with the categories, changing packaging, sizes, and packaging materials. And innovation with new products which is a new area of development for growth for Coca-Cola FEMSA since we acquired Jugos del Valle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just finally, did I understand correctly that, that is the priority for not just for long-term, but also particularly the second half of the year in terms of SKU proliferation?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you referring to priority to innovation, Celso?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just the expansion of the innovation, whether its packages or brands, more I guess, on the packaging side, my understanding was that -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's certainly a priority, it is one of the top of mind activities at our operator cap. We have, in not only Jugos del Valle, but also in GS Visa. We have more ideas with different packaging materials and the relaunching of Coca-Cola Zero has proven to be very good so far. It's a new thing again. Remember, that we had a lot of problems last year with all the recall and everything and the problem that we had with the formula. But so far, Coca-Cola Zero is going very well and that &#x2013; I include that into the innovation, as we are trying also to foster single-serve consumption with the liabilities we push also because we believe that that's a trend that is very strategic for Coca-Cola FEMSA, to pursue the competitors. And in this difficult economic environment, in the past, it's going to be a good leverage for our growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question is a follow-up question from the line of Lore Serra.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I wanted to ask a more general question. As you say, you've done a really good job in the past year of putting through price increases and the volume trends have been, I think, very encouraging in light of that. Yet, still if we look at the first half performance, your margins are down 170 basis points and you've always stressed that you're a profitability-oriented company. So if you look out over the next, I don't know, if it's six months or 12 months, how do you get to stabilized margins? I mean, it sounds like currencies will get a little bit better, but you're going to see more sweetener pressure. I'm not sure how much more pricing power you think you'll have. So what are the levers for you to get to more stable margins and can you give us a timeframe when you think you might be able to do that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Lore, well, certainly, this question comes very often in our conferences. Sometimes we experience a very good top line growth. Those measures took us down all the way to our bottom line. I think that as you correctly pointed out, we have been very successful and continue to show organic growth, number one.</p>
          <p>Also, continue to grow through acquisitions or innovation or new developments, which are also helping the top line. And I believe that this year in particular has been a very tough one because when you have such a large impact on FX and some of the raw materials, it's very difficult to adjust for it, to take the full impact of that on the price. We have ratio leverage to bolster the profitability, either to improve prices or to become more efficient in terms of corporate, that we are always looking for those areas. And we have many examples of using less, be it in each formula that we use, of the light weighting that we have been doing, reducing the size of the cap, reducing the cost of labels.</p>
          <p>We are also working very thoroughly in developing new ways to market. It is not only it's the cost of production, you also have your &#x2013; a big chunk of our costs is also related to sales and distribution. You probably have heard that we have been working in redesigning our way to market because of the complexity that we ourselves are generating, that we need to increase the number of SKUs in our company. But that complexity is what is leading us also the top line growth.</p>
          <p>So we believe there are opportunities to be more efficient in the marketplace. We are reanalyzing the complexity of our organization. We are doing some downsizing in the organization in some of the areas where we see some fat. And in general, the message I want to send is, we will continue to look at striking opportunities, because that is in our DNA I think it's been there since the IPO of this company. We will continue to look for more efficient way of doing our &#x2013; of going to the market and provision our costs. We are always looking at all these aspects. We have target for our operators in terms of savings that they have to bring, in terms of payrolls, in terms of cost of raw materials. In every aspect, we have &#x2013; we do follow up every retailer very closely.</p>
          <p>And the message I want to send is that we take the opportunities to grow top line. Sometimes it implies an approach that has either a different business model vis-&#xE0;-vis the Coca-Cola conference where we shared, for example, in the case of non-carbonated, 50/50 the profits and therefore, it starts an implied reduction in the profit pool, although it showed a slight reduction in the asset &#x2013; or the investment that is committed by the company.</p>
          <p>And sometimes you go into lines of business like juices that have raw materials that are very different from what we carry in soft drinks, where you have to buy fruits and you have to buy &#x2013; and to live with the volatility that is cost effects for us, with probably smaller margins than we have expressed in the past. And our goal is how do we improve these margins to get into levels similar to what we have in see as this, especially if we are seeing some cannibalization of, for example, indication of the price. But in cases where we don't see any cannibalization, but we see a different consumption location, we are glad to take extra margins, even if it's not extra cash profits, even though it might not be at the same margin, but it's something that is additional to volume of things that we have. And that's, I'd say, is the best explanation I can give you, Lore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, H&#xE9;ctor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes the question and the answer session. I would now like to hand the call back over to Mr. Trevi&#xF1;o for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>If you'd only let me, to thank you for your interest in our company and obviously, we'll be open for any more questions that you might have for this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for participation in today's conference. This concludes your presentation and you may now disconnect. Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>