<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1491054" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-07-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3057</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial &amp; Administrative Officer">H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o Guti&#xE9;rrez</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Securities USA, Inc.">Lauren E. Torres</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Alan Alanis</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Lore Serra</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Harding Loevner LLC">Margaret E. Kalvar</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Casa de Bolsa Credit Suisse Mexico SA de CV">Antonio Gonz&#xE1;lez</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Alexander Robarts</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening, everyone, and welcome to Coca-Cola FEMSA Second Quarter Earnings Event Conference Call. As a reminder, today's conference is being recorded and all participants are in listen-only mode. At the request of the company, we will open the conference up for questions-and-answers after the presentation.</p>
          <p>During this conference call, management may discuss certain forward-looking statements concerning Coca-Cola FEMSA's future performance and should be considered as good faith estimates made by the company. These forward-looking statements reflect management's expectations and are based upon currently available data. Actual results are subject to future events and uncertainties, which can materially impact the company's actual performance.</p>
          <p>At this time, I'll now turn the conference over to Mr. H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o, Coca-Cola FEMSA's CFO. Please go ahead, Mr. Trevi&#xF1;o.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. Thank you for joining us today. As some of you may have had little time to review the press release we just sent out, I would like to use this conference call to discuss our results and operational trends and allow our team to revisit additional questions after this call. In the face of our continued challenging cost environment coupled with the volatility of our main priorities and tough weather conditions in some of our territories, our operators delivered double-digit revenue and EBITDA growth in both of our divisions.</p>
          <p>During the second quarter of 2012, we continued to integrate the results of Grupo Tampico, Grupo CIMSA and since May, Grupo Fomento Queretano in our Mexican operations. Their performance contributes positively to our Mexican and Central America division and our consolidated results. Organically, the main drivers of our company's performance continue to be our strategy of selective price increases implemented over the past several months, the execution skills of our operators and the strength of our multi-category beverage category or portfolio led by innovation in our still beverage category and our extensive sparkling beverage portfolio.</p>
          <p>In the second quarter, our reported consolidated revenues reached more than Ps. 36 billion, up 28% from the second quarter of 2011. Organically, excluding the integration of our newly merged territories in Mexico, our consolidated total revenues grew more than 16% for the quarter. This increase was driven by average price per unit case growth in every operation and volume growth mainly in Venezuela, Argentina and Brazil.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated sales volume grew 16%, including our newly merged territories in Mexico. Organically, our volume remained flat. However, once again, innovation contributed significantly to 12% volume growth in the still beverage category. This growth was driven by our recently launched fresh brand orangeades in Venezuela, our consumer's preference for the Jugos del Valle line of beverages in Mexico and Brazil, and the launch of Fuze Tea in most of our territories since May, replacing NESTEA and reinforcing the Coca-Cola systems bet on these fast-growing beverage segment.</p>
          <p>The performance of our strong portfolio of flavored sparkling beverage brands such as Hit in Venezuela and Fanta in Brazil, coupled with the growth of brand Coca-Cola in Argentina, Mexico and Central America, compensated for overall volume declines in Colombia and a decrease in volume from our water portfolio in Mexico.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, savings arising from lower PET cost in most of our operations and lower sugar cost in South America division were only partially offset by increased cost of fructose in Mexico and Argentina combined with the average depreciation of our main operations, local currencies as applied to our U.S. dollar-denominated raw material cost. Consequently, our consolidated gross margin expanded 10 basis points to 46% in the second quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated operating income grew 8% to Ps. 4.7 billion in the second quarter. Organic operating income remained flat. As in the previous quarter, we continued to reinforce our marketplace execution and investing our returnable packaging base. We continued to experience higher labor cost in Venezuela, in combination with increased labor and freight cost in Argentina and slightly higher freight cost in Brazil due to changes to the transportation regulation in that country.</p>
          <p>We've registered additional expenses related to the development of information systems and commercial capabilities in connection with implementation of our commercial models and we made certain investments related to the development of new business lines. Most of these expenses will recur going forward as we continue to prepare our company to capture more opportunities in the future.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, as a consequence of a change in the labor law in Venezuela and the changes to labor tenure among other areas, we register a one-time provision in our other net not operating expense lines. During the quarter, tax shield related to interest on capital included in a dividend declared by our Brazilian subsidiary resulted in a lower effective tax rate at the consolidated level. For the quarter, our consolidated net controlling interest income remained almost flat at Ps. 2.7 billion.</p>
          <p>Now, I would spend some time talking about the performance of each division. In the second quarter, as reported, our Mexico and Central America division sold more than 504 million unit cases of beverages. As reported, our Mexican operations volume grew 28%, including 106 million unit basis contributed by our newly merged territories. Organically, our volume in Mexico declined 1%, cycling a 7% volume increase in the second quarter of 2011. And 8% volume decline in our water portfolio, mainly driven by our efforts to improve the profitability of our jug water platform offset the increase volume of brand Coca-Cola, driven by the performance of our single-serve platform and returnable multi-serve presentations. And the 6% growth of our still beverage category led by the consumer's preference for the Jugos del Valle line of products, and the launch of Fuze Tea, our systems led to continue winning in this important and growing beverage segment.</p>
          <p>In Central America, we generated 2% volume growth in the second quarter. This increase was driven mainly by 6% volume growth in the still beverage category supported by the Estrella Azul portfolio, the launch of the Fuze Tea brand and the performance of brand Coca-Cola, which grew 2% supported by our returnable base.</p>
          <p>Our division's reported total revenues grew 30% to Ps. 17.6 billion. Organically, the division's total revenues grew 6%. Our strong point of sale execution and our ability to deliver the right package at the right price for every consumption occasion supported a 7% organic increase in our average price per unit case in the division during the second quarter.</p>
          <p>With regard to our profitability, this quarter we experienced the higher volatility of the Mexican pesos since 2009 at the evaluation of more than 15% on average. These depreciation of the peso as applied to our U.S. dollar-denominated raw material cost in combination with high fructose prices in Mexico offset savings resulting from lower PET prices. As a result, our gross margin was 47.5% for the second quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>Our operating income increased 5% to Ps. 2.7 billion. In order to achieve our net synergy target, we continued to incur expenses and make investments related to our newly merged territories in Mexico. Among others, these include cost related to restructuring, the distribution and manufacturing network and certain one-time charges, such as legal and banking fees related to the merger.</p>
          <p>Organically, our operating expenses increased due to continued reinforcement of our marketplace execution to bolster our competitive position. Moreover, we made investments related to the development of information systems and commercial capabilities in connection with implementation of our commercial models.</p>
          <p>In addition to these investments, certain other items, many of which are related to the development of new lines of businesses affected our year-over-year comparability.</p>
          <p>Our Mexico and Central America division continue to deliver positive results despite the challenging environment. We continued to foster single-serve consumption of our sparkling beverages, especially brand Coca-Cola. We led the Coca-Cola system efforts to launch Fuze Tea with excellent results, doubling historic point-of-sale progress we achieved with the previous brand. Additionally, the brand equity of our approach and our operators' ability to implement selective price initiatives enable us to partially mitigate the effect of the Mexican Peso volatility.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, we continue to benefit from the investments we have made in returnable presentations, which once again contributed significantly to our sales volume for the quarter.</p>
          <p>In our still beverage portfolio, consumers' preference for our Valle Frut orangeade continued to grow. We also heavily leveraged the strength of our sales, marketing and distribution to successfully launch Fuze Tea. Moreover in Panama, on top of our existing distribution of Estrella Azul line of products in our red trucks, we complemented our offers with Del Prado, the leading juice brand in that country.</p>
          <p>Now, I will briefly expand on the integration of our newly merged territories in Mexico. With regard to Grupo Tampico and Grupo CIMSA, which we rapidly and completely integrated into our Mexican operations since the fourth quarter of 2011. We have already launched the Sidral Mundet brand, increased cooler coverage and raised prices to par with the rest of our territories. We accomplished all of this, while restructuring the distribution and manufacturing network to further improve the efficiency of these new territories.</p>
          <p>Since May of this year we have already incorporated Grupo Tampico, Grupo Fomento Queretano franchising to our Mexican operations with even greater speed. Launched the Sidral Mundet brand, raised prices of certain products and reinforced their local sparkling beverage brand, Victoria.</p>
          <p>Our in-house teams have done a tremendous job so far and consequently we're well on track to meet the Ps. 800 million of net synergies we outlined for you at the end of 2011. Should currency volatility recede, we look forward to a more stable cost environment for the second half of 2012. In addition, the following factors will provide a more stable sweetener outlook for 2012.</p>
          <p>Sugar prices in Mexico have been sequentially stable. We continue to benefit from our stake in Grupo PIASA, and we have lock-in prices for most of our fructose consumption needs. Furthermore, we have seen a more moderate PET pricing environment, which should remain in place for the rest of the year. In this improved cost environment, we are confident that our operators' discipline and superior skill set will continue to deliver positive results for our company.</p>
          <p>Now let me talk about South America division. Our South America division total sales volume grew close to 1% in the second quarter, reaching close to 266 million unit cases. This increase was driven by volume growth in Venezuela, Argentina and Brazil, which compensated for a volume decline in Colombia.</p>
          <p>In our Colombian franchise territory, volume was down 6% in the face of tough weather conditions during the quarter and 10% volume growth in the second quarter of 2011. In Argentina, we continued to see a positive volume growth momentum despite an economic slowdown in the country and 9% growth in the second quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Sparkling beverages growth was driven by a 5% volume increase in brand Coco-Cola. Aquarius flavored water was the driver behind the 8% growth of our water portfolio. In the still beverage category, Hi-C orangeade grew more than 30%, successfully building on a 2011 launch, while this Cepita juice brand continued to grow at a healthy pace.</p>
          <p>In Venezuela, we also continued to see positive momentum as exemplified by our 7% volume growth for the quarter. Our still beverage volume almost tripled due to the success of our Fresh orangeade and the launch of Fuze Tea. In the sparkling beverage category, our volume grew 2%, driven by our flavored sparkling beverage brand. Also, the bottled water category generated 8% volume growth. Consistent with our commitment to innovation, we continue to present our consumers with relevant beverage and packaging alternatives, while reinforcing our marketplace execution, especially our cooler coverage.</p>
          <p>Our volume in Brazil grew more than 1% as compared to 2011. We faced a tougher start to the quarter, mainly due to bad weather conditions but experienced volume recovery in May and June. Our water portfolio volume grew 16%, driven by the performance of the Crystal brand. In the still beverage category, our volume grew 12% driven by the Jugos del Valle line of business and the Powerade brands. Our flavored sparkling beverage volume grew 6%, supported mainly by the Fanta brand.</p>
          <p>In the second quarter of 2012, our South American division reported total revenue growth of 26%, reaching Ps. 18.7 billion, mainly as a result of double-digit revenue growth in Venezuela, Argentina, and Columbia. Our strategy of selective price increases implemented over the past several months across the division accounted for the majority of our incremental revenue growth.</p>
          <p>Lower sugar cost in the division combined with lower PET cost across most of our operations offset the average evaluations of the Brazilian real and the Argentine peso as applied to our U.S. dollar denominator raw material costs. These resulted in 180 basis point expansion of our gross margin, which reached 44.7% for the second quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>Our South America division's operating income grew 12% to Ps. 2.1 billion. Operating expenses were affected by higher labor cost in Venezuela, higher labor and freight cost in Argentina, higher freight cost in Brazil, and increased marketing investments across the division to continue reinforcing our point-of-sale execution and commercial models.</p>
          <p>Our South America division delivered solid top line results in the second quarter of 2012, despite bad weather conditions in some of our franchise territories. Continuous innovation in the still beverage category allow us to capture opportunities through the Jugos del Valle platform, while the launch of Fuze Tea would certainly reinforce our offering in our growing beverage sector. We continue to reinforce our sparkling beverage portfolio with single-serve in returnable alternatives, while our strong portfolio of flavored sparkling beverage brand continues to deliver incremental volume growth. Furthermore, we constantly reinforce our execution capabilities and we expand our efforts to improve cooler coverage in order to support our wide portfolio of beverages.</p>
          <p>As we face the second half of the year, we see international sugar prices remaining flat sequentially, mainly benefiting our Brazilian and Colombian operations. In addition, tea prices will remain stable for the remainder of the year. However, we closely monitor currency volatility which has been offsetting the benefits of lower US dollar denominator raw material cost.</p>
          <p>Finally, I will briefly talk about our financial performance for the quarter. This quarter our company continues to deliver increased cash flow from its geographically balanced portfolio territories, providing us with the continued financial flexibility to look for opportunities in the beverage industry.</p>
          <p>As of June 30, 2012, we had a cash balance of Ps. 9.2 billion and our total debt was Ps. 21.2 billion while our net debt-to-EBITDA ratio was 0.5 times and our EBITDA to net interest ratio of 18.7 times.</p>
          <p>With regard to the potential Philippines transaction, which we previously shared with you, our on the ground deal have nearly completed the evaluation of these operations. On a parallel track, a separate team of our executives is working on the financial valuation model. During the second half of the year, we should be able to reach a decision as to where we should move forward with these undertakings.</p>
          <p>The Coco-Cola system through Jugos del Valle in Mexico have taken an additional step in the dairy category in Latin America by acquiring Santa Clara, one of the leading players in this category in the Mexican market. This transaction will broaden our portfolio of beverages. Moreover, we at Coca-Cola FEMSA are enthusiastic about the opportunity to share our joint lessons from the Estrella Azul venture in Panama with our partner, The Coca-Cola Company. We remain confident by the volatility we faced during the first half of the year, our operators capabilities, our wide beverage offering and our commitment to flawless execution and continuous innovation, which allows to continue delivering increased value for you, our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Thank you as always for your continued trust and support. And now, I would like to open out the call for any questions that you may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from the line of Lauren Torres from HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, everyone. H&#xE9;ctor, my question is relating to the operating margin pressure we saw in the quarter. It seemed it was like more than we were expecting, maybe you are expecting too heading into the quarter. I was just curious if some of these expenses were basically borrowed from the second half or how should we think about the second half? Are they trending higher in both in Mexico and Central America and South America? Why was this, I guess, more than you had initially anticipated, at least we were initially anticipating?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon, Lauren. Certainly the four areas I'll say where we're having a lot of pressure during this quarter has to do first of all with the raw materials and FX movements that we saw during the quarter in most of the countries and certainly the one that I have more off the top of my head being Mexico, the depreciation of the Mexican peso but it was very similar to other currencies, was close to 15% during the quarter, because we were facing the highest number on the exchange rate this year versus the lowest point that we have last year. So that put a lot of pressure on some of the raw materials. So even though we have PET prices in dollars terms coming down, we couldn't benefit because of that because when you translate that into Mexican pesos or Brazilian real or Colombian pesos, we were impacted by that.</p>
          <p>Raw material prices, I mentioned, PET having still more stable environment actually coming down. Raw material prices, the surprise was more on high fructose consume. We had some increases in sugar, especially standard sugar, refined sugar in some other countries had lot lower prices. Certainly, it was the case for Brazil. It was high in the markets where we used high fructose, especially the Mexico market that definitely impacted our numbers. And that's with respect to the cost of raw materials and FX.</p>
          <p>The other important element has to do and that's &#x2013; let me review first in Mexico. The very important element is the expenses related to the merger of these three territories. If you look back, Queretaro happened basically two months ago, so we are just in the process of having a lot of our people doing now the takeover of that and certainly reducing the head count in these territories where we are moving very, very fast. In these three areas, we have already reduced around 750 people in head count with no labor issues at all, not a single note in the newspaper. So that certainly will help us going into the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>We have some other expenses that are not that significant but you have a lot of these small things like, for example, some of these expenses related to doing the due diligence in Philippines. We have that as our expenses in the corporate headquarters which are recorded in the Mexico area. We have, maybe some of you know, we will be moving to a new building, our corporate headquarters at the end of September, very close to our offices here in Mexico City. It's basically, I don't know, less than a mile away. But, as we already contracted the new building, which we are leasing the same that we have, we are at this moment paying double the rent because we haven't left the building where we are. So, these are small things that are piling up and certainly not helping in this quarter that was very difficult on the raw material environment.</p>
          <p>We have and we mentioned that during the first quarter, Lauren. I know that's important for everyone to understand. We have in &#x2013; and let me go back one step and this is for all the territories. In 2010, we have received this news by SAP that the system that we have had for many years was no longer &#x2013; they would no longer support because it was obsolete for them, so we needed to change to all of our systems to a new SAP platform. That expense that was incurred basically during two years was capitalized and we are now in the phase of amortizing those expenses. That's something that we'll have in the future. But certainly it's an expense that is needed just to support the tremendous number of SKU's in all of our commercial practice.</p>
          <p>We have some expenses related to businesses that we are developing like the Blak coffee line of business that we are experimenting with the equipments and amortize with some of these equipments. And that so far, if you look at the P&amp;L of the Blak coffee &#x2013; alternative of the Blak coffee &#x2013; let me use the word initiative, we have probably around $1 million that is affecting this quarter &#x2013; of our next, if you were to look at P&amp;L isolated for Blak. So when you add up a lot of these little things that's basically what is not helping us in the SG&amp;A numbers.</p>
          <p>When you move to South America then, which is also very important. Very important that everyone has in mind that the labor regulations in Argentina and in Venezuela are very tough and that we have suffered increases in salaries and compensations for middle class &#x2013; middle level workers and even white-collar workers in our offices that are substantially above inflation and that's something that is changing &#x2013; that is &#x2013; that's the situation in those countries.</p>
          <p>We have been able to increase prices importantly in those two countries and within that we basically compensated part of that but not all of that. Some of those labor cost increases affect also the third party that give us service for freight, plus some of the gas prices that have been increasing.</p>
          <p>So when you add all of these costs, I think the fact that we have pressures on FX, plus raw materials, together with some of these elements of one-time charges. And then this &#x2013; a bunch of small things that start piling up in a quarter, where the wind was not in &#x2013; we were headwind, no. So my expectation is that the second half of the year, some of these one-time charges will be isolated and removed. I expect that the FX environment, although today was a very tough day, will be little bit more better for us. We're expecting prices of cane sugar and PET to remain stable. I'm a little bit concerned with corn because of what we have seen with corn prices and the potential impact on high fructose. But I think that, all in all, I do see second half of the year that would be better on the margins than what we're presenting in this quarter. It's probably a long explanation, but I think the result that we have might &#x2013; that I extended on this answer to all this extent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. That's very detailed and helpful. Just, can I ask around that answer. I think previously you had talked about an operating margin being relatively stable this year with a better second half, do you think you could still hit that target?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that the good news, Lauren, here is that we are increasing the top line at a faster pace than what we were anticipating, which is very good. I mean, when you look at the revenues growing 30%, it's a very important movement. So, with that in mind, I think that margins will be slightly below what we had last year. But what I like to think is that once we recapture the profitability of some of these territories and start having all these synergies embedded in the systems, we certainly start seeing that kind of growth in the bottom line. The fact that revenues are growing at this pace, even if it's because of acquisitions, but the fact that we can immediately start putting new pricing architecture in these territories, continue growing volume, continue to penetrate on coolers and market share, I think that is good news for the future.</p>
          <p>Every single market where we're operating, we have increased in market share. The only exception is a small reduction in Brazil in colas. All the other territories in every category, in every geography, we have positive behavior in our market share numbers. We have positive behavior in brand awareness. So I think that the base is there for us to start producing the bottom results that this company deserves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that for the end of the year, given the fact that the volume &#x2013; the revenues is growing faster than what we're anticipating. I think that it's possible that we see a reduction in some of our market. Remember also just to &#x2013; one final point here, as we have new categories, remember that water and sometimes juices, when the raw material is expensive and certainly milk and dairy products, their profitability is smaller than what we have in soft drinks. So I will also focus in how our amount in dollars, in terms of maybe income or operating profit is increasing as well as margins. But it's normal that as we change the mix of our growth, we see some pressure on the margins. Thank you, Lauren.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Alan Alanis with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, H&#xE9;ctor. Thank you. I have a question regarding your working capital. I mean, we saw a deterioration of Ps. 1.8 billion during the quarter. And on my calculations, your operating cash flow is substantially below last year's second quarter and the first quarter of this year. What's driving this? Are there some recurrent or non-recurrent elements? And that will be my first question. My second question has to do with accretion and dilution of the acquisitions, when do you expect them to be accretive?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Alan. I think that in general, we might have some impact here on non-carbonated drinks and some of the inventories there. But other than some adjustment that we have done in Brazil on working capital for the group, but was suffering a little bit during the last quarter. I don't have anything in my radar screen that strikes me as odd in working capital. Let me give you some numbers.</p>
          <p>When we look at &#x2013; if I look from the 1 of January to the first half of the year &#x2013; during the first half of the year, free cash flow as the ultimate measure of generation power of the cash of this company, where CapEx are involved, working capital is involved also, it's growing importantly. We have generated close to $400 million of free cash flow, of which we paid close to $400 million in dividend in May. We paid down some of the expense &#x2013; some of the indebtedness that was embedded in the three mergers, especially Queretaro because maybe some of those happened. Probably Tampico happened before year-end. But some of those &#x2013; CIMSA happened during the first part of the year. And our CapEx program that is very aggressive. So I am not that worried with working capital. We follow very closely these indexes. We have had some increases that had to do with some inventories, but it's basically one or two days, but nothing major to move.</p>
          <p>I think that with respect to your second question, Queretaro is still on the works, because we just finalized &#x2013; we closed the transaction in May. I feel very, very confident with Tampico and CIMSA. As I mentioned, we are increasing prices to the pricing architecture that we have. We are closing down some of the facilities &#x2013; production facilities, adjusting some of the warehouses. As a matter of fact, we just have a board meeting where we have an approval to move one of the returnable PET lines from one of the plants in Tampico to our Villahermosa plant for better logistics. So those are savings that we'll start accumulating in the second part to the year or beginning of next year. And we also get approval to move two production lines from CIMSA to the new plant that Queretaro built very recently.</p>
          <p>So that Queretaro will be an important center of production for us. So we are very well ahead and very active on moving things around in these territories. So if you ask me right now, are these operations accretive? Yes, these operations are accretive already. I think that Queretaro will need a little bit more time to mature. And as I mentioned, adjusting close to 750 people is expensive, but we already have done that. It's part of our results for this quarter and we will start benefiting from that starting next quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you so much, H&#xE9;ctor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Lore Serra with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, H&#xE9;ctor. I wanted to ask just as a follow-up to what you're talking about in terms of the mergers. Could you give us an estimate of how many kind of "one-time" expenses you had associated with the three acquisitions that are in your &#x2013; I don't know second quarter or first half numbers associated with some of the issues you've mentioned and how much more is left for the third quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>During the quarter, Lore, more or less in terms of liquidation expenses and some due diligence expenses mainly related to Queretaro, the number is around Ps. 200 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>During the second quarter, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how much do you anticipate for the balance of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have a definite answer right now, Lore. Let me check with the plans that Ernesto Silva has for Mexico. I know that they are adjusting some of the distribution and production capacity still going forward, so we might see some. But my feeling is that the bulk of Tampico and CIMSA is already done. We might still have some for the Queretaro because it is very recent. So I'll ask Pepe to review that and give you a better idea for the third and fourth quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And if we look at the first two transactions, what kind of a run rate are you? If I remember correctly the first two were about Ps. 600 million of the Ps. 800 million in synergies. What &#x2013; if we sort of mark-to-market, where you are right now? How ramped up are you on those synergies? Should we see a lot of them, sort of on a run rate basis into the second half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll say that around 60% of the synergies that we're anticipating for those two first transactions are already placed and we will have them for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. Okay. And I guess, I would like your impression, I mean, the pricing you've taken sort of across markets, is really strong, I mean, it's very attractive given, if we measure historically. So I guess it's a little hard to see all of them on the margin pressure. But when you talk to the operators, how comfortable are they with the pricing environment in the different regions. I mean, I guess you mentioned competitively you're doing well, but maybe particularly in Brazil where you're going to have to take a lot more pricing, I guess with some of the excise tax changes. How comfortable are you with taking pricing from these levels across your different regions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Lore, I think that in general, the measures I want to give here is, in every market, in eight of the nine countries, we feel confident that we can continue to improve prices slightly as always, measuring a lot what the competitors do. I will give you the examples of the largest market. Brazil, since we have some impacts where the value-added taxes over there, everyone is increasing prices and everyone should continue increasing prices in Brazil in the near-term.</p>
          <p>In Mexico, I think that we have flexibility, although I have to recognize that Pepsi, our main competitor is very aggressive with some specific packages in some specific regions. But one does need to &#x2013; I mean, I would like to remind everyone that in areas of the value of Mexico, PepsiCo now is the third brand in colas, so they are desperate to move to start getting some traction in volume. And the only country that I feel a little bit more cautious about pricing is Colombia. I think that Colombia because of the reason we have disclosed for many quarters. There's very tough competition that we have with Postob&#xF3;n and the flavor brands. We feel that if we want to get the per capitas of Colombia to the levels that we have in other countries, it might be necessary to do a resetting of the prices, so that we start generating a lot of volume growth and it's something that we are discussing as we speak...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Pardon the interruption, ladies and gentlemen. Your conference will resume momentarily. Ladies and gentlemen, we will now resume with Q&amp;A. <mark type="audio gap" /> (43:24-46:07)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry about that, problem with the line. I was saying Lore, that in Colombia it's where I feel a little bit more uncomfortable with respect to the prices, mainly as a result of a strategy that we are discussing with the Coca-Cola company that in order for us to really grow the per capitas of the market there. We are analyzing the possibility of resetting prices to probably to have more accessible growth to our consumers and see how that reacts. And we will be doing some experimentation over there. But in general, I think that the pricing environment continues to be positive as always, very competitive pressure that we have. Thank you, Lore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your question comes from the line of Margaret Kalvar with Harding Loevner. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. I wanted to ask what your thoughts were about volumes, which seemed a little bit light? And, if you could give me more color on reasons and any trends or views you have or progression during the quarter either volumes getting stronger or weakening as we went into the successive months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon Margaret. In general, I think that we have to isolate some of these categories and conflicts. In Colombia, we suffer a little bit on the volume, but we have a very strong pricing during the first half of the year. And that certainly &#x2013; as you look at Colombia in revenues, the revenues were positive even though we have a negative volume trends. The rest of the conflicts where good in general. Mexico was a little bit soft. When you look ironically, we were like 1% below. But it was mainly the issue with Bolivar.</p>
          <p>So, in general, I will say that, I still feel confident with the consumer sentiment in most of the countries, although the Argentina is a little tougher to read. Venezuela, the volumes are doing very well. We changed from NESTEA to Fuze Tea to match our price, we're expecting some reduction there, but volume trends are very good. As we mentioned, we increase progress to what &#x2013; to the progress that we had with NESTEA and basically NESTEA was in operation for a few weeks, because they were struggling to get production and distribution in place that we started in May.</p>
          <p>So, I feel confident with that. Obviously macroeconomic environment affect this. For Mexico, it's one of important how the U.S. performs macro-economically. For Brazil and Argentina, I'm not a bit worried because of the commodities and the impact that we have, and certainly we have seen some kind of a slowdown in Brazil and Argentina, where still our volumes are continuing to be positive. And that's more or less the story Margaret. I think that some products or some categories are better than others, brand Coca-Cola continues to be strong everywhere. And as I mentioned market share &#x2013; in terms of market share, we are growing everywhere, everywhere, in every category, in every product, except a little bit of reduction in colors in Brazil and a little bit of flavors in Colombia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Have you noticed any of the increase in per capitas in the areas of Mexico that are below the medium that had been sighted as potential drivers of continued volume growth there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in Mexico it has been more ample. I mean there is no specific market that is &#x2013; that certainly has been outstanding either geographically or socio economic. I mean it's more in every category and every consumption occasion. We have been growing the volumes. And for the per capita small that is stable are increasing a little bit, now depending on some of these categories. And that's the same for the other companies. We haven't noticed any strategic movement in a specific geographic area or socio economic area that is improving the per capita.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Margaret.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Antonio Gonz&#xE1;lez with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for taking my question. Hello, H&#xE9;ctor. I wanted to ask two things. First, on the jug water business in Mexico, can you give us some insights H&#xE9;ctor on what do you think needs to be changed in this particular business so that your volumes are turned around to keep the distribution channel or is it the pricing that needs to be fixed? And my second question has to do with Fuze. Would you be able to share some insights on how were you able to launch a new brand in Mexico so rapidly and with the result that you obviously showed today in terms of your still beverage portfolio? What were the main challenges that you saw there and probably how those &#x2013; this launch talk about capabilities of innovation that you guys have developed over the last few years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Antonio. In water, I think that the jug water business is something that, if you go back in time a little bit, Coca-Cola, the original Coca-Cola FEMSA didn't have much. Then we acquired the business from CIMSA because they were selling jug water in Mexico City. We started to learn from that. Then when we acquired these new territories, especially CIMSA and Toluca and Tampico, they have very good jug water penetration in their territories and they have a water business that is profitable. Some of the learnings there is that jug water cannot and should not travel a lot because distribution expenses will kill your profits. So, either you sell in the main cities with a small production plant in some of those territories or you better stop serving faraway territories and we are adjusting a little bit of that.</p>
          <p>The other important learning is that most of these other companies have home delivery, home and in offices also now. But home delivery is important and they have good profitability in there because you keep the retailer margin and that's an important element that we have been developing also in Coca-Cola FEMSA. When you think of the opportunity of &#x2013; if you have a crowd that is taking jug water to homes and you start putting juices and potentially they approach and some soft drinks, I think that there is a combination for our niche business that will bring some profitability in the future for Coca-Cola FEMSA.</p>
          <p>With respect to the second question and which is more related to, I assume to Fuze Tea, I think that in general having this idea that since the beginning of the year we knew that by May 1, we will stop selling NESTEA. The whole system prepared for that. The formula was owned by the Coca-Cola Company, so we didn't have an issue with the formula. The shape of the bottle was owned by Coca-Cola Company, but the labels and the name and some other small things in the label and the shape of the bottle from, leaves, tea leaves that are embedded there, are the property of Nestl&#xE9;. So we were able to prepare our system to a campaign in advance, a very good marketing campaign in my opinion starting to create some attraction to Fuze Tea and obviously some [something] and then we put all our sales force to start selling this product even in places where we didn't sell NESTEA before. And I feel that as a result, I have to be honest, we were lucky a little bit that Nestl&#xE9; as I mentioned was struggling a little bit with production capacity because they didn't have any production capacity in Mexico or the other countries and also with distribution capacity. So they are doing some, for example, in Mexico I know very well that they are doing some channels with Modelo and some other channels, traditional channels with Jarritos to try to leverage that distribution. But I think that also &#x2013; we were also helped by the fact that they were a little bit late on this process. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much, H&#xE9;ctor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Alex Robarts with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks. I have two questions. First, interested to hear a little bit more about the volume trends in Brazil, you talked about them just now. But, we're seeing double-digit volumes just down the road in Rio in the second quarter. You've got &#x2013; CSD seem to be flat here for you guys in 2Q in Brazil. I mean, I understand, you mentioned the weather issues, but have you been taking price such that you've been seeing some impact on the volumes and to the extent that we've got some market share loss in colas, just curious to know what was going on there? And if we can kind of get the fuller picture on this tax increase, 3% to 4%, does that sound like what you need to do to pass on this increase? And do you expect that to be really done before the October 1 implementation date? So that's kind of the first question.</p>
          <p>And the second one relates to the Philippines and I appreciate you've done and completed some of your ground work out there. Can you share with us some color or what some of your findings were? The market seemed to contract, the CSD market last year in the Philippines seemed to &#x2013; decreased about 5%. Just wondering what the pace of the recovery of that market was this year and any other thoughts if possible about your findings in the Philippines that would be great?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Alex. Brazil, first. Brazil, we're having increases in prices in June. We're planning to increase prices again in September and broadly one more at the end of the year basically, as you say, to compensate for the additional taxes that are scheduled to be implemented, if I remember correctly, by October as I mentioned.</p>
          <p>The estimate that we have from our operators down there is that somewhere around 4% price increase should set us level with the new tax. So that will basically compensate for the new taxes and we believe that the holdings will start moving prices. And when I say that we lost a little bit of market share, probably it was been very exaggerated. It is just a few fractions of basis points in market share. But I'm being completely open with you as I mentioned that that's the only place where we were losing a little bit of points there. So, that's &#x2013; my impression is that that's basically what is driving some of the volume trends in Brazil. I mean, if I remember correctly first quarter, we were around flat. Volumes this second quarter, we are around 1.5% to 2% above. But everything has to be with the fact that the economy is decelerating a bit and we are increasing prices because of this tax situation that we have in Brazil.</p>
          <p>With respect to the Philippines, we have been doing some ground work as we explained. The trends look positive and in fact some 96 million people inhabitants. They sell around, a little more than 500 million unit cases. The Coca-Cola Company reported in their recent reports that the increase, if I remember correctly, 6% to 7% margins during the quarter. So, the trends are good. I think that in general, we are enthusiastic about the opportunity. We need to complete all of our work there and once we complete that work to start looking at valuation processes and start negotiating with the Coca-Cola Company based on that valuation. And obviously as always as soon we have more information that we can share, we'll share that with you. But, we feel enthusiastic about this idea of &#x2013; it looks like an interesting market Alex, in many aspects very similar to what we have in Latin America, a lot of fragmented retail market, a lot of small mom-and-pops. Here the consumption is good because in other parts of Asia, it's more drink that are warm and not bubbles, noncarbonated and brand Coca-Cola has good penetration there. So I think that as soon as we can share more information, we will certainly share that with you in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I would now like to turn the call over to management for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you everyone for your attention to this call. And thank you for accommodating this call in the afternoon. It was kind of strange, but it was complicated with the agendas. And Jose and Roland will be available also to follow with additional answers to these questions. Thank you so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>