<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1427347" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-10-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>3057</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial &amp; Administrative Officer">H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o Guti&#xE9;rrez</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Securities USA, Inc.">Lauren E. Torres</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Alan Alanis</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Lore Serra</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Celso W. S&#xE1;nchez</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Casa de Bolsa Credit Suisse Mexico SA de CV">Antonio Gonzalez</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and welcome to Coca-Cola FEMSA's Third Quarter 2011 Earnings Results Conference Call. As a reminder, today's conference is being recorded and all participants are in a listen-only mode. At the request of the company, we'll open the conference up for questions and answers after the presentation.</p>
          <p>During this conference call, management may discuss certain forward-looking statements concerning Coca-Cola FEMSA's future performance, and should be considered as good faith estimates made by the company.</p>
          <p>These forward looking statements reflect management expectations and are based upon currently available data. Actual results are subject to future events and uncertainties, which can materially impact the company's actual performance.</p>
          <p>At this time, I would now like to turn the conference over to Mr. H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o, Coca-Cola FEMSA's CFO. Please go ahead, Mr. Trevi&#xF1;o.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us today. During the third quarter of 2011, our portfolio of franchise territories across Latin America delivered doubled EBITDA and bottom line growth, despite the challenging commodity cost environment and the lower market volatility, we have faced during the year.</p>
          <p>The main drivers of our performance for the quarter were our revenue management initiatives implemented over the past several months across our territories and the solid performance of our sparkling and still beverage portfolio.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, our consolidated revenues were more than Ps. 30 billion, up 18% from the third quarter of 2010. On a currency-neutral basis, our consolidated total revenues grew 16% for the quarter, driven by average price per unit case growth in most of our operations and volume growth mainly in Mexico, Colombia and Argentina.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated sales volume increased close to 5%, mainly due to the strong performance of our sparkling beverage category, supported by brand Coca-Cola in Mexico and Colombia as well as double-digit volume growth in the still beverage category, driven mainly by the Jugos del Valle line of business in Mexico and Brazil and the Cepita juice brand in Argentina.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated gross profit increased 16% to Ps. 14 billion in the third quarter of 2011. Higher PET and sweetener cost across our territories were partially offset by the average &#x2013; appreciation of our main operations local currencies as applied to our U.S. dollar denominated raw material costs. As a result, our consolidated gross margin declined 90 basis points to 46.3% as compared with third quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated operating income grew 10% to Ps. 4.7 billion in the third quarter, supported by the strong operating income growth recorded in each of our divisions. Gross margin pressures, combined with higher labor costs in Venezuela and increased labor and freight cost in Argentina, led to a decline in our operating margin of 110 basis points to, 15.4%. On a currency-neutral basis, our consolidated operating income grew more than 8%.</p>
          <p>Our consolidated EBITDA increased 12% to Ps. 5.9 billion, as compared with the third quarter of last year. Our consolidated net controlling interest income grew more than 7% to Ps. 2.3 billion in the third quarter, reflecting increased operating income that was partially compensated by a higher tax rate, mainly generated by an increase in the tax on shareholder's equity in one of our subsidiaries in the South America division.</p>
          <p>Now let me expand on the performance of our operations. As a point of reference, in August 2011, we announced changes in our business structure. Starting from this third quarter 2011, our Central American operations will now be reported together with our Mexican operations in the new reporting segment that will integrate the Mexico and Central America division.</p>
          <p>Our Colombian and Venezuelan operations will be reported together with our Brazilian and Argentinean operations in the new reporting segment that will integrate the South America division. During this conference call, we will be making reference to these reporting segments.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, our Mexico and Central America division recorded more than 5% volume growth, selling close to 370 million unit cases of beverages. Volumes in our Mexican operations grew 5%, this growth was driven mainly by the sparkling beverage category, which grew 6%, supported by brand Coca-Cola in multiserve presentations and by the still beverage category, which grew more than 8%, due to strong performance of the Jugos del Valle line of products, along with Nestea and PowerAde.</p>
          <p>During the quarter, our water portfolio volumes increased 2%, driven mainly by water in single serve presentations, which grew 8%. In our Central American region, we achieved 10% volume growth during the third quarter. This increase was mainly driven by brand Coca-Cola, which grew 12%, combined with high single digit volume growth in the still beverage category, supported by our recently incorporated portfolio Estrella Azul brand, products and the performance of the Jugos del Valle line of business.</p>
          <p>Our average price per unit case in our Mexican and Central America division rose close to 5% in the third quarter. This increase resulted from selective price increases implemented over the past 12 months, mainly in our Mexican operations. As a result, our division's total revenue grew more than 10%, to almost Ps. 13 billion.</p>
          <p>With regard to our profitability, the impact of increased PET and sweetener cost across the division was partially offset by the appreciation of the average exchange rate of the Mexican pesos as applied to our U.S. dollar denominated product material costs. Compared with the third quarter of 2010, our gross profit increased close to 8% to Ps. 6 billion. And our gross margin declined 120 basis points to 47.7%.</p>
          <p>Our operating income increased close to 8% to Ps. 2 billion. Operating leverage achieved through higher revenues combined with controlled operating expenses in Mexico, partially compensated for gross margin pressures across the division. As a result, our operating margin decreased 30 basis points to 16.3%. Our EBITDA grew more than 7% to Ps. 2.6 billion compared with the third quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>In summary, our Mexico and Central America division delivered positive results for the quarter advancing on many fronts. The brand equity of Coca-Cola and its wide preference across our territories allow us to continue with the implementation of our strategy of selective price increases targeted to mitigate the increased cost of raw materials.</p>
          <p>Our initiatives to foster the availability of sparkling beverages in returnable presentations, combined with our continued efforts to provide our consumers with new packaging alternatives such as 400 and 200 milliliter single-serve non-returnable presentations for brand Coca-Cola in Mexico. And our affordable 12 ounce presentation for brand Coca-Cola in Central America, are truly successful.</p>
          <p>These presentations are significantly increasing our number of single-serve transactions contributing to our price mix. With regard to our still beverage portfolio, we continue to incorporate new beverage alternatives for our consumers. As exemplified by our recent integration Estrella Azul brand portfolio in our Panamanian operations through the joint venture that we have with <mark type="ph" /> those brand for (09:38) Coca-Cola Company.</p>
          <p>Together, we've recently re-launched this important brand and presented the consumer with a new image.</p>
          <p>Beginning last August, our operators started to distribute shelf-stable milk and juice products in our reference. Leveraging our distribution fleet and reaching more consumers through these high quality products. As you may know, this month, we announced the successful completion of our merger with Grupo Tampico's beverage division. We are pleased to have closed the transaction in such a short period of time. And we'll integrate this franchise result into our Mexican operations as the product of this year.</p>
          <p>Regarding, our merger with Grupo CIMSA, we continue to advance in this process and when we receive all the necessary corporate and government approvals, we will state to successfully close this transaction as of the first quarter of 2012.</p>
          <p>With regard to our profitability, we have seen additional increases in both sugar and resin costs. These increases affected the profitability of our Mexico and Central America divisions and produced gross margin pressures, particularly in the month of September. However, we have continued our efforts to control our rate in expenses, allowing us to partially compensate for these pressures.</p>
          <p>As we entered the final quarter of the year, we see increased global economic volatility from abroad. Nevertheless we are convinced that our operators will find revenue management strategies and cost disciplines will continue to mitigate raw material cost pressures.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn our attention to our new South American division. Our South American division's total sales volume grew close to 4% in the third quarter, reaching almost 280 million unit cases, this increase was driven mainly by the strong volume growth we achieved in Argentina and Colombia. In Colombia, our volume increased 9% due mainly to the solid performance of our sparkling beverages category supported by the 17% growth of brand Coca-Cola. This growth more than compensated for volume declines in our water and still beverage portfolios.</p>
          <p>Moving to Venezuela, our volume declined 3%, high single-digit volume growth in our flavored sparkling beverage portfolio and the still beverage category was outpaced by declines in the rest of the various categories.</p>
          <p>On a sequential basis, we have gradually improved our volumes in Venezuela recovering from a difficult start of the year. Our operators continue to evaluate implementation of different portfolio strategies for our consumers, such as introducing affordable one way PET package, expanding our single-serve returnable presentation availability and introducing new still beverage offerings in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>In Brazil, our volume grew more than 1%, successfully building on our very strong third quarter of last year, in which we posted 13% volume growth. Our sparkling beverage categories grew 1% mainly driven by our Schweppes and Fanta brand, our still beverage category supported by the Jugos del Valle line of business and the Matte Leao <mark type="ph" /> product line (13:26) grew close to 20%, these increases compensated for our volume decline in our water portfolio.</p>
          <p>In our Argentina franchise territories, we recorded strong volume growth across every category, leveraging solid consumer momentum. The sparkling beverage category grew 10% driven by the 8% volume growth of brand Coca-Cola and 16% volume growth in our flavored sparkling beverage category, mainly supported by the Crush and Schweppes brands.</p>
          <p>The still beverage category continued strong momentum posting considerable growth due mainly to the performance of the Cepita juice brand, the successful introduction of our Hi-C orangeade and Hugo our new juice product. Our water portfolio also grew significantly driven by the Aquarius flavored water product line.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter of 2011, our South America division total revenue grew 25% to Ps. 18 million. As our result of double-digit very good growth in every territory. Excluding beer which accounted for Ps. 942, our total revenues reached Ps. 17 billion. Selective price increases implement over the past several months across the revision of volume growth from Argentina, Colombia accounted for the majority of incremental rates.</p>
          <p>With regard to our profitability our South America division gross profit increase 23% to Ps. 8 billion. Higher sweetener and PET cost across the division were partially offset by the appreciation of the average exchange rate of our main operations, local currencies are supplied to our U.S. dollar denominated raw material costs. As a result, gross margin declined 70 basis points to 45.2% for the third quarter of 2010.</p>
          <p>Our operating income grew 12% to Ps. 2.6 billion, operating leverage achieved through higher revenues was affected by higher labor cost in Venezuela and higher labor and freight cost in Argentina, consequently, our operating margin declined 170 basis points to 14.8% in the third quarter. Our South America division's EBITDA increased 17% to Ps. 3.3 billion in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>In summary, our South America division delivered strong results in the third quarter of 2011, leveraging the continued preference for brand Coca-Cola throughout our growing returnable base and the increased scale of our still beverage category. We're able to provide our consumers with more alternatives to satisfy different consumption occasions.</p>
          <p>Our strategy of introducing new beverages in the marketplace over the past several months, in our still beverage category offer induces tea, coffee and dairy related growth is proving successful. We are confident that the multi-category portfolio's high quality products we have developed is not only a competitive advantage, but also an attractive proposition for our customers and consumers.</p>
          <p>Now let me walk you through our financial performances for the quarter. This quarter, our geographically balanced portfolio franchise territories delivered increase cash flow generation. The revenue management initiatives implemented across our territories and the strong volume performances on Mexico &amp; Central America division as well as our Colombian and Argentine operations were the main drivers of our cash flow generation. As of September 30, 2011, we had a cash balance of Ps. 18.7 billion and our total debt was Ps. 22.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Our net debt to EBITDA leverage ratio was below 0.2 times and our EBITDA to net interest coverage ratio was close to 20 times, highlighting our financial flexibility and the strength of our balance sheet. The cash position and the strong cash flow generation our company has delivered in past several years provide us with the necessary flexibility to continue growing our business more organically and through mergers and acquisitions in the beverage things. We will continue to invest in the production, capacity required to meet the growth we ambition through our territories and to foster innovation across our various categories.</p>
          <p>In conclusion, our operation generated strong results for the quarter. Our operator's execution of strategies decides to foster our portfolio volume growth, coupled with the implementation of refined quality management strategies across our territories are enabling us to gain important operating leverage to compensate for the increased cost of raw materials and protect our year-to-date profitability.</p>
          <p>We enter the final quarter of the year. We'll continue to adapt our business to the changing economic conditions and implement the necessary initiatives to sustain our profitability. We are confident that the resilience of our industry, the strong brand equity of our multi-category of portfolio beverages, the innovation capabilities of our talented team of professionals, and the relentless pursuit by our operators of the right execution of the point of sales are key factors to continue growing our business and delivering increased value for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Now <mark type="ph" /> I think to conclude (19:42). Thank you for your continued trust and support. And now, I would like to open the call for any questions that you may have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from the line of Lauren Torres [HSBC Securities]. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, H&#xE9;ctor. My question relates to the cost pressures, obviously, that we saw in the third quarter and your expectations for cost whether it would be commodity costs or expenses as it relates to your operating expense line. Looking into next year we saw some notable margin contraction in the quarter. Just curious how you think that's going to play out over the next several quarters. Similar pressures as what we saw this quarter, and if so what are the offsets? Is there more pricing ability in your part or is it more of just OpEx control that you mentioned?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Lauren. In terms of the commodity pressures, we continue to see pressure on the sweetener side. We see both corn and sugar prices in the local marketplace. Remember that some of the areas that &#x2013; not necessarily for international prices or to &#x2013; because of different types of different situations in the marketplace. But in general, sweeteners, we continue to see pressure and we'll see for next year prices a little bit higher than what we have up to this moment.</p>
          <p>Just to give you an idea on a consolidated basis, for the all Coca-Cola FEMSA, the strength that we have from sweeteners and PET for this quarter was close to Ps. 700 million, just additional costs that we have compared to the previous year. Part of that we'll try to do with very good prices that we have in Brazil last year because the year before, we were successful in implementing some hedges that were grown up at very good prices or the prices continued to &#x2013; before the prices started to go up. But in general that number is around $50 million of less profitability than we have this quarter &#x2013; just during this quarter.</p>
          <p>So, our anticipation for next year is that we will continue to see some pressure in sweeteners. In PET, we're starting to see some reductions, basically in the last two weeks. So PET, we have a little more optimistic scenario going forward, but again, the volatility in these markets have been all very kind. In terms of saving that obviously, as you see from this report, we have seen &#x2013; you can see that we have been to able to increases prices importantly, basically in every market, and everyone on the conference to compensate for that. And we are seeing that our competitors are also increasing prices, because they are feeling the same pressures that we have, so that's the positive side of that front.</p>
          <p>In the OpEx line, we continue to work and say that we have been a bit more successful in Mexico and Central America. We still need to work a little further and our operators in South America have, as one of the priorities, to really try to structure those operating expenses in a different way and start extracting some efficiencies.</p>
          <p>In South America, what has happened, which is difficult to control by our operators, is that salary increases in Argentina and Venezuela have been very large, in excess of inflation. And because of the very high level of employment that we have in Brazil, we are suffering also some pressure there, as not only having to pay more for our workers and employees in terms of salaries, but also re-training them, because they leave for other industries or other companies, because the market is very good for workers. So in those three countries, Argentina, Venezuela mainly as a way of the general increases on salaries, and in Brazil, because of the low unemployment and the economic activity that you see there, we are suffering a little bit from that effect. So with those comments, I'll give you a very good picture of what we're seeing in terms of raw materials and <mark type="ph" /> demographics (25:36) and my believe is that we will be able to continue to increase prices to compensate back to those effects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. And just as a follow-up, I'm not sure if you're prepared to comment on margins, because with the pressures that we've seen over the next couple quarters, you think you could basically stabilize them, or should we see improvements, or a similar decline to what we saw this quarter over the near-term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, in general, we say that Mexico &amp; Central Americas, I feel more confident that we'll have stable margins and I'm a bit concerned on South America because of the reasons that I mentioned, with the salary pressures in those countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Alan Alanis from JPMorgan. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much. Hi, H&#xE9;ctor. I want to follow-up a little bit on this &#x2013; on the comment of the pervious question. I mean this area of the operating expenses, I mean I appreciate that you mentioned now Brazil. Besides labor, anything else that it's explaining this 28%, 29% in operating expenses above the 24% growth of revenues of the region? H&#xE9;ctor that would be the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean, besides salaries, we have seen a little more activity in the marketing expenses, especially in Colombia, Brazil and Venezuela. And in Mexico, we're doing an additional campaign in terms of marketing expenses. And you know that that line will include full replacement in anticipation of a unified Pepsi bottler in Mexico, so there is a whole campaign in Mexico of trying to capture additional points of sales, getting good positions in the stores and everything. So you will see some increases in the marketing expenses line during this quarter and the next two or three quarters. And other than that, I'll say the other expense that is a little bit out of line is freight in Argentina.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But sounds like most of them are recurrent. I mean, there is just new levels that you'll be having and, as you said, you'll have to offset via pricing, correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think that my expectation, some of them are more recurrent. I think that the marketing expenses that I'm commenting is a more discretionary expense. We don't see the pricing. We can talk on that. We don't see the profit or the results that we anticipate from that. You can start reusing those expenses. Really, that's a dialogue that we have to have with the product of the company, and we know that dialogue's sometimes difficult, but you have seen, because of the performance that we have the part, that's a memory but a variable that we can adjust. So the marketing expenses I feel very comfortable that we are convinced that it's important that we increase a little bit those expenses, especially for the beginning of next year, but it's totally discretionary balance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Salaries, sometimes we, the expenses, raw materials, but that's a different story.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Now below the operating line, you have a Ps. 287 million gain from derivatives instrument. Is this a COGS hedge in sugar or &#x2013; and how do you see these hedges and these derivative instruments going forward, H&#xE9;ctor?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I don't know, you are referring to the tables reconcile. I think that the Ps. 287 million that you mentioned is a loss that we have that is related to the part. We changed some of the &#x2013; we were able to issue Peso denominated debt and we swapped that into dollars, because it was a cheaper way of financing. We wanted to have dollar debt, but it was cheaper to issue the bonds in peso because of the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (30:44) of the market that we have here. So at the end of the day, we got a lower dollar rate that we won't have had if we had issue directly bond in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And because of, in the balance sheet, you do have the end of the period exchange rate and this query is a little bit tricky, because during the quarter, the currencies, as you know ,were depreciating importantly so that basically happened during September. So this quarter, we have the benefit on top of some raw materials that we were paying with a lower exchange rate than last year. So at the end of the year, the exchange rate is, most of the currencies depreciated substantially. That's a law that we have on converting those peso bonds into dollars <mark type="ph" /> index, (31:37) which is totally, as you know, is plain vanilla hedges, nothing exotic, it's just moving from pesos into dollars.</p>
          <p>We also have some dollar denominated cash balances that produce a better and that's why you have a foreign exchange gain which is almost the same size of that loss, because we have dollar cash balances that compensates part of that exposure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it. That's very useful. Thanks so much, H&#xE9;ctor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Lore Serra from Morgan Stanley. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I just wanted to ask a couple of follow-ups to what's been asked. On the COGS side, I'm just wondering a bit more if you could talk about where you see the pressure? Because it seems like sugar's leveling out and maybe could fall, and you say PET is going to fall. So could you just give us a sense of what you guys are seeing, to see the continued pressure?</p>
          <p>And then in terms of the OpEx, I understand the markets are very different, but it took you a long time to get sort of the Mexico operating expenses under control and it looks like you've now done it for this year, which is great. If you kind of kind of compare and contrast the markets, and obviously there are some differences in terms of the labor markets, et cetera, but on the structural basis, are there things that you've done well in Mexico that you can do more rapidly in other markets to control the inflation that you're seeing in the different markets? Thanks, H&#xE9;ctor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Lore. Yes I think that, in general, let me start with the first question, the first part of the question is raw materials. Sweeteners, we basically have gone to, for example, for Mexico, agreed with our suppliers on basically some of the prices for next year. And those prices are, in average, a little bit higher than what we have this year. It's not much, I'd say around 5%, 6% on average of what we have this year, and that's why we're basically saying &#x2013; in the first question from Lauren I was saying that, in sweeteners, we're anticipating a little bit higher prices in general.</p>
          <p>We are seeing, as I mentioned, some reductions in PET...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am sorry, what about HFCS, because you use a lot of HFCS in Mexico, will that be under pressure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, no, that basically what I was referring to &#x2013; the agreement with some of the suppliers just have to do with HFCS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In cane sugar, we don't have any agreement yet, because that's more a complex environment and it's impossible to hedges with that. And the suppliers, so far we haven't found a supplier that is willing to agree on a price for two or three quarters in advance. It's more kind of a spot market. So in HFCS, I'll say there 50% to 70%, it's closer to 70% of our need for next year, already we have a <mark type="ph" /> slighter effect (35:05) and as I mentioned, slightly above what we had last year. And with respect to the OpEx, I think that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry and PET, what's your view on how much PET will go down this year, or next year rather?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That I don't have any idea. We just started to see some reductions, in that our budget calls for flattish PET prices for next year. We might have some positive moves because of the reductions that we have seen in that in these two weeks. But our anticipation is flat PET prices for next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to OpEx, I think that <mark type="indiscernible" /> (36:04) in Venezuela and Argentina had to do with salaries. I think that there are very good opportunities in Brazil. John Santa Maria as you know is now in charge of that area. John will <mark type="indiscernible" /> (36:24) to start looking at some of the process. We are working a lot in the basics, the basics of the business. For example, some of the problem that goes <mark type="indiscernible" /> (36:44) we can improve. So it's always good to have a new set of eyes to look at this area.</p>
          <p>How fast can we change that? It is difficult to predict, but obviously as I mentioned the attention and the bonuses of the executives are linked to improving this OpEx line and the right incentives are there to start improving. We feel confident that what we have done in Mexico we can replicate in some of the other areas, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (37:34) is a little tricky but there are as I mentioned incentives are there to start.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Lore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And the next question comes from the line of Celso S&#xE1;nchez from Citi. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi, good morning, H&#xE9;ctor. A very simple question actually. The concentrate terms that you have as I recall have a fairly lengthy standstill in terms of what until the next increase would happen. I'm taking something between five and ten years from when it was enacted. So my question would be you obviously have made a couple of acquisitions, it seems like there could be more in Mexico specifically. Do the terms that you have and terms of the standstill, do those apply to all other bottlers as well or they don't as you potentially merge with or acquire other bottlers? What's the mechanism through which the terms that you have can be applied to those territories? Is that another negotiation or is that kind of accounted for in your standstill that you had dealt with The Coca-Cola Company?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The same question. This standstill that you refer it basically covers all of Mexico. In the rest of the countries, there is no specific agreement on concentrate. We always try to work with Coca-Cola Company and the idea of growing the size of the pie rather than trying to split that by differently. But the only guarantee that we have is that in Mexico we still have few more years of this standstill. So the two acquisitions that we have done in Mexico are covered by that. We have the same terms with respect to the standstill. So in that respect its easier do the valuation of this operation, because you can anticipate the cost of concentrate also. It's easy to evaluation to that respect, with respect to the concentrate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just a follow-up to that, in the countries where you operate and more than one bottler operates or another bottler at least besides you operates, is it fair to assume that in every country the concentrate for those apply to the whole country? In other words, the concentrate pricing formulae is the same for all bottlers in a given country or can that differ in some countries amongst different bottlers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To best of our knowledge it's the same in every country. For example in Brazil, the 16 bottlers will have the same formulae and in Mexico every bottler has the same formulae. To the best of our understanding, we don't know if The Coca-Cola Company has very specific special agreement with some bottler, but we believe it's the same treatment for every bottler within a country.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Antonio Gonzalez from Credit Suisse. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, thanks for taking my question. Hello, H&#xE9;ctor. I wanted to ask first on Brazil, could you give us an update on the competitive environment, particularly within CSDs. Are you seeing, in other words hearing your main competitor some aggressive promotions particularly at the <mark type="ph" /> modern trade? (41:44) And I was hoping you could comment maybe on how do you feel your portfolio has evolved over the last 24 months or so? Of course you've talked a lot about SKU diversification in introduction of returnables lately and I was hoping to hear your comments on how do you feel you're prepared potentially for a longer period of more aggressive price competition in Brazil? And whether you can comment on if your market share in CSDs and particularly in colas is stable up until now with this price aggressiveness?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Antonio. In general, I'll say that we have seen in most of our markets we have seen brand Coca-Cola behaving very, very well. We have a very, very slight erosion in Brazil but it's less than 0.1%. It's very, very small but in general in some of the number, brand Coca-Cola moved, very important during this quarter.</p>
          <p>My general sense of &#x2013; what I can share with you in terms of the competition is that we have very good segmentation of our portfolio. I think that we excel at doing that. Whenever we have a very aggressive competitor we have returnable presentations that are closer to those prices. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (43:28) consumers we have these very small presentations like the 200 milliliters that we're selling in Mexico at Ps. 3 which is, as I said very good price for a product like that. So we are seeing <mark type="indiscernible" /> (43:48) now from adults using that presentation as an indulgence. It's only 200 milliliters and they no longer &#x2013; they doesn't care about the calorie intake and they take that.</p>
          <p>So in general, I'll say that we have very good market spreads where we see a bit more competition is in the Colombian market with Postob&#xF3;n that sometimes, let's say they can be more aggressively on prices. But as you saw, we reported brand Coca-Cola in Colombia grew very well. Obviously it's significant because last year we were suffering a bit. But we were gaining share importantly in Colombia. In flavors in Colombia, we were losing a little bit of share. Remember that Postob&#xF3;n is the leader there in flavor.</p>
          <p>So in general I'd say that with cost pressure in raw materials that we have, most of our competitors are following &#x2013; are <mark type="indiscernible" /> (45:00) increasing prices. So I don't see a lot of pressure on that front. Let's see what Pepsi is going to in Mexico now that they're integrating all the bottlers in the whole country <mark type="indiscernible" /> (45:17). So far we don't have a reason to believe that there would be <mark type="indiscernible" /> (45:23). They have paid for some accounts, ready-to-serve package <mark type="indiscernible" /> (45:29) Mexico. It was an account that Coca-Cola had for many years now it's a Pepsi operation. They paid high amount of money for that. And you can argue that maybe they will gain some accounts, well that's not going to change the market dynamics much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, H&#xE9;ctor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from the line of Lore Serra from Morgan Stanley. Please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the follow up. H&#xE9;ctor, I just wondered there is a lot of noise in the market about M&amp;A and I just want to make sure that or just to confirm your views. Obviously you've talked in the beginning about the fact that you still have a lot of room on the balance sheet side even with the two acquisitions you're making in Mexico and you remain committed to more sort of bolt-on acquisitions like that, some of these properties moving is creating more interest on others. But obviously there is a lot of competition for those properties. So I wonder if you could just put in perspective kind of the priority and maybe the possibility of deals on the smaller side like what you've done with CIMSA and Tampico versus the sort of large deals that might be more global in nature. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Lore. Well, that's a tough question because obviously it's difficult to predict, what would be next in terms of M&amp;A activity. I think that in general, we have commented that areas of potential interest in the future is North America market. But I truly believe that's going to take two or three years before The Coca-Cola Company wants something there and at some point in time, we need to value if that's interesting or not for us.</p>
          <p>We have in the meantime, more of this, medium size or a smaller bottler in Mexico, Brazil that we would like to do something similar to what we have <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:05) beginning of the year. We certainly are very much interested in doing something like that.</p>
          <p>So if you ask me, in terms of providing this, I think that it's, when the Arca Contal transaction was announced I expressed that that will create the environment where we want to review their own situation. I think that for every bottler in Mexico to review their priorities and where they are standing and everything. I think that that's still <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:45), I think there will be I see possibilities in that front, sooner rather than larger transactions on a global basis like something like in North America or something like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Or rather global transactions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Or global transactions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But there's very little <mark type="indiscernible" /> (49:09) also willing to do the transaction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I will now turn the call over to Mr. H&#xE9;ctor Trevi&#xF1;o, FEMSA's CFO for closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you for your interest in our company and as always Jose and his team will be available to answer any remaining questions <mark type="indiscernible" /> (49:37). Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, that concludes today's presentation. Thank you for your participation. You may now disconnect. Have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>