<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1371632" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-03-10</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9099</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Wolfgang Reitzle, Chairman-Executive Board</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Georg Denoke, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Norbert Barth</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Neil Tyler</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Markus Mayer</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Jean de Watteville</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Peter Clark</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Evgenia Molotova</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Nadeshda Demidova</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Stephan Kippe</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Stephen Kippe</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Laurent Favre</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="corprep">Jerry Kent Masters</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, ladies and gentlemen. From me a warm welcome to those who have dialed in to our full-year results conference call 2010.</p>
          <p>Actually, 2010 has been a very successful year for the Linde group. Overall operational results were strong, and we further strengthened our strategic setup.</p>
          <p>Now I would like to take you through the following agenda points, as marked on Page 3 on the presentation. I hope you have that in front of you. I will start with some highlights of our 2010 figures, and will then move over to the strategic focus.</p>
          <p>Here I will give you a short overview on the impact of our HPO initiative, and the growth potentials for our company. Before I hand over then to Georg Denoke for his specific financial topics, I will present our outlook for 2011, as well as our mid-term guidance for 2014.</p>
          <p>Now please turn to Slide 4. Our group sales increased by 14.8% to &#x20AC;12.9 billion, while the operating profit with a class of 22.6% to &#x20AC;2.925 billion proves an above-average increase. The group operating margin further improved by 140 basis points to 22.7% and the Gases operating margin increased to 27%.</p>
          <p>The earnings per share adjusted by the allocation of the purchase price of BOC increased by 50.4% to &#x20AC;6.89, and by this reached a new record level. Also the adjusted ROCE grew by 210 basis points to 12.5%.</p>
          <p>Driven by stringent working capital management, the operating cash flow, again, improved by 13.1% to &#x20AC;2.422 billion. This allowed us to reduce net debt by &#x20AC;622 million to &#x20AC;5.5 billion. Later, Georg Denoke will give you more details on the use of cash flow.</p>
          <p>The impact of the normalization of the global economic environment and the success of our HPO initiatives is already visible in our 2010 results. Major drivers have been the strong momentum of the Chinese market, in particular, and the growth markets in general, as well as the normalization in the mature regions, such as Western Europe and the U.S.</p>
          <p>Let me start with a breakdown of the group sales on Page 5. Gases sales increased by 14.8% to &#x20AC;10.2 billion or 5% on a comparable basis. The comparable figure represents the price and volume effect, excluding not only currency and natural gas price effects, but also changes in consolidation.</p>
          <p>A normalization of the demand was visible in all product areas where as the recovery in the cylinder business gained more momentum, especially in the fourth quarter of last year. Sales in the Engineering division were as expected, above the level of 2009. As a result of the global recession, the portion of small and mid-size projects has significantly increased in 2010. The execution of the order backlog of around &#x20AC;4 billion is fully on track.</p>
          <p>As you will see in a minute, our profitability has not been affected by the change in the size of these orders.</p>
          <p>Looking at the operating profit development on Page 6, you see that the positive development of the group's operating margin was driven by a strong performance in both divisions. The operating profit in Gases increased by 16.3% to &#x20AC;2.76 billion, and was above the level of the record year 2008.</p>
          <p>The margin increase continued. With additional 40 basis points the margin increased now to 27%. Due to the successful project execution, the operating margin in the Engineering division remained 11%, well ahead of our target range of 8%.</p>
          <p>Now let's talk about key numbers of our Gas and Engineering results, beginning with a product area split of the Gases division on Page 7. Despite the global recession, our Health Care business grew in 2009 and continued this trend in 2010 with a further increase of sales by 4.2%. This shows that underlying mega-trend is intact. Later, I will come back to the mega-trends in general.</p>
          <p>In the year 2009, the take-or-pay contracts of our tonnage business have proven to be resilient to the crisis, with 9.6% we achieved in 2010 and almost double digit growth on comparable basis. This performance is, of course, supported by a continuous contribution from new start-ups and ramp-ups. The opportunities in this area have increased in particular in the growth markets.</p>
          <p>Also, our merchant business developed quite well in 2010 with a solid growth of 6.6% in the bulk business and 3.4% in the cylinder business. The cylinder business, with its small scale customers, is usually the last segment to recover. As expected, the business growth in this segment gained speed, in particularly in the fourth quarter 2010. A continuation of this trend will further optimize the loading of our plants.</p>
          <p>Let me now talk about the order situation in our Engineering division on page eight. The order intake, as you can see, of &#x20AC;2.149 billion, is below the level of the previous year. It is to be mentioned that 2009 was dominated by one large scale project in Abu Dhabi with an order value of around $1 billion. As already mentioned, the order intake for small and medium sized plants has increased and order intake of &#x20AC;622 million only in the first quarter shows that the Engineering business further normalizes. Our order backlog remains strong with around &#x20AC;4 billion of orders still to be executed. We have a solid basis for excellent project execution and support for our Gases division.</p>
          <p>I'm now turning to slide nine, with a quick glance at the summary of the progress of our HPO initiatives. As a quick reminder, I shall mention that HPO is a holistic program covering the full value chain of our business across all regions. You know that we accelerated this program in 2009 due to the exceptional economic environment and achieved &#x20AC;300 million gross cost savings. In 2010, additional &#x20AC;160 million gross cost savings have been achieved. Going forward, we confirm our target range of &#x20AC;650 million to &#x20AC;800 million of accumulated gross cost savings in 2012.</p>
          <p>Please do not forget that HPO is not a cost mitigation program that we implemented due to the crisis. HPO is addressing the execution of daily work of every single employee. We are targeting best practices or processes throughout our global organization.</p>
          <p>As already announced in this morning's press release, the supervisory board of the Linde Group has appointed Mr. Sanjiv Lamba as a new member of our Executive Board. From now on, Mr. Lamba will be responsible for our business in the dynamic growth markets of greater China, South and East Asia and the South Pacific region. He will also be assuming responsibility for our Asian joint ventures and for the electronic gases product segments. By the way, he will be based in Singapore.</p>
          <p>We are also focusing on two other global mega-trends. I will go into more detail about all of these later. The first is energy and the environment, while the second is the growth market of health, a market served, as you know, by our Health Care business. So then we can derive long term benefit from the potential offered by these promising sectors, we have made other changes at the most senior management level. Each of these mega-trends has been allocated to one of the executive board members responsible for operations and we have bundled together the skills of each member and reallocated the regional responsibilities as follows.</p>
          <p>Mr. Masters is responsible for our worldwide Health Care business and will also continue to promote our activities in North and South America. In addition, he looks after our liquefied gases and cylinder gas business and actually he will be based in Murray Hill in the United States.</p>
          <p>Mr. Belloni has assumed responsibility for Clean Energy, the development of energy and environmental technologies. And at a regional level, he is in-charge of our business in the EMEA economic area. That is in Western and Eastern Europe, the Middle East and Africa. He also manages our global on site business and since many years, our Engineering division. He will be based in Munich.</p>
          <p>The creation of a new executive board portfolio and the appointment of Mr. Lamba demonstrate our awareness of the great importance of the growth markets in Asia to our group. This is where we perceive the greatest opportunities in the coming years. Therefore, I will dive a bit deeper into the mega-trend growth markets now.</p>
          <p>On slide 11, you can see our general business approach in the new growth markets where we usually enter as early mover to build up our customer portfolio. By leveraging the synergies between our Engineering and our Gases division in respect to engineering capabilities and in respect to our long term customer relations, the Linde Group can further differentiate from pure price selling towards a more solution driven client partnership. The buildup of the geographical infrastructure and the know-how about application technologies are further steps to develop growth markets.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, you will see our position in the main growth markets. We have a strong position in growth markets from the combined BOC and Linde gas set-ups and as you see, we have further leveraged these leading market position through a significant CapEx spend. Out of the total Gases investment of almost &#x20AC;5 billion over the last four years, roughly half has been spent in growth countries. As a result, the share of sales in growth markets of total Gases revenues has continuously increased to now one-third in 2010.</p>
          <p>On the next slide &#x2013; slide 13, you can see the expected growth potential. Here you can see an extra correlation of the additional industrial gases volumes for the year 2020, compared to 2010. We expect a high underlying growth in the growth markets and in particular in Asia. And this structural growth is expected to be based on above average GDP growth, a trend to further outsource and an increase of the gases intensity, driven by applications.</p>
          <p>In a local market structure, like in the gases industry, the current market position is of relevance in order to benefit from the respective growth potential of that market.</p>
          <p>Now on slide 14. As already outlined earlier, a strong market share in a growth market is an important competitive factor in the expansion of the business. This is the first reason to outline that in four out of five growth markets, the Linde Group has a leading market position.</p>
          <p>The second reason is to show this leading gases setup in comparison to our long-term customer relations in these regions, resulting from the activities of our Engineering division. To give you a quick glance only at the last decade, we have picked out the market with the highest growth potential, Asia, which you can see now on slide 15. In the Gases division, Middle East and Asian market is covered by three regional business units. Here you can see that we have sold more than 160 air separation units, hydrogen and synthesis gas plants to external customers in the last decade through our Engineering Division.</p>
          <p>As you might be aware of our more than 130 years' engineering history and the technology portfolio of our Engineering division, which also includes natural gas plants and olefin plants it becomes obvious that we have developed strong long-term customer relations. An example for this successful utilization of these synergies is our regional business unit Greater China, as you can see now from the next slide. Based on our engineering footprint, we entered the Chinese market as first international gases company already in the 1980s. Today, we have over 4,000 employees and around 50 wholly-owned companies and joint ventures.</p>
          <p>We operate more than 150 plants, cover five important industrial clusters and have introduced industry-leading operations standards. Our resulting financial track record in China is very positive with growth in consolidated sales of 37%, now to &#x20AC;576 million.</p>
          <p>On slide 17, you can see that we serve leading customers in the pillar industries, oil and petrochemicals, chemicals, metallurgy, electronics and others, such as, for example, the food industry. Also based on these partnerships, we assume to be well positioned for the growth potential in Greater China.</p>
          <p>Please now move to slide 18, our complementary Engineering and Gases setup also offers attractive synergies in the energy and environmental mega-trend, from a customer as well as from a technological perspective. The energy and environmental mega-trend includes a broad range of technologies and applications, such as clean coal technologies or the better use of fossil resources. And example for the later is our joint venture with Adnoc in Abu Dhabi, which has a joint CapEx volume of US$800 million and is expected to go on stream this year. Actually, this is a nitrogen scheme for enhanced gas recovery.</p>
          <p>With significant existing growth markets, in particular, in enhanced oil and gas recovery and in LNG, this mega-trend energy and environment can be considered as an important growth driver today, and in particular, we think, on a mid and long-term scale. Estimates of the annual market revenues in these segments in 2030 are up to &#x20AC;140 billion. On Slide 19, you will find some project examples.</p>
          <p>A further example for the existing growth markets is merchant LNG. We are currently building an LNG terminal on the Swedish east coast, where no natural gas pipeline grid is available. LNG will replace LPG, light and heavy fuel oil and therefore, contribute to an emission reduction. We received the LNG from Linde engineering customer in Norway. For the mid-term growth market, the award winning biofuel plant for producing LNG from Linde fuel gases shall be named as an example. The LNG produced by the plant is used to fuel 300 refuse trucks of waste management.</p>
          <p>This bio-to-liquid technology reduces the carbon emissions by 97% compared to diesel. CO2 handling is rather a future growth market, although there are already successful projects such as the supply of CO2 to greenhouses in the Netherlands. Through a network of pipelines and distribution lines, we provide with our joint venture partner CO2 from a Shell refinery to more than 500 greenhouses, which require CO2 for their photosynthesis.</p>
          <p>This recycling approach replaces the combustion of natural gas and therefore, reduces the CO2 emission. These examples shall give you some feeling on our good positioning in this developing market segment.</p>
          <p>Now our next slide, the health care mega-trend has provided continuous sales growth through and after the crisis. For the Linde Group, as the second largest medical gas supplier, there are clear opportunities for further growth. The market environment is characterized by a structurally growing end market for our Gases business, due to an increasing and aging population, as well as increasing wealth in the growth markets.</p>
          <p>There are clear opportunities, for example, due to an increased use of medical gases and the trend to outsource gas services. On the next slide, you will find the extrapolated growth potential. As already shown earlier for the industrial gases market, you can see on the top left corner, the additional medical gases market in 2020, compared to 2010.</p>
          <p>The main portion of the growth potential of around &#x20AC;5 billion is in the mature markets, but also around 20% of the potential is already in the growth markets. Therefore, we aim for a further expansion of our business activities, in particular in the area of care concepts, home care and gas therapies. At the same time, we want to increase our geographical coverage into the growth economies.</p>
          <p>With the overview on the mega-trends, their respective growth potentials and the positioning of the Linde group, I hope you've gained an impression of our growth potential. What we can be sure of is that with our extensive and diversified range of technologies and our gases and engineering operations we are well &#x2013; I mean, very well equipped to seize the upcoming growth opportunities.</p>
          <p>Now let me finish with our outlook on page 22, which is based on the current economic projections. On group level, we expect in 2011 further growth of sales and operating profit. Furthermore, we reconfirm the target range of &#x20AC;650 million to &#x20AC;800 million gross cost savings of our HPO initiatives in the years 2009 to 2012.</p>
          <p>In the Gases Division, we expect an increase in sales. This growth will be driven by continuous ramp ups out of our tonnage product line as well as ongoing structural growth in health care. Moreover, we assume a further recovery in the merchant product areas of Linde, which is a, as I already mentioned, late cyclical business segment. We aim to achieve an over proportionate operating profit increase.</p>
          <p>In the Engineering Division, we expect 2011 sales to reach at least the 2010 level. Our order intake in Q4 clearly confirmed that the investment climate for our key plants types have now normalized. We can also confirm an unchanged target margin of 8%.</p>
          <p>To summarize my key observations after a successful year, there are strong mega-trends offering structural growth potential in our core businesses and we have the right set-up, I think, regarding local market shares, technologies and customer contacts. We have further improved our already solid financial structure with strong cash flow and profitability and therefore are, I think, ready to embrace the opportunities of the describe mega-trends.</p>
          <p>We are fully committed to further strengthen our profile on our continued path towards a high performance culture. In order to give you some guidance on how to translate this into figures, we provide the following mid-term targets.</p>
          <p>In 2014, we wanted to achieve on a group level an operating profit of at least &#x20AC;4 billion. We want to further grow the adjusted return on capital employed to 14% or higher. I mean, the &#x20AC;4 billion in euro, not dollars.</p>
          <p>For the Gases division, the average CapEx to sales ratio shall be 13% plus. Why do I say plus? Plus could be when large scale energy projects come into play. As you can imagine, our ambition is to outperform the markets with our revenue increase and at the same time, we will remain fully focused on our increase in productivity through our high performance initiatives.</p>
          <p>Now thank you very much for your attention. I now hand over to Georg Denoke, our CFO, for more details on financials and we will both be available for your questions after that. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good afternoon from my side as well. I will focus in my presentation on the operational performance, the project pipeline and CapEx as well as on the financial performance.</p>
          <p>I will start with development of the group's key financial indicators on page 24, all of them reaching new record levels in 2010. The adjusted EPS increased by 50.4%, to &#x20AC;6.89 and the return on capital employed improved by 210 basis points to 12.5%. Also, the performance of the operating cash flow has been strong again resulting in a 13.1% increase to &#x20AC;2.422 billion.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, page 25, you find the quarterly performance of the operating cash flow, as well as the development of the investing and the free cash flow. The operating cash flow accelerated throughout the year. This positive development is based on the increase of the operating profit and especially in the fourth quarter, on the further improvement of the working capital.</p>
          <p>The investing cash flow increased in the year 2010 by 7.6% to &#x20AC;1.065 billion. Please have in mind that the investing cash flow is a net figure which includes the cash-out for assets and acquisitions, as well as proceeds from the disposal of assets and the amortization of receivables from financial services. The free cash flow in the last year advanced by 17.8% to &#x20AC;1.357 billion.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the sales development of the operating segments in the Gases division on page 26. The operating segment Asia and Eastern Europe has posted the strongest comparable sales increase of 11.3%. On a reported basis, sales advanced by 21.9% to &#x20AC;2.239 billion.</p>
          <p>We have seen an unchanged growth momentum in Asia with greater China being the biggest growth driver in the region. Major startups in 2010 in the region include large air separation units, for example, for the customers Wanhua and Ningbo Steel in China and two bigger merchant plants in India and Malaysia. Moreover, the economic turnaround in Eastern Europe during the course of the year was also visible in the total recovery of our business development until the end of the year.</p>
          <p>Sales in Western Europe increased by 6.8% to &#x20AC;4.021 billion. The 3.6% growth on a comparable basis was, meanwhile, still held back by the contractual pass-through of lower energy prices to our customers in the U.K. market.</p>
          <p>Our business development in Western Europe was positively affected by the overall recovery of the Western European economy, resulting in higher capacity utilization at existing facilities. The startup of a number of new plants had also a positive impact on our business.</p>
          <p>In the U.K., for example, a major air separation plant for our longstanding customer Tata Steel went onstream at the steel hub in Scunthorpe. Another large air separation plant started operations for our customer Voestalpine in Linz, Austria. Sales in the operating segment, Americas, advanced by 15% to &#x20AC;2.279 billion. On a comparable basis, sales increased by 8.6%. This acceleration was driven by an improving momentum in both regions, while, as expected, of course, we have seen the stronger upward trend in South America. The general improvement in the economic situation in North America resulted in an increased demand for industrial gases overall. This has led to a higher capacity utilization of our existing plants.</p>
          <p>We also benefited from new start-ups in North America, including a hydrogen plant in Lemont, Illinois, and another new facility for liquefied carbon dioxide gas started production in Fulton, New York. In the partnership with the ethanol producer Sunoco, we purify the CO2 which arises during the production of this bio-fuel.</p>
          <p>This new plant means that Linde now has the largest CO2 capacity in the region, enabling the company to meet the rising demand from liquefied gas customers in the food and in the chemical industry.</p>
          <p>In South America, the good GDP growth in Brazil and also in Chile and Argentina was feeding volume increases in our bulk and tonnage product areas while the sales growth in our health-care business remains strong as well. Also in this region, we benefited from the start-up of two air separation plants.</p>
          <p>Gases sales in South Pacific and Africa have delivered a reported growth of 25.8% to &#x20AC;1.784 billion, driven to a large extent by strong currency gains. On a comparable basis, sales growth per end of the year stood at 2.5%. The profitability of our region is highlighted on the next page, with the detailed operating profit by operating segment. You find the margin as red on that slide. The 40 basis points increase of our Gases margin to 27% is supported by the continuous implementation of high-performance organizational initiatives across all regions. In Western Europe, the operating profit increased by 12.7% to &#x20AC;1.184 billion. The operating profit margin hence further increased by 150 basis points to 29.4%.</p>
          <p>In the Americas, our operating profit went up by 16.3% to &#x20AC;499 million. The operating margin of 21.9% was slightly above last year's level. The margin development was thereby diluted by the contractual pass-through of higher natural gas prices to our hydrogen customers in this region. Driven by the strong sales development, the operating profit in Asia and Eastern Europe advanced by 19.7% to &#x20AC;667 million. The operating margin of our growth market activities remained with 29.8% on a high overall level.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, also in this region the operating margin was negatively impacted by the contractual pass-through of higher natural gas prices. Our operating profit in South Pacific and Africa improved strongly by 22% to &#x20AC;460 million. Just as for the sales development, this increase is also due to the translational currency gains in those regions. The operating margin for the full year stood at 23.3%.</p>
          <p>Considering the use of cash, please have a look on the Gases CapEx split by operating segment on page 28. In the year 2010, we invested in the Gases Division &#x20AC;1.326 billion, which is an increase of 28.9% against 2009. Asia and Eastern Europe saw, as we expected, the steepest increase with a 54.1% rise in allocated capital spending. This reflects our strong pipeline in these growth regions with, among others, major capital outlays to projects in Asia.</p>
          <p>However, also Western Europe had a substantial acceleration in investments with an increase of 26.5%. The share of CapEx allocated to growth markets was in 46% in 2010, which is slightly up on last year's figure.</p>
          <p>Let me turn now to the project pipeline in the gases division, on page 29. The total investment amount of our pipeline for the years 2008 to 2012 is &#x20AC;3 billion, with 70% of it being allocated to growth markets. We won a number of new contracts in Greater China across all industry sectors. The most important project signings were with TISCO, <mark type="inaudible" /> , GCL, BUE and TSMC in Taiwan.</p>
          <p>In Eastern Europe, we succeeded in establishing a foothold in the emerging Kazakhstan market, where we signed a new contract with ArcelorMittal for a large air separation unit. Besides being a sizeable tonnage scheme, it will also allow us to further develop the liquids business in this growth market. Another contract for a large ASU was signed with our long-term customer ThyssenKrupp at their steel site in Duisburg in Germany.</p>
          <p>Since our last communication, the total project amount by an on-stream date for the year 2012 further increased to &#x20AC;550 million and more over, we have signed additional contracts, of course, with start-up dates beyond 2012. We see an increasing number of project opportunities with a large portion in growth markets. This is also visible in the growing amount of project opportunities on a 12 months forward basis, moving up from &#x20AC;2.7 billion one year ago to now roughly &#x20AC;4 billion.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, page 30, you'll find the development of the CapEx sales ratio in our Gases division. The original guidance in 2007 for the years until 2010 was in average CapEx sales ratio of 13%. We see today that we are exactly at this level. And this year, we expect a CapEx figure in the Gases division of around &#x20AC;1.5 billion.</p>
          <p>For the period 2011 to 2014, we give the guidance of an average CapEx sales ratio of around 13%, which correlates with our mid-term target for group operating profit of at least &#x20AC;4 billion, as Dr. Reitzle already mentioned. The expected average CapEx sales ratio does not already include all the potential upside from mega-projects, which is the reason why we have added a plus to the 13% ratio.</p>
          <p>In the four years planning period, the focus will be on enhanced oil and gas recovery. Such mega-projects can be realized either as a subsidiary business or in a joint venture structure. This would have a different impact on the CapEx amount, as you know.</p>
          <p>Just to remind you about the enhanced gas recovery project with Abu Dhabi National Oil Corporation that goes on-stream this year, middle of the year, if this project would not be a joint venture, then the average CapEx sales ratio in the last years would already have exceeded 13%.</p>
          <p>The investment amount is here around &#x20AC;800 million in this joint venture structure. Such projects as subsidiary business would also have a significant impact on our key financial figures. The return on capital employed would be negatively influenced over the construction period, due to a significant amount of investment with no earnings impact during that phase. Of course as you know, this will change over the ramp-up period with earnings flow in the P&amp;L statement.</p>
          <p>Going to the net debt bridge on page 31. Due to the strong operating cash flow generation of &#x20AC;2.4 billion, we were able to reduce net debt substantially by &#x20AC;620 million to &#x20AC;5.5 billion. This positive development was achieved despite an increased investment cash flow of around &#x20AC;1.1 billion, the net interest payments of around &#x20AC;300 million and the dividends of &#x20AC;350 million.</p>
          <p>As you can see on the next page, based on further de-leveraging and the increase of the operating profit, the net debt EBITDA ratio came down from 2.6 times to 1.9 times. This provides us with the flexibility to realize additional opportunities resulting from the mega-trends in the future.</p>
          <p>I also wants to remind you that we received in April 2010, the upgrade by both rating agencies S&amp;P and Moody's by one notch to A minus and A3 with a stable outlook.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, Page 33, you find the debt maturity profile. As you know us, our conservative approach regarding refinancing and our solid financial position are reflected in the balanced mix of financing instruments on the right-hand side and long dated maturity profile on the left-hand side of the presentation.</p>
          <p>Similar to previous years, more than 90% of the financial debt had a maturity of more than one year, and 50% of more than five years. As you know, you can see in the appendix our short term financial debt of &#x20AC;459 million covered by cash and securities of around &#x20AC;1.2 billion, and by a fully undrawn facility of &#x20AC;2.5 billion, which leaves us a with a liquidity reserve of &#x20AC;3.2 billion.</p>
          <p>As a result of the successful deleveraging and interest rate management in the group's financial result has continuously improved in the last three years, as you can see on Page 34. In the year 2010, the financial result amounted to &#x20AC;280 million. The year-on-year improvement was also positively impacted by an income of &#x20AC;29 million arising from the reversal of an allowance for financial receivables relating to a loan from the BOC Edwards disposal. As you might remember in 2007, we sold BOC Edwards and agreed with the buyer a vendor loan.</p>
          <p>For 2011, we expect the financial results to be around &#x20AC;300 million. Also this year, we will have the positive one time contribution resulting from the second portion of the BOC Edwards vendor loan repayment of additional &#x20AC;30 million.</p>
          <p>The tax rate of the operating income remained stable. However, the group's tax rate slightly increased in 2010 compared to 2009, and this is mainly due to the impact resulting from the continuously decreasing depreciation in relation to the purchase price allocation, which in 2010 led to lower tax benefits. For this year, we expect the group's tax rate to be in the range of 24% to 25%.</p>
          <p>Looking into the dividend development on Page 35, we will propose to our shareholder in the annual general meeting on May 12th to increase our dividend for the fiscal year to &#x20AC;2.20 per share. With an increase of 22%, this proposal is consistent with our dividend policy, which means the dividend should reflect the development of the operating profit.</p>
          <p>So let me summarize. The year 2010 was a strong year for Linde. We achieved new record levels in all key financial indicators. We further reduced net debt, and have a very solid balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, we are well placed to benefit from factual mega-trends with our strong position in growth markets, and the business synergies between our Gases and Engineering portfolio in energy and environmental applications.</p>
          <p>Based on a sustainable cash flow generation, and the long-term financing, we are able to invest 13% or more in the Gases business in the coming years. That means we are well prepared for the realization of growth potential resulting from the mega-trends in the future, but we still see further improvement potential, and we want to become even better.</p>
          <p>Our aim is to be a high performance organization, and we want to install a continuous improvement culture throughout our organization in order to leverage our leading business set up into sustainable long term profitable growth.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention. We will be happy to take your questions now. Operator, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from the Norbert Barth. Please go ahead with your question and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hello, it's Norbert Barth from Westlb; perhaps the first question concerning Engineering. You had in 2010 what you said really a record year with 11% margin, and your guidance you said you stick still to the 8% level. So do you think that 2010 was more or less a one-off record year? Or if the guidance in 2000 &#x2013; what you gave on 8% more a cautious one, so should we look a little bit for a better situation? So can you elaborate a little bit on that? And the second question concerning the general midterm target 2014, as you said. Can you explain a little bit what you have put behind on CapEx? You said okay, this 13% target will consist, but with a plus, so are there already some mega projects included in? And can you perhaps elaborate a little bit what volume could these additional bigger mega projects means on CapEx level? And also perhaps you have in the last years succeeded much in bringing all the costs down. If I see all these growth projects, do you not believe that there are perhaps was a time that you have also additional costs by taking new people on board. So is that really a trend that you also could up to 2014 further bring your costs in relative terms down? And perhaps the last question, just picking up for clarification here, what you said on the financial interest outlook 2011. This &#x20AC;300 million, what you indicated, is that including already this &#x20AC;13 million one-off or is that additionally coming?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Ja. Thank you, Norbert, for your questions. As you know us, we're a conservative company, and when we talk about outlook, we want to normally achieve what we promise to the capital markets. Of course, there can be significant impact as we experienced in the downturn period in 2009. Nevertheless, we now came really close to the &#x20AC;3 billion target for 2010 with more than &#x20AC;2.9 billion, of course, supported also by our currency next year. For Engineering, it's been above 8%, so the small word which we included was above 8%. Of course, the 11% was really in result out of the history which was signing contracts in the peak of the year of 2008, executing them against a, let's say, weak market in 2009, where the buyer was in a strong execution momentum against the supplier. So from that perspective, we have really realized additional earnings out of that moment in time. And, therefore, the guidance is the plus 8%, and especially when we look into the years further down the road, when we talk about '12, '13, '14, we believe that the 8% is really a long-term view, and it is compared to the industry benchmark and leading number, which is here our target number.</p>
          <p>The CapEx question related to 2012, 2014. As I said in my presentation, it's been 13% plus. In the &#x20AC;4 billion plus EBITDA target we have assumed a 13% CapEx sales ratio, which is in average roughly &#x20AC;1.6 billion per annum, and it is, of course, without these significant mega-projects which are difficult to anticipate, and, therefore, I made the historical example of the enhanced gas recovery scheme for the Abu Dhabi National Oil Company in our joint venture, Elixier, where you see an &#x20AC;800 million investment, which is, of course, not consolidated, because it's a 50-50 joint venture. Here the majority is not allowed for a foreigner against the Abu Dhabi setup.</p>
          <p>So from that perspective, I think when you take that example you can see if we execute &#x20AC;1 billion over three years the kind of impact in the erection phase on the one hand from a royalty perspective. So no inflow, but this would be consolidated, of course, an increase of capital employed, but then of course, later an additional upside. And we do see more opportunities in that environment and that market segment, especially in the years to come. So there is no guidance for the impact of the additional out of energy and environmental mega-project because it's difficult to forecast, and we don't want to fire up the market. But I think we were very clear in the presentation of <mark type="inaudible" /> what kind of market size we see until 2015, for example, and then you can make your assumptions and a little bit rough we also want to leave for you. On the people development, of course, I think I would like to hand over to Dr. Reitzle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, actually it's clear that the outlined growth perspectives, especially for the emerging markets, and by this, specifically, for China and India, means that within the next ten years we definitely have to hire a few thousand people. And you are right, usually hiring somebody, training the people, it is a certain upfront cost and investment, and usually, then, the sales and the profit streams will come with a certain delay. On the other hand, I think you know beyond our official HPO target, which we already communicated to you now for more than two years, which says &#x20AC;650 million cost savings till the end of 2012 means that we will &#x2013; actually, we will not stop at the end of 2012.</p>
          <p>We, hopefully, till then have a cultural element implemented in our company, which is based on continuous improvement. So we will have, and are working hard for that, a permanent increase in efficiency and productivity, and I think even with the front loading, hiring new people for our future growth, we should be able not to significantly influence future results negatively for a certain period. I think it should be possible to absorb that within what we usually can derive out of our continuous improvement program. So I would not see that as, let's say, as a negative in the short-term working towards a long-term bright future. I think we will manage that to cope with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Norbert, the final question from your side was about the financial result. Around &#x20AC;300 million includes that from a conservative viewpoint.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Tony Jones. Please go ahead with your question and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Thanks for taking the question. You were saying that the cylinders comparable grew by 3.4%, and we know this is pretty late cycle market, but I thought a little benefit had been received by price so far. First, can you split out price and volume to this area? And then also can you give us an idea which countries have shown the most promise in terms of volume pick-up or pricing recovery over the last quarter? And then could you sort of give us an idea whether that trend might continue or accelerate into 2011? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So that's a detailed question on the cylinder business, on our PGP business. So when we see the momentum, the momentum of growth against the previous quarter accelerated in quarter four, so it is a later cycle business, the cylinder business. And we saw a positive momentum in the fourth quarter, and it is supported by volume, of course, and it is also supported by price. And we normally do not communicate the split, but it is the year-end and I think it is good to see really on a yearly basis what happens.</p>
          <p>And here the price effect is a little bit more pronounced than the volume effect because of the also first quarter development. When you see the first quarter development of 2010 that was really still negative. So from an overall perspective, the price effect looks positive here when we include that. From an expectation perspective, I think we expect some further recovery because when we compare that today, then the majority of our cylinder business is, of course, in mature regions, and here we are below the levels of the peak in 2008. If we will ever come back, it's a different question I would say. Definitely we will see further potential for 2011.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just one final follow-up. Are you going to try and increase prices a little bit more this year then? Do you think there's possibility? Or do you think competitive activities may be also coming back a little bit?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tony, I think you know exactly what you are talking about, and you also receive very different analysis from different competitors in different marketplaces. So sometimes it looks strange, I think, from your viewpoint. On the other hand, of course, within our HPO program is our productivity targets. The pricing aspect is a very important part, and with a more inflationary environment, definitely our intention is for pass-through. That's also to customers where it is possible.</p>
          <p>In this market segment, you know of course, that the number of customers is very high. So these are millions of customers, and we start here, of course, with list prices and then we see against the volume development what that means for each of the customers, but the intention is definitely there. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. That's helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Neil Tyler. Please go ahead with your question, and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. It's JPMorgan in London. Couple of questions on your balance sheet, please. Firstly, with regards to your current feeling on the level of leverage, you mentioned that it has enabled you to have flexibility to pursue mega-project. I wonder if you could, I suppose, clarify whether there'd been any examples in the recent couple of years where your level of debt has entered into this whole process when pursuing projects or even pulling away from those? Second question, if you carry on at the current free cash flow generation rate, then you'll be looking at, I suppose, post dividends and even assuming a bit of a step up in CapEx net cash flow of sort of &#x20AC;500 million or thereabouts. What's your thoughts with regard to using that, whether there's further deleveraging to take place or whether there might be any other uses for that? And then finally, within the 2011 CapEx plans or within the portfolio of opportunities, I wonder if you could clarify whether there are any project takers or site taker that's within those figures targeted? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think from an overall perspective, I think we have created the headroom which we really like to have for the pace of a mega-trend development, as we explained in the presentation. Overall, I think we never hesitated to take opportunities if there were opportunities even on a higher net debt EBITDA ratio. So from a best-case scenario, as I explained, there are &#x2013; there is the assumption of to be financed out of the operating cash flow because 13%, of course, that should be financed out of the operating cash flow. I think this is the best scenario, and additional mega should be then foreseen as the potential which we have on the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>I think today we believe that the opportunity pipeline is really increasing, and we see opportunities, and from that perspective over the cycle I would say the main focus is to grow, and of course, if there are decapitalization opportunities we would include the decapitalization opportunities. In the &#x20AC;1.5 billion today there are no significant decapitalization opportunities included. I think this is something which should be developed over the footprint also in combination with our Engineering customer base in the next quarters and years. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Markus Mayer. Please go ahead with your question, and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hello, Markus Mayer from UniCredit out of Munich. I have a follow-up question on the CapEx. Could you remind us what the split should be in '11 between maintenance and growth CapEx? And second question was centered in China, in particular in Ningbo and another area there was electricity shortage which affected three air separation plants of Linde. Could you confirm this? And if this was the case, what it would have been the growth if these three ASUs had been not affected?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I start with the last question. Of course, we have these electricity issues in China, but the startup happened now at the end of last year, so we have no electricity shortage. And that is, I think, the situation here in the Ningbo area. From an overall perspective of CapEx and replacement CapEx, let's say it that way. As higher the CapEx number will become, a smaller the portion of the replacement CapEx. I think this is the base scenario. So when you take a normal average CapEx sales ratio, then roughly one-sixth of that is allocated to replacement, I would say, but replacement is also sometimes a volatile word because when you have, for example, new cylinder applications, new sizes of cylinders, new weight of cylinders then this is a kind of replacement.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, it opens up additional market opportunities of the future. So as bigger the number will be when we are significantly above 13%, for example, then definitely the additional percentage points are not for replacement. This is always all for growth CapEx.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Perfect. Thanks</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Jean de Watteville. Please go ahead with your question, and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. This is Jean de Watteville speaking from Nomura; couple of questions. First of all on the working capital performance in Q4, I was wondering if you could bring a bit of color, and particularly is that more related to the Gas business, the Engineering or the other business? If you could describe what it is? And any lumpy element behind that performance would be very helpful. That's the first question. Second question is, I mean, it's quite interesting to see that you're talking about a portfolio of opportunity of about &#x20AC;4 billion; quite a steep increase on one year, particularly as you compare the early key communication, which is talking about an increase, but not of that scale. Can you just present which market has been dramatically improving over the last year in terms of opportunities? We know the long-term trends in the sector, but a lot of them were there already last year, so I'm curious whether there's a particular market where you're exposed to that has improved or it's just your commercial activity that has a really accelerated, and therefore come to that result? And the last and third question, on-site growth has been slowing down in Q4. I was wondering if you could bring a bit of color on what is that, and just distinguish between the effect of ramp-up and start-up versus development of the operating rates in the existing plants? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your questions, Jean. On the working capital from the cash flow perspective in the first quarter, that is supported by Linde Engineering. If you see the improvement, it was a continuation of performance in Gases, but the delta is Linde Engineering here from the performance level. When we talk about opportunities, let's say I wouldn't say that there are major differences from the market visibility in that market space. It's a little bit more than one year if we compare that. I think it's a question how much depressed you have put your own figure at the end of 2009 against the market, and overall, of course, what we have seen is a strong recovery in the Asian markets overall.</p>
          <p>When we talk about opportunities, we can talk about opportunities mainly there, but we also have seen opportunities against the energy mega-trend, and that energy mega-trend is also visible in mature territories and mature countries like the U.S., for example, where you also see tech support with subsidies for some of the interesting projects we discuss right now. So from that perspective it's a mix, but it's clearly from a regional perspective the momentum in Asia and from an energy-related, environmental-related momentum, it's more diverse. It also includes more mature countries like U.S. and Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the onsite performance in quarter four, there were some major shutdowns which were negatively impacting our comparable growth rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. And what's the contribution of startup in 2010 versus the underlying organic growth?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we don't split that out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right, too bad. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Peter Clark. Please go ahead with your question, and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Peter Clark from G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale. Couple of questions left. The first one is regarding with the European pricing situation. Obviously we've heard from your peers, but merchant pricing has been under a little pressure or has been negative. You touched on the cylinder pricing I think globally. I'm just trying to get a feel for how the pricing and the volume were in the bulk business in Europe, in particular. Because one would have thought there was pretty strong merchant growth coming through towards the end of the year, year-on-year, particularly in Germany. And then the second question, the comments obviously &#x2013; the dividend policy &#x2013; about the dividend should reflect the development of the operating profit. Obviously, you're getting a much stronger balance sheet. You've got a lot of cash flow being generated. The <mark type="inaudible" /> is still extremely healthy. Just wondering if there's potential for some more catch-up, if I could it put it that way, against some of your peers in terms of the yield? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter, thank you for your questions, and when we look into the pricing details, of course, in the merchant arena, as we always pointed out during the quarterly communication last year, U.K. was, of course, impacted by the reduction of electrical energy pricing. And that is in pass-through also on the bike customers, and of course, it has an impact also on the merchant customers. So when we look into Europe then you have a negative pricing impact from a total merchant perspective in the U.K. market, too, as you have it also of course in tonnage, so from that perspective that was a little bit weaker. We have discussed in Q3 call the differences in the German market between other competitors and us, and you have seen us communicating and stronger performance in Germany than the others.</p>
          <p>I think this is really that the merchant business is a very detailed business. It goes with a lot of products, and you have to exactly understand what you want to do. So that I think is at last year for Linde overall. From an Eastern European perspective, of course, we have seen Eastern Europe coming out all of the crisis latest, and this was the most significant impact if you compare the lead table of growth rates before the crisis. So here we have seen at the beginning of the year a weakness and in merchant, we still see this a little bit, but overall I think these are the details I want to give to you on an European performance level in merchant. The wish is always big when it comes to dividend. I think whatever kind of dividend you communicate you can ask for more. I think I would like to answer that we definitely see growth opportunities, and I think we want to catch up this growth, and deliver this through performance and the guidance is really that we follow the operational performance more or less.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Evgenia Molotova. Please go ahead with ahead with your question, and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Thanks a lot for the questions; Evgenia Molotova from UBS. I have one question on margin improvements and on Slide 24 in particular. As far as I understand, I'm looking at the EBITDA margin of the Gases division, and it's improved year-on-year and as far as I understand, the majority of this improvement is due to the improvements in Western Europe in margin. And I was just trying to understand how much of this improvement is due to the lower Gas pass through, so the margin because of the raw material &#x2013; because of the gas and how much of it because of HPO? And also looking forward, how can I forecast the margin improvement? This is the first question. And the second question about the cylinders. You said that you're not sure that the level of cylinders activity in developed markets will ever return to 2008 level. I was wondering does it mean that the level of return capital employed in developed markets will never achieve the same level again or how will you combat that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I start with the last question, Evgenia. So I think this was a conservative answer from a CFO. So from that perspective, no indication on return on capital employed reduction in that market because while we run a lot of activities in the basket of our HPO program that we should avoid debt, of course. It was only the indication there was a crisis a year ago, and people were not aware of the situation we have experienced a very nice 2010, and in this space people see more upsides and downsides. This was the only background against that comment I think.</p>
          <p>On the margin development, overall the split is not available how much comes through the pass through and how much comes through HPO. But definitely you know in Europe that we are running also here, for example, HyCO schemes for refinery customers, so you have a dilutional impact on that level in Europe too as in other territories, like in Asia and Singapore we have the same cost to the greatest extent from North America. So you see this also in Europe and the rest really comes especially in Europe out of the HPO program which has also from a mitigation perspective still an impact in 2010 because in Europe the adjustment takes longer when you have to negotiate with works councils on a country level. So from that perspective it's heavily supported by HPO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Georg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Nadeshda Demidova. Please go ahead with your question, and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Nadeshda Demidova from Equinet. Your cash generation is really impressive, and that's why my question concerns your cash use. You were able to decrease your net debt to EBITDA to below 2. Can we assume that this ratio would remain at the lower end of your target range of 2 up to 3 times? And I didn't know if you communicate some kind of target gearing? And another question on your acquisition strategy, I understand your focus is on the health care-related gas market. What opportunities do we see in this market? And how should we see that all takeover targets went to your competitors in the past months and quarters. Do you probably observe some kind of a fierce bidding process in this market? And the last question. Can you just probably provide us with an approximate breakdown of pure gas and <mark type="inaudible" /> in your health care sales? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your very detailed questions. I think I gave a clear answer to your last question, and I would say no, I don't have a breakdown for you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For that one. On the use of cash, of course, I think we gave the guidance and the guidance is that we see really more opportunities in the energy environment, and if we can catch up with these opportunities, of course, we do have the flexibility to go back to a higher level of net debt EBITDA ratio. I think this is a good message. When we stick to this 13% then that will be in a way financed out of the operating cash flow, and what is left will be then available for the leveraging or for dividends or for some acquisitions in the health care arena.</p>
          <p>I think we focused heavily in the last year on our further HPO development. We have acquired a couple of smaller business, mainly in Asia, for example the Sri Lanka business which we acquired in November. So from that perspective it was not against a market development where we see that this is all unreasonable. I think we always have an eye on targets available, and then we decide depending on market share situations, for example, and opportunities if we want to get that, and then of course, there will be competition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>[Operator Instruction] Our next question comes from Stephan Kippe. Please go ahead with your question, and announce your company name. Sir, your line is open. You may go ahead with your question</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Stephan Kippe from Commerzbank, Frankfurt. Just one question with regards to your new CapEx guidance and in connection with your operating profit and ROCE target. Does that complete the other &#x20AC;4 billion, and especially the significantly increased ROCE only a result of CapEx plans? How do you expect to really fundamentally increase the ROIC? Is that a mix effect? Will you focus on areas where the capital returns are better? Or are there above the HPO program that you already have other improvements already part of the scenario how you want &#x2013; plan to achieve the 14%? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Stephan. I think it's in combination, of course. There is the assumption that we continue with HPO, and that we fulfill what we have promised until 2012, and then there will be further years to come, and we will not stop with HPO. So there is a continuation of productivity gains, and we will come back to you when we have delivered 2012.</p>
          <p>And then we will see how we communicate against that the starting point, but definitely we haven't stopped increasing productivity in the planning period. And then the additional part then comes out of the growth assumption, of course, and I think this is a combination how you should run your model.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If I may add, is part of that increase also a fact that some of all the project that you may have invested on ten years ago, five years ago have now been written off largely, while continuing to deliver nice earnings and sales?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think this is the wrong question for Linde. Of the aging of our plants we are really around a new starter, so there is no accounting effect in a way supporting that development. It's a performance driven development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Laurent Favre. Please go ahead with your question, and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. It's Laurent Favre from Bank of America Merrill Lynch, and thanks for taking my question. I've got two questions. The first one is when you were talking about the need to have strong market shares in the key regions. One region where it's quite obvious that you don't have that strong market share position is in North America, so I was just wondering if you could share with us your view on this market and whether you would be prepared to do something to address the market share? And the second question is a question on the contribution from joint ventures in Gases, &#x20AC;85 million in 2010. This year you will have the Adnoc contribution on top it. I'm just wondering should we model for a bit more than &#x20AC;100 million of net income from joint ventures? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I start with your last question on the development of the share of net income. Yeah, I think the share of net income should increase a little bit against the on stream date of our joint venture in Abu Dhabi. That is a confirmation. Can you repeat your question on North America? We had problems to fully understand your question about the market share development here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It was more of a general question on your positioning in North America where you don't have a very strong position. So I'm just wondering is this an area where you are prepared to put a bit more capital, both CapEx or even external?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think we the North American market as a position we have achieved, I think, and we have given the CapEx plan in a way to you what we invested last year. I think on that basis we have an organic development. We see additional opportunities when we include, for example, the silent revolution from an energy perspective in the Linde Engineering business.</p>
          <p>For example, we experienced shale gas opportunities. We see additional energy-related schemes, but also Kent Masters is here at the table, and I think I hand over to him, and he can probably talk best about the North American markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would just say we look at our business regionally there. So it's not so much the overall share, but what is in the pocket. So we've got nice shares in different geographies. So we're not uncomfortable with our market share position.</p>
          <p>When you look at it nationally, it's diluted, but if you look at it regionally, which is important in our business, the shares are not that bad. So we're pretty happy. We typically are one, two, or three, maybe, in markets that we play in there, so it's not something we're drastically trying to change.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Laurent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>[Operator Instruction] Our next question comes from the line of Thomas Davoda. Please go ahead with your question, and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thomas Davoda from Myfirst in Frankfurt. I have one question left. Looking at the peer group we have seen some different speed in top line growth, especially Eliceet. It seems to be relatively aggressively growing on the top line. My question is do you see any changes in the competitive environment? More in particular, is there somebody out there trying to buy top line growth by jeopardizing margins? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think this is a question which is difficult to answer. Of course, when you are in a competition environment in some of the Asian markets and some of the territories, definitely you see sometimes somebody who behaves unreasonable. That was also happening in the past, as you know, and we have explained the background, for example, in some of the public available data, like in India, for example, there was a public bidding. Overall, I really would say there is still the discipline we have experienced in the past in the marketplace.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>We appear to have no further question at this time, sir. So I'll hand the conference back to you. Sir, would you like to end the conference call?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there &#x2013; if there are no further questions, definitely we are happy to end now, and we are looking forward to our communication beginning of May when we look into the Q1 figures.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your participations and your questions. Good-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation today. This concludes today's conference. You may now disconnect your lines. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>