<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1246291" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-08-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9099</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Thomas Eisenlohr, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Georg Denoke, Chief Financial Officer and Employment Director</participant>
      <participant id="3">Jean De Watteville</participant>
      <participant id="4">Markus Mayer</participant>
      <participant id="5">Aldo Belloni</participant>
      <participant id="6">Andrew Stott</participant>
      <participant id="7">Andrew Benson</participant>
      <participant id="8">Matthias Cornu</participant>
      <participant id="9">Neil Taylor</participant>
      <participant id="10">Peter Clark</participant>
      <participant id="11">Tony Jones</participant>
      <participant id="12">Rhian Tucker</participant>
      <participant id="13">Karan Khemani</participant>
      <participant id="14">Virginie Boucher-Ferte</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen and welcome to the Linde Q2 Results Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in listen-only mode until we conduct a question-and-answer session and instructions will be given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And just to remind you this conference call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand over to Thomas Eisenlohr. Please begin your meeting and I'll be standing by.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, and good afternoon, everybody. It's Thomas Eisenlohr. Thank you for joining the call for our first half year results today. Georg Denoke, CFO will be hosting the call and Aldo Belloni, Member of the Executive Board is also available for your question.</p>
          <p>We would like to ask you to restrain yourself to one question in the first round of the Q&amp;A session in order to allow everyone to get through. I will now hand over to Georg and we will open the line again for your questions at the end of the presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you, Thomas. Hello, this is Georg Denoke. Welcome to our earnings call also from my side. Let's start with an overview of the key facts and figures on page three of the presentation.</p>
          <p>Group sales of &#x20AC;5.476 billion and group operating profit of &#x20AC;1.104 billion declined by 12.5% and 12.2% respectively compared to the first half year of 2008. As you know, we are booking the restructuring charges linked to the acceleration of our HPO program in the reported EBITDA. So if we exclude these one-time charges to isolate the operating performance our operating profit was actually down by 6.9% only. Reported EPS declined by 34% to &#x20AC;1.47, while the adjusted EPS decreased by 24% to &#x20AC;2.06. Before restructuring charges, the adjusted EPS declined by 13.6%.</p>
          <p>In spite of the lower sales volumes due to the financial and economic crisis, we have maintained a strong cash flow generation. Operating cash flow increased from 816 million to &#x20AC;841 million. This strong performance reflects our hard work on working capital management and cost structures.</p>
          <p>This is a key observation for me from the second quarter. While there was no significant recovery in market circumstances, we have still managed to further strengthen our profitability.</p>
          <p>You have to be aware of that we took another &#x20AC;47 million of restructuring charges in the second quarter. So, to make that very clear, we have now booked &#x20AC;67 million out of the total expected charge of around &#x20AC;70 million.</p>
          <p>Excluding these one-time charges, our group operating margin was up significantly by 130 basis points to 21.4%. As you will see, we are benefiting here from the ramp-up of cost savings out of the acceleration of our HPO program.</p>
          <p>Concerning the outlook 2009, we expect, based on the improvement in macroeconomic signals, we have seen at the end of quarter two a further recovery of our performance in the second half year compared to the first half as the economic improvement takes hold. Nevertheless, the sales and earnings level as in the record year 2008 is no more attainable.</p>
          <p>I'll start with the overview of the group sales split by divisions on page four of the presentation. With sales of &#x20AC;4.35 billion, the Gases Division saw in the first half year a revenue decline of 7.6% on reported basis. The underlying sales development was minus 6.7% or minus 3.5% including the contribution of bolt-on acquisitions.</p>
          <p>The Engineering Division posted first half year sales of &#x20AC;1.113 billion, the decline there was the high sales level of the previous year is mainly due to the different project structure and physical completion. The order backlog was &#x20AC;4.4 billion at the end of the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Group operating profit, on page five, was down 12.2% to &#x20AC;1.104 billion. Again, adjusted for restructuring expenses, this decline was 6.9%, with the group margin of 21.4% exceeding last year's level by 130 basis points.</p>
          <p>In the Gases Division, operating profit was down 4.7% to &#x20AC;1.138 billion. Synergies, the accelerated implementation of HPO and positive pricing helped here to cushion the volume impacts within the sales decline. Our Gases operating margin hence even increased to 26.2% versus 25.4% in the first half year of 2008.</p>
          <p>In the Engineering Division, the year-on-year reduction in sales mirrors the lower recognition of revenues versus the second quarter of last year. In terms of margin, we stay on track towards our 8% target level. When comparing the operating profit development, please have in mind that last year's figure includes the profit on disposal of the market wells business.</p>
          <p>Finally, as I already explained our restructuring charges of &#x20AC;67 million per end of June are booked within the EBITDA of the other consolidation segment.</p>
          <p>Moving into more details of our Gases performance, we start given the volatile market environment with the look at our performance in the second quarter 2009 on page six, if you compare the second with the first quarter 2009, sales increased by 1.7%. This improvement was driven by the first recovery steps in the emerging markets. In the mature market, sales run rate is not further deteriorate and show a stabilization.</p>
          <p>On the basis of the slight recovery in sales, operating profit in the Gases Division increased by 8.4% to &#x20AC;592 million in the second quarter with the margin improvement of 170 basis points to 27%.</p>
          <p>This margin performance should also be put into the year-on-year perspective. This global GDP significantly down versus last year, our gases sales were in the second quarter 8.9% below the previous year level.</p>
          <p>However, we managed to limit the resulting decline in operating profit to 2.6%. Operating margins hence increased by 180 basis points year-over-year. The pass through of low &#x2013; lower natural gas prices and the tonnage segment had of course a positive effect to debt development. But even excluding this item, we still have an underlying margin improvement of 80 basis points.</p>
          <p>In an environment of lower volumes and capacity loadings, this is clearly a strong performance driven by the acceleration of our HPO program. And as we are moving over the usual presentation of regional performance, let me underscore that this margin increase was supported by all our operating segments.</p>
          <p>Moving to page seven, sales and operating profit for our operating segments are shown on the next four pages, starting with western Europe. The sales of &#x20AC;1.849 billion, western Europe has reported the year-on-year decline of 11.2%, operating profit of &#x20AC;506 million was down 12%</p>
          <p>Despite quite lower volumes, our operating margin hence stayed strong at 27.4%. Comparing quarter two with quarter one 2009, the margin improved by 190 basis points. The year-on-year comparison of reported sales and operating profit is of course, still strongly impacted by the weakness of the British pound. Adjusted for currency, natural gas price and consolidation effect, the comparable sales decline was 6%.</p>
          <p>As I've said earlier, there was no major turnaround in volume in Western Europe markets over the second quarter. Sales run-rate is stabilized compared to the first quarter, but we cannot speak yet of any real recovery.</p>
          <p>The Healthcare product segment kept growing and the pricing size overall remained supportive.</p>
          <p>In the operating segment Americas, sales of &#x20AC;993 million were down 8.2% on reported and 8.4% on comparable basis. Operating profit, however improved slightly by 1.9% to &#x20AC;210 million.</p>
          <p>The substantial margin increase of 210 basis points towards 21.1% was driven by a lower natural gas price pass-through as well as our early capacity adjustment and HPO initiatives.</p>
          <p>Just as in Western Europe, the trends in the second quarter shows a stabilization, but no recovery of sales, run rates compared to the first quarter. From year-on-year point of view, volumes are of course; still significantly lower than in the first half year of 2008, partly offset by positive pricing.</p>
          <p>South America keeps holding up quite well, actually not only Healthcare, but also Cylinder sales showed underlying growth in this region.</p>
          <p>The operating segment Asia and Eastern Europe posted sales of &#x20AC;877 million, 7.2% below the first half year of 2008. On comparable basis, sales were down 7.4%, supported by the accelerated implementation of our productivity initiatives and the performance of our joint ventures.</p>
          <p>Operating profit, we treated only 1.1% to &#x20AC;266 million. At 30.3% our operating margin hence strengthened by a further 180 basis points.</p>
          <p>Our emerging markets segment Asia and Eastern Europe has in the second quarter shown the clearest signs of the potential economic recovery. Given the year-on-year contraction in industrial production, volumes for the six months period are still below last year's level. However, we have seen more encouraging trends towards the end of the first half year.</p>
          <p>Eastern Europe has hold &#x2013; its decline and stabilized volumes in the second quarter. In Asia some regions and markets have shown &#x2013; positive trends in underlying sales run rates.</p>
          <p>Product rates have overall improved from the low levels of the first quarter with especially China spending out. The stimulus program in China is generating positive momentum and the signing of our new joint venture with Sinopec for a tonnage contract in Chongqing Inland China in April also reflects this strong support of the economy for future growth.</p>
          <p>With our leading position in both Eastern Europe, Middle East as well as in South and East Asia in China we had the strong set-up to benefit from the stronger upturn of economic conditions in these regions.</p>
          <p>Moving to page 10. The operating segment South Pacific and Africa posted a sales increase of 5.4% to &#x20AC;666 million in the first six months. The consolidation of the LPG business, Elgas, below cost to more than compensate the adverse exchange rate effects on the Australian dollar and the South African rand.</p>
          <p>On a comparable basis, sales were down by 4.6%, including the both on acquisition of Elgas the sales increase amounted as to 16%. Operating profit increased by 8.3% to &#x20AC;156 million. The margin hence strengthened from 22.8% to 23.4% by 60 basis points reflecting positive pricing, our cost initiatives and the relatively stable underlying business performance. Comparing quarter two with quarter one 2009 the margin improvement was 380 basis points.</p>
          <p>Volume declines in the South Pacific region were indeed very modest, thanks to a still very robust economic environment in light of the global situation. Beside the positive pricing our sales and operating performance in Australia was also supported by growth in the Healthcare product area in the rental business.</p>
          <p>The economic situation in South Africa, our major markets in Africa was meanwhile still difficult, mainly due to the general inflationary environment, thanks to our rigorous price work. We however, saw our business stabilizing in the second quarter. All in all our performance in the operating segments hence reflect that the general economic environment globally in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Mature regions move from the downward trend into a stabilization phase while emerging markets showed the first signs of recovery in the month of the quarter. As an illustration of our strong emerging market set up we have summarized our sales exposure on the following slide page 11.</p>
          <p>Already more than 30% of the Gases revenue are achieved in emerging market. Our exposure is regionally quite well spread. The biggest markets are Asia with more than one-third and Eastern Europe and Middle East was around 25% of our emerging market revenues, followed by South America and Africa.</p>
          <p>And I just want to remind you that around 50% of the total gases CapEx in the last two years was invested in the emerging market. Clearly, we believe that the emerging market should be able to keep delivering above average growth rates and this will be beneficial to our performance.</p>
          <p>The next slide page 12 shows you the sales bridge in the Gases Division for the first half year. The combined price volume effect in the first half year was, as mentioned, minus 6.7% with volume decline partly offset by positive pricing, exchange rates have improved in the second quarter. The U.S. dollar effect has actually turn positive now.</p>
          <p>However for the six month period exchange rates have reduced gases sales by minus 1.4% on reported basis. Again, please have in mind here that our combined revenues in British pound, South African rand and Australian dollar are actually higher than our U.S. sales.</p>
          <p>The natural gas price effect did further intensify in the second quarter towards the half year impact of minus 2.8%. As already discussed, the contractual pass through of natural gas prices towards our tonnage customers does not affect our operating profit. Therefore the decline in sales is made up by an improved margin.</p>
          <p>The consolidation effect finally was again positive at 3.3% reflecting the consolidation of our formal joint venture Elgas in Australia and the Saudi Arabian business SIGAS.</p>
          <p>Business trends in the product areas of our gases division for the first half year were affected by the global recession, as shown by our overview on page 13. In the first six months of this year bulk sales were down by 9.1% on a comparable basis to &#x20AC;1.074 billion.</p>
          <p>Cylinder sales decreased on the same basis by 9% to &#x20AC;1.779 billion. Compared with the first quarter 2009 sales in bulk and cylinder in the second quarter 2009 improved by 0.4% and 4.2% respectively.</p>
          <p>This underlined the slight recovery in quarter two including some seasonal effects. As seen in the regional breakdown the operating segment Asia and Eastern Europe as well as South Pacific in Africa have been driving the recovery in our merchant market activities.</p>
          <p>In the tonnage segment, the underlying volume reduction whereas the previous years are cautioned by the contract structure of our take-or-pay contracts, sales were down by 5.4% to &#x20AC;989 million for the first six months of the year.</p>
          <p>The average capacity utilization in our schemes also started to recover over the course of the quarter. The quarter-on-quarter sales decline in 2009 of 1.8% includes the negative natural gas price effect, which masked the underlying improvement during the second quarter. As expected the Healthcare product area stays clear of the economic downturn with the comparable sales growth of 5.6% to &#x20AC;508 million in the reporting period.</p>
          <p>On the next page, slide 14, we keep you posted on the current stages of our pipeline of major new projects in the Gas Division. Again in terms of definition all projects taking into account here were, has an investment size of at least &#x20AC;10 million and the year refers to the claims startup date of the plant.</p>
          <p>The pipeline is very stable since our last update in May. The total number of plants startups in the year 2008 to 2011 is unchanged at 64 with the major contribution out of the pipeline to become visible over the year 2010. To complete the picture of our performance in the Gases Division I move on to slide 15, showing the development of our joint venture.</p>
          <p>The proportionate sales for the first half year, as always, not included in our top-line figures are of course still strongly below last years level due to the full consolidation of our formal joint venture with Elgas as of October 2008. However, the share of the net income on the right hand side reflects tonnage start-ups in joint venture structures in the first six months of the year, as well as a continuous ramp-up of earlier starts-ups. Especially projects in China contributed strong growth to the 48% increase in proportionate net income in the first year &#x2013; in the first half year to &#x20AC;37 million. For the full year, we expect the share of net income contribution from our joint ventures of around &#x20AC;60 million.</p>
          <p>Focusing now on the order situation in our engineering division on page 16. The order backlog of &#x20AC;4.4 billion gives us a good sales visibility for the next 18 to 24 months. What we see on the order intakes side is that clients are more hesitant to sign new contracts as they have limited visibility on the demand situation on their side. Nevertheless, we were able to sign the $1.1 billion contact for an olefin plant in Abu Dhabi.</p>
          <p>As you know, this is the third contract we have signed with the Borouge joint venture in the Ruwais cluster. This new order has led to an order intake of &#x20AC;1.3 billion in the first six months of this year, which is a sizable figure in the midst of the worldwide economic crisis.</p>
          <p>Moving to the cash flow development on page 17, the operating cash flow in the reporting period was &#x20AC;841 million, exceeding the previous year figure for the first six months of &#x20AC;860 million. Despite the fall in earnings, cash flow was hence relatively high, especially as a result of stronger working capital management.</p>
          <p>Please be aware that out of the &#x20AC;67 million restructuring costs, &#x20AC;37 million are already paid. Excluding this extraordinary charge, the operating cash flow for the first half year 2009 would exceed the 2008 half year figure by 7.6%. The operating cash flow was negatively impacted by a tax prepayment for the whole year.</p>
          <p>The investment cash flow in the first half of the year was minus &#x20AC;536 million, compared to a net cash outflow of &#x20AC;424 million in 2008. The increase of &#x20AC;112 million in net cash outflow was mainly due to the proceeds on disposal of non-current assets held for sale recognized in the prior year period. To remind you this was a Colombian business and the BOC Edwards Pharma business.</p>
          <p>Cash outflows for investments in the reporting period were &#x20AC;543 million, although some 4.6% below last year's figure of &#x20AC;569 million, our investments remain at a relatively high level. The main path was dedicated to the execution of our tonnage project. Payments for acquisitions of &#x20AC;69 million relate mainly to the acquisition of our subsidiary, SIGAS in Saudi Arabia. The free cash flow before financing activities in the reporting period was &#x20AC;305 million compared to &#x20AC;392 million in 2008.</p>
          <p>Coming to the financial position on page 18, despite the strong cash flow generation, net debt of &#x20AC;6.796 billion is slightly higher than the year-end figure. This mainly related to the high CapEx, the exchange rate movements and the dividend payment occurred over the quarter.</p>
          <p>The majority profile of our financial debt remains well spread. There's more than 80% of financial debt to be due beyond 2010, we have a solid long-term financing in place. Also our short-term maturities are very well covered. Our cash position of &#x20AC;866 million for our quarter end, and our &#x20AC;2 billion syndicated credit facility give us a liquidity reserve of &#x20AC;1.556 billion.</p>
          <p>With the signing of the forward start agreement for a new credit facility of &#x20AC;1.6 billion in June, we have further strengthened our liquidity profile until 2013. Let me stress that this new credit facility will be available at the time our existing undrawn &#x20AC;2 billion credit facility expires in March 2011.</p>
          <p>This forward start has strengthened our financing flexibility as we extend the availability of a significant credit facility from 2011 to 2013. The very good reception and the commitment of more than 20 of our core banks in this self-arranged deal demonstrated the strong confidence of the capital market.</p>
          <p>Before I finish my presentation, I'd like to update you on our outlook for 2009 on page 19. In terms of the economic background, a moderate recovery in the global market environment in the second half of the year is expected. Nevertheless, global economic output for 2009 will still be significantly below last year's level. As the economic improvement takes hold, we expect our group to show a further recovery in the second half year compared to the first half.</p>
          <p>Based on the economic background and the business figures in the first six months of the year, sales and earnings for 2009 at the same level of, as in the record year 2008, are however not more attainable. We confirm the target of our HPO program of 650 to &#x20AC;800 million gross cost savings between 2009 and 2012. The contribution in 2009 will be &#x20AC;200 million gross cost savings.</p>
          <p>For the Gases Division, we are also expecting a better business performance in the second half of 2009 than in the first six months of the year, based on the current economic recovery trends. However, this positive trend will not be sufficient to ensure that sales and earnings for the full year 2009 will reach the levels achieved in 2008.</p>
          <p>In the Engineering Division, the order backlog of more than &#x20AC;4 billion is a good basis for a relatively stable business performance in the coming 18 to 24 months. However, we assume that sales for the full year 2009 will remain below the high previous year figure. The target for our operating margin in this business remains at 8%. We are continuing to implement the strong focus and speed our group-wide measures to strengthen efficiency.</p>
          <p>With a targeted capacity adjustments and productivity improvements, we are ensuring that we get the maximum benefit for our business in whatever shape of recovery the global economy will finally be.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much for your attention. We are happy to answer your questions now. I hand over to the operator, Maria please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And our first question comes from Lawrence Sabra. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good afternoon. Just if could ask one question for now. You were talking a lot about the numbers excluding the restructuring charge, and I was just wondering if I do take out the restructuring charge, it looks like in Q2 your comparative consolidation EBITDA was a lot better than in Q1, down to 35 million from 44 million negative. And I was just wondering if this 35 million negative is a good basis going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it is &#x2013; this average number in the first half year excluding the restructuring charges, that's the run rate I would calculate with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from Jean De Watteville. Please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Jean De Watteville speaking. I will just stick to one question for the time being. It's, as you mentioned, Georg, impressive margins in the second quarter stripping out natural gas price effect, 80 basic points improvement. That has been achieved despite the fact that you had adverse operating leverage impact because of the poor volumes in the high fixed cost business, particularly cylinders but also liquid. And I was wondering if you're ready to share with us what was the negative impact from poor volumes in those merchant activity? And the reason I'm asking the question is obviously to understand when the volume will recover, should we add back that negative impact and so expect some further improvement, everything being equal, thanks to the volume recovery? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the answer is that we have experienced the double-digit volume decline roughly to give you an indication here. And I think this is something which we have experienced because of high base effect in the first half year of 2008. I think this is important to understand that if we look into the last year's development of sales and performance until the end of the third quarter in a way, we had very strong business performance, which is now visible in a decline in the first half year of 2009. So double-digit volume decline is what you should calculate this, a little bit more than 10%; we think it's around 12%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, sorry, my question was the operating leverage impact is on the margins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course. I mean we have some positive out of the volume decline because you understand that when you have some significant volume decline, you also shut down some of the weaker performed assets, let's say it that way. And when it turns back to full volume recovery, you switch off another ASU switch who do not have the same performance level as the average of the business. So I assume not all can be retrained, but most of that should be visible in the top &#x2013; in the bottom line of our margin improvement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So in other words, there is an adverse operating leverage, but there is also a mix improvement as you're switching off low productive ASUs, and therefore the net effect was not so material and we shouldn't expect a big swing back when the volume will come back, is that your answer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think, Jean, you know that this is a mix effect; this is what I tried to explain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think most of what we see is sustainable here, definitely, because we are working on the HPO program, which is an acceleration of what we had planned to do anything -- anyway. So from that perspective, that should remain. Nevertheless, I want to give you the indication that this is an average figure, also impacted by some weak performed assets in the structure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But that is the only point I want to make you aware of.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. That is very clear. Thank you for the answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Most of that should remain a bottom line because these are significant fixed cost savings we have implemented in the first half year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question comes from Markus Mayer. Please go ahead and announce your company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon gentlemen, Markus Mayer from UniCredit. A question on pricing and margins, in the BSF conference call, we've learned from the management that said it that currently are renegotiation their take-or-pay contract. Are you currently also in negotiation, and if so what do you expect for your margins in this distribution asset?</p>
          <p>And another thing <mark type="inaudible" /> said they are currently also in pricing negotiations, and say see that their end customers or for them it's much more difficult to fix the prices in quarters before, do you also see this and what are the effects you expect out of this?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your question. As we always say on the tonnage side, I think you hold the line in whatever environment. So of course we have discussed over the year as we have the bankruptcy issue, and Chapter 11 of Linder Bazel that we had in negotiations, for example, in the bankruptcy situation. Nevertheless, we are normally critical supplier in these situations, so we leverage our strong position here. So I can't confirm what you refer to the BSF discussion, but I was not part of that telephone call. Nevertheless, I can confirm that we had a strong tonnage contractual situation, so here no additional stress in the system.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the cylinder business, I think this is heavily linked to the market share positions you are in, in the different regions of the world. And as we explained, for example, in our last conference call, we have very, very strong market share positions in the merchant business where we have in a way an strong performance also now in the second quarter. So, of course, you can assume as longer the crisis will hold, as more difficult the situation can become, but at that point of time, we are proud of managing the situation in -- as it is in our strong market share situations like in South Pacific, for example, like in other parts of the world. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And we've got another question from Andrew Stott. Please go ahead; announce your company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Merrill Lynch. I had a few questions actually. Sorry I &#x2013; my fault; I missed the comment on cost savings, the schedule for this year. And if at all could you give guidance for 2010 and '11 as well, and the split in the cost savings as we go forward? The second question was, second-quarter margin in the South Pacific and Africa region was pretty impressive, I mean a huge improvement on Q1. Do we work with that Q2 number or is there anything specific in that?</p>
          <p>Third question was pricing, could you say what the contribution from pricing was in the quarter? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you, Andrew, for your questions. Regarding the ramp-up, I think you haven't missed anything here. As we always said, the gross cost savings is 650 to 800 million. I think we see an acceleration of that in the year 2009. Normally when we started that program, beginning of 2008, we assumed that we do not achieve 200 million gross cost saving in 2009 because of the structural initiatives we are in here. It's against the standardization of the processes as you know.</p>
          <p>We are in a way a patchwork of acquisitions of the last years, so it's clearly in standardization process, which will pay off at the end of the period; this means 2011, 2012 more strongly. Nevertheless, now of course we had some run rate effect of 200 million this year. That's I think the working number for us too, when we go into the next year's.</p>
          <p>Regarding South Pacific, this is an, as you said, insignificant margin improvement. Most of that is sustainable, but there is also one seasonal impact as we always say, related to the LPG business, which is from an southern hemisphere perspective, now winter times in South Pacific, as you know. So we are favoring in, in strong performance of the LPG business against that background. On the pricing side, I think we were very clear on the volume side now around 10 to 12% on the volume side, this means it's about around 3% pricing impact. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from Nobert Barth. Please announce your question and company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. Nobert Barth from WestLB speaking. Perhaps you have already a little bit discussed but perhaps can you go a little bit more in detail about your product segment: bulk, cylinder, healthcare and tonnage, what especially was the earnings situation? I know that we don't disclose it but perhaps you can elaborate a little bit on a qualitative basis? And also, if you would perhaps give an indication where the biggest price and volume impact was. It's clear it's in tonnage and so on, but also in the other lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you for your question, Nobert. I think you are rightly so that we do not disclose the earnings profile of the product areas for good reasons, because that is heavily linked to the regional setup of the different business mix in these regions. And as I pointed out already, especially in areas where we have a strong market share position, then merchant position is &#x2013; also from a productivity perspective on the stronger side. So from that perspective, most favorable developments we experienced in the second quarter is definitely the area in the southern hemisphere. So that's South Pacific, that's Africa, but also the impact of the Asian market and stabilization of the Eastern European market. I think this is all linked to the emerging market setup, plus South Pacific. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from Andrew Benson [Citigroup], please announce your company name. Andrew Benson, please go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We hear you now, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, I must have had the mute on, I apologize. I'm used to speaking to myself. Can you talk about your CapEx outlook in net debt movement? I mean it's gone up a bit <mark type="inaudible" /> exchange rates. Where do you think it will be at the year-end, where do you think you can drive it to? <mark type="inaudible" /> talked about the resurgence of interesting new tonnage, contracts from emerging regions during the course of the second quarter, and that gives them a degree of confidence for the outlook. Can you give us what you see is happening? And also, I know you haven't won a new business during the course of the second quarter, whether there is anything in the offering, and how that will allow your CapEx plans or your CapEx to develop in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think, I'll start with the CapEx guidance and the question related to the debt, and I'll then hand over to Aldo for the tonnage performance. On the CapEx side, as we said earlier and I think we stick to that, it's roughly &#x20AC;1.35 billion CapEx, which we expected for last year. This is against the strong &#x2013; as you pointed out, against the strong project pipeline on the tonnage side, and on all the projects about &#x20AC;10 million we presented to you. So from that perspective that is in strong development here. Next year depending on the situation now on the tonnage business, on the development which we experienced positively in the last quarter in some of the geographies in the emerging market, that question is open but most likely it could be slightly below that number at that stage. Nevertheless, we are confident <mark type="inaudible" /> against the background of the business as we see.</p>
          <p>Only to close the second question related to the debt, I think we experienced here a higher debt level in this quarter, because of the CapEx development. The high CapEx because of the currency movements &#x2013; with the currency movements, of course, one has to be very careful with the forecast here. Nevertheless, we assume a rather stable development over the next six months. Nevertheless the different currencies where we are in, there's still a strong volatility when we compare U.S. dollar and we compare pound, which is now stronger again, South African rand or Australian dollar. So the mix is neutral at that stage, but overall it has significant impact from a regional perspective. So assuming that this is stable then we would see a slight better net debt position at the end of the year, I think, because of the operating cash flow over the next six months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry; you said better than now or better than the end of '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please say again, Andrew, sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Better net debt than now or better net debt than the end of '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, it's better than now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so now I hand over to Dr. Belloni.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> Andrew, I think it's fair and easy to confirm the resurgence of tonnage opportunities in Q2, just because Q1, of course, was so bad and people were under shock. I can confirm that there is a high level of activity, of course in China and in India, and strangely even opportunity in the steel industry, refining, very few in chemistry. So I would put it in this order of, let's say, activity intensity. And basically I'd say that three quarters of the opportunities are in these two countries.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Now Matthias Cornu, please go ahead with your question and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. Matthias Cornu from Exane BNP Paribas. I had one question on debt. One contributory on short-term debt, could you give us more detail on the different lines you have there, what is rolling, what has to be repaid over the next six, 12 months? And do you expect to draw on your credit line to do so or issue maybe a new bond?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you for that question. I think as we've always said, I mean, this is from an overall perspective in 2009, we have refinanced a lot already at the end of 2008 with the two bonds in September and then in December. So there is no, in a way, obligation from an overall effect from an refinancing perspective. Nevertheless, we will make use of the market conditions opportunistically. Overall, we are very happy with our maturity profile, which has lengthened really significantly beyond 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And what is rolling basically in the 1.3 billion &#x2013; what could be renegotiated for the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have commercial papers, as you know, in that line, which is roughly &#x2013; I think now 800 million of that is the commercial paper. So this is more significant part out of the 1.3.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Neil Taylor. Please go ahead with your question and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. It's JPMorgan in London. On the joint venture numbers that you disclosed, the 37 million in the first half, could you just explain the mathematics around the full year guidance for 60? How that pans out over the remainder of the year?</p>
          <p>And then on the engineering business, I wonder if you would mind commenting on whether you were hoping to gain a piece of the business from the Shell contract, the floating LNG contract? And then finally, Dr. Belloni, I wonder if you could also perhaps comment on the new tonnage opportunities? And just talk a little bit around how you consider the overall quality of the assets which you will be supplying in a, sort of, longer term structural context when you consider tendering for business? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start with the joint venture question and the net income &#x2013; and the share of the net income in the joint venture spectrum. As you know, Neil, the net income is somewhat volatile number, so we are here little bit more careful with the guidance because we experienced also in the past of the bigger schemes some more volatile net income impact. So overall the fixed EPS and adjusted number for one impact out of our Pemex scheme in Mexico. I think this is the biggest scheme in the net income section from the perspective of revenue recognition. So from that perspective, if I adjust debt and I only take the run rate impact from the strong performance of the Chinese joint ventures then the 60 would be the right number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Your first question was dealing with this announcement made by Shell. Of course, we made public couple of years ago that we are interested and we are developing a concept for floating LNG. And yes, of course, the Shell opportunity was considered. However, since the very beginning it was clear to us that the size of the floating facility envisaged by Shell was much larger than the size of the model &#x2013; the standard model that Linde has developed together with SBN and therefore we are excluded by this tender.</p>
          <p>With regard to the criteria which we adopt in order to select or concentrate our efforts on tonnage. Of course, the first criteria is the industry segment, we of course, wish to increase our engagement, for instance, in the energy sector.</p>
          <p>This is the number one at the moment where we're focusing in order to cater for the long-term sustainability of this type of business. Then we look at the geography, of course, we try to avoid cluster risk as much as we can. And we favor emerging markets. And at the end of the day we look at the site and the customer to see how this target prospect is fair in comparison to its peers, of course. These are the general criteria which we use in order to focus our efforts.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's very helpful. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter Clark, please announce your company name and go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's SoGen [Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale]. Georg, quick one on the cylinder business, you alluded to &#x2013; the volume is remaining under pressure in some areas. I mean in cylinders obviously the sales &#x2013; the underlying sales year-on-year about double the decline as the first quarter. Now, I know year-on-year obviously you were facing a very stiff comparison, particularly in terms of I think pricing and things like specialty gases were going through the roof. Just wondering what's happening in the cylinder line in terms of the sort of volume price progression as you can skew on when you look year-on-year within &#x2013; again probably most focused on Europe? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think overall, of course, as you pointed out rightly, we see the base effect out of 2008, I'm repeating I know but it's an important part of the comparison over the quarters. So from that perspective we are experiencing a volume decline year-on-year because of the prices and then stronger development, also until end of September in the last year which we experienced. So, from that perspective, you can assume that this is an double-digit decline as you know.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, the important part I think here is what we always said when it comes to the crisis impact, rental is holding up nicely. In a way it's overall even growing. From this perspective, so if you add that together then you can say, of course, Europe &#x2013; Western Europe is impacted harsh by the crisis in the cylinder business. But also here rental is a very stable component in the cylinder business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question comes from Tony Jones [Redburn]. Please announce your company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. This is from Redburn. Just a quick question about your project pipeline for gases. Could you give us an update please in terms of how this sort of competitive landscape is looking at the movement and how tenders are actually working? And I heard back from a couple of your competitors that because the market is becoming increasingly geared to sort of emerging market, bid pressure is forcing some of the pricing a little bit down and just whether that might have an impact on the return on capital in the long-term anyway?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I hand over to Aldo here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Yes. Well, as I said one of the previous questions, the number of opportunities that are definitely decreased and this mathematically implies that there is enhanced competition. We have to negotiate quite harder with regard not only to prices, but also terms and condition profile. I think the market discipline is still there. And of course, given our self-imposed constraints on CapEx, we are also very selective, which is of course is maintaining the margin and the returns as in the past.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just as a quick follow-up then, does that mean over the long-term, we'd expect to see slightly lower growth than we might expect just to preserve profitability?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that, we have just to increase our yield in success rate for our projects.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question comes from Rhian Tucker. Please go ahead with your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Rhian Tucker from Credit Suisse in London. A very quick question on the where we're pushing on some time now? Of the 17 tonnage projects that are due to start up in 2009, how many do you have yet to start in the second half? And what kind of quarterly pattern are we going to see in those? Or is it possible that some of them could still be pushed into 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Rhian, I think, as we explained that is in the presentation, including the joint venture start-ups. So what we have experienced and you saw that in the share of the net income development, we are experiencing a ramp-up in the first half, especially in the joint venture section. And as we always said 2010 will be stronger from an top line visibility than 2009 because of that. I do not expect that there is a product further postponement into the year 2010 because we were through that adjustment now already a couple of months and we haven't seen a further delay into the years to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So you won't give us a number of how many JVs started up in the first half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think overall it's an figure which we do not disclose at that point of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ana Daveva, please go ahead with your question and announce you company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon. Ana Daveva from BHF Bank. I am just wondering &#x2013; on the HPO program, which you've been alluding to for a couple of time. Can you give us an indication as to what has actually been achieved in the &#x2013; for we know the first quarter &#x2013; but in the second quarter of the HPO program?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think what we have seen and that is a clear acceleration of the program. So we have an stronger impact in the second quarter compared to the first quarter. Also because of, first, a restructuring mitigation effort really came through in the second quarter. If you have the run rate of 200 million, you take 100 in the first half year, 100 in the second half year then you have, I would say, an split of two-thirds, one-third roughly against the first quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And our next question comes from Karan Khemani. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Karan Khemani from Cazenove in London. Just in terms of your exposure to contract that will have to be accounted for under IAS 17 as a result of IFRS 4. Is the exposure limited to &#x20AC;118 million for this year, or could further contracts in your backlog be identified over the coming years that have to be accounted as embedded financial leases? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think this is a very detailed question, now we have in the back-half of the presentation on page 24 the total year impact which we expect roughly 118 million negative on sales and EBITDA because as year sale, half of that 64 million in the first half year, last year, 63 million this year. So I think if there is no extraordinary development you can double that in a way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. No, that's very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And Jean De Watteville has a follow-up question. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi, it's again Jean De Watteville from Nomura. Question on engineering please. Dr. Belloni, you said at the start of the year that you were quite optimistic about maintaining a good volume of order intake in '09, because you had obviously large contracts under negotiation. And I remember in the last conference call you talked particularly in petrochemicals. Obviously, we've seen that with the Baruth contract signed just at the back-end of Q2. I was wondering if you can give us some -- an update of what you have in your book right now under negotiation. Do you still believe that you have other large contracts in <mark type="inaudible" /> that could be achieved? And you shared with us a figure of 2.5 billions order intake for 2009 as being achievable. Do you still believe that what you have under negotiation that you can still make 2.5 billions order intake this year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Jean, your question is very intimate and I'm not going to disclose the names of the contracts we are negotiating. You are right that I alluded that this was &#x2013; at the March press conference that there are still number of indiscernible] opportunities available. I think the petrochemical pipeline at the moment is quite empty. I think that we have exhausted the bulk of gas that we had a exhausted that. Don't forget that we at the end of 2008, secured also the naphtha cracker in India. So in the matter of less than six months, Linde has booked two major polythene contracts, which is actually outstanding results. Now we are focused more on natural gas processing and other energy-related projects. I think that the volume is there, whether we will be successful and reach the 2.5 billion order intake is &#x2013; I can't give you a guarantee of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow-up on natural gas processing technologies, historically you used to be strong in small to mid size plants in cold countries. Is that still your domain of expertise or you have broaden your product offering in that domain?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your memory is really outstanding. Well that comment was related to LNG. Now the natural gas processing project, I'm referring to now, these are different projects, these are de-sulfurization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>NGL extraction. And these projects are very large. They are primarily in the Middle East or in Mexico or the Northern part of South America. So there we have a full portfolio. We have no restrictions in terms of size or climate and support.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, very useful. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Matthias Cornu. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Matthias Cornu again from Exane. Dr. Belloni, you mentioned before on your contract that you have less opportunities in chemicals. I just wonder if you can make any comments on the existing business? And have you seen any clients in chemicals or maybe in steel shutting down definitely capacities? Or do you see that as a coming risk due to the restructuring that have been announced by a number of your clients?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, everybody has read about, say, at least temporary closures of plants. Many plants have been mothballed and very few of them have been re-commissioned. Some announcement has been made of, let's say, final shutdowns &#x2013; or overcapacity has been removed from the, let's say, egoistic perspective of engineering contractor. This is not bad, because this capacity will come again, but not at the same size. So there is a shift &#x2013; a major shift towards countries with hydrocarbon resources or countries with a large domestic demand, like China, for instance. So I think that the announcement by a big chemical company to, let's say, remove capacity from, for instance, U.K. or North American sites is not necessarily bad news.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. It's very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Markus Mayer. Please announce your company name and go ahead with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Markus Mayer again from UniCredit. A follow-up on engineering. Can you remember how much project engineering are currently delayed, and if you have seen already cancellations <mark type="inaudible" /> conference call? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I cannot confirm that. I think that now, the projects which are still underway are so robust they have survived their first and the second wave of let's say financial shock. At the moment actually I have customers offering money to accelerate some projects we have under construction. So I think that there is more confidence or let's say the quality of the projects which are still under execution is very high.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew Stott, please go ahead with your question, and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Merrill Lynch; again thanks. Pension cash cost, is your previous guidance still hold, it's just I noticed that provision had gone up on the balance sheet? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think what we experienced of course is that the pension development against the yearend 2008 was weaker in quarter one than in quarter two. I think from a cash perspective, I think this is as you know sometimes quarterly driven, it's not all over the year. You'll see the details in our half-year results in the development of the cash flow statement. I would deal with this on a half-year basis and multiply that by two if you want to pluck a number, but it's not only driven by the quarterly equalization.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's okay. So I can use your first half as a base?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I have no number for you here, Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question comes from Glenna Strome. Please go ahead and announce your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hello. Good afternoon. It's actually Virginie Boucher-Ferte from Deutsche Bank in London. I've got two quick questions, please. First of all, in tonnage, could you please say, how have your operating rates developed in Q2 versus Q1 compared to your take-up level? And what has been the sequential developments for the quarter, let's say April compared to June?</p>
          <p>And the second question on pricing, a follow-up one. I understand that merchant and cylinder pricing those depend on market share positions and how economic conditions develop. I'm assuming further recovery in H2 as you state in your outlook, could you please give an idea of the level of year-on-year pricing development you are expecting in H2 versus H1 unbalanced in merchant and cylinder, especially as I guess that some of that has already been agreed with your customers? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, I will start with capacity utilization question and Georg would follow suit with pricing question. We have capacity utilization only for tonnage, by the way. I mean, I am talking about pipeline contracts which is now as we speak between minus 10 and minus 15% as opposed to previous year. And with regards to the sequential development, we have improved by let's say five to seven points against Q1. And now Georg with <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the development on the pricing side is, of course, positive influence by our initiatives at the end of last year. I think we were implementing price initiatives pre the crisis, so we are participating from that as long as the crisis will hold on, you see this also with the competition that the price effect is in this quarter with the comparison a little bit smaller compared to the previous quarter.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, as I said earlier, we have especially in the merchant area, a very positive rental impact on the cylinder side, which is holding up very nicely and developing nicely. So it's very difficult to forecast.</p>
          <p>Of course, we try to implement pricing initiatives in areas like, for example, South Africa, where we have high inflations; here we are catching up significantly. This is true for South America too. But overall I am a little bit more cautious on the pricing side until the end of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And Markus Mayer got another question, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Markus Mayer, again from UniCredit. Last question from my side. On your rental business, are there any customers giving back their cylinders or from this side no change of the business yet, that's over?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I think what I try to point out and I repeated that there is positive trend on the rental side, so it's really a plus number on a global basis. So, from that perspective you can understand that probably customers keep their cylinders even if they do have lower business activity, and overall trend beside that is not visible in the number. So, only a positive rental trend is visible in the cylinder numbers on the global basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, perfect. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And there are no more questions present at this time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>So, if there are no further questions, thank you for the participation in the call and looking forward to our next discussion at the end of quarter three. Bye, bye. Have a good time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation. This concludes today's conference and you may now disconnect your lines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>