<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1474729" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-05-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9099</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Dominik Heger</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="CFO, Director-Human Resources &amp; Employment">Georg Denoke</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS AG (Broker)">Thomas Gilbert</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura International Plc">Jean G. de Watteville</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Commerzbank AG (Broker)">Stephan Kippe</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep" affiliation="Member-Executive Board">Aldo E. Belloni</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Andrew G. Benson</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs International Ltd.">Rakesh Patel</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA (UK)">Peter A. Clark</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. International Plc">Peter J. Mackey</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="MainFirst Bank AG (Brokerage)">Thomas Swoboda</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Linde Analyst Call for the Results of the First Quarter of 2012. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode, until we conduct a question-and-answer session and instructions will be given at that time. Just to remind you, this conference call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>I would now like to hand over to the Head of Investor Relations of Linde Group, Dr. Dominik Heger.</p>
          <p>Please begin your meeting, sir, and I'll be standing by.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. This is Dominik Heger from Investor Relations. Thank you for joining this early call for our three months results. Georg Denoke, Member of the Executive Board and CFO will be hosting the call and Professor Aldo Belloni, Member of the Executive Board will also be available for your questions.</p>
          <p>I kindly would like to make you aware of the fact that today our Annual General Meeting will take place. Therefore the call is limited to slightly less than one hour. I thank you in advance for your understanding. I will now hand over to Georg Denoke and after his presentation, you will have the opportunity to address your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you, Dominik. Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. From my side also a warm welcome to our three months results conference call. I would like to apologize, especially to the US colleagues for the early morning call. As already mentioned by Dominik, our timeframe for this call is limited. I will focus on key slides to have enough time for your questions. I open my presentation with a quick overview of Linde's performance in the first three months of this year on page three.</p>
          <p>Overall the profitable growth trend is intact despite the recent more volatile macroeconomic environment. Our focus on the megatrends, growth markets, energy and environment and healthcare is paying off and is offering structural growth potential in our core businesses.</p>
          <p>With &#x20AC;3.5 billion, our group sales increased by 5.4%, while the operating profit grew by 6.2% to &#x20AC;808 million. This equals the group margin of 23.1%, which is 20 basis points higher than the same period of 2011.</p>
          <p>This performance resulted in earnings per share of &#x20AC;1.68 and adjusted for the allocation of the purchase price of BOC of &#x20AC;1.89, both are slightly up against quarter one of 2011. If we had adjusted for the one-time effects included in the EPS figures of 2011, the EPS growth would have been double-digit.</p>
          <p>Please be reminded that the referenced one-time effects in quarter one 2011 were the early repayment of the vendor loan related to the 2007 sale of BOC Edwards and the change to the pension scheme in UK. I will come back to this topic during the call.</p>
          <p>In the Gases division, solid growth in all markets contributed to the performance, compared to the quarter one of last year, the operating margin in the Gases division improved by 20 basis points to 27.5%. Based on the performance, we reinforced our outlook of growth in sales and operating profit compared to the record year 2011. We also reconfirmed our full commitment to our HPO approach, which we expect to result in &#x20AC;650 million to &#x20AC;800 million gross cost savings by the end of this year.</p>
          <p>I'll start the detailed look at the performance by division on slide four. Gases sales increased by 7.3% to &#x20AC;2.9 billion. On a comparable basis, sales grew by 4.1%, this shows the underlying growth trend with continued growth in all regions. We have seen the strongest growth in our product area Bulk.</p>
          <p>The Engineering division is as expected with growth in sales of 1.7% to &#x20AC;601 million, roughly on the same level as in the prior year period. The order intake was dominated by orders from the Middle East as well as from Asia. The order backlog has further increased to &#x20AC;3.7 billion. We will see now on slide five, the growth of the group operating profit; as already mentioned the group operating profit grew by 6.2% in the reporting period.</p>
          <p>Those divisions contributed to this positive development. The Gases division achieved an increase in operating profit of 7.8% in the first three months. At the same time, the operating margin improved by 20 basis points to 27.5%.</p>
          <p>The Engineering division contributed again with the strong operating profit development. We saw an increase of 17.7%. In our last conference call, we gave the margin guidance for 2012 of at least 10%. With 12.1% in the reporting period, the margin in the Engineering division is at a high level. This strong profitability was driven, in particular by the successful execution of a number of individual projects.</p>
          <p>Please, let me remind you that 2011 figure of others and consolidation includes a positive one-time effect &#x20AC;16 million. As mentioned, this effect resulted from changes made to the UK pension plan.</p>
          <p>I'll give a more detailed picture of our Gases division and move on to page six, which shows our sales bridge. As outlined, before the underlying price and volume effect for the reporting period was 4.1%. This does not even include our strong contribution from joint venture activities, which would result in an increase of 4.8%. The contribution from currency effects is positive with 2.4%.</p>
          <p>The sales impact from the pass-through of higher natural gas prices was 0.7% also slightly positive and had its major impact in the reporting segment Asia-Pacific.</p>
          <p>On the slide seven, you can see the comparable growth by product area. Comparable growth excludes currency effect and natural gas price impacts. The performance of the individual product areas confirms the overall steady trends in the Gases division. We achieved with 6.4% our highest growth rate in Bulk. We increased revenues by 3% in the product area Cylinder. The product area Tonnage increased by 3%. As indicated, we have seen strong growth in our joint ventures. Joint venture activities included, the growth rate would increase to 5.7%.</p>
          <p>As already mentioned in our full-year results call, the start-ups are rather in the second half than in the first half of 2012. In addition, we had some plant shutdowns in the first three months of this year. Healthcare continued to give a robust performance with revenue growth of 4%.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, I will go a bit deeper into the details of our operating segments, and will start with Europe, Middle East, Africa. The economic development in EMEA in the first quarter was, as expected, lower than last year. Due to our low exposure in Southern Europe and in general favorable geographic footprint in Europe, we achieved revenue growth of 3.7%, which was 3.3% on a comparative basis.</p>
          <p>We succeeded in winning major orders and in paving the way for the acquisition of the Continental European Homecare business of Air Products. For this acquisition, we received full clearance by the European Commission and we are able to execute it at the end of April.</p>
          <p>The most prominent example of onsite project wins in the last quarter was the agreement to supply onsite gases to Sadara petroleo chemical company in Jubail, Saudi Arabia. We will invest US$380 million to supply products to the joint venture between the Saudi Aramco and Dow Chemical.</p>
          <p>For the supply of carbon monoxide, hydrogen and ammonia at one of the world's largest chemical complexes. Linde's Engineering Division will design, supply and build the new gases plant on Sadara's site in this important petrochemical cluster. The scheme is planned to come onstream in 2015.</p>
          <p>The next operating segment is Asia-Pacific. Here, we realized revenue growth of 14.3% in the first three months of 2012. On a comparative basis, the increase was 4.8%. The growth was impacted by stagnating demand in the market for electronic gases. Revenue trends during the reporting period were also affected by planned shutdowns.</p>
          <p>We have seen a softening of the growth trend in Asia in the fourth quarter of 2011, which also continued in the first two months of this year. But already in March, we have seen strong growth in Greater China. We also achieved revenue growth in the other regions of the operating segment.</p>
          <p>In the on-site business, we received a number of new contracts in the first quarter of 2012.I would like to mention one example; we will supply gases to the chemical company Dahua Group at its site in Dalian in North Eastern China. Under this &#x20AC;70 million on-site contract, we will de-captivate two existing air separation units and will construct a new air separation plant with production capacity of 38,000 normal cubic meters of oxygen per hour, which will replace the old plants and will supply additional product to meet the rising demand. The new Air separation unit will also produce liquefied gases for the regional gases market.</p>
          <p>I move on to the operating segment Americas. In Americas, we achieved revenue growth of 7.8%, which is on a comparable basis an increase of 5.9%. In North America, the improvement in the general economic situation also resulted in higher demand for industrial gases.</p>
          <p>We saw above average trends in Tonnage and Cylinder especially in the Canadian market. As a result of relatively robust economic trends, we achieved double-digit growth in South America and solid growth in North America. On page nine, the profitability of our operating segment is outlined.</p>
          <p>Also here I start with EMEA. The operating profit increased by 4.8%, this resulted in an operating margin of 28.7%. This is a further increase by 30 basis points, which was supported by our HPO program. Asia-Pacific was up 11.2%. This resulted in an operating margin of 27% compared to last year, it has to be taken into account that the pass through of increase in natural gas prices has an adverse effect.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, we continue to invest in future structure growth in the region. You might know that we have currently projects under execution in Asia-Pacific, which has a value of around &#x20AC;1.5 billion. Therefore, we employ new staffs in the rapidly expanding Asian markets, especially in China.</p>
          <p>I will move on to Americas. Here, the operating profit rose by 11.8% supported by higher capacity utilization in all product areas. At 24.3%, the operating margin exceeded the figure for the first three months of 2011 by 90 basis points supported by our HPO initiatives.</p>
          <p>In general, I would like to point out that the standardization and productivity improvement within our HPO program contributes to the margin development in all operating segment.</p>
          <p>Please turn to slide 10 to see the latest figures of our engineering division. In the first quarter of 2012, we achieved 1.7% sales increase as expected and as already outlined, an increase of the operating profit margin to 12.1%. The order intake increased by 70.9% to &#x20AC;759 million. This development was also fueled by the Tonnage contract wins in the Gases division.</p>
          <p>It underpins the Tonnage growth strategy of Linde and the synergetic setup of our two divisions, Engineering and Gases. The strong order intake has contributed to the increase of our solid order backlog. It now stands at &#x20AC;3.695 billion. This positive trend was due in particular to the already mentioned major contract in Saudi Arabia.</p>
          <p>The order intake was characterized not only by this substantial project, but also as in previous quarters by a number of small and medium-sized new orders. These also include several projects won by Linde subsidiary Cryostar from South Korean shipyards as well as the project win in the market for the efficient exploitation of shale gas reserves in North America.</p>
          <p>Let me move on to our unchanged outlook on page 11, based on the current economic forecasts, our objective is to continue to achieve increases in Group sales and operating profit. I have outlined in the beginning that we reconfirmed the target range of &#x20AC;650 million to &#x20AC;800 million gross cost savings of our HPO initiatives until the end of this year.</p>
          <p>For the Gases division, we expect further financial year 2012, a slower growth rate than last year, and a stronger growth in the second half. You have seen over the last year, our productivity improvement track record and to be continue with this focus. We assume growth in Bulk and Cylinder business to be in line with the macroeconomic trends, and also based on our focus on gas applications.</p>
          <p>On top of this, the growth will be driven by the strong footprint in the growth markets and in healthcare by the contributions of our acquisitions of the Continental European Homecare business of Air Products.</p>
          <p>Please let me remind you that we gave for 2012, the CapEx guidance for the Gases division of around &#x20AC;1.8 billion, with this, we will be above our historic average of the last year's of 13% CapEx sales ratio.</p>
          <p>As you know, we anticipate for the Engineering division to achieve the same level of sales as in 2011 and an operating margin of at least 10%.</p>
          <p>For 2014, we plan to achieve on group level an operating profit of at least &#x20AC;4 billion. We intend to further grow the adjusted return on capital employed to 14% or higher. The growth will be supported by continuous ramp-ups out of our very strong project pipeline of new on-site contract wins.</p>
          <p>For the Gases division, the average CapEx sales ratio shall be 13% with the plus added for potential large scale projects in the megatrend energy and environment. This megatrend as well as the megatrend's growth markets and healthcare have offered and will offer structured growth potential. With our synergetic Gases and Engineering divisions, we have the right setup regarding technology, local market shares and customer contracts.</p>
          <p>As you know, our ambition is to outperform the market with our revenue increase, further strengthen our profile as a resilient company, and at the same time remain fully focused on our journey to become a high-performance organization.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention. We will be happy to take your questions now. Operator, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from the line of Thomas Gilbert. Please go ahead with your question, announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>UBS. Good morning. Good morning, Georg. Good morning, Dominik. Three quick ones. The gross &#x2013; you said that gross rate in Gases in the second half going to be above the first half. Does your comment exclude the acquisition of Homecare business and their products so are we talking underlying growth here?</p>
          <p>Second question. Corporate costs in the first quarter 60 million, somewhat higher than what I was looking &#x2013; just looking for guidance for the full-year or for a quarterly run rate?</p>
          <p>And then thirdly in your slide that you used to have a slide with a number start-ups in the Tonnage business &#x2013; so one, two years out that's not there. Can you just remind us how many start-ups this year was for H1 versus H2 and whether anything has been cancelled or slipped into 2013? Thanks for taking these three questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. Thomas, thank you for your questions. I think definitely the guidance stronger second half compared to first half is more volume oriented guidance based up on what we expect from an macro economical development in these markets in GDP and IP in the different end markets. So it's of course &#x2013; on top of that, you will see the impact of the consolidation of the acquired healthcare business in Europe for AP.</p>
          <p>The other part is I think when you look in to the quarterly performance of our corporate costs then you really have to have in mind that, first of all when you compare that you have pension impact also in the previous &#x2013; in the previous quarter 2011 and when we talk about the number, I think it is as it was in our last full-year's call, around 180 million for the year, which we expect at that moment in time.</p>
          <p>When we look into the pipeline development, there is of course, one major change, which is beyond 2014 in our pipeline, which is the Sadara win. I think this is something which you have heard about. In the other columns, therefore we haven't put it in the backup, and thought that we save little bit of time from today's perspective. There is no change, no cancellation in the pipeline we presented at the year-end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just on the H2 versus H1 split this year, so 60% of startups in the second year or 65%? Just how much is the skew H2, H1 on the startups?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think when you want to compare that it's difficult. What we disclosed, therefore, I don't come up now with new numbers to discuss this. I think we had an impact of 750 million investments coming on stream. Total investment amount from a project perspective in 2012. In 2013, we had 650 million and in 2014, we disclosed that number already last time with 550 million.</p>
          <p>So it is &#x2013; I think the main part and that is of course a disadvantage that we can't consolidate these joint ventures. The real growth in quarter one was visible in the big scheme in Abu Dhabi, the Mirfa scheme where we have seen gas recovery based on nitrogen where we had some significant growth. If we would add that up, you would see really the stronger growth in on-site. Therefore, from operational perspective you could argue, there is growth in the system, but from a consolidated perspective I think you have what we discussed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Jean De Watteville. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi good morning, Jean De Watteville, Nomura. My first question is on cash flow, working capital outflow has been higher than my forecast for the first quarter and that is despite the fact that you had a pretty good quarter in terms of order intake in Engineering, which usually coupled with pre-payments.</p>
          <p>So I am wondering, if you can share with us some explanation particularly comments about the seasonality factors in Gases, comments about any pension related charges in Q1 and for the rest of the year? And lastly, for the pre-payment in engineering, is there a delay on the payments you expect. So that is the first question.</p>
          <p>Second question is pricing, can you add any color on the price trends for Cylinders and Bulk if possible by region? What is the trend? Is there improvement and any figure would appreciated.</p>
          <p>And lastly, just can you help me to re-quantify &#x2013; I don't think you have given that recently, you obviously at Linde have some oil related businesses like the LPG in Australia and LNG now in Sweden, can you quantify how big is the business, right now? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks Jean for your questions. Related to cash flow, I think it's important to understand that you have much more internal orders. Also when we talk about the big project, for example, now in Saudi Arabia that's for us the first big Tonnage scheme in Saudi Arabia, therefore it's internal. So the pre-financing effect when you say that we get prepayments &#x2013; you get prepayments of course in the systems through the Gases entity into Linde Engineering, but from a consolidation perspective that's of course for the group neutral.</p>
          <p>So you see an impact, which is a kind of synergy we were talking about since a longer period of time that we want to grow our Tonnage business based on our successful Engineering division and that's an impact which you see in cash flow, because you have at the moment less third-party prepayments in the system. This is the biggest impact on the change of operating cash flow. Of course, besides the vendor loan issue, which we explained already, which was around 60 million that is the other deviation of quarter one 2011 comparison.</p>
          <p>Gases in itself is very positive development, so there's nothing negative to be reported.</p>
          <p>The second part on the pricing and volume discussion, I think overall, I think we have seen a very strong pricing continuation of quarter four &#x2013; in quarter one what was expected, I think also from yield side. From a volume perspective, I think we have to give you some visibility within the quarter, so we had a rather soft start in January, February, and we have seen a very strong March from a development perspective. And that is also true, related to the PGP business, the Packaged Gases business and the merchant business and the Cylinder in regions.</p>
          <p>So, from an European perspective, if I give you some guidance, we have seen, first of all, in all regions we're PGP positive. For all operating segments, we saw positive volume and pricing effects in our Cylinder business, but with a stronger component in pricing than in volume. That is I think what I really can disclose to you.</p>
          <p>From an LPG, LNG perspective, from a volume business that we have in South America &#x2013; sorry in South Africa, a stronger LPG business and we have in South Pacific a stronger LPG business. And then we have started in Nordic, of course with our LNG business. And if we would like to disclose the number, I think it is as we said, in the last calls from an year-end perspective, I would say somewhere between 300 million to 400 million on a yearly basis from an overall perspective. That's I think what we disclosed at that moment in time based on that segmentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Very clear. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Stephan Kippe. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Stephan Kippe from Commerzbank, two questions. If I'm not mistaken, I've seen that the comparable growth rate in Gases is below Q4 levels in Q1. Could you please, maybe elaborate a bit about what the main contributor was, maybe a base effect from a better Q1 or is the volume development or other factors that played into that sequential slight deterioration? And maybe you &#x2013; given that you said that volumes in March were better maybe give us an outlook where you expect that growth rate should be in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>And secondly, you mentioned in the Engineering and new project in connection with US shale gas market, could you please give some more light on &#x2013; shed some more light on that in terms of what you expect from that market where &#x2013; what the percentage of these contracts are maybe, currently in your order backlog? And what your expectation is in terms of engineering from that shale gas trend are?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you for the questions. I think, when we look into the sequential development and some of that is answered in my previous answer to the question of the development of the quarter. It's really that the start was softer from an global economy perspective in January and February, and we have seen a very strong March &#x2013; if not to say even the strongest March, I would say ever.</p>
          <p>So from that perspective that is influencing the whole situation, but overall, I think the main consideration from my perspective is we have seen very strong growth in the Tonnage business, which is not in the top line. I think this is something you have to understand. This does not mean that there is no growth in the system. Only we are not able to consolidate that business. But it's in a way doubling the Tonnage growth when you take into consideration the big scheme in Abu Dhabi, which I was mentioning.</p>
          <p>So from that perspective, I think you shouldn't be &#x2013; let's say distorted by the consolidated number, which is a little bit softer. I agree, but if you really put the context what we have seen in joint venture development, then it would be in line with the quarter four.</p>
          <p>It's more that &#x2013; the turning point is different. Quarter four was going south month-by-month, yes, better October, November, December and then we had a plateau building on January, February and March is coming a bit strong and that is I think the point that the other is really more the capacity allocation, which is visible top line and which is in joint ventures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you. And....</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. The other point, which I could add is that there were some planned shutdowns in Tonnage as I mentioned in the speech that is of course impacting also a little the visibility at that moment. For the shale gas question I hand over to, Aldo.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning from my side as well. The shale gas business in North America for Linde Engineering is related to our subsidiary in Tulsa, Oklahoma, where we are since decades using a special process named Cryo-Plus, which is very apt for the recovery of NGL, it means C2+ hydrocarbons from the shale gas. The shale gas is particularly heavy, so it's very important that prior to feed this gas into pipelines, these heavier hydrocarbons are removed or recovered.</p>
          <p>We started selling these packages in the second half of 2010 and since we have maintained a very robust pace. These are order intakes between $60 million, $80 million up to $120 million each and the accumulated backlog so far from this business is somewhere around $400 million.</p>
          <p>But of course, it is also &#x2013; further induced shale gas business, which we are starting to develop and we see very encouraging signals, out of these C2+ streams of course there is a very important petrochemical boost in North America; new ethylene projects are being launched or new ethylene furnaces are being added to existing plants to make use of this C2 components, and we are very successful in this field this way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question comes from the line of Andrew Benson. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Citi. Thank you. Can you just to start by I probably got in late; I didn't hear, just a couple of little qualifiers. Can you just dimensionalize the one-offs in the first quarter of last year; how significant they were, and also the &#x2013; your bought some plants, I didn't catch where that was.</p>
          <p>I also didn't understand, perhaps it's just too early in the morning, they asked &#x2013; Thomas's question on the bias of the growth from the Tonnage in the second half versus the first half. And also can you just dimensionalize the impact of &#x2013; you talked a about lot of planned shutdowns in the first quarter as well, just a sort of qualifiers please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you for the questions. Again, I think the one-times are based on two facts; mainly one is the pension scheme, which was &#x20AC;60 million in the first quarter and then &#x20AC;30 million in the financing result through the BOC vendor loan, which we received through the disposal of the BOC Edwards healthcare business last year in the first quarter. These were the main important one-times out of 2011</p>
          <p>The second part related to the development of the Tonnage schemes, I referred to the slide which we had in our quarter four pack where you saw the very strong pipeline of opportunities which we have in 2012 with &#x20AC;750 million; from a project volume perspective 2013, &#x20AC;650 million; and 2014, &#x20AC;550 million. That is the basis for the strong development where say this is a very strong growth which we foresee especially in the upcoming years in Tonnage. We never had a bigger pipeline as we have it today from a Tonnage development perspective.</p>
          <p>2012 is a little bit &#x2013; from the perspective of top line visibility, unbalanced. Because the big scheme in Abu Dhabi would have now of course in great full effect on a quarterly basis, which is not top line visible. This was something I was referring to and which is in a way doubling visibility of percentage in first quarter. So it's not 3%, it's rather 6% through that scheme coming onstream. And the other part is that we have and we'll see some more schemes coming on stream in the second half than in the first half. This is what we were discussing. So I hope that helps.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. But is it &#x2013; I mean Thomas said was it two-thirds or one-thirds. I just didn't get the answer I mean I...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I didn't answer it. That was the point so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. I get it. Okay. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So you didn't miss it. I didn't answer it specifically.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So from that perspective there is nothing unclear. From a shutdown perspective, Yes, we had shutdowns in the first quarter which were impacting a little bit the onsite growth from a top line visibility.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But is that about &#x20AC;10 million, &#x20AC;20 million effect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That &#x2013; around.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Rakesh Patel. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there, from Goldman Sachs. Just a couple of questions, if I may? Those orders in the Tonnage statement, I wondered if you could give us some idea of the impact of the shutdown that you had in? How that compared relative to last year?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, I think in February, you talked about 400 million coming from the impact of shale gas in the Engineering division, since I think around 2009. I just wondered, if you could give us some idea of the growth rates that you saw in Q1 and how we should think about growth in that particular part of the business going forward? Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think to your &#x2013; really to your first question related to the shutdown impact in onsite, I think the number, which was mentioned earlier as the question &#x20AC;10 million to &#x20AC;20 million is a good ballpark; it's rather at the lower end than on the higher end. I think this is what you can expect.</p>
          <p>From a shale gas perspective, I think the growth rate is significant. It started not in 2009 really for us, it started in 2010, in the first quarter in a way and then in each of the quarters following, we had order intake and that is a kind of, of course technology, which we have, but which &#x2013; if we would specifically link that to the shale gas component then the growth rate is of course enormous, because we start from zero.</p>
          <p>And that is today more order backlog than say it's visibility and as Dr. Belloni said the around &#x20AC;400 million is a number, which is in order backlog number really from the perspective and we expect continuation also in 2011 because after the heavy investments in the shale gas fields, of course, the companies really want to harvest what they have in this &#x2013; in the upcoming development of these fields. So from that perspective, we expect a further continuation of that trend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Peter Clark. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, it's Peter Clark from SG. Two actually, I'm going to follow on from the shale gas, just going down a step looking at manufacturing the general industrial market because Praxair particularly are very vocal saying there's been a real kicker to the recovery here from the lower energy price and they are seeing a lot of production moving back in from emerging markets, all CapEx decision is coming back to the US</p>
          <p>Just wondering, is that something you're already seeing perhaps in negotiations, you mentioned ethylene as an example somewhere there, but just from a general manufacturing; the kicker that's coming in there and if you're seeing it in negotiations in the portfolio?</p>
          <p>And then also on HPO, I think we were running at &#x20AC;630 million in the first quarter &#x2013; early first quarter, I just wonder, you're clearly in the guidance range for the full-year, just wondering, if you've got an updated number for where we stand today? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think &#x2013; well, Peter you were specifically asking in a way about the North American development and we discussed this also in the full-year call. I think what we see from a perspective of investments downstream chemical activities coming back into the US; we saw employee statistics going up, strongest growth last year in the chemical business in the North American footprint.</p>
          <p>So we will participate from that, of course, especially from our opportunity in the first step in Engineering as we disclosed that based on shale and then probably there is some additional downstream chemical opportunities that's very clear.</p>
          <p>We are participating from a shale gas perspective also in the volumes of, for example nitrogen CO2, which are used for the fracking in some of the locations. And when we then talk about the broader manufacturing footprint I think we have to differentiate a little bit because some of that is also related to the packaged gases business and here we don't have the footprint in North America for the packaged gases business.</p>
          <p>As you know, we have that in Canada, of course, as a business; we have the specialty gases business in the US but we don't have any more &#x2013; the footprint in PGP. On the merchant, of course, we do have the full fledged offer for bigger manufacturing industry. That's definitely something, which will also influence us. And as I explained it, it comes through Engineering then into the Gases business.</p>
          <p>The HPO effect, I think we have no specific number for you. We really say, we are on track on that quarter, of course, when you see the &#x20AC;650 million to the &#x20AC;800 million then we are on a very positive trend line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Within the range. Thank you. I guess...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our next question comes from the line of Pete Mackey. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yes. Good morning. It's Peter from Morgan Stanley. And apologies, I did join the call quite late, so you may already have addressed this. I have just got a couple of quick financial questions. You saw some obviously higher financing costs reflecting the gross cash on the balance sheet ahead of the Air Products Healthcare acquisition.</p>
          <p>It looks as if you're going to still be sitting on balance sheet structure that is sort of more cash weighted than your &#x2013; what you'd guided to as your target of two times EBITDA. I wonder, if you can give us an idea &#x2013; sort of intensions with regard to the balance sheet for the rest of 2012, please.</p>
          <p>And secondly, I think there was a release of a tax provision. You may well have already addressed this in your introductory comments and I apologize. I wonder if you could just remind us of your full-year guidance please, perhaps including that the release of that tax provision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, EBITDA &#x2013; I start with the tax item immediately, and only to remind us we have a little bit to speed-up because we run into our next meeting, so I try to be fast. 24% tax rate guidance remains. We set around 24% that is I think for the full-year, still the guidance even, if you have seen now a number which is slightly below 20%.</p>
          <p>On the balance sheet, I think you have to understand that we have &#x2013; from a perspective of cash management, we had a couple of payments. One is, of course, the acquisition and one was the repayment of maturity &#x2013; the bond maturity which we placed in 2007. We bought back some of that in the fourth quarter with the placement of a new bond. But we paid in April and of course, we are talking about end of March quarter. But in April, the situation from a cash perspective changed significantly also based because of the repayment overall.</p>
          <p>From a financing cost perspective, of course, we have because of that and slightly higher financing cost level. But it was also against the big volatility in the markets &#x2013; the big discussions around banking.</p>
          <p>So we will keep, I think an additional strategic cash reserves because of criticality in the system of around &#x20AC;600 million. This is what we achieved, but definitely not &#x20AC;1.6 billion. When we talk about the use of our cash flow delivery, of course, we have very high investment level this year. We told you that this is &#x20AC;1.8 billion. So from that perspective, we will have definitely a negative free cash flow this year, which is fully in line with our planning and your planning.</p>
          <p>So from that perspective, we will move up to a net-debt-to-EBITDA ratio which is not anymore 1.6 times. But the upper end which we saw is 2.5 times only to really bring across the debt number. But that's not for 2012 as you know. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Thomas Swoboda. Please go ahead with your question announcing your company name.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>MainFirst Bank. Good morning. Sorry if I missed that, but did incur any significant project costs for the SAP rollouts in Q1? And do you have any idea of what costs you will be facing for this project in the quarters to come only if this is significant. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not significant. They are really nothing, this isn't ramp-up, it's a long-term program I think, which you, know is part of HPO to harmonize the landscape and it will ramp-up, of course, in the years to come because we will have more roll-outs. But I think it is &#x2013; it would be too much now to talk about a quarterly impact at that moment in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So low single-digit million number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I have no guidance for you at &#x2013; I think we would give a guidance if this would be significant &#x2013; it is a slight increase but it would too much at that moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>It appears, you have no question at this time. So I'll hand the conference back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you very much for your great cooperation. We are totally in line and it was a very lively discussion. Thank you for giving us the opportunity also to talk about the one-times, so I hope really we had the time to explain that and looking forward to our continued communication in the market and in the next quarter. Thank you very much. Have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for your participation. This concludes today's conference and may now disconnect your lines. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>