<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1499906" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-08-31</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9492</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Unverified Participant</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Strategic Development">Leonid Arnoldovich Fedun</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for visiting us at the last day of summer. It is always a pleasure to host such an event. Just draw the line, so to say; we draw the line under the past summer and gradually take us into the fall and winter.</p>
          <p>Today, we will be presenting the financial results of our company for the first six months of the current year. And at the same time, online, we have a large group of investors and analysts. We will be receiving questions from the audience here and from the phone line and online as well. We will do our best to answer your questions as completely as possible. I think you know everyone at this table. I will not waste time on introductions.</p>
          <p>The key financial results in the first six months of 2012 amounts to: net income of $4.8 million (sic) [$4.8 billion] (1:20), basic earnings per share $6.3, EBITDA $8.8 billion, net debt $5.4 billion, free cash flow $1.7 billion. At the same time, I wanted to point out that the net income in the second quarter of this year amounted to $1.018 billion, which is approximately half of the consensus of the analysts that expected profit. At the same time, this is the highest profit and one all Russian companies. And we are in the fifth or sixth place and one international independent companies.</p>
          <p>I'm talking about the second quarter. Second quarter turned out to be very difficult. Why? There's a difference between the expectations of the market and the reality. There are three reasons &#x2013; three key reasons for this. First of all, negative FX differences due to depreciation of the ruble during that time and an increase of taxes that we were due to be in Russia. And this combination amounted to $670 million. That's the difference that we had on the first quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>Secondly, the increase in stock inside the group approximately by 0.5 million tons. This is explained by the fact that we saw that the market was in a depression and that the oil prices were falling dramatically. So, it's no surprise that we'd started to hold back some of our stock, hoping that in the third quarter, there will be changes in the market as well as changes in the customs duties.</p>
          <p>You've seen that we cut &#x2013; dramatically cut our access of oil products from Russia, hoping to get benefits in the third quarter which actually happens. So, you will see a positive difference in the statistics for the third quarter this year. And also, there was a deal, a deal that was mandated to us by the government of Kazakhstan. We have to sell a share in Karachaganak, which resulted in a loss for us. So, if you put these three factors together, you will see that the expectations of the market as regard net income and the amounts that we actually obtained would be almost identical. So, that is the explanation of this difference.</p>
          <p>This quarter and this half year was not the best in the history of the company but if you look at the results of our competitors, our performance is much better despite that LUKOIL is behind Rosneft in terms of production of oil. In hydrocarbons, our net income is higher as than that of Rosneft as well as TNK-BP.</p>
          <p>Next slide. If you look at weightage indicators, LUKOIL is characterized by better weightage performance per barrel of production in terms of EBITDA as well as net income per barrel of production. That tells us that despite a rather challenging macroeconomics, the company continues to remain a financial leader in our industry.</p>
          <p>Next slide, please. The main factors that played a role on the whole of our performance, if you take the first six months of the year on the same period of last year of 2011, the biggest negative effect was due to an increase in tariffs, in particular, Transneft tariffs by 6.4%. Then the increase in the mineral extraction tax, 10.4%; export duties, 6%. What is missing here is that there is the so-called scissors or the fork of about 10% because the oil prices were falling in the second quarter. And you know that the export duties is set on a monthly basis. And because of that, these factors proved to be rather bad for all oil companies in Russia.</p>
          <p>The key operating results; production has decelerated by 1.8%. Production of marketable gas went up 10%. Oil refining went down by 0.5% because we have to slow down refining in Western Europe. The high-octane gasoline production in Russia went up 13.1%, which is excellent. The new excise tax &#x2013; a lower excise tax will be soon introduced, and our company will be getting that excise tax for the so-called gasoline of Group 5, or in plain English, Euro-5, and we will be only company that will get profit through these excises.</p>
          <p>We also have current exports of crude oil &#x2013; sorry, of crude oil &#x2013; of oil products. As I've already explained, the overall market current exchange in the foreign market was not good for us, and we cut it by 0.3%. At the same time, we increased actually the crude oil and domestic sales of petroleum products. So, we see a steady increase in demand for high-octane gasoline in Russia. This is because the sales of cars here are very high. I believe that in the first six months of the year, the car sales in Russia increased 16%.</p>
          <p>There is now a substitution of old cars that used to run on gasoline with an octane number of 92. And especially in the Central region, people are moving to cars running on gasoline 95. And we hope &#x2013; we expect that in the next two or three years, we will see further development of this same trend unless there is a traffic collapse, of course, for obvious reasons. Today, the assembly lines here in Russia are reaching a peak of the assembly production capacities. Of course, this is generally positive for the development of the Russian market of fuel oil &#x2013; of fuel.</p>
          <p>The production of hydrocarbon stabilized in the first six months. We see a certain decrease in production in liquid hydrocarbons. We have already reached <mark type="ph" /> a full (8:30) curve there as well. I'm talking about the Nenets District. But if you look at daily production, you will see that in 2012, we reached stabilization. We expect that starting from September, October, we will be at the level of production that we had in 2011. And as we promised, from 2013, 2014, we expect to see a growth in production of hydrocarbons.</p>
          <p>It is also very pleasing that we managed to overcome the challenges in Western Siberia. You can see that we don't have any dramatic downfalls as we had in summer of last year. Currently, production there is very stable; there were no plunges. We introduced new methods of production. We are using more and more state-of-the-art technological wells and this is the result &#x2013; we have also undertaken a lot of measures towards increasing oil recovery factor. So, all of that such the foundation for stabilization of production in Siberia.</p>
          <p>The Caspian, the Caspian region today, this is the most profitable region for our company because as you know, certain exports, special export regulation applies today to that region incentivizing the development of that region. We successfully completed drilling of two more horizontal wells with very high inclination rate with very high angle. And this immediately resulted in an increase of production by almost 100% on the previous year. And we expect the tender next year, the Korchagin field will reach its design of production. And from 2014 or maybe in 2015 &#x2013; in 2015, we will add Filanovsky field to that flow.</p>
          <p>We also see that we are making progress in some other areas. As you know, we had a successful exploration at Sarmatskoye a lot. We managed to prove and actually to increase our CO2 reserves, CO2 reserves where we reviewed the proven reserves. And by the end of the year, we expect that there will be a final picture on Centralna acreage. And it means that we will be able to start developing Centralna field together with Gazprom and our partners in Kazakhstan.</p>
          <p>I have already mentioned horizontal drilling, as you can tell, the number of horizontal wells went up 69%. And in terms of kilometers, we also have made a lot of progress today. LUKOIL is one of the leaders of the industry &#x2013; horizontal drilling. This is not a silver bullet, but it is one of the means of increasing production but today, it's one of the most efficient.</p>
          <p>We have also accumulated best practice on stage-by-stage fracturing when we adjusted wells through 12 to 15 fracs. This is something similar that was being done in the United States to produce shale oil. And this has already given us some very encouraging results. So, we see that before rates can be increased, we just need time. We just need time to understand how long we will be able to sustain such low risk and what kind of production we will be able to obtain on such wells. It will take us a couple of years to make our conclusions on that.</p>
          <p>West Qurna 2 is on track. We signed all contracts with contractors so far. And we keep our fingers crossed. So far, we do not see any constraints or any challenges of not reaching the plant production on time. You understand this is not your regular region and, of course, anything can happen, but there are people who wish to share that pie or this huge pie with us. I can't name names at the moment, but there are several companies that have already expressed their wishes to participate together with us in the development of that field. I believe that in due time, you will know the names of those companies.</p>
          <p>The Uzbekistan project, it is also going on very successfully. We launched a new field. In one year, we manage to add 69% of the oil production and today, Uzbekistan is playing a greater and greater role in the production of gas within LUKOIL.</p>
          <p>You know that China &#x2013; China decided to double transportation, gas transportation capacity from Central Asia. And of course this fits the supply diversification plans that we have. For you to understand, we do not sell gas directly to China. It is the government of Uzbekistan that sells gas to China. And they're doing this through their authorized company. We are only receiving a compensation that was prescribed by the contract.</p>
          <p>Financial results, these were published or actually, these results have been published earlier today on our website. I think you already have time to look through them, so there is no need to comment then again.</p>
          <p>I've already mentioned that our company focuses on high-octane gasoline production at Russian refineries. This is a highly profitable segment of the Russian market. If I'm not mistaken, from the 1st of September, there will be this new excise policy in place on high-octane environmentally-friendly gasolines that are in accordance with Euro-5 standards. And the lower excise tax will apply to such gasolines.</p>
          <p>We expect that if you recalculate this in annual terms then because of this lower excise, we'll be getting additional $300 million of profit. We are the only company that is fully ready to supply the Russian market with <mark type="ph" /> other (15:31) Euro-5 gasoline of our own production. At the same time, the European refineries are not doing great. That is to say the margins there have improved slightly, but we are not yet witnessing a full recovery there. We expected that some refineries will be closed down but in fact, they are not closing down. They are acquired by new owners. I don't &#x2013; we can't understand, really, what the new owners will be doing with the production &#x2013; with the gasoline produced there with those low margins.</p>
          <p>Our refineries in ISAB, Zeeland, Burgas and Petrotel will be &#x2013; should be within profits. At Burgas, we are currently conducting an overhaul, a reconstruction. And in terms of performance, it should enter the top 10 of European refineries and through this plant will ensure its strong position in the Balkan market.</p>
          <p>The market of gasoline and some fuels changed actually. There is no sense anymore to conduct arbitrage transactions with North America. We <mark type="indiscernible" /> (16:45) today. United States of America is fully supplying itself with gasoline and fuels. So, all the gas transactions today are used mainly to produce diesel, which is the main car fuel for Western and Eastern Europe. We expect in 2013 and 2014 the situation in Europe to ameliorate.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses. I have to note that our operation expenses did not grow overall. Actually, some of them went down due to two factors. First of all, the regime of operating expenses optimization that is an effect in the company. And also, this can be explained by the ruble depreciation which affected our performance.</p>
          <p>This is the breakdown of operating expenses. You can see the lifting costs are at the level of $4.86. Right now, we see a certain parity between the ruble and the dollar, a certain stabilization. We expect our operating expenses to grow at the rate of inflation at Russia right now. Inflation at Russia is decelerating. So, we believe that they will remain stable and quite low.</p>
          <p>SG&amp;A, selling, general and administrative, and transportation expenses reduced because of ruble weakening and because we did not raise our expenses.</p>
          <p>Net income reconciliation. You can see the dynamics of our net income on the slides. So, the main impact on the reduction of net income was attributed to taxes. And if you compare this on the first quarter and the second quarter, the minerals extraction tax went up again because of foreign exchange rate differences but export duties, export duties &#x2013; they have the most impact on our results, 1.8, as I again have already mentioned that actual tariff.</p>
          <p>Cash flow reconciliation &#x2013; no, CapEx breakdown, our main investment goals into exploration and production. And as you can see on the previous year &#x2013; on second quarter of the previous year, we almost doubled our investment in exploration and production, again because of major projects of our company like the Caspian then West Qurna; all these projects will be back pretty soon. They're all very efficient.</p>
          <p>The company also invests a lot into refining. We increased our refining investment by 35%. You know that we do have some commitments to refurbish our refineries, and our company honors these commitments. And it turns out that this is actually a profitable thing to do because the excise tax policy in Russia encourages that kind of investment.</p>
          <p>The company maintains a very stable financial position. Net debt of the company went down by $193 million or 14%, one four. Cash and cash equivalents went up. A favorable price environment in the third quarter &#x2013; it's two months already of the third quarter, right? Almost two months now. We have reached two months of the third quarter. Well, all of this tells us that the company is developing very well. And most likely at the end of the third quarter, the Board of Directors &#x2013; unless something dramatic happens, the Board of Directors will decide to pay out first preliminary or interim dividends for the first time. We never did this before. But, again, keeping our fingers crossed, I hope that nothing bad happens. The company still has a very robust competitive position in the industry if you look at <mark type="ph" /> net (21:57) and compare BOE or if you look at the free cash flow, we are one of the best in the industry.</p>
          <p>Conclusions. The company continues its policy of constraining its expensive way of actively investing into production. At the same time, we buy back shares from the market when again the conditions favor such a decision. We have already explained that we've set up a special mechanism to buy shares at the right time. You know that we reserved significant amounts for these purposes. We have always bought back shares from our special vehicle. We decided to do this to be able to take relevant decisions without any delay promptly in order to maintain stability of our shares. As you noticed probably that in recent times, our shares have been quite stable. And we also hope that in the coming years &#x2013; we know that in the coming years, we will continue buying back shares from the market at the most opportune time for the shareholders and for the company itself.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much. We are ready to take your questions now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Mr. Fedun?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Net income is down. We don't require how many percent to also cut the investment program and did the Board of Directors consider this issue today. Well, net income doesn't &#x2013; it has nothing to do with investment program with the cash flow. As much as you've notice probably that we have enough cash flow and the money is there even if one quarter is not the best quarter in our history, it doesn't have any impact on our investment program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, it's still <mark type="ph" /> $40 million (24:03)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It's still &#x2013; it's the same program. For next year, we are looking at the same figures &#x2013; the same estimates that we made before and we don't want to &#x2013; we do not want to change our dividend policy as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are there any negotiations to get a license? Do you get an acreage next to <mark type="ph" /> independents? (24:33) Well, and if so, when do you expect to get a license?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are about to continue the interpretation of the data. We actually got a very rich logging material. We've got a lot of logs. We are currently interpreting the seismic. We expect that till the end of this year, we will finish that work. And from the search stage, we'll move to actual exploration. As to additional acquisitions, this can only be done after additional drilling.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And a second question, if I may? You spoke at length today about the Caspian. In terms of Karachaganak, what is the level of production that you expect at the end of the year, and what is the data for the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The design in capacity &#x2013; the design production, if I'm not mistaken, it's roughly 2.5 million tons. That's production at Karachaganak at the end of next year, and about 1.5 billion of gas. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Bank of America; thank you very much for the presentation. I've got two questions. If we take your reports in the first six months, you've made about $5 billion in capital expenses. At the start of the year, LUKOIL announced that your CapEx will be about $3.5 billion. Should we expect a drastic increase in CapEx for the next six months, or you are going to review your estimate of CapEx for this year?</p>
          <p>Second question, the $1.8 billion that you got back at the end of negotiations to buy assets abroad, have you already used them up or &#x2013; I couldn't find anything about this in the report?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>CapEx. First question, CapEx. Based on my experience, many year experience, there is always a certain savings on CapEx. This is because the &#x2013; it is not always possible to assimilate all the capital investments that was allocated at the start of the year. There will not be a lot of changes to our capital expense program for this year. Usually towards the end of the year, especially in such areas as Siberia, we have a lot of spending to build winter roads and similar things.</p>
          <p>I don't think that there will be a lot of change to this $13.5 billion program, maybe just a little bit. And also this is because we are more widely using the system of open tenders, in particular, we organize the tenders. For the development of Filanovsky field you know that we organized several major, very big tenders. And this gave us about 16% of savings from the region expenditure that we planned before. This amounts to huge, huge money.</p>
          <p>Hopefully, these tender procedures will also enable us to reduce the originally planned investment. And as to the <mark type="ph" /> $1.8 billion, it was $1.76 billion. (28:19) That is correct. Yes, we got that money back, and we used this cash to set up the special vehicle to buy back shares of $2.5 billion. So, that money is currently working for the shareholders to maintain stability, the FX stability of our shares &#x2013; or rather not the FX stability, obviously, but the <mark type="ph" /> cost (29:02) stability. Yes, the money came back to us and now they are being reused to ensure stability.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>One more question from the phone line. Prosperity Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>According to IFRS reports, FX also is $300 million. You're saying that you paid a high tax because you have an excess income in your Russian subsidiaries. How come in one place you've got income and in others, you've got loss?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:34) who is a more competent person to talk you through this question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the Russian companies, we have income because we calculated accounts receivable in foreign currency, and we have to pay a tax from this extra income. And because of this calculation and because of ruble depreciation, we will also have to face an FX loss. So, yes, in Russian accounts, you will see an income on which we pay tax. And on the other hand, in U.S. GAAP, you will see an FX gain &#x2013; I'm sorry, an FX loss. These are paper losses &#x2013; paper profits because we are keeping our accounts in several different systems.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's take another question from the phone line. Any other question from the analysts, please, before we give a chance to the press to ask their questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Bank of America, another question. Sorry for this pause. One more question. Are there any decisions made on this interim dividend payout? And the capital expenses stay at the same level, the current level, will you be able to carry both capital expenses and increase dividends payout for minority shareholders this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much for paying attention to what I'm saying. This is where I ended my presentation. I was saying that the two months of the third quarter fill me with optimism that the board will be able to ask &#x2013; the Board of Directors to pay out dividends based on the results of the third quarter and not only to minorities. As a shareholder, I too expect to get something.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One more question from the front line, VTB Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Thank you for the presentations. I have a question about the FX loss. Apart from loss in the P&amp;L, we also saw an active effect on cash flow. Is the nature of that loss the same, and how big were your FX losses in the second quarter of 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Once again, which losses do you mean? Could you please repeat your question? I'm not sure &#x2013; are we talking about the FX losses, foreign exchange &#x2013; is that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, and the effect on cash flow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we have just explained this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Could you...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I just wanted to say that the taxes that we paid, is it just a reconciliation of your accounts receivable and currency, this does result in actual outflow of cash. So, the results that you saw in the P&amp;L, these same items may not be in the cash flow statement. The only outflow that we have is the actual tax on the profit paid from the profits that the subsidiaries are &#x2013; local are paying.</p>
          <p>In the second quarter, the loss is $415 million. And in the P&amp;L, it's the loss on outflow from &#x2013; sorry, outflow &#x2013; I'm sorry, I'm not sure I can hear you very well. Which page are you referring to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>FX, FX loss, cash flow in half &#x2013; in the first six months is $380 million of loss. In the first quarter, you showed $377 million of profit. So, the second...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, okay, I got the question. We are showing the non-cash effect of revaluation. This is revaluation. The cash flow is a revaluation of ruble-denominated loss like what we've got from ConocoPhillips. So, in the first quarter, when the ruble was appreciating, we had an increase in that debt. So, it was a non-cash FX loss. And now, in the first six months because the ruble depreciated, we restored some of the loss positions. But overall in the first six months, we ended up with a small loss.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question from URALSIB Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions. The first is on the tax that you pay in Karachaganak, around your operations in Karachaganak and also a question on the advanced payments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As for the second question, I've tried to explain this already. In order to set up a special vehicle &#x2013; special tool to finance a buyback of shares, so that the shares would not be &#x2013; and this money would not go into, I don't know, refining or exploration, we set these cash sites. We put it into an SPV, and that's exactly the <mark type="ph" /> 700 and 740. (36:29) And it all amounts to $2.5 billion out of $148 million that were already spent in the second quarter to buy back their shares because, again, the market was favorable. We have some time until 2015, if I'm not mistaken, to undertake such transactions, and you are witnessing such transactions.</p>
          <p>And as to the first question, the Karachaganak question, these are the taxes in Kazakhstan. There is nothing that we can do about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Got you. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. We will stop taking questions from the phone line now, and we will be getting questions from the press and the audience.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The Russian News Agency. I do have a question about Karachaganak. The loss is actually the income less taxes. No, actually, would you have a little profit there but you said that <mark type="ph" /> it was off. (37:28)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is a certain sales tax in Kazakhstan. You know that Kazakhstan took this decision and then the consortium also confirmed their decision to sell their share. And for us, it boils down to a loss.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the buyback, out of $2.5 billion how much have you already invested?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>$148 million as I've explained. You can find it in the reports.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And a question on West Qurna; when will we know the names in West Qurna? You said that there are companies willing to share the success of West Qurna with you. When can we know the names?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't know. I can't tell. It's hard to say. We bought shares to $127 million in the second quarter, and you can find this in the report &#x2013; in the statement. So, we'll take one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have several.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, several more questions. Could you please speak into the mic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you still have plans to go to the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, and when may it happen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It is still in our plans. There is just some legal challenge in that Russia needs to sign the so-called &#x2013; I will be translating into Russian <mark type="ph" /> now (39:03). There is an &#x2013; IOSCO. You know IOSCO, the International Organization of Securities Commissions? And they prescribe certain rules. In particular, they set the standards of disclosure for case of insider trading.</p>
          <p>The government of Russia has already drafted a special law that's currently in the State Duma. We believe that this new law will be approved within this year. That's what I was told. And after that, a memorandum will be signed between Russia and Hong Kong to recognize the listings of both countries. And then LUKOIL or likewise any other Russian company will not have any more barriers of entering the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. Right now, this protocol with IOSCO has not been signed yet.</p>
          <p>The Ministry of Energy is working on a methodology of allowances and benefits for new field development, which feels &#x2013; when the government approves this methodology, this document &#x2013; right now, there are dozens of projects of this kind. It doesn't make any sense to discuss all of them now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The Norwegian tenders, what are the companies with whom you partnered for Norwegian tenders?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With Norwegian companies? Are there many Norwegian companies? No comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. One more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Argus and Timan Pechora, as far as I know, you built a new pipeline. A point of clarification, are you going to transport your own oil there or you will let other companies use your plan as well <mark type="ph" /> the Nakhodkinskoe (41:05) There's a <mark type="indiscernible" /> (41:09) a couple of years ago when you started construction that you were saying that they would love to use that route?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You know that we are negotiating with the relevant companies, and we also hope that there will be supplies from Trebs and Titov oilfield. Total, no, I don't have any information that Total addressed us. I do not have any information.</p>
          <p>Interest equals tariff. If the tariff is very interesting, then everyone is interesting. The tariff is not a...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your participation. When we see each other again in three, four months' time after the end of the third quarter &#x2013; in three months, when we see each other in three months' time, there will be a lot of more exciting news from us. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>