<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1163253" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-06-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9492</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Andrei Gaidamaka, Head of Investment Analysis and Investor Relations Division</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Leonid Fedun, Vice President, Head of the Main Division of Strategic Development and Investment Analysis</participant>
      <participant id="2">Andrei Gaidamaka</participant>
      <participant id="3">Scott Darling</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Dear ladies and gentlemen, today, we start our teleconference on our First Quarter Results. It will be conducted by Leonid Fedun. And we also have in the room Mr. Gennady Fedotov, who is Vice President for Corporate Planning; Igor Kozyrev, Deputy Chief Accountant; and Sergei Epifanov, who is in charge of U.S. GAAP Accounting. And my name is Andrei Gaidamaka and I am Deputy to Leonid Fedun.</p>
          <p>With this, I would like to pass it to Leonid to start the presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. I will be speaking in Russian. And with this, we'll start our statement with the disclaimer about our forward-looking statements. I think that you know all the words. The words are familiar. And let us move to the main facts. Let us bring in the next slide.</p>
          <p>So, who is in charge of changing the slides please? Okay. So, I think this is the first quarter in our LUKOIL history wherein we have almost $25 billion in sales, plus 59% year-on-year and EBITDA about $5 billion plus 99%. The basic EPS is $3.83 per share. It is plus 146%, and importantly, free cash flow despite much higher taxes is plus 971%. It is ten-fold, 1.3 billion. So the macro economic situation is shown in this slide. The oil price rose 71%. The national price for natural gas rose by 25%, and petroleum products have also seen a strong rise, importantly, diesel fuel and gasoline in Russia.</p>
          <p>Also, electricity, transportation have seen a strong rise. And so you can see that the figures when people say about 9% inflation in Russia, these figures look funny because all our figures show are a little bit higher. And you see that real ruble appreciation has been more than 17%. And you know our position that we will be issuing our statements in rubles or euro. And mineral extraction tax was higher by 88% and crude oil export tariff was up 74%, which is higher than the growth rate for oil price. So here are our main operating results. We have minus 4.5% in oil production. We will talk about the reasons in detail a little bit later.</p>
          <p>Marketable gas production was at 18.8%, and the hydrocarbon production was minus 2.1%. Oil refining, the most profitable indicator for the company was plus 8.6%. Crude oil exports was lower by about 14%, and we increased exports &#x2013; petroleum product exports by 10% and increased retail sales of petroleum products by 21%. This means that we are focusing on the most profitable sectors of our operations. It is retail sales in Russia; it is the most profitable things for us. The second most profitable thing is export of petroleum products. And we export crude oil only when we can't refine it and sell it somewhere. So marketable hydrocarbon production, you can see that we saw a rise year-on-year in the first quarter of the last year. And this year, we are seeing a slight decline.</p>
          <p>The main reason is that the production in West Siberia is falling, and I have spoken publicly on this issue. So the reason is very straight forward, West Siberia was launched as a production region when the North Sea and other mature areas -- West Siberia is falling not very steeply, not very fast and Preopskoye field, which came onstream in the mid '90s. It is not falling, but we are seeing a decline in the future. I think that in Bashkortistan and Tatarstan we have seen that, and we are also anticipating that in West Siberia. Of course, we understand that there are some more reserves in Russia, which would allow us to sustain the production. It is Caspian. It is Timan-Pechora. It is East Siberia. And I think within five days we will be unloading the first anchor from South Khylchuya. And I think on the 24th day of the month, we will officially launch South Khylchuya, which will produce about 7 million tons and which will help us make up for the decline in the West Siberia.</p>
          <p>And in the next year, we will start drilling for Korchagina. And, again, in the next year, we will start drilling and producing in the Caspian region. So these are the two areas on which we are going to focus to compensate for the decline in West Siberia.</p>
          <p>We also concentrate on natural gas, which is according to the Russia legislation is the most profitable hydrocarbon. We have grown our marketable gas production by 20%. And we are going to do more of that in the future because the price growth for natural gas is faster than for petroleum products. And it is very sustainable, which is unlike petroleum products where prices are more volatile. So, it is more forecastable and therefore, it is better for us.</p>
          <p>The next thing is crude oil refining. We increased the refining volume by 85,000 barrels per day. And we are going to increase that even further. We increased refining in Volgograd, in Nizhny Novgorod. And you know that we have been planning to add about 10 million tons of refining capacity within 10 years, and we are going along this program very smoothly. And the huge investment that we have made in refining and in making Euro-4, Euro-5 and other petroleum products, products which we are promoting as ECTO. We have seen great support from the government. And excise taxes for such products will be changed, while environmentally adverse petroleum products will be taxed by high excise taxes, and more environmentally friendly products will see a decline in excise taxes.</p>
          <p>All this just is to show that the huge investment that we have made in green technologies is seeing great support from the government. Of course, we are not anticipating radical changes here, because we are not the only company in Russia. There are also state-owned companies. But we are certainly seeing the recognition of the importance of health and environmental issues by the government.</p>
          <p>So the financial results is a controversial issue because a lot of analysts said that the difference between the two quarters was about 1.5% or one working day. When you compare quarter-to-quarter, you need to understand that we have the same financial results with lower oil production. This is just for the understanding to make it clear, because very few analysts understood that.</p>
          <p>If we look at year-on-year figures, almost all indicators grew very fast. And the difference in the net income is one working day, or 1.6%. And importantly, we have a huge free cash flow.</p>
          <p>The sales reconciliation; one factor is the change in the retail prices, which is connected to the growth of price in crude oil. The other factor is the change in the structure of retail sales and of different sales. This is the factor that is within the control of the company. So the change in the structure is that we sell more value-added products, high value petroleum products. And they are not only high value, they are also highly profitable.</p>
          <p>And this leads us to the next slide, in which we can see that we have plus about $2 billion for our oil, but we have a rise from 8.5 to 14 in petroleum products, which all just shows that this is a more efficient segment, a more profitable segment, and the company tries to focus on it more and more.</p>
          <p>Ideally, we see a future without any exports of crude oil. We want to refine everything, refine in Russia and in our international refining facilities everything we produce. So operating expenses; the rise in operating expenses is totally in line with inflation and real ruble appreciation. The lifting costs were plus 14.9%. And so I don't think this corroborates the talk that the company -- that in the company lifting costs spin out of control. Of course, we understand that the depletion of West Siberian fields will grow and it would be difficult to control our OpEx. But I think that our program of moving into new more &#x2013; into new areas will help us control our OpEx.</p>
          <p>OpEx growth drivers were the following. Here you can see that the main factor is the real ruble appreciation, 17.3%. If this factor is used in comparison with our lifting costs, you will see that, in reality, our lifting costs went down, not up. All other drivers, the growth in refining costs, for example, it is connected to the growth of refining volumes. And here, again, it was just plus 6.4%, which says that we are optimizing our refining costs. We have special programs for the optimization of costs for every refinery, which is based on Solomon Indexes. This is the name of the company, which devised those indexes, and we are going very well in line with this program. And it already gives us some results in this quarter. Although the costs are growing, the refining volumes are growing even faster.</p>
          <p>Transportation expenses; some time ago, it was our main headache, but right now, which is important, we are decreasing SG&amp;A and transportation costs due to the optimization of logistics mainly. The infrastructural investments, which we have made, are in making our own terminal at the Vysotsk. And we will expand this terminal in the future. We are now in the negotiation process. We have our own terminal in Kaliningrad, and we are launching a transshipment terminal in Varandey for the South Khylchuya. We are launching our own pipeline from Durham to Almetievsk. Everything allows us to decrease transportation costs, and increase accordingly the efficiency of our business. The taxation for LUKOIL, I think that this slide speaks for itself. We can see that the government very efficiently squeezes everything it can squeeze out of us. And today, I think we are coming close to $35 billion per year. And I think we are breaking all the records in the world here.</p>
          <p>So, I don't think there is a lot of necessity to comment on the tax innovations, which have been suggested by the Russian government. So the first is the decrease of mineral extraction tax. This is simplification of the tax administration system for companies who produce heavy oil and who produce at mature fields. And the tax breaks, which will be very long for fields in such regions as Caspian and Timan-Pechora.</p>
          <p>All this, of course, will create a new impetus for the industry because we think that finally the government has recognized that everything has a limit, and the oil and the oil fields, which we inherited in West Siberia from the Soviet Union, they are nearing the late years of their lifecycles. So here now we are being flat and we are going to decline in the future. And if the government wants to see Russia a leader in oil production, we need investment. And we need about $2 trillion in investment, that is offshore, it is East Siberia, first Caspian, maybe some other seas including the Arctic continental shelf, which is seeing very interesting political situations and tensions right now.</p>
          <p>And if you remember, in the late '60s and '70s, there were such developments for other continental shelves. And, of course, this means that companies need to have some cash in order to invest. $2 trillion is a figure, which I can always confirm. And this is for -- just for the coming years. And now the ball is on the government's side and the government needs to define the scenario for the future. If they want to stabilize the production, these tax innovations are okay. If they want to grow production to some other level, we will need more money. If they want to increase it more, we will need even more money.</p>
          <p>So, to put it very simply, we need to understand the scenario the Russian government would like to pursue. And we are ready to work with any scenario, with any tax burden. For us it is not critical, we can produce oil now with 4, 4.5% growth. We can be flat. We can grow by 2%. Everything right now hinges on the amount of investments the government will deem are necessary in order to stabilize and increase -- possibly increase production.</p>
          <p>Net income dynamics; you can see the net income reconciliation in the slide. And I think it has very little to comment on. All figures are clear. And one thing I would like to add is, again, the difference of one working day. And if you look closely at the figures, I think we could have even better indicators.</p>
          <p>Now, the next slide shows the cash flow reconciliation. And even though we made a lot of CapEx, even though we made a lot of acquisitions, you can see that at the end of the quarter, we have more than $1 billion in free cash flow at the end of this quarter. And much of that money will be allocated for dividends and for further investment.</p>
          <p>Here, you can see the CapEx breakdown. LUKOIL is still one of the largest investors in the Russian economy. And we sustainably invest about 10 billion in CapEx, including E&amp;P, about $2 billion. We also invest in refining and retail sales heavily. And in this quarter, it is $2.412 billion.</p>
          <p>And now, I will say a few words about the new discoveries, which I have mentioned.</p>
          <p>Our joint venture with Gazprom has discovered the largest structure in the Caspian so far. It is called Tsentralnaya, or Central in English. And we expect about 2 billion boe. And for the contemporary world, this is a very good discovery. We expect this will be a good structure. But it is a deepwater structure. And we think that liquid to gas ratio will be 55 to 45. Of course, we have only one prospecting well there, and we are anticipating the results of 3D seismic after which we will make a refined estimate. And we will prepare for the drilling of the second prospecting well.</p>
          <p>The structure will be developed together with a Kazakh company. We expect it will be KazMunai Gas, with which we already have a joint operation at Khvalynskoye. And we will enter into the production sharing regime. And as far as I know, the State Duma, the lower house of parliament, has approved the production sharing regime with a special law.</p>
          <p>Without Tsentralnaya, the Caspian reserves, which LUKOIL controls is close to 5 billion boe, which just says that we only need investment incentives to start developing these reserves.</p>
          <p>We are already finishing the preparation of drilling for the Korchagina rig, and we will start production here next year. And on Filanovskogo and after that Khvalynskoye will be developed. And right now we are preparing, and in the next year we will be drilling Yalama. It is very similar to Tsentralnaya. The first well was dry because we didn't have deepwater equipment, and we drilled only in the west of this area. But the acreage is very promising. We now understand that. And so the potential for this region is very good. And what is also important is that we have a very good experience of cooperation with Gazprom.</p>
          <p>The next discovery is smaller, but it is close to the retail areas, and it is in a well infrastructured area. This is our JV with Priazovneft, and this is a discovery in the Temryuksko-Akhtarsky acreage. It has very light oil, very high quality oil. And we can see about 10 promising structures there. And maybe we are looking at about 200 million barrels here. For this area it is a good figure because the lifting costs will be very low. It is not deep. It is in shallow water. And the reservoir seem to be very good for extraction.</p>
          <p>So we have said that we would go into offshore. And we are doing that. And LUKOIL is already operating on three continental shelves in the Baltic, in the Azov Sea and in the Caspian Sea, which means that the dangers that state-owned companies would monopolize offshore projects, the fears that they would do that are, I think, not very consistent with reality.</p>
          <p>So the conclusions are very simple, that the company is developing dynamically exceeding market expectations. And we anticipate other factors like tax burden decrease, accelerated refinery, throughput growth and gas processing expanding and cooperation with State companies, and new discoveries and implementation of efficient projects in the E&amp;P business segment.</p>
          <p>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. And are there any questions? No questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Please ask your questions into the microphone. A question from Reuters. You said that the decline in oil production in the first quarter was 4.5%. I think Mr. Alekperov was talking about 1.8 to 2% of production growth. Do you sustain this forecast?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On all hydrocarbons, yes. Not oil, but all hydrocarbons. So we will be expecting 1.8 to 2% plus. This is on all hydrocarbons. What about oil? I can just &#x2013; cannot just say on top of my head about oil because we are finalizing the analysis. But our net back from oil and gas, they are the same. Even gas is more profitable than oil. So people just are too negative &#x2013; talk too negative about gas. Although I always say that I think -- with current taxes, I think, gas is one quarter more profitable than oil. And in the next year, we are expecting even more difference in profitability between gas and oil. Any more questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Energy Intelligence. Can you talk in a little bit more detail about the new tax innovations? So for example, did you calculate how much cash can LUKOIL free up as a result of these tax innovations? And do we get you right that these new tax changes are not enough to break this declining dynamics? And so what about peak oil? From what you were saying in the interview with the Financial Times, the understanding was that peak is either close or the peak has been passed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Okay. Let us take these questions on one by one. Okay. This is a purely investment issue. This is the issue of calculation from the government side. It is up to the government to understand what kind of oil production it needs. From the company side, it is very easy to calculate. For example, we will have a profit of 12 billion, and 3 billion depreciation and well, 15 billion. So we will need 15 billion, and we will spend about 10 to 12 billion per year for investment. So if we have 15 billion instead of 10 to 12, of course, we will be able to produce more.</p>
          <p>In the current situation, LUKOIL, I think, will go up 2.3% with the current tax situation. And at first, our geologists said we can go up 4%, but with the CapEx, which is right now prohibitive for us. So it is up to the government to define what they want, either flat production or declining production or growing production or production which is growing fast. But if you want to grow fast, you need to add about $8 trillion to the $2 trillion that I was already talking about.</p>
          <p>And without the tax breaks, so, we are looking at the decrease in the extraction tax and administration simplification is about $1.5 billion.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just for me to understand, so are we talking about 2% of hydrocarbons growth? Okay. Hydrocarbon. And can you have &#x2013; do have any calculation for petroleum products?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, today we just read in the Kommersant newspaper, the innovations that have been suggested. They look very radical. And state-owned companies will hardly be ready for these innovations. But we are ready, and we are happy that they just materialized. So do we have any questions over the phone? Okay RBC, Russia.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Why do you think that oil and gas sector, including LUKOIL are falling faster than others in the stock market?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the first thing that we know is that several investors are going to enter the Russian oil and gas stock market. And there is always some correction before such events. I just cannot say that our statements is the reason and our results is the reason. So someone is playing bear here and some people are maybe cashing out. Maybe this is due to the decrease in oil production or decrease in oil price, but this is an open secret. Everyone can see the figures on a daily basis. And I think Rosneft, Surgutneftegaz and Gazprom are in the same situation right now. And well, new players they just create for them opportunities for entering into the market. Well, I would like to clarify one thing. If you look at the statistics, you will see that LUKOIL is better than many, is better than many in terms of the movements in oil production volumes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language].</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>When people are talking about tax breaks, they are talking primarily about offshore products. Is it the same for internal sea &#x2013; for the shelves of internal seas or continental shelf or deep sea shelf? So what is actually meant Caspian or what -- Azov Sea or whatever?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think you can see that we are working everywhere together with state-owned companies, and so the government is very friendly on the benefits. So I think that this will apply to all the shelves. Well, you don't invite state-owned companies. They come themselves. And for us it is a great honor and a great happiness to work together with them. Any more questions, ladies and gentlemen?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you comment on the growth in other operational expenses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the question is about the growth in other operational expenses. The reason is that we are also up on other operational income. So we sell not only oil and gas and petroleum products, but we also sell, for example, transportation services. So we have growth there. And the growth of income is faster than growth of costs. This was the first question.</p>
          <p>The second question was about the million tons of oil &#x2013; about a half a million tons of oil, which was produced but not sold. They are in our operational reserves, and this is the only reason and I think it is pretty straightforward.</p>
          <p>And the third question is which downstream asset LUKOIL bought in Russia in the first quarter. According to the standards, we include the advance payments on the acquisition transactions. So far we don't disclose the details because the transactions are not finalized yet, but there are some advance payments, yes. Any more questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We have questions from London.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the question is about the growth of refining on third-party refineries. The reason is very simple. Unfortunately, we so far cannot refine everything we produce. And we need to &#x2013; and we need to invite third parties in order to take profit of the differential on the export tariffs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I would like to give the floor to our people from London. There are several questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For London if you have any questions please ask them. You are on the open air.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Scott Darling from Lehman Brothers. I've got three questions. The first question is, can you just clarify your understanding of any future tax changes, and more importantly, the timings of those changes starting from the ones, which have recently been cleared by the government? My second question is just to clarify your production growth. Am I correct in saying that in medium term, based on the current fiscal regime, you are happy with growing production at 4% per year, which is slightly lower than your previous strategy comments around 5.6 to 6.7%? And then the other question is, what's your overall view on the oil price? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your questions. All the tax innovations will take effect in the first day of 2009. So it will be pretty fast. The State Duma is working with these new taxes right now. And I think you can confidently include them in your models for the next year. The second question was -- so in the current -- in the future fiscal environment, we will grow 2, 2.5%, maybe up to 3%. Right now we are finalizing the calculation of our growth forecast. We don't know how long the tax breaks of our offshore fields would be.</p>
          <p>A lot of figures -- a lot of theories were about that five, seven or 10 years, but I think we are looking at 2.5, 3.5%.</p>
          <p>And what about the growth of our oil price? Of course, if we knew that, we would be working only for ourselves. And our forecast is &#x2013; the only forecast that we can give is there are no long-term factors for a decline in the price of oil. The first reason for that is that we have not seen a single large discovery of easily accessible hydrocarbons in the past decades, unlike the '70s, '80s, even '90s. We have not seen that in the past decade.</p>
          <p>And, today, Total was talking about &#x2013; was talking that we are nearing peak oil. And I would agree to that because the focus is being moved to heavy oils, to heavy oil fields and to deepwater oil fields. And all these are the fields, which require huge investments for exploration, production and lifting. So I think that we all should prepare for alternative fuels and for hydrocarbon saving. Hydrocarbons are a finite resource and the question is &#x2013; the question of when is really irrelevant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do we have any more questions from London? It looks like London is satisfied. Do we have any further questions from other locations? <mark type="Inaudible" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have another question. We have another question of the reasons for the decline of refining volumes in first quarter 2008 compared with the fourth quarter of 2007. I think the reason is that, traditionally, in the first quarter we make a lot of repairs in our refineries. And we do that because the pricing is the worst throughout the year in the first quarter. And so this is the best time for repairs and maintenance. So in some of our overseas refineries we made planned repairs, so there was no unplanned downtime.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A question from Interfax. Recently, there was an announcement that CapEx throughout the year would increase to $15 billion, although previously you had talked about 11 billion. So why such a movement? And do you think that you need that much money to sustain the volume of production?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it also &#x2013; this figure &#x2013; this new figure also includes the acquisition costs. We are going to announce this acquisition within some time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>If there are no more questions, then, thank you, ladies and gentlemen, for your time. Well, we will comment on that in the future. Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>