<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1237381" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-06-03</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9492</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Company Representative</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="operator">Operator</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>[Starts Abruptly] On the contrary, the budget owes us some money. Well, the point in fact is that we have the highest growth of oil production in Russia. So we have grown by 3.5% in Q1 this year. Next slide.</p>
          <p>Well, macroeconomic and tax environment, as you see, all the prices are going down a bit. On the positive side, we're seeing taxes going down as well. The minerals extraction tax and the export tariffs, they're all down, and the ruble is also appreciating. Well, it's positive 18.6%. So it's negative actually, but it's positive in terms of our cost. And it's negative because unfortunately we had bad exchange rate differences on the entire volume on all our accounts receivable. And electricity tariffs are also up as you can see.</p>
          <p>Well, of course, in this economic turmoil, we adopted an anti-crisis plan. And we implemented this plan consistently working with our suppliers and working with our internal costs. Like I said, the appreciation of the ruble was just 18%, but as you can see all the costs, lifting costs and all the other costs are substantially above this difference, and it's all due to the efforts taken by our management. Next slide.</p>
          <p>Well, we should thank the government because in this difficult time they reduced the tax burden. The base minerals production rate was reduced. Tax holidays were introduced and the time lag was reduced while calculating the export duty, and the structure of the income tax was also changed. But the government has just announced that this holiday is over. And today, the State Duma is going to decide on increasing social tax, which should have a negative impact on all oil companies. Next slide.</p>
          <p>Well, our main operating indicator is oil production, up 30.2%, and gas production is down. As you know, Gazprom took unprecedented measures to reduce their gas production. So basically, they're behaving like OPEC in this situation, and OPEC reduced oil production back then and that had a negative impact on the prices. Well, skeptics said there would be no influence, but they got it wrong. So hopefully, the steps taken by Gazprom will result in price stabilization in the markets starting from Q3 this year. And we will be able to return our gas production to our desirable levels because gas storage facilities are going to be empty all across Europe in the near future.</p>
          <p>Well, refining, 8.5% up due to the acquisition of this Sardinia Refinery and to the launch of Odessa Refinery. Of course, in these conditions with demand in Russia going down, we grew our exports. Our sales were down 0.5%. Well, actually, what it does it that &#x2013; there hasn't been anything serious in terms of decline in demand for refined products. You see there's so little decline in demand in period of crisis. Next slide.</p>
          <p>Well, this is refining volumes in Russia. As you can see refining margins, and it's about 2007 levels. Well, utilization is at a pretty high level still &#x2013; and here you can see also the breakdown of our refining volumes growth &#x2013; well, due to this Volgograd refinery which is now being revamped. So when the oil price crossed the $60 per barrel level, the profitability was up substantially and it should be reflected in Q2 and Q3 results hopefully. So we're expecting our efforts to rebound our North Sea Volgograd and Perm refineries. And we want to reiterate the fact that in the near &#x2013; in the next five years, we are going to increase our refining volumes from 5 to 7 million tons in the Russian operations without any new acquisitions. Next slide.</p>
          <p>Well, main financial results. Well, they've been published in the Internet on our website, and so basically nothing to comment on here. Just one thing probably, we have pretty substantial EBITDA. Although production and refining is lower than other Russian companies, but in terms of EBITDA and profits from operations we have the same level which means we're very efficient. Next slide.</p>
          <p>Well, sales breakdown. So as you can see, the main thing here is sales of crude oil in foreign markets, so they make the main contribution to our sales. Next slide.</p>
          <p>OpEx. Well, our OpEx, all our operating expenses have been down. Like I said, a little bit increase in refining costs because we put on stream our stake in this new refinery. And I also want to draw your attention to the fact that the cost of acquired crude oil and refined products from third companies is substantially down. And so during the year it went down more than 37%. Next slide please.</p>
          <p>Well, what we can see here is that we can control our OpEx. The lifting cost at $3.1 per barrel, it's lower than in Q1 2007. Well, two favorable factors here, like I said before. It's the depreciation of the ruble, the weakening of the ruble, and also a reduction of costs with our suppliers and our internal costs. And number two is the launch our YK field where the lifting cost is, of course, much lower, less than $2 per barrel, so which has a positive impact on our entire lifting cost. So basically what you can see in this slide is the changes we have had overall in terms of our costs. Well, if you compare it to Q1 2007, the cost is down by more than 35%, which of course is an adequate response to the crisis we had to operate in the first quarter this year.</p>
          <p>Well, transportation, SG&amp;A, well, all these expenses are down and, of course, there is a reduction in transportation costs. It's been a positive factor because the transportation tariffs were reduced and the tankers tariffs reduced too, while our Transnet costs were up 1%. But since we reduced the usage of Transnet by 3%, this had almost no negative impact on us, and here we had the same level as Q2 2007. So it was in this period when oil was about $70 per barrel, if you remember. So there is some consistency between our costs and the market prices. Next slide.</p>
          <p>Net income breakdown, well, operating expenses are going down. The income tax is going down. Well, the overall tax burden is down. Of course, net income is down because the oil and gas prices were reduced substantially. So that's how much profit we have as of today.</p>
          <p>Well, a little impact of this foreign exchange rates fluctuations because the ruble is getting weaker the same rate as before, which means our treasury took very effective measures to compensate for those exchange rate differences to protect us from the negative impact of those fluctuations on our net income.</p>
          <p>Well, cash flow breakdown. Well, $3.197 billion at the end of Q1 2009, which means we have a pretty stable financial situation in LUKOIL. Next slide.</p>
          <p>Capital expenditures breakdown. Well, the main item here is exploration and production. That's where we spend the bulk of the money. At the same time, you should look at our exploration and production costs in ruble terms, not in dollar terms. And the exchange rate was about RUR33 per dollar. So as you can see, the real reduction in capital expenditures in the finding and development would be just several percentage points. So this &#x2013; because of optimization, and so this reduction &#x2013; this substantial reduction you're seeing here is due to the exchange rate fluctuations. Well, some optimization in refining and sales, but this cost optimization is not going to affect our refinery revamp plans.</p>
          <p>And the last section is devoted to the beginning of industrial operations in the Caspian. So several weeks ago, as you know, our Prime Minister was visiting our facility in Astrakhan, the platform that we're building for the Yu.Korchagin field is going to be the first offshore project ever done by any Russian company independently, and hopefully that &#x2013; hopefully the development plans are not changed. And as we promised, the first two blocks have been set on the water and we're now beginning to develop our infrastructure in Northern Caspian.</p>
          <p>Well, speaking about three active reserves, it's a little bit &#x2013; it's like about 5 billion barrels of oil equivalent. That means we &#x2013; in the future, we will be able to focus on the Russian shelf in the Caspian.</p>
          <p>Well, speaking of the Caspian region and production forecast, that's what it looks like at the moment and that's the structure we have today. Here we are working with some other Russian companies. On this central block, we are working together with the Gazprom and in the north western block we are working with the Rosneft, which means that the Caspian region is going to be very soon a province that could really compensate a serious decline in production we're seeing today in West Siberia. Well, that's the structures we have erected already and they're now being transported, and so all our capital expenditures and investment plans in the Caspian are going to be delivered fully.</p>
          <p>Next slide. Well, I want to emphasize that LUKOIL is the only Russian company doing &#x2013; developing those offshore projects independently. We are working in the Baltic Sea and you know that our block has been recognized the safest, the most environmentally safe block in the Baltic area. We built this terminal in Varandey, which can be called the northern most engineering facility on Earth, and I think this year we are beginning to develop the Caspian block.</p>
          <p>Next slide. Well, the positive side of the international financial crisis, optimized investment program, the positive impact of the weakening of the ruble, cost optimization and substantial reduction of tax burden, which I mentioned before. And so we are seeing all those factors in our operations.</p>
          <p>Well, we keep developing despite this crisis. And so we've seen quite a lot of extra optimism over the last three weeks because the oil price in ruble terms is like the beginning of 2007 and it was not the worst year in the Russian oil industry and in the history of the Russian situation overall, which means that the devil is not as scaring as they present it sometimes.</p>
          <p>Thank you for your attention. Now, I am going to take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, your export sales, I was just looking at your export sales, you've seen some fluctuations quarter-on-quarter. And in your operating expenses, you have some credit, like you said, because of inventories and it had a contribution to the operating expense in this quarter because you did not sell all the crude oil. So if you could just elaborate on that because the 17% increase in exports, at the same time &#x2013; so I'm not seeing a reconciliation here. Well, so why do we have this difference in forecasts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, all our export data is taken from the customs declaration that we fill in and so they are controlled by the government. And so the related number of ways you can ship oil, it's Transnet, railroad and water. Water was closed in Q1, so we use only two ways. So Samantha, they probably have the wrong data. Well, so export increase was due to the fact that the Korchagin was put on stream. It's the first private terminal. More than 1.5 million tons of crude oil was shipped in Q1, number one. Number two, the demand in the Russian domestic market was reduced, again all those transactions with crude oil and refined products. So when crude oil is about $30 per barrel, to us, it did make sense. And now it's becoming &#x2013; so when we're about 60, so it makes a perfect economic sense now. That's why exports were up.</p>
          <p>In Q2, Q3, it will be the other way round. So refined product exports will be going down &#x2013; and crude oil exports will be going down and refined products will be going up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, one question about the ruble depreciation. So it's appreciating and you mentioned some measures to compensate for those changes. So can we expect a &#x2013; like a zero sum gain in those currency gains going forward? Or was it just one-time steps. So maybe you're using some hedging, currency hedging?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we do not have serious accounts receivables in rubles. So that's what makes us different from our competitors. Well, in the past, the ruble strengthening was playing in their favor and now it's playing the other way round. But of course, our dollar denominated costs, again, could change because the ruble is strengthening and it's up 7% over the past few weeks. And of course, we'll have to take extra measures to make sure that we can cover the lifting costs and to keep them at the bay, so we remain highly profitable. So we aren't going to get any gains, any currency gains and it's our advantage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because I remember in Q4 you had a substantial figure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, yes, we did. That's why we tried to make sure we get rid of most of our accounts receivable. So we wanted to do it, and that's good. And we also took a substantial ruble loan. So now it's &#x2013; we're at a zero level here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What's your personal opinion of &#x2013; you mentioned OPEC and OPEC influence on world crude oil prices and for us it's always a big mystery. Is it like a balance between supply and demand or maybe just the people investing in oil to protect themselves against inflation, the weak dollar and &#x2013; so in your opinion, have we reached &#x2013; have we hit the bottom of this crisis? Is it going to be better or is it going to be worse?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, speaking of pink clouds, I've never seen pink clouds. And speaking of OPEC, I think OPEC can really control oil prices and the overall reduction in oil demand worldwide could be 25% and OPEC reduced it by 4%. It's more than necessary on the one hand. On the other hand, China, an important factor, well, China is trying to defend against the weak dollar. It's not speculation that China and India, they are trying to get rid of the dollar by buying reserves worldwide in Africa, in Brazil. In Russia, you know they've signed contract with Rosneft. And so they're reducing their dollar reserves in exchange for liquid and necessary reserves. At the same time, they're increasing oil purchasing because they expect the price to go up and to make an extra profit on it.</p>
          <p>So the demand from China and other emerging markets is not going down. All Americas tends to play on crude oil. You remember those Cushing gains when it was $10 cheaper than Brent, but since that WTI is living its own life, not connected to the reality. Now, it's back to normal. And the demand is reflected in those energy prices that we have today. Yes, the search and demand for natural resources we have today is connected to just one thing. It's no longer fears, it's just a comprehension of the fact that the &#x2013; we're seeing a dollar devaluation, serious inflation, dollar inflation. And so people going in commodities trying to &#x2013; basically to hedge themselves against that, which means that demand for energy is still very high.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Please introduce yourself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>World Energy Magazine. So you mentioned your investment, your capital expenditures optimization, so if you could just provide more detailed figures? The second question is on the Gazprom, reduction of Gazprom's operations of gas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, so we have this information on the slide. Well, the gas production went down by 240,000 boe per day, it's about 10%. And you know Gazprom, they reduced their production by 17%. So there is a correlation here. The investment program, well, as compared to last year, went down about 30% in dollar terms and it's about just 5% in ruble terms, so it's very insignificant changes really.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One more question, if I may. You managed to do &#x2013; to get such substantial lifting cost reduction?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, three factors. Well, could you just put up this full on the screen? It's slide 11. So all these factors are given there, slide 11, please. So as you can see, number one is cost reduction, lifting cost reduction and other operating expenses, also this 18% ruble devaluation. These are the main factors. Well, of course, flow rates were up due to this Y-K field being put on stream.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Interfax. Well, the substantial spike in refining cost, what was it caused by?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you could repeat the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in the previous slide, you said that the cost &#x2013; the refining costs are up substantially. So if you could elaborate on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if we start refining 9 million tons at the refinery, and those costs were not reflected last year. Well, of course, these costs are just added to the overall cost of refining. It's just you increase your refining volumes and the costs are up, it's just arithmetic miracles here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, overall for the year, if you look at the specific cost of refining per ton, it's lower than last year. Have you been able to negotiate with the Croatian company, INA, on -?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's the first time I've heard of such negotiations from you. Well, but we heard some news from local representative in this country. Well, I have no idea what those local managers are talking about, but we have not considered this issue in the headquarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>What do you think about your Q1 financial results, your overall impression?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, in a nutshell, the company has proven it can work effectively under pressure, in just one sentence. So we can generate a positive cash flow in the most unfavorable economic conditions, one just could think of, say, three years ago.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, a question on forex loss, so your broke even, didn't you? Or you had some substantial losses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it was minus 84 million &#x2013; minus 15 million overall. Just 15 million. And we have an item in the budget, so we can have a look at this breakdown.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Italian press <mark type="inaudible" /> had a meeting in the Italian Embassy today and they said that LUKOIL would like to work on gas with <mark type="inaudible" /> in Italy. What are your plans and what are the timeframes involved?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, nothing to comment on so far. So we want to do a lot of things, but some times you cannot implement your ideas quickly. There was a plan. That's true. But as soon as these plans become realistic programs, we'll let you know. Of course, we are interested in all projects and all plans that could generate us a profit from oil and gas production or sales, which is our core business. Is it that it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>A question from Bloomberg. Have you received an approval from the Kazakhstan government to acquire Lukarco? And if not, why?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the question of approval, it's up to the seller to make up their mind. It's BP. And as far as I know, there are negotiations going on between BP and the Kazak government, and we are not seeing any concerns here. That's how I would put.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we have some questions from Barclays Capital. How you are planning to finance your short-term obligations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, they can be easily refinanced and we have no doubts here. The capital market is open for such borrowers as our company. Well, sometimes we're not happy with interest rate of 6 to 8%, but still it's better than in Q1. So we have no concerns here. The problem with the Russian banking market is not that there is no money. Problem is that there are no reliable borrowers who could take this money and LUKOIL is considered as one of the serious and reliable borrowers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you planning any bond issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we've talked about several times. So if we are happy with the spreads on long Eurobonds, if it's better than what the banks are offering, then, of course, such an issue could be possible. Well, TGK will be new utility segment, right. And in the annual report, you will &#x2013; you're going to see the segment and it will be completely disclosed because energy prices &#x2013; electricity prices are up more than 15% and so we have a bright future for TGK-8.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you're production forecast?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So we're still within the framework of our previous forecasts, an increase of more than 3%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do we have any questions on the phone, on the line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Question from Lowe Binka from B2B Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> I have a question on your operating costs. This adjustment $145 million due to your reserves changes. So if you could give us some guidance on your reserves in physical terms in Q1 and Q2, and if you could also give us some guidance on your gas production in '09 in Russia and in Uzbekistan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the second question is very easy. Our production completely depends on whether or not Gazprom is going to take our gas. Well now we are seeing a 10% decline, but speaking of my expert gut feel, as soon as the gas price goes down two times and it basically happened from 140 down to 20, and European countries will start replenishing their storage facilities. And hopefully the issue with Ukraine will be resolved and they will find the money to pump 20 billion cubic meters into their storage facilities, and we will be able to immediately resume our production.</p>
          <p>And Uzbekistan we sell to the government and they sell this gas in the market. No problems here. In terms of reserves reduction of costs of course we are not talking about physical volumes, we are talking about reevaluation. So those inventory figures, it's a reduction of the value of our reserves we have in the refineries and at our retail stations and in some of the tankers which are en route to their destination.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So this 345 million is just -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's just pricing issue. It's a pricing issue. And it's not third party, it's our own assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well a question from Platts. So what is going on with West Qurna-1? So are you participating in this tender?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, West Qurna has been onstream since 1979, and so they've been producing some oil since then and the government is going to announce a tender, they sent out documents. Well, when this tender is going to take place, and whether or not Lukoil is going to be participate, I cannot tell you right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On Turgai Petroleum, on this 50% joint venture have you made up your mind on this issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, this issue again, it depends on the new Kazak legislation, on the preemptive rights etc., etc. And Mr. Alekperov met with government officials on this, and we are now in talks with them. So I expect us to reach agreement and we will be able to put it on our balance sheet, those reserves and this production, in this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Discovery Financial Corporation. I have a few questions. Your production in the Y-K field, what's &#x2013; how much are you going to produce in '09, what's your investment forecast in '09? And the <mark type="inaudible" /> stations, how many are going to open this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the Y-K production about 6 million tons, well about maybe 7 million tons, we will reach the plateau this year. It's about 7.4 million tons of production in the feasibility study. On the retail stations, I don't think we should acquire any new retail stations this year, but we will see because the prices for those assets are much better and there were a lot of attractive offerings. But we will try to do a careful screening, and we are not going to rush on this issue.</p>
          <p>And the investment program, we announced it and it will depend on the ruble to dollar exchange rate. Well I cannot forecast it, but I think the ruble is going to get stronger, it's my feeling. So the amount in dollars will be growing, but in rubles it will be stable and I don't think it's going to change unless we have any major acquisitions in this timeframe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So you think that your ruble investments in '09 will be lower than in '08?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, you didn't get me. In rubles they are flat and the reduction in Q1 was caused by the fact that the ruble was getting weaker. And in Q2 and Q3 they will be up because the ruble will get stronger. But we report in dollars, that's why we have this correlation. In rubles it's constant, plus or minus a little bit, of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, your decline in net income in a nutshell, if you could explain that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the prices went down from 140 to 20 and our net income should be negative. But, thanks to dedicated efforts by our petroleum experts we made us a profitable operation. It's a pretty simple fact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So are you planning to resume your exports in Germany, and is that necessary at all?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, if the netbacks is above the alternative options we will resume those supplies, because our job is not to separate countries or regions due to some reasons, but to make sure that we have maximum return on each ton of crude oil and petroleum products sold. Right, let's take one more telephone call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Sir, we have a question from Michael Duni from Ural Bank .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, I'd like to get back to this foreign exchange policies. Is it because your accounts receivable in dollars are up, and your short-term ruble obligations were down, right? And if you could let us know your dollar denominated accounts receivable per dollar and the amount of loans you attracted for Q1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we changed our monetary position from an active one to a passive one and our ruble assets &#x2013; our ruble liabilities are above our ruble assets. So why we reduced our accounts receivable, and it's due to some subjective factors and to some objective factors, because companies started paying taxes &#x2013; on the tax not the same as before. And our ruble liabilities were up at the same time. So we increased our ruble denominated loan portfolio, and this changed our monetary position from an active one to the passive one, and that's why our loss was just $15 million. And it's not connected to our ruble assets and liabilities, but it's because we took a euro denominated loan and it produced a little loss for us in this Q. All the other positions were closed. That's why we had those insignificant currency losses in our reports.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>So thank you, we've been going for 45 minutes. I'd like to thank you for your time and for your attention and see you for when we disclose our Q2 results, which is going to be more positive for our company and for our country. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>