<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1172517" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2008 Earnings Call - UK Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>845</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Sir Victor Blank, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Tim Tookey, Acting Group Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">J. Eric Daniels, Group Chief Executive</participant>
      <participant id="3">Sir Victor Blank</participant>
      <participant id="4">Jonathan Pierce</participant>
      <participant id="5">Tim Tookey</participant>
      <participant id="6">Peter Toeman</participant>
      <participant id="7">Alastair Ryan</participant>
      <participant id="8">Eric Daniels</participant>
      <participant id="9">Manus Costello</participant>
      <participant id="10">James Irvine</participant>
      <participant id="11">Michael Helsby</participant>
      <participant id="12">Derek Chambers</participant>
      <participant id="13">Tim Tooley</participant>
      <participant id="14">Sandy Chen</participant>
      <participant id="15">Lee Goodwin</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, good morning and welcome. Welcome to the Half Year Results of the first half of 2008 from Lloyds TSB Group. With me on the platform this morning are Eric Daniels, our Group Chief Executive; and Tim Tookey, the Acting Group Finance Director. And they will both join me in making some prepared comments first of all, and then we will take questions from the floor.</p>
          <p>As you might possibly have noticed, the first half of 2008 has been a period of considerable turbulence in the financial services sector. With the marked slowdown in the U.K. economy as a whole, this is impacting both consumer and corporate confidence. Whilst no bank can be completely immune from market turbulence, the impact on Lloyds TSB has been relatively limited.</p>
          <p>We've been able to focus on growing our business. And we put in a very good underlying operating and financial performance in the first half of the year. This continues a succession of good results as Eric and his team have put the group on a solid footing and have really driven forward the business to where we are today.</p>
          <p>Our success is based on building a strong, well thought through business model. We're able to add real consistent value to our individual and our corporate customers with a full range of banking insurance and life products that they need to manage their personal lives and their businesses effectively. The result is that our model produces lower risk and higher quality earnings.</p>
          <p>Looking at the results overall, there are a couple things that strike me in particular. Firstly, it's important to note that there continues to be really strong momentum in our core businesses. We have plenty of headroom to continue growing, particularly through cross-sales of products, as more and more of our customers buy from us an even greater range of products and services.</p>
          <p>And secondly, particularly important, is that there is quality and prudence built into our portfolio. For example over the last few years, we've forgone the apparently higher margins in some of the more exotic and higher risk areas of lending, and instead ensured that are exposures are conservatively managed. We have good security and cash coverage for our loans, providing a good level of protection from falling valuations. Our actions over the last few years have prepared us well for any slowdown.</p>
          <p>Now Tim and Eric will cover these areas in more detail and will give you evidence as to why we believe that we have a differentiated and a proven business model that can not only withstand a low growth environment, but which is a model which positions us to capture share and to increase profitability at the same time.</p>
          <p>We will not be immune from any slowdown, but we believe that the strength of our business model means that we are pretty well positioned. So in the light of this, the Board has decided to increase the interim dividend by 2% to 11.4 pence per share.</p>
          <p>On that note, let me pass you over to Tim Tookey. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Victor and good morning everyone. This morning I am pleased to be representing a robust set of results, which once again demonstrate the underlying momentum we have established in our business and the benefits of our lower risk or conservative operating model.</p>
          <p>During the first half of the year, we've delivered an excellent underlying performance, driven by our core relationship businesses. Before moving my focus onto the strong relationship business performance, it is appropriate to touch on some of the facts that affected our statutory earnings.</p>
          <p>Whilst insurance volatility was a significant feature in the first quarter of the year, I am pleased to say that we only saw modest further impact in the second quarter. I would just remind you that whilst policyholder interest volatility is a debit above the line, there is corresponding credit in the tax line, where you'll see in the news release the significant reduction is our tax charge.</p>
          <p>The other items here have all been previously disclosed. Adjusting for these items, you can see our continuing business profit down 19%. Adjusting also then for market dislocation, we get to the strong underlying performance of our key relationship focused businesses that have delivered 11% profit growth.</p>
          <p>Relative to many of our peers, the impact of market dislocation has clearly been limited. But nevertheless, we have had a combination of mark-to-market adjustment and impairment charges that totaled 585 million pounds in the first half and I will go through these in more detail later.</p>
          <p>On an underlying basis, we see the continued execution of our growth strategy, delivering improved income growth of 9%. At the same time, we have continued to maintain excellent cost control, achieving strong positive draws whilst ensuring that we continue to make ongoing investments in the business.</p>
          <p>As a result, our trading service grew strongly, up 14%. We've highlighted several times within recent announcements the corporate impairment levels have been unsustainably low in recent years. We're now seeing the expected increase as the economy slows. And this is the dominant factor behind our 18% increase in impairments.</p>
          <p>Overall profit before tax grew by 11% with earnings per share and economic profit growth at 5% and 7% respectively. And as you will see, we also continued to deliver a high return on equity.</p>
          <p>We've made fundamental improvements to the business in each of the last three to four years and the results are evident on each line of the P&amp;L. Firstly, the good income growth is a result of building customer relationships and balancing growth across assets and liabilities. In addition, our margin outlook has started to improve with increases across virtually all products.</p>
          <p>We continue to focus on sustainable cost reduction that then creates headroom for further investment in our business. And our strong productivity program has once again delivered strong benefits, and we will deliver on track net cost benefits of 250 million pounds this year even after reinvestments.</p>
          <p>Our asset quality remains satisfactory and we've actually seen improvement in the quality of our retail book. Alongside this, we have continued our work on capital efficiency and as you know we transitioned well from Basel II. Our capital position remains robust, with a total capital ratio of 11.3% and a core Tier 1 ratio of 6.2%.</p>
          <p>Finally the robustness of our model, including our strong customer deposits base, has meant that we have continued to fund very successfully at market leading rates despite the recent market turmoil.</p>
          <p>Turning now for the drivers of income growth. In retail, asset growth was 8% driven primarily by mortgage balances where we achieved a 24% share of net new lending in the first half, while unsecured retail lending was broadly flat in the slightly declining market. We have seen very good growth on the liability side of the balance sheet, and our savings growth has been particularly strong.</p>
          <p>Retail deposits increased by 10%, including strong growth in wealth management. And over the last 12 months, saving balances have increased by some 8 billion pounds.</p>
          <p>In the wholesale bank, we continue to lend good quality customers throughout the more challenging conditions, benefiting from our strong liquidity position and the excellent liability growth of 16%. And this liability growth was achieved across our corporate and commercial customer bases as well as within our international businesses. So we are delivering good growth on both sides of the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Turning now to margin. Half on half product margins have begun to increase and more than offset the mix effect. In particular, margins have widened in the corporate book, and margins on mortgage allocations have improved significantly. Our margins have of course benefited from our more favorable position in the current competitive environment.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the individual divisions and looking specifically at the drivers of income growth in the retail bank. This is now a familiar picture. Once again, we have seen the liability side of the balance sheet making the greatest contribution to overall income growth. And this remains important in terms of income sustainability, because liability net earnings tend to be more recurring.</p>
          <p>We continue to make good progress in driving income from both savings and investments. And our focus has been very much on growing core savings deposits. These relationship balances are the more profitable areas of our savings book and are also important from a liquidity perspective, because they tend to be more sticky.</p>
          <p>On the asset side, we saw continued income growth from lending, as we particularly benefited from our strong mortgage performance, although this has been offset by lower commissions from creditor insurance products, reflecting a decrease in the proportion of sales through the branch network.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the wholesale division, where excluding market dislocation, income is up 18% year-on-year. Most of this growth came from our two key relationship businesses &#x2013; Corporate Markets and Commercial Banking &#x2013; although both Asset Finance and International Banking income have also delivered improving trends. Commercial Banking income increased by 9% reflecting disciplined growth in both lending and deposit balances and an increased focus on the more valuable higher turnover customers where their needs are greater.</p>
          <p>In Corporate Markets, we have continued to develop our businesses across our core corporate customer base. This long term relationship strategy, as well as the development of new product capabilities, has enabled us to deliver very strong growth in cross selling income, up 64% in the first half &#x2013; notably from interest rate and currency derivative products. The most important dynamic of this slide is a significant bias of our income growth towards relationship-based sales.</p>
          <p>The significant turbulence in global financial markets over the last 12 months has clearly affected all banks. However, Lloyds TSB's limited exposures in the key areas of contagion means that we are relatively well positioned. In our news release, we have been as transparent as possible and split the impact of market dislocation into its different components.</p>
          <p>In the first point to note is that we have no direct exposure to U.S. sub-prime ABS. We've broken out our CDOs held as part of our structuring business. In terms of the un-hedged positions, we have written down a further 62 million pounds, leaving limited residual exposure amounting to some 70 million pounds, which relates to super senior high-grade notes of 2005 vintage, and with no underlying assets defaults.</p>
          <p>We also have a holding of CDO super senior notes, which is fully hedged with the CDS from a monoline insurer. During the first half of the year, the group has written down the value of this protection by 170 million pounds, following a further rating agency downgrade of the guarantor. The gross value of the position stands at 297 million pounds.</p>
          <p>At the half year, the reliance placed on the swap was a 121 million pounds, down from 155 pounds at the year end. In addition, we have approximately 1.4 billion pounds of CDOs, down from 1.9 billion at the year end, hedged by leading financial institutions with our exposure fully cash collateralized. The risk here therefore is effectively global bank counter party risk.</p>
          <p>We have limited SIV capital notes holdings. All of these SIVs are fully funded, although the costs of funding have clearly increased. This, combined with some uncertainty of the future funding, has led us to write down the value of our SIV assets by 46 million pounds. And as you can see, this leaves us with on a small residual exposure. In addition, we had a further 85 million pounds of SIV liquidity backstops. During July, these liquidity backstops have reduced further to a single draw facility of 22 million pounds.</p>
          <p>Looking back, it's pleasing to see that we have considerably reduced these exposures from 370 million pounds at the year-end to just 22 million now. We've also provided details of the impact on our trading portfolio, and we're aware that not every bank has done this, but we wanted to continue to ensure that we provide clear disclosure.</p>
          <p>We have seen mark-to-market falls in parts of our trading book, which reflects the market wide re-pricing of credit to our liquidity and to a lesser extent, credit. The greatest write down of 170 million pounds represents a variety of mark-to-market adjustments against high quality assets, primarily high quality senior European and U.S. bank loans and investment grade corporates. We're confident in the underlying quality of these assets and we expect a recovery in values over time.</p>
          <p>In addition, we have seen a write down through reserves of 630 million pounds in our AFS book. Pleasingly, this is an improvement of about 100 million pounds from the position as detailed in the May interim management statement. Over two-thirds of the write down relates to the ABS assets held in Cancara, our conduit, where over 90% of all ABS bonds remain AAA rated, and in which there has never been a default on any asset since its inception six years ago.</p>
          <p>In addition, there is no exposure either directly or indirectly to sub-prime U.S. mortgages and only very limited Alt-A exposure. Throughout the first half of the year, Cancara has of course continued to fund well. The remaining asset write downs are split between U.S. government backed student loans and major banks' senior paper on high quality of ABS of which more than 95% is AAA rated. So as we've said before, while no financial institution is left unaffected by the recent market dislocation, the impact on the group is relatively low.</p>
          <p>Turning now to Insurance and Investments, where we have seen a resilient performance against the backdrop of difficult equity markets. Through rigorous cost control, our investment management operation SWIP has maintained its profitability, despite the effect of falling markets on its income.</p>
          <p>In General Insurance, profit growth of 63 million pounds is predominately due to the welcome lack of severe flood claims this year. Scottish Widows has increased its IFRS profits by 15% as result of an improved mix of protection sales and their increase in Corporate Pensions business. On an EEV basis, Scottish Widows' profits were up 4% after adjusting for surplus capital repatriation.</p>
          <p>Scottish Widows delivered a good sales performance, growing market share in a difficult market, with sales through the more profitable bank assurance channel up 8%, reflecting good protection sales and strong growth <mark type="inaudible" /> through our Wealth Management business.</p>
          <p>The new business margin remains strong by industry standards at 3%, but includes the impact of the change in sales mix. Existing business profits remain robust with weaker persistency in life and pensions being offset by favorable experience in the Lloyds business. And the expected return on shareholder funds reduced as a result of lower levels of free assets.</p>
          <p>As well as growth, return as an important metric throughout the group and improved Widows capital efficiency combined with our capital repatriation program means that our return on embedded value has again increased and now stands at 11.7%.</p>
          <p>Turning now to cost. As you would expect, tight cost control continues to be priority, all of our divisions have once again delivered a strong cost performance, notwithstanding the continued investments we are making in the business. All divisions have once again delivered income growth ahead of cost growth, and as a result, our group cost income ratio continues to improve significantly and now stands at 46.6%, down a full 2 percentage points.</p>
          <p>Moving onto impairments. The group charge for impairment losses grew by 22%, excluding the impact of last year's corporation tax rate change and market dislocation. In the retail bank, we indicated earlier in the year that we did not expect the impairment charge to be significantly higher in the first half of this year compared to the first half of last year. And indeed our expectations have been realized with the charge increasing by only 4%. Asset quality trends across the retail portfolios remain broadly stable. And the quality of new lending continues to be strong.</p>
          <p>Looking at the unsecured portfolios, the asset quality ratios for both personal loans and credit cards have improved, and we have had to reduce the overall level of arrears. In the mortgage business, arrears have remained broadly stable up 3% over the last year, reflecting a slight uptick in the last couple of months. 36 million pounds of the increase in the mortgage impairment charge relates to the impact of the first half fall in the house price index. This is where falling house prices increased the loss given default in our impairment calculations.</p>
          <p>Looking forward, our view is that full year house price falls could be between 10 and 15%. By way of illustration, our prices to fall 12.5% this year. We might expect the HPI impact on our impairment charge in the second half of the year to be approximately 100 million pounds. We've historically used dynamic delinquency charts to demonstrate the quality of our new business. I won't dwell on these detailed charts, but you will see from the loan charts here that the quality of new business remains strong. And within cards, the trend is similar, with later vintages showing improved stable trends. These charts continue to highlight the strength of our loan books. And the recent lending in both our loan and card portfolios continues to perform well.</p>
          <p>We have an excellent U.K. LB mortgage portfolio with an average indexed loan to value of 47%. In addition, the average LTV for new business was unchanged to 63%. The full breakdown of our portfolio shown here clearly emphasizes that conservative nature of our book. There was highlighted earlier we have seen increased impairments in the mortgage but largely as result of the full in HPI are raised profile remains strong compared to our pairs. I have used some CML data here to bring out some comparative indicators that demonstrates the high quality of our mortgage book compared to widely available industry data operates the some of the industrial data is only available a quarter in the risk.</p>
          <p>Looking at three months in the rates data, C&amp;G rates have increased by only 3% in the last 12 months, compared to an industry average of the 27% rise in the 12 months to March 2008. Our new repossessions rate as a percentage of total mortgages in 2007 was just half of that of the industry average. Looking further, our properties are in positions we tend to operate about half of the industry average, and our share of properties in possession is less than half our implied national market share.</p>
          <p>Turning now to look at our WIB impairments. As expected, the underlying impairment charge increased, reflecting a modest increase as a result of the economic slowdown in the U.K., growth in the book and a small number of specific provisions in corporate book. Impairments in asset finance followed a similar strong trend to the unsecured retail book, increasing only slightly half-on-half.</p>
          <p>Asset quality in the SME book continues to be strong, reflecting in part our strategy of focusing on secured lending, although we are seeing some early warning indicators starting to turn. The increase in the first half charge predominantly relates to one specific case within the commercial finance portfolio. So whilst overall asset quality in wholesale remains satisfactory, we are seeing the expected increases in charges compared to prior periods.</p>
          <p>In the past, there have been some questions about our property lending, particularly given the recent growth in the book. So I thought it would be helpful to share with you some facts. We've set out why we are confident in the quality of our portfolio.</p>
          <p>At the end of June, lending to property companies amounted to 20.9 billion pounds or about 20% of our overall wholesale lending. The portfolio splits approximately one-third residential and two-thirds commercial property. Of the residential lending, over half is the local authority backed public housing. Within the commercial property portfolio 80% is investment or effectively corporate credit lending. And the balance is development lending and is subject to strict lending criteria. For example we required that the interest expense is fully covered by pre-let income and that the overall level of lending does not exceed 60% of the gross development value.</p>
          <p>Our geographic spread is consistent with the market as a whole, although we don't have any direct development lending in either the city or docklands. Our loan to value on the commercial portfolios as a whole is around 60%.</p>
          <p>The new lending this year is predominantly investment business and does met our strict risk appetite criteria, offering lower LTVs, higher interest cover and the normal full set of covenant protections. With pricing having lifted materially and the attractive profile of LTVs on new business, which has averaged 54%, this transaction has been highly remunerative. We have also avoided lending, at over 75% LTV.</p>
          <p>By way of example, the two largest commercial property deals done this half had LTVs of 39% and 34% respectively, with good quality covenants in place. This highlights our stance of lending to cash flows rather than purely to property values.</p>
          <p>There has been a great deal written about the scale of the slowdown in the U.K. and the knock-on impact on impairments. So I thought that this would be a good time to pause for thought and reflect on some of the key factors behind our impairment outlook. In terms of the economy as a whole, consumer confidence is low, but, despite recent months increases, unemployment levels remain at a relatively low level.</p>
          <p>Overall corporate liquidity remains satisfactory, but again, confidence is much lower than a year ago. Against this backdrop, we continue to lend cautiously, focused on the increasing number of profitable opportunities and lending to customers that fix our relationship model.</p>
          <p>In terms of unsecured lending, our asset quality remains good. And our current arrears performance remains satisfactory. As a result, we do not expect the retail unsecured impairment charge in 2008 to significantly exceed the unsecured impairment charge in 2007. However, in the context of the uncertain U.K. economic environment and the potential for increased consumer insolvencies, we are continuing to enhance our underwriting, collections and fraud prevention procedures. So, whilst the outlook remains uncertain, we are well-placed to deal with the economic headwinds before us.</p>
          <p>I've already spoken about the good income and profit momentum in the business. However, this growth has not come at the expense of returns. Our return on equity is high and stable, and we've continued to increase our economic profit. And this reflects well on the underlying performance of the business.</p>
          <p>Turning now to risk rated assets and capital, I've already commented on the strong earnings growth in our core relationship businesses. This has been achieved through targeted assets growth across our business franchises, benefiting from our robust capital position and strong funding capability. And this growth has been achieved at attractive margins, despite the increase to cost of funding to the group.</p>
          <p>Risk rated assets growth of 8% over the last six months, includes approximately 2 billion pounds of increased weightings as a result of the house price index reducing. We have taken a significant proportion of net new mortgage lending in the first half and at better margins that we have seen for some time, as well growing our corporate and commercial banking books.</p>
          <p>Our capital position shows a total capital ratio of 11.3% and the core Tier I ratio of 6.2%. On this basis our capital position remains robust, despite having had to absorb the impacts of mark-to-market adjustment on dislocated assets and insurance volatility in the first half.</p>
          <p>When considering the appropriateness of our capital base, we start with an understanding of the group's strategy and risk appetite. Our lower risk business model is generating strong earnings and we have had only modest write downs from dislocated assets.</p>
          <p>Our balance sheet reflects many years of prudent business growth, based upon through-the-cycle relationship banking. And, although we won't be immune from the impact of an economic downturn, we are comfortable that our capital position remains robust.</p>
          <p>Before I finish, I'd just like touch on the liquidity position of the group. Throughout the crisis, we continued to fund well and at market leading rates. And there are number of factors behind this.</p>
          <p>I've already mentioned not just the absolute size, but also the growth that we have seen in our customer deposit base. And as a result, we have maintained our conservative wholesale funding profile. Our strong funding position is evidence by our AAA Moody's credit rating, which was reaffirmed earlier this year.</p>
          <p>Finally, not only we maintained a consistent market presence, leveraging our long-term relationships, but we've always ensured that we maintained significant funding headroom. Our high and growing customer funding base is a key part of our funding models. We currently have over 162 billion pounds of customer deposits, the majority of which was sticky relationship deposits.</p>
          <p>This includes nearly 47 billion pounds of current account balances. As result of the strength of our relationship customer funding base, our overall wholesale funding requirement is significantly lower than our peers.</p>
          <p>Overall, this translates into a funding advantage for the bank. Such that during the recent period of market turbulence, our funding operations continue to fund on a business as usual basis. In summary then, in the first half of 2008 we have achieved a strong set of underlying results, notwithstanding the challenging market conditions, building momentum across our high-quality, balanced set of businesses and maintaining satisfactory asset quality. Cost management remains strong and we have again delivered wide and positive draws</p>
          <p>Once again, we have substantially improved our cost/income ratio and we have continued to both grow the business and maintain our high returns. Finally, we have a robust capital position. The Board's decision to increase the dividend about 2%, balances our confidence in the Group's future earnings capability with a level of caution reflecting the slowing U.K. economic environment.</p>
          <p>And with that I will hand over to Eric who will take you through a further review of our progress.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Tim. Good morning and thanks very much for coming. You've heard from Victor and Tim about the good set of results that we've achieved during the first half of the year. Our statutory profits were clearly impacted by the market dislocation charge and the effect of insurance volatility.</p>
          <p>However, to get a better view of what's going in the business and our prospects looking forward, it's more appropriate to look at the core business performance. All of my subsequent slides are prepared on that basis.</p>
          <p>I would like to spend the next few minutes giving you my perspective and some context around the results. Over the past five years we've been executing against a strategy and business model that was designed to build strong customer franchises and generate high-quality earnings throughout the cycle. I am pleased to report that this latest set of earnings continues the trajectory that we have established and gives us another data point in our strong track record of delivery.</p>
          <p>All three of our divisions had good momentum on both leading and lagging indicators. However, we're entering a different part of the cycle, where we, along with the rest of the market, predict lower economic growth for the next several periods. We believe that while we will not immune to the slowdown, the organization is well-positioned. We have a robust business model and will benefit from the measures that we have taken over the years to strengthen our core disciplines and lower volatility.</p>
          <p>We enjoy a good capital and liquidity position and a funding cost advantage which allows us to capture market share at better margins. All in, while our first half results were impacted by the market dislocation, our core business performance reflects the strength of our business model and demonstrates our successful execution against that model.</p>
          <p>Let me remind you briefly of the strategy and our business model. Our objective is to build strong customer franchises. We believe that a sustainable, long-term franchise must be built around the customer. In pursuit of our strategy, we identified a series of key disciplines where we wanted to establish clear advantaged capability.</p>
          <p>First, we wanted to be better than our peers at acquiring and deepening relationships. We measure our success by looking at indicators such as sales volumes, new customer share, and share of customer wallet. And the result is sustainable growth on the income line. This provides stable annuity-like revenue streams and high future value, as customers give us more of their business.</p>
          <p>The second set of disciplines centre on being an increasingly efficient and effective organization. This is not just about reducing costs, but structurally changing the organization to consistently serve our customers better, make it easier for our staff to be more productive and to free up capacity for investment in future growth. The result is a consistent improvement in the cost income ratio and enhanced customer satisfaction scores.</p>
          <p>The third set of disciplines is around the effective use of resources, and deals with how we set risk appetite and allocate risk capacity and capital. Our relationship approach means that we have a consistent posture toward our customers. We set out risk policies to go through the cycle. We're more conservative in the expansionary periods, but we're still there for our customers in the slower parts of the cycle.</p>
          <p>We manage our balance sheet and funding conservatively. Our risk appetite is set with a view that we will maintain our standards in good and less good times, and this will result in robust capital ratios, more predictable earnings, consistent growth and high returns.</p>
          <p>With that backdrop in mind, let me walk you through our trajectory over the past several years. I'll give you a progress update on each of the divisions and show you how we're positioned for the next several periods.</p>
          <p>Our underlying income growth was up 9% for the first half, with each division growing well. The pleasing thing about the income growth is that it is solidly based, as it is derived from an increase in the number of customers, improved sales and growth in market share. Also pleasing is the fact that we've been growing while raising our already high risk standards. Given the momentum we have in acquiring and deepening relationships, we expect to be able to continue to grow.</p>
          <p>In the first half of the year we continued to improve our productivity, with a full two percentage point gain, and we maintained the trajectory we established some years ago. The programs in procurement, group manufacturing and straight through processing are well embedded. Given our successes to date and our ongoing focus on productivity, we expect to be able to further improve our cost income ratio.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier, our growth has been achieved without compromising our high standards for risk. The asset quality ratio has been consistent over the past several years, and we've improved our portfolio quality. We have not chased share at the expense of greater risk, and we've often sacrificed margin in exchange for lower risk. For example, we allowed market share in the IFA introduced mortgages to fluctuate when we couldn't get adequate terms and conditions. Within our corporate portfolios, we never went covenant light, and our leveraged loan exposure is limited.</p>
          <p>Over the years in commercial lending, we moved more of our book to a secure basis, which now represents some 87% of our portfolio. We have a high quality asset portfolio and we're well positioned for the future.</p>
          <p>We've seen good progress on the income line. We've managed down our cost income ratio consistently while funding major investment programs. Our portfolio is in good shape and our risk is well-managed. The sum of these efforts has led to an 11% growth in core business profits for the half, continuing the double digit growth trend we established several years ago. We've built momentum though our unremitting execution against the disciplines underpinning our business model and that gives us confidence as we look forward.</p>
          <p>We enjoy some of the highest returns in the industry, in no small part due to our focus on economic profit. When we set the strategy, we look to achieve both growth and returns for our shareholders and we're delivering.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn to the divisions. In the retail bank, Helen and her team have delivered an excellent profit growth of 15% led by income growth of up 6%. As a result of improving and leveraging our terrific retail franchise, we've established market leading new business flows across the majority of our key business lines.</p>
          <p>We're number one in new current accounts and added value accounts. Number one in new credit card issuance, number two in mortgage lending, number one in personal loans, and number three in savings. We've seen continued good growth in sales volumes, with each of our channels reporting strong progress. Branch sales are up 7%, telephone sales up 27% and internet sales up 49%. This has flowed through to growth in market share and all products show good progress over the period.</p>
          <p>Our momentum in acquiring new customers and deepening relationships with our franchise customers means that we're able to continue to grow, although we'll only do so where we can have appropriate returns and at a suitable risk profile.</p>
          <p>As importantly as attracting new customers, we're growing cross-sales as we deepen relationships with customers. This is key to customer retention and building annuity-like income streams.</p>
          <p>The scale and breadth of our customer franchise supports better lending decisions and offers a lower cost for incremental sales. The top graph shows the additional number of products we sell at account opening. The number of products sold at initiation has almost doubled from two years ago. We're continuing to deepen relationships with our customers over time. The bottom graph shows the increase in products sold to customers who joined us in June 2006.</p>
          <p>As you can see, we've consistently improved our product penetration, which rises from 1.6 to 2.5 products and we've much more opportunity for future growth.</p>
          <p>We have real momentum in acquiring and deepening customer relations in the retail bank. And when we overlay that with good risk management, the focus on deposit growth and our drive for sustain productivity improvement, we are well positioned for the future. Over the past several years, we've increasing concentrated on lending to franchise customers where we have experience with the customer and superior information that allows us to make better credit decisions.</p>
          <p>99% of our personal loans and 90% of our credit cards are to franchise customers. Over the past two years, we've put in place improved collections systems, which have boosted collector productivity by over 50% and we've actually increased the number of collectors by 15%. Our mortgage arrears have been stable and Tom showed you the more recent <mark type="inaudible" /> we've secured had better arrears performance.</p>
          <p>Turning now to insurance and investments. We've delivered another strong growth with profits of 31% or 11% excluding the extraordinary claims impact from the floods last year. Archie and his team continue to deliver good results despite the challenging equity markets, which have resulted in a move towards more cash-based products.</p>
          <p>Scottish Widows has improved its market share and is a leading provider of life and pension products. We saw an 8% increase in bank assurance sales, which is our more profitable channel.</p>
          <p>In the IFA channel, we saw an overall reduction of sales of 5%, inline with the fall in the market. Although we did see strong sales and pensions during the period. We're targeting the more attractive business lines and the more select number of IFA's to insured we generate the appropriate returns.</p>
          <p>Particularly pleasing has been fact that we've improved our overall level of sales while maintaining our returns, and that continues the trajectory that we've seen in recent periods.</p>
          <p>As with other businesses, an excellent cost performance contributed to the results in Scottish Widows and we now benchmark as one of the most efficient life and pensions providers. This is exactly where we want to be, as we face into more difficult market conditions. In our general insurance business we see an excellent opportunity to grow the bank assurance performance as we continue to cross-sell into customer need across the business franchises.</p>
          <p>Moving now to the Wholesale Bank, Truett and his team have put in a very strong performance, with profits up 22%, excluding the market dislocation charge. This performance is driven by the investment that we made over the years, in new teams and new products. We're also using our access to liquidity to support our customers at a time when market conditions have changed, and this reflect the strength of Lloyds TSB's balance sheet and the prudent manner in which we manage our business.</p>
          <p>In the mid corporate sector, we've seen excellent progress in our market share, which has risen from 12% to 14% and we've achieved this without reducing our asset quality. We've also seen success in terms of winning greater share of our customers' spend, and our cross sales have risen by 64% in comparison with the prior period.</p>
          <p>In commercial banking we've also seen great progress, we achieved increases in market share in our target markets as our account managers continue to be very successful in attracting the profitable, high-turnover customers switching from other financial services providers.</p>
          <p>In addition, as a result of our strong market shipment with the retail bank, we also retained the leading position in business startups. The strong 9% income growth reflects the success in acquiring and deepening customer relations. In the wholesale bank we've taken a through-the-cycle approach to risk. We've maintained our high standards through the more expansionary period, and we've not slackened in terms of covenants, coverage ratios and security.</p>
          <p>As Tim showed you, our lending in commercial real estate is well thought through and errs on the side of prudence. We showed you with the four-year results that our portfolio quality has actually improved over the last couple of years.</p>
          <p>We've taken higher impairments in wholesale in this half and we are ever approaching more normalized loss ratios. But we believe that the portfolios will hold up well in a slower growth market. We also believe that we're well positioned with our limited exposure to some of the more problematic areas such as leverage lending or lending to hedge funds.</p>
          <p>One of the drivers underpinning our results and our confidence in the future is that we've invested in the business to support growth and we're seeing the benefits flowing through. We've increased our investments sharply over the past several years as you can see from the chart, which includes revenue, CapEx and marketing. These figures do not include the investment in new people, where, for example, we've seen a 19% increase in front office staff and products in markets over the past 18 months to support new business lines. In large corporate, we've seen a 17% increase in relationship managers. And in the retail bank we've increased fund line branch staff by 600 &#x2013; by 500, excuse me.</p>
          <p>So, let me summarize my comments. In the first half of 2008, we have clearly been impacted by the market dislocation and insurance volatility. But when we look at the core business results, we once again delivered strong operating and financial performance. We've consistently executed against our customer focused model. We've established market leading positions. We have good momentum and good opportunity to grow. Our customer based business model, our through the cycle approach to risk, our focus on efficiency position us well for the slowdown in the economy. When combined with a robust capital and liquidity, we believe we can continue to grow and capture share in future periods. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Eric and Tim. We're happy to take questions now. If you could give us a name and house and then we will decide among us who's going to take the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we start over there, on the third row. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. It's Jonathan Pierce from Credit Suisse. Can I ask three questions, they're all on house price related issues. The first is, well I suppose all three really for Tim. But the first is on which house price index you're using in these calculations. The second question is really on the impairment impact as house prices come down, because clearly, the distribution the LCV implies, it's going to be a non-linear increase in impairment as prices fall and that's kind of confirmed by your suggestion that in the first half there was a 36 million pound impact. And for about the same impact on house prices in H2, that's rising to 100 million pounds. So I'm just wondering whether you've run the numbers, what the impact of a further 12.5% fall would be thereafter. Will it be some multiple of the 136 that we're looking out for this year? The final question is on risk weighted assets. I'm assuming the non-linear relationship again applies here. So can you give us feel for on your 12.5% fall in HPI this year, what the risk weighted assets would do in the second half of the year? We've obviously seen 2.3 billion in H1, will it be a multiple of that in H2? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I have caught all three of your questions, so let me take them in turn. We use a blend of the publicly available house price indices rather than relying on any particular one. So we certainly take into account Nationwide, The Halifax and obviously the RRTS data as well in forming our own view. And as you can see, using that data we're giving a range of likely outcomes for the full year rather than taking guidance on any particular one over the others. So we use those to inform our views on how house prices will likely to behave in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>On the second part of your questions to impairment charges. You're right to observe it's a non-linear impact. We would all expect that to be the case. In terms of how we run the numbers on a further 12.5%, well as you'd expect we run all sorts of different stress scenarios on our models, looking at both the profit as well as the pure impairment impact. So you would &#x2013; you will notice, Jonathan if you were to take a further increase in house prices, house prices well beyond that 12.5, then yeah you would expect to see a further movement in impairment.  It does actually &#x2013; the impact does actually flatten out as you go beyond it. It's not right to assume that it is infinitely geared. Let's remember that the impairment calculation is actually looking at your loss given default and the impact of HPI on that. So you actually have to take a view of what level of defaults and repossessions you're going to have.  So that is as much driven by the actual quality of the book and how one is managing that, whereas of course the impairment aspect is purely looking at those people who are in default or repossession. So I'd guide you again assuming that if you take a multiple if you wanted to run a hypothetical 25% fall.</p>
          <p>The same is true also on the balance sheet side. As you rightly observed, there's been a 2.3 billion impact in the first half. I would expect there to be a broadly similar impact in the second half, in line with the illustrative 12.5% guidance on &#x2013; in the midpoints in the range on HPI for the full year. Okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks. Can we go over there, please? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Good morning, it's <mark type="inaudible" /> from RBS and three questions as well please. All on the balance sheet on the first half of the year relative to the December numbers that you had given us. Firstly in terms of the corporate loan growth, something like 12 billion pounds. Could you give us some sense how much of that would relate to new lending, which you had commissioned in the period and how much of that would reflect the draw down of commitments, which had been put in place before the credit crisis started?</p>
          <p>The second question is on the credit loss reserves coverage. Given your cautious outlook for the economy, can you explain to us why the credit loss reserves coverage to impaired assets fell in the period from something like 45% to 43% and what would need to happen for you to move to rebuild that ratio, which is what we would anticipate in a slowing economic environment?</p>
          <p>And then the third question on deposits. A sharp slow down in the increase of deposits generated in the first half of the year, something like 5 billion pounds, which is less than half the run rate from the second half of last year. So could you give us some forward looking indication as to whether that's the new level that we should get used to? And if so will the loan to deposit ratio for the group continue to rise, or is that a ratio which you're explicitly managing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I think Tim, those are for you as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Again I'll break it down into three and if I miss one, please remind me, I'm sure you will. On draws versus new lending, the vast majority of the increase in lending in the corporate business is actual new lending, rather than draws on existing facilities. Yes of course there's some draws on existing, but the vast majority of it is new lending where because of our strong liquidity position, the bank is able to take advantage of the significant number of quite profitable opportunities being brought to us. And to a degree, cherry pick the kind of clients that we wish to take on. I made reference from the podium earlier, that making sure that we're growing with those kinds of customers who fit with our relationship model. And that's where the majority of that corporate lending has come from and we are very pleased with it.</p>
          <p>You asked about credit loss reserves coverage. I congratulate you on getting to the numbers, you found them in two different halves in the book and I agree with your 43, 45. If you had also done the figure of June of last year, you will have found that it was 44%. And actually ,the move between 43, 44 in the year or 2% from year,, really is very modest. And we are quite comfortable with the level of impairment provisions that we're covering against our impaired assets. The overall credit quality in the books remains very satisfactory indeed.</p>
          <p>Your third question was about deposits. I am not quite sure that I followed all the numbers. There has been a small increase in the loans deposit ratio during the first half. I think that probably reflects to some degree us standing back from offering some of the highest deposit and savings rate balances that some of our competitors are having to. I think what that reflects is that we can still grow our deposit balances, and deposit balances are up by 12% over the year. To be able to do that in an environment where we are not offering the best rates, I think actually is a very creditable performance and shows the level of attraction to customers to come to the bank and avoid us having to offer those kind of rates. But what you really get is the hot money and the hot money that disappears as soon as somebody else goes and posts another special offer rate. So actually we're very comfortable and very pleased, actually with our level of deposit growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, thanks. Could you just give us the some sense as to where you expect the loan to deposit ratio to go over time, please? Will it continue to rise or is that the ratio that you are explicitly managing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would not be surprised to see a small increase, further increase in the loans deposit ratio. But if you look at the mix of our funding, you will see that we have maintained a constant balance between deposit based income and our reliance on the wholesale markets. So keeping that balancing in check is very important and that's a core part of our overall management and balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. The next question. Down in the second row here, I'll come over <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter Toeman from HSBC. I wonder if you could provide some more color on the movement in the equity Tier 1 ratio, which has gone down from 7.4 to 6.2. I appreciate the expansion of risk weighted assets is a big driver of that and 2 billion has come from the revised risk rating of mortgages, but the underlying growth, the WRA, it's still 7% for the half year. So I wonder if you could tell us what your expectation is for WRA growth going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim..?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's absolutely fine. Yes, you're right, it has come down from the 7.4%, Peter to 6.2 at the year end. Let's also remember that the core Tier 1 ratio during the first half of the year, you have to bear a disproportionate proportion of the whole year dividend. So that's actually a factor that some of the phasing of how the dividend coming off reserves and therefore the capital within core Tier 1 impacts on the headline ratio itself. Also during the first half of the year, we've had an unusual combination of the insurance volatility as well as the significant, relative to zero impacts of mark-to-market adjustments on our dislocated assets. And we would not expect that kind of a cocktail of insurance volatility market dislocation to repeat itself going forward to the same scale.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Gentlemen over there. Thanks</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Just development on the same, really. It's Alastair Ryan from UBS. You put on 20 billion of lending and 5 billion of deposits in the first half and your shareholders equity has fallen by 1.5 billion Sterling. You are the only bank after <mark type="inaudible" /> that's going to be putting up those sort of metrics, so rising loan deposit ratios, falling capitalization. How long does the market have to stay down before you have to stop doing that as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Eric?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that we have been very clear that we are content with our level of cash flow. We think that we are one of the best capitalized banks in the marketplace. Because we have managed prudently through the cycle on both a capital and liquidity basis, this is really something where we can continue to grow our business even though others have withdrawn from the market. As Tim mentioned, we are being very selective in terms of the new deals that we are putting on. We are very happy with them. Any time that you can do commercial real estate deals as we've mentioned at 39 and 34% loan to values with very good names, strong covenants and good cash flows and very, very good margins, we should do it. We should continue to expand because we can. So we don't feel at all uncomfortable with our present posture.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gentleman, who is on the fifth row, third one in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Manus Costello for Merrill Lynch. You made much in the presentation of the improvement in return on equity, which in part, it has to be said was driven by lower equity. But given that 27% level in the first half and given that most of your competitors in both the U.K. and indeed internationally would say that ROEs are reducing, would you encourage us to think about that 27% as a sustainable level of return on equity for Lloyds going forward?</p>
          <p>And then my second question was just on disclosure. You, at the familiar stage gave us a very useful breakdown of impaired loans by division. And in particular we noticed the impaired loans in the corporate division, which were about 850 million, just over that I think, at the year end stage. Do you have the similar number for the half year stage, please within corporates?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of return on equity, if you saw the chart we have been absolutely consistent in terms of our focus on both growth and returns. If you recall in the not too distant past about five years ago when we set the strategy, we enjoyed some of the highest returns in the market and the question by analysts at that time was how can you possibly achieve growth and maintain the return, something has got to give. Well, over the past five years we've consistently maintained or improved our returns and at the same time we've achieved growth. It comes from leveraging the franchise and building on those core disciplines that I spoke about: acquiring and deepening customers' focus on productivity and focus on being an effective organization. And so we see no change in terms of our focus on the same core disciplines, we expect that we will achieve and continue to achieve both growth and returns. In terms of the impairments, let me turn it over to Tim and Tim if you had another comment about ROE as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think so. I don't on ROE, but on the impaired loans we haven't broken it out in the news release between the different divisions. But the majority of the increase in impaired loans across the half actually does relate to the wholesale international banking division.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Gentleman, who is sitting right in the middle.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. It's James Irvine from Dresdner Kleinwort. I just wanted to ask, Tim, when you are thinking about capital for the year ahead, what are you thinking about the write-downs that you have made on your dislocated assets? I guess you'd say that some of those are definitely gone forever now. But are you assuming that you're going to write any of that back this year? Or in fact, are you assuming further write-downs in the second half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank for the question, James. Very difficult one to call what's going to happen in these markets going forward. We certainly don't plan or assume for a level of write-backs to happen in the rest of year. That may, of course, happen. And I think what that reflects is the fact that a proportion of the marks that one take are actually liquidity related rather than being credit related. And various commentators are trying to gauge the rough split between what may be a timing difference i.e. liquidity mark versus credit. That's very difficult to do. But we are not dependent upon those marks coming back in the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay and I have a second on mortgage volumes. Clearly, your mortgage volumes have gone up pretty strongly versus last year. I was just wondering should we expect that to increase quite a bit further in the second half of the year, given your Northern Rock agreement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jim, what we have done and we have always been very, very clear is that we will let the IFA introduce mortgages as float in terms of, can we get the appropriate margins and can we get the appropriate terms and conditions. And so, we are well capitalized given that we can, in fact, let that share grow and wane depending on where the market is. We don't really have a forward-looking projection and we don't set forward targets on that basis. It will depend on what the market can bring. Now, the difference between the IFA introduced and our own mortgages is that we jealously guard our share that's originated by Lloyds TSB. Those are customers, they are deep relationships and we treasure that relationship with the customer. The Northern Rock deal is clearly something that we believe will be an important source of origination for us. But again, it's very difficult to call that in isolation with the rest of the market. We will simply have to see what conditions are permitted.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Gentleman...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, it's Michael Helsby from Morgan Stanley. I just got three unrelated questions if that's okay. Firstly, following on from the ROE and the capital question. One of the reasons why your ROE is a lot higher than peers is because you use a lot of the Insurance division's capital within the banking book. And certainly if we reduce your core equity Tier-1 by the deduction that you are going to have to do in 2012, then your core equity ratio is about 4.9%, which is clearly, given the recent capital increases, a lot lower than peers. So I was wondering if you could tell me a couple of things. Firstly, what do you see as an appropriate level of what we'd call a banking core equity Tier-1 &#x2013; or a core equity Tier-1 as you measure it. And secondly, if plan B &#x2013; or sorry &#x2013; if plan A doesn't come through, i.e. the economy is a lot worse, what's your plan B to that in terms of dividend, capital increase, et cetera?</p>
          <p>Second point is on margin, because I note your net interest margin clearly went up versus the first half of last year. But it was flat versus the second half of last year. So I was just wondering if you could give us a steer in terms of what you think the outlook for the second half for this year is. I know there is a lot moving parts.</p>
          <p>And lastly on PPI. Looks like you had about 13% of your underlying profits in the first half of the year coming from PPI. Clearly there has been a big paper, discussion paper from the competition commission. I was just wondering what your response to that is, and whether you see that profit as being at risk. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. Eric is going to start with the comment on capital and then I will pass it over to now pass it over to Tim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Victor. Very quickly, we basically are very comfortable with our capital position and I think Tim will amplify further. But the core Tier I ratio, while an interesting ratio and sometime that we certainly look at, is not the primary regulatory ratio. It is the total capital ratio whereas you know we stand at a very robust 11.3%. Again, Tim will have more comments.</p>
          <p>Turning very quickly to margin, what we have seen over the past several periods, and we would expect to continue to see, is that we have a funding cost advantage, which contributes to our margin. We are also getting better pricing virtually across the board in virtually every product category. However, despite those two favorable pieces, you also have the different mix impact. We're growing our corporate book and our mortgage books faster than some of the others, personal lending for example or credit cards for example. And so while you're watching product margins increase, you're seeing the mix impact dampen some of that increase. We would expect to see some of that same factor going forward.</p>
          <p>Finally on PPI what we believe and we've certainly seen the comments, we follow it with great interest, is that we offer an absolutely superior product. Our pricing is more or less in the middle of the range. We have a more benefits-rich product than our competitors. We think we offer good value for customers and we have our independent research would tell us the customers value the product. So we'll have to see what eventually is going to come from that. Tim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Eric. I agree with everything you said on capital. I don't agree it's right to look at one particular ratio or focus on one. Moreover, I think it's appropriate to look at all of your capital positions and understanding of our risk appetite in those strategies. In that sense one would set one's appetite for the right level of capital commensurate with a broader capital analysis. This takes into account the risk profile and the asset quality of the bank. In that regard, I think it's worth remembering that the balance sheet has got many years of prudent lending, basically comes from the &#x2013; through the cycle of criteria. And that leaves the balance sheet in pretty good shape. On top of that our risk appetite has been low for some time, so that wouldn't be immune from anything that's coming to us in terms an economic downturn. Our overall risk level and therefore capital strength to us, leaves us in a very robust and comfortable position.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="inaudible" /> two questions slightly unrelated, if I can. The first one is about the U.S. charge. I note you're, you mentioned this before and I note the very carefully worded statement, but I also note that <mark type="inaudible" /> involved where fines can be scalable relative to the extent of the misdemeanor. Can you comment on whether or not this a once and for all charge or would there be further charges to come from the U.S. exposure?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We think that we've taken a prudent position in terms of reserving for this. We obviously don't comment on the conversations with our regulators.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And the dividend that really is the most important question. You're clearly much more cautious than you were six months ago about the outlook for the U.K. economy; can you just comment on why you bothered to increase the dividend by 2% and what you think about where that positions you going forward? And also comment on your thoughts on the coverage ratio looking into next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's basically with <mark type="inaudible" /> for the moment. We are comfortable you clearly talked that on capital position and we are very confident in the growth of our businesses each of which if look at the underlying performance have performed very strongly in the first half. And we felt that we wanted therefore to indicate that to give confidence both in our own financial position and in the prospect of growth and signal that with a small increase in dividend for our shareholders. So I think that's the background to the dividend increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And your thoughts on coverage?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't really <mark type="inaudible" /> on coverage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Derek Chambers, Standard &amp; Poor's Equity Research. First a couple of questions on the credit card area. One is could you comment on the changing dynamics of that business where you seem to be moving to a more transactional customer base. So how does that impact the income statement?</p>
          <p>And secondly you passed over rapidly on the response advantage on credit cards. If it looks as if it's not quite as straightforward as humble loans, could you just take us through what you're seeing there because it obviously <mark type="inaudible" /> improving trend positive invoice?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I'm happy to take the second part of the question on <mark type="inaudible" /> sorry if I went through the graph a bit quick there. I think what the chart showed there is the blobs and I put blobs on the end of the recent vintages showed that the recent vintages by quarter are performing in the middle of the pack and better than that over, if one compared it against the positions and go back I believe on the chart several years. So I think we'll be comfortable in that current vintage in the way that's performing, in terms of the profile of the book and...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What I'd add and I completely agree with that we don't run our card business to minimize losses. We run it to maximize the risk/reward ratio and so we you're seeing in terms of our fine tuning you'll see each vintage has slightly different performance, is as we judge the market and as we basically direct our sales to more and more segmented parts of the portfolio you'll sees some variance. Broadly, we are very comfortable with our arrears levels on the cards. Now we are seeing some changes you noted between what we will called transactors and revolvers and as we launched our deal card which has been enormously successful we are attracting in more transactors as of late, that we are very comfortable doing that because the fees that we get from that card at the merchant discount is in fact an attractive proposition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Another question. Gentlemen, back in the row.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. This is Michael Helsby from Morgan Stanley. I don't like to go on, but I hear what you are saying about the total capital ratio and I fully take that on board. But a lot of your peers have given as a target tier 1 and I think most investors within the market, be it U.K., Europe or U.S. certainly putting a lot of more focus on core equity tier 1 when looking at capital ratios. So I was just wondering again if you could maybe give us a view on what you think is an appropriate level of core equity? And then I have just got a slight follow-up question as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I would like to give a quick comment and then I turn it over to Tim. But Michael, I think that we are in a slightly different position than many of the other banks around the circuit. We are well capitalized if you look at our capital ratio today on virtually any measure, we are extremely well capitalized. And what I think is happening is other banks are capitalizing up to our ratios. So we are very comfortable. We don't &#x2013; we haven't given any further guidance, in fact, we never gave guidance in terms of what minimums we were shooting for on a total capital basis, much less than any other ratio. So I think that what you can do is look through our track record of handling capital extremely prudently and we will basically continue to manage in a fashion where we will run a very healthy capital ratio. Tim?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have anything in particular to add.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sorry, can I just have one quick follow-up question. Just I noted at the IMS statement that you had an expectation that the economy was going to improve in 2009 versus 2008, based on at the time I think that's what you said, but I was just wondering if you told us about your GDP forecast is, I'd be interested in knowing what you're planning purposes for growth the next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well I think that the interims, excuse me, at the interims we said that we were expecting 1.6 to 1.8% growth this year and about 1.3 next year was our statement, we would expect that we're going to slightly higher toward the higher end this year, the economy's doing slightly better than we predicted around the &#x2013; closer to the 1.8 than the 1.6 and what we expected it's going to be slightly lower then the 1.3 that we called out in the interims. So we don't see any huge tectonic changes.</p>
          <p>What we see however as the economy continue to evolve is that the chances of recession are higher than they were when we last looked at &#x2013;  when we last reported, but our base case is still for positive growth, albeit at lower levels. Tim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Is somebody out one the &#x2013; no? Yes, in the fourth row. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys, it's Sandy Chen from Panmure Gordon. Just two related questions just on impairment charges. I just wanted to make sure that I heard this correctly. The guidance on retail unsecured impairment charges for flat '08 versus '07 I am trying to put that together with the growth and the actual unsecured personal loans and as well just relatively negative outlook in terms of arrears trends; how do those two things go together? And also on the broader &#x2013; just given you leading market shares in several key areas in customer loans and I appreciate that your arrears performance is significant better then the peers, can you give us some guidance in terms of your peak arrears expectations, maybe in reference to what happened in the early 90s?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me deal with the first parts of that and perhaps <mark type="inaudible" /> the second part in second On the guidance given I think you misheard me; I didn't actually say flat. What I said was that we wouldn't expect the retail unsecured impairment charge in '08 to significantly exceed the insecurity impairment charge in '07 so, Sandy if you don't mind that's a slight refinement in how you played it back to us from the floor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of peak arrears we are clearly looking at what has happened during the last several cycles and what we do is we model a best case and then we stress test those and more extreme scenarios. I think that I would not give any particular guidance other than saying that very clearly we are comfortable with our portfolios, we've given you guidance that we think we are going to be able to continue to grow and our portfolios are well positioned and so that's a statement of confidence in terms of what we have been doing over the last several years. So I think that's about as much guidance as we give.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's Mike Trippitt with Oriel Securities. It's bit of a follow-up on that actually on the guidance that you have given for the impairment charge 100, the suggestion of a 12.5% price for 100 million impairment. I think the question I have got is actually on the arrears level underlying that; as far as I can see you've given I think some data on repossessions, you've also said arrears are up, I think 3%, I'm not sure if you're disclosing actually what the arrears are on the mortgage book at the moment either as a percentage three month plus or three to six months or whatever and in the on the 100 million in the second half, are you assuming any increase in arrears or is it at the current arrears level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me see what I've got here Mike for you. You are right, we haven't given an arrears figure on three months plus in the presentation. What I can tell you from my  notes here that our arrears numbers are lower than the CML average by some way and in fact the arrears numbers on our three months plus arrears book  buy to let portfolio are significantly better, they are fraction of the CML and that reflects the fact that a lot of our buy to let exposure is actually to our core customers. Therefore, it's core relationship business where actually the profile of it is much stronger. I can't remember what's the second part of your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's the 100 million charges you are assuming the current level of arrears run rate, so you expect any deterioration?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. That's based upon our estimate of where arrears will trend to over the rest of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But sorry to try and pin you down, I mean we are talking half the CML average? I haven't met a bank yet that's over the CML level, but I mean half or? Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, it's Lee Goodwin from Fox-Pitt Kelton. Just a couple of follow up questions actually to previous ones, firstly on that impairment point and secondly on capital gain.</p>
          <p>Just on this impairment point I mean the relationship business isn't linear as you say quite rightly because one would expect in fact that arrears and defaults will actually rise as house prices fall because as well as loss given default rising, more people are getting the difficulty will be unable to trade their way out of their difficulties or to refinance. So one would expect that to be this is not linear relationship and I don't really see how it flattens off as you described. But I would like to think ahead to next year and assuming that we get 12.5% for this year and assuming we do get a further decline next year maybe more modest than 12.5%, but should we be thinking about some multiple of 100 million for each half as the impairment charge for next year? So that's my first question. I've got a related question on capital &#x2013; I'll come back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean it's not linear. There does come a point at which it levels off because you start to look at the quality of your book and the likelihood of people getting into arrears. I think the big thing dynamic for us that could really change it is actually if there is a significant spike in U.K unemployment. It's actually unemployment that is the biggest driver of people then moving into arrears and then that gives you the issue where your lost given the full impact can come through and results in a direct impairment charge. So I'd actually think that unemployment is probably the bigger issue as far as '09 is concerned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, but if we assume say 5% I don't know how, house price decline next year on top of 12.5, we are looking for something significantly more than a 100 for each half of next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you're in sort of theoretical modeling from floor to podium, why don't we have a chat afterwards and I'll talk you through it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fine. But you will appreciate that this is a very important question and is what we are grappling with at the moment.</p>
          <p>Second issue on capital just to come back to this point, one ratios, I think it's absolutely correct as some of my counterparts has said that there is focus on this in the market, so it would be helpful for you to give us a little more idea about where you are targeting and I think the other point is I know we would move from Basel 1 to Basel 2 now. Some of you competitors are still reporting on Basel 1. I wondered if you could give us some indication on where the ratio might have been on the Basel 1. At the end of last year just to help you it was 1.1 percentage points lower than Basel 2 capital ratio which would therefore suggest a Basel 1 measure of 5.1% if we applied the same thing crudely. If you are not going to do that could you give us an indication of what the Basel 2 charges please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Three questions in that and certainly now we are not going to comment on pillar two and the last one, the middle point of your question was right into part one. Actually we don't look at it, we don't even calculate it under Basel 1 anymore. Basel 2 is the basis on which we measure and manage the business. It's the way we're regulated. So it's entirely appropriate and actually the way we looked it.</p>
          <p>In terms of the first part of your question look, please don't apologize for keep asking the questions. Please don't be offended if I bat it straight back and say, look, we have given a full answer on where we stand on capital. We don't really focus on any one measure. Moreover you've got to do a full capital analysis that looks at the risk appetite and exactly what you've got on your balance sheet. I think if you do that below its ESP, you'd be hard pushed to disagree that our capital position's robust.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One last question and then &#x2013; thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Alastair Ryan at UBS again. Could I just ask on the sale in your wholesale something and what was sort of less than one year proportion would pay in by this shift over the last 12 months?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We haven't broken out the less than a mobile. We are at 10, 20s of the average &#x2013; and longer and it was due to last year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very, very much for coming and to joining us. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>