<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1408723" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-07-26</date>
    <companies>
      <company>11895</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Vice President-Investor Relations">Daniel Briggs</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Treasurer">Sheldon Gary Adelson</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="President, COO, Secretary &amp; Director">Michael A. Leven</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co., Inc.">Mark Strawn</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="President-Global Gaming Operations &amp; EVP">Robert G. Goldstein</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co., Inc.">Janet M. Brashear</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Joseph R. Greff MBA</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Senior Vice President">Kenneth J. Kay</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Agricole Securities (USA), Inc.">Jon Oh</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Felicia R. Kantor Hendrix</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Shaun C. Kelley</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Securities International, Inc.">Harry C. Curtis</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities LLC">Robin M. Farley</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Union Gaming Group">Bill Lerner</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. My name is Ally and I will be your conference operator today. At this time, I would like to welcome everyone to the Las Vegas Sands Second Quarter 2011 Earnings Conference Call. All lines have been placed on mute to prevent any background noise. After the speakers' remarks, there will be a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Thank you.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the conference over to your host, Mr. Dan Briggs. Sir, you may begin your call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ally. Before I turn the call over to Mr. Adelson, let me remind you that today's conference call will contain forward-looking statements that we are making under the Safe Harbor provisions of federal securities laws. The company's actual results could differ materially from the anticipated results in those forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>Please see today's press release under the caption Forward-Looking Statements for a discussion of risks that may affect our results. In addition, we may discuss adjusted net income, adjusted diluted EPS and adjusted property EBITDA, which are non-GAAP measures. A definition and a reconciliation of each of these measures to the most comparable GAAP financial measures are included in the press release. Please note that this presentation is being recorded.</p>
          <p>With that, let me please introduce our Chairman, Mr. Sheldon G. Adelson.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:20) Thank you, Dan, and good afternoon, everyone. On behalf of our management team and our Board of Directors who are here with me today, I would like to thank you for joining us. In an effort to get to more of your questions, I'll provide a brief overview of our results in the quarter and then turn it over to Mike, who will provide some quick operational updates. We will then move to the Q&amp;A part of the call.</p>
          <p>So, let's get started. I want to begin by saying that across every part of our operations, I could not be more proud of the team members and management teams who helped us achieve this historic quarter and these results are truly historic. So, let me spend just a minute reflecting on what the company achieved over this past quarter.</p>
          <p>First, the company record $2.35 billion in revenue, a 47% increase compared to $1.6 billion during the same quarter one year ago. Second, a company record and to the best of our knowledge an industry record, $902 million in EBITDA. This is an increase of 90% of last year's $473 million of EBITDA. Finally, the company produced adjusted earnings per diluted share this quarter of $0.54. This is compared to last year's second quarter, which produced adjusted earnings per diluted share of $0.17 and what I understand is also an estimate of &#x2013; a consensus estimate of $0.43.</p>
          <p>More broadly speaking, our growth curve has continued unabated. We have shown steady consistent growth. And in fact, these results represent the eighth quarter in a row that we've increased our EBITDA from one quarter to the next. As the only operator with a presence in the world's two most lucrative gaming markets, Macao and Singapore, we see absolutely no reason, no catalyst at hand, which would change this upward trend.</p>
          <p>Let me now give some commentary on our specific property operations. I'll start in Singapore, where Marina Bay Sands recorded a whopping $405 million in adjusted property EBITDA. While I believe the ramp up process is still ongoing in Singapore, Marina Bay Sands generated net revenue of $738 million and an EBITDA margin &#x2013; are you listening? 55%. Just wanted to make sure you heard it.</p>
          <p>Rolling Chip volume for VIP business was a record $12.2 billion. Non-Rolling Chip drop mass market was $1.1 billion, and Slot Handle reached $2.38 billion. Our combined mass win was nearly $4.2 million per day versus $3.7 million per day during the first quarter of 2011. So, that's sequential. That's an increase of 14% quarter-over-quarter, which we think is pretty healthy. As we used to like to say in Boston, how about them apples?</p>
          <p>The property also saw its hotel average daily rate increase to $295, while occupancy rose to 90.8%. Demand is quickly starting to outpace supply at Marina Bay Sands, and ADR and occupancy are continuing to rise. It's important to point out that the property's non-gaming amenities, like the hotel, are very valuable contributors to its overall profitability, especially with the profit margins they're able to deliver.</p>
          <p>Now, I'm being advised that I need to help manage all of your expectations as it relates to our <mark type="audio gap" /> (5:40) in Singapore, something I haven't been very good at in the past. So, I'll leave you with one simple conservative statement, which is this: now that we have entered our second year of operations, it is increasingly clear that Marina Bay Sands is becoming the most successful integrated resort in the history of the hospitality, gaming and entertainment industry.</p>
          <p>So, with what I think is an expectations managing remark behind us, let's turn to our results in Macao. The Macao property is operated by our majority-owned subsidiary, Sands China Ltd., also enjoyed a very strong quarter. Total net revenue for Sands China was $1.2 billion. As you know, we place an emphasis on EBITDA and EBITDA margin, and we continue to widely lead the market in both categories.</p>
          <p>Macao property operation's adjusted EBITDA was a record $392 million. $392 million, an increase of 27.5% versus the same quarter last year while adjusted property EBITDA margin was 33%. Again, a leading figure. The Venetian Macao delivered record property EBITDA of $258 million with a 35% EBITDA margin. The Venetian Macao remains comfortably in its perch as Macao's leading mass-market property, and as we expected, the opening of Galaxy Macao has served as an additional feeder for the Venetian on our Cotai Strip.</p>
          <p>Gaming volumes grew in each segment of the business during the quarter. with Non-Rolling Chip drop increasing to a record $1 billion. Slot Handle jumped 22% compared to the same quarter a year ago, while Rolling Chip volume increased by 37% compared to last year. The Sands Macao once again displayed its level on the Macao Peninsula by delivering adjusted property EBITDA of $96 million, up 18% from the second quarter of 2010 and delivering a run rate that is approaching the record levels of profitability the Sands achieved prior to the opening of The Venetian Macao in August 2007.</p>
          <p>Non-Rolling Chip drop was up 18% year-over-year, while Rolling Chip volume increased to $7.75 billion. Slot Handle set an all-time record of $463 million. The Plaza Casino at the Four Seasons delivered $38 million in adjusted property EBITDA, up from $33 million a year ago. The Plaza Casino is primarily designed to cater to the VIP part of the market, and in a moment, Mike will give you an update on our current initiatives designed to enhance our Rolling business there.</p>
          <p>Before turning to our U.S. operations, I want to highlight one more thing in Macao, which is the performance of our retail business. Retail sales at the Venetian's Grand Canal shops were up 50% year-over-year, while sales at the shops at the Four Seasons soared by 70% compared to last year. We're now collecting more in percentage rents than we ever have at this point in the calendar year. We have always been the most fervent believers in Macao's ability to succeed and flourish as a retail destination, and clearly that faith is now being rewarded.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the U.S., our Las Vegas properties reported adjusted property EBITDA of $93 million, an increase of 41% versus the same quarter a year ago. Stronger cash hotel revenues from convention, group meeting and FIT customers reflect the improving Las Vegas environment. Sands Bethlehem in Pennsylvania recorded adjusted property EBITDA of $21 million. The hotel at Sands Bethlehem celebrated a successful opening during the quarter and along with the forthcoming retail mall and event center, we believe Sands Bethlehem is well positioned for additional growth.</p>
          <p>So, with that overview of our quarterly results, let me now turn the call over to Mike for a couple of operational updates. Mike?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Sheldon, and good afternoon, everyone. Let me start with an update on lots 5 and 6 in Macao. We have finalized franchising agreements now with two very prominent international hotel brands for lot 5 and are now working with those companies to coordinate an announcement for those brands, which we expect will come very soon.</p>
          <p>The opening of lot 5 is still on target for the end of quarter one next year, about eight months from today, and will feature a 600 room, five-star hotel rooms and suites, along with a 1,200 room four-star hotel rooms and suites. The property will also open with a variety of retail offerings, more than 300,000 square feet of meeting space, 11 food and beverage establishments, along with 106,000 square foot casino and VIP gaming areas. The opening of what we are calling lot 6A, which will feature nearly 2,000 Sheraton-branded rooms, is on track for the third quarter of 2012. Along with its casino, the opening of lot 6A will include most of the $13.7 million square foot complexes remaining dining, entertainment, retail and meeting facilities.</p>
          <p>Thereafter opening in early '13, lot 6B will feature an additional 2,000 rooms and suites under the Sheraton Towers brand. From our view, the opening of lots 5 and 6 is a watershed moment for Macao, as it takes its place among the leading business and leisure destinations in Asia. The addition of 6,000 plus rooms from three world-renounced international hotel brands, each armed with powerful global distribution systems, will be an important catalyst to growing our non-gaming businesses in Macao and, in particular, our MICE business. They will be the only properties to open for the foreseeable future.</p>
          <p>As Sheldon alluded to earlier, let me now provide an update on the initiatives we're implementing to grow and enhance our VIP business in Macao, and more details on that Rob Goldstein later. Last quarter, we talked about building better relationships, hiring additional marketing talent and improving service standards as some of the software we were using to enhance the growth of our VIP business. Together with those ongoing efforts, we have now accrued and are embarking on a $125 million capital expenditure campaign, which will help us complete the hardware part of the process. These capital investments will be used for a variety of projects, several of which will be completed ahead of Chinese New Year in 2012.</p>
          <p>We believe these investments are vital to the long-term strategic positioning of our VIP business in Macao. Let me close my remarks with a couple of significant personal announcements. First, we are happy to announce that we have appointed George Tanasijevich as President and Chief Executive Officer of Marina Bay Sands. George joined the company in 2004 working for us first in Macao, and was our very first Singapore employee. In addition, Benny Zin, who has served in a couple of roles since joining Marina Bay Sands has been named the property's Chief Operating Officer.</p>
          <p>In Macao, the SCL Board of Directors will approve later this evening the promotion of Ed Tracy to the position of Chief Executive Officer. Ed, who is currently serving as President and COO of Sands China Ltd, has just completed a very successful first year in Macao. The combination of George, Benny and Ed, along with John Caparella in Las Vegas and Bob DeSalvio in Pennsylvania, gives us a team of experienced and dedicated leaders at each of our properties.</p>
          <p>We are extremely confident that this team will provide stability and deliver growth across all of our portfolio. So, that concludes my brief remarks. At this time, Rob Goldstein, Ken Kay, Sheldon and myself will be happy to address any of your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And your first question comes from the line of Mark Strawn. [Morgan Stanley &amp; Co., Inc.]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. Great quarter. Two questions; first on Singapore, I know you guys want to keep expectations under control. But maybe generally speaking, as we transition into the summer period, there is maybe a thesis out there before that the summer could be the seasonally strongest period. Do you still think that's going to be the case as you look forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I gotta tell you, if July is any indication, it seems to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that the question Mark, the summer is &#x2013; ?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is the summer likely to be the best quarter of the year? But it's difficult to say. Last year, we were still ramping from the opening. We continue to ramp, and I think we'll continue to ramp for many, many months, if not years, to come. And this quarter, we're just finishing July, we have 26 days to speak about, but we're not going to speak about it. But if July is any indication, then it would indicate that summer would be the peak season. But then again, I read in an analyst's report yesterday that December is supposed to -- that the last quarter is supposed to be the best season. I think it's too early to tell which is the best and which is the second best quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Because the only thing on the event calendar or holiday calendar this summer that would cause any seasonal shifts at this point, or it should be a pretty standard quarter with maybe some better seasonality is what it sounds like --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't see any of that at this point. There are some Singapore holidays that go on and what have you, but I think that's everywhere. Once again, I think as Sheldon said, the -- I think we said this last quarter too, understanding the seasonality of Singapore is going to take a while. I think it's going to take us another, probably through another six or eight months before we really get to understand what that seasonality is.</p>
          <p>Right now and for the past quarter, as I said before, the segments that are working in the property are all working, tour operators, convention business, banquet business, food business, transient FIT business and gaming business are all working together very, very well. And it's really from a past experience, frankly, I've never seen a property of this size and magnitude ramp as quickly from the day it was opened. And we still have a couple of more big events coming with Louis Vuitton opening in September and two more nightclubs and about another 30 or 40 retail stores. So, we're not a 100% open even yet and we don't have the subway coming as well, which comes in January or February of '12. So, it's hard to say what that seasonality process is at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That's very helpful. And just one follow-up if I may on Macau and maybe this question is for Rob. I know you've highlighted in the past some of the key maybe investments and getting the right junket relationships in place in Macao to really drive that VIP business. Do you have any general update on how that process is going and maybe just a general sense of timing on some of those?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, as I said before, it's an ongoing process. I mean, it's both -- it's a capital spend to improve physical products, it's relationship driven. It's also additional conversion for more capacity of VIP. I think if you break out our results, our Venetian numbers bode pretty well for the future in the VIP segment will be in the market. We're struggling more in The Sands and obviously a lot of work to be done physically there and we're disappointed we didn't do better in the Four Seasons, I think we will.</p>
          <p>But it's a three part process, it's conversion of the space physically to be more competitive, it's better service and for certain it's enabling us to work with better junket teams over there in Macao. Haven just spent a week there and I think we're making great progress. It's not coming as quickly as I wish it would come, except for the Venetian, a nice gain there and I think you'll see it. It takes a while to figure out to Singapore and, obviously, we are showing some results and I think you'll find in the future that our opportunities in Macao in the junket segment will improve materially.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, and congrats on a great quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Janet Brashear. [Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co., Inc.]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. As we're talking about Macao, I wonder if you could describe the mood in Macao, as you think about the Chinese political transition in 2012 and whether or not there's a thought that there's any particular impact that it will have on Macao?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nothing. I mean, those people, I think, Zhang Dan Peng is going to be &#x2013; he's been to Macao recently. And I think the relationship between Zhang Dan Peng used to be the head of the Hong Kong Macao, Taiwan Affairs Office. He's quite familiar with Macao, I think if anything, hopefully he's more disposed, favorably disposed toward Macao.</p>
          <p>But since Macao is responsible for its executive administrative decisions under their basic law agreement forged many years ago, I think that we don't expect any unusual events, any extraordinary events. But now that you asked the question, I think that Zhang Dan Peng maybe a little bit more favorably disposed toward Macao because of his experience with it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But as you think about local political environment, as you said, within Macao, we've heard from some other concessionaires that they are guidance to add integrated resort elements to their Cotai plans, from the government? Are you getting any input as well or are they not giving it to you because you're so far long in your development at this point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we are the guys who brought up the subject with the government. I've been saying that ever since we opened the Sands in 2004 that anybody that opens any property should be required to have a matrix of both gaming and non-gaming activities, and to start off with that the gaming portion of the total construction square footage should not be more than 10%. And if a say cut back on certain percentages of say exhibition or convention space or shopping, they ought to cut back on the casino space.</p>
          <p>So, we are all in favor of that. And as we said, as migration originally called for the more critical mass we have in Cotai, the better. Galaxy has helped and supported our City of Dreams, helped to support Cotai as the place to go. And other analysts are talking about now the Galaxy is open that validated the Cotai and the desire of everybody else, SJM, MPEL, Wynn, SJM, all the others are anxious to open in Cotai.</p>
          <p>Now, I want to remind you that when I came up with the notion, it was swamp and a bay. Now,  nobody wanted the land, now everybody wants the land. So it just validates, I'm very happy. I remember saying many years ago that I would even welcome Steve Wynn on Cotai to create some critical mass, but now that I've had dinner with Steve Wynn, I'd even welcome him more. So, getting critical mass in Cotai is important today and I see it happening.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Janet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Joe Greff. [JPMorgan Securities LLC]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, everybody. A few quick questions here. On Singapore, the volume metrics across-the-board were much better than we had forecasted and probably with the most upside relative to our estimate on the Rolling Chip volume. Can you comment there why you think you grew Rolling Chip volume, is it more effective guys in the field, is it gaining market share? Is it something you're doing at the property, is it something with your competitor creating a different set of competitive pressures? If you could help us to understand that, that would be helpful, and then I'll follow up with a couple more.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well obviously Joe it's a lot of things, it's not one variable, it's many. Obviously, the product itself is iconic, which is very helpful if you're in this position. People want to come to NVS, it's a product people know not just in the Rim, but worldwide. Too, I think it's at the very desirable -- Singapore is a wonderful place to visit and the Mainland Chinese and other people in the Rim, the Japanese, very comfortable in that environment. It is a very special environment, easy access, culturally comfortable. I think that you're seeing more and more of that, I'll also point out I think it actually works very well the Macao operation there.</p>
          <p>David Sisk and Tracy and I were having the discussion about Macao, we think it's not even &#x2013; a negative impact, maybe positive, but we're finding customers we hadn't seen before, large customers and a different customer seeks out the Singapore experience. I think this gets better, as the mainlanders get more comfortable and the Japanese and Thailand. It's a very diverse mix, it's plentiful, it's very elite and as our product improves, we will be building more suites on the 55th floor in tower three. I think you'll just simply see it get better over time. I can't speak to RWS and haven't been in contact with them recently, but I suspect Singapore is a market that is starting to mature and getting stronger every day. And I think it can continue to grow and improve. It's a different experience in Macao, it's a very, very special experience.</p>
          <p>I will take my outdoor team in the field. I think our team, led by Larry Chiu, has been exemplary. We have a really strong presence in every major Asian capital. And I think those guys on the property and in the field have done a spectacular job and the results speak for themselves. But I think we're just -- I think we're at the beginning of that process, we're not matured yet at all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe put another way, Rob, on the VIP side in Singapore, is it driven by increased number of VIP patrons or is it new or repeat or is it just men for a VIP trip?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, I think it's increased. We have gained <mark type="indiscernible" /> (27:00). The truth is, it's all of the above. We are seeing very, very high-end customers. We are seeing diverse representations from a geographic perspective. We are seeing repeat, because people like the product. And also we're seeing it as the kind of place that &#x2013; it talks to Indonesia as well as Malaysia, Japan and Mainland has definitely discovered -- the Mainland Chinese have definitely found a comfort.</p>
          <p>So, it's all of the above. The kind of numbers we're experiencing in the growth, 20 plus percent. It doesn't come from one piece, it comes from many different variables, all of the above, very honestly. We're maturing as a team, we're maturing as a property, and Singapore is just a great place to visit. So, it's a wonderful situation right now across.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And. . .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Joe, I think we should also add Joe, because I anticipated the question, that Rob and the guys, we have not changed the structure financially. We have not changed the credit financially. We are doing the same things from an organization standpoint. I think Rob is being a little modest here. My own view of it is that he has put together a phenomenal team of people. And these people are now just starting to really, really go. And I think that's why -- that's really why we're seeing the big difference. So, obviously, the hotel was there before, and now that team is maturing. And the expectation of their performance, not only there, but wherever else we go in Asia, we're going to have a base to be able to grow from there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Goldstein modest, never happened.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Very modest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, switching over to Macao if I may, of the Rolling Chip volume, what was the mix between direct and junket?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our mix doesn't change a lot, we're still running, the great majority obviously is about four to one in favor of junket. But as our goal is to not be our direct business but not soften the junket side as a result of favoring VIP. In the past, we were premium focused.</p>
          <p>We want very badly to encourage strong relations with the major junket people in Macao. We are trying to emphasize if a customer wants to come direct, they can. I think David figured out that if we want to service both ends of the spectrum, we don't want to lose our junket perspective. But still the driver. Sheldon has referenced the importance of junkets in Macao.</p>
          <p>We're really beginning there. Once you figure out our service objectives and we really get our relations right, and how we fix our house physically especially in the other two properties, not the Venetian as much, I think you'll see a lot better improved performance. We're still -- we offer the premium direct option but we stress the junket side, we want very much to grow our junket relationships.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. And then, a question for Ken on the Singapore refinancing, if you can give us a timing update?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Singapore or are you talking about Macao?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Singapore.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Singapore. We haven't started that process yet. We're getting to the tail end of the kind of refinancing in Macao and once we've put the finishing touches on that, we will be down talking to lenders with regard to opportunities in Singapore. So probably that conversation -- those conversations will take place in the next month, month and a half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks, guys. Good results and Sheldon, you and Steve should have dinner more often.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Yes, if I do, I'll turn vegan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your next question comes from the line of Jon Oh. [Credit Agricole Securities (USA), Inc.]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. I'll start with the question on Macao. Give us just a quick update on especially the Venetian across the board on mass market, your Rolling Chip as well as the direct VIP, especially since the opening of Galaxy Macao. Have you seen any significant change in foot traffic and also in the VIP players that come in, their frequency of visits? Any color will be helpful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're very supportive of the Galaxy. I visited last weekend, and think it's certainly helping the Cotai. What it's helping do is make Cotai a good option for the customer. There is no question that they're bringing value to the market. We're seeing a significant improvement and I think we're able to see -- it helps our cause, it's a positive for us. We hope those guys continue to grow and do better because obviously it's always good in any market, your competitors do well.</p>
          <p>And I think we're seeing it's helping, is it material -- not material, the VIP nor the mass. What's material, our guys doing a better job of marking the building, taking advantage of our access to borders. I think our mass marketing approach gets stronger by the day, our border reception's stronger today, our ferry business stronger by the day. We've got to help build our house and Galaxy is a part of it, but it's really not material at this point to our core business in VIP nor mass.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is it fair to say that so for now the observation it's a positive, it's not a negative?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's not negative, that's for sure, it's not negative. It's positive, it's a question of how positive it can get. I think again as more players come to the Cotai, a piece of the Macao is better for &#x2013; we're the biggest player there, we made the best effort to be there, Sheldon got out there way in advance. So, I was over at the 5 and 6, we have so much real estate, we welcome and want to see more growth in Cotai clearly. Has it been material at this point? No, it hasn't driven our business in any segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just and a follow-up on that Singapore. Great quarter and it's encouraging to see that your Rolling Chip volumes are up, almost I think by my count, 50% since fourth quarter last year. Could you maybe just share with us on what are your thought process with respect to junkets being approved in Singapore? How far is the government into that approval process and any guidance on timeline as well as any color on that will be very useful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, we all know that junket issue is a government issue. And we don't know, we can't speak to the government's intensions. We simply wait their advice and council, and when it happens, it happens. Yes, we've got a number of junkets for review by Mike and Sheldon, that we're considering. We have not submitted one application yet. So, to sit here and opine as to what the government will do, timing-wise or eventual result will be foolish.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would like to make a comment that I may have spoke otherwise in the early going a year ago. As I understood it in the past, they said the government said that if a junket rep was approved for one property it will have to re-apply to do business with the second property, but maybe I misunderstood that or they made themselves misunderstood. The way it is today is that if they approved for RWS, all we have to do make a request --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>-- without resubmitting all the information and getting second approval. So, essentially, whoever submits for one property will -- the junket of that will be able to work essentially for both properties. And they're still, I don't know. The scuttlebutt is that they should have some answers by the end of the year. The scuttlebutt also is that a lot of the Macao's junkets reps have not yet submitted apps, and who knows, it's up to the government. We don't know and we'll see what happens. But then in the meantime, we're doing very well, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Felicia Hendrix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good afternoon. Rob, I was just wondering, you mentioned -- or actually Mike you mentioned but Rob, I was just wondering if you could touch on this, the $125 million capital campaign in Macao. If I heard correctly, that's going to be finished by Chinese New Year 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Some will. Our goal is to be finished by Tuesday, but it's little difficult. I mean, we have a lot of work to do, Felicia, in our houses and it touches, as Mike referenced, all three stores, the Plaza, Venetian and Sand. It will come intermittently, probably the first piece will come at the end of this year, a piece will come during the first quarter and some will not happen till second quarter.</p>
          <p>In short, design approval out of Las Vegas, getting appropriate contracts, as in labor, and the team there, Ed and David, feel comfortable with design system operationally. But it's just like our approach in Singapore took a lot to get there, it took a lot to get there in Macau, we still think we're a year away from having maximum capacity and the right spaces. Unfortunately, the process is probably another 12 months, but pieces will get done this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we ought to give an advance running to Ken Kay that from the $125 million, we'll have to tap our pretty cash account.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is that your petty cash Sheldon, or is that --?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Either the company's or mine, I've shown my willingness to you of my petty cash account in the past and now they want to take the interest rate back from me.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, Rob, just on that same subject, you were saying that the Venetian you not as far along -- there's just more work to do with the junkets. I'm just wondering as you talk to them, what are their sticking points and I know this all takes a long time. But I'm just wondering how long you think it might take to return to low-teens market share on the VIP side?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. We're very convinced that will happen. We said in day one, it's a one -- 18-months or 12-months to 18-months process. I think it's three things that we think have to happen. One is the relationships, which I think David and our team over there are really focused on, and I think we're there on the relationship side. We've got the four or five junkets we want, have now committed to us verbally, and some are moving, you'll see move this quarter into that space. Two, which was physical build-out to make the space both pleasurable to be in but also operationally. Service levels we can do much better at.</p>
          <p>And, obviously, it's not a deal-driven relationship as much as it is relationship driven. I think that's where our team has really done a great job of bringing it together. But I don't think you will see the full benefit of things, until the first quarter of '12 and then beyond that. But, I really feel very confident we're going to get there. And I think we've giving it every day and our team at Macao gets it, we can do more short-term, especially at the non-Venetian properties. At the Venetian, we're very pleased with our share this quarter. We're starting to feel a sense of we're participating in the growth in Macao in that segment.</p>
          <p>We already I think are dominant players in the mass, but clearly we've got growth. And I also reference that that growth still is too early to focus on high-end, plus the Wynn guys have done a tremendous job on the high-end side. We want to grow our, we're very strong on the mass, but we think there is lot of opportunity on the high-end to <mark type="indiscernible" /> (38:40) the right people to service those people and the right physical spaces. And all that's part of that capital we spoke about. It's not significant relative to the upside of this company. We feel we can do better in Macao, and we will do better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's really helpful. Thank you. And if we could just move to Las Vegas, I mean, clearly, your marketing strategy proved successful this quarter. But you also benefited from the strong conventional calendar set for you. So, I'm just wondering how you're thinking about your cash comp mix in the third and fourth quarter? And then, also, I'm sure you know that Steve Wynn mentioned strong demand in his property in July in Vegas, and I'm wondering if you're seeing that as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me answer the first question. What we've done in the cash comp situation is adjust over the year. What you will see in this quarter and the next number of quarters are going to be based upon how the management adjusts the cash and the comps. We've been successful, particularly at moving it the way we want to. There are some opportunities we believe we are seeing that we will take advantage of. Our forecast is pretty good on that matter both in cash and comps, but we were managing now for the rest of the year.</p>
          <p>Looking at it, we've got a good convention calendar the rest of the year. So, that allows us to manage those cash and comps a little better. So, I think there is still some upside for us in that area. The Venetian, I should also mention when you're talking about capital in Macao, they're also investing a significant amount of capital in the Venetian here.</p>
          <p>We're doing a lot of work in our room facilities as well as our casino situation and by mid-time next year, we're going to have a lot of this stuff in this building and we're one of the very few in the Vegas market that has the capital capability to change the outcome. And so, we're going to be doing that, we've got some catch-up to do and it's being allocated.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Has your room demand been strong in July?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think generally Vegas market in July, in total, has been pretty good. I'm hearing from the other competitors that it's been pretty good. And I think our performance in July will be above what the expectation levels is for what people are saying about Las Vegas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. And then just finally in Singapore, I'm wondering where you are with your ETG capacity, your electronic table games?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we already had --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There is nowhere left to grow there. As of this week, we've got a last piece on the floor. We're fully allocated now based on government approval. So, we're there totally -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've got room for another 175 units. Was it ETGs or slots?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (41:41) So today, Felicia, at this date, we're there, but we weren't there at June 30, at the end of last quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The ETG numbers that were running at about $650, $675 per day. And on the weekend, we're getting to $1,100 a day. On the ETGs, this is an amazing ETG market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It sure is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Really very incredible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You saw the growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wish we had the slot hold percentage but we can't &#x2013; we've got to give the same percentage. Clearly, electronically, each seat doesn't compute its own game. There's one game to control all the -- whatever number of seats there are, 75 to 150.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we grow our win by sequential Q-on-Q by 18% and we look forward to keeping going in that direction. It's, as Sheldon referenced, the ETG market, there is one of the time, much stronger than anywhere else in world and it appears not to slow down. So, very encouraging ETG numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Shaun Kelley. [Bank of America Merrill Lynch]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, everyone. I just wanted to start by passing on my congratulations to you, George and Ed, on their promotions.</p>
          <p>I guess my first question was on Singapore. I just wanted to ask, you talked a lot about the VIP side. But Rob, could you just give us your sense on -- you continued to indicate that the mass-market is kind of continuing to ramp. Those numbers kind of beat our estimates. Could you just give us a sense just on how that trended across the quarter and whether it's kind of ramping each successive month there just kind of as you watch the business continue to grow?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. It's ramping, it's very consistent. It's not one month down the next business is growing, you saw the mass table -- to me, the story in Singapore, which has always been extraordinary, is the mass table and the spot with Q-on-Q 15%, 16% sequential growth. I don't know how to portray the future because every day is different. But the growth has been steady for May and June, is appears to keep going in that direction. We have days where there's 2 plus million for the weekend.</p>
          <p>So, look, it's a wonderful story, and I don't know where it ends or how much it keeps going but we had a very consistent upward trend April, May, June, if it is the end or beginning. And it's very gratifying, I think that the team there has done an excellent job of moving the floor, looking at every square inch of real estate to maximize the opportunity. And of, course the margins, which Sheldon referenced last year, we thought wouldn't be as aggressive, but it turns out they are retainable were 67%, 68% on a blended rate and no reason why it shouldn't continue. So, it's all very positive coming at ATG slot mass table.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We went up 16% on 3.7% or 4.3%, win per day in the last market, which is the last tables in the slot were ETGs. That's a 64% annual rate, that's one hell of a ramp after being open for a year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful. And I guess just as follow-up. I mean, on the expense side, the numbers were up again a little bit sequentially. But, this time, obviously revenues were up significantly more. Are we at the right level kind of on a per day expense rate now, is this kind of about the right run rate for the property exclusive of maybe a little bit on the retail side left open just as we think about kind of modeling going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the answer is yes. And some of those expenses go up if you look at, it's dependent upon some of the VIP rolling. As that goes up, we'll get some more expenses. But by the end of the day, from the rest of the building on an undistributed expense basis, we're pretty much where we're going to be. We don't see any real radical change in that. So, I think from a modeling standpoint, you can model where we are.</p>
          <p>By the way, we're always looking for opportunities to do better there and continue to look at it. But I think from a stability standpoint, after one year we pretty much know what it's going to cost, and what how many FTEs we need to run that building.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, thanks, Mike. And my next question is on 5 and 6, that's kind of the next day event catalyst for you guys. Could you just give us your thoughts on how many table yield kind of right now you're planning on opening with just kind of what's the target for the first part of the casino? And then, how many tables will be in that the second batch, which I think if I caught your prior comments right, in the prepared remarks was with lot 6A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we got about 200 tables in each of the two casinos plus the 150 or so, 140, 150 and the. . .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think 110 or 155.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's around, between all of them, it's about 400 to 500 tables between the casinos.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>400 to 555. . .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then the other thing is though, the electronic table games are ramping up very well in Macao now. And that's going to affect the amount of space we use in the casinos and we are not quite sure exactly what that count will be, but in fact, I think you can estimate comfortably 200, 200 in each and that about 120, 130 in the Plaza for now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful, Mike. And then, just to clarify the ATG's count as swap position in Macao?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's whole limitation. . .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think it's 1 table for every 50 seats, they count them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One, it doesn't matter, it goes --.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It doesn't matter. . .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, one slot machine for every 50 seats?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. It's <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:10) one table game.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They are estimating that 50 seats would be the equivalent of one table game, but there was no limitations on seats use.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There was always a with slots here, you're very comfortable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful. Thanks, guys. I appreciate it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look at that, we're add more detail on that for you at the next quarter when we get real close to the opening and we'll know exactly what we're going to be doing. But that's in the state of flux at the momentum. But that's approximately what. . .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Harry Curtis. [Nomura Securtites International, Inc.]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, can you hear me?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can hear you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Go ahead, Harry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. First of all, Sheldon, we have to thank Dan Briggs for controlling our expectations for Mandalay Bay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For Mandalay Bay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, from Marina Bay Sands. That shows you how old I am</p>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (49:05). Yeah, okay. Okay. Let's start with sites 5 and 6. Rob, are you learning anything from your move back into the VIP side, or the junket side, in terms of physical plant, when it comes to five and six, have you done redesign there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>How are you promoting that or building that out so that you can compete with those that have really significant share on that segment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's pretty simple. It's a learning process every day. And there's no secrets out there. The Wynn numbers are extraordinary in that new segment and we look to their design as well as the Galaxy people and we're trying to incorporate the best things from that, the best things available from those respective houses, along with our own experience at the Venetian.</p>
          <p>But in the end, it's access, it's service, it's not that big a surprise, the same things remain consistent whether it's Las Vegas or it's Macao or it's Singapore, it's access, it's desirable environment, it's service, it's relationships. It's not pricing, it's more about those elements. And as we referenced earlier, we have a long way to go, but I think you're going to see some very, very promising results from us in the future quarters, vis-&#xE0;-vis junket segment in Macao, including 5 and 6.</p>
          <p>So, yeah, we're learning every day. We're doing this for long time, but you learn every day from smart people and you learn to incorporate <mark type="inaudible" /> (50:50) and I think 5 and 6 will reflect some of that. I also think we've got some good opportunity though, in the Plaza, to go back and that's a great building, it's under capacity as far as the VIP segment. So, I think we can expect some pleasant surprises in future Macao in the VIP from us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Harry, I just want to point out that it wasn't the absence of a completed room or one nicer room, or one not so nice room. It was that last year what Jacobs said, he hurt the relationship with the junket reps and we're getting that back now. So, now people will come back and we're getting new ones and they want more substantial presence. Reminder that we were running very close on the gross income, a couple of years ago next to SJM running in the mid to high-20s as a percentage of market share, even though we don't think it's that important, which reflects that we had a lot of the VIP market.</p>
          <p>And we're the leading -- if people looked at learners unusual metrics of who is leading in the mass market, how many people were coming, we edged out SJM to <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:13) properties on visitation. So, we're number one in visitation now according to that. And so, we're getting back the relationship with the junket reps and new relationships. So, we're screening those out and we'll have them back. And I think people, I don't know anybody that's putting any estimates in for lots 5 and 6, and I don't know why, maybe because it's taken so long to finalize. But, we think 5 and 6 is going to be the only property open within the next three to five years. And that the -- and part of it two periods.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Rob, where are you in changing the physical plant on the Plaza?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Its capacity, Harry. We're looking at the capacity opportunity and it's a great building. The Plaza Mansions are great, the Four Season itself is a terrific hotel. It's a world-class spa and shopping. Retail is doing very, very well there, now even plus plus. But we have under capacity at 42 junket tables. What Dave and Ed are focusing on growing the capacity on levels two and three.</p>
          <p>And we have other additional opportunities within that space to convert. We think we can do a lot better in terms of adding, love to see the Plaza to get to over 100 tables. There's huge EBITDA potential, if we fix our junket relationships, Sheldon referenced that a second ago, but also takes capacity growth on the gaming table themselves. And that's where we see the biggest single opportunity for us there. We have sufficient capacity. If we have room, make it larger, so we have to take advantage of that room and the same thing we want to get more in tables into the nation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's also very honestly is getting the right junket guys in this space versus nonperformers. In the end, it's just looking at your building and say, who's underperforming? If the junket can deliver twice or three times, then why have that junket versus one that's delivering one-third of that. So, it's about the right people in the right spaces.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, the last question relates to the promotional environment. When you compare the promotional environment before Galaxy opened to what it's been, oh, say in the last month or two, has it changed much?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think there is more end-up competitions in the town in general. And that's part of the caution on the mass side because it's easier to drive the top line and the question is how do you drive top line and maintain your margins and EBITDA? And I think you are seeing a lot of people worship the revenue numbers especially across the board in Macao.</p>
          <p>The single worship seems to be on the top line, but in the end of the day, they've got to make money too. I think there has been some pressures from some of the operators because the huge growth market is very tempting at every segment, mass, swap table, junket to over spend. I think you have to remain disciplined and that's how you make money, that's the big driver for top line. There is more promotional pressure, but I think our team has done a very good job of monitoring it and maintain margins that you see by the good stuff coming out of Macao.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Very good. Thanks, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're welcome.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Robin Farley. [UBS Securities LLC]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks. I had a question on site 5 and 6 and you gave a timeline from Q1, 2012 to early 2013 with the staged openings. I'm just wondering do you have the number of workers you need on site today to hit those timeframes or do those timeframes still require additional workers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have the workers now to make those timeframes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great. And then, on Singapore and I know you're trying to manage everyone's expectations, but on that the volume in VIP there. Can you comment on how sustainable, in other words, do you think that this is an above average quarter? I mean, you've said you think Q3 maybe the best of the year, but is this quarter sustainable with upside likely, or is this kind of an above average quarter in terms of what you expect for volumes for VIP specifically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (56:30) but I'll agree with that. The truth is, it's a learning curve and  we've demonstrated slow and steady wins the race. I think, I've said before, I'll say it again, the property is extraordinary, so is Singapore as a destination, if we keep doing our job, I don't see any reason why we can't maintain and do better VIP, the team in the field is very, very good. The businesses there, Singapore is a wonderful destination.</p>
          <p>Can I answer if the third quarter is better than second quarter? I cannot. I really don't know, but I believe in my &#x2013; I've always believed in Singapore since the day we've opened it, and I believe it's going to perform very well. Whether VIP's third quarter is better than second quarter, I just don't know. But I have a lot of confidence in the team, in the building and the location. Singapore is just a terrific place to operate and people want to come there.</p>
          <p>So, if the Pacific Rim keeps knocking out these ridiculous wall creations, I'm assuming they want to gamble, I think it we'll do okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We know, but what we can't say. But I want to say is that do you know, when you about the possibility, that Singapore has only been open a little more than a year, both properties. And to think that we've saturated the entire market of like 3 billion people within the market radius, is not a credible thought.</p>
          <p>There's no way that we've saturated the market, just no way. And the more that people get to learn by word of mouth that Singapore is the place to go, we don't have to tell them Singapore is the place to go, but it's now the place to go to gamble, it's the place to go for tourism, it's the place to go for conventions. And Singapore is now no longer known as a stuffy conservative place, nobody is making jokes about that chewing gum, but everybody is talking about what great restaurants there are, what a good time you can have when you go to Singapore and what a great destination it is for both FIT and convention. And I don't see, there's nobody can convince me that we've even touched the area of saturation of the market. I think Singapore is going to continue to grow and grow and grow.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>By the way, Robin, did you hear the 55% number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I heard. I noticed that, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And your final question comes from Bill Lerner. [Union Gaming Group]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Hey, guys. Two related questions, both VIP. Let me ask Rob, if I can. In Singapore, Rob, how bridled, I guess is probably since everything is so billed up, rightly, how bridled do you think Rolling Chip really is? You've talked about limits, taking them up, and I suspect the more -- the greater tolerance for risk you have, the greater demand you could see at VIP. So, that's really sort of a structural question, and the others they're more macro about Macao.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think Sheldon answered it very well. I just think there were as far as the markets in Asia, continues to create well -- everybody wants to travel. I think the growth in VIP is not just strategically very, very strong. We have raised our -- when I think we talked about this, we believe &#x2013; I believe very strongly in, and David, Mark, our team believes with and have advised Mike and Sheldon that we think higher day limits is a positive approach to take.</p>
          <p>We've seen enormous action and the swings in Singapore are dramatic, and the volume equally dramatic. I don't know whether they said previously, the demand is there for Singapore. We're privileged enough to operate two unique places, Macao, definitely service a different clientele. I think the difference is we're seeing customer who wants to come to Singapore, can get to Singapore, can move capital to Singapore and doesn't need actually junket intervention.</p>
          <p>What we're seeing is the growth in that market without junket intervention in terms of the credit, et cetera. But I don't know -- I see no reason why we can't grow our business in the VIP segment in Singapore for sure. This is only the beginning, hopefully is not the &#x2013; this is just beginning, not the top.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. And then. . .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>About choice in Macao, what you're asking --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I didn't ask Macao yet. The Macao question really is do I guess with the passage of time now, Rob, and your full focus in gaming globally, what's your sense on what's really going on at the VIP demand level there? Right, so we've been through reserve requirement tightenings that have not had a noticeable, if any, impact on credit issuance or just overall demand. There have been other structural changes and macro factors that, I guess, any naysayer would have been wrong about with respect to impact. So, is there just something we don't understand? And in the mass market, it seems like it's unbelievably nascent for a lot of reasons. But junket on the other side is sort of would love your view on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First of all, I think it's important. We're clear that we mad this bet and it was a magnificent bet. The capacity we have to grow our junket as well as our mass business is just unparalleled. I mean, we're over there. Everyone is pitching to go over there, but we're there, and we'll be there in a big way in a few short months.</p>
          <p>So, I see my job and the people I work with in Singapore, Macao is maximization of the real estate. We made the right macro bet, how we make the thing work and improve our businesses. And I think clearly our mass business has been exceptionally strong and will get better as our properties get better. I think the offerings are terrific. The VIPs are very different business, having been there a couple of days ago and almost trampled just coming off the ferry with families and all kinds of people are going to see Macao. The Macao I started going to 30 years ago is a lot different than Macao today.</p>
          <p>But the VIP is a very different segment. And if you read the publications and the word from naysayers, about the real estate, broken bubble, et cetera. Having been there through last week and having spent a lot of time listening, you don't see evidence of that, you see evidence of a very wealthy, very healthy market. A lot people with a lot of money and a lot of desire to gamble. If there's a problem, I sure didn't see it last week, I went all through Macao on the Cotai as well the principle side, and boy it was sure fluffy at the VIP.</p>
          <p>I went through to all the major houses and it was very, very impressive, and I don't see it. Now, I am not an economist, I can't predict what's going to happen in the real estate in Shanghai or Beijing, that's not my area of expertise, but I can tell you that I'm not seeing any weakness on the part of the junket people. I'm not seeing weakest part of the customers. I think our job is to get our fair share of it and we've yet to do that.</p>
          <p>And I think shoulder up is to grow well past difficulties, but the future is ours and it's growth, it's sunny and as long as our team stays committed and focused. I'm not that where the Chinese economy or the capital, that's beyond our control. Within our control, we build the spaces and we simply cater to the customers and make sure this is right and moving order for. That's my take.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we've got to adjust our budget because we have to send out of towels. We afraid of our towels, but we send them out to people who get egg on to their face for their wrong projections. We're going to send them on to almost every analyst in the Street. Ken, can we fit that in the budget?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If we have money left over.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. If you need change for a billion, give my wife a call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rob. Thanks, a lot  guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bill. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, we have reached the end of our allotted time. I would now turn the call back to management for final remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Final remarks. Well, my final remarks is just what I repeated, which you probably got from me before. I see no reason why our continued growth pattern and our trend going upwards will be abated, will that any of our metrics will contract. I think on the VIP side in Macao, we've got that problem solved. All we have to do is just clear out the spaces and we think we ought to be back to where we should be. We're looking forward to an increase in the gross revenue, but I'm very proud of the fact that what really accounts, you can't put gross revenue in the bank because you've to pay expenses and taxes and commissions.</p>
          <p>So -- but I think that our EBITDA, we continue to lead the pack and by a substantial margin. Now that's the most important thing, we could put that in the bank and that's how we create value for shareholders. So, I see us continuing to go up. I see Singapore as a very, very unique place and I think Macao will also experience it. As more and more people go to places they like, it's like a rising tide, it's going to carry our boats. And because I've never seen a boat stay in the water when the tide went up, unless there was a hole in the boat. And I've never seen a boat stay up in the air, stay up in the air, when the tides went down. So, a rising tide carries our boats. And so, I think Macao will -- look at the percentages of growth in Macao, it's amazing, it's just staggering.</p>
          <p>So, I think that what's happening in Singapore is that we wish that we had greater capacity. I think in next quarter, we'll be reporting some interesting things. And so, my motto for the day is onwards and upwards. Thank you all for being part of this call and we look forward to our next call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>