<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1457978" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-02-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8597</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Trond &#xD8;deg&#xE5;rd Westlie</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="ABG Sundal Collier Norge ASA (Denmark)">Lars Heindorff</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Christopher G. Combe</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Bank Plc (Broker)">Robin F. Byde</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Svenska Handelsbanken AB (Broker Denmark)">Dan Togo Jensen</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="RS Platou Markets AS">Carl C. Bachke</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Capital (Europe) Ltd.">Rob J. Joynson</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Jyske Bank A/S (Broker)">Frans H&#xF8;yer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the A.P. M&#xF8;ller-Maersk Annual Report 2011. Today, I'm pleased to present Group CFO, Trond Westlie. For the first part of this call, all participants will be in listen-only mode and afterwards there'll be a question-and-answer session.</p>
          <p>Speaker, please begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. We're here to cover the full-year results for 2011 for A.P. M&#xF8;ller-Maersk. And I will touch also on some of the Q4 numbers when we go through the presentation. Going to page two, the safe haven or the forward-looking statements. While you watch that, I can start with saying that the &#x2013; 2011 was an acceptable year for A.P. M&#xF8;ller-Maersk, driven by good results in the Oil, the Terminals side as well as the Drilling and Supply side, considering the difficult shipping markets.</p>
          <p>Going then to page three, and a look at the highlights, and as I mentioned, the first bullet, I just covered, and so, all in all an acceptable result for 2011. Maersk Line turned loss-making and is taking actions to restore profitability and improve supply-demand stability. And we also have, during 2011, made significant investments and commitments in the long-term growth in growing industries. So in 2011, we have been executing on the group strategy. We are building and developing the portfolio of discoveries and prospects with the aim to increase the production from 2014 up to the 400,000 barrels equivalent per day exploration.</p>
          <p>Maersk Line has broadened its service palette as well as regained market share. The Daily Maersk is delivering well, and it's a success. APM Terminals has adjusted and expanded its portfolio together with being more efficient. Maersk Drilling have delivered high uptime and also committed for new long-term growth. And we have signed to sell the Maersk LNG and the quoting is scheduled for this week. So all in all, we have delivered on &#x2013; progress on our strategy and making an acceptable result for 2011, considering that the shipping market is difficult.</p>
          <p>Going then to page four, the group financial highlights, the result &#x2013; the improved profits in all major businesses, so if you go to the bottom left on the slide you see that all the columns to the right is actually increasing. They're increasing by actually a total of $1.1 billion, so we are having a very good development in oil terminals, drilling supply and others. The challenge is, of course, the volatility in the shipping sectors, specifically on the Maersk Line. In total, the revenue increase was 7%, the profit decline was 33%.</p>
          <p>And as you can see, the difference is of course that Maersk Line is having a lower number in 2011 of more than $3.3 billion, and the decrease in total is only $1.6 billion and that is sort of just underlying what I'm saying of Maersk Oil terminals and drilling supply. The free cash flow for the year is &#x2013; or the year operating cash flow is $7.3 billion and we have used for capital expenditure $9.8 billion. So the negative free cash flow is $2.5 billion, leaving us at &#x2013; the net interest bearing debt year-end at $15 billion.</p>
          <p>Going to page five, on Maersk Line, the volume &#x2013; we had increased our volume year-over-year by 11% and thereby regaining our market share to a sufficient level. The &#x2013; looking at the numbers of the full year of 2011, the profit is a loss of $600 million. That is due to the decline in rates and also the increase in cost, specifically the bunker that has &#x2013; bunker price increased 35% compared to 2010. The average rate for 2011 was $2,828 per FFE. But you can see that the rate was declining during the year, and in fourth quarter the average rate were $2,671. So, the EBIT per FFE during 2011 was a loss of $75.</p>
          <p>The additional services and the reliability is very good in Maersk Line. The fourth quarter, in average we're at 87.5% and daily Maersk service concept introduced in the fourth quarter had an on-time delivery of 98%. So, we are delivering on the service palette and the increased ease of doing business with our customers and feeling that we get a very good response from our customers on that. A technical thing, in the fourth quarter since the negative results of the fourth quarter is almost $700 million, there is one-off cost of restructuring provisions as well as impairments of slightly more than $100 million.</p>
          <p>Going then to the next page, page six, on Maersk Line; as mentioned, Maersk Line is having its long-term strategy on reliability, ease of doing business, environmental impact and competitiveness. We're still focusing on that even though we are making changes to our pricing strategy as well as taking out capacity in the market. The CMA agreement that was announced last week is going to effectively reduce our capacity on Asia-Europe. We're going to maintain our deployed tonnage but the average speed reduces, as well as we're doing some extra port calls.</p>
          <p>So in total, we do think that that will at least assist visibility in the market. We have increased &#x2013; announced our rate increases for 1 March and 1 April. It remains to be seen how effective they will be. So we are looking positively towards them, but it remains to be seen how effectful it will be over a period of time, because we do see that we have an over-supply in the market. So, we need to focus on the possibilities of additional opportunities to have capacity reduced.</p>
          <p>Going to page seven on Maersk Oil; production declined, as anticipated, during the year with 12% year-over-year due to Qatar and production &#x2013; lower production in Denmark. The U.K. went down as a result of the collision incident that happened in February. And all of this is slightly offset with the increase of production coming out our acquisition in Brazil on the SK Energy, and that is the Polvo Field. The revenue is higher, going up with $1.4 billion from 2010 for the full year due to higher oil price. We have increased the exploration activity and here we see effects of that. We have &#x2013; Chissonga was declared commercial. We are doing &#x2013; working on the development plan and we expect that to be finished either late 2012 or beginning 2013. We see good positive developments on Avaldsnes, part of the Johan Sverdrup field in the Norwegian sector. We have development plans approved on the Golden Eagle and we have hydrocarbon finds that are encouraging. So all in all, there has been good development in our prospect portfolio as well as good progress in all the new development projects. And as a result of having the arbitration with the &#x2013; our Algerian arbitration, that is also &#x2013; have a possibility of coming up in the near future.</p>
          <p>Going then to page eight, continuing on Maersk Oil; on top left you see the Maersk Oil share of production coming down with approximately &#x2013; estimated to come down approximately 20% from 2011 to 2012. We see that that is a high percentage; it's due to FX. It is Qatar that is coming down to the lowest R factor. It is the DUC exchange that we will surrender 20% of DUC to the Danish Government, but the net effect of that should be limited as a result of the compensation that is done on the tax side.</p>
          <p>On the bottom line, we actually see the exploration costs going forward and we see high exploration activity. We have finished 14 exploration wells during 2011. We are involved in our &#x2013; approximately 30 drilling prospects that either are in process or planned in 2012, and it's all our field for development, Angola, Brazil, Kazakhstan, Qatar, U.S., Norway and U.K. So, we expect the drilling exploration costs to be above the $1 billion in 2012.</p>
          <p>Going then to page nine, APM Terminals; a good year for the Terminals side, both on the growth aspect as well as the adjustment of portfolio, in addition to optimizing &#x2013; or enhancing the efficiency. So, we are increasing the underlying results with almost 24%. We are from &#x2013; if you take out the impairments and gains in 2010 and compare it to 2011, we are increasing the results from 2010 number of 492 to 611 in 2011. So, it's a very good progress. It is a turnaround of the inland service together with a lot of efficiencies. And the portfolio expansion where we see Callao, Poti and Gothenburg being ongoing businesses that we have successfully bought. And the Moin and Lazaro Cardenas is going to be greenfield operations that is more on the long haul of expanding the business in Terminals. So looking at the exposure of Terminals going forward, in the emerging market it's a good profile. They had a return on invested capital in 2011 on 13.1% and we see that the margin development is improving, even though that the volume growth is more volatile also for the Terminals.</p>
          <p>Going then to page 10, on Drilling; we're delivering profit in 2011 of almost $500 million, improved efficiency and uptime on most of the rigs as well as introduction &#x2013; 12 months, full year for the new semi-submersibles. That is really what is driving this. We had a very high uptime, been very effective of the planned inspection and upgrades. So a lot of rig days during the year, so a very efficient year for Maersk Drilling. The return on investment capital is 12.7%, up from 11%. And we see that 2012 that we have a good contract base for 2012 but we also have yard space and upgrades in 2012 so that we foresee a slight lower rig days than 2011.</p>
          <p>On Supply Service in page 11, delivering well slightly increasing from $772 million to $824 million in revenue base; developing well on the profit to $210 million. So, the increase is good. The contract coverage in 2011 but also suitable exposure to the spot market for 2012, so we're in a reasonable good position. The second half of 2011 was better than expected due to &#x2013; the North Sea rates went up and it was also higher activity in Brazil and Angola, but that activity level was down on the pricing side with the addition of new vessels. So looking forward, the &#x2013; we see that market is reasonably good on the anchor handling side, but there are still ships coming in on the supply side in the market.</p>
          <p>Going to then page 12, the summary slide on other core businesses; for the tanker side, it has been a challenging market in 2011. We had done some investments, both planned and sort of opportunistic in 2011 as a result of our strategy going forward. We still see a challenging market going forward in most of our segments even though there are differences within the segment in the tanker industry. On Damco, we are continuing margin improvement and portfolio optimization, as you can see in the numbers. And we have acquired a China-based air freight forwarder that will pick up and increase the volume of air freights, which is needed for Damco going forward.</p>
          <p>Svitzer had good development, 11% in revenue growth and a 20% increase in EBITDA development. So all in all, good development focused on the towage in the harbors and efficiency on that together with including new terminal projects for longer-term contracts. Dansk Supermarked Group; so a relative flat market in 2011. Some growth as a result of expansion of new stores, but it was margin pressure, specifically on the non-food, and we also saw a slide from &#x2013; slide towards the discount change in the &#x2013; specifically in the Danish market. Successfully sold off Netto UK with a good gain.</p>
          <p>Going then to page 13 on the consolidated numbers, good growth in &#x2013; or a 7% growth in revenue from $56 billion to $60 billion, driven by volume increase in Maersk Line countered by the rates decrease and the second driver in this development is of course Maersk Oil and Gas. We have a slight decline in EBITDA to $14.661 billion. That leaves the EBIT number for $10.274 billion. The tax increase is &#x2013; in 2011 comes as a result of the composition of our earnings. We have high earnings in Oil and Gas, which has a high tax percentage. We're up to 73% tax in our Oil and Gas division. And as a result of being in tonnage tax in the Shipping side, as a result of changing results we don't see an effect of that. And that means that we are increasing our tax rate and that means that we are delivering a profit for the period &#x2013; or for the year in 2011 of $3.377 billion.</p>
          <p>The cash flow from operating activities is sort of $7.3 billion and cash flow used for capital expenditure is short of $10 billion comprising also of the acquisition of SK Energy of $2.4 billion during the year. Net interest-bearing debt is then $15.3 billion. The return on invested capital for the group is 8.3%. And I also would like then to underline that this is a year where we're not delivering on the Shipping side. We are delivering specifically improving on the Terminals, the offshore service we're drilling and supply ships, as well as Maersk Oil. And that is the reason why we actually are delivering the rates on invested capital of 8.3%. The Board has proposed to maintain the dividend level of NOK 1,000 for our B-shares or per share of a nominal value of NOK1,000 and that is the same as in 2010.</p>
          <p>Going then to page 14 and look at the waterfall on the development of net interest-bearing debt, the EBITDA is $14.6 billion, slight change &#x2013; minimum change in working capital. We paid taxes of $6 billion. We spent money on the CapEx side of $9.8 billion, paid financial items for $0.9 billion and dividends and others paid for short of just $1 billion, leaving the net interest-bearing debt at $15.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Going to page 15 on the outlook statement for 2012, the A.P. M&#xF8;ller-M&#xE6;rsk Group expects a positive result, lower than 2011. Cash flow used for capital expenditure is expected to be around the same level as in 2011, while cash flow from operating activities is expected to fall in line with the result.</p>
          <p>Going to the outlook for the core growth business unit, Maersk Oil expects a result significantly below the result for 2011 based on expected 20% decline in the share of oil and gas production to a level of around 265,000 barrels oil equivalents per day at an average price of $105. The production decline is predominantly caused by share of production in Qatar and the natural maturation of the North Sea fields. The transfer of 20% ownership of DUC to the Danish North Sea Fund by mid-2012 will reduce the group's production share in Denmark, but will have no impact on the net earnings. Exploration costs are expected to be above $1 billion.</p>
          <p>Maersk Line expects a negative result in 2012 as a consequence of excess capacity. Global demand for seaborne containers is expected to increase by 4% to 6% in 2012. We expect a lower growth than that &#x2013; lower on the Asia-Europe trades, but supported by high growth in the North-South trades. APM Terminals expects a result above 2011 and to grow more than the market, supported by volumes from new terminals.</p>
          <p>Maersk Drilling has almost full contract coverage at attractive rates in 2012 and expects the result in line with 2011. Maersk Supply Service expects the result at the same level as in 2011, with one-third of the available vessel days in 2012 not yet contracted. The total result from all other activities is expected to be at the same level as in 2011, excluding divestments in gains and impairments. And of course, the rest of this is substantial. It is very much dependent on price expectations in the container market as well as the world oil price, which are the big drivers, as well as currency effects on this. You have some sensitivity effects on the right side on page 15.</p>
          <p>So for the final remarks on page 16, we do see an acceptable result for 2011, driven by the positive result in Maersk Oil, APM Terminals, as well as the offshore service in drilling and supply service. The strong results and continued focus in oil and terminal and drilling business, we see that we &#x2013; the growth allocation for investments going in 2012, we will focus on oil terminal and drilling business. We continue to deliver on Maersk Line strategy. We have regained our market share to a satisfactory level and going forward, we will defend that market share. We are focusing now on profitability and restoring freight rates with the rate increases and focusing on reducing our cost and efficiencies. We have started to adjust our capacity. And as of today, we see no need for new capacity commitments, short to medium term. On Maersk Oil and Gas, we will continue our development on prospects. Together with that, we will focus on making sure that the declining production will stop at 2014 and then go upwards towards the long-term plan of getting to 400,000 barrels a day.</p>
          <p>Overall, we would say that the 2012 will be a challenging year on different circumstances. For the Shipping side, we are in the supply-demand challenge as well as &#x2013; even though we are taking actions it is uncertain weather that supply &#x2013; that those effects will be sufficient to actually create that balance. On the oil and gas side, we're in the midst of the declining production towards 2014 where it changes. But we're also in the midst of high investment phase in both prospects and development plan. We are en route towards our 400,000 barrels per day, but we will have challenging years when it comes to P&amp;L effects, as we are seeing for 2012.</p>
          <p>So with that, that is our presentation. So, I open up for questions and answers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Our first question come from Mr. Lars Heindorff from ABG. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, gentlemen. A question regarding the container business; you mentioned a bit that you have planned or you have announced rate increases here from the 1st of March and again from 1st of April. Could you give us any sort of highlight or any sort of flavor on what has been the impact thus far from customers and also to what extent you believe you'll actually be able to implement those rate increases?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, what we have seen is after some others of our competitors announced those rate increases, we also announced our rate increases and have seen that the rest of the market has followed that announcement. We are positive that these rate increases will stick, but there's always the risk of supply overhang in the market. So, it comes down to a price discipline that needs to be the leader. So, I guess that we have to wait and see how first quarter pans out to actually see how much it actually is. Our ambition is, of course, to maintain that and we are focusing on that right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Earlier on you have been stating now for the last couple of quarters that your main focus was to maintain your market share. Is this a change of strategy from Maersk Line that you're now focusing more on profitability rather than market share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the &#x2013; during 2011, we have regained the lost market share that we actually lost in 2009. So, we have picked up market share during 2011. We are comfortable with the market share we have right now. So, the situation is that we haven't changed the strategy. The strategy levers of Maersk Line are still the four elements of environment, ease of doing business, the reliability as well as the competitiveness by having the ambition of beating the market by 5% margin. As of now, we are developing that strategy very well. We have come far in the last four years. We still need to focus on it, but we have come far. So looking at that, this is more a change of tactics relative to that we regained the market share and now we see that we're going to grow with the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then regarding your capacity growth with the reductions that you're now doing and the slow steaming you're doing on Asia-Europe, you said you're going to reduce capacity by 9%. I'm curious to find out what sort of growth we are looking at capacity-wise for the full-year 2012, whether you will have at least some numbers of new deliveries coming in? So what do you expect to be sort of total capacity growth for 2012 if you adjust for this 9% decline on Asia-Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, our &#x2013; we don't have any new deliveries coming in on Asia-Europe during 2012. The competitors &#x2013; some of our competitors have; I don't have that sort of &#x2013; that number top of my head right now. But as we see it right now, we do think that as a result of new capacity coming in on the Asia &#x2013; that we've said coming in on the Asia-Europe, there is a need for additional capacity reductions for it to have some sort of stability in the market. So we are, on our part, looking at that toolbox to see how much we can actually do in the future. So, we're not excluding that we are going to do more on the capacity reductions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then the last question regarding the Oil and Gas, you've earlier mentioned that an announcement regarding Chissonga would be out mid-2012 and now, if I recall it correctly, you stated that you expect an announcement late 2012, early 2013. We have seen now for the past couple of quarters that you have sort of postponed the expected announcement regarding Chissonga. Could you give us an idea or maybe an update about what's going on and what is the reason for this postponement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, to take the last one part first, the reason is pure technical. I mean we are &#x2013; have declared the field commercial to the Angolan authorities. So in that regard, we have &#x2013; I mean it is &#x2013; has defined as &#x2013; at least formally been filed as a commercial field. When it comes to the development plans, we are doing &#x2013; we have done replacement wells during late 2011. We are doing another replacement well during the fall of &#x2013; sorry, during the spring of 2012, and then all these elements actually lead into the technical development of the field. So, that is why the final element of development plan has been &#x2013; is basically postponed as a result of new finance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Christopher Combe from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning. I just have a follow-up question on market share. So looking at the last few quarters, clearly you've restored your market position and today you've announced that you find it to be satisfactory. How sensible do you think that is in light of the numerous operational tie-ups which have yet to really take full effect? And could that potentially shift the priority back to market share solely, which is what was suggested by your recent press release, that that is the top priority?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I do think that we have to look at this both in terms of what has happened during the last year. We have seen at least in the fall that we have seen some alliances coming together as well as new alliances being made on the infrastructure consolidation. What that leads to is, of course, difficult to say, but we do think that this is partly a response to our daily Maersk offering that we have introduced into the market.</p>
          <p>Having said that, we're still of the opinion that we do think that consolidation &#x2013; real consolidation in the industry is needed. It is fragmented. And as a result of that, we are looking at to see what effect the consolidation in the infrastructure is actually happening &#x2013; is going to deliver going forward, and that remains to be seen. How sensible it is, is always a question, but the industry is in need of making the necessary returns going forward. We do think that our market share is satisfactory as we see it right now. We will defend that market share. So we have been very clear that if we see new changes in that, we will make certain that we take actions to actually uphold our market share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And if I hear you correctly then, is it the right conclusion that you're more confident in the absence of true consolidation and perhaps a bit more skeptical of what kind of action competitors might take with these looser operational agreements?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the answer is basically yes to that. And I do think that we have seen, as you say, the looser at least infrastructure consolidation. And that we &#x2013; remains to be seen what effects that does on the longer-term stability on the supply-demand level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's &#x2013; and one very last one on oil and gas. Can you give us a big picture sort of in terms of expectations with regard to reporting going forward; should we expect any material sort of consistency or improvement in the detail of reporting on incremental development?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we have said earlier, we are working on that incremental improvement and hopefully we will get into that &#x2013; I cannot give you a timeline on that because that is not decided, but we have improved. Internally, we are working on making sure that we can consistently report with the aligned market practice. So, we are working on that. That's why I cannot give you a date.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Robin Byde from HSBC. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Oh, yeah. Morning, guys. Just a couple from me please. Firstly, on the container side and bunker surcharges, could you just update us on how much of the increased bunker costs at the moment you can recover or what's the sort of recovery rate and should we be thinking 50% or 80%?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, just on the terminals business, can you just talk a bit about the pricing environment? Things are tough out there. Can you lift prices? If so, in which regions and then just a follow-up to that one if you like, can you just remind us about the mix of business between Maersk Line and other carriers at your terminals? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To take the terminal side, first. Do you think that we increased slightly on the third-party business in the terminal side? I believe the number is 46% or 47%, up to 46% or 47% right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So in that sense, we are still working on third-party involvement and it is increasing even though the increase this year in 2011 was not as high as it was in 2010. Coming to the recovery rate on the BAF during 2011, it was a challenge during 2011 as a result of the prices and due to the fact that the prices are coming down that much, the long-term contracts is not that many. So the recovery rates as of 2011 is around the 60% level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your second question on the pricing environment, it is, of course, a challenge to see the pricing environment specifically in the regions where you have clear oversupply in the market. And as I said earlier, on the questions, it is hard to say how much of that is going to stick. We are working hard that these price increases will stick as for now. But then we have to look at how the reactions in the market will be and have to apply with the market because as I also mentioned, we are satisfied with our market share of today. But we will define that market share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So just in terms of terminal handling rates, do you think you'll be able to lift those this year at all across your whole network?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I mean, one way is, of course, the bunker adjustment factor but there are other surcharges there. I do think that the effect on other surcharges is not going to be that dramatic. It's still good. When it comes to the bunker adjustment factor, it is difficult to say how much long-term contracts and how much short-term contracts and how the market is going to develop. So it's difficult to give you another guidance on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Dan Togo from Handelsbanken. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning, gentlemen. I'm sorry to go back to this rate outlook, et cetera, but you haven't really commented on how much of the segue rate increases in Asia-Europe that you sort of implied for your guidance, you're guiding a forward loss in your container business in 2012, but how much of this and what is the impact you expect from the slack rate increases both here from 1st of March and from 1st of April?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we are not being specific on that. And that is, of course, due to sensitive issues relative to the market. So we cannot be specific on how much rate increases we put in the numbers. We have delivered to you guys actually the sort of the analysis on the work. The rate increases that we have now and the other one is that we believe that Maersk Line is one of the negatives this year. We're coming in &#x2013; if you look at the rates of the fourth quarter, so we're coming into the fourth quarter of 2012 and it's a very difficult situation. The rate increases is going forward from 1st of March to the 1st of April, and I can't give you further guidance on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fair enough. Then one question on your contract coverage. It is, of course, varying a lot between markets. But if we look at Asia-Europe, how is your contract coverage going into 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We usually &#x2013; we're not commenting on that. But since we are commenting on the recovery factor as a result of the short-term contracts, it is, of course, if you take the weighted balance of the previous years, we are shorter today than we have been earlier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just a household question on oil and gas. The tax rate in oil and gas, 73% this year &#x2013; or in 2011 you mentioned. Should we expect the same in 2012?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We expect it to actually rise a bit and that is due to how we actually are developing. And the reason for that is we are having the average rate on the countries where we produce oil, is basically a stable short of &#x2013; a short rate of 70%, so we are assured of that. But since we are developing in new countries where we have a slightly conservative element of not &#x2013; of recognizing the deferred tax assets or using the tax loss carry-forwards, we're seeing that it's still development coming on in the U.S., in Brazil, in Angola that we're not going to be able to recognize for a period. And therefore, we see that the tax rate is going to increase.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just one final question on Containers; how close you &#x2013; are you to considering actually laying up vessels in order to mitigate the oil capacity we are seeing in the market right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As I said on my wrap-up sheets, we basically have all the alternatives in the toolbox and we are evaluating all of them even though no concrete decisions yet have been made.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But I guess it's a decision that needs to be made within the next month or so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we are well aware on the situation, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Carl Bachke from RS Platou Markets. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen. Look, if I may, could I go back to Maersk Oil and have a question regarding the Qatar PSA. Do you implicitly are now guiding significant lower entitlement volume for 2012 even though that your price assumption is actually lower than realized in 2011. Can you give us any flavor on this sort of surprise in the large drop and any particular sort of contract elements there that we should be aware of?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The element is that we have had a step-wise decline in one other factors that is in the PSA agreement. Now we have at the end of 2011, we have come to that point as we have come to a step-down on that element what we call the R factor. And as a result of that, we now are having a step-down and that is down to the lowest level in that PSA agreement. So we're not &#x2013; we're at the lowest level and that is why there is such a significant change from 2010 to 2011. Going forward, we will not see those changes because then it's more  an element of the oil price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. So I take it that you are at this lowest level and hence, all things being equal, you will stay at this level but not go further down. Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just a final question, could you give us any updates, if any, on the process for extension of that same contract beyond 2017?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, no, I cannot give you any updates more than we're still working on Qatar Petroleum. We have very good relations. We're working diligently on potentials and possibilities. There's no formal process on the extension yet. But as I said earlier, we have done this field now from the mid-90s. We have been successful in developing it. We have very good relations with the Qataris. So we hope and feel that we are in a good position but it's still going to be a competition in the end but good relations with Qatar Petroleum.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And if I may just one final question. In your guidance of 265,000 barrels per day in 2012, does that imply a certain growth in both UK and Brazil production from 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It involves this slight element of our <mark type="indiscernible" /> (45:52) coming into play or being restored in second half of 2012. And I do think that Maersk is going to be in production late fourth quarter but it's not going to be any significant amounts relative to the 265,000 barrels a day average.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. Robert Joynson from Macquarie. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody. A few questions from me. First of all, on containers, could you possibly give us some color on for the Asia-Europe contracts which has been agreed since the start of the year, is it possible to indicate what proportion of those contracts, if any, have been index-linked? And also just thinking on Asia for the time being, your guidance of 4% to 6% growth in volumes for the Group as a whole with lower growth on Asia-Europe, could you indicate possibly just how much lower on Asia-Europe we should thinking of?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, when it comes to the sort of the details on contracts and how long they are and whether they index or not, we're not disclosing on that kind of level. So I'm sorry to not be able to help you on that. When it comes to the growth aspects, we do think that as a result of our relative wait on where we are bigger in contracts or bigger at players in the different regions, we think it's fair to say in our outlook that even though we see the market growth being 46%, we have a higher exposure towards the Asia-Europe relative to many of the other geographies. Therefore, we are focusing and we are expecting that the growth in Europe, at least on the GDP side, is going to be low, zero or maybe negative. And we are uncertain to how much the volume growth is going to be on Asia-Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. And then just a question on the Terminals business as well; if you look, the EBITDA margins of that business consistently improved over the past several years, could you maybe just provide some color on how much room for further margin improvement remains there over the next two, three years maybe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think that the low-hanging fruit is basically taken out. We have operational and we have the efficient. We have operational-wise, we have adjusted the portfolio so I don't think it &#x2013; but we are sort of working long term relative to get efficiency measures into play. And we do also have, of course, some optimization to do on our portfolio because we still have under performing terminals. So there is still work to be done but the low-hanging fruit has been taken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, fine, thank you. Just a final question on Oil &amp; Gas. In terms of the 20% expected decline in production in 2012, should we expect roughly a 20% decline in both the North Sea and Qatar or should we expect one of those businesses to be significantly better or worse than that number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we haven't allocated that and we basically said 20% due to the fact that we are handing over the North Sea while it's mostly both maturing and declining productions as a natural course as well as we we're giving away the 20% midyear to the Danish government. So that's the two elements but we haven't guided on the segregation between those two.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the Mr. Frans H&#xF8;yer from Jyske Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning. You mentioned the 9% reduction of capacity on your Asia-Europe loops. Could this tonnage be put to good use in other trades or do you plan to idle them?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we said in the presentation, as we stated very clearly that we're not taking or idling any ships. They are going to be maintained. We're going do a  slower steam. We're going to take the steam further down on the roundtrip. And in addition to that, we are doing more port calls as a result of the agreement we have done with CMA. And totally, we will maintain the ships and routes but we will take out capacity of 9%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And with regard to chartered vessels, you have increased that part of the fleet quite significantly over the past few years and I was wondering whether given your statement also that you feel there's no need to make any further new build orders, do you have much scope and perhaps plans to reduce your fleet by handing back tonnage to owners?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as we said in the presentation, we do have sort of the toolbox that includes all elements of the possibilities of reducing capacity. So handing back tonnage is, of course, one of them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll come back to the rate assumptions which is underlying your guidance. I understand the point you make about not wishing to discuss the sensitive Asia-Europe trade. But so without getting too close, could you talk to us about the level of $2,828 per forty-foot container in 2011? Do you foresee that &#x2013; do you assume in your guidance that that number will be going up in 2012? And could you give us a rough ballpark figure or a range for how much percentage increase you foresee?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well that is basically just a different way of asking a question on the rates. So the element is, as I said, I do think that it is important to understand that even though the rates were more than $2,800 in average during 2011, the rates were declining. So starting point of going into 2012 is the average of fourth quarter going and that is 2006 unchanged. And so...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Understood.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...I do think that has been sort of the starting point. We do acknowledge that that rate is too low to have a sustainable return in the industry. And therefore, we have taken actions on our part to focus more on the profitability side and we'll see what the consequences of our actions will be in the market.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And finally just a question on that $105 million charge you mentioned in line in Q4, was that included above the EBITDA level or below the EBITDA level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Included in the EBITDA level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Mr. <mark type="indiscernible" /> (53:20) from Carnegie. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. If I may return just to the question regarding market share. You say you are satisfied regarding the current market share but looking into 2013 when you start to get the first 18,000 TEU ship delivered, are you still satisfied with the current market share taking into account what will be delivered are very large ships next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As we see the development and the growth in the market and we do expect that to be within sort of the scenario that we are playing that the Triple-E ships will come into play and it will be an effective contribution to our fleet on the Asia-Europe. And we do foresee that that will be embedded in our statement of growing with the market with the existing market share.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So with your current market share, you will be able to utilize those 18,000 TEU ships satisfactorily?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The answer to that is yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The last thing, regarding charter cost, I can see you haven't done a split regarding shipping costs, vessels costs. Could you give us some kind of indication about how much we should expect that the vessel costs in total will decline in 2012, taking into account the lower charter rates we have seen and the duration of your portfolio of chartered ships?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as we said on the cost increase during 2011 compared to 2012, we have seen terminal charges and de novo charges and a lot of other charges of the more monopolistic nature having increased some and driving our cost side. How the TC and what level of TC rates is going to decline as a result of today's market and sort of &#x2013; we haven't quantified that but that's one element of our focus point of making sure that the cost per FFE is coming down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>There are no further questions at this time. Oh, we have a question from Mr. Christopher Combe from JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Well, I just had one follow-up regarding the Triple-Es. I believe probably one or two years ago, there was some disclosure that chartering capacity Asia to Europe was about 10% of total for A.P. M&#xF8;ller. How do you foresee that in the future post the 20 deliveries of the Triple-Es? Would we expect to see that number move towards Europe?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the element of what kind of &#x2013; how many ships we have? Actually, I don't remember how much ships we have on time charter as relative to Asia-Europe compared to the others. I do think that we have disclosed quite extensively as to on how much time charters in total we have, but I don't have that percentage. What we have as a view is that growth for the &#x2013; we want to maintain ownership of our strategic vessels. And for those type of vessels that has a market or commercial market out there that is tradable with outside our strategic focus points we can have the vessels time chartered. So other than that, I don't think I can be more specific for your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
          <p>[05M8JC-E Trond &#xD8;deg&#xE5;rd Westlie]</p>
          <p>Is that all? Thank you for all the questions. This is the result for the 2011 and the fourth quarter. I do think I just want to reiterate acceptable results for 2011 driven by Maersk Oil, Terminals, as well as Supply and Drilling. Good progress on those. Difficult shipping market. Specifically, you'll see that Maersk Line is coming into a negative in the fourth quarter. That is why we have taken actions to improve our own position relative to the supply/demand balance as well as the pricing environment. And we do think that the 2012 is going to be a complicated year but we do also see that we have good starting points from the businesses that went well in 2011.</p>
          <p>So with that, thank you very much for listening and we'll see you when we announce the first quarter result. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>