<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1171640" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Interim 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-07-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>846</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Bernard Arnault, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jean-Jacques Guiony, Finance</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Antonio Belloni, Group Managing Director</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Christope Navarre, Wines and Spirits</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Philippe Pascal, Watches and Jewelry</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Yves Carcelle, Fashion and Leather Goods</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you for attending this presentation of our First Half Results. This is an easy exercise this evening because the performance is very good as you could tell by reading the press release which we just have published. We have a 12% organic growth, further increase of the operating margin.</p>
          <p>We have improvement in our operations everywhere including in developed countries in Europe and in emerging economies, in particular Asia, where in the first half of 2008 we had an excellent response from the customers for our products, the performance in the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>The second half of 2007 was similar to the performance of the first half of 2008. We have the operating &#x2013; the profit from recurring operations up 7%, of course, there is a foreign exchange effect on the like-for-like basis, the growth would have been 19%. Operating margin is 20% for the first time, so up in the first half, and the net income is up 7%.</p>
          <p>So once again, we're able to show that LVMH is able to continue a sustained growth, both in profit and in revenue, in spite of the environment where monetary conditions are a source of concern around the world, and yet we manage to pull through, the first half then of 2008, we have to point out that there is a good balance between the various countries where we are present in terms of growth, very strong growth indeed in the U.S., very strong growth as well in Asia. And there is very good growth in Europe for all our brands, all the brands of the Groups &#x2013; of the Group are up in spite of the foreign exchange situation &#x2013; for the exchange rate situation and the general economic climate. Louis Vuitton in particular, has recorded double-digit growth throughout its business lines, and its operating margin is just as outstanding as ever.</p>
          <p>In the first half of 2008, we've recorded great growth in Perfumes &amp; Cosmetics. That growth is very high, indeed up more than 12% and very significant compared to the competitors, because it is at least three times that of our nearest competitors. Growth in our profit is also remarkable, as regards Wines &amp; Spirits, the strong growth in business in the second half of 2007 made up for slower growth in the first quarter. The reason why it was slow in the first quarter is that we had a price increase that had been anticipated at the end of 2007, and that slowed growth. Watches &amp; Jewelry are also doing great, there is significant growth.</p>
          <p>Major event was the acquisition of Hublot, and we'd like to greet their leaders here in this room today. The Hublot watches are remarkable watches. They are not in our figures yet, because we haven't consolidated the figures, but in the second half of the year we will see the Hublot figures.</p>
          <p>Selective Retailing is also growing very well, in particular Sephora have confirmed their profits month after month, especially in the U.S. In China as well, very good presence of Sephora and in Europe indeed, Sephora is very dynamic indeed with excellent performances.</p>
          <p>Now what's the outlook for the second half of 2008? The economic and monetary contexts are uncertain, having said that, the position hasn't been too good for the past six months. I believe that in economic terms, things are not going to get better but they are not going to get much worse. In monetary terms, the position isn't good, but I can't imagine the dollar going much further down than it is already.</p>
          <p>So in this context, we are fairly confident that we should be able, in the second half of 2008, to produce high performances very much in line with the performances of the first half, and indeed July has been right in line with the performance of H1. Indeed to sustain our objectives for the second half, we have a number of new launches, in particular for Wines &amp; Spirits, and Christophe Navarre will tell you about that.</p>
          <p>Perfumes &amp; Cosmetics as well, and we have a number of initiatives underway, Dior with man perfumes, Guerlain and others as well, so here we are very confident for the second half. For Watches &amp; Jewelry, as I was saying, we will be incorporating the Hublot business, and of course Hublot is doing extremely well. It's difficult to find new products and I certainly am grateful to Mr. Biver for making it possible to acquire these goods.</p>
          <p>They are very difficult to get a hold of. And we have a number of new shops opening around the world, so we'll tell you about this in the presentations to come, and we have also good &#x2013; well, a number of new launches and specific initiatives for more the specific new openings. We'll tell you more about that as well.</p>
          <p>So as regards H2, I believe we will be able to improve on our market shares, like we did in the first half, and we will strengthen our position as leaders in the luxury goods business for LVMH. And I can certainly confirm the objectives for tangible growth in our performance in the second half of 2008, and now Jean-Jacques Guiony will give you details about the figures for H1.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. Good evening, I am going to run through the financial highlights for the first half. As last year, we wanted to combine the announcement on revenue and on profit. So, I will start with a few slides on the revenue to detail the performance.</p>
          <p>So growth as Mr. Arnault &#x2013; organic growth 12% of our revenue for the first half, 5% in euros to achieve 7.8 billion in euros &#x2013; the difference between the two is 7%. That's a currency effect on our revenue of 7%, no doubt the highest that we've had to bear.</p>
          <p>If we look by business segment, Wines &amp; Spirits show organic growth of 6%. You'll recall that organic growth for the first quarter was very modest &#x2013; close on 1% and we therefore recovered the situation in the second half. More about that in a moment. Continued good performance in Fashion and Leather Goods 14%, Perfumes and Cosmetics 13% for the first half, Watches and Jewelry high at 15%. That's the highest score across the group. 15% organic growth for the first half in Selective Retailing also on a high note. There's a particularly strong currency effect on retailing because of the exposure to the dollar.</p>
          <p>Turning now to revenue by a quarter to illustrate what I said a moment ago, Wines and Spirits, Christopher will speak to that but far better in the first quarter than the second. Q1, there was a timing of price increases with inventories in our main distributors towards the end of the year, so sales suffered from that price hike and the inventories and that was partly resolved in the second quarter with organic growth of 6% on the half, stability of growth in the Q1 and Q2 in Fashion and Leather Goods and Perfumes and Cosmetics. Selective Retailing, essentially Travel Retail activities was slightly more &#x2013; posted a slightly more modest growth towards the end of the &#x2013; but of course Sephora had showed remarkable performance at the end of the first and second halves.</p>
          <p>Sales by geographic region, Japan is still losing 1%, that's the impact of local growth. You will see there is no particular currency effect in Japan for the first half. The yen was similar to last year, the U.S. losing just over 1%, that's not a local growth but a currency effect because the dollar lost 14%. That impacts on our revenue by geographic area in euros and the other areas recovered these drop in percentages Europe that grows slightly.</p>
          <p>Just a word on the growth of our main geographic areas. The U.S. dollar growth 9%, very favorable. Much is said about the slowdown in the U.S. area. We don't really see it. 9% growth, Wines and Spirits are still in slightly negative territory but a figure that's far better than Q1. The inventory effect that weighed on sales for the quarter that is disappearing. Fashion and Leather Goods remarkable figures, ditto for Perfumes and Cosmetics, slight slowdown in Watches and Jewelry and Selective Retailing. Sephora is continuing to post exceptional performance.</p>
          <p>Japan, it's more challenging minus 6% growth on the half shared by most of the businesses. Wines and Spirits continue to post challenging performance in Japan, a very big inventory effect because of the scale of the price hikes in the Q1. It's a seasonal activity. Champagne vary Q4 so it's difficult to draw down the inventory levels challenging performance for the second half of the year which hopefully should be better. Asia, these are figures in euros, very favorable, 13%. Most local currencies are pegged to the dollar. You need to add between 10 and 14% depending on the country to have the local currency growth.</p>
          <p>Local currency growth equal to 25% in Asia, exceptional figures, good across countries, of course China which is driving growth in the area, Hong Kong, Macao, but also Taiwan, Korea. The whole area is in a very favorable situation. Europe, 10% growth performance that remains very good, shared across business segments. Wines &amp; Spirits had a first quarter relatively modest putting in a far better performance in Q2. As expected, Wines &amp; Spirits didn't enter promotional approach in Q1 and so have achieved far sounder growth in Q2 with excellent figures. Fashion &amp; Leather Goods very good. Watches also up. Very commendable performance in Sephora across Europe, posted a remarkable performance all in all across U.S., Asia, Europe, very useful growth levels.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the income statement, with first off revenue, 5% at 7.8 billion, gross margin up 20 basis points, 65.6% faster than revenues, good containment of income and expenses. Advertising up 6%. Administrative expenses in line with revenue, up 5%. So, profit from recurring operations 1.5 billion, up 7%. We'll see the impact on profit from recurring operations but we're very proud to have a performance across the half where profit from recurring operations is growing faster than revenue. Other income and expenses not much to say, at a low level essentially, depreciation of brands, financial income, tax on profits, 28.5% of the pre-tax profits, and group share of net profit up 7% in line with profit from recurring operations.</p>
          <p>Just a word on the <mark type="inaudible" /> of profit from recurring operations by business segment. Wines &amp; Spirits posting a growth of 4% for a variation of revenue in euros but slightly negative. Good cost control managed by this business segment during the first half to achieve a growth in profit against the challenging sales. Fashion and Leather Goods up 5%. Perfumes and Cosmetics, Watches and Jewelry posting good performance, far higher than that of revenue in euro with considerable margin improvements in both cases. Selective Retailing with a 5% growth is slightly lower than that of its revenue. There's a dollar effect there that is quite significant, so in total 7% growth of profit from recurring operations.</p>
          <p>Just a word on the currency effect. It's the same approach every time we present our results. 170 million which is a sad record but we've never had such a currency impact that was so negative. 12% on revenues, so excluding the currency impact, our profit would not have grown by 7% but 19%. We also see that the currency impact is highly focused on Fashion and Leather Goods, 112 million leathers of course at dollar effect which was quite predictable very considerably but Fashion &amp; Leather Goods, which achieves much of its profits in sales in Japan also has a yen currency effect but not on the sales because the rate was almost constant from quarter-to-quarter but important hedging gains last year, that would not replicated at Q1 this year, so there's a negative currency impact on the yen, which affects Fashion &amp; Leather Goods in particular.</p>
          <p>A word on financial income: Firstly, the financial cost &#x2013; the cost of debt; cost of debt, debt on average remained stable across the first half as came last year, but rates increased by 10%, average rate was 4.5% last year, 5.5%, hence the increase in the cost of debt that you can see on that chart. Currency hedges &#x2013; the cost remains stable for the first time, it will no doubt not happen again, it's stable at a high level. The annual cost of currency hedges is of the order of 60 to &#x20AC;70 million, so the first half we've notched up an important part of this cost. So the cost will no doubt be lower in the second half unless particular currency hedge operations arise given impact in currencies that we can't predict today.</p>
          <p>Results on CapEx, dividends, sales from disposals, that's about stable as last year, 60 million so in total financial income of the same order as last year with 102 million. The financial structure has not changed significantly from hub-to-hub. Inventory levels have increased. We see in the balance-sheet structure linked to be increase in our business and inventories through the non-current liabilities, an increase proportion of the long-term debt has increased compared to short-term debt and considerable liquidity, because we have four billion of un-drawn credit lines for our treasury bill line of just over one billion. So we still have a flow of treasury to meet any requirements, which is useful in the rather ill-equipped markets that we have today.</p>
          <p>On cash flow, our cash flow from operations up by 4% from 1.1 to 1.150 billion, slightly lower than the profit from recurring operations, there's not much to say about that. The working capital requirements have increased quite significantly, this is an inventory effect. We have all several inventory effects, the traditional which is that of Wines &amp; Spirits that constitutes the reserve for future growth. So we increase the Ode V and Wine, Cognac and Champagne inventories and then Vuitton last year ended with high volume growth and inventory levels which were too low and which needed to be replenished so we've begun to replenish inventory levels at Vuitton to avoid running out in stores and thirdly, it &#x2013; for the other Fashion and Leather Goods, we have a system where we deliver to our customers sooner, which is excellent for revenue and profit but as a corollary we have to build inventories and this has a negative impact on working capital and on inventories in particular, increase in our CapEx &#x2013; 455 million, growth that is essentially due to Vuitton's Sephora retail activities that are working very well today and we've decided to continue to invest in those businesses so that they can expand in the future. So in total a change in available cash flow, which is almost balanced across the half. Lastly debt &#x2013; &#x20AC;4.2 billion at the end of June traditionally it's high. The night of December 31, because we pay the bulk of our taxes and dividends during the first half. Debt last year was 3.8 billion at the same period, the increase of equity half. So the gearing has got &#x2013; is at 34% not too different from last year which was at 32% that's what I wished to say. Over to Tony.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon and let's now look at the details of the various businesses and then we'll give the floor to my other colleagues. In Portofino, we have the Christian Dior Parfums, perfumes this is a good &#x2013; by way of introduction if you look at all our brands we have in organic growth of 13% throughout the product lines and that's better than the average. Profit from the recurring operation is 22%. We have an organic growth &#x2013; well significant organic growth around the world specifically in Europe, Asia and the United States. Parfums Christian Dior has continued to its position as the world star to growth is a strong sustainable, profitable and lies in a true commitment to quality. The improvement in Perfumes and Fragrances is based on the vitality of our big names, J'Adore, in make-up good performances, indeed best reflects the success of the latest launches, in particular Addict and DiorSkin the &#x2013; cosmetics for the face. Guerlain, is doing well. We have a Terracotta and Orchid&#xE9;e Imp&#xE9;riale which are strong, strengthen our position, in the higher range. We also have good performances with the Givenchy and this is in particular, Ange ou D&#xE9;mon perfume, Make Up For Ever, Acqua di Parma and Parfums Loewe also improved of course, our product range and our presence in the stores for the strategic perspective for 2008.</p>
          <p>This strategy hasn't changed. We want to improve market shares but also improve operating margin and that strategy has served us well for the past &#x2013; in the past years. Our priority is of course to improve quality and growth of Parfums Christian Dior and first and foremost we have a significant program to support the big names and that of course is the best expression of our brand J'Adore, Capture, Poison, Addict. Escale &#xE0; Portofino is a great success, but the major event of the year was the launch of a new men's perfume, Dior Homme Sport which is embodied by or represented by actor Jude Law. We'll also have strong developments in other brands. For Parfums Givenchy we have this new mascara, which was so successful that we had to double production. So with Givenchy, we have Play, new perfume that has come out in September and we have Justin Timberlake, an outstanding ambassador for that perfume.</p>
          <p>For benefit we have this sort of a different sort of unusual approach, very San Francisco look, which has made it a very profiteer in Asia and then on the picture you have KenzoPower that confirms the Japanese star of this brand with this refined outline and this is Jude Law as I said, the ambassador of the Dior Homme Sport and you can see the picture during, the clip during the Olympic games.</p>
          <p>If we look at the Selective Retailing this is the picture for the Sephora shop in the Netherlands, so we have 13% growth in revenue in the first half, the profit from recurring operations is up 5% and this is due partly to the fact that that's a negative effect of the dollar, but all regions are looking up. For DFS, we have good revenue and profitability &#x2013; are, the Japanese tourists &#x2013; sorry the Chinese tourists are stepping up business in Hong Kong and Singapore, where there's a larger share of revenue. The new territories in particular the joint venture in Vietnam, the new stores in the T3 Singapore Airport and in Auckland Airport, to these had a successful launch and we are confident in the future as well, and then we have the product mix is migrating towards the higher end. Of course, all the categories are doing well, but Cosmetics, Wines &amp; Spirits are speeding up their performances. Regarding Miami Cruise Line that is on the ships, the performance is varied but by and large the performance is high and our work in terms of merchandizing and improvement in the store, this has made up for the lower propinquity on the part &#x2013; sorry, the lower proclivity of the part of U.S. customers to purchase luxury goods.</p>
          <p>Regarding Sephora, we have an outstanding performance in all continents and especially in Hong Kong, U.S. and France and a good performance of sephora.com. Innovation of course is what will make us successful around the world, that we have as many as 809 stores around the world. So this is a huge network with as many as 53 new openings since the beginning of the year. Of course new openings take us to new territories, Quebec, the Netherlands and a number of new towns in China.</p>
          <p>On 17, July 1998 the first Sephora store opened in the United States in SoHo in New York city. 10 years later in the self same shop on 17 July, 2008 we had a rather wild party celebrating the long road we have &#x2013; the long way we have come and I would like to talk about market share gains year-on-year. As you can see, in selective cosmetics retailing in the U.S., this is a report on our progress in the U.S. as reported by NPD, an independent panel.</p>
          <p>Regarding the outlook for 2008, DFS is going to pursue its development in existing markets. We are going to renovate existing stores to strengthen our presence in existing markets. We has just completed renovation of Chinachem, and we are about to start renovation work on some plaza store. Regarding the new initiatives we told you about, the new Galleria in Macao, it opened last Sunday. And that enables us to intercept Chinese tourists in Macao. We, of course the Abu Dhabi airport franchise was returned and of course then what we want to do is together with our products and our sales force, we want to meet the expectations of a highly diversified patronage.</p>
          <p>We want to continue of course acquire new Sephora market shares around the world and of course we want to have differentiating products, the product &#x2013; the network rather will be expanding at the same pace but we're looking at a higher potential markets, such as France, the U.S., Canada and China. And of course we will pursue our loyalty programs for customers, which is of course what we need to do in the more difficult times. We have millions of members of our loyalty cards and they help us to keep sales up. Le Bon March&#xE9; has persuaded its efforts to improve its image and it's positioned for each of its businesses in Paris. We are working mostly in the new housing in &#x2013; in the new house goods department. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening, ladies and gentlemen I'd like to present the results of Wines &amp; Spirits. The financial highlights were presented to you by Jean-Jacques. Revenue very close to &#x20AC;1.3 billion, a slight decrease but organic growth 6%. Profit from recurring operations &#x20AC;409 million, that's growth level of 4%. If we now look briefly at the highlights of this first half I'd like to say that it's reaffirmed value creation strategy that has always been ours against a backdrop of significantly weaker currencies.</p>
          <p>Organic revenue growth driven by rising stars, Ruinart, Glenmorangie, but also sustained price increases across our markets. 8% on average from Mo&#xEB;t Hennessy As was mentioned a significant improvement in the second half of revenue during the second quarter after a start to the year impacted by the reduction of distributors, inventories. This is due to the unfavorable price increase phasings. First quarter up 1%, we said we we'd recover things in Q2, that's done with 13% growth in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>As I said, considerable dynamism of the rising stars, Ruinart revenue growth in excess of 20%, continuing its global reach. Also our recent acquisition Glenmorangie, good revenue growth in particular &#x2013; in Asia, doubling volumes and worldwide a very good response to the new packaging, the new advertising. Estates and wines continued growth even if it is also impacted by currencies and I'd like to mention the initial very encouraging results, the repositioning of our Belvedere vodka. We had a quite exceptional performance in New York and California &#x2013; New York a very important market for the success of a brand such as Belvedere.</p>
          <p>If we now consider market performance we have a contrasting situations in traditional markets, Europe is on target, continued revenue growth. As to the U.S. and Japan, these are the two countries impacted by inventory draw downs, significant decline in inventories on these two markets, but what we are seeing because of course the U.S., we need a slightly more qualified analysis with the high number of stacks there. We do see declining demand against the backdrop of slowing economic outlook, but very strong progress in high potential markets. It's one of the assets of Moet Hennessy to be present everywhere.</p>
          <p>In Asia, growth of the order of 17%, including China exceptional growth, 33% and this is very profitable growth because China is one of our most profitable markets, Asia, Hong Kong, Taiwan have delivered, everything's fine. Russia has delivered on all the hopes, we've invested a good deal. Growth of the order of 30% driven by Hennessy as in China and significant potential confirmed in the Middle East and Latin America. As Mr. Arnault mentioned a lot of product innovation, it's very important against the present backdrop to be even more creative than ever and we have a lot of product innovations during the first half. The launch of the new Dom P&#xE9;rignon Mill&#xE9;sime, the Grande Vintage of Mo&#xEB;t &amp; Chandon, Krug very dynamic and will be with the exceptional vintage, the Clos d'Ambonnay at a very high price, very limited in number. Also, innovation at Veuve Clicquot with the launch of a contemporary design piece, created by Karim Rashid, Globalight, very successful. New presentation cases for the mythical prestige cognacs Richard and Paradis at Maison Hennessy very well received in China and elsewhere. Integration of  la Bodega Numanthia Termes , exceptional red wine acquired in Spain last year, produced in the Toro region, that has won many accolades in the wine spectator and the flagship of this winery received the 100 score from Robert Parker.</p>
          <p>Glenmorangie refocusing on its premium brands; As you know, Glenmorangie has always had a private label business and so we wish to discontinue that to focus on its premium brands and to dispose of all non-strategic activities. The Moet Hennessy distribution network is a key component. We're strengthening it with new subsidiaries in the Central Europe, Hungary, Poland, the Czech Republic very promising markets with high growth rates.</p>
          <p>As to the outlook for 2008, rest of the year let's say that we will actively support our brands through innovation and creativity. But also by deploying considerable advertising across our brands, a lot of innovation, new developments for global travel retail. Mo&#xEB;t Hennessy the new product that has just been launched, an exceptional cognac sold in the global travel retail. Mo&#xEB;t &amp; Chandon Veuve Clicquot. New champagnes Krug the launch of the 1998 Vintage with two exceptional vintages Clos d'Ambonnay '98 but also Krug collection in 1982, a very rare vintage. As to Ruinart innovation, a picnic trunk reinvented in a sophisticated and unusual way for a winter blanc de blanc and the end of the year, you know that champagne and cognac sales are very strong at the end of the year.</p>
          <p>We've planned a lot of innovation both in packaging to offer our consumers the opportunities of discovering our products in a pleasant setting. So all this aimed at winning new customers. Our objective remains unchanged to reinforce Moet Hennessy in the luxury market. We will continue to put in place initiatives during the rest of the year to accentuate the luxury positioning of Moet Hennessy through numerous advertising and commercial initiatives. A flurry of activity planned, maintaining marketing efforts for even more luxurious and exclusive image for our products. Continued cost containment, it's essential in these times and also continued strengthening of internal synergies and steadfast focus on product quality. So, we're going to pursue value creation strategy in an uncertain global economic context to reach the objectives set at the beginning of the year. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening ladies and gentlemen. On the left hand side, we have a new picture of Uma Thurman who is proudly wearing a TAG Heuer watch, &#x20AC;1,600, this is an entry level watch doing quite well on all our markets and on the right hand side you have a Hublot watch, a Big Bang model and the skeleton frame is on display. The price is &#x20AC;19,400, you can take orders tonight and the closing has just been completed so we all have the Hublot in our figures for the first half. In the first half of the year, organic growth was up 15 &#x2013; was 15%; significant foreign exchange effect 7% and consolidation of our market shares both in Watches &amp; Jewelry. By the way, organic growth on the first half of 2007 was 23%, the profit from recurring operations was up 30%, so twice as much as the growth in revenues.</p>
          <p>So operating margin was &#x2013; went from 9% in 2006 to 18% in the first half of 2008, alone with  structural improvement in profit margins. Rigorous cost control, a critical mass for each business line is why we have such a good performance. On the right hand side, you have the Grand Carrera timepiece in gold; the starting price is &#x20AC;13,000. This collection is extremely successful and that has led to considerable orders in the first half of 2008. Another high point of 2008 &#x2013; for H1, that is &#x2013; growth was balanced, the revenue was stable in Japan, slightly up in the U.S.; a strong growth in Europe, Asia, South America; 14% in Europe. In Asia, China and South East Asia significant growth to the tune of 16% in euro and so you have to add to that 9 or 10 points.</p>
          <p>If you look at growth in local currencies, we have growth, not mentioned here, but the Middle East, Russia and Ukraine have also tangible growth. On operating margin, we have a three-point growth from 15 to 18%. Another significant factor was, well, the acquisition of Hublot, Geneva; this is a very unique brand, a very strong position together with TAG Heuer, Zenith and Dior watches and of course great expertise with Jean-Claude Biver and the entire team &#x2013; management team have great experience. Already TAG Heuer has done extremely well in that portfolio, both in Europe and in Asia.</p>
          <p>In terms of collection of course, the Grand Carrera collection is very successful indeed everywhere including in Japan and the U.S. First half of 2008 was an opportunity to strengthen such icons as Formula One, The Aquaracer, Link, and Monaco, so we've worked quite hard on these flagship brands, and of course we have pursued the stepping up of these brands together with new launches in the U.S. We have the diamond watch, which we showed at the opening slide; we expect this development to spur on this particular segment between 1,500 and $3,000 per watch.</p>
          <p>For Zenith, we're doing quite well; strong growth in particular in the Middle East, Russia, Asia and in U.S., stable performance in Japan. We have new successful models, in particular the one you have on the screen here; this is Chronomaster line and the picture here is a model in stainless steel; &#x20AC;11,000, the gold one is &#x20AC;26,000. We received the great watch Geneva watch contest with Tourbillon Zero G; that model won the award for Best Watch.</p>
          <p>Christian Dior has a joint venture with Dior Couture and that has, well, the synergies have made it possible to improve our position in our various watch stores. Line Christal is also &#x2013; has done extremely well. We have had great success with automatic watches and Tourbillon was extremely successful at launch. In our watches, we have in Asia; single brand shops, we have here TAG Heuer in Beijing or in the Ocean Terminal in Hong Kong. We've opened a Hublot store in Kuala Lumpur in June; I believe that was the third Hublot shop after &#x2013; well there's one in St. Tropez &#x2013; but there is also a shop in Shanghai and here you have another shop in Shanghai for Zenith. The Zenith store on Plaza 66.</p>
          <p>The high points in terms of jewelry; Chaumet has pursued its geographical position; a very targeted and sustained position in our joint venture in Korea. We had of course taken up a new business there, but we have new franchises in the Middle East with Jeddah, Riyadh but we've also opened our first shop in Shanghai. Very dynamic position in Europe; we have double digit great growth in Europe, and we've performed well on our icon line. This Attrape-Moi piece of jewelry is &#x20AC;20,000. We have also access models for Class One Croisiere and Premiers Liens is the first sentimental piece of jewelry that was very successful indeed in the shops, this is your chance to try and grab one. De Beers opened its flagship store in Ginza, Japan. Of course this is a stupendous store on the new &#x2013; <mark type="inaudible" /> one of the very fashionable streets in Tokyo and you have a superb location for this. But that brand was quite happy with presentations in department stores, but it was waiting for this good opportunity, the real estate opportunity on Ginza and it seized it when it was there.</p>
          <p>Jewelry is doing well in spite of poor economic context including in the U.S. and the higher range jewelry is doing extremely well. And we have very targeted new openings in Houston, Galleria Dallas, NorthPark. We've also open a store in the center of San Francisco, I will show you picture in a second. We have a third store in Taiwan and a franchise in Kiev. With Fred we have a pursued our development in France, we've renovated the flagship store in Place Vend&#xF4;me and we've been very successful with Force 10; that new line of which you have an example on the right hand side of the screen.</p>
          <p>A few examples of new stores, we have at the top right corner, top left corner, beg your pardon, the Ginza shop for De Beers. We've opened a new De Beers stores in San Francisco, at the angle of Post and Grant Streets, for those of you familiar with San Francisco. We have a new Fred &#x2013; well, the renovated Fred store in Place Vend&#xF4;me and one of the new Chaumet stores with the brand's coats.  This store was opened in Shanghai in January.</p>
          <p>What's the outlook for the first of &#x2013; beg your pardon, for the second half of 2008? Of course these are more acrobatic circumstances, but we still propose to continue with the new market shares and profitable growth and with TAG Heuer we are pursuing our integration &#x2013; our industrial integration with extended capacities both in Swiss Jura and in Italy we have and in Switzerland, we have in Hublot a &#x2013; sorry, we'll have with TAG Heuer a new series of handheld cell phones.  We have the single mart stores are opening in Asia.  All these are very much in keeping with the values of this brand.  The cell phones will be available in October, we'll be opening a &#x2013; well we'll have the launch in September in London and then the new markets will open in October.</p>
          <p>With TAG Heuer, by the way, all our markets are doing well in the U.S.  So we have just strengthened our advertising pressure with the targeted media, such as the internet and radio advertising on a regional basis.  Radio advertising is apparently much more effective on our sellouts.</p>
          <p>For Hublot now, well, we propose to, of course, integrate Hublot into LVMH and that will have an effect as of the second half of 2008.  We are pursuing this building of a manufacturer in Nyon next to Geneva for the Hublot manufacture.  And of course one of the challenges will be &#x2013; well, it's probably challenging but we want to make sure that we can deliver up to demand for the women's watch product line.  You have a big &#x2013; the automatic gold and diamond watch &#x20AC;20,000 a piece.</p>
          <p>Zenith proposed to deliver new collections, indeed all its collections shown in Basel will be available in the second half and we'll be looking at the classical pieces and the high jewelry &#x2013; high-end watches. We are working in China and India, but will be opening new stores there, but closing others; the less profitable stores elsewhere.  Chaumet has a strong retail business model; this is been successful in the first half and pursued to continue in the second half with new high-end and middle range Jewelry pieces.  We are going work on all our flagships with new openings in Asia, Beijing, Macao, Honk Kong and Taiwan, but we you also have a few new advertising campaign getting ready for the end of this year, beginning of the next year.</p>
          <p>De Beers is stepping up with its collections, in particular its classical pieces.  On the right hand side you have Inara ring; &#x20AC;150,000. Inara means "light" and it's &#x2013; it exemplifies the high-end jewelry anywhere between 50,000 and $500,000.  We will continue its &#x2013; our expansion of stores &#x2013; very selective stores.  We're looking at Florida in the U.S. and Costa Mesa in California, Istania in Turkey, Beijing, Shanghai, and Macao. This should complete our network of stores, but we have a few openings in the Middle-East and we will have as many as 48 or 59 stores operated directly or through a franchise.</p>
          <p>And then Fred will focus its growth on France and Asia.  France is doing well.  Japan now has a good presence as I said in this new store.  We will have also lots of middle range and higher range or high-end jewelry pieces on offer.  So we pursue profitable growth and looking at new market shares in what is after all, a very challenging and competitive context, but we are determined.  Thank you for your attention, and now I'll the call to Yves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening.  Well, you've seen this photograph several times so I'm very pleased to describe Eva Herzigova who was several times involved in our advertising campaigns, Monogramoflage, which is a new one shot collaboration with Murakami, the artist.  What's interesting our relations with the art world is, six years on, to continue to reinvent together new things and I can tell you that the Takashi Murakami exhibition last year at the MOCA LA and Brooklyn will continue this Fall in Frankfurt and he's decided to produce an original work from the Monogramoflage.</p>
          <p>Sometimes the product comes from art and sometimes art comes from collaboration with the product.  Earlier you saw the figures for Fashion &amp; Leather Goods; organic growth 14%.  And if I tell you that the growth of Louis Vuitton was higher than the average across the business, you'll understand once again during the first half, we really are leading the race.  Why? Because the strategy continues to remain the same year after year; organic growth across regions, with the exception of Japan; you've seen that it's the difficult market.</p>
          <p>But strong growth across markets, and in particular &#x2013; and this surprises all our partners &#x2013; department store mall owners, significant growth in the U.S., where even in July we saw absolutely no sign of a slowdown in growth be it in the  U.S., Europe, Asia, or China.  And clearly and I repeating what colleagues said earlier, continued strong demand from emerging countries, but emerging countries for us not just Asia, India.  This year we've opened new countries in Europe, Finland; Helsinki, Romania; Bucharest, with surprising performance achieved at 80, 90% with local customers.</p>
          <p>And this confirms us in the belief of our strategy that we find new pockets of wealth, at places throughout the world; new customers who aspire to luxury goods, some driven by their extraordinary growth.  Qatar is a place where we regret that the mall was built two years after signature.  If we'd known what the price of oil would do, we'd have opened a store twice as big, but we're considering the second store in Qatar as in Abu Dhabi, as well as a second store in Kuwait.</p>
          <p>And of course China, but if we look at the end of the first half we had 15 net openings that's fully consistent with the scope effect that we have year on year. And that is replicated because year-after-year we see no limit to the number of places in the world, districts, neighborhoods, cities and malls where we couldn't regularly continue to have this geographic expansion. The first half I can cite the wonderful Canton Road store which, with the Champs-&#xC9;lys&#xE9;es, are one of the finest successes both in terms of store layout and in terms of sales; they're both neck and neck. And we can also cite Hankyu at Osaka; this store for men with the finest location on the ground floor, and there we were able to demonstrate that not just across luxury goods but for men's goods, we could achieve between two to three times the sales of the brand.</p>
          <p>Bangalore, Bucharest, Helsinki, the Brooklyn museum with Murakami and then the ability to sell a few million dollars in a few weeks, a few months in the museum. It's the perfect illustration of our symbiosis with contemporary creation and we don't really know who creates desire; the luxury brand or the artist; and this is fully understood by the consumers. It's also product innovation as I always say, and I have the impression that I'm repeating myself; the strength and the constraint of Louis Vuitton is to cover all segments of businesses in which we operate. And every season, every year we work in leather goods across these segments.</p>
          <p>The launch of Mahina the bag; soft leather, very body friendly bag that is subtle because the monogram, which is a perforated monogram can be seen close-up but not from afar. This is a segment that we haven't fully tapped but is proving to be extremely profitable for us. There is also Tahitienne a small capsule for the beach; this is a range that will last three months and liven up stores, not just for leather goods. But this will be active during the summer period.</p>
          <p>And also the Galliera, the bag at the top, which is also an innovation in terms of its functionality. There are many leather goods specialists &#x2013; it's very body friendly but in its opening, the fact that there's no zip; it's very modern in the way it functions. And the consumer was right to see that Louis Vuitton not just &#x2013; doesn't just follow trends but is a pioneer in terms of new trends.</p>
          <p>And then Marc Jacobs and Richard Prince new collaboration; one of the most recognized contemporary artists today who really did focus on developing this line. The Richard Prince bags sold like hot cakes this summer and over the summer a year, this ability to produce short lived collections and then major permanents that will run for years.</p>
          <p>Strong growth of accessories over the past 12 months with colleagues we decided to set up a real division of accessories and when we put eyewear, belts, ties, scarves and jewelry. We have sales plenty with accessories that exceeds many luxury brands across that business. Accessories are posting very strong growth, one of the most profitable activities for us, amongst the profitable activities of Louis Vuitton, you have to &#x2013; there isn't just leather goods; there are other territories were we can grow our profitability.</p>
          <p>Advertising we decided last year to have jewel communication the short lived nature of fashion with Eva Herzigova but also the timeless values and for a very long time Mikhail Gorbachev &#x2013; the Berlin Wall will of course be a landmark in fashion advertising. During the half, we presented a corporate film, which was created with Ogilvy during these &#x2013; the timeless values, the film plus the digital world. The way in which we were able to propagate this via the blogosphere does show that we can discuss these traditions with great modernity.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the other brands we can note the continued good performance of Fendi. What we see at Fendi is that the timeless, the iconic values drive sustainable growth, the Maxi Baguette bag, the successful development of Selleria line are the strong growth factors of Fendi with also continued growth of ready-to-wear and shoe collections with a store network expanding 108, 65 stores at the end of June. Donna Karan: strong revenue progress and profitability improvement consistent with the spirit and strengthening design around brand values.</p>
          <p>Difficult to cite all the innovations or achievements of all brands but inter alia we can mention the arrival of Stuart Vevers at Loewe giving new dynamism. Stuart after spending some time with our competitors with Givenchy and Vuitton so it's a return to his formal company. The Marc by Marc Jacobs excellent performance, born in the U.S. but is truly universal; growing number of country seeing the opening up of Marc by Marc stores either directly or franchised. Riccardo Tisci's first men's collection and opening of a new store concept in Paris. The launch of the Berluti line, the Kenzo, the Pucci store network in Hong Kong, these brands are increasing their initiatives.</p>
          <p>If we now look at the outlook here again as colleagues have said of course to use the strength of all these brands in a challenging climate, but there is no reason for it to deteriorate in the second half as compared to the first half with continued profitable growth of Fendi and on Louis Vuitton continue the creative approach; at the last meeting we discussed this that the universe of Damier will be strengthened with the arrival of Damier Graphite after Damier Ebene which was the original 1888 Damier. With the launch of a Damier Azur with Damier Graphite, we have a very masculine territory there which will once again strengthen this aspect.</p>
          <p>I mentioned Monogramouflage and you will see during the coming months further initiatives, sustained store opening program in a new country this year 2008, an absolute record of new territories, the first store opening in Bahrain and in China. Will you slow the pace of store openings in China? The answer is not at all. Between now and the end of the year, three further new stores, one at <mark type="inaudible" /> the conquest of the Chinese Far West, and a program of the order of a dozen units in 2009, we're already working on that. Maintain strong advertising, building both on the fashion and timeless values aspect, a strategy that remains unchanged whatever the economic or currency backdrop, great confidence for the remainder of the year that I will illustrate with this photograph that you've seen the latest photograph of Annie Leibovitz where you see all the timeless values of Vuitton, the travel dimension. Annie took this shot in Argentina, culture, great number of Oscars on this photograph and then the transmission from father to daughter symbolized by the monogram 'Never Full'. Fully Louis Vuitton. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, ladies and gentlemen. Now is your chance to ask questions if there are any.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> Three questions about Wines &amp; Spirits. You had 6% organic growth in the first half but if you look at the documents do you see that involved in Champagne and Cognac volumes are down 5% in both divisions. Could you explain how you were able to get to 6% growth? Was it just because of the price and mix effect, how are you able to get this result and then in the second half do you expect improvement in volumes?</p>
          <p>Now, in Fashion &amp; Leather Goods, do you expect to have a breakdown of organic growth on the region-by-region basis. You say that U.S. and Europe were strong but could you tell us what is due to the presence of tourists and to what extent local tourists make a difference. It look as though in the U.S., local consumers but you seem to be able to keep a low customer shift in the U.S. and then in the first half you have, what's the expectations in terms of stocks and what's the free cash flow figure you expect in 2008 based on the figures you had in the first half of 2008 &#x2013; in the past few &#x2013; last presentation, rather, there was a reference to the fact that you might buy back your own shares. Is this going to happen in view of the recent investments you have made? Do you think this will not happen until 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let's talk with Wines &amp; Spirits. Well, therefore, four answers to this question. Number one, as you pointed out, these talk to considerably our inventories of Wines &amp; Spirits and business has taken up briskly in the last half of 2007, first half of 2008. Mo&#xEB;t Hennessy has done extremely well in Asia and China in particular. As you pointed out, we've increased our prices and this has had an effect on the profit, good thing we did that, and we did it earlier than in previous years, hence the effect on stocks and the fourth aspect of course is the fact that we're able to keep costs down. We maintained our efforts in terms of &#x2013; regarding our promotional ambitions and then of course we have implemented all the measures in terms of advertising precisely to achieve the objectives we had set ourselves for 2008.</p>
          <p>That was the questions on Wines &amp; Spirits. What about Fashion &amp; Leather Goods?</p>
          <p>Well, this strategy has always been to look at local customers and that strategy has always been effective because even if there is &#x2013; there are variations on Travel Retail, local business is still brisk and so if we have sustainable growth in the U.S., this is connected with local customers. Now in terms of the tourist trade, 20 years ago when we &#x2013; tourists which are the Japanese tourists and 20 years ago for the luxury goods, we thought we would open stores where we could find as many as 100,000 Japanese tourists. And now there's no such thing as a single nationality of tourists. We have Russian tourists all over the place. We also have Japanese tourists of course, but we also have Russian people traveling around the world. We have people from the Middle East. And so now, it is not as though we had a single type of customers or tourists. And we find that around the world all our customers have been holding out.</p>
          <p>And regarding the third question about capital expenditure last year we had a &#x2013; about 6% of revenue was allocated to capital expenditure and we have the same expectations for the first &#x2013; we had the same result for the first six months of 2008. We will keep doing the same and we certainly propose to sustain the growth of our brands through CapEx. Regarding the stocks at Louis Vuitton, we were sort of short at the end of last year both for Leather Goods and Wines &amp; Spirits and we &#x2013; for Wines, Perfumes &amp; Cosmetics and DFS, we also increased our stocks because we were looking at new launches, new perfumes but also new stores for instance the Macao store has just opened for DFS, and hence the increase in CapEx. Well, regarding the buyback of own shares. All the options are on the table. This will depend on the price &#x2013; on the market prices. Yes then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My name is <mark type="inaudible" /> and I have three questions. Can you give us indications about the hedging on exchange rate? The expectations for the second half would be less than or equal to the first half. You seem to say less. Can you give us a guidance, and regarding exchange rates, can you &#x2013; we have 170 part is Fashion and Leather Goods. What about Cognac and Champagne? Are you hedged for those? What about 13% growth in the second half &#x2013; second quarter, what's the figure for Cognac, and finally, regarding price increases with &#x2013; well they were high on the Wine and Spirits but for Fashion and Leather Goods, you are also looking at price increases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the currency front, currency hedges the year 2008 is hedged as is generally the case at this point of the year. So, we are hedged on the dollar, 93% average rate of 139 for the year and we're hedged at 95% to 157. The rate is same average rate the end for 2009, 157 but for a hedge percentage at 54% for the dollar. We are hedged at 58% in '09 with an average rate of 151.</p>
          <p>On the overall currency impact on the disaggregation of the 170, we saw the bulk is concentrated on Fashion and Leather Goods for the reason mentioned. The rest is split between the various divisions. Wines and Spirits benefited from excellent hedges. Currency rate that is lower versus its revenue, lower than what we might have expected and for the second half of the year, I am not sure that I gave any indication as to what we might expect regarding the currency impact.  What I referred to earlier was the cost of the currency hedges, which is different and I hope it will be lower because the cost of the currency hedges will be lower the second half of the year, but I won't speak to the currency trends.  It depends on the currency rates in the second half, very difficult to predict today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But still you are looking at better development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But the comparison base is not more favorable, the dollar first half 133 and the second half closer to 141, but we have currency hedges in place during the year and for the first half dollar currency hedges were at 134 and the second half closer to 141.  So we see that tracking the exchange rate levels of the previous year, so it doesn't militate in favor of a considerable improvement in the currency impact in the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding price increases, we will continue our policies.  We will of course adjust for monetary variations, it all depends on that.  We've conducted some price increases at Vuitton in most countries concerned especially Japan and U.S. where the exchange rate has been unfavorable.  Having said that because our brands are strong, we can actually upgrade our prices regardless of the monetary situation, which is not true for other brands.  For instance, when Vuitton increases its prices in Japan, other big brands which I shall not quote, actually reduced their prices on the Japanese market, sometimes double digit decreases.</p>
          <p>Further questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the answer on cognac Hennessy, Q2 growth in excess of 6%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are there further questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's all, I mean I have a question about the taxes that went up in the first quarter. Can you tell us what is, I mean because of the new tax arrangements what do you expect in the second half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, tax rate as such for the first half. The tax rate in the first half is just the anticipation of the full year rate because we pay taxes once a year, so it will be the same.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> from Societe Generale. I found that in your presentation you were not telling the same story about Fashion &amp; Leather Goods or in Watches &amp; Jewelry for leather &#x2013; Fashion &amp; Leather Goods, everything seemed to be all right but for Watches &amp; Jewelry, it was more acrobatic you said, you said that the context was more difficult. Do you see certain brands or certain businesses in greater danger in view of the present context, and likewise for Travel Retail you said that this was &#x2013; had a slowdown as of June. Could you confirm this? Could you explain this?</p>
          <p>And then the second question is about, some of your margin guidance that you gave us, that is a bit unusual you said, you gave the guidance of 12% for Sephora, where do you stand compared to that? 20% for Fendi, I believe, for 2008 or was it 2009, and then 20% for the jewelry, I think, you are well on the way for that, but that was a three-year objective at the time, we must be half way through? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well just to answer you, about the outlook for Watches &amp; Jewelry, when I say that things are challenging, I mean the market is rather difficult for competition, I mean is there, we're determined to continue to increase our revenue profit market share, all my colleagues are in the same situation here, I mean the market isn't any easier &#x2013; it's perhaps more challenging in certain markets, but we have determined teams, and we're not reducing the operational resources on profitability of a division worth 18% for the first six months. We'll see in six months' time where we end the year as compared to the objective set by Mr. Arnault a while back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Well the outlook on watchmaking, multi-brand retailing the competition at the point of sale is stronger and some retailers are more timorous in managing their own inventories, whereas in jewelry, it's your own stores and you're less exposed to the competition even if there are several jewelers around the platform.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The challenge will be to have more growth from the second half than on the first half but even if we're happy with the first half, well then everybody will be happy with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I believe there was another question about the profitability figures for Sephora. We know that part of the profit is generated in the second half of the year. For the first half of the year I can tell you that, profit is very much in guidance and we propose to stay the course. 50% of our business &#x2013; of Sephora business is already completed, but in other territories such as China, we're looking at investments which will have an impact on profitability.</p>
          <p>I see no further questions. In that case, well it's already late. Thank you. In any event, we will be around for a little while, we have drinks waiting. Mr. Guiony has planned for little refreshments and so this will be your chance to discuss the matter further.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>