<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1132060" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>FY 2007 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-02-06</date>
    <companies>
      <company>846</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Bernard Arnault, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jean-Jacques Guiony, Finance</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Antonio Belloni, Group Managing Director</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Christophe Navarre, Wines &amp; Spirits</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Philippe Pascal, Watches &amp; Jewelry</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep">Yves Carcelle, Fashion &amp; Leather Goods</participant>
      <participant id="6">Alexandra Dejean</participant>
      <participant id="7">Bernard Arnault</participant>
      <participant id="8">Antonio Belloni</participant>
      <participant id="9">Jean-Jacques Guiony</participant>
      <participant id="10">Yves Carcelle</participant>
      <participant id="11">Lisa Rachal</participant>
      <participant id="12">Scheherazade Daneshkhu</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, good morning. I'm very pleased to welcome you this morning for this meeting in order to present to you the results of 2007 and to give you some guidance regarding our views on 2008. So on 2007 I'd like to stress the extraordinary performance of the Group, which once again has approved double-digit organic growth. 13% revenue growth with solid progress in historical markets.</p>
          <p>Even greater increase in emerging markets, the US and Europe continue to achieve sustained growth to which is now added the very strong momentum of countries such as China, Russia and the Middle East. Profit from recurring operations is also up by double-digits, up 12% and over the past five years our result has been posting double-digit growth in the profit from recurring operations as well as net income.</p>
          <p>All business groups in 2007 have achieved double-digit growth and the current operating margin is up 22%. It is noteworthy that our business expanded well in the fourth quarter, that December was a good month. We read everywhere that December was a difficult month or at least less good than expected. For us it's the reverse and our business in Japan also expanded very usefully because over the years Vuitton, like the competition, grew on the Japanese market. This performance is all the more noteworthy in view of the strong impact of exchange rate.</p>
          <p>The operating income of the Group is in fact growing by 20%. To show you the impact of the decline in the dollar and that of the yen, even if the yen is up slightly compared to the Group.  The financial debt has been reduced, the gearing ratio is brought back to 25%.</p>
          <p>So we have in 2007 once again increased our lead on the world's luxury market. This stems from overall contribution of all our brands, all our businesses, our star brands such as Dior, Mo&#xEB;t &amp; Chandon, Hennessy. There are many, all achieved exceptional performance. Vuitton once again &#x2013; growth &#x2013; double-digit growth in earnings from development across countries &#x2013; in the US, Europe &#x2013; but across emerging countries as I mentioned earlier, China and Russia.</p>
          <p>Excellent performance of Dior perfumes with the success of all the launches in perfumes, with the new Poison or in makeup with the new foundation or with care products.  L'Or de Vie, an extraordinary product composed from the Yquem vineyard and is expanding in an extraordinary fashion.  Very successful</p>
          <p>Sephora, strong growth rates in the US where for online sales is the leading seller of cosmetics in the US market. DFS where the Chinese clientele is gradually replacing the slow down of Japanese travelers affected by the decline in the yen as we can imagine.</p>
          <p>As regards Watches and Jewelry, TAG Heuer is continuing its remarkable performance as well as our other brands that are all positive, notably Chaumet that has &#x2013; now posting very strong growth, achieving sustained profitability so for that business we have posted growth, very strong growth in the operating income. Noteworthy the growth of brands of the future.</p>
          <p>The Fashion division which is developing in a profitable manner with the success such as <mark type="inaudible" />, Givenchy, Celine and these brands will continue to grow even faster in the future with a number of developments which will yield very useful results for the Group.</p>
          <p>Even at the level of Fashion and Leather Goods, the numbers are relatively limited.</p>
          <p>Wines and Spirits also reinforced their growth, strengthening their value creation strategy, with still the same difficulty which is to have enough raw material, enough grape to put in our bottles and this is rather a pleasant problem but does slow somewhat the growth of our business but as you can see the results of this business are quite outstanding.</p>
          <p>So, a new record year of market share for the Group with a very good distribution of all our businesses and geographical distribution which is extremely balanced enabling us to achieve constant regularity over the year.</p>
          <p>In the room today we have many financial analysts, I would like to give them my perspective regarding their vision of the LVMH Group and the way it is perceived by financial markets because I see that we are very often placed in the category of cyclical businesses.</p>
          <p>I have difficulty in understanding that. LVMH constantly delivers results that are growing whatever the climate. I fail to see why our company should be classified as a cyclical company. We need to revise that judgment given the regularity of results that we post year after year and perhaps place us in a category that is less subject to market variations.</p>
          <p>This now brings me to 2008, because I'm sure there'll be questions regarding the economic climate in 2008. It's true that the year is starting in a rather worrisome situation in terms of the economy and the financial markets in particular.</p>
          <p>Having said that, January was fully in line with the end of the year. Double-digit organic growth for the Group and very strong double-digit growth of Louis Vuitton. So the year is starting in a unsettled economic environment but with very good auguries for LVMH. Our analysis of the situation is that in 2008 we're likely to experience a degree of recession more or less important in the US economy.</p>
          <p>What will the impact be on the Group's business? As I see it, and this is really what I've been seeing over the past five years in the development of the Group. is this crisis, as I believe, is relatively limited.  If we witness a small scale recession, this recession perhaps spanning one or two quarters in the year 2008 and prompting a recovery as of 2009, I believe that its consequences on LVMH will be limited, weak or even non-existent.</p>
          <p>Of course if we were to witness a geo-political catastrophe similar to that of 2008 then things would be different for us. But the economic climate as we can perceive it seems to me to be quite manageable &#x2013; not likely to lead to major consequences regarding the development over the five years of the Group which is set to continue, and that's why we're announcing our forecast normally in 2008. In fact the clientele that we are dealing with is far less affected by the rest of the economy, by these short-term economic swings.</p>
          <p>They have high purchasing power, located in a number of countries where the economic climate will be buoyant even if there's a minor recession in the US.  And so our business will continue to grow with this clientele.  All the more so since our global strategy is to provide our customers with luxury products. This is not a strategy in which a number of other of our peers have launched into &#x2013; and to generate sales. We provide access to increasingly mass-market products.</p>
          <p>Now this is a strategy that can give rise to certain short-term difficulties as we see it with our star brands such as Dior, Vuitton, TAG Heuer, and Mo&#xEB;t &amp; Chandon, Hennessy, Yquem and so forth. We seek to pull our clientele upmarket and the group of clientele &#x2013; of customers in the world capable of buying these products, whatever the short-term economic conditions, well that category will continue to grow.</p>
          <p>So we are relatively confident regarding the year 2008. We have an extremely sustained innovation program across our brands. I won't go into the detail of that because the heads of the various business groups will speak to that. On this photograph you have &#x2013; you can see the new Vuitton bag launched with Richard Prince, more about that in a moment. It's sold out and there are waiting lists worldwide. The problem now will be to manufacture sufficient quantities of this bag to meet demand.</p>
          <p>Wines and Spirits &#x2013; the year is off to an excellent start and we have a whole series of innovations that Mr. Navarre will tell us about.</p>
          <p>Watches likewise. We have a whole series of new products and our market share with the star brand TAG Heuer is growing strongly. We also have great potential across a number of countries where we're not so strong. China with these companies. So, we will continue a very strong innovation policy in 2008. We will be opening up to the emerging &#x2013; to the new countries, expanding into a number of new countries and we will continue to expand in China, Russia, India.</p>
          <p>All this for us is part of a long history because we are the first to have operations in these countries. We are the Group that achieves the greatest success there. In parallel, we will continue to focus on productivity improvements, to improve our gross margin and the operating income year after year whatever of course the economic developments. The targets that we set to our business groups are in no way linked to the economic climates and all the managers know this. We seek to offset the variations of the dollar in our forecasts.</p>
          <p>It's not always easy but we've managed to do that. I now believe that the dollar has achieved a very low level. I'm not sure that it will continue to decline like that for years. It depends rather on the results of US elections. There are however a number of reasons in spite of the environment that is unsettled in financial terms for various reasons that I won't go into here, but there are reasons for us to be very confident for 2008.</p>
          <p>That's the message that I wish to deliver and now over to Jean-Jacques Guiony, our Financial Director, for the detail of the results in 2007.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good morning. We present the sales figure and the profits simultaneously. We'll start with the sales. You have the figures up on the slide. Up 13% for the organic growth in sales, 8% in euros. You can see that there's exchange effect, it's 5% over the year, 10% changes in the dollar, 18 for the yen. So one of the greatest exchange effects for a number of years, particularly in the fourth quarter up 6%. Nonetheless, organic growth was up 13% in keeping with the rest of the year.</p>
          <p>On the business-by-business basis, if you look at Wine and Spirits, the figure is quite remarkable. Overall for Wines and Spirits up 13%, Christophe will tell you more about that. Slight slow down in the fourth quarter because of &#x2013; well the fact that we simply didn't have enough bottles available in particular for champagne.</p>
          <p>Fashion and Leather Goods speeding up at the fourth quarter. Overall 14% for the year. Perfumes and Cosmetics stable at about 12% for the year. In organic growth again, Watches and Jewelry had an excellent year, up 19% in organic growth.</p>
          <p>The fourth quarter was up 13%. This may not look very high, it might even look like a slow down -n in fact that is not the case and in 2006 fourth quarter we had an exceptional sale of one <mark type="inaudible" /> which was itself an exceptional <mark type="inaudible" /> and if we restate that, which was non-recurring you have to add six digits to the fourth quarter growth. So if you look at the fourth quarter growth we are looking at 19% in keeping then with the rest of the year.</p>
          <p>Selective Retailing 12% so a good outlook at the end of the year. You may remember that the first half of the year we had a slow down in Japanese tourism, that didn't quite get back to order but all the same it's looking much better at the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>If you look at the geographical distribution you will have a standard pie chart here. A few comments. In the US down one point because of the dollar, not because of our sales which were extremely good. Japan down two points because of the yen but also because growth in Japan was less than in the rest of the Group.</p>
          <p>Let me just point out that in the first &#x2013; in the top quarter part of the picture. Asia 19% and Others 8%. We're looking at emerging economies &#x2013; so-called emerging economies accounting for 27% which had about a 15% growth. Asia 15% and the others slightly more. Now if you combine the two you can see that you are looking at about 4% growth in the Group, attributable to &#x2013; well which in itself accounts for 25% of the sales. So the Group overall had 8% and a quarter of the sales generated in the emerging countries accounts for that growth.</p>
          <p>If you go to the next slide, the revenue per region by region, so in the US the business was good, 15% in dollar over the year. Q4 was up to 18%, so very favorable turnout, the figures speak for themselves. All the businesses had good performances in particular Fashion and Leather Goods had a very good performance. Likewise Perfumes and Cosmetics. You may remember that the figures a few years back in the US, the figures were not too good and now we're definitely out of that rut and we are looking at double-digit growth in that part of the year-world.</p>
          <p>Japan slightly down &#x2013; half &#x2013; last quarter was slightly down. The rest of the world up high especially Wines and Spirits, Perfumes and Cosmetics at a very high level. Europe, stable growth at 11% overall. You can see that this is a fairly steady growth. Everybody stands at about 11, 12%.</p>
          <p>Selective Retailing a bit high but this is because some of the business in Greece was consolidated and that added a couple of basis points, so we're still look &#x2013; percentage points, we're still looking at about 12% overall.</p>
          <p>Let's look at the summarized income statements. Sales up 8%. You can see Revenue up 8%. Gross margin up 9%, it went from 64.2 to 64.9%, that's pretty good. There was an exchange effect which of course had a major effect on gross margins so cost control meant that we &#x2013; well gross margin grew faster than sales and revenue.</p>
          <p>If you looked at advertising expenses they were up 10, others 6. Administrative expenses in line with sales so the profit from recurring operations was up 12% to 3.555 billion and that is of course the most significant indicators, not just for you but for us in looking at our business.</p>
          <p>Other income and expenses stable compared to last year. We have &#x2013; well because we sold La Tribune, Kami and Omas, these are &#x2013; the main three items, not of the same -for the same amount, but the operating profit is up 12% like the profits from recurring operations. There's another slide about this. Income taxes 27% of pre-tax income compared to 29 last year.</p>
          <p>This is because we had a carry over from last year and that explains why we &#x2013; the rate is lower than in the rest of the World. We have minority &#x2013; DFS and Mo&#xEB;t C bring in additional incomes. So the net profit at the end of the day is up 8%, 2.025 billion, more than &#x2013; we passed the 2 billion mark and of course this is a &#x2013; in comparison with 2007. We have a 2% growth compared &#x2013; in the first half and 12% in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>If you look at recurring operations per business. Overall we can see that margins were better everywhere. Wines and Spirits and Fashion and Leather Goods overall 12%, well 10% for Wines and Spirits and 12% for Fashion and Leather Goods. Perfumes and Cosmetics likewise. Margin was up 15% on profit from recurring operations. Watches and Jewelry, the figure speaks for itself. Selective Retailing, now that figure is quite remarkable because we have a significant dollar effect on a significant part of DFS for the US and in spite of it all, in spite of the dollar effect we are up 10%.</p>
          <p>For others and eliminations we have a major change.  This is rather technical, there are a number of factors involved. Partly the stock options I told you about, that's in the first quarter &#x2013; the first half of the year.  We had a non-recurring effect in 2006 where there was improvement in stock options, now we are in a normal expense in 2007.</p>
          <p>There's some additional provisions. There is some downturn in the media pull and eliminations of profits in inventories. That's a difficult item to assess or to predict but because we sell our &#x2013; well &#x2013; Perfumes and Cosmetics sell to Sephora, well of course you had inventories in Sephora stores, and so corresponding profits are down.</p>
          <p>So this is a technical item, nothing special. Overall 12% in profit from recurring operations. If you look at the standard slide on the currency effect, unpleasant effect because the currency impact is down &#x2013; is negative, minus 255 million and that's the effect of &#x2013; well the sales of our &#x2013; export effect on our companies abroad. We have &#x2013; our retailing companies abroad and the variations of currency gains.</p>
          <p>The latter two were positive but the former was strongly down because of the downgrade of the yen and the dollar to the tune of 10%. So overall the currency impact is minus 255 and has a significant effect on the Fashion and Leather Goods and Wines and Spirits, and without that we would have been up 20% on the year as a whole.</p>
          <p>One quick slide about the quarterly development &#x2013; half-year development for profit from recurring operations. We have to look that in terms of reported profits, we were up 12% for the year, 11 in the first half, 13% in the second half. So improved profitability in the second half and on constant currency the effect is even more dramatic because we had 16% of profit from a recurring process in the first half of the year and 23% in the second half of the year at constant currency.</p>
          <p>About the financial expense, that's a technical item, the costs of financial debt, net financial debt is a paradoxical change because the debt went down and the costs went up. The average was 4.25 to &#x20AC;3. 7 billion but last year we had &#x2013; in the previous year as well, the rate went up from 3.8 to 4.7, so the inventory effect was positive, but the price effect was down &#x2013; unfavorable and so the costs of net financial debt was up. The cost of currency hedge &#x2013; well this is completely impossible to forecast.</p>
          <p>It was 5 billion in &#x2013; 5 million in 2006, 45 in the following year, 5 again in the following year. We &#x2013; all the currency hedges in 2008 were already &#x2013; are already listed as expenses so even if we stopped hedging we would have zero on that item. So we &#x2013; the difficulty is we &#x2013; with the accounting standards for this particular item &#x2013; in the currency hedges, there's not much we can do about that.</p>
          <p>The third line is the most significant to understand the effect of capital gains down in 2007. We still have a 45, but it's still down compared to 2006. So the financial income is more or less normal. I mean we're in the upper part of the bracket but of course there's a degradation compared to the previous year.</p>
          <p>The financial structure &#x2013; not much comments. We have 46% in equity, 41% now but we now have the &#x2013; our item &#x2013; our assets are liquid.  We have 4 billion in confirmed non-drawn credit lines &#x2013; in the present state of affairs, this is rather good for a Group such as ours.</p>
          <p>Now if you look at cash flow operations &#x2013; cash flow generation rather, you look at after tax. In the first half of the year it was a bit complicated because we had some carry over of advance on taxes for the following year. In any case we are up 15% in cash flow from operations before changes in working capital.</p>
          <p>Our changes in working capital were significant because we up making are inventory to meet future demand. In Wines and Spirits we are also opening lots of separate stores. When you open stores you have to put inventory inside and so inventory is up and so the figure is higher compared to 2006.</p>
          <p>Operating investment is up. We are investing. We do believe in the future of our business. We invested in Sephora, and also at Vuitton and so operating investment is up. So the free cash flow is 1.5 billion, stable compared to last year.</p>
          <p>If you look at net debt and equity. Net debt is 3.1 billion at the end of the year, 12 billion in equity so the gearing is 25% round about. That debt does include the effect of the acquisition of Les Echos at &#x2013; completely at 31 December, even though this was not consolidated in terms of balance sheet and income statement for the year as a whole.</p>
          <p>And then finally a comment on the dividend. We will be proposing an increased dividend by 14% to &#x20AC;1.60. We already have spent 35 centimes on advanced payment. If you look at the comparisons of the dividends and the profit over two years, well one year is difficult because net income last year was bloated by non-recurring capital gains, but over two years the growth is 40% on net income and growth also 40% in dividends. So it stands to reason that it is worth pointing out.</p>
          <p>That's what I had to say. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Let's now review the details of each business group. Eva Green who personifies the new Christian Dior fragrance is indeed a fine ambassadress for Perfumes and Cosmetics and the year was also a fine one for this business group. Organic revenue growth 12% and 15% of the profit from recurring operations.  2007 is a further stage of success for our long-term strategy.</p>
          <p>We're targeting strong market growth, above the market and above our competitors, accompanied by a gradual improvement in the operating margin where clearly we have some way to go. What is encouraging is that our market share is growing across geographic areas.</p>
          <p>Our star is Parfum Christian Dior which is continuing to pursue dynamic growth. Major progress in Europe where the brand is leader and the brand is also growing its market share in Asia and the US.</p>
          <p>Fragrances are growing, driven by the success of J'Adore but also other successful launches.  Increase in the capture  care line, strengthening its ambitions in the anti-age segment as well as the Diorskin and Rouge Dior makeup products. A particular advertising investment to increase the outreach of the brand built around some leading personalities in the world.</p>
          <p>2007 was a very good year for Guerlain. Its star brands such as the mythical Terracotta and Imperial Orchid making good progress. The rollout of the new fragrances of Givenchy and Kenzo that are now next to the strong products of this company.</p>
          <p>A good start for Fendi and for Pucci.  These wonderful Italian brands are celebrating their new youth with a return in the universe of perfumes. Lastly, our Californian brand Benefit can no longer be called a niche brand and is emerging as a rising star after the success in Europe and the US. Its beginnings in China in the last quarter of 2007 were very promising.</p>
          <p>2008, our long term strategy doesn't change. Increased market share, strong growth and operating margin continue to improve. The priority once again on Perfumes Christian Dior where growth requires strengthening its top of the range positioning. We're focusing our efforts on the star lines of the Company that represent the best expression of the brand.  Innovation will be strong in Makeup and inspired from the Couture business. Geographically our ambition is global, to strengthen European leadership on the one hand but accelerated growth in China, Asia and the US.</p>
          <p>For the other brands, we're targeting profitable growth. It's an important year for Guerlain, which in 2008 is celebrating its 180 years of exceptional creation dedicated to beauty. The company will present new developments underscoring its prestigious positioning.</p>
          <p>Aggressive program for Givenchy and Kenzo. For the feminine segment we will focus on developing existing franchise through renewed advertising and showcasing in magazines. In the men's segment the brands will launch a new fragrance.</p>
          <p>We plan to strengthen our positioning across Asia markets with Benefit, Make Up For Ever and Givenchy to give us a broad and varied growth platform.</p>
          <p>Turning now to distribution, selective distribution, which is introduced through an original and sophisticated advertising of the Bon March&#xE9;. Organic growth of 12% in revenues and the profit from recurring operations is increasing by 10%. DFS is continuing to grow its market share in Asia against a backdrop of lower spending by Japanese travelers and a weak yen. The growth of DFS is driven by an increase in Chinese travelers. New plans for Macao and opening the business in Vietnam in the final quarter, these are major growth drivers going forward. Tourist flows on these two destinations are already increasing strongly.</p>
          <p>Equally strategic is to ensure that our product offering is tailored to a more varied range of customers in terms of their geographic origin and more sophisticated. Over 80% of DFS sales derive from luxury products and we have customized services that are being developed.</p>
          <p>2008 footfall for Sephora &#x2013; the brand is posting strong market shares in Europe and the United States. On a comparable basis the store performance is in double digits for the seventh consecutive year in the US and the performance of European stores is nearing that of the US. An acceleration of store openings, 135, bringing our network to over 756 stores with the entry into Middle East and Central European countries.</p>
          <p>Online sales are growing across the board. In France we're following the example &#x2013; the US model. But it's the opposite to the loyalty program where the plan was launched in Europe and yielded very good results. And we're exporting this loyalty program to the United States and China.</p>
          <p>An important point to be underscored is the flexibility of our concept and the way it can be adapted to the various markets as you can see on this slide. The category of products that has grown the most in Europe in Sephora is the Fragrance category. In the US it tends to be Makeup and in China Care products so we are adapting to customer needs.</p>
          <p>Closer to home and Paris, the Bon March&#xE9; performance achieved an excellent year confirming its positioning as a luxury, prestige store. We're reaping the benefits of renovations to the Fashion spaces undertaken over the past years as well as the transformation of the Home area.</p>
          <p>For 2008, DFS will remain focused on strengthening its leadership in Asia, the extension of gallerias in Hong Kong, a rapidly growing market is underway. The new concession in Mumbai which opens next week marks the beginning of a history with the Indian market that we hope will be long and full of opportunities.</p>
          <p>More importantly in 2008 is the opening of the galleria at the Four Seasons in Macao in June. It will offer a very broad range with all the most  prestigious brands and a new concept for DFS.  This store will drive the growth of DFS with Chinese clientele.</p>
          <p>As for Sephora, our objective is to continue the very good momentum in 2008. Our efforts focusing on key markets &#x2013; France, the US, and China. The store opening pace will be similar to 2007 but the real key to drive success is once again the growth of sales on a comparable basis. Our solution is to accentuate our policy of differentiation. Exclusive products, innovative services and a friendly, playful setting.  Our customers are delighted to spend time with us and often they make purchases.</p>
          <p>Final point on Sephora, the Sephora University serves to underscore a key point in the development of our concept, a continuous improvement of training for our staff in stores. Even if we are in a self-service setting, our customers sometimes wish expert and objective advice. We have genuine schools focusing on improving our knowledge of brands.  Beauty is used to better meet their needs.</p>
          <p>Thank you.  Christophe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning. 2007 was a good year for Wines and Spirits. This is the fifth year running where we post double digit growth in terms of profit of recurring operations. If you look at the first slide you can see that revenue is up 8%, organic growth is about 13%.  We're looking at &#x20AC;3.226 billion. And profit from recurring operations is up 10% and we passed the 1 billion mark in Wines and Spirits, well balanced between Spirits, Hennessy mostly and Champagne.</p>
          <p>If you look quickly at the highlights of 2007, we have sustained growth of our flagship brands. Champagne in volume was up 4% compared to 2006, Hennessey was up more than 10% in 2007 and Glenmorangie, our next to last acquisition, is right according to plan, up 16%. The Wines business around the world is growing as planned as well, double digit growth there 13% &#x2013; plus 13%.</p>
          <p>Our policy is to have price increases aggressively. Prices were up 5% on average. We have an improved product mix and this is consistent with our value strategy. We have a significant gain in the Prestige Vintage Champagne, with Ruinart in particular we are looking at the absolute leader in terms of Prestige Vintage Champagnes.</p>
          <p>Last year we decided we would have one solid new category with Rose Champagne and we did just that. We have a category of itself, this is a significant market since we're looking at 21% growth and mostly in the US, Europe or indeed, Asia. And if you look at XO by Hennessey, the performance is again outstanding, up 12%.</p>
          <p>Now what you have to highlight again, what you have to emphasize here that is, of course, we have our existing stars but we have rising stars as well which also are moving right along, indeed, sometimes ahead of our expectations.</p>
          <p>There's one such brand which has been doing extremely well, Krug and Ruinart. They've been going up 20% in volume and the profitability is constantly improving. We're looking mostly at the United States, Italy and France but Germany is also a new market as well as Russia.</p>
          <p>Estates and Wines &#x2013; now this has pursued sustained growth with double digit revenue growth. You have to remember that this comes from various quarters in Argentina as well as Australia.</p>
          <p>Regarding Belvedere and 10 Cane, this is, of course, a Rum brand we started in US recently. And, again, these two brands are very attractive indeed and have great appeal to our customers. I'm delighted to see that we acquired Belvedere last summer, that brand has enjoyed a significant acceleration of its growth in the second half of the year. And Glenmorangie and Ardbeg, again, are enjoying revenue growth as planned, as expected more to the point.</p>
          <p>What you should point out is that all parts of the world are growing simultaneously. Europe the Wines and Spirits is often described as a mature market where growth is difficult, well, not at all. It is in fact the first region in terms of growth with a figure of 11%. And we have a number of other possible sources of growth in Russia, Central Europe.</p>
          <p>You know that these markets are developing and making great strides. United States upped sales 10%. Jean-Jacques was telling you more about that earlier on. And Japan, of course, is a difficult market because there are very few brands that have any growth at all there but we enjoyed a 5% growth thanks to Champagne. Because, of course, we're the ones who created the Champagne market in Japan with Mo&#xEB;t &amp; Chandon and Clicquot. And the rest &#x2013; Asia, of course, is growing as well. Regarding Asia outside Japan, there's, of course, lots of growth there but also Vietnam is great growth potential, worth pointing out.</p>
          <p>So back to China, this is an incredible story, we're looking at 31% &#x2013; plus 31% in euros. And this is nothing new and I'm pretty confident this will continue. The only challenge is to have enough bottles. As Mr. Arnault was saying it's the third market in terms of contribution to profit. So this is not an emerging market, this is a market which is already very big and we will continue to invest there.</p>
          <p>With Hennessey we have the number one Cognac brand. And more than one Cognac in two in China is Hennessey. And our market value there is twice as big as our main competitor for Whisky so we are by &#x2013; far and away the most competitive brand in China.</p>
          <p>Russia now, also extraordinary, great growth. Not just in Moscow, by the way, great growth also in other parts of the country. We have growth potentials that need and will be developed. Our joint venture is doing quite well. We started it in 2006 and that enables us to consolidate our retail margin. And we dominate the Champagne market with our brands.</p>
          <p>We've started a new advertising campaign in the US. This is doing well, this is doing well. This picture is taken by Terry Richardson. He decided to have this picture go with a new launch of that brand Belvedere and the fourth quarter was particularly promising and so we are continuing our efforts with Belvedere in 2008.</p>
          <p>Another thing about 2007 is that we supported our brands very aggressively indeed. You had Dom Perignon Oenoth&#xE8;que, a campaign with &#x2013; an advertising campaign orchestrated by Karl Lagerfeld. This is essential also for the well, <mark type="inaudible" /> image of Mo&#xEB;t &amp; Chandon. We have a new packaging and that vintage from Mo&#xEB;t &amp; Chandon was very successful in 2007.</p>
          <p>Now Clicquot started with the Jeroboams called <mark type="inaudible" />, we have a limited prestige series with the new brand, new labels in ostrich and alligator skin that is selling for <mark type="inaudible" /> thousand dollars a piece and extremely well.</p>
          <p>We have a new advertising campaign for Glenmorangie with new packaging to support the international growth, international development of that brand. And that has been very well received by customers. We have this Malt Whisky which will be the reference in terms of luxury spirits.</p>
          <p>And we acquired, last year, 55% of Wen Jun's capital and that of course is very significant for China. We have seven bottles of white alcohol, it's 70cl bottles for $48, and we have very high hopes for that product in the future. We will have a new product which will be even more expensive than this one coming out next year. So we're looking at developing our luxury image in &#x2013; around the world but mostly in Asia.</p>
          <p>And this brings me to say that in 2008, well we're not &#x2013; we'll stay the course, I mean there's no need to change a winning team. But we want to consolidate what Hennessey's leadership in the world of wines and spirits for what are known as super-premium, so we have all sorts of new initiatives. The rest of the world is gloomy &#x2013; well, this is the chance for us to go &#x2013; step on the gas as it were and we have a number of advertising campaigns already taking place.  New initiatives for Dom Perignon.  In particular we want to have greater penetration of the world of the night as it were &#x2013; nightlife in prestigious places around the world. We have also worked on &#x2013; well, the music advertising campaign has been quite well and we &#x2013; this has developed like wild fire in North America and Asia.</p>
          <p>And let me also point out that all the efforts we have made and that we'll continue to make for our retail network and, indeed, for our sales force on our strategic markets, well, of course, these efforts have paid off. Our returns on investments have enabled us to get with very short returns &#x2013; very quick returns, sorry, on new subsidiaries. We created one in Poland but also one in the Czech Republic. And all this is happening at the beginning of 2008 and we certainly expect to reap the fruit of that around &#x2013; in the course of the year.</p>
          <p>We are also beefing-up our sales forces in the United States. This is the right time to do this. In China we are pursuing our investment program which has been underway for about 10 years. And in Japan we are redeploying our sales force precisely to reach out to our customers in a more effective way.</p>
          <p>So we are pursuing our strategy, no changes there. Well, we will want to step-up our innovation and creation efforts. We want to pursue the development of the product mix, the improvements in the product mix. The prices will have to be increased as well and we're doing just that. In Champagnes the prices on the French market have made &#x2013; started making a big difference in France. And this is essential because it is not good to see prices down especially in supermarkets. Well, we're not there but we do want the brand to be improved also through high prices. And, of course, we are trying to streamline our expenses and our structures and we are trying to have synergies that have an effect of our income statement. So 2008, of course, we have &#x2013; are really looking at an increased budget.</p>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, a tribute to our ambassadors, <mark type="inaudible" />, world champion, and Sharon Stone a world champion in another category.</p>
          <p>A year, 2007, which is illustrated by good results, a very profitable growth momentum. In spite of the currency impact our revenue presented to you &#x20AC;833 million, up 100 million, that's a growth of 13% on a reported basis, organic growth 19%. Many of our peers in Watches report in Swiss Francs whereas we report in Euros. We grew by 28% in 2006, 18% in 2005 with a highly concentrated portfolio, very complementary brands. Our revenue has moved from just under &#x20AC;500 million in 2005 to 833 in 2007 on a very compact scope.</p>
          <p>Swiss exports in 2007, 16% in Swiss Francs.  We continued to grow our market share both in Watches and in Jewelry with this focus on very complementary brands, and a star brand TAG Heuer that is emerging as a star of Swiss Watches and LVMH portfolio.</p>
          <p>Increasingly profitable growth. We quadrupled our operating profit last year. This year we're posting an increase of 76% of the operating margin, it grew by 11% last year to 17% this year, and we confirm our target to cross the 20% margin increase down the road. This is the Carrera of TAG Heuer that we were only partially able to launch in 2007 on some markets because of delays in the movements in particular. It goes from 2,900 to &#x20AC;10,000, does demonstrate our ability to grow upmarket for TAG Heuer and innovate.</p>
          <p>What were the highlights of this year, 2007, over and above our market share grains [sic] and an improvement in the operating margin? TAG Heuer, as Mr. Arnault pointed out, is accelerating its profitable growth without any slowdown in advertising and technical spending.</p>
          <p>TAG Heuer is growing across its markets, in all regions, and significantly improving the profitability of its points of sale like the Grand Carrera that I've just shown you. We're continuing to move upmarket and consolidating the icons, be it the famous F1, Aquaracer, Quartz Automatic, The Link and Carrera. TAG Heuer innovated this year with the new movement Calibre S, an electromechanical movement invented by TAG Heuer.</p>
          <p>And the year was marked by the update of store architectures of the stores, the corners. In TAG Heuer 2007 opened about 10 franchise stores essentially in Asia, a few examples later.</p>
          <p>Profitable growth for Zenith, enhanced positioning in high-end watches with this one. This is the old Primero movement with more sports or modern designs such as the Chronomaster Defy Extreme which received the public prize in Geneva.</p>
          <p>Montres Dior &#x2013; their watches are continuing the high-end positioning driven by the success of Christal line. Enhanced image personified by Sharon Stone. And the development of the men's line Chiffre Rouge Automatic which is confirming its growth and positioning.</p>
          <p>On the left shown here is the new advertising campaign for TAG Heuer with &#x2013; for the Grand Carrera. Lewis Hamilton, he ended in second place behind Kimi our other ambassador, and on the right the Chronograph model, Christal by Dior, red sapphires and diamonds, limited edition for Christmas and the Chinese New Year. Priced at &#x20AC;16,000, that's a very elegant way of moving from the year of the pig to the year of the rat this very morning.</p>
          <p>For Jewelry, Chaumet continued its profitable expansion, very targeted. Very promising development in Asia, three stores in Taiwan, a flagship store in Hong Kong opened in 2006, already profitable. There will be the opening of a store in December 2007, Plaza 66, in Shanghai. The success of Attrape-moi jewelry, some high-end jewelry. And the icon's successfully re-launched the Leah line. Improvement in store productivity and openings, in Shanghai, London Bond Street, Moscow, the third store for Chaumet and Nagoya, Jeddah and Riyadh slightly later in 2007.</p>
          <p>De Beers &#x2013; growing profitability and productivity per store. This is a key component of the business model with a number of new stores. The stores directly operated in Japan &#x2013; shopping &#x2013; shops, Las Vegas shopping mall, Houston, and Washington and Taiwan.  Either &#x2013; and franchise, De Beers, Moscow, Dubai, two other stores in 2007, and in Korea.</p>
          <p>Collections &#x2013; Talisman, strong success in our second watch line you can see on the right with raw diamonds and gems. And an internet site launched the middle of last year, very successful increasing store traffic and generating useful sales of rings.</p>
          <p>Fred, strong growth in France with consolidation of iconic new lines, Princess K and Miss Fred.</p>
          <p>Lastly, we've <mark type="inaudible" />. On the left here, Chaumet, the Season Mall in Moscow, Plaza 66, Shanghai for Chaumet, opened in December, inaugurated in Janvier &#x2013; January with Sophie Marceau.  This one here &#x2013; De Beers' Tizon II and the Houston Galleria opened last October. We also opened a few watch stores and corners. We obviously want to improve the visibility and corners in the multi-brand retailers.</p>
          <p>We have launched a number of our own stores, a few examples here is the Senate Store at Shanghai, Plaza 66. And TAG Heuer, out of the 10 stores open this is the one that's just opened in Cape Town on the waterfront which is operated by a franchisor and then St. Martin to strengthen our presence in the Caribbean. The other TAG Heuer stores opened in Asia, duty free in Hong Kong, Singapore, but duty paid in <mark type="inaudible" /> in Hong Kong.  We just opened Jakarta last week and the machine is moving ahead and progressing very usefully.</p>
          <p>Our outlook for 2008, of course, against a backdrop that was mentioned, to continue strong organic growth, higher than that of our peers and to consolidate our market share gain.</p>
          <p>In TAG Heuer considerable investment from a technical standpoint with a watch-making integration in Chaux-de-Fonds for movements. And the Cotonaulle factory that has been in operation for some years and gives us increased self-reliance. The Grand Carrera launched in many countries where it's anticipated &#x2013; develop stores and corners, not just in new markets such as Russia, India, Middle East, China but a few markets where we consider that there are opportunities to go further.</p>
          <p>The launch of a Mobile Phone offer, TAG Heuer developed the model there. And there's already some keen anticipation from specialized retailers and a few department stores and our stores for these technological items that are really in the DNA of the TAG Heuer brand.</p>
          <p>For Zenith we continue to modernize the manufacture, focusing on buildings. We renovated the machines and we will focus on the icons with a well &#x2013; a balance between the modern and classical models. The Dior watches to continue upmarket positioning with Christal and Chiffre Rouge, with some innovations presented at the Basel Fair. And we have a common management between Dior Watches and Dior Jewelry to synergize the offering.</p>
          <p>Chaumet and De Beers with their respective franchise operators plan store openings in Jeddah, Riyadh, Croat for De Beers in the first quarter. Chaumet is now taking control of its Korean partner and will expand in China.</p>
          <p>De Beers in January opened in Hong Kong at the Landmark and will open a flagship store in Tokyo during the first quarter and a store in San Francisco at the corner of Post and Union. Fred is relaunching Force 10 and strengthening its business in Japan having successfully turned around France in a renovation of the Place Vend&#xF4;me store.</p>
          <p>As you will have noticed our objective is of course to strengthen our operating margin at a higher level and that after two years of strong growth where we've moved from 4 to 11% and then up to 17%. On the right, just a nod to a product which is symbolic of our upmarket strategy with the supply constraints. It's the TAG Heuer diamond chrono &#x20AC;2,250 with a diamond index. It shows &#x2013; it generates considerable margin and no supplies difficulties because it's a quartz movement.</p>
          <p>Just to conclude on two topical pictures because in January we inaugurated &#x2013; Jean-Christophe Babin, Lewis Hamilton and the CEO of TAG Heuer who inaugurated the TAG Heuer 360 degree Museum covering &#x2013; spanning 150 years of performance and innovation to which we remain very loyal, an original landscape where our watches, our collections are inspiring some competitors.</p>
          <p>Maria Sharapova, the TAG Heuer icon has just won the Melbourne Open. There were of course two victories, two successive weekends of Tiger Woods, San Diego and last weekend Dubai, clearly illustrating our thirst to win. And the fact that in January our sales and sell-out are encouraging.</p>
          <p>See you in Basel where TAG Heuer, Zenith and <mark type="inaudible" /> will present their new products which before Basel will be revealed to our best customers. So as not to waste too much time, over to Yves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Bernard Arnault was telling you about Richard Prince and Marc Jacobs working together. Last year's show was very much inspired by this cooperation between the two and you can see an illustration of that in this photograph by Abbott Marcus. And you can see the superb models sprawled &#x2013; splayed on Richard Prince's car.</p>
          <p>You can see that the branch is up 14%. We have the returning from operating &#x2013; from recurring operations up 14% &#x2013; sorry, up 12%. Organic growth 14% in revenue. You can see that the performance in Asia was quite remarkable, remarkable in China and of course in Europe and the United States.</p>
          <p>And there is even growth in Japan because a year ago the question was asked what can you expect of Japan. We were looking at growth in Japan in 2007. We have many, a lot of tourist trade and Tony mentioned this earlier on to DFS. Japanese tourist trade is slightly down but this is compensated by a significant increase in Chinese tourist trade, also in the Middle East, and Russian and Eastern European countries.</p>
          <p>Aruba, Panama, Cyprus were three places where we opened up. So that goes to show how variegated we are. And we have 390 stores, 22 new stores and 40 &#x2013; about 40 renovated stores. And we should highlight the fact that we are looking simultaneously at very different markets. So we have a new store in Vietnam, ten years after the one in &#x2013; after the first one. And Vietnam has been the largest growth in Louis Vuitton in 2007. The trend is proceeding in 2008 so this is the new dragon. Ten years after China this is a new force to be reckoned with.</p>
          <p>We have stores in Nagoya, Beijing, Nicosia in Cyprus and in St. Petersburg because of course after Moscow, St. Petersburg is opening up &#x2013; is showing the way to towns in Russian provinces. And we also have a store in Cape Town right next to the one on the waterfront for TAG Heuer. By the way, a new note, a new ring to Richard Prince, 12 nurses that are of course supermodels, all of them.</p>
          <p>We have in 2007 in Fashion and Leather Goods, Damier Azur was a strong growth factor. It took 100 years between 1896 and 1996 to relaunch Damier, ten years to start a new color. And now Damier Azur is one of the pillars, one of the new territories of the brand. And of course this has confirmed its growth in 2007, looking for more growth in 2008.</p>
          <p>Vernis was started by Marc Jacobs ten years ago during the March 1998 fashion show. Pomme d'Amour and Amarante also had &#x2013; enjoyed great success but Monogram also is doing quite well. So 2007, the striking thing is that if you look at our lines, we're looking up.</p>
          <p>Now great performance in Accessories and we have now a single department for belts, eyeglasses, textiles for men and women. And we find that accessories are becoming so significant now that this is definitely &#x2013; this is an entry point for many customers and a loyalty factor for many others.</p>
          <p>Now we have many other products in Leather Goods and in particular for the past ten years we decided to diversify with shoes, ready to wear and watches. These are growing even faster than ordinary leather goods and that of course contributes to the growth of Louis Vuitton.</p>
          <p>And also we made a significant decision last year to add next to this fashion campaign illustrated by Richard Prince's photographs. We have a campaign on the internal values and Mikhail Gorbachev's picture next to the Berlin Wall will be a turning point in the history of advertising.</p>
          <p>And if you look at Takashi Murakami's participation, the curator of the exhibition told us that you brought art into the stores and we want to have stores into art. And this is somewhat controversial but the idea is to have <mark type="inaudible" /> store redesigned by Takashi Murakami inside the exhibition and that was a tremendous success.</p>
          <p>Now if you look at the other brands, the striking thing is that all the fashion brands enjoyed improvement both in quality and in quantity. We can't go over every luxury line. But if you look at all the brands that made it possible to improve performance, we have a new concept store for Kenzo's. We also have a new Riccardo Tisci at Givenchy. But this is for haute couture, a major turning point likewise for Pucci on the international scale.</p>
          <p>If you look at Fendi's dynamic approach we can see that we have the leather goods there, but also the ready to wear collection is growing. Also the new stores, we have 170 &#x2013; 114 shops at the end of 2007. New territories, Spain, Turkey, Switzerland and Bahrain. And you also read that in the papers or saw it on TV, there was a tremendous media event, this fashion show that took place on the Great Wall of China. So you will not be surprised to see that in 2008, we certainly propose to continue Fendi's growth and we will pursue of course all the stores &#x2013; all the other brands as well.</p>
          <p>But let's go back to Louis Vuitton more specifically. We continue innovation with new products. In the fashion &#x2013; men's fashion show last year, you saw a new color for Damier &#x2013; Azur, which is more resort, more feminine. We have a new color known as Graphite and this is therefore more masculine. That will be delivered in the second quarter. And then a new arrival in the stores &#x2013; they are in stores, the bags designed by Richard Prince. This is a limited series. If you want one you'd better line up. You have about 300 or 400 stores in Louis Vuitton &#x2013; Louis Vuitton stores where you can go.</p>
          <p>I talked about Russia, we have St. Petersburg but in the months to come, we want to open stores in the Russian provinces. But China is of course the main potential of growth. We have a new store in Shenyang open last year, Tianjin next week and then throughout the year we'll be opening a couple of new stores in <mark type="inaudible" />, which is 100 miles away from Kazakhstan. And I can tell you that the sky seems to be the limit to growth in that country. There are more than 100 cities with more than 100 million inhabitants.</p>
          <p>There's a new house in Hong Kong. Hong Kong is of course making the most of the Chinese tourist trade. It's the shopping haven for all of Asia and by mid March we will be reopening what is already the second largest store in the world, both in terms of size but also in terms of revenue. And we will be looking at four new countries, Romania, Finland and two countries in the Middle East, Qatar and Bahrain.</p>
          <p>Now as early as September we should be in a position to take advantage of the expansion of our production site in <mark type="inaudible" /> for shoes. We bought 34,000 square meters of land next to the existing site. The site is being built now &#x2013; the new site is being built and the expansion of our manufacturing capacity should kick in, in September.</p>
          <p>And we will continue our advertising campaign. Fashion of course as you saw with Mert and Marcus but we will also continue with our internal values and in the campaign in &#x2013; the institutional campaign there will be 'Life after Gorbachev' and you will see this in a few weeks time. But for the first time, and this is the first time indeed in the history of the luxury industry there will be an audio visual film which will be used both on TV, in theatres and on the Internet. And of course it is my pleasure to show you 90 seconds of pure emotion.</p>
          <p>[Advertisement]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, ladies and gentlemen, we're now available to take your questions. If you could kindly introduce yourselves, any questions please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Alexandra Dejean, Fashion Daily News. The investment group where you remain rather discreet &#x2013; that of Media in LVMH. What's the interest in investing in this area?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, discreet because the figures are very small and the interest is firstly historical. And it's now up to the new management Nicolas Beytout to demonstrate that this historical interest is transformed into profitable interest. And I'm sure that the outlook thanks to him are very considerable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />, Exane BNP. The first question on the level of investment this year is sustained. What about 2008? What are the main investment plans? The debt ratio is relatively low. The ratios in the Luxury market have declined. Do you have acquisition plans sooner than expected? And a share buyback in terms of the share price, would that be an opportunity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, for investments Tony will answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's true that this year we've increased investments. We remain at 6% of revenues. There is one item that is exceptional which is the purchase of the Belvedere brand and then there's a recurring factor which is the acceleration of our investment in Sephora in terms of store openings &#x2013; a return on capital which is quite attractive. Without entering into the investment projects in 2008, the investment will indeed sustain our growth of the order of 5.5% of total revenues.</p>
          <p>As regarding our debt ratio, it has declined. But we're not yet Triple A, we're only A, thanks to [inaudible. So we can still improve our financial strength. As to share buybacks, prices are low. It's interesting to buy. I won't tell you what we'll do because it will increase the share price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Merger markets. The CEO of <mark type="inaudible" /> said that he was open to a minority shareholding in his capital. Is that something that might interest you, perhaps in an exchange of an asset that would not be strategic for you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. We have no interest in this company which is furthermore quite brilliant. Further questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just to return to external growth, you said that you wished to strengthen your efforts on organic growth. You will have noticed that the prices of <mark type="inaudible" /> stopped increasing and are perhaps starting to decline and that your debt capacity was high. Could you perhaps expand on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's true that the price of business is starting with LVMH. LVMH, as the previous speaker mentioned, have decreased. It's no doubt the best opportunity in the market. I'm saying that for investors who are present in the room.</p>
          <p>As to businesses that LVMH might acquire &#x2013; well, we'll see. I believe that there will be increased disparity between various businesses in the luxury market. And so the valuation variances will tend to grow between companies that have star brands, that have brands that are growing year-on-year, which as I said earlier, post &#x2013; have regularity in their earnings and the others that are less protected against short term changes. It will offer opportunities but we have nothing specific in this area of acquisition currently under study. That might open up in the coming years. Internal growth prospects of the Group are very good. As I mentioned our objective is to double the value of the business over the next five years as we've done over the past five years. And to double its earnings. So intrinsically we don't need to have an acquisition in the Group's brands. We have the necessary growth potential to significantly improve the value of the Group. Now if irresistible opportunities were to arise then we would study them. But they would have to be irresistible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the tax rate could we have an idea of the gradual trend increasing as you're exhausting your tax credits over the next years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, the tax rate is increasing for the next few years -it's rather complicated to give you a specific forecast. In 2007 we activated as accounting standards required the deficit tax carry forwards that we'll use in the coming years. That's a favorable impact on the tax rate. There were tax rate decreases unfortunately not in France but in more advanced countries we're able to take up deferred tax liabilities that we put opposite a number of assets. That had a positive effect of the order of 3, 4%. It won't go to 0. But over a two, three years this positive impact will disappear. Like any well organized company we are working to reduce our tax rate. There is a mechanical increase linked to the end of this activation of the deferred tax liabilities, and substantive effort with our brands to avoid paying taxes when its possible, in compliance with local and international regulations of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> from Reuters. Did you &#x2013; have you made an offer on Absolut Vodka?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we made no such offer. I can confirm this.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am from Bloomberg and I have three questions. Number one. Renee Cointreau a few weeks back said that they was dropping inventory amongst wholesalers in the US for cognac. Have you seen the same phenomenon at home? And has Fendi become profitable? And question number three &#x2013; do you propose to increase prices in the US and Japan for leather goods? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the first question is no, and I am not quite sure how Renee Cointreau could have said that. The answer to that is no. Regarding Fendi, we have moved into profitable territory. Regarding possible price hikes, we will have to adapt to monetary variations &#x2013; to currency changes. We don't announce price increases ahead of time. The only way for us to hedge against negative currency effects are &#x2013; well price increases. But it will all depend on currency changes in 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> again and I have two questions on hedging. Could we know what the levels are? And on price mixes you are looking, of course, at well to do customers. If you look at watches and jewelry, prices are high if you are looking at the top end, some time pieces are worth tens of thousands or indeed millions of euros. But for baggage, which is your core business, very few items are more than &#x20AC;5,000 except for a few exceptional items. Any change in this respect?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, a few bags sell for &#x20AC;30,000 but these are a very limited series. But I think what we have is an increased gain in the position of the leather goods. And we have more and more bags selling for more than &#x20AC;3,000 across the territories. So there again there is a potential in the high end growth. But, of course, Louis Vuitton proposes to cover all segments. And so for &#x2013; the dream for any young person is to buy his or her first Louis Vuitton bag, and as his career spans he will, or she will be able to buy more and more expensive Louis Vuitton bags.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On hedging now, for 2008 we have a high hedging level for the yen and dollar, about 80% of the 2008 budget is covered. 1.36 for the dollar and 1.57 for the yen. For 2009 you have some hedges &#x2013; 20% coverage to 1.46 for the dollar. So more recent hedges come closer to present exchange rates, and for the yen 30% of the budget, that's 1.58. The only comment is that the cost of hedging is coming down significantly, because there is not much volatility. The dollar differential, well the dollar/euro rate is evolving in the right way. We had a negative phenomenon for a number years, and now this is a reversal, its not a huge turn around but it gives us more flexibility than we've had in the past two or three years.  Further questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Lisa Rachal from Redburn Partners. Three questions, the first is could you clarify your expansion plans in China in 2008 between the fashion and leather division and also for Sephora. And on Sephora, when you say that you are planning a similar level of openings in 2008 versus '07, does that mean well over 100? And then secondly on growth by region, it's interesting to note that while Asia ex-Japan is, of course, a very exciting region for you, it didn't grow faster than, for example, the US overall in 2007. Could you give us a sense for &#x2013; if there is any significant difference in growth rate by, for example, nationality? If you were to group Asia, ex-Japan and include purchases abroad, would the growth rate look much higher? And then the final question is your strategy for some of the smaller fashion brands, especially Loewe under Stuart Vevers, do you think that 3 to &#x20AC;5 million in sales is a reasonable target for Loewe, Marc Jacobs and Givenchy over the medium term?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First regarding expansion in Asia the figures I gave you are figures in euros. So the 14% growth is in euros. If &#x2013; well there are many currencies that is why we give you euros rather than local currencies. If you see &#x2013; if you look at the local currency growth we are looking at 8 or 9% &#x2013; percentage points.  Not as much as for dollar because we had more growth there. So we are looking at really 23, 24% growth in Asia, but of course, much more than that in China. Christophe mentioned that earlier on. So regarding the differences between nationalities well, of course, China mainland or the tourist trade is the main driver of growth in that part of the world. Regarding expansion plans in China &#x2013; maybe Tony can say something.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well just to answer your question specifically about Sephora store openings.  So, yes, we will be opening over 100 stores in 2008. We had 135 net openings this year, and the issue is sometimes the malls are a little bit late, so I will not commit to a very detailed specific number, but it will be in the same range. Of those, the stores in China will be moving from about 30 end of 2007, 30 to today in fact, between 60 and 70. Again it's not about opening stores, it's opening good stores that work.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Loewe I can indeed confirm that this brand has a good deal of potential. We've just hired a new designer who worked with Marc Jacobs. It has the highest growth rate in Japan, very high growth in Asia. And the potential of this brand is considerable. You indicated a few hundred million euros, it's a brand in the next few years can achieve 3, 4, &#x20AC;500 million. It's an upmarket strategy, that of Loewe.  It's the most prestigious Spanish brand. We now have an excellent management team, a very adapted designer. And I would say that the results are more and more convincing, and we will see a very strong growth of the brand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.  Reuters. You said you were reasonably confident regarding your outlook for 2008, barring a global cataclysm. Could you be more specific regarding the change in operating results compared to 2007?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we are trying to give the general indication, which is always appreciated by analysts, both through its indicative nature and by its lack of precision. So I won't depart from that rule, just perhaps invite you to refer to what has happened over the past five years, and to say that if it were to work like that &#x2013; if it worked like that for five years there is a probability that it will indeed continue for a few years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Scheherazade Daneshkhu from Financial Times. Can I ask you if you are seeing any effects at all from the credit squeeze, and the increased cost of capital? And do you expect to see any effects this year? And the second question on the media, would you like to own the Financial Times?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would love to. But... I think it's a little too expensive for us probably.  While the future will tell us how the available cash flow of the business that we've developed, and with that burdening the finances of LVMH to undertake acquisitions.</p>
          <p>As regarding the economic crisis and the credit squeeze, I believe that this economic crisis, as I said earlier in my presentation, is a crisis that can lead to a recession in the US. Our experts forecast that if there is a recession it will be a rather limited recession, and we would witness an upturn in global activity in 2009. And that the short term trend is good &#x2013; nothing will stop the long term growth prospects. Of course, the subprimes' rather mind-boggling way of managing the loans of people who couldn't afford. You're familiar with the story. We lend money to people to buy a home knowing that they could never reimburse the home, and counting on the increase in the price of the home to repay the loan. Unfortunately the house prices didn't rise, so we are now faced with this problem. And we are suffering the consequences of that on the markets, stock exchanges, banks etc. But our experts view this as a problem, an ad hoc quote unquote problem that is likely to lead to a slowdown, possibly a recession in the US, but not an economic cataclysm. And as regards our customers, these are high-end customers who are not currently affected by this problem. It's true that for Champagne, Monsieur Navarre will confirm this in Wall Street, if the results are good, well the results are celebrated. If they are poor well we drown our sorrows in Champagne. So we always have resources to expand our products. We're perhaps in the second situation, but Champagne sales are growing strongly in the US. So I think the traders, those who have problems like the others drink Champagne for various reasons. So I am not too worried by the impact of the credit squeeze on our business. As to the Group, as Jean-Jacques indicated, currently we have credit lines that are well beyond our requirements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sycamore Asset Management. Just a word on the commitment that Diageo and the minorities of Mo&#xEB;t Hennessy, what's the time-line of the agreement, and who can exercise it?  Who has the discretion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a put at the initiative of Diageo and there is no time &#x2013; it's a put that would only come into play at 80% of the asset price.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Natixis. Just to return to your announcement on January &#x2013; double digit organic growth. Am I right in understanding that Louis Vuitton is also in that trend, double digit? And just to pick up on the growth of Sephora in terms of network of stores and their strategies rolled out with JCPenney, which seems to replicate in certain other countries such as the Netherlands. Could you perhaps just tell us what your strategy is in this regard? And if it's going to be replicated across other countries? There were rumors in the UK.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well in January double digit growth across all areas of activity and Louis Vuitton too. As regards the expansion strategy for Sephora, we've just announced an agreement for the Netherlands if that is what you are referring to, where we have an agreement to use the Bruman Resmond real estate to develop Sephora stores, which also allows us to open &#x2013; and that's our strategy &#x2013; standalone Sephora stores.  It's the same strategy in the US where we are progressing. In the experience with JCPenney, don't forget that we still have a limited number of stores in the US, even if they are growing, we have a long way to go in standalone. And the Penney experience, which is very good in terms of the sales revenues, well, we are working on the operational aspects &#x2013; stores, service, logistics, details to make sure the machine works well. Our strategy remains that to continue to open our own stores, and where an opportunity arises, well we will seek to have agreements if they can operate properly. For instance in the Middle East we have a partner who is working with us, because these are rather more complicated markets to operate and we need a partner.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>One last question? No last question. In that case, thank you very much.</p>
          <p>&#x20AC;</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>