<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1330463" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-07-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>846</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Bernard Arnault, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Jean-Jacques Guiony, Finance</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Antonio Belloni, Group Managing Director</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Antoine Belge</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Yves Carcelle</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Melanie Flouquet</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Bonsoir, Mesdames et Messieurs.  Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. I'm delighted to welcome you to this presentation of the half year results. I believe you've received the reports, which Jean-Jacques Guiony passed around. I believe everybody got a copy of the reports, so you got the figures. I imagine that comments are unnecessary because figures speak for themselves, but I'll say a few words just to provide some comments on the figures.</p>
          <p>This was an outstanding half year, because overall growth was 16% encompassing all our business areas. We had a double-digit growth in all business areas and in fact, we have profit from recurring operations up 33% and 20% for the operating margin.</p>
          <p>So how can you account for such remarkable growth? And here I would like to pay tribute to all the teams that were involved in this half year's hard work. Because of course, the figures all very well, but they are the result of lots of work by motivated teams but also creative artists and fine production units, and we have to remember that these units are located in France, most of them, and in view of the growing figures, we are expanding capacity. Gradually, we are expanding on our workshops. So this is sustained and intense work. Of course, this is guided by creativity, but it is carried by a global market which is quite different from last year because this year we are enjoying resumed growth and therefore business is buoyant, especially in a number of Asian countries, but also in the United States and indeed in some European countries, at least as far as we are concerned.</p>
          <p>We should also point out that -this performance reflects the specificity of our Group, because in this industry very few groups can boast the same kind of success in their product line. At LVMH, we have a well-established strategy. We are very discriminating in choosing and determining our products, and this is what makes us unique in the luxury industry</p>
          <p>Of course referring to cash flow, cash flow again is excellent, so that the debt to equity ratio is down to 20% and of course we are down from the highest historical levels we had in previous years. So, of course, this is all looking very good.</p>
          <p>You might ask whether this good performance in H1 will be repeated in H2. Well, of course, I'm not about to give you a verdict on that. We have to remain cautious, but what I can tell you is that the trend in July has been very much the same as in the first six months of the year, but one has to remain cautious, because of course the global economic outlook is uncertain. We know that there have been a number of hiccups over the past two years. We do not know whether exchange rates will fluctuate; there is a high amount of volatility on the exchange markets. But having said all that, we're fairly confident on H2 and we believe that the success of our products, and because our products, of course, have a very unique qualities that attract a high-end clientele, we have reason to believe that business will be buoyant as well and indeed we gained market shares in all business areas.</p>
          <p>Now in 2010, we shall pursue, well, in the second half of the year, the same cost control policies and that has enabled us to improve profit as a ratio to revenue. We are also pursuing CapEx. We are investing both in distribution and production, and of course our geographic distribution is aimed at the most promising countries, and in particular, we have opened a number of shops for our brands, including Louis Vuitton itself, very successfully indeed, as we've started two new outlets in China, and we shall continue very selectively to expand our distribution networks. Now, we'll have a number of products to be launched in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Of course, the one challenge we do have and indeed this is &#x2013; to some extent it's a waiting list situation for many of our goods, because demand is greater than supply, at least for certain products: production capacity simply doesn't match demand. Of course it's an enviable challenge, I would say, but at the same time it does mean that we have to work out our production timetables more effectively if supply is to meet demand.</p>
          <p>So, now that's the general outlook, and I'll also ask Guiony to look at the figures more closely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Merci. Thank you. Good evening. I'll begin with revenues. So revenues up 16% in euro, organic growth 14%. There was a favorable exchange currency impact of 2%, you'll see how that developed during the quarter.</p>
          <p>Organic growth by business segment: Wines &amp; Spirits put in a remarkable performance, up 18%. A slight slowdown in the second half. Some destock increase; I'll return to that later for questions on that. Destocking effect was particularly marked in the first half, but organic growth of 16% in the second quarter, so that's a favorable trend.</p>
          <p>In Fashion &amp; Leather Goods 14%, a marked improvement, a marked acceleration should I say, in Q2. Worth noting that Fashion &amp; Leather Goods same time last year was already up, so growth on growth, which isn't the case across the board.</p>
          <p>Very good performance of Perfumes &amp; Cosmetics, up 10% organic, Watches &amp; Jewelry, that experienced an early, a challenging beginning of the year in '09, are up sharply, 24%. Selective Retailing, which was also up last year at the same period, is adding growth to growth, very respectable performance, up 13%. Overall, our top line growth, it is indeed very interesting.</p>
          <p>Let's stay with the top line. So you have the breakdown here of Group, total Group growth between the two quarters and the summary of the first half. You see in dark blue that organic growth of the Group was pretty consistent across quarters, up 13% Q1, 15%, Q2. Currency impact, it was negative in the Q1 as you see; it's positive by 7% in the second, so growth in euros is of course far higher in Q2.</p>
          <p>The geographic breakdown of revenue by region: drop in Japan, increase in Asia and this balance, three thirds between the three major continents, which is one of the Group's strengths as you know. More interesting, the change of revenue by region. By local currency, we see that the U.S. remained on a sustained level of business, 20% for the first quarter, plus -- up 18% for the first half, double digit growth for the first half; things looking very good, Japan figures less good even if we saw they're not satisfactory: we're still at minus 6%, on a par for both quarters. Asia remains very good, up 21%, consistent across the two quarters, driven by China which is up 27% but also by other countries: Macao, Hong Kong or Korea to a lesser extent. And it's a pleasant surprise &#x2013; well not really a surprise, because the number was at that level at the first half, up 11% for Europe. Europe is viewed as the laggard in the economic situation; double-digit growth in Europe. We are pleased with that.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the summarized income statement, I won't return to sales that I have already discussed. Gross margin up 19%, store sales up 16%. Improved gross margin, 64.9% gross margin. Selling and admin expenses growing not as fast as revenue. You may have questions on that number effect. In terms of selling expenses, clearly it's the effect of the increase in the size of networks and also our increased spend in advertising behind our brands. For admin expenses, there were a number of complicated effects that I won't detail here, but if you have questions, I will take those later.</p>
          <p>This lag between the increase in the gross margin and the selling and admin expenses lead us to an improvement in our profit from recurring operations up 33% over the period. Other income and expenses down sharply over last year and are essentially the intangibles, depreciation. So the operating profit is up 40%, early or late.</p>
          <p>On the financial income, not much change there. Tax 28.9%; pre-tax income slightly better than last year. Minority interest, slight increase: at DFS and Moet Hennessy, the minority interest there have increased, and in total, net profit up 53%, which is quite remarkable and exceeds for the first the time for a first half tops the &#x20AC;1 billion mark without any specific positive one-off exceptionals to account for that.</p>
          <p>A word on the profit from recurring operations by business group: very good performance as you can see on the right hand column. Everyone's posting double-digits, but higher than those in euro sales so the operating margin by business is up over the first half.</p>
          <p>Good performance by Wines &amp; Spirits in spite of a way of accounting for the harvest, which is very unfavorable as champagne yields are down. Good results for Fashion &amp; Leather Goods, up 28%. Perfumes &amp; Cosmetics putting an extraordinary result, up 50%. I'm not sure we'll be able to repeat that performance in the second half; there's some phasing issues there between the two halves of ad spending in particular, but one, of course, must savor the moment.</p>
          <p>The Watches &amp; Jewelry more than doubled &#x2013; we're talking three-figure increase &#x2013; more than doubled their result. Good performance by Tag Heuer; excellent performance by Zenith in those figures. Beginning to reap the benefits of the efforts put in over a year ago.  A very good performance by Selective Retailing, up 36% whereas revenue increased only by 15% give or take. So that's a very remarkable figure. So in total, 33% increase in the profit from recurring operations.</p>
          <p>-A word on the currencies: here, it's generally negative; here, it's positive. Here, that's very useful. 116 million positive currency impact over the first half; not much of a dollar impact, because the dollar bid on average over the half remained stable at around 1.33 over the same period last year.  Picked up at the end of the half, but on average it's pretty much flat. so essentially on the year.. And then secondary currencies that we generated those impacts, to the tune of 8% of the profit from recurring operations.</p>
          <p>A word on the net financial expense: the first line, of course, cost of net financial debt, sharply down the debt &#x2013; average debt over the half is sharply down. Financial expense is down, interest rates also down. Second reason to bring down the cost of net financial debt, it could have dropped more &#x2013; at least the cost could have decreased further, but as with many companies, we're up to a certain rigidity of our gross debt that -declines according to the maturities. &#x2013; that leads to an increase in cash and in today's market conditions, it's more or less impossible to obtain a significant return on cash. So a sizeable part of our cash then doesn't yield very much. Of course, we can't concern with that. We're going to use that cash to buy back debt and to reduce that gap that is affecting our financial expense.</p>
          <p>So ineffective portion of currency hedge: cost of our hedges is a non-predictable item, as you know. It increases hugely for those interested in the technicalities of the thing, the dollar has increased substantially over the half, while the value of currency hedges &#x2013; or at least the time value of currency hedges &#x2013; has reduced sharply. All the currency hedges have moved outside their currency, so there we booked a significant hedged portion of this cost in the P&amp;L, which accounts for the increase in this number. The other items are not particularly significant, will prompt no specific comment.</p>
          <p>A word on the balance sheet: a solid financial structure, nothing new. It's very robust. Just the word that struck me in preparing these slides is that equity accounts for over half the balance sheet; that's the strength I find in the balance sheets. We increased in inventories; we'll return to that. And of course there was a currency effect. We increased our equity during the half, but nothing exceptional apart from that.</p>
          <p>A word on cash flow: cash from operations, as Mr. Arnault said is, a cause of satisfaction for the first half. During the half, we generated cash before changes in working capital of 1.1 billion. Last year over the full year, we generated over 2 billion, but if I recall well, in 2008 I believe we generated 1.350, so over a single half we generated almost as much as during the full year '08, so that's a commendable, remarkable performance indeed attributable to various levels. Of course, cash from operations, which of course, reflects the operating results that we saw earlier, and also change in working capital requirements. We're able to contain those notably. Inventories. Last year, let's not forget that we suffered from a number of non-recurring items, such as the new Economy Modernization Law, which brought down the supply. That wasn't the case this year.</p>
          <p>Operating investments, slightly up, but below what we had in the first half of 2008, but of course, that's up quite logically with the upturn over the full half. So free cash flow sharply up in an absolute terms, very considerable. On the basis of the cash flow analysis, we considered that our dividend and interim dividend policy wasn't fully adapted. Our interim dividends are 20% of the total. We looked at CAC 40 companies that pay out interim dividends: there aren't many, but it's of the order of 40, 45% of the total.</p>
          <p>So, in order to rebalance the cash flow of the year, not this one, but the net cash flow, after payments of the dividend, we elected to double the interim dividend to move from 0.35 to &#x20AC;0.70 per share, which will lighten the dividend burden on the first half and increase it in second half and we'll redress the balance over the year. This, of course, doubling of the interim dividend is not necessarily significant of the final dividend number that we'll announce next year, but of course, we'll seek to reflect in the dividend trend, the development of our business.</p>
          <p>Our net financial debt, this is an untypical chart that we wanted to illustrate over several years generally net debt at 30th of June is higher than that of 31st of December for reasons I just stated, payment of the balance of the dividend that is greater than that of the interim dividend, so we used up more cash during the first half. It was the cases this year. But given the cash flow that you saw earlier, debt at the 30th of June is lower than that of 31st, it's up 2.565 billion. Mr. Arnault said gearing at 16% which is a relatively low level.</p>
          <p>That's what I wanted to say about the results. Over to Tony, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Bonsoir a toute, [Foreign Language] Good evening. Let us look at all the business areas. I will give you an overview but then my colleagues can take specific questions. So let us start with Wines &amp; Spirits and we have this playful sleeve presentation of the Hennessy Cognacs. The sales, the revenue in this department were up 18% in organic growth and the profit from recurring operations were up 35% as Jean-Jacques pointed out. A good performance in all areas, the U.S. and Europe about 20% and Asia, which held out beautifully in 2009, is still up 9%. The market shows signs of recovery after destocking in 2009. Our brands have a consistent pricing policy. They have their premium positioning, but of course we have worked on advertising as well to maintain our prices.</p>
          <p>Champagne volumes are up 23% with a good development, good advance on the high prestige vintages. The cognac volumes are up 16%, thanks to dynamic Asian markets but also the successful launch of Hennessy Black in the United States.</p>
          <p>In the second part of the year our brand portfolio is in a good position to take advantage of the recovery. Our strategy is to focus our efforts on the great classic champagne, Veuve Clicqot Yellow Label, but also innovation programs at Hennessy, Glenmorangie and Belvedere, which got good response from the customers and we are rolling out new marketing efforts to secure new market share.</p>
          <p>This is the new advertising campaign for Louis Vuitton to move on to Fashion &amp; Leather. The revenue in this business is up 14% in organic growth. The profits from recurring operations up 28%, all regions are doing &#x2013; growing rapidly, except for Japan. As Mr. Arnault pointed out, Louis Vuitton has been able to confirm its amazing, its powerful appeal on this period. All the business areas are contributing to this growth, from leather goods to shoes and indeed ready-to-wear. And our dealers network has extended to 451 stores. We opened two shops in Shanghai, and we inaugurated the house in New Bond Street.</p>
          <p>And for the other brands, we have good recovery for Fendi, thanks to the Peekaboo line and profitability is up, and all other brands in their specific stores and boutiques are doing well.</p>
          <p>Now, this is the London boutique and this shows the brand's ability to combine its roots with modern modernity, with a modern look. And for the second half of the year, Louis Vuitton is looking at the dynamic time to launch new products, in particular looking at the new product line for leather goods in a supple leather. And we also are looking at new territories and we will start the  Tanneries de la Com&#xE8;te leather workshop, which will improve both the production and quality. Fendi is also innovating with new product lines and Marc Jacobs is expanding, or is speeding up its world expansion, but we remain selective in terms of costs and CapEx throughout the Group.</p>
          <p>Perfumes &amp; Cosmetics, revenue is up 10% in organic growth, profit from recurring operations 50%. Revenue is climbing steeply in the U.S. and Asia with the combined effect of stock replenishment and a small recovery in &#x2013; resumption, I meant &#x2013; in final demand. Parfums Christian Dior has performed outstandingly with its unique position in the universe of couture and developed its classic lines. We have good advertising with</p>
          <p>Miss Dior Ch&#xE9;rie and Eau Sauvage and we are developing this new cosmetic line, Capture Totale One Essential, which combines high effectiveness and technology.</p>
          <p>Now, good performances as well for the French brands, Guerlain and Givenchy, with innovations at the end of 2009 turning into a real success, and Benefit and Make Up For Ever are growing rapidly as well and proving to be very profitable worldwide.</p>
          <p>For the second half of 2010, we are looking at new market shares through a sustained innovation and new investment in advertising. Of course, the priority is on Parfums Christian Dior looking at lipstick Rouge Dior, and internationally we will be rolling out Eau Sauvage and a new figure for Miss Dior Ch&#xE9;rie.</p>
          <p>And the other brands also are producing novelties. We have an anti-aging cosmetic for Guerlain. We are expanding the Play product line at Givenchy, and new fragrances at Fendi and Pucci.</p>
          <p>Now, the charismatic charm of a Steve McQueen and the presence of Hublot in football have enhanced our image for Watches &amp; Jewelry. Revenue is up 24% and profits from recurring operations 145%.Now revenue is up in all regions, mostly in the U.S. and in Asia.</p>
          <p>Regarding watches, we have the double bound effect of restocking for our retailers, but also an upturn in demand from our final end users, mostly in specific boutiques and the innovation programs looking at the emblematic lines of metal were also very successful. We have the chronographer by El Primero and the rings by Josephine de Chaumet, very successful. We have the Napolitain likewise. We worked on cost cutting and we are able to improve operating profitability.</p>
          <p>Now, our ambassadors are very much involved in that work. Here you have Leonardo DiCaprio working in our watch making workshop.</p>
          <p>Now for the second half of the year, we propose to strengthen our market shares. Restocking has been taken care of. And now the engine for growth was shown at the Bezons Fair. We were looking more &#x2013; mostly at the high potential markets, including China, where we have some ways to go. TAG Heuer has been celebrating its 150th anniversary, its 150th birthday should I say, with advertising looking at its involvement in automotive in motorsports.</p>
          <p>And 2010 is also a year with our watch brands will be speeding up their industrial integration, the Nyon plant -for Hublot watches is integrating high-end expertise in the watch making industry. And then we have selective brands in &#x2013; for single brands to improve visibility in some of our key cities such as New York, Singapore and Paris.</p>
          <p>And now in Selective Retailing, we have -on organic growth is 13% and profit from recurring operations up 36%. Revenue outstanding throughout, especially in Asia, -particularly dynamic in the Asia. DFS is growing remarkably with the Chinese clientele. We have the Galleria di Macao, which is a real &#x2013; is a truly successful operation, and our flagship store at the Hong Kong Sun Plaza is extending and pursuing its renovation.</p>
          <p>In the short term, we have maybe less results to show for in Abu Dhabi, and Mumbai but these are very promising in the long term. We also have -cost development for Sephora in a number of regions, in particular in China, but also in the Middle East, where we have good visibility for Sephora. But also Internet sales, which are taking up a very powerful market because we also work hard on maintaining customer relationships.</p>
          <p>And in selling concept we are developing, we have decided to take a majority stake in Sack's in Brazil, which is an opportunity to pursue to develop the brand, and we have as many as 1,000 shops opened in the first half of 2010. And the beautiful glass ceilings of the glass roof &#x2013; I beg your pardon, of Maison de &#xC9;dition show our effort to develop the identity of Bon March&#xE9;, and that will be developed with the Hommes Balthazar men's department there.</p>
          <p>And then -DFS -is also extending its services to Chinese travelers and in particular we will complete the second galleria in Macao, City of Dreams and also we have to continue our cost cutting policies this was providential last year and will continue to improve profitability next year.</p>
          <p>Now of course for Sephora, our priority is to expand our market shares, to expand also our network of shops and boutiques, but we're also looking at new territories with high potential to improve our global leadership. We are working in developing those items that make us unique, make Sephora unique and a strategic investment has been decided to have online sales producing technological support but also expanding our presence in Europe.</p>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, ladies and gentlemen we're now open to take your questions. Are there any questions, please, yes? If you can kindly state -your name and affiliation before putting your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good evening, Antoine Belge, HSBC. Three questions, firstly, Mr. Arnault, you mentioned waiting list at Louis Vuitton and possibly a question of undercapacity. Could you remind us how many factories Louis Vuitton has and what are the expansion plans for the next three to five years?</p>
          <p>Secondly, free cash flow generation was very strong especially for a first half -without there being a projection to the end of the year where we can estimate. Mr. Guiony I think mentioned net debt that should be below the 2 billion mark at the end of the year will no doubt be on that. Can we expect a share buyback program or exceptional dividend perhaps earlier than expected?</p>
          <p>And -third question, there are figures in Europe which are very good as you indicated. Are they fully attributable to the boost in tourism thanks to the currency impact, or would you note some local customers who continued to buy and if so in what country?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Mr. Carcelle will tell you about the factories, the plants. Our workshops are many in number, though we have program, but that this program we don't publish the programs, though we tell you about the workshop that's under construction, because it's difficult to hide, but the rest is secret. So, Yves Carcelle will give you some details about the workshop that's under construction. But then it's very interesting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] . All right. Well, as you may have noticed, we have enjoyed steadily growing demand and we have decided to work at expanding our capacity for leather goods. Of course, it's only one item, but we have hired as many as 220 leather smiths. leather makers, which is quite a number in itself. But we've started a new site that was slightly delayed because we had difficulties with the local authorities. But it is in Marsaz; it's a beautiful site. Of course, it is rather inconsistent with our &#x2013; this is a venue, by the way, from the real thing. This is a three GR. But the roof is all glass and so we cannot leave &#x2013; this improves the thermal balance, but it also makes for better integration in the natural site. We've decided to open this out in the country and when you are in a beautiful area like this, people feel like making beautiful products.</p>
          <p>And in Ducey we have leatherworkers in  more traditional, where they will be able to look at Zercor outside the window and that would be most inspiring.</p>
          <p>So this is a site worth mentioning. I believe that very few companies create such industrial sites, for workshops, for manual workshops, in France. And as we &#x2013; I'm mentioning this; Tony referred to the Tanneries de la Com&#xE8;te. This is of course, where leather is tanned. Here, the skins are dried. They remain there for four days, and this is natural &#x2013; well, this natural leather takes four days to change colors naturally from brown to white.</p>
          <p>This is a very environmental tanning factory. We're working with &#x2013; it was a family owned business. And we've decided to start this joint venture. This is a vegetal leather tanning. It is wood, which is a ground wood, which slowly, but surely provides this pigment to the leather. This is totally vegetal tanning technique, a very environmental friendly. The water is not polluted. Of course, water has sawdust in it, so it cannot be consumed, but we are going to introduce the centrifuge to separate out the wood particles from the water, so that the water can be used for natural consumption. So this is a vegetal processing of leather as part of our sustainable development.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So on cash flow, I didn't quite understand the question you're asking, whether we went beyond the 2 billion mark or below the 2 billion market of debt at the end of the year? Was that your question? Well, it's difficult to make a forecast, because thanks to the crisis, we don't do forecasts anymore so, we leave it as a surprise. We hope we'll still have some good surprises, but that's the advantage of the present situation.</p>
          <p>Debt, I recall a few years back in this very room, when we were giving these presentations, people were saying, well, there's too much debt. So now basically your question is not enough debt, if I read you right.</p>
          <p>So what to do with the cash flow? Well, do we need to buy back shares, pay out, I can't really, I can't answer. We'll see. In any event, there's still some debt left, so let's allow a year or two to pass, until the debt disappears and then we'll see.</p>
          <p>Customers in Europe. Well, here we can say that across our points of sale in the Vuitton stores, cosmetics stores, it's very cosmopolitan, it's very local. If you stroll down the Champs-Elys&#xE9;es in Paris, and you look in the Vuitton store, the line waiting outside of people, you'll see that very varied population: French people, Europeans, and that's the case in European countries, and then we have customers, for our brands in Europe, Italy, U.K., Spain. There's a strong increase in local customers, so it's not just linked to tourism. Further questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] . Mr. Guiony, is of course available to take questions or to respond to matters pertaining, matters financial, perhaps on which I'm less competent.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm from the Financial Times. And could you say something about possible acquisitions? Are you expecting to pursue an aggressive acquisition policy and if L'Or&#xE9;al is up for grabs might you be interested?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on your second question, the answer is no. On the first part of your question, difficult for me to answer. Either we have plans, and I can't reveal them, or we don't have any, in which case I don't have anything to say. So it is difficult to answer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>[Foreign Language] Further questions. Oui, monsieur.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" />. Could you give us details about the actual results of Wines &amp; Spirits? There are some items that are, that are only coming into H2. Ch&#xE2;teau d'Yquem in particular is only accounted for in H2? And then, on the cost cutting, you said that you are looking at cutting operating costs. Can you give us details about that, especially as regards advertising?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, Mr. &#x2013; we could tell you about Wines &amp; Spirits, but regarding the Chateau 2009 was an outstanding year and Cheval Blanc, which we sold &#x2013; the new Cheval Blanc  premier wine was sold at &#x20AC;600 a bottle and we sold out in 10 minutes. This has a huge potential because when you look at the development of emerging markets and the taste for high quality wine, there is a huge demand and production is limited in there. Unlike workshops, where we can hire new workers, there we are limited in terms of wine-making.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but &#x2013; and, of course, there is a premier Yquem sales in the first half but of course, this is still consistent with what Mr., our friend Belloni just said. This will not affect the other lines or the other areas of Wines &amp; Spirits.</p>
          <p>[Foreign Language] .</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Are there other questions? Ma'am?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Melanie Flouquet, JPMorgan.  Would you share with us specifics on your strategic outlook, looking at the aging population? Are you going to adapt your policies or your strategies? Are you looking for instance into the hospitality industry? I know you have a small project there, but are there some large industries you are thinking of expanding in the coming years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, population aging it depends on what country you are referring to. In India the average age is 25 in the population. So if you take China, they are also very, very young. Japan, the situation there is different, Europe, ditto, so for us emerging countries or rather young countries with growth potential in their customers, young customers and our capacity to grow that within our brands is considerable. And so we must attract young people and try and retain them for a significant part of their lives.</p>
          <p>New activities, hotel, that's really very small. We launched that from the Cheval Blanc brand. We have number of plans. What we can say, what distinguishes this business, it's still in its infancy, is that unlike other brands that license their brand on hotels managed by other companies, we've opted for a different strategy, and when we bring the LVMH brand to a hotel, we cover not just the design of the hotel, but its operation, with all the service that that requires, without having to do the investment, except in La Samaritaine, , thanks to the work of Mr. de Beauvoir achieved to produce one of the finest hotels in Paris along the Seine River, but saved a building that is quite historic, and we don't actually invest in the freehold. We provide the concept and the overall management.</p>
          <p>So that's the diversification that's just starting. It's something of a start-up. We already have a Cheval Blanc Hotel in a French resort that's doing well. And on the basis of that concept we'll seek to expand it. But it's not a diversification that figures will disrupt the operating balance of LVMH before a few years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, ladies and gentlemen, if there are no further questions, thank you and of course, we're available, Mr. Guiony is, after and over refreshments, to answer any more detailed questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>