<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1405184" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-07-26</date>
    <companies>
      <company>846</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Finance">Jean-Jacques Guiony</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Christopher Hollis</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Telsey Advisory Group">David Wu</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="HSBC Securities (France) SA">Antoine Belge</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Thomas V. Chauvet</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Cr&#xE9;dit Agricole Cheuvreux SA">Pierre Lamelin</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Mizuho International">Michael Ridley</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Prime Brokerage)">Warwick R. Okines</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane Ltd.">Edouard Crowley</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Raymond James Euro Equities SAS">Marc Willaume</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Royal Bank of Scotland Plc (Broker)">John W. Guy</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Kepler Capital Markets SA">Catherine Rolland</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Orange Capital">Krim Delko</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the LVMH 2011 Half Year Results Conference Call. I'll now hand over to Mr. Jean-Jacques Guiony. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, good afternoon and welcome to this conference call. I'm Jean-Jacques Guiony. I'm the CFO of the LVMH Group.</p>
          <p>Before I begin, I must remind you that certain information to be discussed on today's call is forward-looking and is subject to important risks and uncertainties that could cause results to differ materially. For these I refer you to the Safe Harbor statement included in our press release.</p>
          <p>Let's now move to today's topic, first half figures. I shall cover the first part with most significant figures and Chris Hollis, Group's Head of Investors Relations, will cover the main developments of our different business group. After this both Chris and I will be available for your questions. The press release is available on our website, lvmh.com, as well as the slide for today's presentation and the interim financial report.</p>
          <p>So let's start with slide two, and I shall start with the revenues for the first half of the year. As you may see we had a fairly strong semester with all our businesses growing double digit in organic terms. Having in mind that revenue grew organically 14% in the first half of 2010, we can be extremely satisfied. You will certainly note that published growth was lower than organic growth due to the slight negative impact of minus 1.4% stemming from currencies and the disposal of La Brosse et Dupont and Montaudon in the course of 2010.</p>
          <p>Chris will comment main business groups in more details, but main comments are as follows. First, Wine &amp; Spirits had a strong semester with 13% organic growth. <mark type="ph" /> Final (01:47) demand remains strong in most of our geographies, and we enjoyed a 10% rise in volume over the semester. Fashion &amp; Leather is up 14% in organic terms with the very strong double-digit performance of Louis Vuitton despite a very challenging comparison base, and we had a fantastic performance from the other brands with both retail and wholesale operations being on a fast track. Perfumes &amp; Cosmetics is up 11% in organic terms and 10% in euro if we exclude the impact of La Brosse et Dupont consolidation. A strong semester with growth in excess of main markets and market share gains.</p>
          <p>Watches &amp; Jewelry had an outstanding first half with plus 27% in organic terms, showing the return to a more favorable demand pattern. Selective Distribution is also showing a very good performance with plus 18% organic. Both travel and retail, travel, retail and Sephora have shown a very solid growth rate with a very strong positive impact from like-to-like, but also from store openings.</p>
          <p>Let's now move to slide three, where you can see comparison between the first and the second quarter in terms of organic growth. As you may see all groups of business are showing equal or superior growth in the second quarter. Only Wine &amp; Spirit is down as anticipated as the 17% organic growth from Q1 was hardly sustainable over the course of the year. You will note the particulars from figures from Selective Distribution and Wine &amp; Spirits in Q2 and the very solid 16% in Fashion &amp; Leather, which comes on top of a nearly 20% rise in Q2 of 2010.</p>
          <p>Let's now move to slide four, which shows the geographic breakdown of revenues. Europe and Asia including Japan account for roughly one third each, while the U.S. is one quarter. Emerging markets taken together account for roughly 36% of the group's total revenues.</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide five, where you may see the evolution of sales in our main geographies, no major change between the first and the second quarter in most of our geographies, except in Japan, due to the catastrophic events of March. As far as Japan is concerned, revenue change in yen in Q2 was minus 3%, which compares to the minus 9% of Q1. The <mark type="indiscernible" /> (04:01) was up 2%, showing the anticipated return to more normal business conditions.</p>
          <p>Let's now move to the next slide, where you may see our simplified profit and loss account for the period. The main comments are the following. I think we already discussed revenues so no need to come back on that. Gross margin is markedly higher, representing 66.5% of revenues compared to 64.9% in the same period of last year.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses are growing less than the gross margin, with plus 14% for commercial charges and plus 11% for admin charges. Within commercial charges, advertising and promotion is growing 22% on the constant currency basis. Current operating profit is up 22%, with operating margin reaching 21.6%, its highest level for the first half of the year.</p>
          <p>Other operating income and charges are negative by $46 million, reflecting mostly amortization and depreciation of intangibles. I shall discuss financial charges in a separate slide in a minute. And the Group's tax rate is currently 30%, slightly up from last year. Other results, the Group's share in the net profit is up 25% at &#x20AC;1.3 billion.</p>
          <p>Let's now go in some details on the current operating income, which is broken down by business group on slide seven. First of all, Wines &amp; Spirits has a very strong first half, with plus 27% in operating profit, while sales in euros were up 10%. Wines &amp; Spirits enjoyed a strong improvement in operating margin of about 400 basis points, which should nevertheless not be extrapolated to the rest of the year as a significant portion of it comes from the currency impact.</p>
          <p>Fashion &amp; Leather did also extremely well, with a 17% rise in its current operating profit, which compares to plus 13% in sales and shows further improvement in operating margins.</p>
          <p>Perfumes &amp; Cosmetics shows a flat current operating profit. The comparison made in 2010 first half was particularly difficult, as the business benefited last year from a strong rebound in sales, which occurred before the necessary reinvestments in advertising and promotion. Operating margin reached its highest level with 13% in H1 2010, a level that was difficult to match in a more normal business pattern.</p>
          <p>Watches &amp; Jewelry had a very good semester with a rise of 73% in its current operating profit and a 380 basis point improvement in operating margins. This comes obviously from higher sales and a strong operating leverage, but we were able to increase marketing spend by about 34% to preserve the long-term growth potential of our brands.</p>
          <p>Finally, very strong progress as well in the Selective Distribution group of businesses, with an advance of 63% compared to last year. Most travel retail companies <mark type="indiscernible" /> (07:01) had a very strong first half and overall operating margins improved by about 280 basis points.</p>
          <p>Finally, let me address the current impact on current operating profit on slide eight. As you may see on the slide, we have a slightly negative currency impact of $20 million. We started the year with a positive currency impact, which shrank and reversed as the dollar softened and went away from last year's level. Despite the solid hedging portfolio, the currency impact will be significantly negative for the rest of the year if currencies stay where they are today.</p>
          <p>Let's now turn to slide nine and the analysis of net financial charge. Two important points in my view: the cost of debt was flat in the first half with two antagonistic trends, one being the drop in the net interest rates which benefited about half of the debt; the other being the higher average debt in the semester that I shall show you in a minute. The cost of hedging was much lower than last year, as you know, this cost is by and large unpredictable and the drop may not be extrapolated for the rest of the year. Finally, income on the financial investment portfolio was higher than last year mostly due to dividend income from MS and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (08:15).</p>
          <p>Moving on to slide 10, where you may see the balance sheet structure. The structure of the balance sheet did not evolve much in the course of the semester, yet we registered important changes in absolute figures with the equity increase to finance part of the Bulgari transaction for about &#x20AC;2 billion and the first integration of Bulgari's balance sheets. Only Bulgari's balance sheet is consolidated on a line-by-line basis in H1, as the date of change of control is June the 30th. We shall fully consolidate Bulgari P&amp;L in H2 and we'll allocate the acquisition goodwill to its various components in the course of the semester.</p>
          <p>Turning to slide 11, a few words on the cash flow statements. First, cash from operations is up &#x20AC;514 million, more in line with current operating profit. Yet the tax side was quite penalizing as the installment payments timing was not as favorable as in 2010. We therefore suffered a &#x20AC;400 million swing in the cash tax charge over the first half. Obviously, this will not be the case in the second half.</p>
          <p>Working capital requirements were also about &#x20AC;500 million unfavorable to last year. This is not particularly surprising as the rebound in the level of activity sooner or later sets to deriving higher inventories and higher receivables. While do we expect to continue to grow inventories and residuals in the second half, we think the impact should be weighted significant.</p>
          <p>Finally, capital expenditures are significantly up with an additional &#x20AC;175 million for the semester. Overall, cash from operations is about &#x20AC;560 million for the first half of 2011.</p>
          <p>I will finish this first part of the presentation with a comment on the Group's net debt, which you can see on slide 12. The Group's net debt reached &#x20AC;4 billion at the end of the first semester, about &#x20AC;1.4 billion higher than at the end of last year. This increase is mainly due to the payment of dividend to our shareholders and minority equity partners and to the financial investment, chiefly the purchase of Bulgari shares ahead of the contribution of family shares for about &#x20AC;700 million.</p>
          <p>The Group's net debt at the 30th of June 2011 represented about 19% of total shareholders' equity. This ratio will obviously evolve in the rest of the year as the cash-out of about &#x20AC;1.45 billion on the remainder of the Bulgari share will take place in the second half.</p>
          <p>I will now turn to Chris, who is going to review the main developments within our various business groups.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jean-Jacques. I'll review each of the businesses briefly starting with the Wines &amp; Spirits, which starts on slide 14. Further to what Jean-Jacques had mentioned, the Wines &amp; Spirits group had a particularly strong first half with published revenue up 10% at &#x20AC;1.4 billion. After a negative 1% structural impact and a negative 2% currency impact, organic revenue grows 13%.</p>
          <p>Looking at the different categories, Champagne &amp; Wines organic revenue growth for the period was 13% after taking into account a two-point impact from last year's disposal of the Montaudon champagne brand and a slightly negative currency impact. Cognac &amp; Spirits organic revenue growth for the half was 12% after a negative 3% currency impact. Profit from recurring operations were up an impressive 27%. That's up 33% in Champagne &amp; Wine and up 23% in Cognac &amp; Spirits. While this is an impressive four-point margin improvement as Jean-Jacques already mentioned, a significant portion of this improvement comes from the currency impact.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the highlights on slide 16, revenue was particularly strong in Asia, up 28% on a local currency basis, demonstrating the ongoing development of that market. But in all markets, we saw a continued recovery in consumer demand in the first half and were able to achieve price increases in all our key regions, supported by increased marketing while also achieving volume growth.</p>
          <p>Within Champagne &amp; Wines, champagne volumes were up 10% on a comparable basis, that is excluding the Montaudon impact, with particularly good performances from our Prestige vintages. Following unsustainable high volume growth in the third quarter, we are seeing volume growth return to more sustainable levels in the second quarter. The consumer demand is clearly still robust and we're closely monitoring inventory levels. I should recall that the first two quarters are relatively slow for champagne and the bulk of champagne sales took place in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>The sparkling wines and <mark type="ph" /> distinctive (13:26) wines continued their rapid growth, and we announced a joint venture agreement at Ningxia situated in Northwest China to develop premium quality vineyards with a state-run agricultural company there.</p>
          <p>Cognac volumes increased 8%, driven by continued demand for higher end cognac &#x2013; that's VSOP, XO and above &#x2013; as the ongoing momentum in our Asian markets continued. Once again, the inventory levels are being monitored especially in the U.S. Finally, our other spirits have well received product, notably at <mark type="indiscernible" /> (14:00) and Belvedere, supported by innovative marketing campaigns.</p>
          <p>As we look to the remainder of the year <mark type="ph" /> and 2017 (14:09) we'll continue to focus on growing volumes in a controlled way. In Champagne &amp; Cognac, we have high quality products, which have a limited production capacity especially for the older and more prestigious ranges. As a result, we must ensure that growth today does not impinge on the results needed for tomorrow. Within this context, we aim to keep pace with expected increases in demand in key countries including the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>We need to focus on ensuring that we have access to the grapes and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (14:41) supplies that will be necessary to meet future demand. Simply, we will concentrate on further optimizing our product mix and ensuring we have a firm pricing policy. We will also continue to build our Wines &amp; Spirits business by creating innovative new products in response to new customer trends and preferences. Moet's Ice Imperial Champagne conceived to be served over ice or Hennessy's <mark type="indiscernible" /> (15:10), marketed exclusively through digital channels, are examples of these.</p>
          <p>Of course, we will continue to support the future growth by investing significantly in communications, including new advertising and marketing campaigns. Finally, we will strengthen our sales force, particularly in Asia, in China, Southeast Asia, and Vietnam.</p>
          <p>Turning now to the Fashion &amp; Leather Goods, slide 18, published revenue increased 13% compared to the same period last year to reach nearly &#x20AC;4 billion. A negative currency impact of 1% meant that organic revenue grew 14%. Profits from recurring operations were up 17% to &#x20AC;1.38 billion. These results too come on top of significant growth in the first half of 2010, demonstrating the enduring appeal of our brands and our continued ability to define luxury for prestige consumers throughout the world that reflect the creativity and craftsmanship of the artisans in our workshops who are the backbone of our continued success.</p>
          <p>Slide 19 demonstrates each of the regions that delivered notable growth with revenues in local currencies mostly U.S. and Asia up in excess of 20% and Europe increasing 12%. Performance was led by the exceptional momentum of Louis Vuitton, which once again delivered double-digit organic revenue growth during the first half. Progress was made across all these product categories, with particularly outstanding performance from soft leather goods including our Imprints Collection, which we launched in 2010 and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (16:51).</p>
          <p>Vuitton opened new workshops in the first half of 2011, notably in Marseilles in France to keep pace with the continued success of this iconic brand. And this performance is benefiting from two new leather goods lines and the development of custom-made offerings <mark type="indiscernible" /> (17:10) management future concept, while Donna Karan's new Casual Luxe line is meeting with great success. The other brands posted improved results both at retail and wholesale level. We're especially pleased with the progress of C&#xE9;line under its new artistic director, Phoebe Philo, and the accelerating revenue growth we are seeing in that brand.</p>
          <p>Slide 20. During the balance of the year Louis Vuitton will continue to focus on innovation across all its product categories supported by creative campaigns. And as you all have seen our journey with photographs in Cambodia was a subject of our current Core Values communications campaign. In China, Louis Vuitton Voyages exhibition at Beijing's National Museum of China celebrates our 20th year in that country. We'll also be inaugurating new Maisons, notably in Milan and Singapore, creating a new prestige jewelry workshop at <mark type="ph" /> Platte Fondonnes (18:09) in Paris with its own dedicated Louis Vuitton jewelry store at the same location.</p>
          <p>Last month, we acquired La Fabrique du Temps, the high-end watchmaking workshop in Geneva famous for its <mark type="indiscernible" /> (18:24). This company has been a longtime partner of LVMH and its uncompromising standards of quality and innovation are very much in keeping with our own. This acquisition underscores Louis Vuitton's strategy of always choosing the best cores of expertise to manufacture its product.</p>
          <p>Our plans for the second half include developing new products for Fendi and continuing the selective expansion of its distribution network. We will also continue to build on the creative momentum, which has been evident this year at our C&#xE9;line, Pucci, Givenchy and LBD brands.</p>
          <p>Turning now to Perfumes &amp; Cosmetics on slide 21, in a highly competitive market, revenue at LVMH's Perfumes &amp; Cosmetics rose 5% to more than &#x20AC;1.5 billion after a negative 5% structural impact relating to the disposal of La Brosse et Dupont last year and a negative 1% currency impact. Organic revenue grew by 11%. Profits were stable at &#x20AC;181 million. The first half of last year was particularly strong with a rebound in revenue and a relatively low level of marketing expenses in the aftermath of the economic crisis, so the 12% profit margin achieved this half year is a great performance.</p>
          <p>On slide 22, revenue on a local currency basis increased 21% in the U.S., 8% in Europe excluding LBD and 19% in Asia. We saw strong momentum in Parfums Christian Dior's iconic perfumes, J'adore with Charlize Theron continuing to be the face of that brand, and Miss Dior, which was successfully re-launched with Natalie Portman as the new embodiment of that fragrance. We also saw rapid growth in Dior Addict lipstick and the Capture skin care.</p>
          <p>Guerlain's launch of Shalimar Initial was extremely successful, as was the excitement generated by the new pop-up store in Paris with its contemporary look of full face to the future design of La Maison Guerlain on the Champs-Elysees in Paris.</p>
          <p>Givenchy benefited from the good contribution of Play perfume. Benefit expanded its reach with the opening of an e-commerce website in China. Make Up For Ever continued to demonstrate its ability to be at the forefront of innovation with the development with its HD Haute D&#xE9;finition and Aqua lines.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead in Perfumes &amp; Cosmetics, slide 23, we'll continue to focus in the second half of the year on winning incremental market share with sustained innovation and advertising and marketing programs that engage the prestige consumer. We'll further strengthen the brand image Parfums Christian Dior by leveraging the relationship with <mark type="indiscernible" /> (21:16). We will be extending the launch of Hypnotic Poison with Melanie Laurent, the French actress, filmmaker and singer becoming its new muse. We will continue to strengthen visibility at points of sale in order to better express the brand values.</p>
          <p>We're focusing on launching profitable product extensions of the other brands. Among these we'll continue to develop the Orchid&#xE9;e Imp&#xE9;riale skincare line at Guerlain and introduce new women's fragrances at Givenchy, Soin Noir, and Kenzo, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (21:50). In addition, we plan to open Benefit's first store in New York and a new store in Milan for Acqua di Parma.</p>
          <p>Now moving on to Watches &amp; Jewelry, on slide 24, even in this generally outstanding first half performance for the group, Watches &amp; Jewelry was an exceptional performer, achieving revenues of &#x20AC;576 million, up 30% compared to last year's six-month period. After 3% positive currency impact principally from the Swiss franc, organic revenue growth was 27%. Profits from recurring operations was up a full 73%, increasing the margin by 380 basis points. And as Jean-Jacques mentioned the impact of the operating leverage from higher sales enabled an increase in A&amp;P to support the long-term growth potential of our watch and jewelry brands.</p>
          <p>Revenue growth again by region and local currencies, on slide 25, was once again led by Asia at 52%, with U.S. up 28%, Europe up 29%, and even Japan despite the catastrophe was up 8%. Growth resulted from a combination of continued strong demand both in our stores and in our multi-brand retailers as well as market share gains. This led to a solid improvement in the business group's current operating margin to 15%.</p>
          <p>The Baselworld Fair gave us the ability to demonstrate and promote to global retailers in the marketplace our exceptional innovation and craftsmanship, such as TAG's first automatic chronograph watch that's capable of measuring thousandths of a second. Our jewelry brands performed extremely well, led particularly by sales growth in their own stores.</p>
          <p>The first half was marked by a strategic alliance with the Bulgari family under which we transferred the majority stakes to LVMH. After receiving authorization from the relevant competitional authorities the LVMH Board of Directors approved the transfer on June the 30th, and this increases the stake held by LVMH in Bulgari to 76.1% prior to the public tender offer, which is to be launched soon. We're excited about this alliance and look forward to welcoming Bulgari into our family of luxury brands.</p>
          <p>Our focus for the remainder of the year, slide 26, will be on achieving continued market share gains in a market which is self-growing. One in the first half will be the successful integration of Bulgari into the LVMH family. This will double the size of this business and will be done while remaining true to the identity of the brand. We'll also continue to focus on the prestige positioning of our brands through continued innovation and targeted communication. Examples of this are Hublot's new Unico movement and TAG's re-launch of its iconic link collection. Further investments will be made to accelerate the development of our watchmaking capabilities given the prospect of production constraints. And finally, we'll be selectively expanding our network in high potential countries.</p>
          <p>Selective retailing on slide 27 continued to grow its revenues through ongoing innovation and a focus on providing customers with an exciting and unique experience. Revenue rose to &#x20AC;2.8 billion, up 17% compared to last year's half year. There was a positive 2% structural impact from the acquisition of Sack's in Brazil last year and the full integration of Ile de Beaut&#xE9; from June the 1st of this year. This was offset by a negative 3% currency impact, which resulted in an organic revenue growth of 18%. Profit from recurring operations was up 63%. Both travel retail and Sephora contributed to these strong performances.</p>
          <p>Slide 28 demonstrates revenue growth of double digits in all principal regions in local currencies with a 32% increase in Asia, 19% increase in the U.S. and a 13% increase in Europe. DFS benefited from sustained growth of its customer base in Asia, as demonstrated by its excellent performance in Hong Kong, Macao and Singapore, where recent investments are bearing fruit. The business also saw good momentum in North America, in particular at airports.</p>
          <p>Sephora exhibited market share gains in all regions and accelerated its growth in China and the Middle East. It is also off to an excellent start in Malaysia with the opening of two new stores in this new territory for this retail brand. Sephora continues to focus on expansion of its network and to refresh the client experience with store renovations as well as innovative new activities and initiatives, such as the opening of its nail studios in selected stores. Through Sephora LVMH has also increased its stake from 45% to 65% in Ile de Beaut&#xE9;, a key retailer in Russia's beauty products market.</p>
          <p>Finally, slide 29. DFS's focus for the reminder of the year will be to reinforce its upscale positioning strategy both in stores and in products, to expand its reach to a more diversified clientele, to continue its renovation programs in Singapore and Hawaii and to make targeted new investments in high-potential destinations.</p>
          <p>Sephora will pursue market share growth and selectively expand its store network while remaining at the forefront of innovation in the beauty field. An important area of focus will be the further development of its store network and product offerings for the Chinese market. Sephora also plans to open its very first store in Mexico and is expanding its presence in the fast-growing Brazilian market by its controlling stake in Sack's. Finally, it will continue to reinforce its innovation in the offer and services it provides its clients, such as the nail bars or the makeup store.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll now turn the call back over to Jean-Jacques for a brief wrap-up before we take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chris. So I would like to conclude this brief overview of the activity with a few comments on H1 performance highlighting the most significant points. First and foremost, I would like to point out that all our businesses grew double digits in the semester, really showing the strength of our businesses and of our brands. Likewise, all our geographies are showing high single- or double-digit growth rates. Even Japan despite a terrible disaster in March is rapidly returning to normal and posted positive growth in revenues in June. Certainly our businesses despite strong marketing and selling investments were able to contain operating costs to grow within sales and gross margin growth, enabling a strong rise in operating margin. And finally, despite significant investment our balance sheet remains very strong.</p>
          <p>So all in all a very strong performance of the LVMH Group in the first half of the year. What about the rest of the year? Always difficult to make forecast and you know how much we like it, but I shall give you some points which we view as relevant.</p>
          <p>First of all, on a positive note our main markets are well oriented and we see no evidence of a slowdown within Asia or in the U.S. The European markets have proven so far this year to be softer, but we expect both domestic consumption and <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:32) flows to hold that. Secondly, currencies are as uncertain as ever actually, and like many periods in the past, the question is not simply when the dollar will deteriorate. We currently see both the dollar and the euro as notably weak for very different reasons I will not elaborate on. The outcome could be one way or the other. This requires a lot of care, particularly through the pricing and hedging policy of the group.</p>
          <p>Certainly, and finally, we are as convinced as ever that the best way to create value is to invest behind our brands, and we shall carry on doing so in a thoughtful and disciplined way. That is basically all we wanted to say, and we shall now open the Q&amp;A session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We have the first question from Mr. David Wu from Telsey Advisory Group. Sir, please go ahead. Mr. David Wu, you have the floor. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, congratulations on an excellent first half. First question is can you first talk about what you're seeing in terms of cost pressures, whether we could expect another round of selective price increases in the back half? And then just secondly in terms of capacity constraints, just wanted to get an update on whether the new plan in France for Louis Vuitton is progressing as planned and if you're looking to open up any additional production facilities in the back half. And just lastly in terms of the operating margin performance for Perfumes &amp; Cosmetics, I just wanted to get confirmation that the decline really was due to higher ad spending. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. On the cost pressure, which is basically price increase, if I understand correctly, your question. Obviously we will look at what we can do on the markets. It's not absolutely obvious we have passed on a few price increases in the Fashion &amp; Leather brands, in Perfumes &amp; Cosmetics and mostly in Wine &amp; Spirits, unlike preceding years. So we have done a lot already this year and we are reviewing our options for the rest of the year. As always, I mean I never answer very precisely this question as it is part of confidential commercial information that I cannot and will not elaborate on. But we definitely as always think about it.</p>
          <p>Secondly, on capacity constraints, we opened a few <mark type="indiscernible" /> (32:07) in the first half of this year. Obviously, the <mark type="indiscernible" /> (32:13) are coming in full force progressively. So we already had some positive impact from it in the first half of the year, but a significant amount of the production capabilities will also be available, a significant increase in production capabilities will be available in the second half of the year. So this should enable us to significantly rise our availability of product, and we don't expect to be faced in the second half of the year with the same product shortage and capacity constraints as we had in the second half of the year in 2010.</p>
          <p>Finally, operating margins in Perfumes &amp; Cosmetics, the answer is yes to your question. It's mostly the rise in advertising and promotion that explains the slight drop in operating margin. But this rise should be put in perspective with the fact that last year as explained, the advertising and promotion expenses were sort of lagging behind the sales rise that we enjoyed in the first part of the year. So we had this sort of exceptional situation where we enjoyed the rising sales. At the time, we had not yet reinvested into advertising and promotion. So that's a comparison basis with such a very favorable period that really causes the margins to slightly drop in the first half of this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Antoine Belge from HSBC. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good evening. Antoine Belge at HSBC. I had three questions. First of all, can you perhaps comment on the performance of Louis Vuitton versus other brands and can you tell us if Louis Vuitton did better than the average of the division? Given the information you had given previously regarding pricing, is it fair to say that out of the 14% growth in &#x2013; organic growth in the first half, that there was a price effect of around 10%, that the volume growth was rather limited?</p>
          <p>The second question is more on Cognac. I think &#x2013; so you said volume up 8% in H1. I think you gave a 16% increase in Q1 that would indicate no volume growth in Q2. Also, I noted that there was a relatively limited increase in the U.S. Is it related to a policy of trying to de-emphasize your exposure to <mark type="ph" /> DFS (34:52) in the U.S.? And finally in terms of margin, I think you had really an impressive development in the Selective Retailing. Could you maybe comment a bit more into DFS versus the Sephora and also Sephora in the different regions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Well, LV versus other brands, I will not answer <mark type="ph" /> in a way that is close (35:23), but I will not tell you in which way it goes. The price effect that you &#x2013; your assumption is 10%; you're far from it. I mean price impact particularly at Vuitton where we measure it very precisely is much, much lower than that. We had a price impact in main geographies progressively in the course of the semester, but overall I mean the price impact is probably as low as half of the figures. So you're pretty far away and the rest is volume and mix impact.</p>
          <p>Cognac, your assumption for volume is accurate; our Cognac volumes in Q2 were more or less flat. Actually they were significantly up in China, something like 20%, 22% if I'm not mistaken, but they were fairly sharply down in the U.S. in order to avoid the stocking factor that we started to see in the first quarter of this year ahead of the price increase. I mean it's always the same game. We have discussed that many times together. When ahead of a price increase, there is an inventory buildup within distributors and despite depletions were fairly stable throughout the semester we had to reduce our C&#xE9;line in order to avoid a buildup in inventory. So we are ending the semester in the U.S. with a very good level of inventory in the U.S. and elsewhere actually. And we shouldn't have any impairment on our ability to grow sales in the rest of the year due to the inventory situation.</p>
          <p>Final question, on selective retailing and the margins. As you noticed we have an increase of about a little bit less than 300 basis points in margins at Selective Retailing. Both Sephora and DFS are contributing to this figure more or less in the same way. So margins were pretty low last year in Q1 at both Sephora and DFS, but they have recovered markedly in the first half of this year and they both contribute to this performance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just maybe a follow-up, in terms of Sephora, is it broad-based between Europe, the U.S. and emerging markets or is there a particular region which saw a dramatic rebound or expansion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's really broad-based. U.S. and Europe are more or less on the same bar. Obviously we have a larger increase in margins in emerging markets due to the fact that they are starting from a lower point but nevertheless it's really broad-based.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Thomas Chauvet from Citigroup. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Jean-Jacques, Chris. Two questions from me, three actually, the first one on Louis Vuitton. Could you elaborate on your retail strategy and the major change you've done over the last six to nine months? I'm thinking notably about some of the U.S. stores, if you closed or relocated some of the stores. Are you happy about your European retail network now in terms of embellishing the quality of the network? And can you talk a bit about the big Maison that you're planning to open over the next couple of years? So more qualitative comments on the retail network. We could have also the number of stores at the end of June.</p>
          <p>My second question, on China and the potential reduction in luxury import duties, I'd be happy to know what you're hearing from your partners in China and your relationships with the authorities. And what would be your pricing strategy if luxury duties were reduced? Could we anticipate that you would pass that on to the consumer? Maybe that's a na&#xEF;ve assumption. I don't know.</p>
          <p>And finally, with regards to the investment in MS, could you please indicate whether you own any instrument that could give access to MS shares or whether you've bought more shares in the market since in the first half of the year? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, Thomas. On the LV retail strategies, you mentioned embellishing the network, are we pleased with the network from a qualitative viewpoint. I think it's a sort of endless process. I mean we intend to invest in our main asset, which is Vuitton's network, all the time. It's really an ongoing process to invest and to embellish all the stores one by one and to have Maison where we think it make sense for a larger store with more categories of products where we think it makes sense.</p>
          <p>So it's really a never-ending process. As far as the U.S. is concerned, you pointed out the fact that it's probably one of the network where we have quite a lot to do. The average size of stores in the U.S. is smaller than elsewhere. We are working on that. We have closed some stores, opening some new ones. There will be more to be closed; there will be more to be opened. It's a significant reshuffle of the network that we are on the way of doing. It's going to take some time, and it's really as I said an ongoing strategy to invest full-time in our main assets, which is the retail network.</p>
          <p>On China, it's a very difficult question and things are particularly, how can I say, foggy about the perspective of a decrease in import duties. So given the sensitivity of the topic, I can hardly make any meaningful comment on this, and to be frank, the pricing strategy following a potential decrease in import duties remains to be discussed within the group. I mean we'll see first whether this happens or not and then we'll decide what to do.</p>
          <p>On MS, two questions on other instruments, no, we have only 200,000 equity swaps remaining of last year's transactions, which is still in force, and that was well described in our annual report, so this equity swap is still there and has not changed. And in terms of holding, in the course of the semester, we increased our shareholding in MS from 20.2% to 21.4%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jean-Jacques.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Pierre Lamelin. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good evening, Jean-Jacques and Chris. Three questions if I may. Firstly, what was the performance of Fashion &amp; Leather in Japan over the first half? Secondly, we've discussed China; can you share with us the organic growth rate over the first half of Q2 this year? And finally, you mentioned in Wine &amp; Spirits, the FOREX boost on H1 operating profit. Maybe you can quantify the impact. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Fashion &amp; Leather in Japan for the first half is down mid-single-digit, was slight double-digit in Q1 and minus 1% or 2% in Q2. So big difference between the two. And as I mentioned for Vuitton, but it's true for the entire Fashion &amp; Leather division, the month of June was positive. So we really saw two or three months being deeply affected by the disaster and things coming back to normal thereafter.</p>
          <p>China, the gross in Q2, if I'm not mistaken, was 32%, in yuan terms, which compares to 30% in the first quarter of the year. So a slight increase in the growth, which we see in most in most businesses, but basically the same market conditions as we had in Q1. And as far as Wines &amp; Spirits is concerned, out of the 400 basis points margin growth a little bit more than 100 basis points is attributable to a fairly complex currency impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Michael Ridley from Mizuho. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon, gentlemen. It's Michael Ridley from Mizuho International. Just had one or two questions on your Bulgari acquisition. Obviously there's a share swap element, but it's only had a &#x20AC;2.4 billion cash-out for Bulgari. I wanted to ask if that figure of &#x20AC;2.4 billion includes buying back the Bulgari convertible bond or not. What is the cost of buying back that bond? And post that bond what debt is there at Bulgari when you consolidate it onto a balance sheet? And then as a final question on that I'm a little bit confused about what has gone in the first half and what is still to come in the second half in terms of the full acquisition. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. No surprised you're confused; it's pretty complex and accounting is not helping much I must admit. As far as Bulgari is concerned let's break down the acquisition price in its various components, starting with the share component, which is roughly speaking &#x20AC;2 billion, &#x20AC;2.20 billion, something like that. Then you have about &#x20AC;700 million that were shares that we bought after the announcement of the transaction on March 5th, 2011 and before the contribution of the shares by the family group to LVMH on the 30th of June. So what remains to be paid and you have the details in the financial documents, but what remains to be paid is &#x20AC;1.45 billion in cash.</p>
          <p>So that totals roughly &#x20AC;4.2 billion, which is the amount that we announced at the very beginning of this transaction. This includes as cash the impact of the convertibles. We make the assumption, which in my view is correct that all convertibles will be converted into shares and will come to the tender offer that we are likely to launch at the end of August, late August and that should close in late September.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Warwick Okines from Deutsche Bank. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good evening. It's Warwick Okines from Deutsche Bank. Could you please give the LV store numbers at the end of the first half? I think I missed those. And also the gross increase and the net increase over the period. And then secondly, could you just confirm that there were no price rises that went on in Q2? Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>LV store numbers, no, you didn't miss it, because we didn't mention it. It's 458 at the end of the first semester. Gross increase &#x2013; I think it's &#x2013; I think the net is flat and gross it's maybe &#x2013; I think it's plus 5, minus 5, something like that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And price increases in Q2?</p>
          <p>&lt;&lt;A &#x2013; [05Y8BN-E]Jean-Jacques Guiony &#x2013; Head-Finance&gt;: Price increase, they were mostly price increase of 2% to 3% in the euro zone. That's about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Edouard Crowley from Exane BNP Paribas. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, Chris and Jean-Jacques. Two questions. The first one is relating to your recent acquisition of La Fabrique du Temps for Louis Vuitton. Could you just come back a bit on what are the kind of key competencies that you will be acquiring in terms of watchmaking knowhow under the kind of basically mix and initiatives you plan to undertake to basically ramp up your high end of selling at the Louis Vuitton website? And secondly a quick question on India, where a few weeks or months ago we hear that capital could be looking to <mark type="indiscernible" /> (48:11). Is there any development there marginally? What are your views in terms of starting for the Indian market? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. With Vuitton we are getting into some level of details as the purchase price of this acquisition is way less than &#x20AC;10 million, so we are getting into a high level of details. I mean the objective for Vuitton is to be able to master the main production techniques surrounding the manufacturing of watches including movements and including complications. I mean the public Vuitton is very well known for its complications and the ability to really bring value to watches and it's exactly what Vuitton is looking for.</p>
          <p>As far as India is concerned, it's a tricky question. I will not comment on capital investment there; it's a separate entity in which we own a very small percentage. In terms of retail development in India, things are not particularly easy. The market is changing but slowly. There are a few shopping malls in which we can open stores, but we have to be careful to make sure that the promises that we have in terms of overall spendings, basically what the landlords are telling us about what they intend to do with their shopping malls end up being exactly what they have said at the beginning. So we tend to have a fairly cautious attitude when it comes to committing ourselves to new retail developments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Marc Willaume from Raymond James. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think now it's good evening. My first question will be on Sephora. Could you give us the like-for-like sales growth both in U.S. and Europe? Then on the overall A&amp;P, which increased by nearly 100 basis points in H1, could we expect the same kind of increase in the full year basis? And then last one regarding Louis Vuitton. I think at the early stage of this year, taking into account the new production plant ramping up, you were expecting an increase overall further increasing capacity, which can bring 10% growth in volume. Are you still forecasting some kind of volume increase on a full year basis? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. The like-for-like is 12% in the U.S. and 8% in Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's for H1?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's for H1. I don't know if that's for &#x2013; I'm sorry, H1, yes. You're absolutely right. A&amp;P in the second half, always difficult to say, but I think the reason why the growth is what it is is that the comparison base in H1 last year was reasonably low. I mean we had the sort of lagging effects of the crisis and we were not yet in reinvesting mode in A&amp;P in the first half or at least at the beginning of the first half. It didn't happen obviously in the second half so the comparison base in H2 2010 will be very different from H1, and I don't expect a similar rise in advertising and promotion in the second half.</p>
          <p>As far as the volumes, production volumes are concerned, we still expect a significant increase in our production on average 2011 compared to 2010, which should enable us to meet growing demand and also replenish inventories, which is as you know one of our objectives in this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A fourth question just if I may regarding the other activities and I'd say losses and elimination, which reached &#x20AC;124 million. Can you give us some color on those?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The main reason for this increase is that as you know I mean the profit was very solid for the month. For the semester we had the opportunity to take some provisions that had been spread out over the full year, and we took them entirely in the first part of the year. That explains the bulk of the rise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. John Guy from RBS. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, Jean-Jacques and Chris. Just a few questions please. With regards to the recent investments you've made in watches, I mean obviously this is a relatively small size, the acquisition with Fabrique du Temps, but obviously you took on Bulgari as well. I'm just curious to know whether or not you're going to need to make further investments on the manufacturing side given what looks like a sort of steady progression from <mark type="indiscernible" /> (53:22) and Swatch reducing the amount that they'll have to effectively supply going forward. That's my first question. Second question is with regards to the costs on a square meter basis of operating in China versus Europe for Louis Vuitton. I'm wondering if you might be able to share anything there. And the third question is around any planned price rises you have for Cognac in the second half the year, especially within XO and VSOP. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks, John. Watches, well, the answer is obviously yes. I mean, we intend to carry on developing our manufacturing capabilities in movements. You know the various developments we've been on with Unico, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (54:08) and with the 1887 TAG Heuer. We intend to increase the capabilities to produce these movements within these two important brands in the future and reduce our dependency to the outside world.</p>
          <p>So we are investing seriously. We didn't start yesterday; this investment phase started in 2006 basically. So our production capabilities are on the way up. Obviously, the prices, the recession was not good news for these investments as the recession was particularly hardly felt in Switzerland, but now things are back to normal and we are resuming our investment there. So we are pretty optimistic that within a couple of years we should have reduced our dependency to the outside world in a great way.</p>
          <p>The cost of square meter, China versus Europe for Vuitton, I mean it's hard to elaborate, but I would say that when it comes to selling expenses, we don't necessarily view a big difference in percentage of sales in between the euro zone and China. Obviously we have some differences in terms of the cost of employees and the cost of the depreciation costs &#x2013; sorry. But cost of premises tend to be on the way up and the sales entity is not necessarily the same in China as in Europe; it's normally a bit lower. So all in all I mean it doesn't make a hell of a difference, although in absolute terms on the square meter basis expenses in China are obviously somewhat lower.</p>
          <p>And price rise in Cognac for the second half of the year, let's hope we can do it, but I'm not sure. I mean it's a difficult decision. As you know in Wines &amp; Spirits the bulk of price rises are being implemented in the first quarter, not even in the first half, in the first quarter of the year, for obvious reasons linked with the year-end season, which is so important in this business. So given the strength in the demand, particularly as you mentioned in VSOP in Asia, we might look at it, but no decision has been taken yet on this, so I really cannot answer on this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much, Jean-Jacques. Can I just follow up with just one fairly quick one on how you feel with regards to stock levels? I know you talked about coming out of the U.S. and the second quarter feeling a little happier in terms of how clean you were in terms of stock. How does that translate to the other regions? Are you reasonably comfortable after the first half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well you know, inventory issue is mostly a U.S. one as distributors carry a very, very high level of inventory. Basically that would carry 90 days of inventory in the U.S., where as in China it would be 20 and in 20 days in Europe more of the same thing. So the inventory issue I would say is much more fluid when it comes to Asia and Europe than it is to the U.S. and we have very rarely seen any inventory buildup or destocking in this area. So it's mostly a U.S. impact and as I mentioned we have no particular worries when it comes to the inventory impact. In the U.S. inventories exactly where they should be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's very clear. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Ms. Catherine Rolland from Kepler. Madam, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good evening. Several questions if I may. First of all I just wanted to know if you could give us the split of the &#x20AC;20 million negative FOREX impact by divisions. My second question is about the evolution of the operating margin of the Fashion &amp; Leather Goods business. We have a sales growth of 13% including price increases and EBIT is up by 17%, so maybe there was some negative FOREX impact. Or was there any one-off cost that could explain that the operating margin was not more up? And the third point was about DFS. I just wanted to know if you could tell us what was the DFS sales growth rate in H1, please? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, you really want me to go into the details of &#x20AC;20 million currency impact? I mean we used to have &#x20AC;200 million or &#x20AC;250 million currency impact. I mean this one is as low as &#x20AC;20 million. Anyway, so we had something like minus &#x20AC;10 million for the Fashion &amp; Leather and a slight positive figure for Wines &amp; Spirits and the rest is by and large negligible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operating margin in Fashion &amp; Leather, you seem to be disappointed. We are pretty pleased. We had an increase in operating profit, which was 17%, compared to 15% rise in sales. We think this shows some operating leverage in a business where we already have very higher margins, particularly at Vuitton, where you know margins tend to be reasonably flat. So this shows that there was some good improvement in margins from the other businesses, and we are pretty pleased with this, so there was no particular negative impact stemming from anything. I mean we had really business as usual and we did quite well in my view in terms of pushing margin in the Fashion &amp; Leather division. The effect in H1, if I'm not mistaken, in dollars we are up 24%; it's a bit less in <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:00:14) terms, but it's up 24%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. Krim Delko from Orange Capital. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, yes, this is Krim Delko. Two questions. One is on the U.S. I'm very impressed with the growth there, and I was just wondering if you could maybe give us some color on what is driving that growth. Do you think that the dollar and tourism could be a main contributor to that or is this more sort of the U.S. organic story? That's the first question. In fact I'm just curious, if you look at sort of Q1 to Q2 sequentially from Japan, have you seen any reason to be concerned or some sort of slowdown? Or would you say that both quarters have been fairly steady, as expected, and you know, obviously, the question from sort of the background of the macro uncertainty that we've seen in the markets recently. I don't know if you see anything in the business or you would say that business is fairly stable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks. In the U.S. as you may know tourism is a very small factor in the U.S. unlike in the Euro Zone, for instance, or in Europe. Tourism in the U.S. is a few percentage points of total sales. So it's never a very strong contributor to our business, excluding, obviously, Hawaii, where we do the bulk of our sales with tourists. And as far as Hawaii was concerned we did reasonably well despite low arrivals from Japanese. I mean the business did quite well on that side.</p>
          <p>But coming back to mainland U.S. the business was pretty strong and remains strong Q1 and Q2. And it's mostly as you said, U.S. organic, organic stores. Most of our divisions participated to that. Although there were some swings, particularly as far as watches and jewelry, sorry, as far as Wines &amp; Spirits is concerned. But the rest of the business did well and grew slightly in Q2 compared to Q1, where the better growth in Q2 compared to Q1 in the U.S. in most of our activities.</p>
          <p>I may admit, your question about the Q1 to Q2 comparison was about Japan or it was a broader question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a broader question, actually. I was trying to exclude Japan. I know that must have been an impact on your business. I'm just curious if, let's say the first quarter was a pretty optimistic quarter. Everybody was optimistic on the world economy and then things kind of changed and your numbers are very good and I'm just curious to see if you've seen anything in the business that would cause you for concern in any part of the business. This is more of a general question in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, very clear. Not really. I mean if you look at the various figures we discussed I mean we have a Q2 which is slightly better than Q1 with Wines &amp; Spirits, a significant contributor to the business, being significantly down due to I would say the normalizing factor. I mean, it's clear that Wines &amp; Spirits couldn't stay at 17% organic growth for the rest of the year. So it means that all the businesses have more than offset the slight decrease from Wines &amp; Spirits. So from a business viewpoint we have no signs of slowing down and we have no particular concerns.</p>
          <p>As far as geographies are concerned you see that U.S., Europe and Asia are on par or slightly better in Q2 than what we had in Q1. We mentioned China, 32% versus 30%, Asia is 28% versus 24%, U.S. is 18% versus 17%, Europe is flat with 8%. So no particular source of concern. So I would say broadly speaking the answer to your question is no. We have no particular area where we feel concerned about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have a question from Mr. <mark type="ph" /> Rudolph Udon (1:04:54) from Bank of America/Merrill Lynch. Sir, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good evening. You mentioned that Sephora in Malaysia, the brand is enjoying very strong momentum of the other markets you'd consider penetrating in the coming years. And then a second question on FX, I know your hedging strategy has modestly evolved over the years. You mentioned a particularly difficult environment. Are there any changes there in the way you look at hedging? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well for our new countries, yes and no. I mean I cannot really answer such a question. We have plans to develop the brand in many new countries, not necessarily in Europe, but as far as Asia is concerned we think that the playing shield is quite open and there are many countries we could enter in. We've mentioned the fact that we are planning to develop in Mexico and Brazil, Brazil following the acquisition of Sack's, the online retailer last year. So there are many areas mainly in Asia and Latin America where we expect to develop.</p>
          <p>India would also be a place where we would want to develop, but as you know the regulation there doesn't facilitate the access of multi-brand players to the markets so it's extremely difficult and we've found very hard to get into India so far. So that's about it, but clearly Sephora's strategy is broad-based expansion. We're already on three continents and we intend to carry on developing the brands with entering more countries.</p>
          <p>As far as the hedging is concerned, the situation is a bit unique I would say because the dollar is weak, but as I said in my opening comments the euro is weak as well. So it means that it could easily grow I mean probably see the dollar going up or down is more or less the same. Normally as we probably give the dollar going down unless you're proven wrong but the dollar going down is higher than the dollar going up. So we are in a moment in time which makes the hedging policy pretty tricky, and we have not adapted too much to the situation, although the euro being pretty strong, we make sure that when we buy tunnels the sitting of the tunnel is not too close to the current level so that we don't look ourselves just in case the dollar would be moving up, but that's about it.</p>
          <p>So that's a very difficult market to invest in, but as always I mean our objective is not to speculate but to cover the Group. So we have coverage ratios of about 92% for this year and we're close to 60% for next year. So we are I would say we're covered for the 18 or 24 months to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We've a question from Ms. <mark type="ph" /> Chaminade Betchi (1:08:13) from Natixis. Madam, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello everyone. Most of my questions have been answered, but there are just two small ones. Maybe if you can help us, Jean-Jacques, with the estimates you have for CapEx and the tax rate for the full year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you know, half year, there is no such thing as a half year tax rate, so the half year tax rate is basically the same; it's theoretically the same as the one for the full year. I don't foresee any particular transaction or situations that could cause in the second half of the year the full year tax rate to differ materially from what we had registered in the first half, so we are close to 30%. I think that's a good proxy for what should be the full year tax rate.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Even considering maybe the integration of Bulgari?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well. It's going to be only half a year and it's a fairly low figure compared to the rest of the groups. For the year in 2010 and 2011 it shouldn't have so much of an impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And what about the CapEx? Because you mentioned an increase which was quite significant in H1. What is the plan for the full year and maybe the years to come?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think I'd mentioned before that CapEx program for the year will be somewhere in between &#x20AC;1.2 billion and &#x20AC;1.4 billion. It's always difficult to know exactly where we will land but that's the order of magnitude for this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tania?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We have no further questions for the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much if you are listening to us and we wish you a good summer. Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>