<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1184718" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-10-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>343</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Conor Murphy, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">C. Robert Henrikson, Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Steven A. Kandarian, Executive Vice President and Chief Investment Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">William J. Wheeler, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5">Tom Gallagher</participant>
      <participant id="6">William Wheeler</participant>
      <participant id="7">Suneet Kamath</participant>
      <participant id="8">Stanley Talbi</participant>
      <participant id="9">Lisa Weber</participant>
      <participant id="10">John Nadel</participant>
      <participant id="11">C. Robert Henrikson</participant>
      <participant id="12">Colin Devine</participant>
      <participant id="13">William Mullaney</participant>
      <participant id="14">Jeffrey Schuman</participant>
      <participant id="15">Steven Kandarian</participant>
      <participant id="16">Mark Finkelstein</participant>
      <participant id="17">Edward Spehar</participant>
      <participant id="18">Timothy Schmidt</participant>
      <participant id="19">Jimmy Bhullar</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by. Welcome to the MetLife Third Quarter Earnings Release Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. Later, we will conduct a question and answer session with instructions given at that time. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> And as a reminder, today's conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>Before we get started, I would like to read the following statement on behalf of MetLife. Except with respect to historical information, statements made in this conference call constitute forward-looking statements within the meaning of the federal securities laws, including statements relating to trends in the company's operations and financial results and the business and the products of the company and its subsidiaries.</p>
          <p>MetLife's actual results may differ materially from the results anticipated in the forward-looking statements as a result of risks and uncertainties, including those described from time to time in MetLife Inc.'s filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission. MetLife Inc. specifically disclaims any obligation to update or revise any forward-looking statement, whether as a result of new information, future developments or otherwise.</p>
          <p>With that, I'd like to turn the call over to Conor Murphy, Head of Investor Relations. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Julie. Good morning everyone. Welcome to MetLife Third Quarter 2008 Earnings Call. We are delighted to be here this morning to talk about our results for the quarter. We will be discussing certain financial measures not based on Generally Accepted Accounting Principles, or so called non-GAAP measures. We have reconciled these non-GAAP measures to the most directly comparable GAAP measures in our earnings press release and in our quarterly financial supplements, both of which are available at metlife.com on our Investor Relations page.</p>
          <p>A reconciliation of forward-looking financial information to the most directly comparable GAAP measure is not accessible because MetLife believes it is not possible to provide a reliable forecast of the net investment related gains and losses which can fluctuate from period to period and may have a significant impact on GAAP net income.</p>
          <p>Joining me this morning on the call are Rob Henrikson, our Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, Steve Kandarian, our Chief Investment Officer, and Bill Wheeler, our Chief Financial Officer. After our brief prepared comments, we will take your questions. And here with us today to participate in the discussion are Bill Mullaney, President of our Institutional Businesses, Lisa Weber, President of Individual, Bill Toppeta, President of International, and Bill Moore, President of Auto and Home.</p>
          <p>With that, I would like to turn the call over to Rob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Conor. Good morning everyone. I don't think anyone would disagree that the environment in which we are operating is unprecedented. I know it comes as no surprise that the earnings we reported yesterday, which are consistent with our preannouncement earlier this month, reflect the challenges we are facing.</p>
          <p>This was an extraordinary quarter in our industry as we experienced significant deterioration in both the equity and credit markets. As I said in the press release, we are not immune to this, and like all in our industry, we are affected by these markets.</p>
          <p>But let me make one thing clear. MetLife is in a very strong position. Our fundamentals, the value proposition we bring to the marketplace and the unwavering commitments we make to our clients, will not change. We are demonstrating how the approach we take to our business is working to our benefit.</p>
          <p>Just consider this for a moment. MetLife's premiums, fees and other revenues grew 16% this quarter. And we are up 12% year-to-date. That's 12% business growth in an environment where double digit declines are not uncommon. And it is well above the 9% guidance we provided at Investor Day.</p>
          <p>Let me share a few examples. Institutional Business continued to generate significant top line growth across all of its segments as premiums, fees and other revenues grew 30% to reach $4.5 billion. Driving this was a 16% increase in nonmedical health top line as well as $1.1 billion in retirement and savings revenue due to several large pension closeout cases in both the U.S. and the U.K.</p>
          <p>While Individual Business was clearly impacted by the declining equity markets this quarter, variable annuity deposits increased over the second quarter. Also important, variable annuity lapse rates declined and net flows remained positive, both on a sequential and a year-over-year basis. In addition, fixed annuity deposits were up significantly both year-over-year and sequentially.</p>
          <p>In International, we continued to see strong growth as premiums, fees and other revenues grew 12% over the prior year. This top-line growth was essentially driven by all countries, particularly in Mexico and Chile. In Japan, we continued to strengthen our variable annuity distribution by doubling our Japan Post locations from 160 to 320 outlets.</p>
          <p>In short, we are growing our business simply by doing the things that have put us in the strong position that we are in today, talking to our customers, managing our risk and keeping a close eye on expenses. It is important that all of our customers, shareholders, business partners and employees understand that we will continue to manage MetLife for the long term. This long term approach has served us well, particularly with regard to our investment portfolio. Steve Kandarian will provide you more detail in a moment. But I want to talk briefly about our realized losses.</p>
          <p>Like I said earlier, the third quarter of 2008 was an extraordinary credit quarter. But relative to the size of MetLife's portfolio, the company's level of realized investment losses has remained modest. To put this in perspective with regard to our capital position, the $485 million in credit losses and impairments we recorded are not much more than the excess capital we generate in a quarter. In short, this truly dramatic quarter barely impacted our capital position.</p>
          <p>Now I know that you're interested in our plans for the 2.3 billion in capital that we raised two weeks ago. And we will continue to talk to you about that. But let me say just a few things. We are currently enjoying a competitive advantage because we are big, we are strong and we are trusted. The stock offering was completed -- we completed has bolstered our excess capital and positions us well for the future.</p>
          <p>Before I turn the call over to Steve, I'd like to briefly mention our operational excellence initiative, as it's important in the long term approach we take to our business. As critical as our day to day business management is, looking ahead to identify opportunities that will make this great company even greater is critical. We are identifying ways to operate with the utmost efficiency, bring new products to market quicker, and most importantly, promote profitable growth.  We have made some noteworthy progress on this initiative, identifying future cost savings that we expect will reach at least $400 million a year.</p>
          <p>The changes we are making inevitably affect our employees. As such, U.S. based associates whose jobs are being eliminated have been notified, and we are committed to helping all of our associates manage through this change.</p>
          <p>I know that the past few weeks have been very challenging. However, it is at times like this that MetLife sets itself apart due to its stability and strength. Maintaining our common stock dividend at $0.74 a share represents our confidence in our long term outlook and further demonstrates the value we bring to our shareholders. Over the past 140 years, our company has seen extraordinary market cycles, which is why as I often tell our customers and our shareholders that we will always remain focused on the long term. Amid the current economic climate, this approach serves us well.</p>
          <p>And with that, let me turn it over to Steve Kandarian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rob. Given the increased volatility in the financial markets, I would like to spend a few minutes reviewing variable investment income, realized and unrealized losses, and certain components of our portfolio.</p>
          <p>First, let me start with a comment on variable investment income. Pre-tax variable income was approximately $200 million lower than planned for the third quarter, primarily driven by negative corporate joint venture and hedge fund returns. As I've mentioned on the previous two earnings calls, we expected corporate joint venture income to be under pressure due to overall market conditions. Furthermore, we anticipate corporate joint venture and hedge fund returns will remain weak for the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, income from our securities lending program continued to outperform plan due to the steeper yield curve and higher spreads in the reinvestment portfolio. In our securities lending business, we lend various types of fixed income assets, a return for cash collateral which we reinvest in a diversified portfolio of securities. As of September 30, our securities lending book was approximately $41 billion, down from $45 billion at June 30.</p>
          <p>As mentioned on the October 8 pre-release earnings call, the demand for securities lending by our counterparties has decreased. As a result, these balances have declined further to approximately $31 billion as of October 28. Of this $31 billion, approximately $15 billion was unopened, which means the securities can be returned to us overnight. The remainder of the balance has varying maturities ranging from one week to several months.</p>
          <p>Of the $15 billion of securities unopened, about $13 billion were treasuries and agency securities, which, if put to us, can be immediately sold to satisfy the cash requirements. Should liquidity needs accelerate, we have a pool of $14.6 billion in cash to meet those needs. And in addition, we have the liquidity resources of most of MetLife's general account at our disposal.</p>
          <p>While we plan to remain in this business in the future, we expect that balances will decline further in the coming months. Again, we have sufficient liquidity to facilitate this reduction. I will provide a plan for 2009 variable income at our Investor Day in December.</p>
          <p>Now let me cover investment losses for the quarter. Gross investment losses were $465 million, which is in line with the previous four quarters. Only $46 million were credit related sales. Write downs this quarter were $1,048,000,000. Of this amount, $700 million were credit related impairments. This was primarily driven by $548 million of impairments of our holdings in Lehman Brothers, Washington Mutual and AIG. The non-credit related write downs of $348 million consisted of impairments of equity securities and subsequent sales of securities in the fourth quarter that were planned in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>When added together, total credit related losses from sales and write downs were $746 million before tax, or $485 million after tax. Unrealized losses for fixed maturities were $16.7 billion at September 30. 88% of these unrealized losses are investment grade securities. The increase in unrealized loss was driven by significant spread widening across virtually all asset sectors. For example, during the third quarter, single-A corporate credit spreads increased by over 200 basis points to 461 basis points, and AAA rated credit card spreads increased over 240 basis points to 420 basis points.</p>
          <p>Next, I'd like to discuss our real estate related holdings. As of September 30, we held $1.4 billion of subprime residential mortgage backed securities. 95% of these securities continue to be rated AAA or AA, and 80% are from 2005 or earlier vintages, benefiting from stronger underwriting. As of September 30, we held $4.4 billion of Alt-A residential mortgage backed securities. 83% of our Alt-A portfolio is super senior AAA, which provides almost double the credit enhancement of AAA securities.</p>
          <p>In addition, 87% of our Alt-A portfolio is fixed rate. We hold no option ARM mortgages. By contrast, overall the Alt-A market is 66% floating rate including 26% in option ARMs. We continue to run stress tests on our holdings in these sectors. And we remain comfortable with our assets.</p>
          <p>MetLife's commercial mortgage portfolio currently totals $36 billion. We have taken a defensive position in originating and managing our commercial mortgage portfolio. Since 2005, in response to aggressive underwriting and weak deal structures, we focused our mortgage originations on moderate and low leveraged loans.  As of September 30, the average loan to value of our portfolio was 57%, and less than $2 million of our portfolio was delinquent.</p>
          <p>Finally, let me say a few words about our credit portfolio. Last year, we began to reposition our portfolio for a potential recession. Since October 2007, we have sold approximately $7.2 billion of securities we believed were vulnerable in a recession, including $4.1 billion of investment grade corporate bonds and $2.6 billion of below investment grade securities.</p>
          <p>While a portfolio of our size will not be immune to losses, we believe the portfolio is defensively positioned for the current environment.</p>
          <p>With that, I will turn the call over to Bill Wheeler.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Steve, and good morning everybody. This morning I'd like to walk through MetLife's third quarter results. MetLife reported $0.88 of operating earnings per share, a 40% decline from the third quarter of 2007, which is consistent with our pre-announcement earlier this month. As I mentioned then, our third quarter results are respectable given a difficult environment.</p>
          <p>By the way, all the numbers and comparisons I will speak about this morning exclude RGA, which was split off in a transaction which closed on September 12.</p>
          <p>So let me begin with top line revenues, which we define as premiums, fees and other income. Top line revenues were 8.6 billion this quarter, an increase of 16% over the third quarter of 2007. Year-to-date revenues are up 12% over the first nine months of 2007, so our revenue growth is strong.</p>
          <p>In International, top line revenues increased 13% over the prior year quarter to 1.2 billion. Changes in FX rates increased revenue growth by approximately one point this quarter. International revenue growth was driven largely by a very strong performance in our Latin America region.</p>
          <p>In Institutional, top line revenue growth of 30% over the year ago period was driven by strong revenue growth across all of our major product lines. High pension closeout sales during the quarter increased retirement and savings revenue to 1.1 billion. Nonmedical health and other had a 16% increase in premiums over the third quarter of 2007. That was driven by Dental, which was also bolstered by a recent HMO acquisition. Growth in Group Life resulted in an increase of 7% over the year-ago period, which is also quite good.</p>
          <p>Turning to our operating margins, let's start with our underwriting results. In Institutional, our group term life mortality ratio of 90.7% was excellent and below our target range of 91 to 95%. In Nonmedical health and other, group disabilities morbidity ratio was relatively high at 95.6%, and was driven by lower recoveries and higher incidents. In our Dental product, claims utilization was higher than the prior year quarter, resulting in lower underwriting margins.</p>
          <p>In Individual Business, our mortality ratio was 82.7%, effectively on plan. Let me point out that this excludes the impact of reinsurance. If we adjust for that our net mortality results were unfavorable by about $16 million after tax, or about $0.02 per share.</p>
          <p>Auto and Homes combined ratio, including catastrophes, was 89%. Catastrophe claims were 13 million after tax, higher than planned, or $0.02 per share. But this was more than offset by favorable noncash prior accident year development of $27 million after tax, or $0.04 per share. The combined ratio, excluding the impact to catastrophes and prior year development, improved to 85.2% year-over-year. That's an excellent result. This was driven by strong core operating results in the Auto area.</p>
          <p>Moving to investment spreads. With regard to variable investment income, as Steve just described, we again saw mixed performances of certain variable and alternative asset classes this quarter. Private equity returns were well below plan and we experienced losses in our hedge fund. But securities lending income performed above plan.</p>
          <p>Overall, variable investment income was approximately $120 million after tax and other offsets, or $0.17 per share, lower than our baseline plan. As part of the equity raise this month, we indicated that securities lending volume was declining, and Steve gave you some additional numbers on that a moment ago. This will reduce securities lending income in the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Moving to expenses, our expense ratio in the third quarter was high at 30.7%. However, there were a number of specific items that drove up expenses this quarter. First, higher DAC amortization caused by the 9% decline in the S&amp;P 500 in the quarter impacted us by approximately $129 million or $0.18 per share. I've explained this before, but I want to make sure everyone understands that we true up our annuity DAC balances every quarter based on the performance of the related separate accounts. We don't just do it once a year.</p>
          <p>Second, we accrued approximately $48 million, or $0.07 per share related to the first phase of the company's operational excellence initiative. The accrual largely relates to severance of employees who will be leaving around the year end. And we expect this action will result in annualized savings of about $130 million.</p>
          <p>Also this quarter, MetLife announced the decision to commute its excess insurance policies for asbestos-related claims. That amounted to a charge of $23 million, or $0.03 per share.</p>
          <p>Adjusting for these specific items, our expense ratio was actually below guidance, and, therefore, we think our expenses are well under control.</p>
          <p>Turning to our bottom line results, we earned 639 million of operating income, or $0.88 per share. That's a 40% decrease, as I mentioned. As you know, during the quarter MetLife completed its split off of substantially all of the company's 52% interest in RGA. As a result, our share of the operating earnings of RGA in the third quarter of approximately 24 million, or $0.03 per share, is now reflected in discontinued operations. All previous periods have also been reclassed into discontinued operations. The split off transaction results in a GAAP loss of $458 million and a decrease in MetLife's share count of approximately 23 million shares.</p>
          <p>With regard to investment gains and losses, in the third quarter we had net realized investment gains of $456 million after tax. Included in that were gross losses of 465 million and write downs of 1 billion, which Steve has already explained in detail. Losses were offset by derivative gains of 745 million after tax, which arose primarily from the increase in the value of the U.S. dollar in the third quarter as well as an increase in credit spreads.</p>
          <p>We also announced our annual common dividend of $0.74 per share this year, keeping it flat with last year. Our preliminary statutory operating earnings are approximately 1.6 billion after tax this quarter and 3 billion for the first three quarters of 2008. A large portion of this quarter's statutory earnings were caused by the RGA split off.</p>
          <p>And as I'm sure you all know and as Rob mentioned, we completed a $2.3 billion equity offering a couple of weeks ago. With this money, and including existing excess capital and the 1 billion we will receive from the convert in February of 2009, we believe we have total excess capital of approximately $6 billion above what is necessary to maintain a AA rating.</p>
          <p>In summary, the fundamentals of our business remain strong. And despite the market environment, we continue to benefit from our strong diversification. And with that, I will turn it back to the operator for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. With that, we'll go to the line of Tom Gallagher with Credit Suisse. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Just wanted to ask a few questions around equity market sensitivity. First is, can you comment on based on the extent of the equity market decline so far in 4Q, is there an impact to your statutory capital?  That's the first question.</p>
          <p>And then, second, Bill, I guess just to follow up on your comments on DAC. I can appreciate that you all are truing this up every quarter. But aren't we getting close to breaking through certain corridors in terms of longer term assumptions for DAC amortization?  And if so, is there a risk that we could see a much larger charge perhaps in 4Q if you do reset assumptions?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom, yes, okay. So stat capital, we clearly are -- quarter to date, if things stayed where we are in terms of the equity markets, we would certainly see an impact to our stat reserves regarding our variable annuity business. I guess I'll probably -- maybe I should size that a little bit for you. And this is -- obviously, we don't really recalculate RBC. It's actually a long, involved process. But we obviously make estimates about RBC. We have a person who does that. That's their full time job, is to calculate and project RBC for us in our various legal entities.</p>
          <p>We -- think about it this way. We have -- in the third quarter, we had a 9% decline in the S&amp;P 500. And that triggered for us -- we had -- we needed to increase our stat reserves, call it 3 or 4 RBC points. And for us, an RBC point is a little bit over 50 million bucks. So that sizes it for you.</p>
          <p>Now the relationship is not completely linear, obviously. So if you talked about &#x2013; so quarter to date, we've had a 19% decline in the S&amp;P 500, I think. And so, if you sort of doubled the third quarter impact, you'd be left with sort of a 6 to 8% increase -- decline in RBC points. And again, the relationship is not completely linear, so it's higher than that. It might be something like 10 to 12 points. A 10 point impact RBC is roughly 500 million or half a billion dollars of additional stat reserves that you'd have to put up.</p>
          <p>The number is probably a little higher than that. So that kind of sizes it for you in terms of -- if the markets stay where it is, the additional stat reserves we've had to put up.</p>
          <p>I would just say a couple other things about that. A lot of the impact on stat is driven by how do you reinsure, the structure of your reinsurance program, how thoroughly you reinsure your writers. And we think we insure them very thoroughly, or hedge them thoroughly. And then, obviously, the kind of writer contracts you have, we're mainly a GMIB company, which probably, at the end of the day, means lower stat reserves than maybe withdrawal benefits have. So that's -- so all that kind of gets factored in.</p>
          <p>So just to sum up on this, if you think about half a billion, maybe a little more in terms of additional stat impact, and you compare that with sort of our 6 billion of excess capital, it's -- this is a thing. But it's certainly a manageable thing for us given the current environment. So hopefully that'll kind of give you some sense of that.</p>
          <p>Now with regard to DAC, the way &#x2013; we calculate the DAC impact every quarter. And so we look at what the market returns were and we change our DAC amortization. We also use what's called a  mean reversion formula to calculate that. And we are clearly at one end of the spectrum of the mean reversion formula. It's not technically a corridor. So what that means is the impact of DAC -- the impact of the marketplace has a greater effect on the rate of DAC amortization as we get to the end of our mean reversion range.</p>
          <p>So yes, if the stock market stayed where it was, you would see an increase in DAC. Let me just give you a sense of that. A 9% increase -- decline -- a 9% decline in the stock market in the third quarter caused -- triggered about $120 million pre-tax incremental DAC. And that's both on annuities and life. Most of it's on annuities, but some of it's on life.</p>
          <p>So again, if you doubled that, you'd be talking crudely 240 million. And actually, it's -- because you are at the end of the range, it would actually be a little higher than that. So you do see this kind of increase in DAC amortization flowing through the income statement. So it could have an impact on the fourth quarter results. So hopefully that'll give you some sense of the numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's helpful. And just a quick follow-up. So the -- Bill, we wouldn't be looking at resetting assumptions but rather probably coming back within the high end of the corridor?  Would that be the right way to think about it if...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's exactly right. Again, we don't call it &#x2013; and I'm not sure why we don't call it a corridor. But we don't. I know other people do. And I'm not sure they're doing the same thing we are. It's a mean reversion range. And so, we're &#x2013; yes. Because we're at one end of the range, the DAC is -- the DAC adjustment is flowing right through. There's no sort of smoothing impact which you normally get with a mean reversion formula. So it's coming right through.</p>
          <p>But there's no buildup of -- let me put it this way. There's no buildup of DAC that we need to release. Obviously that's the good part of doing it every quarter. We've been releasing it all along.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Suneet Kamath with Sanford Bernstein. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. Maybe two quick ones. First, if you could comment on your variable annuity hedging program and how that works relative to some of the increases we've seen in volatility and if you think your pricing of the riders is appropriate.</p>
          <p>And then second, maybe more of a philosophical question on excess capital. You talked about 6 billion inclusive of the convert next year. How much of that excess capital do you think is really redeployable at this point in time, just given the uncertainties, sort of rating agency concerns?  I mean, is really a 350 RBC ratio where a AA company needs to be? Or is it something higher than that? Just any thoughts on that would be helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think &#x2013; thanks, Suneet. There's a lot of questions in what you asked. So maybe I'll let Stan talk about the hedging program, and so how it's working. I would say we had about -- we think we had about $0.02 of hedge breakage. We normally brag, we never have hedge breakage. But we actually did have about $0.02 worth in the annuities. And then maybe Lisa will talk a little bit about annuity pricing and volatility and what that might mean. And then I'll come back to the -- I'll do the philosophical, is 350 RBC enough.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Yes, as you know, we do balance economic hedges with -- we try to match the accounting. It varies by product. So if you look at the various products that we offer, we've offered just about everything. Our GMDB benefits are hedged, sometimes through reinsurance. And we've also done some capital markets reinsurance as well.</p>
          <p>Our GMAB products, we've had different generations. Our older generation, we've had a pretty effective delta hedging program. With our newer generation, there are some additional features that allows us to do split accounting. And some of it is an embedded derivative. And when we have an embedded derivative, we're able to do a full three Greek match.</p>
          <p>As Bill said, our program has worked pretty well. Our basis differences have been fairly small, and the impact in the third quarter was only a little over $0.02 a share.</p>
          <p>And in terms of pricing our variable annuity hedges, I just want to remind you that to the extent that we are hedging, we generally do long dated hedges. So any kind of increase in volatility that causes an increase in our hedging costs really affects the new business that we've written recently. And certainly, our individual business associates are considering the pricing of those riders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I would just add that in this current environment, it would be imprudent not to look at raising the fees there. And we will continue as we have with different products, like long-term care, we'll continue to make the difficult decisions even if they're not popular.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so I've had some time to think about whether 350 RBC is the right number. Look, obviously the rating agencies make that call. I don't. But I'll give you my opinion and maybe they're listening.</p>
          <p>We've actually raised -- something you kind of -- you need a little sense of history here. Three, four years ago we used to manage to a 300% RBC ratio. And the bar has kind of -- over the environment over the last few years, the bar has been raised from -- it went from 300 to 325, now 325 to 350. And we've sort of been living with 350 now for I think about two years.</p>
          <p>And I think to some extent that's to the rating agency's great credit. They've sort of said the products are a little more interesting, they're a little more volatile. We think a higher capital cushion is warranted. And a lot of people have created economic capital models and said -- that show that 350 is way in excess of what you need. Now I'm not going to opine on whether that makes any sense or not. But that kind of tells you that &#x2013; is 350 enough?</p>
          <p>So in our minds, we look at our business mix and our diversification, and even in this -- what I would call pretty crazy tail environment we're in, and we're still making money. And we are -- and we're still building capital. And it kind of leads me to believe that 350 is probably okay and an appropriate number. In our discussions with the rating agencies, they're not -- this isn't coming up as a discussion point like, well, maybe you need to be north of 350. That's not where our discussions have been. They've actually been very constructive and positive.</p>
          <p>So I guess I think it's enough. We're obviously holding -- you say, well if 350's enough why are you holding 6 billion more? And look, this goes back to what we said in the equity capital raise. We want to be perceived as the strongest life insurance company out there. And we think in the coming world where I think people are going to focus a lot more on strength than maybe price, this is going to work to our great benefit. And that's how we want to be positioned.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll go to the line of John Nadel with Sterne, Agee. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, I have a couple of quick questions. First is, MetLife Inc. is a federally related bank holding company. I was wondering your thoughts on or if you'd comment on whether you'd submit an application for funds under the TARP program and if you'd be interested in that if it was made available to the life insurance space. That's question number one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I was waiting for what question number two was.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I was waiting for your response to figure out exactly which way I wanted to go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I see, okay. Maybe it's a good idea for me to respond to that then. There's a lot of discussion out there in the press and so forth, so let me just respond.</p>
          <p>As you pointed out, and as many of you know but some may not have recognized, MetLife is a bank holding company. It is our understanding that the guidelines in the federal statute allow the company access to the capital purchase program. But other than that, I have no comment on the federal program.</p>
          <p>What I can tell you is what has been discussed in several ways before and on this call, is that we're well capitalized. We have a strong balance sheet. We have financial strength ratings that are clearly among the highest in the industry. Bill talked about the successful common stock offering of 2.3 billion, and that was on top of the excess that we already had as of September 30 of 4. So I think that's &#x2013; other than that, I have no comment on the federal program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. A separate one, but probably somewhat related. There's also an FDIC program available right now that I think is guaranteeing debt issuance. Are you eligible under that as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't want -- let me take another crack at all kinds of such programs and whatnot out there. As long as your notes would show, if you've been following this company, I would say that -- I always say any kind of question around funding or financing, any kind of questions around acquisitions, anything that even looks or smells sort of like an acquisition, including closeout opportunities and whatnot, we always say the same thing. Certainly I do, that we explore every avenue. We explore all options in everything we do. That's what it's all about, to run a major company. And other than that, I don't have any comment on the federal programs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Maybe to go back to the philosophical sort of piece of the discussion earlier. Do you think -- I mean, your top line growth &#x2013; Rob, you hit on it pretty specifically at the open. Do you think that you're already seeing in that top line growth the benefits of sort of your competitive advantage given the strength of the capital, the strength of the brand? And if so, I guess it would be impossible to quantify. But I guess it just goes to the question of do you think you're already seeing it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then the last one is just a quick one on debt to capital levels. Bill, you guys used to have a table in the supplement that at least provided us some adjustments to get to a debt to capital ratio. I think you guys used to focus on, or probably still do, focus on the Moody's level for that. Any chance you can give us an update on where you guys stand relative to that sort of 25% typical target?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we dropped that number. I mean, we used to have our own leverage ratio, and I thought that mine was the best. But I couldn't convince anybody else of that. So we sort of just dropped it because obviously, we are governed by what the rating agencies think the leverage ratio should be. The Moody's ratio right now is sort of pro forma. The equity offering would be &#x2013; leverage ratio about 23.9%. They like us. It's not a bright line. But they like us to be 25 or lower. And so that gives you a sense of where our leverage is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And last real quick one, if in your discussions with the rating agencies sort of the 350 is actually &#x2013; you mentioned it's not something that's coming &#x2013; that's really coming up. What are the key sort of two or three topical areas where you sense that they're most focused with respect to you and maybe more broadly the industry right now?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I got your point. Well, for us, they really -- they want to understand what's going on with SEC lending and what's happening there. Because they know that the -- the world knows. It was in the paper today. Securities lending activity is shrinking around globe. And so, they wanted to make sure that that wasn't causing us any harm. I think we've reassured them, and I think hopefully all of you, that our SEC lending issues are very well controlled.</p>
          <p>We've done a great job in my mind of managing down the size of the program without triggering any meaningful capital losses. And we've really made sure we have the liquidity necessary to deal with that very effectively. So I think that's gone extremely well. I think with regard to -- the other thing I think more broadly is just what we're hearing in the conference calls this quarter, what's going on with the potential statutory capital impact of what's going on with the equity markets. And so, I think that's also a discussion point. And I'm sure they're having that with others, not just us.</p>
          <p>Yes, they're interested in credit losses and stuff like that. But I would say they kind of get it. They know -- they understand it. That is their business, obviously. So they have a good feel for what's going on there. And they realize we're in a highly unusual time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. The next question is from Colin Devine with Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. A couple of quick ones, I would think. First on disability, with the benefit ratio spiking up, should we start to be concerned that that's a reflection of the economy with Met being more I think of as a large-case company, that this may be a trend that continues for a while? Second, if you could give us a little bit more detail on pension closeouts, both perhaps for the quarter but also the outlook in the pipeline.</p>
          <p>And then, on capital, Bill, on RBC, I would take it now that your original plan with the convert was to avoid the dilution from it. And now you're planning to just go with that. But then also, when you talk about the 6 billion of excess, it would seem to me that if we look at what, as you laid out earlier, what may be happening to RBC in the fourth quarter &#x2013; that really some of that 6 billion is spoken for and you're going to have to put it down into the life company to keep that RBC number above 350. Is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Colin, it's Bill Mullaney. Let me start with the questions you asked about disability and about closeouts. In terms of disability, some of what we're seeing may be a function of the trends that we're seeing in the economy. We've talked before about the fact that disability is a product that when the economy gets soft, you do see some impact on your claims. In this particular quarter, the ratio did spike up to 95. It's a little bit outside of our range. But it does move from quarter to quarter. We do see some volatility in that range. And what I would say is there wasn't any one real thing that drove the results up. Incidents was up a little bit. Recoveries were down and the size of the recoveries were down. And all of those things together put some pressure on the ratio.</p>
          <p>We're watching it very closely. We are increasing some of our assumptions as it relates to these things and where the economy's going, to factor that into our prices for 2009. So it's something that I think we are keeping a very close eye on.</p>
          <p>In terms of closeouts, we had a very good quarter for closeouts, almost $700 million in closeouts for the quarter in both the U.S. and the U.K. I would say that the pipeline for closeouts continues to be good. A lot of good conversations with many customers, both in the U.S. and the U.K., around their pension plans, what they're thinking about and what they might do in the future. So we feel pretty good that they'll continue to be good activity in the closeout area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And then finally, about capital. Yes, with regard to the convert, a year ago I would have said we would have offset the dilution from that conversion, the convert by doing buy backs. I think now it's probably just better to keep the money, obviously. So we'll do that. We'll keep the money. And the shares outstanding will increase a little bit.</p>
          <p>With regard to that 6 billion and the fact that we'll have some surplus strength, yes, I think that's right. I mean, I think if -- it's hard to -- I think some of that 6 billion may have to go down into statutory reserves. But technically, it doesn't -- I don't think that'll mean we have to put some money down in the holding company. We run -- rule of thumb, low RBC ratio, we're managing to the high 300s, sort of in the 390 range. It's a little different at the different legal entities, RBC ratio.</p>
          <p>So there's -- we think there'd be enough cushion down in the insurance subsidiaries right now to deal with this surplus problem. We wouldn't necessarily have to move any money down. The full 6 billion is not at the holding company. Some of that cushion is sitting down in the insurance company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But then, is it fair to say the 6 could be more like 5 billion, which is still obviously quite a large amount?  But six may be closer to five?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, probably closer to five, we're at right now. I think that's probably fair. So obviously, we'll see how the quarter ends. But yes, I mean, 500, 600, 700 million sort of -- because of this issue is certainly possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then just one quick follow-up, in terms of your M&amp;A appetite, which is &#x2013; I think Rob's indicated in the past was primarily internationally oriented. Has that changed? And perhaps expanding on what Rob said earlier, would you consider something like the capital purchase program to help finance an acquisition if that was available?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We can't comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that is a yes. Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not commenting because I hate to repeat myself.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll take that as a definitive yes. Okay. In terms of domestic versus international, any change?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, we were laughing so hard we didn't hear your full question. Would you repeat your last question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In terms of your acquisition appetite, I think it's been primarily internationally oriented. Has that now changed or are you also looking domestically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the -- let me -- in terms of what we've looked at, both over time, both internationally and domestically, I wouldn't characterize that our focus has been entirely on -- or even so heavily weighted to international because we look at opportunities both domestically and internationally. But remember, I've always said in times past, and it's probably a little bit different dynamic today, that domestically you have to have a willing seller and a willing buyer. And you have to have an attractive price. And so, the question about price and the question about the willing seller has been a pretty dominant feature in terms of the domestic market in particular. And maybe today we see something different there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll go next to the line of Jeff Schuman with KBW. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I have a question for Steve and then I'd like to follow up. I'm wondering, Met, like a lot of life insurers, has been in cash conservation mode. I'm wondering if you're at a point now where you've kind of got the cash position closer to where you want it, and whether you might start to be more active investing in certain markets and where you might be looking first?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The cash raise had something to do as well with the securities lending program. So as we mentioned, we're going to be shrinking that base. And again, when you think about that program, we have a security we own, we lend it out, we get back cash collateral, we reinvest that cash collateral into other securities. So in essence, our balance sheet grows based upon that program.</p>
          <p>As that program comes down, so will that cash to some degree. We don't know exactly where that number will end up. But there will likely be some cash left over at the end of the reduction in the program. And at that point, we'll certainly start looking at relative value across different asset categories and decide where to put the money.</p>
          <p>We're likely to put that money in this environment in securities we feel are as safe as possible. Obviously, all sectors are being hit by spread widening. I don't think that means that all sectors are equally vulnerable to defaults and delinquencies and losses. So most likely, we'll look at sectors such as now government-backed RMBS with more explicitly a government guarantee than previously. We'll look at sectors like AAA rated credit cards, the kind of first to pay part of the stack. And we'll look at other kinds of securities that are very high up in the structure in terms of credit enhancement, where we feel that the possibility of loss is as low as can be possible in this marketplace.</p>
          <p>So that's where we'll put the money when we finish right-sizing the securities lending program.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And I'm wondering, I guess, how much relationship there is between the -- I guess recent sort of inactivity of life insurers in some of these markets and the unrealized losses that have increased for life insurers. In other words, it strikes me that life insurers are kind of victims of what's happened in these markets. But they've also contributed to market levels by withdrawing from some of these markets. Is it too optimistic to think that as we roll through the fourth quarter and insurers get more active, that they could actually contribute to some additional strength in recovering some of these fixed income markets? Or is that too optimistic?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think you're asking a broad question about what's really occurred here with the credit crisis and the lack of liquidity in markets. So let me just talk a little bit about credit spreads, because this unrealized loss you're seeing balloon on our balance sheet as well as other financial firms' balance sheets really relates to that. So you can think about credit spreads in two ways. One, related to fundamentals. Meaning, it's portending higher actual losses on these securities, defaults, losses in terms of recoveries and so on.</p>
          <p>The second piece is a supply/demand imbalance. Lots and lots of sellers as people delever their balance sheets, whether it be commercial banks, investment banks, hedge funds, while we're not delevering in a major way at MetLife, the fact that we're shrinking the securities lending program in a small way suggests that we're taking a little bit of our asset base down.</p>
          <p>So lots and lots of sellers of securities, almost no buyers right now, and the spreads &#x2013; if you look at in the marketplace driving those unrealized losses, probably do have some fundamental basis to them. But I think the majority of the spread widening relates to supply/demand imbalance. And once, I think, the banks get recapitalized, once the fear factor starts to come down with the intervention by the federal government and other governments across the globe, I believe these markets will start going back to more normal kinds of spreads, given fundamentals not purely based upon these supply/demand imbalances.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thanks a lot, Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll go to the line of Mark Finkelstein with FPK. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Steve, you talked about repositioning the fixed maturities portfolio, kind of going into more recessionary times. I'm just curious what you're doing with alternative assets, either as money becomes available to be pulled out or cash from the LBO funds gets delivered.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We've made commitments in certain categories such as LBO funds where there are draw downs, as you know. So obviously, we will honor all those commitments. And that will go on for a number of years as those partnerships continue. I will tell you that there haven't been a lot of draw downs lately because not a lot of deals are getting done in that area. There's very little credit availability to anyone. So the LBO players simply aren't doing deals right now by and large.</p>
          <p>In the area of hedge funds, we are likely to bring that program down somewhat. And we're going to look closely at the performance of the different hedge fund partnerships we invest in. We're going to make some decisions about which ones we want to remain with going forward. But I think the hedge fund area in general is going to shrink in the coming quarters and the coming year or two. And there'll be a shake out to some degree. And we're evaluating which firms to remain with as an investor.</p>
          <p>So it's likely that that program will shrink somewhat over the coming few quarters on our balance sheet. But in general, we have not been making a lot of investments in the alternative area. Again, not a lot of capital is being put out in the marketplace either. So the fund raising actually is very, very limited at this point in time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. In R&amp;S, premium and deposits were very strong, I think 13 billion according to your kind of policyholder account balance reconciliation. Can you just discuss what you're seeing? I assume money is coming from other competitors. But is that trend continuing post the quarter?  What are we seeing there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we actually saw some pretty good &#x2013; this is Bill Mullaney &#x2013; pretty good net flows in the quarter for R&amp;S. And getting back to a comment that Rob made earlier in terms of flight to quality, there are some companies out there that have been speaking with us about potentially moving money. And so, there are some counterbalances, though, we have funding agreements in that portfolio. And we are seeing some redemptions on our funding agreements as well.</p>
          <p>So I think you'll see some movement both ways in terms of some inflows in terms of money moving to us in a flight to quality way. And then you'll see some other movements downward because companies will be redeeming things like funding agreements to have greater levels of liquidity. So it's likely that R&amp;S fund balances will probably, we think, stay relatively flat for the next couple of quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, Bill, just if you were to look out three to six months from now, do you have any projection on where you think the securities lending portfolio might be?  I think you were at 41 billion at the third quarter. I don't know if you gave an update as to where you are today. But if you had that, that'd be great. And then where do you think we could end up in terms of the size of this portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Steve. Let me take that one. It's 31 billion, as we mentioned, now. And we think it'll shrink over the course of the remainder of this year, perhaps even below the $25 billion level before going back up during 2009 to roughly $25 billion on average over the course of 2009. That's our best case, our best guess, if you will, at this point in time.</p>
          <p>Obviously, this program is driven by two things. One, the securities that we hold in the general account that are lendable, if you will, that fit in the category of lendable securities; and the second thing is the demand on the other side, our counterparties in terms of need for these securities. And given credit market issues, given hedge fund issues, the need for those securities is much lower today than it had been in the past.</p>
          <p>So will there be some recovery there?  We think yes. But at a minimum, securities such as treasuries, agencies and government backed, residential mortgage backed securities are likely still to be lendable going forward -- question mark around corporate securities. So even if you exclude corporate securities, we think we'll probably be around the $25 billion level as a norm for the foreseeable future. But a number could actually dip below that in the interim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll go to the line of Ed Spehar with Merrill Lynch.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good morning. I think I have a few quick numbers questions. I was hoping that you could give us -- and if it's not the precise number, at least a ballpark -- of what the variable annuity account balances are with living benefit guarantees. And again, roughly -- if you don't have exact, what the split is between IB and WB. And then I have a couple of other quick ones.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure, Ed. This is Tim Schmidt. The total living benefit composition of the VA balances would be about 42%, about 39 billion in total. And the split between the GMIB riders and the other withdrawal benefit riders would be about just a little under 50/50 of the total number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>A little under 50/50, the IB to WB?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it would be about 18 of the 38 or so that I quoted.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Is IB?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Is IB, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then, Bill, I wanted to make sure I understood. The $6 billion roughly excess that you're talking about, is that as of the end of the third quarter?  Is it as of today where the S&amp;P is?  I'm not sure where that $500 million potential hit &#x2013; whether that was in that or not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's not. Because obviously, you have got to pick a point in time some time. I would say it's as of the end of the third quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So the 500 million plus kind of affects the statutory impact, and it might be higher than that, would be a subtraction from the 6 bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then could you comment on your capacity to issue preferred securities, given where you are with your balance sheet. How much of this stuff could you issue?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Interestingly...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you were -- obviously, not issuing to buy back stock, but issuing for other reasons.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that's an interesting question. I would have said that in sort of a normal world, given the -- guidelines have sort of what I would call a hybrid basket, if you will, of what the preferred would enter. And also Moody's doesn't necessarily have a hybrid basket. But they have something -- they want to look at the cash flow coverage ratio at the holding company. And those would lead you to believe -- if you kind of thought those were hard guidelines, you'd say, oh, the number's two to three bill, something like that, in terms of capacity. But I view those as guidelines, kind of like in Pirates of the Caribbean. Those are guidelines.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So they're...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's like the high-brow references I can always count on from you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Exactly. Well, my kids watch it. So we live in a world where that may be -- that number may be different than 2 to 3 bill. And depending on what happened to that cash, that would probably be okay with the rating agencies, I bet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And then the final question is, I mean, I suspect they're less than they used to be. But there was a time when you would talk about a lower RBC ratio as being okay relative to some others because of the unrealized real estate gains in the portfolio. Can you talk a little bit about how anybody is looking at that or thinking about that right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve's going to give you the number, part of what he thinks the unrealized gains are in the real estate portfolio. Just for everybody's benefit, we have a lot of equity real estate which we hold at book. We have had a pretty successful track record I think in terms of realizing gains at very big numbers. And so, we're pretty good at that. And there's a lot of value there. That does not get counted in the RBC ratio, obviously. We don't sort of &#x2013; and we view it as a thing that's there, but we don't try to take credit for it. And that's obviously not in our -- what we call our excess capital number, because in my mind, that's not readily accessible, especially in this environment. So &#x2013; but Steve?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we track that number every quarter. It's come down a little bit, but it's still at $3.3 billion pre-tax. And as Bill mentioned, the liquidity in this marketplace, obviously right now, is not great. Lending is limited. But in terms of fundamental value, even in this market with declining prices, we still have a number of $3.3 billion as an unrealized gain, net pre-tax.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And we have time for one final question from the line of Jimmy Bhullar with JPMorgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you. I had a couple of questions for Lisa. The first one is on your variable annuity sales. Based on industry numbers, it looks like the industry's preliminary numbers, the industry will be down in the mid to high single digits. Your sales, I think, were up almost 7% sequentially. I don't think there was a special or anything. But if you could comment on what drove that? And then I have a follow-up after that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Yes, there's a couple of things going on with our variable annuity sales. And we did have some enhancements in the second quarter to our GMIB. We added the dollar to dollar death benefit and we also improved the LWG.</p>
          <p>But really what our sales increase is attributable to, I would say even more so, is this whole opportunity in terms of the flight to quality. And it's where the MetLife brand is really standing strong. With all of the market turmoil, what clients are really looking for are guarantees and safe havens. And that's evidenced by the increase in the rider take rate. And so, while Tim talked about the balances, we were up to an all-time high of almost an 86% take rate on the riders.</p>
          <p>So it's that. In addition, our wholesalers are solid. More of them want to work here and have joined us. And so our narrow and deep strategy with our focus firms has worked as well on the independent side. And so that we do believe that what you'll see in Q3 as we also saw in 2Q is that, again, we will gain market share. So we feel really terrific about our annuity sales overall, both variable and fixed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And lastly, just on the living benefits. Has sort of the high volatility in the market made you rethink about the features that you're offering, or at least raise prices?  A few of your competitors have been thinking about raising prices. What are your thoughts on the long term profitability of offering living benefits, and then secondly, the prices that you're charging for those?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, as I commented a little bit earlier, we are looking at increasing our pricing now as we speak, given the current environment. And we will not sacrifice our profitability here. And so, we're going to make the decisions that we need to make and execute on those decisions. And so, you'll hear more about that as we go forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, lastly, if I could ask one more. Just on your variable investment income. It was obviously below plan this quarter. And if you look at the market overall, IPO activity is pretty much nonexistent. You also have a decline in your securities lending book. So obviously the fourth quarter is going to be weak. But what needs to happen for variable investment income to return to the 300, $350 million range next year?  Or is that even a likely range given the macro environment right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, as we look into the fourth quarter we don't see a bounce back in the hedge fund space or in the corporate joint venture LBO space. And for those areas to improve, the equity markets have to improve dramatically as do the subdebt markets for the LBO players. And I think that's going to be some time before that turns around.</p>
          <p>As I mentioned earlier, in December at our Investor Day, I will give a new plan for variable income for 2009.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And I'll turn it back to you, Mr. Murphy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you. Just a reminder to please -- everyone please join us at our Investor Day in New York on Monday, December 8. And that's it. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> That does conclude our conference for today. Thank you for your participation and for using AT&amp;T executive teleconference. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>