<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1149540" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2008-05-02</date>
    <companies>
      <company>343</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Conor Murphy, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">C. Robert Henrikson, Chairman, President, and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Steven A. Kandarian, Executive Vice President and Chief Investment Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">William J. Wheeler, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5">Jimmy Bhullar</participant>
      <participant id="6">Steven Kandarian</participant>
      <participant id="7">William Mullaney</participant>
      <participant id="8">Darin Arita</participant>
      <participant id="9">Tamara Kravec</participant>
      <participant id="10">William Wheeler</participant>
      <participant id="11">William Toppeta</participant>
      <participant id="12">William Moore</participant>
      <participant id="13">Colin Devine</participant>
      <participant id="14">Lisa Weber</participant>
      <participant id="15">Nigel Dally</participant>
      <participant id="16">Suneet Kamath</participant>
      <participant id="17">Steven Schwartz</participant>
      <participant id="18">Tom Gallagher</participant>
      <participant id="19">Andrew Kligerman</participant>
      <participant id="20">Eric Berg</participant>
      <participant id="21">John Hall</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for standing by, and welcome to the MetLife Incorporated first quarter earnings release.  At this time all lines are in a listen-only mode.  Later there will be a question and answer session and instructions will be given at that time.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  As a reminder, today's call is being recorded.</p>
          <p>Before we get started, I would like to read the following statement on behalf of MetLife.  Except with respect to historical information, statements made in this conference call constitute forward-looking statements within the meaning of the federal securities laws, including statements related to trends in the company's operations and financial results, the markets, or its products and the future development of its business.  MetLife's actual results may differ materially from the results anticipated in the forward-looking statements as a result of risks and uncertainties including those described in MetLife Incorporated filings with the SEC including its S1 and S3 registration statements.  MetLife Incorporated specifically disclaims any obligation to update or revise any forward-looking statement whether as a result of new information, future developments or otherwise.</p>
          <p>With that I'd like to turn the call over to Conor Murphy, head of Investor Relations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Ken, good morning everyone.  Welcome to MetLife's first quarter 2008 earnings call.  We are delighted to be here this morning to talk about our results for the quarter.</p>
          <p>We will be discussing certain financial measures not based on generally accepted accounting principals, so-called non-GAAP measures.  We have reconciled these non-GAAP measures to the most directly comparable GAAP measures in our earnings press release and in our quarterly financial supplements, both of which are available on our website at MetLife.com on our Investor Relations page.  A reconciliation of forward-looking financial information to the most directly comparable GAAP measure is not accessible because MetLife believes it is not possible to provide reliable forecast of the net investment related gains and losses which can fluctuate from period to period and may have a significant impact on GAAP net income.</p>
          <p>Joining me this morning on the call are Rob Henrikson, our Chairman and Chief Executive Officer; Steve Kandarian, our Chief Investment Officer; and Bill Wheeler, our Chief Financial Officer.  After our brief prepared comments, we will take your questions.  Here with us today to participate in the discussion are Bill Mullaney, President of Institutional; Lisa Weber, President of Individual Business; Bill Toppeta, President of International; and Bill Moore, President of Auto &amp; Home.</p>
          <p>With that, I would like to turn the call over to Rob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Conor, and good morning, everyone.  MetLife had a strong first quarter.  We grew our top line results by 11.5% to reach a record of $9.4 billion in premiums, fees, and other revenues.  We increased operating earnings per share by almost 8% and grew our book value despite the challenges posed by the credit and equity markets.  The fundamentals of our business are strong, and I want to share a few specific examples with you.</p>
          <p>With our leading position in the group marketplace, Institutional Business continues to demonstrate its ability to generate outstanding results.  Across the board, Institutional performed extremely well as it benefited from solid underwriting, strong investment spreads, and continued expense discipline.  Operating earnings grew 23% over the prior year period, with each segment growing at a double digit rate.  Institutional's operating ROE was an impressive 22.5% for the quarter.</p>
          <p>In terms of our overall group insurance, I'm pleased with the 2008 sales season so far.  In general, quote volumes are consistent with or up from 2007 levels.  We have also been through the January 1 renewal season, and are seeing persistency that is well in line with our expectations.</p>
          <p>In retirement and savings, we have won closeout cases both in the U.S. and the U.K.  I'm also particularly pleased with non-medical health where revenue grew 13% and operating earnings increased 49% year-over-year.  This double digit growth was driven by very strong results in disability and dental.  Our organic growth in dental was complemented by our recent acquisition of SafeGuard, which as I mentioned last quarter gives MetLife dental HMO capabilities rounding out our offerings in several key growing local markets.</p>
          <p>Total earnings for Individual Business were relatively flat year-over-year, impacted by lower market performance and an increase in mortality in variable and universal life.  Despite the turbulence in the economy, however, Individual Business generated some key positive results during the quarter.  We increased life insurance sales by a solid 9% year-over-year.  In addition, we collected $3.2 billion in variable annuity deposits and net flows remained positive.  We continued to benefit from having the broadest distribution in the industry and we remain well positioned to continue to capture the growing retirement opportunities in the U.S.</p>
          <p>As you know, we are consistently investing in our operations outside of the United States to ensure that International Business will continue to be strong and a growing contributor to MetLife.  International financial results continue to be impressive.  Premiums, fees, and other revenues grew 25% over the prior year period to reach 1.2 billion and our operating earnings grew 10%.</p>
          <p>In particular, business in Latin America was very strong this quarter.  In Mexico, where we are the market leader, our top line grew by 14%.  We also completed our acquisition of AFORE Actinver during the quarter.  This transaction expands our distribution in Mexico and strengthens our position in the pension business.</p>
          <p>Turning to Asia, the volatile equity markets in Japan had a negative impact on sales which were down 17% in the quarter.  However, sales were up in the rest of the region including South Korea, which grew by 82% due to the significant increase in agents.</p>
          <p>Steve Kandarian will provide you with an update on our investments in a moment.  Briefly I'm pleased with the overall performance of the portfolio.  As we expected, we saw marginally higher level of credit losses due to the current credit environment.  In addition, we also recognized losses on our foreign currency and interest rate hedges.  However, let me remind you that we use hedges to reduce risk and those losses are positively offset by corresponding gains that are recorded elsewhere in the financial statements.  Let me assure you that strategically the portfolio is well positioned to support MetLife's businesses now and in the long run.</p>
          <p>Last month MetLife celebrated its 140th year in business and today our fundamentals continue to be strong.  While the current economic environment may remain volatile, we will continue to benefit from having a diverse mix of related businesses.  Looking ahead, they will continue to serve us well as we remain disciplined focused on the bottom line and committed to providing value for our shareholders, and with that I'll turn it over to Steve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Rob.  I would like to provide you with an update on our portfolio and its performance over the last quarter.  During this period of strong headwinds, our portfolio performed well and we remain comfortable with the overall strength and diversification of our assets.  While recent market volatility impacts the current value of our holdings, it also presents us opportunities to purchase high quality assets at very attractive spreads.</p>
          <p>First let me start with a comment on variable income.  Pre-tax variable income was approximately $20 million higher than plan for Q1.  We experienced higher corporate joint venture and securities lending income versus plan.  While Corporate Joint Ventures continued to perform well, we expect these returns to moderate during the remainder of the year due to tighter credit conditions, volatile equity markets, and general economic conditions.</p>
          <p>Securities lending income was also strong due to the steepening at the front end of the yield curve and higher spreads in the reinvestment portfolio.  We anticipate that securities lending will out perform plan for the remainder of the year.  On the negative side, hedge fund returns were below plan reflecting weak performance for the sector generally.</p>
          <p>Now let me cover investment losses for the quarter.  Gross investment losses as noted on page 34 of the QFS [Quarterly Financial Supplement] were $532 million, in line with the previous three quarters.  Of this amount, only $45 million were credit related sales.  Write-downs were a relatively modest $186 million.  Of this amount, $80 million was related to financial institutions and $24 million to structured finance CDOs.  In addition, there were $43 million of real estate reserve adjustments due to mortgage sales as we continually review and upgrade our portfolio.  The remaining $39 million of write-downs were connected to a variety of fixed maturity and equity securities.  When added together, total credit related losses from sales and write-downs were $231 million before tax or $150 million after tax.  This represents less than 7 basis points on our overall portfolio and is in line with our expectations given current market conditions.</p>
          <p>Losses on derivatives not qualifying for hedge accounting increased this quarter to $580 million.  Virtually all of our derivatives are used for hedging purposes.  The increase in losses on derivatives in Q1 is primarily attributable to our foreign currency and interest rate hedges.  As you know, MetLife invests in a diversified global portfolio.  When we purchase assets denominated in a currency, a foreign currency for the U.S. general account, we generally use foreign currency derivatives to swap the cash flows into U.S. dollars.  As the dollar weakened during the quarter, the decline in the value of these derivatives was reflected on our income statement while the increase in the value of the hedge assets was reflected on our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>In addition we use a variety of interest rate hedges including interest rate swaps, floors, and caps to better match assets and liabilities and protect against interest rate changes.  Among the hedges we employ is an interest rate swap in which we pay a fixed interest rate and receive a floating interest rate.  These swaps convert fixed rate assets into floating rate assets to better match the cash flows of our floating rate liabilities.  The significant drop in short-term rates during Q1 resulted in a net decline in the value of these interest rate swaps.  Just as with our foreign currency hedges, these swaps do not qualify for hedge accounting and the decline in the value of the derivatives is reflected in our income statement while the increase in the value of the hedge assets is reflected on our balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Unrealized losses, which appear on page 36 of the QFS, also increased during the quarter due to spread widening.  For example, spreads in the investment grade corporate bond market have widened about 80 basis points during the quarter.  In addition, spreads in other asset classes such as structured finance widened even more dramatically often beyond what the underlying fundamentals would suggest.  While this caused our unrealized loss position to increase on current holding, it also presents opportunities to purchase assets we believe are relatively safe even during economic downturns at attractive spreads.</p>
          <p>Finally I'd like to briefly discuss our commercial mortgage holdings.  We owned approximately $18.6 billion of commercial mortgage backed securities at March 31st.  Based upon our fundamental underwriting analysis, our strategy has been to focus on AAA rated securities from the 2005 and earlier vintages.  Overall, 95% of our CMBS portfolio is rated AA or AAA, and approximately 75% of our holdings are from the 2005 and earlier vintages which benefit from better underwriting and price appreciation.  We remain comfortable with the quality of these holdings.</p>
          <p>In addition to CMBS, we also hold approximately $36 billion of commercial mortgage whole loans originated by MetLife's real estate department.  We view this origination capability as a competitive advantage for us.  The average loan to value of this portfolio is approximately 55% and only 6% of the portfolio has a loan to value of 75% or greater.  There continues to be limited new issuance in the CMBS market.  This is providing us with attractive opportunities to make low leverage, high spread loans on any properties in any markets.</p>
          <p>So in summary, our risk management efforts and fundamental analysis approach have positioned us well for the current economic environment.  With that, I will turn the call over to Bill Wheeler.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Steve and good morning everybody.  MetLife reported $1.52 of operating earnings per share for the first quarter, which was a 7.8 increase over the first quarter of last year.  This morning I will walk you through our financial results and point out some highlights as well as some unusual items which occurred during the quarter.</p>
          <p>We had top line revenues, which we define as premiums, fees, and other income, of 9.4 billion, a record.  This represents an increase of 11.5% over the first quarter of 2007.  Institutional had a strong quarter with revenue growth of 13.7% year-over-year. All three product areas in Institutional: group life, non-medical health, and retirement savings had excellent growth.</p>
          <p>International's revenue grew by 24.6% over the year ago period.  Foreign exchange rates positively affected revenue growth by approximately 6 points, excluding the currency impact, international revenues grew by about 19% over the year ago period with stronger annuity &#x2013; led by stronger annuity sales in Chile.</p>
          <p>Turning to our operating margins let's start with our underwriting results.  Underwriting experience was somewhat mixed this quarter.  We had some very good results and also some weaker areas among our various product lines.  In Institutional, group life mortality of 93.8% was within our guidance range of 91% to 95%.  In non-medical health and other, group disability's morbidity ratio improved to 80.6% for the quarter, well below our target range of 89 to 94.  This strong result was not due to an unusual reserve release, but instead was primary caused by favorable disability recoveries.  We had much higher than normal mortality experience in both our reinsurance business which is RGA [Reinsurance Group of America] and in Individual.  Individual's mortality ratio of 93.4% was driven mainly by higher frequency in older blocks as opposed to high life cases.</p>
          <p>Turning to Auto &amp; Home, the combined ratio including catastrophes was 90.8%.  Included in this result is a prior accident year reserve release of $23 million after tax compared to a $30 million after tax release in the prior year period.  Catastrophe losses for the quarter were 5 million after tax higher than plan.</p>
          <p>Moving to investment spreads, in general investment spreads were good this quarter.  Variable investment income was approximately $13 million after DAC, tax, and other offsets or 2 cents per share higher than our baseline plan.  But the performance of certain variable income asset classes was mixed as Steve just explained.  Obviously, the market environment continues to be volatile, but we feel that our variable investment income plan is still appropriate.  The steep drop in short-term interest rates caused our investment margins in Group Life and retirement savings to be strong, and you can see that in the reported spreads.  However, the weak equity market significantly affected the profitability of our variable annuity business.  In our plan we assumed that equity markets increased by 5% during the year.  In the first quarter the S&amp;P 500 declined by about 10%, which is a swing of 15 points versus plan.  Our rule of thumb is that each 1% move in the S&amp;P 500 is worth a penny a share over the course of the year.  We estimate that the decline in the equity markets cost us 6 cents per share versus plan this quarter.  And unless equity markets improve, there will be a continuing drag on earnings versus plan for the remainder of the year.  But of course the market is up so far this quarter.</p>
          <p>Moving to expenses, our overall expense levels came down as we anticipated.  If you recall, we projected an expense ratio of 28 to 29% in 2008.  Our expense ratio in the first quarter was 28.1%, which was very good.</p>
          <p>Turning to our bottom line results, we earned 1.1 billion in operating income or $1.52 per share, representing a 7.8% increase in operating EPS over the first quarter of last year.</p>
          <p>With regard to investment gains and losses, in the first quarter we had net realized investment losses of 560 million after tax.  Steve just gave a good explanation of what's in that number.  The only thing I would like to add is that included in the net realized loss amount was the January 1st, 2008, impact of adopting FAS 157 which was $19 million net of income tax.</p>
          <p>Our preliminary statutory operating earnings are approximately $600 million this quarter, a timing difference relating to the tax deductibility of policyholder dividends reduced statutory operating income by approximately $110 million this quarter.  Total statutory capital at March 31st is approximately 20.9 billion.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter, MetLife repurchased approximately 20.4 million shares of common stock at an aggregate cost of 1.25 billion under both accelerated share repurchase agreements and open market purchases.  At March 31st, 2008, MetLife had 260.7 million remaining on its existing share repurchase authorization, but in April of 2008, an additional 1 billion share repurchase authorization was approved by the board.  So in summary, this was a solid quarter, and obviously a good start for MetLife in 2008, and with that, let me turn it back over to the operator so we can take your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. And our first question will come from Jimmy Bhullar [JPMorgan].  One moment, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you.  I have a couple of questions.  The first one is on your outlook for variable investment income, you mentioned you feel okay for the rest of the year, but if you can talk about dynamics; in securities lending, the margin is picking up, is that enough to offset a potential for a no improvement in private equity for the rest of the year?</p>
          <p>And then the second question that I have is on your retirement and savings business, on spreads, were relatively good this quarter despite the fact that variable investment income was slightly short of plan in that segment, and most of that was driven by I think a 45 basis points sequential decline in crediting rate.  I'm assuming that that would sustain if interest rates remain where they are right now, but if you could talk about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jimmy, I'll talk the variable income question.  Steve here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi.  Our view is that our guidance still is pretty good guidance going forward.  Obviously it's hard to predict variable income, that's why we call it variable, but as we look at the different components, securities lending appears to have some pretty good wind to its back for the rest of the year.  Just given the shape of the yield curve which was actually hurting us last year now has really turned around and is helping us.  Our liability costs have gone way down in that program, given high spreads, reinvestment rates are attractive compared to liability costs for us, so we think that's going to perform well for the remaining three quarters of the year.</p>
          <p>We have been talking about CJV [Corporate Joint Venture] income being extremely high in the past, and questioning whether that would continue.  We had a pretty good quarter here still in Q1 of '08, but we do have some visibility in terms of how these markets work, and we think that the remainder of the year will probably be a lot tougher for CJV income.  A lot of that what they do in terms of realizing gains is re-capping deals, which right now is pretty hard to do in this marketplace with the credit problems; selling companies to others who are leveraging up, and that's hard to do as well. So, I think that CJV income is likely to tail off here for a period of time and we think the offset from sec lending will pretty much neutralize that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jimmy, it's Bill Mullaney.  With regard to your question on spreads, you will recall at Investor Day for R&amp;S [Retirement &amp; Savings], we said that we have spreads between 115 and 130 bps.  This quarter we came in at 151.  My expectation for the balance of the year is that we should be coming in somewhere between 130 and 150 basis points, so I would say we're more sustainable in terms of where our spreads are than what we had originally said we would be at Investor Day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Darin Arita [Deutsche Bank].  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.  Question again on the securities lending income.  To what extent would you say this is the normal level of income you would expect to earn given an upward sloping yield curve at the short end, and also are you buying hedges to protect this income should the yield curve flatten?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's hard to say what's kind of normal in sec lending, because there are different components to how you make money.  The positive right now is not just the upward sloping curve but also the spread levels, which are very high.  You're seeing those spread levels impact other things negatively to us, at least in the reported balance sheet basis we talked about that, but certainly providing us good opportunities to buy safe assets at very attractive spreads.  So as long as those spreads remain very wide, we're going to have very, very strong sec lending.  But I would say that it's hard to know what happens with spreads over the course of the year, and overall we think the program is going to be attractive in terms of income for the remainder of the year.</p>
          <p>We do put on hedges.  We pretty much run the program with trying to cut off if you will some of the down side risk to the program.  When you do that, you do lop off some of the upside gain during certain periods. So yes, we do have hedges on.  They remain in place.  We have caps, we have floors, we have interest rate swaps.  We have reduced the amount of interest rate swaps for strategic reasons just given what our view is of rates right now, but we still have swaps in place.  So the program is hedged, it runs kind of if you will within some band.  There is variability within that band but we do lop off the bottoms and the tops with our hedges.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And how far out is it hedged?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're asking how far out the hedges go?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There are a variety of hedges that go up through early 2010, I believe, but it depends on the specific kinds of hedges we're talking about.  There is some caps, floors, and swaps, and it's not one for each of those three categories.  It's a whole series of these hedges that we put in place over a period of time. So they kind of roll off and we put more on as time goes on, so we put hedges on in Q1 for example that didn't exist when we last talked to you.  And some of the others have rolled off or been sold.  It's kind of an ongoing dynamic process that we engage in with our hedges.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.  Great.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question will come from the line of Tammy Kravec with Banc of America.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Good morning.  Couple of questions.  First on your hedging program, obviously you had a pretty big test in the first quarter with the equity market decline.  Can you talk about how you feel your program is performing against your guaranteed liability?</p>
          <p>And my second question is on Japan and what you're seeing there in terms of competition.  Hartford made some commentary about the competitive environment being pretty intense, and I'm also curious whether you think FIEL [Financial Instruments and Exchange Law] has already played through there, or whether you would expect some more effects from that?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tamara, it's Bill.  I'll start with the variable annuity hedge program.  It worked well again this quarter.  And we obviously listen to what our peers say, and some of them seem to be having some difficulty.  We think our program works well, we think we do it right, we spent a lot of money investing in the technology to make sure we do it right, and so that continues to work well even and you're right I think this quarter was a very good challenge, and it continued to perform.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are you fully hedged with this program?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That's always a difficult question to answer given the nature of some of the riders we write.  We're -- we do hedge all three Greeks, and we are hedged given sort of the accounting that we have on the way our riders work.  We make sure we are hedged to offset that as best we can, so we're as fully hedged as we think we really can be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tamara, hi, it's Bill Toppeta.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Bill.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, how are you?  On the Japan question, I would say of course the Japanese annuity, individual annuity market is a competitive market.  There is no question about that, having said that, I think that we are doing quite well in the competitive environment.  I have some preliminary results on the bank channel which tell me that for the first quarter, we were second in variable annuity sales to Tokyo Marine and second in fixed annuity sales to Alico, so even though the market is down certainly in the variable area, we are down consistent with the market, not more than that, but consistent with the market.  So it is a challenging market, but I think that part of that of course is related to the performance of the equity markets in the country.</p>
          <p>As far as FIEL is concerned, I would say the effects are wearing off.  I think things have gotten considerably better in this quarter, and I would expect that as we go through the remainder of the year, those effects will pretty well be a non factor as far as we're concerned.  Is that okay?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  That's great, thank you.  And I also wanted to ask about Personal Auto &amp; Home, and just your general commentary on pricing and loss cost trends and what you're seeing in frequency and severity in that business?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is Bill Moore, Tamara.  Yeah, I think clearly and I'll talk about overall pricing now, we feel pretty strongly that we are closer to the end of the soft market cycle than we are the beginning, and one of the reasons for that is that as you look at some of the margins of the companies and where they are in terms of their combined ratio, we're starting to see rate increase activity of more than we are decreases.  Even for us at MetLife Auto &amp; Home, about 70% of our rate activity in the first quarter was for rate increases versus a significantly more reduced number last year.</p>
          <p>In terms of the pricing cycle, the loss cost, yeah, our expectations in loss costs will remain in the low single digits.  That's what we're seeing for us, and that's just pure frequency and severities.  And we're offsetting that as you know if you look and followed our Investor Day guidance, we're mitigating that because of some initiatives we put in place to reduce our expenses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, great.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>And the next question will come from the line of Colin Devine with Citigroup.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  I'm going to spare Steve the questions and I think I'll focus on some of the others.  First for Lisa; and I don't think there is any way to sugarcoat the variable annuity sales being a disappointment this quarter.  They're certainly much weaker than several of your leading competitors.  What happened there?  Is it &#x2013; one quarter is not a trend.  Are there some new features coming out to sort of get these things reinvigorated?  Maybe you can tell us what was behind the disappointment?</p>
          <p>On the Institutional side, I was wondering if you have seen any pickup in quoting activity on pension closeouts since so many large corporate plans froze at the end of last year?</p>
          <p>And then finally for Bill, you just made a comment on the hedge program that the accounting is hedged.  And I just wondered if we might clarify that?  Is your hedge program hedging the economics of these living benefits, or is it instead just hedging the GAAP results?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Why don't I start with the variable annuity sales?  Our variable annuity sales compared to the industry were actually really very credible.  Our deposits were down 4% year-over-year, and if you look at the VaR's preliminary results the industry is down about 10% year-over-year, so we compared really pretty favorably.  We do see that our variable annuity sales are tied to what is going on in the equity markets, and that is particularly true in the third party channel where there has also been a lot of change particularly in the wire houses.</p>
          <p>Having said that, we are retaining the business that we have on the books, and we also if you saw the press release, we also announced some enhancements and changes to our variable annuity product line just this past Monday, and there's a lot of excitement in the marketplace around that.  We can tell that by the number of requests that we're getting for kits, and of course as with any change, it takes a while to get those changes baked in, but we're satisfied with our quarter and we are optimistic going forward given some timing in the market and some of the new features and products that we have.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Are those features approved in New York?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The -- we have our new LWG [Lifetime Withdrawal Guarantee] is approved in 42 states.  It is not approved in New York yet, and we also have changes to our investment portfolio where we -- where we have introduced American Funds which is going over really well.  Oppenheimer Funds as well, and some changes to our GMIB plus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Lisa.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Colin, it's Bill Mullaney.  Let me spend a minute talking about what's going on in the pension closeout market.  I think you saw from our results in R&amp;S this quarter that our revenues were up 59%.  That was driven primarily by closeout sales in the first quarter.  We did over $250 million of closeouts, which were reflected in that number.  In terms of the overall market, you're right that there were more plans that froze as of the end of the year.  One of the things that we're watching closely though is the overall funding status of those plans. Equity markets have been down fairly significantly, and so one of the things that needs to be in place in order to be able to engage in a pension closeout is the plan either needs to be funded completely or the employer needs to be able to put up some additional money to be able to make the closeout work.  So that's something that we're watching.  I would say that our pipeline for closeout activity continues to be good.  We talked in Investor Day about having a billion dollars in our plan in terms of pension closeouts, and right now we're optimistic that we're going to be able to achieve that objective.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and finally on our variable annuity hedging program, we have a variety of riders for our variable annuities.  Sometimes it's more of a withdrawal benefit, sometimes it's a GMIB or interest rate benefit, and interestingly or not interestingly, the accounting of those is different, and so when a GMIB liability is put on or we have guarantees, the accounting liability we would say is not -- does not accurately reflect the overall economic liability.  So we're left with a dilemma.  Do we match -- do we hedge to the accounting, or do we hedge to the economic or do we try to somehow bridge the gap?  And the reality is we try to bridge the gap because if we -- the problem is of course if we actually hedge to the economic, that would create an incredible amount of volatility in our reported GAAP statements.</p>
          <p>So we have a baseline hedging program which hedges the accounting liability on GMIB which is our biggest rider, but we also buy a lot of long dated puts opportunistically to try to get to the economic liability as well, and so that is sort of -- that's how we manage it, Colin, if you will.  But that's why I always hesitate to say well you're fully economically hedged, well not entirely on GMIB we're not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay then, Bill, maybe the real question then is not how the accounting optics of the hedge program performed during the quarter, but really how did the economics perform?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we actually think they performed fine, and when we look at where our liability account balances are and in terms of where the -- and in terms of our separate accounts guarantee exposure, we think it's very manageable.  The long dated puts we have in place are helping us a lot here, so the accounting works, yes, but the long-dated puts work as well.  I'm sorry, so <mark type="inaudible" /> is going to add something here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry; I was trying to whisper something to Bill.  As part of our overall risk management on the variable annuity riders, we also engage in reinsurance and we have a substantial amount of reinsurance on some of our income benefit riders as well as the riskier elements of our guaranteed minimum death benefits, particularly the ones that have ratchet features on them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we have done is we have executed not with traditional reinsurers but with really investment banks.  We have introduced reinsurance agreements, which also sort of bridges this problem between accounting and economic liability if you will, and so &#x2013; through reinsurance arrangements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  And we have a question then from the line of Nigel Dally with Morgan Stanley.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you good morning.  First on your investment portfolio, as you mentioned in your prepared remarks, the gross unrealized losses rose substantially to 8.8 billion.  Now, I understand most of that was spread widening in high quality investments but it also seems like you're now sitting on 2.7 billion of losses that are 20% or more below water.  I was hoping you could review with us your impairment policies.  Do you use a bright line test, and if so if these bonds remain underwater over the next quarter, will you be forced to take some impairments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nigel, it is Steve.  Yes, the bucket for 20% or more less than 6 months is now about 2.6 billion in bonds.  A lot of that obviously is based upon the &#x2013; or virtually all of it is based upon the spread widening.  Interest rates have come down which increased the value of the bonds while the spreads have widened more than interest rates have come down.  Now, we have seen since quarter end a reversal to some degree of those spreads and interest rates both.</p>
          <p>So the question will be does this remain in place for six months first of all, this very broad widening of spreads you have seen across the entire market, and my guess is you'll see some moderation of that spread widening, and things will fall out of that bucket.  We looked at parts of that bucket already just to see where things moved in one month, and about 20% of at least some of the riskier assets have fallen out of that bucket.</p>
          <p>Now, who knows what happens over the next five or six months.  These securities that show up for March 31st, 2008 really got there in the month of March, so that's basically their first month of a six-month general rule of thumb that people use in terms of looking at things like impairments, and I probably should talk a little bit about that as well, the impairing policy.</p>
          <p>The basic rule of thumb that we use is especially for fixed income securities is to look at what has been 20% under water for six months.  We look at whether we intend and have the ability to hold those securities to recovery, and we look at the contractual cash flows and say are we still receiving all of our contractual cash flows, are we likely to continue receiving all those contractual cash flows based upon the structures we buy and the mortgage backed security world or the bonds we buy in the corporate bond world.  Obviously we look at the fundamentals, is the company able to pay us back, what is their status and so on.</p>
          <p>So a lot of what you see in some of these buckets are securities that in many cases are issued by companies with single-A, AA ratings, and we have seen some real spread widening in certain categories of the marketplace, so our gut is that these are money good securities in the vast majority of cases, but we will reassess things as time goes on, and as new information is provided to us, and we will look at things six months out and take a hard look at those impairments.</p>
          <p>Now, let me just add one more thing because I think it's important for people to understand.  If we were to go and be let's say ultra conservative and start writing things off that we really thought were money good securities, that then reverts back into our income in future months and years, and one could look at that and say well is that really a fair representation of what the true accounting should be and take a one-time hit on securities you think really are money good and there is no reason to really write down, and then take it back into income over time, so it's a balancing act.  We don't want to impair securities that we really think are money good.  On the other hand, we don't wait six months if we think a security really is not going to be money good. Some of the impairments we talked about today in our remarks were not after six months or after one month when we got some news that suggested to us that we should take a hard look at it and we did impair certain securities very quickly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then second question, on capital.  It seems like you've still got significant excess capital in holding company liquidity. At Investor Day you commented to the 750 million of buyback beyond that necessary to offset the extra units is what you were targeting.  What you did in the quarter effectively offset the equity units so is 750 million still a good estimate for the remainder of the year, or is there potential for that number to move higher given that you haven't been hit by many of the issues that have impacted many of your peers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Nigel, yeah, you're right, we did do a lot of buyback activity in the first part of the year, and just sort of coincidentally it's not on purpose we bought back 20 million shares and that's roughly the amount of the convert, the shares that will come out of the convert in the third quarter.  So, yeah, you would say, well, you must have 750 to go, and our philosophy is we made a commitment on Investor Day regarding buyback activity, and that's what we're going to honor, and when we get to that point, then we'll see.  I mean, I guess obviously there's a lot of turmoil out there and maybe there will be an acquisition we'll want to do.  We're just going to be flexible.  We'll see where we're at, and then decide what we want to do, and it also somewhat depends on the stock price.  The reason we bought so much stock back in the first quarter is we were being very opportunistic.  The stock spent a lot of time in the 50s in the first quarter, and our attitude is that's a pretty big buying signal, so we bought back about as aggressively as we possibly could to get it cheap, so we'll just have to see how -- I guess my answer is yes we do have a lot of dry powder even after this buyback activity, and we'll see -- we'll just have to stay flexible about what we do in the latter part of the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's great.  Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  We do a question from Suneet Kamath with Sanford Bernstein.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Two questions.  First on the other than temporary impairment, it seems like we're hearing different approaches across companies, and I'm just wondering why that is?  Is that company specific interpretation of GAAP accounting, or is it the auditors, just any thoughts on that?</p>
          <p>And then second, in terms of your expense control, obviously you're at the lower end of the expense ratio target for the year.  How should we think about that trending over the balance of the year?  Do you expect to pop back up?  Are there any investment initiatives that you have in place that maybe were light in the first quarter or conversely are there additional opportunities to save costs and perhaps drop below that 28%?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So let's start with the accounting.  I'm probably not qualified to answer this question.  I don't know what really &#x2013; obviously we all listen to the same earnings calls about what some of our peers are doing.  We obviously have a very different approach. I guess my feel &#x2013; and I don't think we're inconsistent with where our outside auditors are in terms of what we need to &#x2013; what we should be doing regarding OTTI.  So I have a hard time explaining kind of what some of our peers' motivation is.  I don't &#x2013; we don't think that's really appropriate.  We think that you do need to exercise &#x2013; you should not have a bright line test.  You need to exercise judgment about whether or not these securities are really money good or not, and because we think that's the fairest representation of what's really going on in the company.  And we don't &#x2013; so the idea of I'll take a capital loss and then it will just accrete back into earnings over time, that strikes me as financial engineering not necessarily good accounting.  So I guess, I mean, that's sort of I guess our take, but again I'm sure I'm completely unqualified, and somebody will explain to me I'm wrong, but obviously what we think we're doing is the proper interpretation, and also is I think our outside auditors would agree with us.  So I don't know if that helps.</p>
          <p>The second thing about expenses, yeah, it was a good number this quarter.  First quarter often is a good number for us for a variety of reasons.  I think we're still basically in my mind on our plan number which is 28 to 29% is what we said.  That's a substantial drop from last year's number which I think ended up at about 30.5, so we're &#x2013; so we have sort of ratcheted down sort of spending levels this year already.  Is it possible to move more, yeah, probably.  But that's a decision we'll obviously be monitoring over the course of the year.  Obviously some of the spending we're doing we're trying to build growth for the future, and so that's a little bit about our philosophy there.  So we'll clearly &#x2013; yeah, expense levels we can bring them down further if we thought it was appropriate, but right now I think we're tracking well on plan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, maybe just one quick follow-up on the OTTIs.  I guess given the current environment I have been hearing more &#x2013; seeing more analysis done on book value inclusive of AOCI.  I know that you show it both ways, but can you just confirm that the rating agencies when they look at your say leverage ratios and those sorts of things, do they use book value including AOCI, or do they exclude it?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>They exclude AOCI in terms of calculating leverage ratios, but &#x2013; and you're right, I have noticed too, this quarter people are now are focused on book value with AOCI.  The one thing you've always got to keep in mind here is AOCI is a mark-to-market of our assets or most of our assets of our investment portfolio.  It is not marking the liabilities.  Okay?  The liabilities are affected by interest rates just the same way the assets are, okay?  So if we mark the &#x2013; and so if you &#x2013; so I still think I would probably exclude all those AOCI.  In terms of looking at straight book value in terms of what's really going on, because obviously if you're only marking one side of the balance sheet, I think you're getting a little distorted picture, so that's important why we show it both ways.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, and we have a question then from the line of Steven Schwartz with Raymond James.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning, everybody.  Just for what it's worth, I totally agree on the AOCI comment.</p>
          <p>Lisa, I wanted to talk about the annuities.  Colin touched on that, but what is your thought here?  I mean, we have seen the industry is down.  There was some thought that maybe the various riders would protect that part of the annuity industry from market downturns.  I don't think we have really seen that.  Can you kind of comment on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean, I think that the market downturn has -- you know, the resulting impact is a temporary dip, and that's what we have all seen in the marketplace, and frankly that's what we have experienced some of ourselves.  Having said that, you know, we really believe that now more than ever is the time when people are looking for guarantees, and they want our guarantees, and so it's not ever going to be a product or a rider in and of itself that is going to make the difference, but really the whole package.  And that's what we're seeing; and so, yes, while we have some of our new products and features that are coming out, it's the content of what they are that are going to make a difference, so when you look at features like age banding and American Funds, they give people more confidence, and so I think it's &#x2013; I think it's temporary, and as I said before, fortunately we faired better than most of the industry this quarter in our variable annuity sales, and it's the business that we're keeping that we feel &#x2013; we feel especially good about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.  And can we touch on the adverse mortality in VUL?  Maybe flesh that out a bit.  You said it was older blocks of business which I think is consistent with what RGA said if I remember correctly, but can you flesh that out?  RGA mentioned on its call that they hadn't seen anything adverse so far during the second quarter.  Also maybe if you just flesh it out, there was more January and that's what affected it and you didn't see it in February or March or maybe vice versa if we can just get some sense?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me just start, and then I'm sure that <mark type="inaudible" /> or Bill will pick up.  In terms of our adverse mortality, we typically see Q1 as more adverse than any other quarter, and so again we saw that, and yes, it was &#x2013; it was especially -- it was especially worse than we're used to, but as I said, always Q1 we have the worst mortality.  Having said that, it is older blocks of business, business that has been on our books for quite some time.  It's across the board, so it's not in &#x2013; while it's in UL, it's not in any one particular channel, so whether it's MetLife or the old Gen Am block of business, New England Financial, it's really across the board.  It's at all safe amounts, and so it's not the older ages that are jumping out.  The other comment that I would make is that what is consistent is the mortality, those blocks, there was less reinsurance, and so that's what you're seeing the effect of.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll just &#x2013; <mark type="inaudible" /> .  I'll just add one thing, Steven.  I think Lisa basically covered all the points, but we do see the first quarter blip that she mentioned and we do see volatility quarter to quarter, and we have taken a look at recent history in terms of that volatility and we're comfortable that it's still within our expected ranges so we really think it's just a first quarter phenomenon that we're seeing in the industry as well as the lack of reinsurance on specific policies this quarter, which also moves around from quarter to quarter, and it was also still within our acceptable bands.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> , could you point to any causes of death, flu maybe, something like that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Not specifically, no.  There has been some speculation about that, since it's been an industry wide phenomenon, but we haven't seen anything specific yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  Our next question comes to the line of Tom Gallagher with Credit Suisse.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.  First just a follow-up I guess more philosophical on the AOCI question.  Bill, I agree with you in terms of the accounting disconnect between the mark on assets versus liabilities.  I think that's particularly true when it's due to interest rate swings.  Do you think that still applies though when we're in an environment where interest rates decline and your book value still goes down because of widening credit spreads?  That's my first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, you're right, base interest rates declined, but obviously credit spreads have gone up, and that's most of the reason why &#x2013; that's most of the reason why our &#x2013; we have had the effect our AOCI has gone negative and stuff like that, so I should &#x2013; we shouldn't even go here in terms of accounting discussion, but all of your employers are obviously marking to market more and more of their liabilities which means they're marking to market their debt.  Because our credit spreads and obviously every financial institutions credit spreads have also gapped out, and so people are marking them in certain cases people are marking to market their liabilities and of course recording big gains.</p>
          <p>I don't know.  I'm not sure what the answer is to deal with that.  I mean, obviously that seems like an odd distortion too, where if our creditworthiness seems to improve, therefore we're going to have a loss on our income statement.  So I think it's without getting too philosophical about AOCI, I guess I sort of feel like, look, you'll have market volatility.  We're obviously having a lot of market volatility right now.  I think if you want to get a clear picture of what is really happening in our book value, I think you have to look beyond that, right, because spreads will tighten.  They have already tightened this quarter, and I think obviously some spreads are really &#x2013; credit spreads are at really historically wide numbers and we know they'll tighten in, and so you have to kind of look at it on a normalized basis.  So that's a little bit why I would say my advice would be you've got to look beyond AOCI.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Fair enough.  On that comment you made about spreads tightening so far this quarter, that was sort of my follow-up.  I know part of the sec lending strength has been driven by slope of the curve, part has been wider credit spreads.  Now that it seems like corporate spreads are tightening by the day here so far this quarter, is that &#x2013; does that potentially start to at least take some of the steam out of the sec lending spreads, or have we gotten wide enough or steep enough on the yield curve side where we still have good momentum?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tom, it's Steve.  I think certainly for 2008 which is what I was talking about, we still have a very favorable environment, meaning we own securities that go out over a year.  Some are floating rate, but some are fixed, and certainly these fixed rate assets that we have purchased over the last quarter or two have very attractive spreads are locked in now for that period of time.  So again for 2008, I feel pretty good about the lumpy performance of that portfolio.  Over time, obviously those spreads will bounce around, and it will have an impact, and again that's why we call it variable income.</p>
          <p>If I can just go back for one second on your AOCI comment, if you look back for example back in the first quarter of 2007, we had a very large unrealized gain in our books, which again goes through AOCI, and that in some ways wasn't real either and that's why we really don't focus on that all the time, because that was simply spreads coming into historically tight levels.  We weren't going to sell those securities.  They were basically defeasing liabilities.  We are going to hold them to maturity in most cases, and the same is in the reverse here.  We're seeing some real spread widening, we're seeing certain sectors like Alt-A where we hold over $5 billion of Alt-A securities, 84% of what we own is enhanced AAA, super senior AAA, the chance of those things defaulting are so remote it's minuscule, yet those things are bouncing around all over the place in terms of the impact on unrealized losses.  It's nearly $700 million of unrealized losses on securities that to bust you'd have to go into a worse decline of real estate than the depression.  So how valuable is this number?  I think it's worth looking at, but I think you have to look through it and understand what's behind it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  And our next question then comes from the line of Andrew Kligerman with UBS.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks.  Bill, I think maybe a month or two ago, there was some concern that maybe auditors might require that MetLife take a hit on variable investment income if they became aware of losses right away as opposed to the roughly two quarter lag on private equity and other asset classes.  In this quarter, did you accelerate any charges relative to the lag?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, you were breaking out a little bit Andrew, but I think I got your question which had to do with the timing of our revenue recognition in the private equity portfolio, and let me just take a step back on this for everybody. If any of you invest in private equity funds then you know you have to file your income taxes late, right, because it takes a while to get your results from the fund and we have the same problem on a bigger scale. Private equity fund mark-to-markets or returns take a while, and there are certainly a group of funds and many of them are international funds we're in where we &#x2013; it takes &#x2013; we don't get the fund results until two quarters effectively two quarters after the period, the time period they're marking, so we have this lag problem.  Now, some we get faster, but we have sort of made a rule of thumb about we don't try to cherry pick which ones we report faster or which ones we delay, so that is why we have this lag problem.</p>
          <p>Lag problems are bad.  Okay?  You shouldn't &#x2013; you should try to avoid them as much as possible, but we're trying to what we're trying to do now is see if we can get some of our general partners or GPs to try to give us our financial results faster, so that we can speed up our reporting of those numbers, and that's really where our focus is.  So the answer is, no, we didn't accelerate anything this quarter, but it remains a concern in terms of can we speed up the reporting of these numbers.</p>
          <p>By the way, I should just clarify here, on about half the private equity portfolio, we have the sort of lag issue.  On the other half we just record the income when it comes into us as cash.  So that's sort of a good way to think about it, which is I think as timely as we can make it.  So that -- so, no, we didn't speed up &#x2013; we ended up not speeding up any reporting of returns this quarter, and so we do have this lag issue, which sort of means of course that that's why we have continued to sort of have good results even kind of this first quarter a little bit.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Got it.  And just out of curiosity, it sounds like your OTTI methodology makes a lot of sense, but let's say you were very much by the book more than 20% unrealized loss over 6 months more than a 50% unrealized loss over a three-month period, do you think that your OTTI number would have been materially larger and maybe percentage wise or any thoughts around that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, and it wouldn't -- I don't think it would have been materially larger because look at the &#x2013; the way to show that is look at the aging schedule in our QFS on page 36, and what you'll see is that really until very recently, the numbers that were we had virtually no securities lower than 20% mark.  Okay?  That number is a very modest number two quarters ago.  It crept up a little bit last quarter and then obviously got bigger this quarter, so I think the answer is no, I don't think it would have been very different this quarter.</p>
          <p>But if we did -- and by the way, I don't like the expression "by the book."  If we went by the book.  The book -- we think we're going by the book.  So if we had a different methodology and a bright line test, which we don't, no, I don't think the difference this quarter would have been very much different.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent.  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  And we have a question then from the line of Eric Berg with Lehman Brothers.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.  Good morning.  Bill, continuing -- Bill or Steve, continuing on the issue of other than temporary impairments, consider a case where a bond has been valued in the marketplace for less than its amortized cost, a significant discount, say trading at 60% of cost or 70% of cost for an extended period, and you decide not to impair the security because in your analyst view, it's money good to use your expression.  What is typically &#x2013; if there is a typical case, what is your best sense of what is going on in the situation like that?  In other words, how could it be that your guy is saying you're going to get paid fully and millions of investors who comprise the market are saying basically, "No, you're not," and you say you're right?  Obviously you can cannot get into the heads of investors, but as best as you can sort of generalize, why is it the case that you're sort of right and the rest of the market is wrong about the value of the bonds?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Eric, it's Steve.  I think from a financial theory point of view, you make a good point, which is in a perfect market, these things would trade reflecting true risk.  At the same time if you pick up the papers, and you read about investment bank melting down, major money center banks getting multibillion dollar infusions of capital because of problems in their balance sheet, and you're seeing these major financial institutions as well as hedge funds unwinding a tremendous amount of leverage has built up over the last three or four years and in certain markets this is resulting in some real supply and demand imbalances and we believe they're going to be relatively temporary imbalances and things will go back and trade closer to true risk reward kinds of tradeoffs that you are talking about, but in the meantime, you're seeing things that are trading at prices that are hard to justify from a fundamental perspective.</p>
          <p>That's why I made a couple comments in my prepared remarks about seeing some very attractive opportunities especially in the AAA segment of various asset classes that we invest in, and why we're buying into some of those asset classes now because we're seeing these imbalances from the supply and demand problems floating through to spreads that you just can't make sense of, so to us that's a buying opportunity on the one hand.  On the other hand we see things like I talked about Alt-A where they're kind of bulletproof structures at the super senior level where you have subordination levels at 12% and historical highs of 1 or 2% losses, and if you stress that to 4 or 5%, you don't get close to busting the structure of 12, and you're saying this is people doing great leverage unwind and there is no one on the buying side, so there's a few money cash investors out there like insurance companies that are coming in and swooping up some of these assets at attractive spreads, but for a period of time you're seeing unusually wide spreads.</p>
          <p>As we mentioned, April has seen some of these spreads come back in &#x2013; not as far as they went out but still come in to some degree, and we think the market eventually will get to a point where price -- the price of risk will be properly priced.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I had one follow-up question.  It will be my final question related to the private equity partnerships.  I noticed that in the quarter the yield on the asset class captioned "equity securities and other limited partnerships" fell by more than half from the December quarter to it looks like about 7% from 16%.  So initially looking at these numbers, I had thought that you already were experiencing a sharp, sharp decline in private equity returns, but I just heard Bill say that you had a pretty good quarter still, so maybe you can reconcile what would appear to be a sharp -- the difference, a sharp decline in yields on the one hand, with the idea that you had a fairly respectable quarter still in private equity returns.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We had an unusually strong quarter in Q4 of 2007, sort of off the charts.  It was like a 40% kind of return, and we have been signaling that some of these returns just weren't going to hold up.  So basically we saw things kind of falling off here.  Bill was mentioning the equity method accounting on private equity and for the year 2007 we had these unusually high returns.  There is a lag effect.  And now we're seeing the returns go back to much more moderate levels but still in this case, slightly above plan.</p>
          <p>So what Bill was referring to and I was referring to in my remarks was that we slightly outperformed our plan for 2008, and I should mention that our 2008 plan did take into account our view that this sector would moderate in terms of performance.  At the same time you didn't see our overall guidance go down for variable income because we thought sec lending would do better, which it has.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have some follow-up questions, but I'll fellow up with Conor.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  And our last question this morning comes from the line of John Hall with Wachovia.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thank you very much.  I just want to talk briefly about the variable income again, but from the context of the changing mix.  From the comments I guess the sense is that over the next year, we're going to see it coming from different buckets, and I'm just wondering how that is going to affect the different business units?  Are there some units that are more heavily invested in certain asset classes and are going to see their earnings as a result go down and others go up, and if you can just address that, and then I have one quick follow-up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>John, I'll take that, I guess.  Yeah, it will change how variable income shows up in our business lines a little bit, but I'll be honest, off the top of my head, I couldn't say which ones will go up and down. But it's not dramatic, let me put it that way.  It might swing it 5, 10 million bucks in any given quarter for a given business line, but it won't be dramatic, but it will move it around a little bit and obviously sometimes it moves it around this quarter.  For instance, non-medical health which has a little bit of private equity returns had a relatively poor quarter because they weren't in the right funds, so that already happened a little bit we get that kind of noise.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, and then just finally, Bill, you reminded us that you've got some reinsurance agreements out there on the variable annuities.  I was just wondering if you can share the amount that you passed on to reinsurers in the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I can't.  I can't do that off the top of my head.  We'll have to get back to you on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But is it a material type of number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, is it material?  No, the contracts are not necessarily material, but what they are is they're important to variable annuities in terms of the liability that we're pushing off.  <mark type="inaudible" /> will give you a little color here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The two types of variable annuity riders which are not embedded derivatives involve our income benefit riders and our guaranteed minimum death benefits.  We have roughly half of our GMIB in force that is not part of direct hedging program reinsured, and in terms of the GMDB, as I mentioned, it's the riskier one, so it's a smaller percentage, but it's a high amount of the vega risk that is reinsured.  Just another point I didn't make before, which maybe I'll make now is that when you hear about some of these rider enhancements, some of those are designed so that they're treated from an accounting perspective as embedded derivatives which gives us the ability to directly hedge them.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="21" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.  And at this time, I would like to turn the conference back for any closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for bearing with us, and we'll talk to you next quarter.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Great and thank you.  Ladies and gentlemen, this conference will be available for replay starting today Friday, May 2nd, at 10 AM Eastern Time, and it will be available through next Friday, May 9th, at midnight Eastern Time.  And you may access the AT&amp;T executive playback service by dialing 320-365-3844 and then enter the access code of 917200.  That number once again is 320-365-3844, and again enter the access code of 917200.  And that does conclude our conference for today.  Thanks for your participation and for using AT&amp;T's executive teleconference.  You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>