<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1224373" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-04-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>351</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Clifford B. Fleet, Vice President, Investor Relations, Altria Client Services Inc.</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Michael E. Szymanczyk, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">David R. Beran, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="4">David Adelman</participant>
      <participant id="5">Michael Szymanczyk</participant>
      <participant id="6">David Beran</participant>
      <participant id="7">Ann Gurkin</participant>
      <participant id="8">Christine Farkas</participant>
      <participant id="9">Thilo Wrede</participant>
      <participant id="10">Erik Bloomquist</participant>
      <participant id="11">Chris Burritt</participant>
      <participant id="12">Judy Hong</participant>
      <participant id="13">Thomas Russo</participant>
      <participant id="14">Adam Spielman</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day and welcome to the Altria Group first quarter 2009 earnings conference call.  Today's call is scheduled to last about one hour, including remarks by Altria's management and a question-and-answer session.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />  Media representatives on the call will be able to ask questions following the conclusion of questions from the investment community.</p>
          <p>I would now like to turn the call over to Mr. Cliff Fleet, Vice President, Investor Relations for Altria Client Services.  Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and thank you for joining our call.  This morning, we will only be discussing Altria's 2009 first quarter business results and will not be discussing the status of litigation.  Our remarks today contain forward-looking statements and projections of future results, and I direct you to the forward-looking and cautionary statements at the end of our earnings release for the review of the various factors that could cause actual results to differ materially from projections.</p>
          <p>As a result of the spinoff of Philip Morris International in the first quarter of 2008, our reported results reflect PMI as a discontinued operation for the first quarter of 2008.  Revenues and operating companies income for PMI are therefore excluded from Altria's continuing results.</p>
          <p>Since Altria acquired UST and its smokeless tobacco and wine subsidiaries on January 6, 2009, US Smokeless Tobacco Company's and Ste. Michelle Wine Estates' financial results from January 6 through March 31, 2009 are included in Altria's 2009 first quarter consolidated and segment results.  Additionally, Altria has revised its reporting segments as a result of this acquisition.  Beginning in the first quarter of 2009, Altria's reporting segments are cigarettes, smokeless products, cigars, wine, and financial services.  For a detailed review of Altria's first quarter business results, please review the earnings release that is available on our website, www.altria.com.</p>
          <p>Altria reports its financial results in accordance with Generally Accepted Accounting Principles.  Today's call may contain various operating results on both a reported basis and on an adjusted basis, which excludes items that affect the comparability of reported results.  Descriptions of these measures as well as reconciliations are included in the earnings press release.</p>
          <p>Now it gives me great pleasure to introduce Mike Szymanczyk, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of Altria Group, Inc.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Cliff, and good morning to everyone and I appreciate you all joining with us this morning.  This is an earnings release with lots of moving parts in a year with still change to go in it.  But I think it's fair to characterize our first quarter performance as so far so good.  Our business results we think are on track with our plan.  Our cigarettes, cigars, and financial services segments delivered strong profit growth.  Cigarette infrastructure costs are declining ahead of schedule, and the UST integration is proceeding as planned.</p>
          <p>We're also encouraged by the initial results from our special price promotion on USSTC's premium brands in the Southeast where their premium MST retail share has stabilized and begun returning to retail share growth.</p>
          <p>Altria delivered adjusted earnings per share growth from continuing operations of $0.39, up 5.4% from the first quarter of 2008, in line with our expectations.  These results were driven by higher operating companies income growth from our continuing businesses as well as the operating companies income contribution from US Smokeless Tobacco Company and Ste. Michelle Wine Estates, partially offset by higher interest expenses.</p>
          <p>We delivered these results despite a challenging economic environment.  Economic conditions remain weak with high unemployment and low consumer confidence.  And the Federal government significantly increased the excise tax on tobacco products as of April 1, as you all know.  And the FET increase impacted the wholesale and retail trade inventory levels on our tobacco businesses and thus volumes for the quarter.  Dave will go into more detail on trade inventory movements that occurred during the quarter when he reviews our business segment results.</p>
          <p>In addition, the FET increase changed cigarette pricing dynamics in the marketplace in the second half of March and into April 2009 as manufacturers used different strategies to deal with the FET increase.  PM USA is closely monitoring these changing dynamics and will make adjustments to its plans as appropriate as the quarter progresses.</p>
          <p>In early 2009 in January, we successfully completed the acquisition of UST, which included its premium MST [Moist Smokeless Tobacco] brands Copenhagen and Skoal.  And we're pleased to have completed all financing related to this acquisition in the first quarter of 2009.  As you know, in February Altria issued $4.2 billion in long-term notes with an average weighted coupon rate of 9.4% to refinance its bridge loan facility.  And previously toward the end of 2008, Altria had issued approximately $6.8 billion in long-term notes with an average weighted coupon rate of 9.2%.</p>
          <p>In 2009, one of our key priorities is successfully executing the UST integration and that's proceeding very well.  Earlier this month, USSTC relocated its corporate headquarters to Richmond, Virginia.  And in the second quarter, we plan to combine the USSTC and PM USA sales forces into a new entity, the Altria Sales and Distribution Company.  This new sales organization will service all of Altria's tobacco businesses with an organization of approximately the same size of PM USA's sales force before the UST acquisition.  We plan to absorb substantially all of the costs related to the integration of UST in 2009 and remain on track to deliver an estimated $300 million in integration cost savings.</p>
          <p>USSTC already has taken a number of important steps to enhance the value equation on their leading premium brands.  In February, USSTC implemented a special price promotion in the high volume Southeast region on Copenhagen and Skoal.  And as I mentioned, we are encouraged by their retail share performance.  In March, USSTC announced a national list price reduction of $0.62 per can on Copenhagen and Skoal.  These actions require upfront investment spending which are a drag on near-term profitability, but will be offset by cost savings that are realized later in the year.  We believe these actions position the company well for future volume and moderate retail share growth in the MST category.</p>
          <p>Altria and its operating companies cost management programs continue to add value for shareholders.  Across the Altria family of companies, we achieved $140 million in cost savings in the first quarter.  Altria expects to achieve approximately $720 million in additional cost savings by 2011, bringing the total projected cost reductions to $1.5 billion versus the 2006 cost base.</p>
          <p>PM USA continues to focus on reducing cigarette infrastructure ahead of volume declines.  And the company announced earlier today that it plans to cease production at its Cabarrus, North Carolina cigarette manufacturing facility by the end of July 2009.  PM USA first announced in June 2007 that it would be closing the Cabarrus facility to address manufacturing overcapacity resulting from ongoing declines in US cigarette volume and reduced contract manufacturing.  PM USA is taking today's action to address ongoing cigarette volume declines including the projected impact of the recently enacted Federal Excise Tax increase.</p>
          <p>The company plans to complete decommissioning the facility during the 2010.  The Cabarrus facility closure is part of the manufacturing optimization program in PM USA, which is expected to deliver ongoing annual savings of $188 million by 2011.</p>
          <p>Before I turn the call over to Dave, I want to reaffirm Altria's 2009 EPS guidance.  We remain confident of delivering 2009 adjusted EPS growth of 3 to 6%.</p>
          <p>2009 is turning out to be a difficult year for most companies, but we believe Altria is well positioned to continue delivering strong shareholder returns.  Appropriately managing the value equation on our brands combined with Altria's aggressive cost management programs and the successful integration of UST should allow the company to continue growing earnings.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to turn the call over to Dave Beran, Altria's Executive Vice President and CFO, who will discuss Altria's business segment results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mike.  Let me start with the Cigarette segment, which delivered strong operating companies income in a challenging environment.  Reported cigarette operating companies income increased 9.9% versus the prior year period to $1.1 billion due to list price increases, lower promotional allowance rates, decreased promotional volume, and lower SG&amp;A spending, partially offset by lower volumes, as well as charges primarily related to the Cabarrus facility closure.  Excluding these charges, the Cigarette segment operating companies income increased by 10.7% to $1.2 billion.</p>
          <p>First quarter results were impacted by the April 1 increase in the Federal Excise Tax.  The FET increase led to significant wholesale and retail inventory depletions to minimize floor tax payments on their inventories.  PM USA believes that these inventory depletions disproportionally impacted Marlboro as the trade focused on that brand due to its higher sales velocity.</p>
          <p>PM USA cigarette shipment volumes declined 14% in the quarter, but were estimated to be down approximately 5.7% when adjusted for changes in trade inventories and calendar differences.  In April, PM USA saw higher out-of-stock levels at retail, particularly on Marlboro, as well as evidence of wholesalers and retailers rebuilding PM USA's cigarette inventories.  PM USA estimates that total cigarette industry volume declined 5% in the first quarter of 2009 when adjusting for those same factors.</p>
          <p>Marlboro continued its strong retail share growth as it gained 0.5 share point versus the prior year period to 42.4%.  Marlboro achieved these results despite lapping last year's very strong first quarter retail share performance.  Marlboro's price gap versus the lowest effective price cigarette was 43% in the first quarter.  Marlboro's net pack price was $4.50 and the lowest effective price cigarette was $3.14.</p>
          <p>Additionally, the discount segment's first quarter share remained stable at 25.4% versus the year-ago period.</p>
          <p>At the end of March and just prior to the FET increase, Marlboro's price gap versus the lowest effective price cigarette widened to approximately 50% due to price increase timing differences and competitive promotions.  By the second week of April 2009, this price gap has narrowed to 47% as marketplace prices continued to adjust to the FET increase.  PM USA believes the percent price gap will continue to fall to the extent the full FET impact is realized on the lowest price brands in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>Marlboro's strong share growth was more than offset by share declines on Virginia Slims, Parliament, and Basic.  PM USA's strategy is to maximize the long-term profitability of these brands with focused regional investment spending.  These brands continue to perform well in their respective areas of strength.</p>
          <p>PM USA's total Cigarette segment retail share declined 0.3 share point versus the prior-year period.  For perspective, PM USA's retail share was unchanged versus the second quarter of 2008.  Overall, we are very pleased with our first quarter Cigarette segment results.  Marlboro continued its strong retail share performance and profitability growth was very strong.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to the smokeless product segment.  During the quarter, USSTC took investment spending actions which laid a strong foundation for future profit growth, but impacted segment profitability.  USSTC quickly moved to enhance the value equation on the leading premium brands in the first quarter with a special price promotion and list price reductions on Copenhagen and Skoal.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter, Copenhagen's and Skoal's national net price gap versus the leading discount brand was approximately 80%.  In the Southeast region, where USSTC implemented its special price promotion, Copenhagen's and Skoal's net price gap versus the leading discount brand fell from approximately 105% in January 2009 to an approximate 58% in March.</p>
          <p>Copenhagen and Skoal's national retail shares were each sequentially down 0.2 share point versus the fourth quarter of 2008 to 24 and 24.9%, respectively.  However, USSTC's premium retail share responded well to the actions taken in the Southeast region.  Its premium retail share at the end of March increased versus early February 2009.  While not predictive of future results, we are encouraged by this information.</p>
          <p>In the first quarter of 2009, USSTC's domestic MST shipment volume declined 5.3% to approximately 152 million cans, but was estimated to be flat on adjusted for the following.  First, the trade reduced inventories on USSTC's products to minimize floor tax payments and in anticipation of the price reduction of Copenhagen and Skoal.  Second, USSTC discontinued its multipack deals in favor of everyday low prices.  And finally, USSTC incurred increased product returns from retail as the PM USA sales force assumed retail responsibilities in a broader store set than USSTC's sales force, resulting in an inventory cleanup.</p>
          <p>USSTC believes MST industry volume continued to grow an estimated 6 to 7% in the quarter.</p>
          <p>As a result of charges related to the acquisition of UST, actions taken by USSTC to enhance the value equation on its MST brands, and costs associated with Marlboro smokeless products, the Smokeless Products segment reported an operating companies loss of $2 million.  This loss was primarily due to pre-tax charges of $128 million related to the UST acquisition, consisting of employee separation cost as well as inventory adjustments and other integration costs.</p>
          <p>First quarter operating companies income results were further impacted by special price promotion spending in the Southeast and costs for the wholesale incentive program that lowered the price of some of USSTC's brands.  As the year progresses, cost of this spending will be offset by cost savings.  Excluding the exit, integration, and acquisition related charges, adjusted Smokeless Products operating companies income was $126 million.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to cigars, which reported very strong results in the first quarter. Unlike cigarettes and MST, there was no floor tax in the Federal Excise Tax increase for large cigars.  Consequently, trade inventories increased in advance of the April 1 Federal Excise Tax increase.</p>
          <p>Middleton's cigar shipment volume increased 10.4% versus the prior-year period to 345 million units.  Middleton's volume growth reflects wholesale inventory accumulation in advance of the Federal Excise Tax increase and new product pipeline volume for Black &amp; Mild Wood Tip.  Middleton believes that total machine-made large cigar industry volume continued to grow at an estimated rate of 4%.  Excluding integration cost, operating companies income for cigars increased 32.6% versus the prior-year period to $57 million due to higher pricing and volume growth partially offset by costs related to the introduction of new wholesale and retail trade programs.</p>
          <p>Black &amp; Mild had another strong quarter of retail share growth as its share increased 0.9 share point to 27.9%.  The brand benefited from the introduction of Black &amp; Mild Wood Tip as well as its new brand equity campaign "Enjoy Black &amp; Mild".</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to our new Wine segment.  We are pleased with the fundamentals of Ste. Michelle's underlying business performance, though there were some short-term events impacting first quarter results.  Ste. Michelle suspended shipments during the first week of January to take inventory prior to the closing of the acquisition of UST by Altria.  Wholesalers purchased wine in advance of this suspension and also further reduced their inventories in the first quarter of 2009.</p>
          <p>As a result, total Ste. Michelle wine shipments declined 7.2% in the first quarter of 2009 to approximately 1.2 million cases.  However, Ste. Michelle's volume from wholesale to retail was up approximately 6% during the first quarter of 2009.  In addition, Ste. Michelle's retail volume as measured by Nielsen and Food &amp; Drug was up approximately 11% in the first quarter of 2009 versus the prior-year period.</p>
          <p>Net revenues for the Wine segment were $75 million and reported operating companies income was $1 million.  Excluding the $8 million in acquisition related charges, adjusted operating companies income was $9 million for the 12 weeks that Altria owned the company.</p>
          <p>Let me conclude with Financial Services.  Reported operating companies income increased $46 million to $120 million, primarily due to higher gains on asset sales.  Additionally, all lessees are current on their lease obligations and there were no changes to the $304 million allowance for losses.  Management believes that the amount is prudent based upon the underlying credit quality and collateral value of its existing portfolio.</p>
          <p>Mike and I will now be happy to take your questions.  While the operator compiles the calls, I'm going to cover a few housekeeping numbers.  The average weighted cigarette state excise tax at the end of the first quarter of 2009 was approximately $1.13 per pack.  To date, three states and Puerto Rico have increased their cigarette excise taxes with an average increase of $0.56 per pack.</p>
          <p>CapEx was $43 million and ongoing depreciation and amortization was $78 million.  Our first quarter MSA [Master Settlement Agreement] and quota buyout accruals were approximately $1.1 billion or $0.67 per pack.  Of the $0.67, MSA represents $0.61 per pack and the quota buyout represents $0.06 per pack.</p>
          <p>Additionally on April 15, PM USA made its full 2008 MSA payment of approximately $4 billion.  And finally, we anticipate that our 2009 full-year effective tax rate on operations will be approximately 37.1%.  However, our first quarter tax rate was 38.7% due to certain non-deductible costs related to the UST acquisition.</p>
          <p>Operator, do we have any questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />  Our first question comes from David Adelman with Morgan Stanley.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike, first a question for you, I'm curious.  At PM USA over the next couple of quarters in the cigarette business given the FET dynamics, I'm curious.  Are you thinking any differently than you might have in a more normal environment with respect to how you're going to balance market share dynamics versus profitability?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, that's a good question.  Let me talk about that for a couple of minutes.  Look, when you have something like the FET event, that's a dynamic that impacts every single cigarette product that's on the marketplace in the country.  And it's a pretty significant event and it unfolds over time.  It just doesn't happen all at once.</p>
          <p>So we anticipated as we went into the year and thought about if a FET did occur that there would likely be a dislocation in the marketplace that would take place over probably a couple of months as the market moved, as retailers moved, and they moved at different paces.  And some tried to take advantage by winning some share during that period and some responded in a defensive way during the period, so that we would see generally a pretty dislocated marketplace.  And on this case given the timing of the FET, that's probably from the back half of March, given when some of the pricing begin to occur, through call it the middle of May.  And I think that's where we are now. Dave's comments relative to gap movements are an indication of that.  You're seeing the market work its way through this period of time.</p>
          <p>Our philosophy here is to not get too excited about the period of dislocation.  We like to have a static baseline and not find ourselves trying to respond to temporary market conditions as the market moves around.  And once it settles in, we can see where we are and we'll go back to doing what we normally do, which is we look at the market.  We identify areas where we may have gap problems and we correct those, and we build our brands based on equity enhancing activity.  Gap management for us is not how we build the market on our brands; it's really making sure that's not an impediment to the other kinds of things that we do in the marketplace to build the brands.</p>
          <p>So I think as we go on through the second quarter, we'll see the markets settle out.  And then as it does that and we move on through the back half of the quarter, you'll see more normalcy.  But we're of the mind to be thoughtful about monitoring what's going on and know what the situation is in terms of how the market settles out before we do too much from a resource point of view.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, so to paraphrase, you're not unduly concerned if you were to lose some market share for a short period of time as long as the low end of the market is moving up over time with pricing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think the key here is to let the markets settle out before you decide what you're going to do.  Because otherwise, you're moving into a moving playing field and that doesn't allow you to know what you are doing, so that's the way we look at it.  Actually, what's I think more important than market share during this period is really volume.  And we have a forecast for the year on volume; and I think importantly, we'd like to see volumes show at a level that's equal to or better than our forecast.  Regardless of where shares are in a short period of time, it's really where is the overall volume circumstance going to be.  I think so far so good is a good description of the circumstance.</p>
          <p>So that's how we are looking at it.  So it's &#x2013; I think you have to be reasonably pragmatic here.  Otherwise, you can waste a lot of money on things and we don't see that as the right way to do it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, and then one other quick question.  At UST, you're saying that adjusted for anomalies in the quarter, shipments were essentially flat.  And I'm just curious with higher levels of promotional spending; shouldn't volume trends be better than that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you've got to look at the smokeless market in a similar way to the cigarette market in the first quarter.  Keep in mind we changed a number of things.  We did have some investment spend in the Southeast region.  But in other markets around the U.S., toward the end of the quarter we were extracting what has been the normal promotion vehicle in the marketplace, these multipack deals, in anticipation of the overall price reduction approach that we announced that went into effect at the beginning of April.  So there was &#x2013; yes, some investment in the Southeast, but there was also an extraction of promotion activity in the marketplace as well.</p>
          <p>And then you have to add to that the fact that the trade took the opportunity to reduce inventories because they had a floor tax situation in MST just like they did in cigarettes, compounded in our case by the fact that we were reducing our price.  And we announced that ahead of time because you have to, to get the trade prepared.  They naturally buy as little as they can going into that circumstance because we give them a limited amount of price protection, and they want to see if they can make a profit on that.</p>
          <p>So I wouldn't again get too caught up in trying to read anything into the volume in the first quarter in MST because there is so much that moved around.  It's impossible to read, but our best estimate of it is that it was pretty flat when you factored in all of those things.  And it will be easier to read it once we get to the end of the second quarter and we look at the whole half. In fact, all of these businesses from a quarterly point of view right now aren't &#x2013; the quarterly numbers aren't going to mean a whole lot.  It's really for example looking at the half where we'll see how things washed out in terms of inventory and so on.</p>
          <p>Cigars are the same way only reversed; there was no floor tax, so we had inventory build that has provided probably an overstatement of volume and income growth for the first quarter, and that will wash out in the second quarter.  I think that's how we've looked at it.  But when we do adjustments, and we try to do adjustments so we can understand whether or not we think we're on track, when we do adjustments, we feel pretty good about it. It looks fine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Ann Gurkin with Davenport.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, I just wanted to start with...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning; UST, just the mix of the business of Skoal and Copenhagen as a percentage of the volume dropped more than we would have thought versus the fourth quarter.  Can you just help me understand those numbers?  Is there anything unusual in those volumes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again it's items that I mentioned a minute ago, Ann.  It's really the trade reduced their inventory at retail and wholesale because of the FET.  And because of our price decline, we pulled the plug on multipack deals.  And then we subtract returns from our volume, so we did a cleanup in the marketplace as we expanded coverage into the USA sales force.  And so there was a higher than normal level of return activity that we anticipated in the quarter because of that, but it impacts the numbers, those are really the items.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Should we expect the mix to move back towards that 84% or so Skoal and Copenhagen as a percentage of the total volume?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would expect to see with our value equation actions in the marketplace that yes, we would see Skoal and Copenhagen be the strong part of our portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, and then secondly, if you could just give us an update on the likelihood that the Senate may take up the FDA bill?  It has passed the House.  Your outlook if you care to comment, and is there any change in Altria's position on potential FDA regulation of tobacco?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We supported the bill in the House, and I think the situation in the Senate remains a bit unclear as to exactly when and what the Senate will take up.  But no, our position hasn't changed relative to the bill that we supported in the House.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Christine Farkas with Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Good morning, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Christine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to start with cost savings if I could in the quarter.  These were quite strong, certainly above what we were looking for.  And I'm just wondering if you're surprised at the pace of how this is coming through and if this is just accelerated or pulling forward or do you see perhaps the program in cost savings getting bigger in the end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Right now, what you have is what we've announced in terms of cost savings, and I would say we're pulling it in at a good rapid rate.  So I wouldn't attribute it to higher levels of cost savings at this point.  I'd attribute it to speed that we're moving along pretty well both from a cigarette infrastructure point of view and from the perspective of the UST integration.  Both of those things are going if not on schedule, a little bit ahead of schedule, and that's what we'd like to have happen.  That doesn't mean in the end, we may find ourselves with a better performance relative to costs, but I wouldn't attribute it to that at this juncture.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And just to be clear, you haven't actually realized any UST synergies in the quarter.  Is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't think that's entirely correct.  But I think that the way I would look at that is I would say yes, we've begun to reduce staffing at UST; but at the same time, there are one-time costs that we incur at the time that we reduce the staffing.  So the fact is yes, we realized some synergies.  But no, they didn't show up as a positive from a cost savings point of view yet.  They will though once we get past the one-time charges.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks for that.  Secondly on the second quarter, I think you're pretty clear about the disruption around March and April, the deloading and the loading.  And of course, it sounds to me as your comments about so far so good means demand elasticity is so far probably running along as you had expected.  I'm just wondering in looking at the second quarter, would this be the quarter where we see the greatest sticker shock from consumers in the sense that this is where we might see the sharpest decline in category volumes and then it moderates?  Or could we see as people understand the pricing or see the level, can we see that actually decelerate as we go through the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think relative to us, our products because we were up &#x2013; started in early March, and this is probably important for people to understand what's different about us.  We started in early March, earlier than anybody else.  Because of that, the trade had more time to deload inventory on us than they had on anybody else.  And because of that, pricing on us probably moved the fastest in the marketplace.  So I would say for us, we've probably seen pretty much what is going to wind up being the peak.  Probably not that the marketplace dynamics and the gap movements would indicate we haven't fully seen all of it reflected in other places in the marketplace.</p>
          <p>So I don't think that for us there is any more sticker shock really of any significance for the consumer.  There may be some other things.  Because there are folks who lag that; there are folks who actually spin into it.  I mean we have some major competitors that have actually spent into the increase.  And so eventually the tax man gets his money, and so eventually that's going to come home to roost, but it hasn't fully happened yet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's helpful.  My last question if I could just touch on minority interest, that was quite a decline year over year.  And I'm just wondering if there is anything else in that number aside from the underlying contribution from SABMiller et cetera, anything else in that number that would account for the 26% decline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, there is not, and we look at the SABMiller investment as a good long-term investment.  They have great brands.  They have great management.  And just like the recession is impacting business this year and worldwide, we're seeing some impacts there.  But for further questions, I would direct those questions to SABMiller.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Dave.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But we feel good about our investment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And Dave, when you describe this as a good long-term investment, should we read into that as any change of your views of how you see SABMiller or that stake fitting into your long-term plan?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No; as we said back in CAGNY, we are spending 2009 to evaluate our total alcohol strategy.  We are doing that in 2009 and we'll get back to you, so don't read anything into my comment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right.  Great, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Thilo Wrede with Credit Suisse.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike, you just mentioned at the beginning of the call that the manufacturers &#x2013; different manufacturers had different strategies to deal with the FET increase.  Could you elaborate on that a little bit and tell us why you think that you had the right strategy there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it will remain to be seen whether or not we had the right strategy.  But as a practical matter, I think you did, you saw different people take different approaches to it.  And some of them have different structures in their pricing and they approach it from a reduction and promotion, some with increase in list price, some with a combination of activities.  And then coupled into that, you saw some spending strategies; we've seen some spending strategies unfold.  They look like they were tied with the FET.  In other words, they represent changes in the strategies going into the FET and appear to be opportunistic situations where people will give renting share a try to see if some of it sticks.  That's what we've seen. I wouldn't comment on any of them specifically, but I do think that there have been a number of different approaches.</p>
          <p>And there have also been a number of different approaches by retailers too, and that has an impact on pricing and price gap.  You have some retailers who hold back hoping to build some share, and you have other retailers who go very quickly, and you have some test the market in terms of how high they can go and then gauge the competitive situation and have to adjust accordingly.  You have lots of different approaches going on.  And that's why I say I think it takes a couple of months for all of that to settle out, and then that gives you a read of what kind of marketplace you're dealing with.  And then you can make decisions about how you want to go forward on a longer term basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Then the adjusted volume number for the industry as a whole is down 5%.  Is that just reflecting all the distortions in the quarter or should we read into that that there is maybe a change in consumer behavior and the volume decline is accelerating now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think remember, you had this adjustment that started at the beginning of March.  So we really had an adjustment that impacted about 30% of the quarter.  So I think there was some elasticity that affected the quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But that would presumably be taken care of when you adjust the number down to just a 5% decline for the industry rather than 14%, no?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The elasticity, remember the 14% is more driven by inventory change, okay.  So inventory change wouldn't be part of your elasticity curve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But pricing could impact elasticity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, got you.  And then one last question, New York State put out or one petitioner in New York State put out a proposal to ban cigarette sales in grocery stores and flex stores, which follows similar actions in both San Francisco and Boston.  Is that a trend that is accelerating across the country?  Are you seeing more proposals like this cropping up in cities or states, and what's your take on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I haven't &#x2013; I'm not aware of a grocery store situation.  But yes, you're right; there is a pharmacy situation in San Francisco.  I wouldn't call it a trend, but certainly we've seen some proposals in that regard.  I think that &#x2013; I don't know that they from our standpoint they make a lot of sense, but nonetheless you're seeing some of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's nothing you're concerned about right now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, you have a broadly distributed product and its predominant channel is really c-stores [convenience stores] and c-gas [convenience/gas], and volumes in some of these other channels have declined over the year.  So I don't think that there is a shortage of retail distribution category.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>At this time, we'll begin taking questions from the media.  <mark type="Operator Instructions" />  Our next question comes from Erik Bloomquist with JPMorgan.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just wanted to follow up then on the smokeless promotion in the Southeast.  I was wondering what kinds of competitive responses you saw to that within that promotional period.  And then secondly, I was wondering if the share stabilization that you saw in that region or in that period, if there was a benefit from an easier comp because you had both Swedish Match and Reynolds American launching new products in the same period last year, so that made the comparison slightly easier for the USSTC brands.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry, why would it be easier?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So with the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There was a lot of activity last year...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...in the first quarter, which actually would make the comp probably more difficult.  But I don't know that I would say that there were something there that made it easier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  But could you comment then on competitive activity then in response to the $1 off promotion?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know how to do that for you.  I mean we don't necessarily try to make comparisons on competitive activity, so I would...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so they didn't &#x2013; there wasn't really any &#x2013; you're not willing to discuss any competitive response?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would decline to answer it because we generally don't try to make comparisons on competitive activity.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right.  And then moving to the cigarette division, could you quantify the size of the deload?  Is it fair to think it's around a 3 billion stick event?  And it sounded like from your previous answers and the commentary at the beginning of the call that we could expect that to come back then in the second quarter as things begin to normalize.  Is that a fair way to think about things?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we'll have to see what happens, but I think what we've said is we've seen some evidence of that taking place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then again this was alluded to a little earlier in one of your earlier questions, but is there any indication that the consumer behavior has changed?  It sounds like the price elasticity has stayed about the same and that moreover, there doesn't appear to be any meaningful change in terms of consumer down-trading.  Is that also fair way to characterize things?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not going to characterize the second quarter at this point.  As I already mentioned to you that you saw some expansion of the gap that took place and that there will be some disruption in the marketplace I think from the latter part of March through probably the middle of May.  That's how we've looked at it.  And so we'd expect to see some movement taking place because gaps are going to be variable around the country in different marketplaces.  So I'm not going to try and predict exactly how that comes out during that period of time.</p>
          <p>My point earlier was that I'm not sure that that's really meaningful.  What's going to be important is once it settles in, where does it settle in and then where do we go from there.  And I don't think we're really going to know the net result of that until we get on through the second quarter.  At this juncture, the market is still moving around; and to draw conclusions about it at this juncture I think is a bit misleading.  It doesn't tell you much because it's point-in-time data, and the next point in time you look at it, it's different.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Chris Burritt with Bloomberg News.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chris.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, good morning.  Thanks for your time, a couple of quick questions.  Mike, can you explain your &#x2013; or PM USA's strategy as it goes to state legislators in places like North Carolina where tax increases are on the table?  What argument is the company making to hold the line on those proposed tax increases?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that varies based on what the tax proposal is, so they're not all the same.  They're different, and so I think you have to look at them individually.  But I do also think that tobacco users have been burdened by a high tax increase by the Federal government this year.  And so I think that the states need to be judicious and thoughtful about what they do on taxes because there has already been a significant tax increase put on the consumer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thanks.  And Dave, if you could offer me a little bit more explanation on the average price of Marlboro; I believe you said 3.50 a pack.  Is that the average in convenience stores?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It was not 3.50 a pack.  That was the lowest price products in the store.  For the quarter...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>4.50.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For the quarter, the average pack price was $4.50.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm sorry...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>For Marlboro.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>4.50.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And that's the average pack price in c-stores.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can you tell me how that compared to the year earlier quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'd have to get back to you on that.  We don't have the answer to that question right here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Judy Hong with Goldman Sachs.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Judy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>On the industry volume down 5% in the first quarter of 2009 when adjusted for the inventory changes and the calendar differences, Mike can you tell us what that number was before the March price increases and after?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, which business are we talking about, Judy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, on the cigarette side, you said the total cigarette industry volume was down 5% for the first quarter if you adjust for the inventory changes.  I'm just wondering what that number was running before the price increases in March and then post-price increases?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have that of the top of my head but I think you can look at the year-end information for 2008.  I don't think there was any meaningful difference.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I guess I'm just trying to understand the price elasticity here in terms of what happened after the March price increases at the underlying consumption level.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think you can calculate that yet...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...when you have a month in March where it was all moving, so it's really pretty hard to draw that conclusion because these are estimates and you've got lots of moving parts, so I wouldn't try and do that at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And just to clarify your volume being down 5.7% adjusted for the inventory versus the industry down 5%, so you lost shipment share, but you gained retail share.  And the difference is really because you guys have taken price increases earlier than the industry so that impacted your shipment numbers more?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We lost a little retail share.  Recall we lost 0.3 total USA versus previous year in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We were flat to the fourth quarter, but we lost 0.3 share point total USA in the first quarter versus the prior year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then as you saw some of the dislocations happening in the marketplace with the price gap widening towards the latter part of the quarter, the share trends also were negatively impacted if you look at the retail numbers than the full quarter number would suggest?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure I understand your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You talked about the price gaps widening after some of these price increases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You're looking for share information into the second quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Not necessarily in the second quarter, but what has been happening to share post some of the price adjustments that you saw from a competitors' perspective and from your perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, I don't know that we have enough data at this point to draw any conclusions about that, Judy. That's why I continue to say that you've got a period of dislocation here.  It runs from around the middle to the latter part of March and it will likely run on through the beginning of May where you're going to see things sort themselves out.  And to draw any conclusions about share trends during that period of time is probably misleading because they'll move around.  One week they'll be different than they are another week depending on how the markets move and what kind of activity goes into the marketplace.  So I just think trying to hone in on that and draw conclusions about it at this point it doesn't give you much that's worth operating with.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I wasn't asking for a conclusion.  I was just asking what color you have from a share perspective.  You talked about the price gap movements and not to really give any color on the share movement, which is pretty factual from my perspective.  It just seems like...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No color because color would be misinterpreted.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  On the interest expenses, Dave, it looks like the first quarter just seems to be running ahead of the run rate?  Can you tell...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In the first quarter, we had the additional charges related to the financing of the UST transaction, one-time charges in the first quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And can you quantify how much that was?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That was approximately $85 million.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And then on the tax rate, when you say 37% or 37.1% for the full year, that's including some of the charges that you're taking this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that 37.1% is on the underlying business.  The additional, the difference in the tax rate in the first quarter is not in that 37.1, but it's a one-time event in the first quarter that will as a percentage of the total will go down over time, but 37.1 on the underlying business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, so 37.1% compares to the 38% in the first quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, 37.1% is the effective tax rate on the business.  In the first quarter, there were some items associated with the acquisition that are tax deductible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Those items happened in the first quarter.  And then starting in the second quarter, our effective tax rate should be 37.1%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  So on the full-year basis because if I calculate the tax rate adjusting for the one-time items in the first quarter, I get much lower tax rate of 33%.  So if you get to the...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We will follow up with you, Judy, on that.  Cliff will get back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, all right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Thomas Russo with Gardner Russo Gardner.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi; good day.  David, there are couple of just balance sheet oriented questions.  When you unwind positions at Philip Morris Capital and take gains like you mentioned in the quarter, where do the proceeds from those sales go? And that's the first question.  Second, what would be the cash flow consequences of the pension fund do you think for '09 or 2010?  How much will that consume cash would you expect?  And then third, what is your flexibility to return whatever free cash flow you might generate to the debt paydown of your highest coupon, longest term debt?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Three balance sheet questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Three questions; first question, when we sell assets at PMCC, the cash comes into the business.  It's reported in the income statement, but the cash comes in.  And we have &#x2013; if you look at the asset portion of the balance sheet, finance &#x2013; the net finance assets, which are approximately $5.1 billion, that number would go down, which is the total Financial Services assets.</p>
          <p>The second question, right now we look at 2009 from a funding standpoint on pensions, we're still in the neighborhood of approximately $20 million, which represents the non-qualified piece of our plan that we can't fund.  So that could move around slightly, but at this point in time we're not seeing any large movement there.</p>
          <p>The third question, as we look at our balance sheet and we look at when debt comes due and our ability to generate cash, yes, we will be looking at our overall debt structure.  We have some debt coming due this year that's short term of approximately $875 million over the next couple quarters.  And when we look at our liquidity and our access to the commercial paper market and the amount of cash that we have currently, we don't need to go back into the long-term bond market.  There again, we could just based on the overall rates, but we are looking at our overall tranches going out into the future, but right now we're comfortable where we are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your final question comes from Adam Spielman with Citigroup.  Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, good morning.  One quick question, you said very clearly that the moment is too early really to judge the impact I think either of the elasticity or the market share trends.  But I was wondering when you think it would be reasonable for perhaps yourselves and investors to actually come to a firm conclusion about how these things are behaving; and whether I guess that with some of the second quarter results, we can reasonably expect to have some degree of clarity or whether it's really going to be something we don't really know about until the third quarter results.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that, as I've stated that probably by the middle of the quarter, we should have a market that has digested the FET, and then we'll return to a more normal competitive circumstance.  And then we'll get to see what happens in that circumstance and how people respond to the new market that exists over the back half of the quarter.  And so I would say probably what will be most important to us will be the trends in the back half of the quarter, not the front half of the quarter.  We'll want to see how things are progressing at that point in time.</p>
          <p>And as I mentioned a minute ago, volume will be important.  So what's the volume trend appear to be and in particular as we get the inventory adjustment completed that we return to more of a normal volume flow.  So as we get toward the end of the second quarter, we should begin to have a volume trend that's more predictive of what we'll see.  Although I say to you that when we see these large increases take place in a state, although we normally see a pretty good spike down immediately after the increase and then we see volume return sharply although not completely.  And then the curve begins to extend out and it can take six months or so before you finally have the market settle back in to its adjusted level.</p>
          <p>So some of it, a good portion of it is likely to happen in the second quarter relative to volume, but probably it will extend out into the third quarter before it's complete.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Will you give us when you announce your second quarter results an indication of how things have moved in the last month of the quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll see when we get there, but we'll try and give you information that's useful to you so you'll understand how the market is shaping up.  That's our objective at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Actually, can I ask another question just in summary? You've said a couple of times that the cost savings are if anything ahead of schedule, which is great, but you've obviously left your EPS guidance unchanged.  Can I read I think into the fact about the underlying business excluding cost savings from that maybe is not quite as strong as you were expecting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Our guidance is 3 to 6%.  So as I said, we've reaffirmed our guidance and we continue to feel like we're going to fall within that guidance range.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but you've also said your cost savings are ahead of schedule.  That means to say that if I look at the business excluding cost savings, and maybe I'm reading too much into this, maybe there's slightly...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think you're reading too much into it.  I mean there are a lot of pieces to the puzzle, and they all come together with the guidance range and I think we haven't &#x2013; we don't have any reason to change our guidance range at this point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Fair enough. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  At this time, I would like to turn the floor back over to Mr. Cliff Fleet for closing comments.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you all for joining us today.  I invite you to listen to Altria's webcast of its 2009 Annual Meeting of Stockholders on May 19.  If you have any follow-up questions after today's call, please call us at Investor Relations.  Thank you and have a good day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  This does conclude today's Altria Group first quarter 2009 earnings conference call.  You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>