<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1485947" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-06-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>555</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Investor Relations Lead">Bryan Hurley</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chairman, President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Hugh Grant</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Senior Vice President">Pierre Courduroux</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Jeffrey J. Zekauskas</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">David Ian Begleiter</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">Vincent Andrews</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Cleveland Research Co.">Michael Piken</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">P.J. Juvekar</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Agricole Securities (USA), Inc.">Mark W. Connelly</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Jefferies &amp; Co., Inc.">Laurence Alexander</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Wells Fargo Advisors LLC">Frank J. Mitsch</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Duffy Fischer</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Susquehanna Financial Group LLP">Don D. Carson</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Piper Jaffray, Inc.">Michael E. Cox</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch, Pierce, Fenner &amp; Smith, Inc.">Kevin W. McCarthy</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="Gulley &amp; Associates LLC">Mark Gulley</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Robert A. Koort</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Greetings and welcome to the Third Quarter 2012 Monsanto Company Earnings Conference Call. At this time, all participants are in a listen-only mode. A brief question-and-answer session will follow the formal presentation. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> As a reminder, this conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>It is now my pleasure to introduce your host, Mr. Bryan Hurley, Investor Relations Lead for Monsanto. Thank you, Mr. Hurley; you may begin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Lewis, and good morning to everyone. Thanks for joining us for Monsanto's Third Quarter Earnings Conference Call. I'm joined this morning by Hugh Grant, our Chairman and CEO; and by Pierre Courduroux, our CFO. Also joining me are Manny Cruz, Bryan Corkal, and Ashley Wissmann, my colleagues in Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>The call is being webcast and you can access that webcast and the supporting slides at monsanto.com. The replay will also be available at that address.</p>
          <p>We're providing you today with EPS measures both on a GAAP basis and on an ongoing business basis. Where we refer to non-GAAP financial measures, we reconcile to GAAP in the slides and in the press release, both of which are posted to our website.</p>
          <p>This call will include statements concerning future events and financial results. Because these statements are based on assumptions and factors that involve risks and uncertainty, the company's actual performance and results may vary in a material way from those expressed or implied in any forward-looking statements. A description of the factors that may cause such a variance is included in the Safe Harbor language in our most recent 10-K and in today's press release.</p>
          <p>With our guidance update last month, our conversation today is intended to do three things. We'll highlight the business drivers that have Monsanto on track for a second year of 20% plus ongoing earnings growth in fiscal year 2012. We'll provide clarity on how those drivers then set up our growth in 2013, and we'll provide the guidepost on the financial metrics that shape our view on 2013.</p>
          <p>I'll start with our fiscal year 2012 performance and in particular a brief review of the financial results for our third quarter on slide 4. Very simply, our performance in the quarter directly flows from our guidance update last month, so you see the positive trends we described flow through our financial results today. The results roll up to ongoing earnings per share for the quarter of $1.63; that compares against ongoing EPS of $1.28 in the same quarter last year as the strong overall performance across the business drove the upside in both our quarterly results and in the increased full-year guidance from last month.</p>
          <p>You can see that across-the-board performance best looking at the year-to-date results; start with Seeds and Genomics where gross profit is up 20% through the first nine months. That is the biggest factor in our growth this year. Within that, corn is the biggest driver, with gross profit up more than 30% for the year. That growth comes from three geographic areas: the core U.S. business, the acceleration in Latin America, and our other global seed businesses, highlighted by the rapid expansion in Eastern Europe. This growth reflects the combination of mix improvement and volume expansion as we step up the value of our product portfolio, increase our total corn volume, and saw particularly strong planted acres in nearly every key corn growing region. This performance is flanked by good year-to-date performance in our soybean and cotton businesses, while softness in the vegetable business reflecting the soft European economy continues to offset a portion of that overall strong Seeds and Genomics growth.</p>
          <p>Also as we indicated in our guidance update, we also saw strength from our Ag Productivity segment. That uptick also comes across the board. As we've achieved strong volume mix and pricing in Roundup, we've had another good year in our lawn and garden business and we're seeing growth in our selective chemistry offerings.</p>
          <p>On the cash side, our strong business results also flowed into our free cash generation as through the third quarter free cash flow was $311 million, compared with cash flow of $237 million through the first nine months of 2011. In sum, this top-line growth through the third quarter speaks to the earnings power of the global business in a growth mode.</p>
          <p>So, from here, let me turn it to Hugh to lay out how we see the next stage of growth in fiscal year 2013.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bryan, and good morning to everybody on the line. With our largest selling seasons now complete, this third quarter is the punctuation mark on another year of compelling performance in our business. Simultaneously, it's the jumping off point as we expect to carry this year's momentum and the continued strong growth in fiscal year 2013. I'll start this morning by highlighting three of the most compelling accomplishments that defined 2012, reflected on slide 5.</p>
          <p>First, we captured the momentum that we've seen building in the business. This began in 2011 and it continued through 2012. With back-to-back years of across-the-board performance and 20% plus ongoing earnings growth, we're clearly in a growth mode. Second, we've taken the business to a global stage. This was the first year our international business was roughly an equal contributor to our total growth and that's the leading edge of a trend as we see growth accelerating in a couple of these key geographies. And, third then, maybe most importantly, the strategy that we set out two years ago to focus on yield and bring more product choices to our farmer customers is now in full swing.</p>
          <p>With that strategy firmly in place, it means what we need to do to drive growth in 2013 is simply a continuation of what we've accomplished this year. That consistency is important both with our farmer customers and within our own organization. So, taken together, those three factors create a clearer line of sight of growth than we've had in some previous years and that's reinforced as we've reconfirmed our projection of mid-teens ongoing earnings growth for fiscal year 2013 from the higher expected 2012 base of $3.65 to $3.70.</p>
          <p>If you move to slide 6 that means we can focus today on how we take our strategy forward to drive that growth. The specific opportunity for Monsanto in 2013 actually starts on a much larger stage. Simply put, the drivers of global agricultural growth are real and they're ongoing. It's a well told story but I think it bears repeating. As rising global incomes drive more demand for protein, it creates a runway of opportunity that expands for more than a decade, which we show on slide 7. While this is an opportunity for many in agriculture, it's even more pronounced for us. We are a yield company, and we have the products and the technology and the right markets to meaningfully drive productivity. So, things like yields, acres and prices will move from year-to-date, but structurally the business drivers that we're focused on continue to play out for an extended time horizon and given the larger global volatility that's a really meaningful backdrop.</p>
          <p>As you think about how that translates to our growth, the logical place to start is the U.S. It's a core market and we expect it to continue to be a major contributor to growth in 2013. One of the big reasons is the build-out of our platforms in corn and in soybeans, shown on slides 8 and 9. With sales behind us and an early line of sight on returns, we project our reduced refuge family will be on more than 25 million acres this year, ahead of our projected high end of 24 million acres. Likewise, our Roundup Ready 2 Yield soybeans are coming in near the high end of our initial range as we reach close to 30 million acres in a total soybean market that may decline in 2012. These are both platforms of momentum and they're a key for 2013, which will be stepping each platform up even further.</p>
          <p>The next big driver in the U.S. is the volume growth and mix benefit that we get from the annual upgrade of our portfolio with the latest high-value germplasm, captured on slide 10. In 2012, we've clearly seen an increase in total U.S. branded seed volume, practically across the key corn and soybean platforms. That puts us on the track for organic share gains at our brands in both of these crops. And, going into 2013, this germplasm refresh will certainly be as important to growth as it was this past year.</p>
          <p>Coming into this year, we projected a total portfolio price lift in corn in the range of 5% to 10% from this refresh. That has played out at to plan and while we haven't communicated specific prices, we project that same 5% to 10% range in portfolio price lift for 2013. That speaks to the consistency that we want to reinforce with the farmer customers, the predictable financial benefit of this annual upgrade as well as why our practical approach to pricing creates a positive lift, even in a variety of commodity price environments. So, the combination of that platform build-out and germplasm upgrade means that we're adding a big increment of growth on our biggest geographic base and that anchors a significant portion of our 2013 opportunity.</p>
          <p>So, as you move from the U.S. around the world, you can see why we focus on our international business as a powerhouse of growth in 2013. That all begins in Latin America on slide 11, as the corn opportunity is driving some of the most pronounced growth rates in the company right now, and we're on the front edge of trait penetration. If we start with Brazil, the rapid trait growth today was primarily driven on just initial trait penetration of first and second generation single traits. As we look to 2013, the key for Brazil is the beginning of the upgrade to the first true double-stack trait and VT PRO 2. We expect to step that up from a small amount of our mix this year to the second biggest trait in our portfolio in 2013. That's important because the gross profit lift, as we upgrade from the first-generation trait to the double-stack, is between 70% and 80% per acre.</p>
          <p>That same pattern holds true for Argentina on slide 12. In 2013, the key in Argentina will be the upgrade from the double-stack to the triple-stack. The conversion is expected to be in full swing in 2013 and we expect Triple PRO will be over one-third of our branded mix. Like Brazil, the gross profit upgrade is important as there's a 20% to 30% lift over the existing double-stack And, if you take Latin America as a whole, the beauty of this trait curve is it's not a one-shot benefit. Coming behind today's upgrades are multi-trait stacks that create a runway that we expect carries out over the next half decade.</p>
          <p>If we move from corn to soybeans in Latin America, we don't expect it to be a big financial contributor in 2013. But, the launch of Intacta in Brazil this year is a major strategic milestone which we show on slide 13. In fact, the Intacta opportunity is among the biggest single drivers that we see over the next few years. We see Intacta as a step-change for soybean farmers. And, farmers' own data from our recent Ground Breakers trials showed yield benefits of better than 4 bushels an acre. This creates somewhere around $80 an acre in total value for our customers, so the appetite for this technology is very strong. And, as we launch it this year, the portion of that benefit that we capture becomes a major financial step-up compared with the first-generation Roundup Ready in Brazil. If you pair that with the increasing optimism that we have for taking this technology to Argentina, Paraguay, and Uruguay and the total opportunity over the next several years targets more than 100 million South American soybean acres.</p>
          <p>From Latin America, I want to zoom out to the next big piece of our 2013 global opportunity and that's our corn-breeding opportunity, highlighted on slide 14. Rob Fraley often talks internally about our breeding engine being our biggest but our least appreciated blockbuster. It's an engine that allows us to upgrade a significant portion of our product portfolio across crops and across our most important geographies every single year. And just like what I described in the U.S., that upgrade creates the mix, pricing, and volume opportunity that drives our international business. You see this in 2013, as we expect our corn business to grow in conventional seed markets, ranging from Mexico to Western Europe.</p>
          <p>But, perhaps the best near-term example of that opportunity is in Eastern Europe, on slide 15. The corn footprint in Eastern Europe is as big as Brazil and it's been expanding. We fast tracked our breeding upgrades, drawing on the translation that we get as we take our leading U.S. germplasm into this market. In the past few years, we've nearly doubled our share and became one of the leading seed companies in Eastern Europe. And, with the expanding acres and our ability to upgrade our offerings every year, this is another of the fastest-growing businesses in our global family.</p>
          <p>From that picture of the big growth drivers, there's a couple of areas that round out our growth projections. Notably, we expect the vegetable business to rebound to growth in 2013. Going into next year, we see more diversified geographic growth and some early contributions from new products, returning this business to a growth mode, on its way to becoming our third largest crop in the coming years. Second, within the seed business, we continue to see steady contribution from our cotton business. This is actually one of the highest margin platforms that we have so we continue to see it contributing to our margin opportunities.</p>
          <p>And, no conversation about growth is complete without a nod to our R&amp;D. By definition, the pipeline isn't a contributor to 2013 earnings but is definitively the driver that will turn over the next layers of growth beyond this year. Today, we have more platforms that will drive yield than ever before. You can see that in slide 16. Considering the output of all the platforms, we have the potential to launch a major new innovation that steps up yield every year this decade. And, we've turned over some new cards and opportunities like Integrated Farming Systems and our BioDirect platform that establish the line of sight on new growth, beginning as soon as 2014.</p>
          <p>It's one thing to crystallize these growth drivers on a call like this, but I also think there's real power in seeing the products and the technology behind the business first-hand. So, this year our Whistle Stop Tour will highlight these future growth drivers to give you that first-hand view. We hope many of you will be able to join us in August to experience our technology, talk to our teams, and see this growth in action.</p>
          <p>So, before I hand it off to Pierre, let me leave you with the key points that strike me as we now bridge between 2012 and look forward into 2013. First, I like our momentum. With back-to-back years of 20% plus ongoing earnings growth, we're firmly in a growth mode. We have a strong strategy in place, and I'm very pleased with our execution. Second, there's more opportunity to come. Despite the annual focus on commodity prices, acres, and yields, the reality is the demand driving global agriculture is real and it's growing and that creates a lot of opportunity for a long, long time. And, third that opportunity is translating into tangible growth for Monsanto. If we combine our momentum and the overall opportunity, I feel as good about our growth going into a year as I have in a long time. We have more growth drivers than ever in my time as CEO and those fundamentals carry us to further growth in the future.</p>
          <p>So, thanks again, and with the remaining time, let me it hand over to Pierre.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Hugh, and good morning to everyone. Today, Hugh laid out the cases for how we see our growth objectives in 2013. As CFO, there are three things I want to add to the discussion to help provide some color on how we see the growth translating into our financial statements.</p>
          <p>First, I want to reinforce our fiscal year 2012 guidance and use the third quarter data to complete the financial picture of our view of the year. Second, I want to highlight the key drivers for the trends we see carrying into 2013 financials. And, third, I want to speak to how we see that growth translating into cash and enabling our strategy for cash deployments.</p>
          <p>Let me start with a practical look at the walkthrough of our guidance on slide 17. As I consider our financials, the most important point for me is that the data for the third quarter really validates the trend we expected coming into the year. The first point is that the majority of total growth came from Seeds and Genomics and that's certainly consistent with what we laid out coming into the year. In general, we entered the year with a range of expectations for the key drivers in Seeds and Genomics and through the third quarter, with the exception of vegetables, those businesses are all delivering at the high end of those early expectations. So, taken together, you'll see the strength reflected in our step-up of gross profit guidance for Seeds and Genomics to between $6 billion and $6.05 billion for this year.</p>
          <p>Secondly, Hugh didn't spend any time talking about our Ag Productivity segment as we continue to see that as a steady contributor, another source of significant incremental growth, but for this fiscal year, we track very nicely against our strategy and we've seen some upside in each of the three businesses within this segment. This performance is reflected in our new full-year gross profit expectation of approximately $900 million. Practically, I think we're in a good steady-state run rate for this business, and our planning assumes a relatively consistent band for the segment going forward.</p>
          <p>Third, on the cost side with the acceleration of the business this year, we've used some additional SG&amp;A in the form of commissions and some investments in our people, structure, and organization. Likewise, with some of the expanded R&amp;D platforms that Hugh mentioned, we've made some incremental investments in our research this year. As a result of the accelerated business growth and the investments in both categories, I see us potentially above the upper end of our original ranges for SG&amp;A and R&amp;D for the full year. So, as we round out this year, we feel very good about our bottom-line guidance of $3.65 to $3.70 of ongoing EPS and at the high end of that, we will deliver up to 25% growth in ongoing earnings from last year.</p>
          <p>From here, the last talking point in the fiscal year will be the fourth quarter. Given the pattern of earnings flow for the third quarter, we expect a larger loss in the fourth quarter this year than we saw last year. As I look at the key business drivers in the fourth quarter, the biggest strategic element is the corn business in Brazil that Hugh emphasized and the early season check for Brazil corn is going very well so we expect it to be a positive factor in Q4. However, as we previously mentioned, the earning power of that factor won't fully offset the incremental changes we see in other areas, including the timing of the Australian cut in trade fees, the lower relative soybean POD revenue in Brazil, and some of the additional operating expenses that come in the quarter.</p>
          <p>If I now shift from this practical look at the financials to some of the trends behind the numbers, I think it helps establish a couple of the early guideposts to translate the growth Hugh described into our financial outlook for 2013 and we provide a couple of looks at our fiscal year 2012 financials on slide 18. First, our growth in 2012 has been split evenly between the U.S. contribution and growth from our international regions. The strong growth rate in international regions like Latin America and Eastern Europe provide a very nice complement to the core expansion in our U.S. business, and our growth mix next year should be near the 50-50 ratio we see this year.</p>
          <p>Now, if we look at the second cut, our growth this year tracks roughly 40% from volume and 60% from price and mix. The clear majority of that price and mix comes from the mix side as the strong adoption of technology and the annual breeding upgrade Hugh emphasized provide a significant benefit. And, as I think about 2013, we expect those core upgrades will drive more of our growth, and the price/mix component will be an even stronger contributor to growth than it was this year.</p>
          <p>Third, if I now look at the sources of our Seeds and Genomics growth in 2012, we see the strong majority coming directly from the fundamentals, the strategic drivers of the business, while a smaller portion reflects the benefit of the uptake in global acres this year. Given so much of the growth is driven by the strong fundamentals of the business, it reinforces our confidence that the strategic levers Hugh laid out really underscore our opportunity for 2013.</p>
          <p>And, as always, as we lay out our planning for 2013, we recognize some of the structural variability in agriculture, and we build our plan around a range of assumptions. Practically, we do not plan that the 2012 spike in corn acres will repeat or that some of the peak spot prices on commodities will hold. Rather, our assumed acre and commodity price bands reflect the ranges we've seen over the past few years and that approach to some of the key macro variables reinforces our confidence in our ability to deliver our business results in the normal ebbs and flows of our industry.</p>
          <p>As we look at the final translation into 2013, the last point I want to make is around the strategy for cash. In 2012, we again see the cash generation capability of our business, and I'm particularly pleased to highlight that we see ourselves as a technology company that is able to deliver consistent and strong cash flow. Converting earnings into cash is one of my clear priorities. As we use that cash, I continue to see investment in the business as a priority, especially in areas that can add to our growth opportunities. In the last quarter, we announced a technology acquisition that will help accelerate our efforts in integrating farming systems, and we are always looking for further acquisitions that can build out some of our growth platforms.</p>
          <p>Our strong cash flow also allows us to prioritize the value we can return to shareowners. Over the past few years we've tried to strike a balance between our share buyback program and our dividend payouts. With some additional buybacks in the third quarter, we are nearing the end of our current authorization. And, in the last month, our Board authorized a new $1-billion program which we expect will allow us to continue our ongoing buyback activity.</p>
          <p>Through the third quarter, we've used a total of more than $900 million on dividends and share buybacks or almost half of our projected full-year free cash flow. As I think about the next step in cash deployment, today we are actively looking at how we can drive this cash strategy to further optimize how we translate the continuing growth in our core business into new opportunities and more return for our shareowners.</p>
          <p>Let me conclude by stepping back from the numbers for a moment. I'd summarize by telling you that there are two things I'd take away from this third quarter. First, the third quarter is a punctuation mark that validates the strong year we've delivered financially. With up to 25% ongoing EPS growth, we've seen growth come from where we expected to see it and we are on track with a strategy based on strong fundamental business drivers. Second, we take a very clear-eyed view on 2013 and when we do that, we see compelling opportunities that give us the confidence to project financial growth even from this higher base. With the business engine that's in place, I am confident in our ability to deliver in 2013.</p>
          <p>With that, let me turn it back over to Bryan for the question period.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Pierre. We'd now like to open up the call for questions, and as we typically do I'll ask that you please hold your questions to one per person so that we can take questions from as many people as possible, and you'll always be welcome to rejoin the queue for a follow up question.</p>
          <p>With that, Lewis, I think we're ready to take questions from the line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now be conducting a question-and-answer session. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from the line of Jeff Zekauskas with JPMorgan Chase. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jeff.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For the nine-month period, were your U.S. soybean seed volumes up or down? And for the nine-month period, were your U.S. corn seed volumes above 6% or below 6% in volume?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeff, thanks for the question. I'll maybe ask Pierre to say a few words, but directionally on both of them, they're both up. So we're pleased on &#x2013; as I mentioned in my remarks, we're pleased on volume growth because they were up and they were ahead of the market in both segments. But, Pierre, I don't know if you have any other color on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean maybe the only color we can give is that, in both cases, we see our growth in volume faster than what the market has been reflecting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yup, yup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yup, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of David Begleiter with Deutsche Bank. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, David.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>You had just given the weather stresses in the Midwest. Are you expecting more differential performance for your corn seeds this year, given your enhanced germplasm? And could that benefit &#x2013; would that benefit 2013 market share gains?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I &#x2013; so nobody celebrates lousy weather and it is warm and dry. I was driving in this morning &#x2013; they're talking about 108 degrees here in St. Louis in the next couple days, so it's a warm, dry stretch. I think what you're alluding to, David, is our genetics tend to do well in warm dry conditions.</p>
          <p>Our roots and stocks perform better than our competitors in these conditions. It's not something that you would hope for, but we have an edge in that. This year, we're feeling good about share gain in both corn and in soy and I think that die is cast this year, but it generally helps if they see that performance in the field, when growers are making up their mind this fall.</p>
          <p>But I'm kind of playing for harvest this year before we get into that. I mean we're &#x2013; the reality is we're growing a lot of seed ourselves. The vast majority of that is irrigated, but it would be real nice to see a splash of rain at some point.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, thanks for the question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Vincent Andrews with Morgan Stanley. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and good morning, everyone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Kind of the question is, we're about to have another year of difficult weather, probably much lower than expected yields and then who knows this plays out, but it certainly feels like it's headed into the low 150s, if not into the 140s. Can you talk a little bit about &#x2013; seed supply was tighter than normal this year, particularly with the smaller manufacturers, can you talk a little bit about where that would go next year, let's assume the yield is between 145 and 155, how tight could the seed market be at both ends of that band, assuming we have to plant another 96 million acres of corn?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Vincent, thanks for the &#x2013; I mean that's a multi-factorial one. So as I mentioned in the previous point, we are growing seeds right now, the majority of our seed &#x2013; not all &#x2013; but the majority of that seed is irrigated and it is geographically very diverse. I think for some of the smaller producers, the way this year's setting up, you could see a repeat performance the last production season where it's going to be tight for some of them and there is a possibility for all of us in the market, if this continues, that we could be looking a little bit more towards Latin American production in the back end of the year. But I would remind you that even with the tight production constraints in this last season, we felt confident in our ability to supply a 96 million acre market and that's what we'll gear our production against this year as well. So it's still an early call, but it is very, very warm and very &#x2013; even have been <mark type="indiscernible" /> (32:27), but I don't think &#x2013; we're going to be a lot smarter in a month's time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just as a follow up, the amount of winter production that you budgeted into your sort of mid-teens growth forecast for next year, is that above or below normal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's within averages and the one point, Vincent, is &#x2013; I mean that's one of the points we made &#x2013; I mean we are budgeting the market next year to be in a range which is consistent with the last couple of years, so we're not shooting for a 96 million acres in our mid-teen guidance. I mean I think it's an important point there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, understood. Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>In fact, Pierre, you would say...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We're looking at a range in between 92 million and 94 million acres in the U.S. This is what we based our plan on. Having said so, as Hugh mentioned, we feel comfortable if the market was going to spike up again, we'd be ready to supply the market. But this is not the base for our financial assumptions in our mid-teens guidance next year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Michael Piken with Cleveland Research Company. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, hi, congratulations on a good year. I just wanted to follow up on the South American opportunity. You guys had talked about in Argentina that Triple PRO could reach up to one-third of the portfolio this year, and I was wondering if you could give some more sort of number for the Double PRO in Brazil? And then similarly on Intacta, if you could give us any sort of outline for kind of your expectations for fiscal 2014 and would we expect to see a similar type of slow ramp up in year one in fiscal 2014? And how quickly that could ramp up? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll say a few words on Intacta and Pierre maybe say a lot better on Argentina. So Intacta is going to be a really significant product for us. Next year is our launch year. That's going to be small. We will be constrained in the amount of seed that we have available. So the way I would think of it, Intacta in Brazil, is 2013 is the set up year. It's financially immaterial, but it really sets up 2014 and particularly 2015. So 2013 is a tee up for two big years in Brazil, and we continue to make steady progress in Argentina. So Pierre and I were down in Brazil recently, we saw the pre-launch activities. But I think Intacta is all we play for.</p>
          <p>And then corn is quite different. Corn, the opportunity is very near and present. And maybe a few words on that Pierre.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. To come back to your question regarding how we are thinking about Double PRO in Brazil, so Double PRO is going to be our second largest, I mean the second largest part of our portfolio next year in Brazil. And actually the key limitation there is our ability to ramp it up fast enough. So it is going to be the second largest, and we are looking at potentially a third of our mix which still leaves us a lot of runway. But as I mentioned, I mean here the critical factor is definitely our ability to ramp it up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of P.J. Juvekar with Citigroup. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Hi. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, P.J.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So question on Brazil, and how do you get paid there and how much do you get paid there? Your POD system is getting challenged in the courts and so how do you protect your franchise down there? And secondly, on Intacta you mentioned that you expect savings up to $80 per acre. Do you believe that you can capture one-third of that savings just like you do in the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>P.J., thanks for the question. So &#x2013; and let me start with Intacta, so as I mentioned in the last conference, Intacta has the capacity to be a game changer. Growers spend more on insect control than they spend on weed control in Brazil. It rains at the same time every day. A lot of it is equatorial conditions, and insects, they can skeletonize a crop. So you're right, we're creating about $80 worth of value on an acre, and that has consistently proven out on our Ground Breaker trials. And we've not declared on pricing, but I think a third to a quarter of that $80 value would be a reasonable benchmark on thinking about how we would share that through.</p>
          <p>On POD, just two or three points; I don't think there's much new here. We've seen challenges repeatedly over the years. The way I would think about it is the system is eight years old or seven &#x2013; seven or eight years old. Before the system was set up, we never had any capacity for capturing value. If you look at this last year, the amazing thing that's changed in our collection system is in this last year we sold more bags of soybean seeds than we did &#x2013; we captured value through fresh bags of brand-new seeds than we did off the back of trucks at collections. So it's a dynamic system, and it's changing. And farmers are recognizing the value of new genetics and fresh seed every year, especially when you look at global prices of soybeans, so you should never say never but I'm encouraged with the trends that are occurring there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Mark Connelly with CLSA. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. When we look at the issues that we've seen in the last few months on cotton, we've got &#x2013; we're planting less in the U.S. We've got the policy flip-flop in India. Now we've got questions about dominant resistance in China. I'm just wondering how you're thinking about cotton's position in your portfolio, especially after you say that vegetables is going to be number three. I mean, do you think that cotton has peaked?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for the question. You're right, we've seen a bit of a retreat on acres but we saw a gigantic spike last year. So if you normalize the curve and you look over five years, I'm less concerned about the acres in the U.S.</p>
          <p>The flip-flop in India, just to kind of put a bit of color on that, India held back domestic supply. In other words, they sat on exports for a while. As I understand it, they've open the doors again and they've had record crops and now beginning to be exported again. So as I mentioned in my remarks, cotton on an acre is one of our most profitable crops. I think that we'll see cotton being eclipsed by vegetables but that's not a weakness in cotton, it's a strength in veggies.</p>
          <p>And if you look, we've just finished our five-year plan and I would say directionally when you look at that five-year plan and you get in the year four and five, probably more than five to four, we see with our acquisitions the vegetable business having the capacity to pass cotton. But I don't want it to be seen that cotton is going to be downgraded. And so I think continued improvements in Bollgard, the run out of dicamba tolerant genes on top of that, there's a good story in cotton going forward as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Laurence Alexander with Jefferies &amp; Company. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Could you tease out a little bit more detail the path for the vegetable business that is how much of it is going to be volume versus margin and particularly on the margin, how much of it is back end loaded?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm going to say a few words and ask Pierre to give you a little bit on mix. I think &#x2013; as I mentioned in my remarks, I think next year we'll see &#x2013; we haven't laid much of this out but next year we'll see the front-end of some new products coming and with those new products you get the opportunity to look out a little bit at price and the value that you create and a little bit of margin uptick that comes with that. We've cleaned a lot of obsolescence so that's a one-time effect. And we're not optimistic that we'll see a turnaround in Europe next year, but when you look to the East, there's a crescent and I'll let Pierre talk a little bit more about this, but I think we don't expect to rebound in Europe but we see some of these other markets picking up, Pierre, right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah and where we see the growth, I mean, in the next couple of years is definitely in adjusting our efforts, I mean, in Eastern Europe, the Middle East where we've seen a lot of the business go over the last couple of years and so, as Hugh mentioned, we've done a lot of work in Western Europe to clean up our portfolio and adjust our business model there but we are also expanding, I mean, in the Middle East specifically but also in India and potentially in China, so this is where we're going to be seeing, I mean, volume gains definitely. And as Hugh mentioned, we are starting to see some of the products coming out of our breeding pipeline that are going to be bringing some additional value. So it's really redeploying our resources and really looking at the market and then bringing the new products, I mean, we've been putting together over the last couple of years. This is how we see this business definitely rebound.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Frank Mitsch with Wells Fargo Securities. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, gentlemen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Frank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hey, Pierre, I wanted to follow up on your comment on use of cash flow. You were indicating that year-to-date that 50% has been spent on share buyback and dividend, but then right after that you seemed to veer into more focus on growth and I'm not sure if you were signaling M&amp;A or organic means to grow. So I was wondering if you could expand upon that and while you're at it, if you could also offer some comments with respect to the recent Precision Planting acquisition?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So what we've been doing over the last couple of years, I mean, regarding our cash flow and regarding return to shareowners, what we've tried to do is strike a balance in-between the use of our dividends and buybacks and we came roughly to a 50-50 type of balance and right now, I mean, we've got a very strong balance sheet. We've got, I mean, enough free cash to generate a lot of our own growth and we're looking at how to redeploy this cash on an M&amp;A perspective as you mentioned, but also how we can return the cash more efficiently to our shareowners. So this is really what we are signaling here. We're taking a hard look at how can we optimize the return to our shareowners through buybacks and dividends as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, so that might be a faster pace of buyback than just the typical offsetting of dilution thing, possibly?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we've not made any decisions at this point and we are really taking a hard look at it and taking inputs there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then, Frank, you mentioned Precision Planting so just &#x2013; I'll be really brief, but a couple of words on our whole precision agriculture or IFS, integrated farm solutions. So we are looking at &#x2013; if you look at growers today, one grower told me I'm data rich and insight poor. So they're drowning in data, but they're looking for the key data that leverages their decisions, and they're looking for that data on a timely manner. And our acquisition of Precision Planting over in Illinois I think is a first and a cornerstone acquisition for us as an investment in this space. So we are going to be building models that allow the grower to access prescriptions that unlock more yield on an acre.</p>
          <p>In the last two years with our own field trials that Rob and his team have led, we're seeing with big growers who are already sophisticated; we're seeing 8 to 10 new bushels of corn on an acre using some of these systems. So more accurate planting, more controlled spacing, a number of hybrids planted across the same field; we're seeing 8 to 10 new bushels, which I kind of think of as literally a new trait. And if we can deliver consistently and predictably 8 to 10 new bushels, there's a business in there. So I'm very excited with the deal we've done with Precision Planting, and I think we will be investing more in this space.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for the questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Duffy Fischer with Barclays. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. If we could go back to Intacta for a second, just three questions on that. Which countries do we need to see the export approvals before we're willing to launch, would be one? Two, if you go into Argentina, how do you protect the IP down there relative to what happened with Roundup Ready the first time around? And then just, three, on the launch in general, a lot of the stats look similar to the launch for Roundup Ready in the U.S. that didn't go as planned. Kind of what are the differences in how you're going to launch down in Brazil? How much more research have you done? Did the actual yield benefits &#x2013; are there and will be seen by the farmers in the first couple of years? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thanks for the questions. So if I can just remember them &#x2013; the first one we're still waiting on Chinese approval, so that's still to come. The others have come in good order and actually ahead of the tape. So we're waiting on China, and that would be our last approval before we rolled.</p>
          <p>Your other question was Argentina and what makes us feel better about Argentina? We've been rehearsing in Argentina for nearly a decade. So we've been waiting on the opportunity that Intacta brings. If you think about what needs to happen in Argentina, there's four or five areas, I'd just kind of quickly run through. One is IP and establishing a patent down there for Intacta. We've achieved that. That's in place. We've submitted for regulatory approval, so that's pending. The third one would be forming direct agreements, so contractual agreements with growers. And we've made really good progress there. And we're in discussions with the grain handlers there.</p>
          <p>And I would say I feel good about the progress we've made across those four areas. And when we have green lights in those four areas, then we would be good to go in Argentina.</p>
          <p>And then your last question, one was...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just around the U.S. Roundup Ready launch versus down there, and what the differences will be?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, and that's a great question. So lessons learned. I think we garnered &#x2013; I think we all learned a lot with the U.S. launch, and our conclusion coming out of that U.S. launch was we were going to work much more closely with our grower customers when we rolled new technologies. And we started a beta testing system that we call Ground Breakers, and I can tell you, Pierre and I and Rob Fraley were there and met 150-ish of the 500 Ground Breaker growers in Brazil and the lesson learned is, working directly with 500 people who are advocates for the technology, they've touched the product itself, they can talk directly about the weed control, the yield improvement, the insect control and that's a groundswell movement.</p>
          <p>So, having that group in a room talking about their experience with technology, I don't think there's any substitute for that. So that's really an absolute offshoot from what we went through in the U.S. We've got Ground Breakers in Brazil. We have Ground Breakers this year right now in drought testing in the U.S., and next year we'll have a significant Ground Breaker program in the U.S. on our Roundup Ready 2 by dicamba soybeans. So all that came directly out of the early launches in the U.S. So that's how I would think about it. It's leveraging wisdom.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Don Carson with Susquehanna Financial. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Hugh, I want to go back to the U.S. market, I mean this was the first year you appeared to have a more segmented strategy and I know you had significant amounts of VT Double PRO available. Was that the key driver of the upside in volumes to the Reduced-Refuge Family? And how do you see that benefiting you from a share and earnings standpoint as you go forward? And will &#x2013; you mentioned &#x2013; just mentioned the Ground Breaker and drought-tolerant corn. Will that enhance your position in the Western Corn Belt as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Don, thanks for the questions. So it's interesting. I would say that the Reduced-Refuge Family across the board grew. We increased &#x2013; as we predicted &#x2013; we increased the number of hybrids in SmartStax. The Double PRO was a brand-new segment for us and we were really limited in availability. So this year we had a reasonable amount of volume and it was being placed in markets that we were largely absent from. So if you think about the Western Corn Belt, we were competing with &#x2013; we're directly competing with our competitors with an improved offering with a Double PRO Reduced-Refuge, so it was a really powerful combination.</p>
          <p>I think as we're looking at 2013, there's even more that we can do in that space. So I don't think we've really seen the full capacity of Double PRO playing out and I'm optimistic about what we see in 2013.</p>
          <p>If I look across our growth this year, we were up in volume. We beat the market &#x2013; so Pierre's point, we outperformed. So we grew faster than a growing market and I think a big piece of that was, number one, our yields. We outperformed in yields, and when farmers put their hands in their pocket this year, they were looking at yield data from a year earlier. Number two, as to your point, is Reduced-Refuge and the growth in that platform; and number three, is Refuge in the Bag. I think that was a game changer and when farmers got a RIB, they're not going back. It brings convenience, ease and better recordkeeping, and I think it was the three of those in combination that really drove velocity this year. And the nice thing about it is, it plays into 2013 as well, so it's not a one-off effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just a follow-up on that, what was your availability of VT Double PRO this year? How much more could you have sold? And just remind us what your market share is in that double stack territory versus your say 37% national market share?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's a lot less than our national market share. We were latecomers to the segment and it was the part of the country where we were visitors, but we weren't resident. So it's &#x2013; we've made a mark, but there's a long way to go. We've never broken that out, Don, but if you kind of think about it as 2011, 2012 and 2013 &#x2013; 2011 we'd a handful of seeds; 2012 it was meaningful; and 2013 we won't be short. So that's kind of how I think about it. 2011 was the tryout; there was a lot of people interested. 2012 we placed it on with key customers and got a bit more traction, but 2013 will be unconstrained.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Michael Cox with Piper Jaffray. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks a lot and congratulations on a nice quarter guys. My first question is, I was hoping you could discuss the size of the field trials for the prescription model this year as compared to what you've done last year, perhaps the last couple of years, and as you gear up to a 2014 launch of that prescription model? And then a quick follow-up, if I could. Has Latin America grown to become large enough that as I look at your fiscal first and fourth quarters combined, could you be making money in total in those shoulder quarters in 2013?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pierre, maybe start with the shoulder quarters and how you think about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So when you look at fourth and first quarter, so fourth quarter of this year, first quarter of next year, we're definitely expecting to see growth coming from South America and the South American corn business. I don't think it's going to get us into a EPS positive range next year in 2013. We're not going to be there yet. But definitely we should see some growth coming from South America and mostly our corn business there. So growing but still I think when you look at those two quarters, those are still going to be loss for us in the foreseeable future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then your other question on IFS and scale, here's kind of how I think about it. This year will be hundreds of growers on thousands and thousands of acres. So it's bigger than small-scale field trials, but it's still sub-threshold in terms of commercialization. If you pan out to 2014, just to give you an idea of this curve, and I think this is &#x2013; it's maybe not absolutely</p>
          <p>Right, but it's directionally correct. If you think to 2014 we'd be on 1.5 million to 2 million acres. So if you think the progression in 2012, 2013, 2014 we'd be on a couple of million acres by 2014 with these programs.</p>
          <p>The interesting thing for me is when we look at these progressive, sophisticated growers and the work we've done in the last few years, these are farmers, these are growers that are looking for that next increment, but feel that they've maxed out. So that next increment is that they're stretching, but they can't see it. And the encouraging piece is if you can unfold eight to ten new bushels on the front-end of these growers through predictive systems, then as we build predictive algorithms and start to aggregate this data, I think this has the capacity of going pretty fast once we start rolling.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Kevin McCarthy with Bank of America Merrill Lynch. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. Hugh, I guess two questions for you on the subject of prospective seed pricing for fiscal 2013. First, is the contribution in terms of price mix likely to be larger for corn or soybeans or about the same for the two crops in North America? And then second, with regard to pricing and also in light of the really sharp volatility we've seen in the commodity complex in the last couple of weeks, should we be thinking of your pricing decisions as wholly decoupled from commodity price volatility at this point? Or is there flexibility to move within the ranges that you've outlined?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Kevin, thank you. So I'll take a swing at this and then invite Pierre for any add-on. I think, we said this year we were about &#x2013; price gains of about 5% to 10% and we kind of tipped our hats that we would be looking somewhere in that region coming into the new year. I mean it's the delicious irony of this business. We are worried about what the crop is going to be this year and what it's going to yield and we're already talking about pricing for the spring of 2013. I think as a very rough guideline, 5% to 10% probably is a good touch point.</p>
          <p>There's probably a bit more strength in corn than in soy simply because of our technology offerings and the wide range of choices that we have in the technology breakouts in corn. Don mentioned Double PRO and the whole Reduced-Refuge Family.</p>
          <p>And then your second point on commodity pricing, so you're right, corn's had a big run-up in the last week, $6.50 corn and December price $6.50. This is going to be all over the place and I would kind of take your point, I think we're largely decoupled and I wouldn't be holding your breath on as pricing against a big run-up or as cutting the price on some kind of slump. So I think growers look at us as a significant piece of leverage on optimizing yield regardless of where that pricing band sits. And the lesson that we've learned, in a business that's seasonal and where we get rewarded for serving that grower year after year is, consistency is a big, big deal. And it's a big deal for our own organization. It's a big deal for the grower. So we're going to play into that I think more than we have &#x2013; than we had been doing. But Pierre, any other points?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, two things. The first one regarding the point Hugh was making regarding commodity prices; we don't price to commodity price every year. What we try to do is have a thinking that takes into account commodity price, but over a period of three to five years, and that's really what we're trying to do when driving our long-range plans. And our strategy is pricing to a range of commodity price within which we can have the mix upgrades we're looking at.</p>
          <p>The second point I wanted to make regarding your specific question around the impact of mix versus the fuel price, once again we are looking into mix being the key driver of our 5% to 10% price appreciation in 2013. So mix &#x2013; the mix upgrade from our germplasm and from the adoption of the Reduced-Refuge Family in the U.S. is going to be the key driver.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pierre &#x2013; at the risk of repetition I would just add one thing. Pierre made the point earlier, Kevin, we went in this year assuming 92 million and 94 million acres. And we went into this year with price assumptions of commodities of $4 to $6. I think as we sit here today and we think about next year, we are directionally in 92 million and 94 million acres again, and our pricing would be $4 to $6, so that may be kind of specifically addresses your concern. I think we would produce beyond that in the opportunity of a spike, but in terms of planning and budget and our mid-teens growth, we're not holding our breath for a blockbuster crop or gigantic prices.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's helpful. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Lewis, this is Bryan. I recognize we're running tight on time. Maybe we have time for two quick more questions, and then Hugh will wrap things up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from the line of Mark Gulley with Gulley &amp; Associates. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, my question has to do with the weather this year as well with drought conditions and all that. As you talk to your grower customers and how they look at rootworm pressure, and how they might alleviate some of the drought pressure, because they have more triple stacks, are you seeing a shift back towards triple stack corn, given the conditions that farmers are seeing the last three years, including this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Mark, thanks for your question. I'd say what we're seeing is the continued progression of SmartStax. So if you look at where they're placing their bets, particularly where they have had high infestations and particularly where they're reluctant to break corn on corn, because it's so profitable. They're moving more to SmartStax. And where they've been pushing us is increasing the range of hybrids and increasing the choice.</p>
          <p>So, if I look at our &#x2013; the translation from order books to planting, that's where we've seen the growth. And I would expect, you never know, but if you look at the long-term weather forecast, you look at what's playing out, I would anticipate as we go through harvesting in the back end of this year, that's where we're going to be pressed again as looking for more of that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Lewis, we can probably take one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>No problem. Our last question comes from the line of Bob Koort with Goldman Sachs. Please proceed with your question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Good morning.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Bob.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I appreciate the opportunity to not talk about European debt and Chinese industrial production. Hugh, you mentioned in the slide deck the progress you've made on Roundup Ready 2 beans, the three-quarters penetration on your brands, and needing maybe to get the licensees to catch up to you. What can you do to motivate them? And then how big of a hurdle is this, the patent expiration that's a couple of years out now?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Bob, thanks for the question. And I agree with you on agriculture is a good place to be right now. I think the biggest encouragement that we can give is the encouragement that we also receive, and that's the pull from growers. So it seems like 100 years ago, but when we launched these platforms and you're in that first million acres, this is show and tell, it's all push and there's skepticism because you're launching something that's never been seen. I think when you get to the size of these platforms, when you look at what we've achieved from a momentum point of view, this is the coffee shops and this is growers talk to growers and it's the old seeing-is-believing or the show-me state.</p>
          <p>Once you get to this point, it's never done-is-done, but there's a tremendous amount of enthusiasm, particularly with bean prices where they are right now. So the biggest encouragement we can give to licensees is yield differential and the performance, and this becomes the critical year with the amount of acres that we've got out there.</p>
          <p>So I &#x2013; you had a two-part question, what was your other piece? Was there &#x2013; did you have another point, Bob? No? So that was it and then the other piece I was going to add was dicamba and there is tremendous interest for dicamba tolerant beans. So as we look towards patent expiration, key for us was allowing growers the opportunity to see improved technologies early enough and I'm delighted with the progress that we've made and I'm looking forward to getting Ground Breaker trials out this next year on dicamba as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>So maybe, Bryan, I'll just wrap up. We've run over a little bit. I just &#x2013; let me thank you again for everybody that joined us on the call. The third quarter for us ironically is the last stopping point before we turn our attention to 2013. In many ways the year is done and we start looking into 2013.</p>
          <p>So let me just talk one more time about 2012. We feel very good about 2012. We captured momentum in our business and we've put together back-to-back years that prove out that we are in a growth mode. I think that sets up the fact that here at Monsanto, our teams feel equally good about 2013. We'll continue our strategy and that gives us a clearer line of sight on our growth than we've had in some previous years and that reinforces our confidence.</p>
          <p>And finally, as we highlight our growth in 2013, we're looking forward to giving you a firsthand look at some of the big drivers that we've covered today, our Whistle Stop event in August, and we all hope that many of you can make it and you'll get a chance to meet our talented people, many of them from our international businesses that will be there and you'll see why we're so excited about the growth that we have in our global businesses. So thanks very much for your support, and being with us this morning. All the best.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's teleconference. You may disconnect your lines at this time and thank you for your participation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>