<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1405385" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-07-29</date>
    <companies>
      <company>354</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Senior Vice President-Investor Relations">Alex Kelly</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President, Chief Executive Officer &amp; Director">Kenneth C. Frazier</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="President-Global Human Health &amp; Executive VP">Adam H. Schechter</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Peter N. Kellogg</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (United States)">Catherine Jayne Arnold</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities LLC">Marc Goodman</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Barclays Capital, Inc.">Alison Yang</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs &amp; Co.">Jami Rubin</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Sanford C. Bernstein &amp; Co., Inc.">Timothy M. Anderson</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Agricole Securities (USA), Inc.">David W. Maris</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank Securities, Inc.">Barbara A. Ryan</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Gregg Gilbert</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. LLC">David R. Risinger</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Leerink Swann LLC">Seamus Fernandez</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Cowen &amp; Co.">Steve Scala</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities LLC">Christopher T. Schott</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day everyone and welcome to Merck's second quarter 2011 earnings conference call. Today's call is being recorded. At this time I'd like to turn the call over to Alex Kelly, Senior Vice President of Investor Relations. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Brooke, and good morning everyone and welcome to Merck's 2011 second quarter earnings call. Before I turn the call over to Ken, I want to point out a couple of things.</p>
          <p>First, there are a number of items in the GAAP results in this quarter such as acquisition-related charges, restructuring costs and a one-time tax benefit. We have excluded those items in our non-GAAP reconciliation tables so you can get a better sense of the underlying performance.</p>
          <p>Next, we've also provided tables to help you understand the revenue trends so in our press release you see three tables, first table is the GAAP results, the second table reconciles GAAP to non-GAAP on the P&amp;L and the third table provides the sales results for the company, the products and the business units. During the call we'll be referring mostly to tables two and three when we discuss our performance.</p>
          <p>Finally I'd like to remind you that some of the statements we make during today's call may be considered forward-looking statements within the meaning of the Safe Harbor provisions of the U.S. Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. Such statements are based upon the current beliefs of Merck's management and are subject to significant risks and uncertainties.</p>
          <p>Our SEC filings, including item 1A in the 2010 10-K identify certain risk factors and cautionary statements that could cause the company's actual results to differ materially from those projected in any forward-looking statements we make today. Merck undertakes no obligation to publicly update any forward-looking statement. The SEC filings, as well as our earnings release and the tables are available on our website at Merck.com.</p>
          <p>So now we're ready to begin. This morning I'm joined by Ken Frazier, our President and Chief Executive Officer; Adam Schechter, our President of Global Human Health; and Peter Kellogg our Chief Financial Officer. Now I'd like to introduce Ken Frazier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Alex and good morning, everyone. This is a time of great opportunity at Merck and our second quarter, which was strong, is indicative of the focused progress we're making to deliver on the goals I outlined for you earlier this year. This quarter we delivered top line sales growth of 7%, driven by a strong in-line portfolio and new product launches together with disciplined expense management while allocating targeted resources to fund our future growth drivers. This resulted in double-digit non-GAAP EPS growth. That is our game plan and we are continuing to execute on all aspects of our growth strategy by maximizing our product portfolio, delivering the R&amp;D pipeline, expanding geographically, and building upon the newly renamed Merck Animal Health Division and Merck Consumer Care.</p>
          <p>We're delivering this top line growth while continuing our efforts to streamline and transform Merck's operating model. In terms of maximizing the current portfolio we had another quarter of double-digit growth for many of our key products such as JANUVIA, JANUMET, REMICADE and ISENTRESS. In addition, Merck Animal Health once again made solid contributions to our total performance.</p>
          <p>Another driver of our second quarter performance is the progress we're making in launching new products around the world. With more than a dozen product launches under way in various markets, we believe this speaks well of our ability to deliver new drugs from our research pipeline. As I said last quarter, we firmly believe that the predominant driver of long-term growth and sustainable value creation for Merck will continue to come from discovering and developing new and differentiated products that address unmet medical needs.</p>
          <p>VICTRELIS is just such a product. It is the first in class protease inhibitor and a significant medical advance. As you know, the U.S. launch is underway. We are concentrating our efforts to ensure that patients are treated appropriately with the new standard of care. While many physician prescribers thus far have yet to initiate patients on triple combination therapy, we're encouraged both by the early demand and positive feedback from physicians, payers and patients.</p>
          <p>It is hard to overstate how rewarding it is for the Merck team to be able to bring such a significant new product to patients who need it. Our recent approval in Brazil now makes VICTRELIS the first in this new class to be approved in the U.S, EU and Latin America. Adam will speak more about the VICTRELIS launch in a moment.  Beyond the VICTRELIS approvals we've also received three recent approvals in Japan: GARDASIL, ZOLINZA and CUBICIN.</p>
          <p>From a lifecycle management standpoint we filed two applications with the FDA. The first is for an expanded indication for both VYTORIN and ZETIA based on the data from the SHARP trial for the treatment of patients with chronic kidney disease. If approved, this will be the first and only cholesterol-lowering therapy with proven cardiovascular outcomes for this set of patients. The second is for a preservative-free formulation of COSOPT.</p>
          <p>We've also made additional progress in the pipeline by enrolling the first patients in the 30,000-patient anacetrapib outcomes trial. As I mentioned to you last quarter, we are not in a business as usual mode when it comes to managing our investments in R&amp;D. We continue to improve the decision process by which we either commit to or discontinue projects and we're being more aggressive about prioritizing the programs as well as the therapeutic areas where we will invest.</p>
          <p>With the number of important trials scheduled to complete in 2012 and 2013, we remain confident in Merck's late-stage pipeline and we look forward to telling you more about our progress at the R&amp;D and business briefing which is planned for November 10th.</p>
          <p>While our late-stage pipeline holds great promise, we know that to become a global healthcare leader we must tap into the research and pipeline opportunities wherever they are around the world. To do that, we have to be continuing our partnerships with the right companies.</p>
          <p>One such example is our strategic collaboration with Hanwha Chemical Corporation. Under the terms of this agreement, Hanwha and Merck will work together to develop and commercialize a biosimilar form of Enbrel, one of the leading biological products on the market today. This unique collaboration is entirely consistent with our approach to allocating investments across R&amp;D segments that reside at different points on the risk-reward continuum.</p>
          <p>This enables us to better balance risk and timing within our overall portfolio and maximize the value of our pipeline and inline product assets. Biosimilar candidates, for instance, can provide Merck with a solid return on investment with less product development risk relative to an unproven mechanism. Overall, we remain on track to have five biosimilar candidates in late-stage development by the end of 2012.</p>
          <p>Another key aspect of our growth strategy is geographic expansion. Just last week we announced an agreement with Simcere Pharmaceutical Group in China. This partnership leverages our marketing capabilities and Simcere's broad reach in China's emerging cities to increase access to medicines while providing potential for near-term commercial benefits to both companies. Overall, this agreement increases Merck's presence in China while also helping us to operate in this must-win market with margins consistent with a profitable growth strategy. Meanwhile, we're seeing strong year-over-year growth of 30% in China.</p>
          <p>Moving on to operations, this is a time of ongoing transformation as we reshape our company to adapt to our changing environment while becoming more lean and nimble. We remain on course to achieve our $3.5 billion target merger cost savings by the end of 2012. We remain on track.</p>
          <p>Beyond this, however, we believe we need to do more. As I've said previously, we are committed to growing our company. To do that, we are moving on from our initial merger integration targets to focus even more aggressively on reducing our cost structure so that we can continue to invest in profitable growth. Therefore, today we announced a new phase of our merger restructuring program which we first began in February of 2010. The program is designed to further optimize our cost structure.</p>
          <p>Here are the highlights of the phase we announced today. We plan to reduce our combined workforce by an additional 13% by 2015. These planned job reductions will come disproportionately from the elimination of non-revenue-generating positions such as administrative and headquarters personnel, consolidation of office facilities and ongoing sale or closure of manufacturing sites including animal health facilities. Importantly, at the same time as we are reducing our overall employee base, we have been hiring and will continue to hire in key areas like emerging markets where we have significant growth opportunities before us. We also expect to realize additional annual cost savings of $1.3 billion to $1.5 billion.</p>
          <p>My intent is that most of this will drop to the bottom line through a combination of investments that produce top-line growth and reductions in our operating cost base by the end of 2015. Depending on the opportunities in front of us, we will reinvest some of the savings whenever the returns justify the investment to drive longer term growth and profitability. This will enable us to boost both near and longer term profit margins and ensure that we can be fast and flexible in capitalizing on the best growth opportunities whenever they arise.</p>
          <p>For our people, this won't be easy. But the realities of our environment dictate the need to operate more flexibly and nimbly from a lower cost base. We are taking these difficult actions now so that we can grow profitably and continue to deliver on our mission well into the future. By improving the effectiveness and efficiency of our operations and focusing on ways to deliver customer values through innovation, we are positioning Merck for sustained profitable growth.</p>
          <p>In closing, Merck remains totally focused on growing both the top and bottom lines. Our results demonstrate our ability to do just that as well as advance the pipeline and establish innovative partnerships which will support our growth strategy. I believe we are well positioned to continue accelerating our momentum, leveraging the benefits of the merger and delivering on our mission to discover, develop and provide innovative products and services that save and improve lives around the world. Thank you for listening and I'd like to now turn the call over to Adam.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Ken and good morning everyone. It's a pleasure to speak with you today and provide you with an overview of the performance of Global Human Health. Global Human Health had another strong quarter with revenue growth of 7.5% or 3% excluding the impact of foreign exchange. The acceleration of our human health top-line sales to $10.4 billion was driven by growth across all regions and double-digit growth for several of our largest products.</p>
          <p>We are continuing to execute on our commercial growth strategy that I discussed last quarter and we're doing that through the following: Growing our core business, expanding our core business, and accelerating new launches such as VICTRELIS. We will do this while making smart and timely investments in the growth opportunities before us and by focusing on the needs of our customers.</p>
          <p>So first let me focus on what grew in the core business which includes the largest, most developed markets. I'll start with the United States. The United States represents about 40% of our pharmaceutical and vaccine sales. U.S. sales grew 2% year-over-year and were driven by double-digit growth from our diabetes, infectious disease, neuroscience and vaccine businesses. Our core brands, such as JANUVIA and ISENTRESS continue their consistent strong growth. This quarter we also had solid contributions from GARDASIL and better supply levels of ZOSTAVAX which is encouraging. The fast growth of these brands was offset by lower sales in our respiratory franchise due to a slow allergy season and lower U.S. sales for our cholesterol franchise. The overall positive performance in the United States shows the benefits of having a strong portfolio of diverse brands in multiple therapeutic areas.</p>
          <p>Moving to Europe and Canada, sales were up 9% this quarter driven by double-digit growth of our diabetes, immunology and infectious disease franchises, the favorable impact of foreign exchange and the impact from movement in inventory ahead of our SAP implementation in Europe. The growth was achieved despite approximately $250 million of unfavorable impact from EU austerity measures, generic erosion and the return of Subutex and Caelyx. We continue to see the EU as an area of long-term opportunity for differentiated brands despite many of the macro challenges in the individual markets.</p>
          <p>Moving on to other areas of growing the core, there are several brands that stand out as examples of winning through differentiation and execution. Let me start with JANUVIA and JANUMET which grew 35% this quarter. With only five years on the market the JANUVIA and JANUMET franchise is our second largest franchise and now has 26% market share in the global branded oral anti-diabetes market. We are investing globally and locally in JANUVIA and JANUMET to ensure we continue to grow the business and capitalize on all market opportunities. We are also investing in lifecycle management as we have multiple fixed dose combinations under regulatory review.</p>
          <p>Moving to SINGULAIR, sales grew 8% driven by the strong growth in Japan and U.S. pricing which was offset by a lighter than expected allergy season in the United States as well as austerity measures in Europe and Turkey.</p>
          <p>In immunology franchise strong REMICADE sales with about 26% year-over-year growth were driven largely by class leading share of the gastrointestinal indications. We are enthusiastic about the opportunities ahead for REMICADE as we leverage our robust lifecycle management platform and grow the brand in the retained markets. As a reminder, as of July 1st, we have retained territories representing about 70% of our 2010 REMICADE sales as part of our arbitration settlement. In the markets that we're retaining: Europe, Russia, and Turkey, REMICADE sales were $552 million.</p>
          <p>Combined sales of VYTORIN and ZETIA were flat in the quarter as sales growth in international markets offset declines in the United States. The international performance was driven by growth in Japan and the emerging markets. This quarter we also submitted supplemental applications to the U.S. and European authorities for the use of VYTORIN and ZETIA in the treatment of patients with chronic kidney disease based upon the findings from the SHARP trial.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to discuss how we're expanding the core. As part of expanding the core strategy, we're making planned and opportunistic investments to grow our business in the fastest growing market: the emerging markets and Japan. In the second quarter we invested in excess of $100 million more in emerging markets than we did last year and those investments are paying off. I'll start with the emerging markets which grew 10% to $1.9 billion in the quarter and contributed 18% of our total GHH sales. The growth was driven by the top six markets which grew a combined 12%. We continue to see the benefits of our strategy and investments in high-growth markets like China and Korea.</p>
          <p>In China, sales were $206 million growing 30% driven by the infectious disease and respiratory franchises. Our growth in 2011 has consistently exceeded market growth and is being driven by the top 10 products which account for 90% of the sales and growth in China.</p>
          <p>One of the opportunities we have is to expand our reach with our core brands in China and we believe it's important to partner with a local Chinese company. Therefore, we've entered into important partnership with Simcere. This JV will give us greater reach and a broader portfolio in the fast-growing cardiovascular market in China. Unlike some deals which take time to develop, we believe the Simcere partnership will provide immediate benefits in 2012 that will build over time. We look forward to building the JV with our partner and are looking for further opportunities to expand the JV in the future.</p>
          <p>We're also expanding the core by investing in Japan which grew 23% to $1.1 billion in the quarter. The performance in Japan was driven by the strong growth of JANUVIA, SINGULAIR and ZETIA as well as solid contributions from new launched brands such as BRIDION. We look forward to launching GARDASIL, CUBICIN and ZOLINZA which were all recently approved in Japan. We're building a strong track record of launch excellence in Japan and have high expectations for bringing these new life-saving products to patients and physicians.</p>
          <p>It's not only Japan where we're accelerating new launches, in total we now have more than 12 products launching around the world which together contributed more than $350 million to the top line this quarter. I'll share some insights from two of our key launches, VICTRELIS and SIMPONI.</p>
          <p>For VICTRELIS we're pleased with the execution of the U.S. launch. Given the particular dynamics of this market, the differences in the length of treatment, four-week lead-in and the use of specialty pharmacies, many of which do not report data to IMS, tracking weekly IMS data cannot yet paint a complete picture of performance. It's still early but we expect to be able to share more robust data in the third quarter call when the launch will be further along. There are, however, some insights we can share that make us confident that the launch is off to a strong start.</p>
          <p>Managed care is providing coverage along the lines we expected. In tier three for most commercial accounts and tier four for Medicare Part D all know most plans have not yet completed their formal reviews. We had a good level of initial orders at the launch and we're already seeing reorders from customers and the feedback from the field has been very positive. It increases our confidence in the uptake of VICTRELIS in the United States.</p>
          <p>In the EU, as you saw last week, VICTRELIS was first to market which is important as we head into the second half of the year and Health Ministries make reimbursement decisions. I was in Paris for the global launch meeting a few weeks ago and I can tell you, the team is ready to go. The team is ready to launch in emerging markets as well. Brazil became the first of these high-growth markets to approve VICTRELIS just last week. This is one of the top markets for PEGINTRON so we expect to have a strong position in Brazil with both physicians and payers and now that we have agreements in place with Roche in both the United States and other markets, we'll have deeper reach to support the launches of VICTRELIS around the world.</p>
          <p>For SIMPONI we have more robust data to provide. We've already launched in 21 markets where Merck has retained commercial rights and we're doing very well. We're exceeding the performance of others in the class and generating great momentum as we head into the second half of the year. In some countries market share is already above 7% and in many markets our market share is greater than the two most recent competitive launches. While there have been supply issues on the auto-injector we expect these issues to be resolved by next year and we have enough prefilled syringes to meet demand.</p>
          <p>In the territories that were retained as part of the J&amp;J arbitration settlement, our combined immunology business with both REMICADE and SIMPONI generated $611 million and about 70% of the growth in total of the franchise.</p>
          <p>Looking at the broader group of new product launches we see at our current pace the new product launches are expected to contribute in excess of $1 billion in incremental revenue in 2011. Therefore accelerating new launches continues to be a very important element of our growth strategy.</p>
          <p>So in summary, we had another strong second quarter and it's clear that our focus is on driving profitable top-line revenue growth and we did that in the second quarter. We will continue to elevate our resources and evaluate them to ensure that we are funding the right growth opportunities in a very targeted manner and we will continue cutting costs where possible and appropriate. We look forward to updating you on our progress and performance throughout the year.</p>
          <p>And now I'd like to turn it over to my colleague, Peter Kellogg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Adam, and good morning.</p>
          <p>As you heard from Ken and Adam, we continue to execute on our growth strategy. This quarter we grew the top line 7% and non-GAAP EPS 10% and we continue to make strategic investments necessary to fuel future growth, as Ken mentioned. Based on this performance, we are reaffirming our full-year top-line targets and raising the midpoint of our non-GAAP EPS target range.</p>
          <p>My remarks today will focus on our non-GAAP results which exclude acquisition-related charges, restructuring charges, including those related to the announcement today, and a one-time tax benefit following the conclusion of an examination of certain prior U.S. federal returns.</p>
          <p>Now let's get into the results starting with revenue. Total revenue for the quarter was $12.2 billion, 7% above a year ago. While ForEx benefited revenues this quarter, excluding the ForEx benefit revenue grew 3% over prior year. As Adam said, our key brands and markets, including the emerging markets, and launch products all contributed to this growth. As you can see from the year-to-date sales growth of 4% we are right on target to meet our low to mid-single-digit revenue growth target for 2011.</p>
          <p>We remain confident in our top-line performance and our ability to achieve growth this year even overcoming the J&amp;J settlement that took effect on July 1st. Now let's talk about expenses starting with product costs.</p>
          <p>Our non-GAAP product gross margin of 76.7% in the quarter benefited from product mix and manufacturing efficiencies. For example, we continue to drive growth of JANUVIA and produced a higher volume of ZOSTAVAX, while our manufacturing team continued to drive efficiencies that reduced product cost.</p>
          <p>Moving on to M&amp;A, marketing and administrative expenses of $3.4 billion were up over the second quarter of last year. As we said earlier in the year, we are continuing to realize cost reductions, enabling reinvestment in opportunities for growth. Let me take a moment to provide you with more detail on M&amp;A.</p>
          <p>This quarter's expense reflected four items that added over $300 million when compared to the same quarter last year. First, the unfavorable impact of ForEx was the largest item. Second, we made over $100 million in incremental investment in emerging markets verse the prior year. Third, we invested in the success of our launch brands, most notably VICTRELIS. And lastly, the Healthcare Reform fee added to our expenses this quarter. These items account for the entire increase versus prior year. Given current spot rates and our continued plans to make targeted investments in growth of new products and emerging markets, you should factor these items into your assumptions for the rest of the year.</p>
          <p>Moving on to R&amp;D, research and development expense of $1.9 billion was below second quarter 2010. We continue to invest in our most promising opportunities and continue to advance the late-stage pipeline. This quarter we are, once again, lowering the top end of our 2011 R&amp;D target range by $100 million to a new range of $8 billion to $8.3 billion. This range reflects our continued focus and financial discipline as we strive to improve the ROI of our ongoing R&amp;D operations.</p>
          <p>Moving to tax, our non-GAAP tax rate was 24.3% in the second quarter. There are a number of items contributing to the rate this quarter. First, we just completed a U.S. federal review for years 2002-2005. As a result of that, we increased our FIN 48 reserves on a few items. Second, there was a discrete item in the second quarter that will not reoccur in future quarters and third, the rate was affected by product mix. As a result of these items, we are updating our anticipated tax rate for the year to a new range of 23 to 24%.</p>
          <p>Non-GAAP EPS for the second quarter was $0.95 per share, up 10% over the same quarter in 2010. Our 2011 non-GAAP EPS range is now $3.68 to $3.76, the new 2011 GAAP EPS range is $1.95 to $2.17. As we look to the balance of the year we do expect that the fourth quarter will be stronger than the third quarter. So to wrap up my comments about the second quarter, the quarter was characterized by operational sales growth and continued cost efficiencies which enabled us to fund strategic investments in new product launches and emerging markets and still grow non-GAAP EPS by 10%.</p>
          <p>Now, we have been very aggressive at taking out costs since the merger. I am pleased to tell you that we are right on track to achieve our $3.5 billion merger synergy target. The reality is we need to do more. We want to position ourselves for sustained and profitable growth well into the future.</p>
          <p>Today we are announcing plans to further streamline our operations and reduce our cost base. These plans include further reducing head count by an additional 12%-13% beyond our previous target of 17% and further reducing the number of manufacturing sites, including animal health sites, and the consolidation of other facilities. These will generate an additional $1.3 billion to $1.5 billion in annual savings by the end of 2015.</p>
          <p>So in summary, what you've heard from Ken and Adam and myself is that we are executing on our growth strategy in 2011. With the additional efforts we announced today we continue to demonstrate our commitment to driving out inefficiencies in our cost structure while making the right investments necessary for growth.</p>
          <p>This quarter we received approval for four new innovative medicines in the U.S, the EU and Japan and we launched VICTRELIS in the U.S.  We also continued investment in key growth areas such as the emerging markets. We entered into important external collaborations with Simcere and Hanwha and we delivered growth on the top line and double-digit growth on the bottom line.</p>
          <p>Thank you, now I'll turn the call back over to Alex.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Peter. We're ready to open up the call to answer your questions. In order to get through as many callers as possible I'd ask you to please limit yourself to one or two questions and note that we will not take any follow-up questions. If you do have additional questions you're always welcome to rejoin the queue. So Brooke, we're now ready to begin the Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. Your first question comes from Catherine Arnold with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, and good morning. I have two questions, one I wanted to ask if you could give us a directional sense for what pricing of VICTRELIS will be in Europe and Latin America relative to the U.S., even if you can't give specific pricing just a directional sense?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, Ken, you talked about the five biosimilars that you expect to be in late-stage development next year and I was wondering if you could give us an update on where Merck stands right now as far as its current capability to manufacture biosimilars and to the extent you'll need external capabilities, how you see that market opportunity? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Catherine, I'll answer the first question. So giving you a directional sense of the pricing of VICTRELIS, it's going to be about the same as that in the U.S.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And on the biosimilars, question, thank you, Catherine, first of all, we'll have a lot more to say about this in November but let me assure you that we're working to ensure that we have in place all the capabilities necessary to succeed in this marketplace. We realize that it's important for us to get these products to market early on and that means that we have to have all aspects of our production chain in place.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And Catherine, I would just note that we have identified three of the programs already in biosimilars: so first is the Enbrel biosimilar that we just announced with Hanwha and then we have two, we have a Neupogen biosimilar in development and we also have a Neulasta biosimilar in development as well. More to come.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Marc Goodman with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. I just want to make sure I understand on these cost savings. Should we go into the model and take out $1.3 billion of savings, you know, just across the board, or are you saying that part of it may be made up for from revenues instead of just taking costs down?</p>
          <p>And, then, the second question is can you just give us a sense of &#x2013; you said in the press release something about JANUMET with manufacturing being an issue for not getting approved, can you give us a sense for what happened there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Marc, thank you, for the question. Let me just reiterate how I am thinking about the additional cost savings of $1.3 billion to $1.5 billion. As I said earlier, my overall intent is most of this, not all of it, will drop to the bottom line through a combination, first of all, of investment that drives top-line growth. Secondly, some reductions of our operating cost base.</p>
          <p>So I'm looking at it from the standpoint of what I said all along, which is that we intend to invest with high ROI hurdles in what we think are good growth opportunities on the top line while at the same time having a very strong bottom line. And so, you know, as I sit here today, I don't know all the opportunities that we'll have to reinvest some of the savings to justify longer term and short-term growth, but I do anticipate that some of it will be invested in the top line and other parts of it will be sent to the bottom line directly by reducing operating costs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, then, Marc, I'll answer your question with regards to with JANUMET XR. We received a complete response letter related to the resolution of preapproval inspection issues and the issues do not require any further clinical studies. We anticipate being able to respond to their questions very quickly, within weeks, and then we anticipate the issues will be resolved quickly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Tony Butler with Barclays Capital.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, this is Allison Yang asking a question on behalf of Tony. I would like to address the press release statement regarding telcagepant. We were wondering how many Phase III trials have already been done or completed for the project. As Ken and Dick have both focused on striving to achieve ROIC, was there anything that can be done to arrest the project earlier in the process?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Adam, do you want to start that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to telcagepant, it was a decision to discontinue the development of it because of an assessment of the data that we had across the clinical program that included findings from our recently concluded Phase III studies. The Phase III studies are completed. Based upon that and the data, we made the decision to discontinue the clinical development program. And, you know, I think that we continue to look for ways that we could try to eliminate programs quicker where it makes sense and I think there's some learnings from this but also we continue to evaluate ways that we can end programs when they make sense as quickly as possible.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>OK, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Jami Rubin with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Jami, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, can you hear me, hello.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry about that. Sorry about that. I'm having problems this quarter. But anyway, my question to you, Ken, is, you know, very good news on the long-term cost savings, I think that's something that investors wanted to see. I'm just curious to know why you're now not reinstating your long-term earnings guidance which you pulled after the fourth quarter?</p>
          <p>And my other questions relate to VICTRELIS, Adam if you could tell us what VICTRELIS sales were and a little bit of color around how you think the co-promoting agreement with Roche is going. I noticed that the PEGINTRON sales looked a little bit light this quarter, which I'm not sure I entirely understand, and if you could talk about the European label, epo use in Europe tends to be more restrictive than it is in the U.S. and I'm just wondering if you see that as a headwind as you market this drug? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Jami, I'll have Ken start.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, for the question, Jami. As I said when I withdrew the long-term guidance, the way that I intend to run this company is I intend to make smart investments that will drive our long-term profitability and growth and that continues to be my view of how I should look at this company.</p>
          <p>What matters in the long-term as far as I'm concerned is are we making the right investments in our product portfolio to grow it? Products like JANUVIA and ISENTRESS and others, are we making the right investments today that allow us to have a long-term profitable growth strategy in the emerging markets.</p>
          <p>And then lastly, are we being smart about the investments that we make on internal and external R&amp;D. That's basically where I continue to see the company going. I don't intend to reinstate the long-term guidance. What I believe is the case is that we need to be flexible and responsive and adaptive to whatever happens in the outside world but my ambition, I want to just underscore, is to grow the top line with a leveraged P&amp;L and I will continue to deal with the issues that I confront, both opportunities and challenge, with that model of a company in mind.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Adam, do you want to take the VICTRELIS question, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So Jami, let me give you a little bit more color on VICTRELIS. To start with, sales are $21 million and those were strong initial orders that were part of the launch and we've already seen reorders already occurring and the way I think about the initial orders is most wholesalers look to get a couple months of supply and you have to look at the cost of a month of supply to give you a sense of what that initial ordering was.</p>
          <p>In terms of what we're seeing in the U.S, first of all, most healthcare professionals haven't even written for either the PIs right now, less than 10% of the target prescribing universe of 8,000 physicians have already initiated a patient on triple therapy, that's why I keep saying it's still very early. What we're hearing qualitatively from market research and also from our field representatives and also with physicians that I've talked with is that they see a very strong and good efficacy profile with VICTRELIS. They believe there's good overall safety and tolerability profile with no surprises and the dosing of personalized therapy, they believe it's a bit complicated but they believe it will become easier over time. So it's early, there's still a lot of work to do but it's going well.</p>
          <p>In terms of the Roche co-promotion that is going well also. They are out there with material to be able to talk about the appropriate use of VICTRELIS with their physicians and we see that that co-promotion agreement is going well and that's why we were excited to expand it outside the U.S. to other parts of the world.</p>
          <p>With regard to the European label, we're pleased with the label. PPO use, as you know, varies market by market but they deal with the issues that they need to deal with already with PEGINTRON. So I believe that they'll be able to figure out how they want to deal with the issues around epo market by market.</p>
          <p>In terms of PEGINTRON, sales were lower primarily due to the continued warehousing of ATV patients, they're still bringing these patients into the market and there's a lot of clinical trials out there which also accounts for the lower use of PEGINTRON.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Tim Anderson with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. I want to pick up on Jami's point about long-term guidance. Your policy of not giving any long-term guidance elements essentially puts you out of sync with the majority of your peers and I'm wondering why they feel comfortable giving it and you guys don't? There's a lot of moving parts, things like your cost-cutting program, you just goosed up your tax rate for the year by 250 basis points. What should we expect on something like that going forward? So I hope you change your policy at some point and start to reinstate long-term guidance.</p>
          <p>My question on IMPROVE-IT, can you confirm that you have the 75% of events now that we might get an update on the second interim look soon and, then, can you update us on where you are with your ZETIA atorvastatin fixed-dose combination? From what we can tell it's something that you're still very actively pursuing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim, thanks for the comment, I appreciate your sharing your views. I continue to believe that the right approach for us at this time is to continue invest in what we believe to be profitable growth opportunities, to grow the top line with a leveraged P&amp;L and that's where we are at the moment and I continue to think that in the world in which we're operating my responsibility is to make the right investments to drive growth in the long-term but also to allow the company to be adaptive to what's happening in the environment and that's, again, how I intend to run the company.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Tim, this is Adam. With regard to IMPROVE-IT, the 75% interim look will occur this year and we also plan to file the eze-atorva combination product in 2011 as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from David Maris with CLSA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>David, are you there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>David, your line is open, if you have your own phone muted, please unmute.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry about that. Since everyone's opining, I might as well do the same. Ken, actually, I'm fine with no long-term guidance, so tick one in the other column. Too many companies set it out there and it's an artificial thing and excuse to do bad acquisitions, and it's managing to a bar.</p>
          <p>But that-aside, can you tell us a little bit about the strategy in China? You've done a couple really interesting deals there recently. Is this building out a footprint for a sales force, is it accessing drugs, maybe a little bit more detail on Simcere but also where, in a few years, will you be sales force wise in China? Will it be predominantly Merck reps or will it be some sort of combination of the two?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, David. I'm going to turn it over &#x2013; thank you for your question, David. I'm going it turn it over to Adam but I'll just say from a big picture standpoint, I continue to believe that the right way to approach a big must-win market like China is to not necessarily duplicate the model that we've had in the developed markets, a model that, frankly, we are now in some ways dismantling in these markets. I think the right thing is to decide how you can be flexible and how you can ensure that the growth that you have today and in the future is profitable growth in those markets.</p>
          <p>We know the pricing is different in those markets. We know that it's helpful to actually have partners in those markets who know the markets, who can help us have the right kind of cost structure so that's my overall view is I want to have growth, I think there's tremendous opportunity in these markets, but it has to be profitable growth that rewards shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And let me give you some color on China. So we're pleased with the performance in China. And the way I think about our strategy in China, it really is to develop a significant presence with Merck, Sharp &amp; Dohme, but to partner with local companies to augment our capabilities and also to expand our reach significantly. We currently have about 5,000 people in China. We have about 3,500 sales representatives and we continue to increase our sales representatives but they're concentrated primarily in the largest provinces in China.</p>
          <p>With deals like Simcere, we're able to expand our reach into other provinces in China but also capitalize on their knowledge and know-how to operate within the Chinese market and I think that that's very helpful and very important.</p>
          <p>In addition to that, we're looking for ways to improve our access through multi-channel capabilities. We already have the ability to reach 170,000 physicians in China that our representatives don't call on through multi-channel capabilities whether it be mobile technology, teleconferencing capabilities and other ways, e-mail and so forth. So we continue to look to utilize technology, which in China there's multiple different technologies we can use to expand our reach.</p>
          <p>So we look at it as a way for us to invest but to invest where it makes sense for a multinational company to invest and, then, to utilize partnerships where partnerships can help us significantly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Barbara Ryan with Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Thank you. Most of mine have been asked but just to follow up on VICTRELIS, I appreciate that it is early days but I think in the Vertex call they did talk about what they saw as the mix of patients between treatment na&#xEF;ve and add-on therapy and I wonder if sort of 50% of the patients coming from treatment na&#xEF;ve pool is consistent with what you're seeing as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, so Barbara, thanks, for the question. It really is just too early to give you percents and breakdown. I can tell you we're doing a lot of work, a lot of research to understand the mix but the data that's out there is really not robust enough to give you a number that I feel confident is the right number. Let us continue to do some more work, I'll have some more information that I'll be able to share on the next quarter call and we'll share with you the best information that we have that we believe is accurate as soon as we can.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Appreciate it. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Gregg Gilbert with Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, two for Ken. Ken, within the additional cost savings you've outlined, what difficult decisions did you have to make as it relates to R&amp;D, either specific programs or philosophies?</p>
          <p>And secondly, at this point, how would you describe your strategy and goals for consumer and for animal health? I'm not asking if they're core, we've already asked that, asking for a little more meat on the bones on how you view the strategies and goals for those two segments going forward, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for your questions, Gregg. I would say, first of all, with respect to R&amp;D what we're doing in R&amp;D is a continuous effort to provide more rigor and focus on ROI. That preceded the latest announcements. The latest announcements will affect R&amp;D in the same way that it affects the rest of the company. We're really trying to go at administrative headquarters-type personnel, the people who are, in effect, not directly as involved in discovery and development. We're trying to spare what we call revenue-generating, you might think of it as more aimed at indirect labor than direct labor, if I can put it that way.</p>
          <p>I think on the animal health situation, I would say that we think we have a very strong business. It's the number two business in the world in terms of size. We think it has really good profit margins. We see an opportunity to build on that business as we go forward and we're going to look for really good opportunities to build on top of that business where we can create shareholder value. We think there's really great macro trends that affect that business so we're very happy with that.</p>
          <p>We also are happy with our consumer business, although I, frankly, have acknowledged that the consumer business could benefit from having greater scale and particularly internationally. and again, the way that I think about that is I have to look at that as a part of our portfolio and look at the opportunities that we have across the entire portfolio in terms of how we run in effect our internal capital markets in terms of how we, you know, allocate capital to create the most return for shareholders.</p>
          <p>So I would just say that animal health and consumer are important to us. They're a part of our strategy. How we proceed to make them even more meaningful in the context of Merck is, I think, the challenge that we have going forward. But we will not make investments anywhere unless we think they will pay off for shareholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from David Risinger with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. I have two questions. First, I was hoping that you could please discuss hepatitis C in a little bit more detail including how much of the $21 million was stocking and how IMS data for boceprevir may be different from telaprevir because it was a decent leading indicator for telaprevir sales.</p>
          <p>And then second, Simcere's annual China sales run rate is about $350 million, which is pretty small for a business. Could you please remind us what Merck's sales run rate is in China and how your partnership is going to work with this small organization?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Why don't I take that and I'll answer your first question and, then get to the second. For hepatitis C we had $21 million in stocking, and there's a couple ways to think about it. The first one is we were approved in the middle of May. If physicians were going to do a four-week lead-in, which is the label, then we'd have about two weeks' worth of actual prescriptions according to label. Now, we know some physicians already had patients on intron and just added VICTRELIS immediately so it's very difficult for us to know exactly how many physicians were following the four-week lead-in exactly or how many were adding to patients that were already on PEGINTRON.</p>
          <p>The second thing to think about is the wholesalers think about how many months of inventory they want to have on the shelves and based upon a number of months they want to have on the shelves, they'll purchase that from us. When you think about the cost of VICTRELIS per month, then you have to think about how many months of supply the $21 million could actually equate to. What I will tell you is that wholesalers have begun to reorder already.</p>
          <p>In terms of the IMS data, the other thing to think about is that most of this business goes through specialty pharmacies and the IMS data is not nearly as robust in specialty pharmacies. We are shipping to almost all of the specialty pharmacies, there's over 20 of them out there and IMS ability to report depends on which specialty pharmas actually give data to them. We don't have insight into that. At this point in time it's way too early to look at share from IMS data or actually try to extrapolate share from sales data because the cost of therapy per month is very different between the two products.</p>
          <p>With regard to China, it's about $200 million per quarter. We grew 30% this quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>OK, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Seamus Fernandez with Leerink Swann.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. So I was just wondering if we could maybe get an update from Peter specifically on, you know, the thoughts, again, around the second option with AstraZeneca and again expectations for timing of when that decision would be made if it's made in 2012 and what's baked into your guidance assumptions.</p>
          <p>Second, for Adam, just wondering, can you update us in terms of just the pharmaceutical sales in the emerging markets which accounted for 18% in the quarter, are you still targeting 25% of sales in 2013, particularly given the restructuring of the REMICADE agreement?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter, you want to start?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you, Seamus. As you know, the AstraZeneca JV has a &#x2013; or AstraZeneca, the company, has an option that they can exercise next year. And of course we have no insight and I think they have actually articulated they haven't made a decision yet. So at this point, though, and what we've always assumed is that they would exercise their option, you know, probably sometime during the first half of next year and obviously we have no insight to that but it's just a planning assumption that we make to think about that and, of course, if they do exercise their option then our equity income will be reduced following the close of that but we'll get a payment as it's calculated in the agreement. At this point, though, unfortunately Seamus we don't really have anything else to add, it's really their decision and I think they've articulated they haven't yet made that decision.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And, then, with regard to the 25% of sales in emerging markets the answer is, yes, that is still our target.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, operator we have time for two more questions, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from Steve Scala with Cowen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Regarding the ZOSTAVAX sales of $122 million in the quarter, is manufacturing sufficient such that we may view $122 million as a minimum number in any quarter through the end of 2012? So that's the first question.</p>
          <p>And then the second question regards telcagepant. Was the discontinuation due to liver findings and is Merck view that the mechanism is flawed or that telcagepant is a suboptimal molecule? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the second one, I think we'll be able to address that in greater detail at our annual business briefing. Certainly we ran into issues with the molecule here. I wouldn't necessarily extend that logic to all molecules in the class. I'm not saying one way or the other. I think that's a question that we continue to look at in our research labs and we'll have more to say about that.</p>
          <p>In terms of the run rate in the second quarter, we were pleased in the second quarter to have available supply to clear a significant number of accumulated backorders. We're continuing the work to release doses as quickly as possible going forward but as inventory builds we may have additional backorders going forward so I would say that I can't say that the supply in the second quarter necessarily dictates quarterly sales going forward. What I can tell you is that we are working diligently to solve the issues so that as we go forward we can get out of backorder and assure the kind of supply that the marketplace is looking for with respect to a vaccine that is well received.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Steve, it's Alex. I would just note that on our website we do &#x2013; on the merckvaccines.com there is a supply statement that's posted there and that indicates when we plan to ship orders based on when they were received. So we're still in a delay of shipping orders from the time they're received.</p>
          <p>Okay, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your final question comes from Chris Schott with JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks very much. I just had two questions. The first was on coming back to the restructuring, when I consider the level of annual savings, can you give us some color of where you're going to be at the end of 2011 relative to this $4 billion to $4.6 billion target? I'm just trying to think about how much incremental savings we should be thinking about if we look at the end of the this year through 2015 that could either flow through the P&amp;L or be used for reinvestment?</p>
          <p>And the second question, if you could just comment on share repo activity in the quarter? I was surprised we didn't see share &#x2013; a little bit more share count reduction given last quarter's share repo announcement and your significant ongoing cash flow. I guess maybe when you're answering that, could you also comment, is there a target net debt or leverage ratio that you're aiming for that we should also be keeping in mind as we consider cash flow here? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Chris, I think actually all of those questions are mine. So that's great. I think &#x2013; let me take the first one which is the restructuring and let me holistically answer that one. So going back to the merger value capture piece, the $3.5 billion, as we come through the midyear point right now, we're basically at about the $2.5 billion out of $3.5 billion achievement level in terms of savings and productivity and efficiencies from that. So we feel pretty good about that.</p>
          <p>The additional announcement we made today will roll out over the next couple of years. So it is not all active this year. It will begin kicking in probably more significantly in 2012 because of actions taken as we go through the balance of this year, so that's probably the way I would assume it is we will continue to move forward on the original value capture and this new plan will really take the balance of this year to get rolling and start to see some benefits as we go into next year.</p>
          <p>On the share repurchase, we were active, actually, during the quarter on share repurchase. We actually repurchased 9 million shares, you know, for something in the neighborhood of $300 million, so as of mid-year we have $6.1 billion outstanding on the board authorized share repurchase program. Obviously offsetting that was the timing of stock grants to employees in the first half of the year. So that's our status and we do sense that we will on an ongoing basis see a downward trend on shares outstanding, I think that's a fair assumption given the share repurchase program we have outstanding, so that's certainly an ongoing program.</p>
          <p>Finally, in terms of net debt, as you know, we have a slight net debt position today and the way we think about it is we think about that holistically relative to our credit rating and I think &#x2013; we'd be glad to go through in more detail, but we work very closely with the credit rating agencies and understand their methodology and applying that methodology to our balance sheet and our business mix and portfolio, we target to be in the credit rating &#x2013; have the credit score that we have right now and we don't intend to have that go up, very importantly, as our balance sheet strengthens, nor do intend to have it go gown unless something catastrophic or significant happens. So and I think we kind of announced that at the start of the announcement of the merger that we were targeting this credit rating zone and that we would try to stay there for as much as possible.</p>
          <p>Now, you'll see on our balance sheet that for the second quarter, as we finished second quarter we had about $16.5 billion of cash and investments and about $18 billion of debt. That's the detail but a slight net debt position but we really focus on the credit rating and we like where we are but very importantly as we go forward in future years, we do not intend to have the credit rating go up which means that obviously we would be very shareholder-friendly. As we continue to have strong cash flows we do not plan to have that build up on the balance sheet.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Ken, would you like to say anything in closing?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, first of all, I thank you all for being on the call today and just to remind you the way we're thinking about the future in this company we're very optimistic that we can grow both the top and the bottom lines in this company over time. What that means, first of all, is that we have to be really focused on executing in the inline products we have and the launch products we have and in the pipeline, importantly.</p>
          <p>In terms of ensuring that we can make the necessary investments to drive top-line growth, we're also focused on our cost structure. We recognize that we are facing a SINGULAIR patent expiration next year as well as an environment that is a lot tougher than in the past and so we're determined to look at our cost structure to make the kinds of changes to allow the company to operate at a lower cost base and to be able to adapt to the market conditions and to take advantage of the opportunities that we believe that Merck has in front of it.</p>
          <p>So, thank you very much for listening today. We look forward to talking to you again in the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Good-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, this concludes the conference. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>