<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1253239" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-10-22</date>
    <companies>
      <company>354</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Eva Boratto, Investor Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Richard T. Clark, Chairman, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Kenneth C. Frazier, Executive Vice President and President of Global Human Health</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Peter N. Kellogg, Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Chris Schott</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Peter Kim</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">David Risinger</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Catherine Arnold</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Eric Lo</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep">Bruce Kuhlik</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Steve Scala</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Jami Rubin</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Keyur Parekh</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">John Boris</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, everyone. Welcome to Merck's third quarter 2009 earnings conference call. Today's call is being recorded. At this time I would like to turn the call over to Ms. Eva Boratto, Vice President of Investor Relations. Please go ahead ma'am.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Cynthia and good morning. Welcome to our call to review our business performance for the third quarter of 2009. Joining me on the call today are Dick Clark, our Chairman, President and CEO, Ken Frazier, our Executive Vice President and President of Global Human Health, and Peter Kellogg, our Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer. Also here to participate in the Q&amp;A session are Bruce Kuhlik, Executive Vice President and General Council, and Dr. Peter Kim, Executive Vice President and President of Merck Research Labs.</p>
          <p>Before we get into the details, I would like to go over some logistics. On this call we will review the results contained in the release we issued at 7:30 this morning. You can access this through our Investor Relations section on Merck.com, and I would remind you this conference call is being webcast live and recorded. The replay of this event will be available later today via phone, webcast and podcast.</p>
          <p>As we begin our review, let me remind you that some of the statements made during this call may discuss certain subjects that may contain forward-looking statements as that term is defined in the Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements are based on management's current expectation and involve risks and uncertainties which may cause results to differ  materially from those set forth in these statements. The forward-looking statements may include statements regarding product development, product potential or financial performance. No forward-looking statement can be guaranteed and actual results may differ materially from those projected. Merck undertakes no obligation to publicly update any forward-looking statement whether as a result of new information, future events or otherwise.</p>
          <p>Forward-looking statements in this press release should be reviewed together with the many uncertainties that affect Merck's business. Particularly those mentioned in the risk factors and cautionary statements in item 1A of Merck's Form 10-K for the year ended December 31, 2008, and in any risk factors or cautionary statements contained in the company's periodic reports on Form 10-Q or current reports on Form 8-K which the company incorporates by reference.</p>
          <p>We will begin the call with brief remarks from our senior management and then open the call for your questions, and expect the total call to last approximately one hour.  With that, we will begin with remarks from our Chairman, President and CEO, Dick Clark.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Eva, and good morning everyone. This morning I'm pleased to discuss our company's strong third quarter performance, update you on our readiness for the pending transformational merger with Schering-Plough and highlight how we continue to plant the seeds of sustainable future growth through innovative partnerships that will position us as a leading global health care company for many years to come.</p>
          <p>By continuing to concentrate on the fundamentals and growing key global pharmaceutical brands, we realized top line revenue performance of $6 billion in the third quarter, delivering worldwide revenue growth of 2% on a year-over-year basis. And by continuing to concentrate on lowering our costs and streamlining activities throughout the organization, we recorded third quarter non-GAAP earnings per share of $0.90 and GAAP earnings per share of $1.61 per share. Our strong third quarter is evidence that Merck has maintained our focus on business performance and overcome a challenging economic environment, while continuing to ensure our operational readiness for the pending merger.</p>
          <p>Sales of key products particularly SINGULAIR, JANUVIA, JANUMET and ISENTRESS during the third quarter illustrate the base that we are building upon to create a new Merck for the new era in global healthcare. And that day is just around the corner as we continue to expect to close the merger this quarter. We have made significant progress in our planning during the past three months and have achieved a number of key milestones during the third quarter. Perhaps most importantly, shareholders of both companies voted overwhelmingly to approve the proposed merger this past August. In addition, we announced a global leadership team for the new Merck that will include executive committee level positions for Consumer Healthcare and Animal Health as well as the addition of a chief medical officer and a chief compliance officer. About 40% of Schering-Plough's senior leaders will be part of the newly combined company in executive roles.</p>
          <p>We completed the $4 billion sale of Merck's interest in our animal health joint venture, Merial, to Sanofi-Aventis. And we filed with regulators in the European Union seeking approval of our merger with Schering-Plough. Both Merck and Schering-Plough are working diligently and cooperating with regulators in other countries to obtain all necessary approvals.</p>
          <p>When all the necessary approvals are in place, I am confident we will be ready to hit the ground running on our first day of business as a new Merck because of the quality of our integration planning and the strong momentum we are building. Out of the gate, we will hold a leadership position as the new era in global healthcare dawns. As such we will continue to focus on critical areas such as healthcare reform, anticipating customer needs, and growth areas such as emerging markets, biologics and vaccines.</p>
          <p>Before year-end, I'm cautiously optimistic that the U.S. will finally pass major healthcare reform. Merck and the pharmaceutical industry stepped up earlier to support real change. Throughout, we have supported healthcare reform that improves quality through market-based competition, encourages innovation and ensures that every patient who has been prescribed one of our medicines or vaccines have access to it. Our participation in healthcare reform in the U.S. demonstrates that in response to a rapidly changing operating environment, Merck is taking the bold actions necessary to adapt to the future environment.</p>
          <p>That is why in the new Merck, we plan to take advantage of our broader and deeper inline product franchises when the merger is completed. We will pursue the significant growth opportunities we have identified in three key areas: emerging markets, biologics and vaccines. The cross divisional approach we're taking will allow the new company's commercial, research and manufacturing divisions to dedicate the necessary focus and resources to take and sustain leadership positions.</p>
          <p>As we have built the foundation of the new company in recent months, we have been guided by four underlying principles:  We must ensure a smooth transition for our existing customers. We must have the right people in the right jobs in the right culture. We must capture synergies in the form of cost savings and revenue growth opportunities. And we must stay focused to maintain momentum in our late stage pipeline.</p>
          <p>One thing is certain: with the opportunity of our pending merger with Schering-Plough we're more externally focused than ever. We're listening even harder and gaining a deeper appreciation for what healthcare solutions our customers around the world &#x2013; patients, physicians, and public and private healthcare providers alike &#x2013; are saying they need. To this end, we are busy cultivating new scientific discovery and delivery opportunities, the future growth for our company by seeking out the best science and the best innovation to improve healthcare.</p>
          <p>In the past quarter alone, we have added a seasonal flu vaccine to our U.S. vaccine portfolio, developed by our long term partner, CSL Limited, which now means that Merck will market eight of the 10 vaccines on the recommended schedule for adults in the US. We've launched the Hilleman Laboratories, a first of its kind research and development joint venture between a leading pharmaceutical company and a world renowned research charity, Wellcome Trust, with a non-profit mission to focus on developing affordable vaccines to prevent diseases that commonly affect low income countries.</p>
          <p>We've closed an exclusive global collaboration and license agreement with Portola Pharmaceuticals for the development of a potential novel new medicine to treat cardiovascular disease. All of which is part of the reason why the  plans we are making for the future are so exciting and hold so much promise for so many. Now I would like to turn it over to Ken.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Dick. And good morning, everyone. As Dick mentioned, revenue for the third quarter 2009 was $6 billion, up 2% compared to last year including a 3% negative impact from foreign exchange.</p>
          <p>Overall, a combination of factors drove our growth in the quarter. We continue to generate strong growth for our newest brands and markets around the world. ZOSTAVAX sales were bolstered by the return to full supply and increased origination linked to the start of the fall flu season, and SINGULAIR continued its sales momentum. Looking at the results geographically, we saw volume growth of 6% outside the U.S. which was offset by foreign exchange. In the U.S. we achieved sales growth of 4% despite the continued impact of a loss of marketing exclusivity for some of our brands. We are pleased with the continued momentum of the business and the focus of our teams as we move toward the planned merger with Schering-Plough.</p>
          <p>Now turning to individual product performance. Starting with SINGULAIR, sales in the third quarter were $1.1 billion, up 5% versus the prior year. Outside the U.S. excluding exchange, we generated strong growth of 11%. We recently achieved leadership in Japan, and in Europe we are seeing strong growth in key markets including France and Spain.</p>
          <p>Moving to JANUVIA and JANUMET, global revenue grew to reach a combined $664 million in the third quarter, up 39% versus the prior year. The JANUVIA JANUMET franchise continues its strong performance in markets all around the world. In the vast majority of markets where more than one DPP-4 exists, sitagliptin is clearly the market leader. In the U.S., JANUVIA and JANUMET have achieved a new milestone as the number one branded family of products prescribed by endocrinologists.</p>
          <p>We are positioned well to address the competition entering the market. More than 16 million prescriptions have been written in the U.S. alone since our launch in 2006, and we have favorable formulary positioning. We have invested in the continued success of these brands by making them a top priority of our sales and marketing organization and frequently introducing new data to offer physicians and patients new treatment choices in managing this progressive disease.</p>
          <p>I would like to share with you some recent examples. JANUVIA was approved for restricted first line use for the treatment of type 2 diabetes in the EU this past August. It is the only DPP 4 in the EU to have this indication. JANUVIA and JANUMET are under regulatory review in the U.S. and the EU for use as add-on to insulin, and in September we received a positive opinion from the CHSP for this indication. In the U.S., we continue to implement patient programs through direct to patient advertising, physician office programs, and pharmacy initiatives to address potential cost sensitivity including the impact the economy has had on certain patients.</p>
          <p>Lastly we are extremely pleased with the recent approvals of JANUVIA in Japan and China. As you know, Japan is the second largest pharmaceutical market in the world, and JANUVIA is the first introduction of a new class of agents to treat type 2 diabetes there in ten years.  During a recent trip to Japan, I had the opportunity to review the launch plans with the team, and I'm confident that the brand will be successful in that critical market. Also as you know, we're very focused on growing our emerging market business. The JANUVIA approval in China is an important milestone.</p>
          <p>Next ISENTRESS continues to perform well with another quarter of strong, steady growth. Sales in the third quarter were $197 million, up 14% sequentially versus the second quarter 2009. In the U.S., third quarter sales were 95 million and market share continues to exceed the last five HIV launches in new RX market share. Outside the U.S. we achieved $102 million in sales thanks to strong uptake in markets including France, Spain and Italy.</p>
          <p>The recently approved expanded indication for ISENTRESS in both the U.S. and now the EU makes ISENTRESS available for patients who are new to treatment and patients who are treatment experienced. This means that ISENTRESS is a very important option for physicians and patients to consider at each stage of the treatment continuum.</p>
          <p>I will now move to our vaccine business. Starting with GARDASIL sales as reported by Merck in the third quarter were $311 million, a 22% decline when compared to the third quarter of last year. In the U.S. sales declined 20% versus third quarter 2008 but increased 19% sequentially versus second quarter 2009. Performance in the quarter was in line with our expectations driven primarily by increased vaccination of the 13 to 18-year-olds during the back-to-school season. We also saw modest increase in the 19 to 26 first dose vaccination. While this gives us some confidence that our programs are beginning to have an effect, we remain focused on addressing the barriers in these challenging age groups. Ex-U.S. sales as reported by Merck decreased 27%, attributable to the high penetration rates in early adopting countries such as Australia, where so many in the 12 to 26-year-old population have already been vaccinated and the initial adoption of school-based programs in all Canadian provinces in the third quarter of 2008. Growth in less mature or later adopting markets such as Korea is partially offsetting the decreases.</p>
          <p>Let me now touch on yesterday's news regarding use of GARDASIL in the U.S. The ACIP voted to recommend permissive use of GARDASIL in boys nine to 26 years of age, and the ACIC recommended vaccine for children funding for males. The recommendation for BFC funding for males will enable access and importantly remove the potential barrier to underserved populations. However, we expect the uptake in males to be much less than uptake for females due to the differences in the strength of their respective ACIC recommendations and the lack of a cancer claim in males. I would remind you though that only GARDASIL is indicated for use in males.</p>
          <p>And in a separate vote, the ACIP was clear yesterday in recognizing the clinical differentiation of GARDASIL. The proposed language for the revised HPV recommendation explicitly states that the quadrivalent vaccine GARDASIL is recommended to prevent vaginal and vulvar cancers, genital warts, as well as cervical cancer. The recognition of the unique value of GARDASIL further supports our strong positioning in the marketplace. In countries where physicians have a choice, GARDASIL is the clear market leader.</p>
          <p>Moving to ZOSTAVAX, third quarter sales as reported by Merck were $84 million and were more generally reflective of underlying demand now that supply is stable. We have been rolling out new marketing programs in physicians' offices and pharmacies to help doctors more easily integrate ZOSTAVAX into their routine standard of care. We're continuing the consumer campaign for ZOSTAVAX initiated in July. These new programs coupled with full supply and increased patient originations during fall flu season should position ZOSTAVAX for strong growth.</p>
          <p>In the other vaccine categories, I want to take a moment to discuss Pneumovax 23 our vaccine for pneumococal disease. Third quarter sales were $130 million and reflect an acceleration of demand as more patients originated earlier in the adult immunization season due to additional media attention on the H1N1 pandemic and seasonal flu. Looking ahead to 2010, we are pleased to expand our adult vaccine portfolio in the U.S. to include the seasonal flu vaccination Afloria, which we recently licensed from CSL. As Dick said, with the addition of Afloria, Merck will have marketed eight of the 10 vaccines on the recommended immunization schedule for adults in the US.</p>
          <p>Now finally, let's discuss the performance of our cholesterol JV. Worldwide sales for ZETIA and VYTORIN as reported by the Merck Schering-Plough joint venture were each $514 million in the third quarter. Sales of ZETIA were down 4% and sales of VYTORIN were down 9% versus the prior year. The rate of prescription market share declined in the U.S.; however it appears to be stabilizing. Outside the U.S. sales in the third quarter were down 1% relative to third quarter 2008 and were up 9% after adjusting for exchange. We remain committed to investing in ZETIA and VYTORIN while prudently managing our expenses. For many patients, particularly high risk patients, statins alone are not sufficient to get them to their LDL goals.</p>
          <p>Given this, we believe these products will continue to be valuable treatment options for physicians by helping to get more patients to their LDL goals. The MSP joint venture is prepared to engage in dialogue with scientific leaders at the upcoming AHA meeting in November. Our goal is to provide fair and balanced scientific information to the medical community and other constituents. Looking forward, we are excited by our combined strong cardiovascular portfolio and pipeline after the close.</p>
          <p>Across our organization, we are encouraged by the momentum of many of our key brands and are excited about the other near term opportunities ahead of us. As we look forward to the new Merck, there are a number of near term launch opportunities in major markets around the world across both companies' portfolios that have significant potential. We are focused on ensuring successful launches, continued momentum for our inline brands, and maintaining strong and productive customer relationships as we prepare for the integration with Schering-Plough.</p>
          <p>So with that, I'll turn the call over to my colleague, Peter Kellogg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Ken, and good morning everybody. I will provide an update on our third quarter results and our full-year 2009 guidance. I will also comment on what you can expect from us in the first half of 2010. As I've said previously, our non-GAAP results exclude restructuring costs as well as pre-closing costs related to the merger, including interest, commitment fees and external integration costs.</p>
          <p>With that said, let's get into the results. Merck reported third quarter non-GAAP earnings per share of $0.90 representing a 13% increase versus the third quarter of 2008. Our GAAP EPS was $1.61 per share, including a gain from the sale of our share of Merial. We are pleased with the strong performance this quarter. The 13% increase in non-GAAP EPS over the same quarter last year reflects strong operating performance, including growth for our newest brands in markets around the world, an improvement in gross margin versus prior year, and continued expense management of marketing and administrative spending.</p>
          <p>There are a couple of other items that I would also like to mention. These are that foreign exchange negatively impacted the top line by 3% and the bottom line by 2%; we increased our legal defense reserves in the quarter by $55 million. Now these two negative impacts were roughly offset by a third item. We benefited from $127 million in portfolio gains this quarter as we liquidated securities in advance of the merger closing.</p>
          <p>Now on revenue, our total revenue for the quarter as reported by Merck was $6 million. And Ken walked you through our strong product performance so I'll move on to other areas in our P&amp;L. Third quarter materials and production costs were $1.4 billion. When you exclude restructuring costs in both years, this represents a 1% decline in costs and a 76.8% gross margin in this quarter. Now on a guidance basis, we continue to anticipate PGMs at a 77 to 78% rate for the year excluding restructuring costs.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to marketing and administrative expenses. M&amp;A expenses were $1.7 billion, as reported. Excluding merger related expenses of 56 million, M&amp;A expenses declined 3% versus Q3 in 2008. The current quarter's exchange benefit was entirely offset by the aggregate $55 million increase to the VIOXX and FOSAMAX legal defense reserves. As I said previously, we expected higher marketing expenses particularly focused on seasonality and the back-to-school season for vaccines in the second half of the year. We did increase promotion this quarter in support of our international launches in vaccines, especially ZOSTAVAX, and we are seeing the benefit in our top line.</p>
          <p>The cost of this increased support was more than offset by the continued benefits from our new commercial models and corporate G&amp;A efficiency program. We do expect to continue the emphasis on promotion of our key brands and new launches in Q4. And as a result, we expect to see higher spending relative to prior quarters. In particular, we will be supporting the continued launches of TREDAPTIVE in the EU and the launch of JANUVIA in Japan.</p>
          <p>Now turning to R&amp;D, our research and development expenses in the third quarter were $1.3 billion. When you exclude restructuring costs in this year and 2008, research and development spending is up 6%. This increase is primarily driven by $50 million of upfront payments associated with our previously announced licensing of a factor 10A program from Portola Pharmaceuticals.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to equity income. In the third quarter Merck recorded $688 million of equity income, an increase of $23 million. This increase is attributable to income from the AZLP joint venture partially offset by a decline in Merial equity income. Now remember that the sale of Merial to our partner Sanofi was finalized on September 17, and therefore income from the last couple of weeks in the quarter was not recorded by Merck. Likewise, given the divestiture, you will not see Merial equity income in Merck's fourth quarter results.</p>
          <p>Now let's talk about other income and expense. For the third quarter 2009, other income net is $2.8 billion. This includes a $2.8 billion gain on the sale of Merial. When you adjust for this gain and $88 million in merger related costs, other income on a non-GAAP basis is $117 million compared to other expense of $31 million in the third quarter of the prior year.</p>
          <p>There are a few items driving this year-over-year change. First, in the third quarter of 2009, Merck realized approximately $127 million of portfolio gains from liquidating securities in anticipation of the Schering-Plough merger closing, as I mentioned earlier. Second, as we anticipated, interest income of $33 million was $110 million lower when compared to the prior year as a result of lower interest rates and a change in our investment portfolio mix towards cash and shorter dated securities, again in anticipation of the merger closing.</p>
          <p>Third, in the same quarter of last year, Merck recognized $88 million of portfolio losses and $52 million of exchange losses. So if you take these three factors, I think that pretty well explains the change year-over-year in that area.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to the tax rate. Merck's third quarter GAAP effective tax rate was 31.9%. Excluding the impact of Merial sale, restructuring charges and costs related to the Schering-Plough transaction, the non-GAAP effective tax rate was 24.7%. While this rate is similar to the rate that we saw at this time a year ago, it is higher than the first two quarters of 2009. We anticipated this, as the tax rate in the first half of this year included benefits from various tax settlements.</p>
          <p>So turning to guidance, we continue to expect our full year non-GAAP tax rate to be approximately 21 to 24%. So, overall, a very successful quarter.</p>
          <p>Now I would like to discuss with what this means for our guidance in 2009. And before I begin, let me remind everyone that this guidance is Merck's standalone guidance; it exclude any contributions by Schering-Plough as a result of the expected merger and any costs incurred upon closing.</p>
          <p>We continue to expect the merger with Schering-Plough to close in this quarter &#x2013; in the fourth quarter. And once this closing occurs, the standalone guidance for Merck will no longer be applicable as the companies &#x2013; as the combined companies fourth quarter reported results will include Merck results for the full quarter and Schering-Plough results from the closing date through the end of the year.</p>
          <p>With that, let's get into our guidance. We are pleased with our operating results this quarter and expect that our key products will continue to perform well for the rest of the year. In structuring our guidance for the year, we did consider a few other items. First, we do not expect any further significant portfolio gains. Based on our current levels of cash investments and anticipated cash flows between now and the expected close of the merger, we do not anticipate needing significant additional funding to close the merger.</p>
          <p>Second, fourth quarter results will exclude equity income for Merial, as I mentioned earlier, which contributed approximately $50 million to equity income in the fourth quarter of 2008. Third, we expect that fourth quarter M&amp;A spend will be higher as we support our key brands and new launches in line with the guidance we've provided throughout the year.</p>
          <p>Given our year-to-date performance and these factors, we are raising the bottom end of our non-GAAP EPS guidance to $3.20. This results in a full year Merck standalone non-GAAP EPS guidance range of 3.20 to $3.30 per share. We are also decreasing our M&amp;A guidance range to 6.8 to $7.1 billion. All other guidance elements remain the same. You will find a breakdown of these on the guidance page of the press release issued earlier today. We are also adjusting our GAAP EPS guidance range to $3.69 to $3.89, which includes the gain on our sale of Merial.</p>
          <p>Our merger guidance is still applicable. We continue to target a high single digit non-GAAP EPS compound annual growth rate from 2009 to 2013 for the combined company. We continue to anticipate the transaction will be modestly accretive to non-GAAP EPS in 2010.</p>
          <p>Now, as we look ahead to the first quarter of 2010, which we anticipate being our first full quarter of the new Merck, we want to emphasize that EPS expectations should be moderated relative to the full year outlook. As we have already seen in Merck's 2009 trends, our first quarter non-GAAP EPS was less than second and third quarters as we had expected. We expect to see this pattern in the new Merck due to the seasonality of our business, specifically our respiratory franchise and vaccine sales.</p>
          <p>Other factors that you should keep in mind that will be specific to the new Merck include, first, as Ken said, there are a number of upcoming launch opportunities for the new Merck. A substantial amount of promotion effort is planned in the near term to ensure the success of these launches. Second, the synergies we expect to capture, while substantial, will not be immediate but rather will be achieved more heavily in the second half of the year.</p>
          <p>Now with that said, I would like to look ahead for a moment and share our thinking about the timing of 2010 communications. Given the anticipated fourth quarter close of our merger, we expect to hold our fourth quarter and full-year 2009 sales and earnings call during the second week of February, which would be about two weeks later than our normal timing. I am sure you can appreciate the need for the additional time given the additional complexity of our combined financials, the added requirements to develop purchase accounting for the first time, and additionally we will use this time to develop adjusted financial statements that are most useful for investors to understand the trends of the combined businesses.</p>
          <p>In addition, we expect to hold our annual business briefing during the second quarter of 2010 rather than in early December as has been Merck's practice in the past. We believe this will make the briefing most useful for you, because it will enable us to speak to the products, the pipeline and strategy of the combined company. Accordingly we expect to provide annual guidance around the timing of our first quarter 2010 sales and earnings call ahead of the ABB. We really look forward to an exciting future as the new Merck and thank you very much.</p>
          <p>Now I would like to turn the call back to Eva.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Peter. We will now open the call to take your questions. We will take your questions in the order they are received and try to get through as many as possible. At this point I will turn the call over to Cynthia who will communicate instructions for our Q&amp;A format and introduce the first question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Your first question comes from the line of Chris Schott with JP Morgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, thanks. Just had a couple of quick questions. Maybe first on the R&amp;D side. For ISENTRESS QD, can you just provide us an update on that program, where are we with enrollment, when we can anticipate data.</p>
          <p>Second, on the R&amp;D side, with the Portola in-licensing, when can we think about that program moving into Phase III? I know a number of your competitors have data releases expected over the next year. Should we expect that Merck is going to wait to see how some of these studies before moving forward?</p>
          <p>And then maybe, finally just a bigger picture question. In the current economic environment, we're seeing co-pay assistance programs meaningfully boosting usage of products in certain therapeutic categories. Is this something that Merck would consider more broadly employing for some of your products? I guess I'm thinking about newer products or categories, maybe specifically something like a JANUVIA, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chris. This is Peter Kim. With regard to the ISENTRESS QV, that program is moving forward. We have not made any announcements in terms of additional developments there. The project date for that remains 2011.</p>
          <p>With regard to Portola, that program is in Phase II of clinical development, and we are actively engaged in discussions with our new partners to move that program forward. And we have not made any announcements about when that will go into Phase III.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Chris, for your question about the economy and co-pays. We are very mindful that the impact of the economy really does make a difference, particularly to certain lower income, middle income patients. And among diabetics, as you know, they are often on multiple medications.</p>
          <p>And so we do, in fact, have programs that are couponing programs that are discount programs that are aimed at helping patients be able to absorb some of the economic impact of their co-pays. We actually target those programs. We're very cognizant of the differential impact that has had across geographies within the U.S., as well as certain patient demographics. So we really do try to target those programs where we think they'll create the greatest good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of David Risinger with Morgan Stanley.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thanks very much. I have two questions. First, could you just comment on the sequential trends in JANUVIA prescriptions? It seems like the IMS data suggests that JANUVIA has stopped growing in new RXs in the last several months.</p>
          <p>And then second, with respect to the cholesterol joint venture, I believe that Merck management has commented that you expect revenue growth for that cholesterol joint venture in 2010. Is that correct? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the JANUVIA question, we have continued to see growth for JANUVIA. I think fortunately we are continuing to see growth, as we mentioned on the earlier part of the call, and we have a number of programs in place to continue to drive the future growth of the brand, including making it now our top priority for our sales and marketing organization. We continue to introduce new data. We continue to add on, for example, with the long-acting METFORMIN as well as the peoglibzone.</p>
          <p>So we continue to implement a number of patient programs, direct to patient advertising. We have physician office programs and pharmacy initiatives to address, as I mentioned a few minutes ago, the potential cost barriers on patients. So we continue to believe that we can drive additional growth. It is now the focus of our efforts now in -- particularly our U.S. sales force.</p>
          <p>On the cholesterol sales force, I mentioned earlier, in earlier calls, we do expect growth. We have not said exactly when. The products continue to grow outside the U.S., and we continue to believe that JANUVIA -- excuse me -- that VYTORIN and ZETIA are important treatment options, particularly as people try to treat to the newest treatment goals around LDL lowering, and in particular, for high risk patients.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Catherine Arnold with Credit Suisse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. Two topics. One for Peter, in terms of the staph vaccine, I'm wondering if it's reasonable to think that at your second quarter briefing you might have an update in terms of your go/no-go decision? And if you could give us any sense in terms of what the hurdle rate would be in reduction of incidence of staph.</p>
          <p>And then as far as the upcoming ARBITER 6 HALTS data, I know you guys are not in control of that, but you, no doubt, from a marketing perspective, have to be thinking about various outcomes of that meeting. And I'm wondering, the next day, if the study is favorable to niacin, which given the patient population, isn't a crazy thought, what are your sales reps going to say in reaction to doctors asking about that? And what will your medical information folks say to the same? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Katherine. With regard to the staph vaccine, there is nothing to update you. As you know, last time, I told you that we did anticipate a delay in the proof of concept decision due to slower enrollment as well as significantly lower event rates that were occurring in that trial.</p>
          <p>With regard to ARBITER 6, I'd just like &#x2013; a few points. One is that obviously ARBITER 6 -- we don't know the results of that study yet. I do think, as you know, it is a IMT study. It's not an outcome study. And we certainly think it's important to note that IMT studies have had inconsistent results in the past.</p>
          <p>One notable example that you're probably familiar with is the cashmere study, which was a 12 month study comparing 80 milligrams of Atorvastatin to placebo. And in that IMT study, comparing 80-milligrams of Atorvastatin to placebo, there was not a statistically significant difference between the two groups when measured by IMT. And as all of you are very well aware, that result stands in marked contrast to multiple large clinical outcome studies that have shown a clear benefit of Atorvastatin on reducing cardiovascular disease.</p>
          <p>That said, as you point out, Catherine, the study was &#x2013; the ARBITER 6 study was conducted in patients that had been extensively pre-treated with statins, had well controlled LDL, but relatively low HDL. So therefore it's a study design that would likely favor niacin. In addition, there was no placebo control, so even if there were a difference to be observed between the two arms, one couldn't determine an effect for either treatment approach versus placebo.</p>
          <p>And finally, it's a small study. There are fewer than 400 patients in this study. So therefore, we think, again, not knowing the results, it would be inappropriate to draw conclusions about the outcomes from that study regardless of the result.</p>
          <p>The way to study this question, of course, is to do a true outcome study. And as you know, that's what we're doing, with IMPROVE-IT. And indeed, happy to let you know that IMPROVE-IT, through extensive efforts on the part our investigators to expand the number of countries as well as sites, is now doing very well, and I'm pleased to announce that the enrollment has now increased to over 15,000 patients. So we fully expect that this study, IMPROVE-IT, will answer the question in the way it should be answered, which is an outcome study.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So from a commercial standpoint, Catherine, I want you to know that we have a proactive plan in place for AHA, and the company -- both companies will have a strong presence there.</p>
          <p>We also know how important it is not only to provide fair and balanced scientific information at that meeting, but to also have the right outreach to the medical community and other key constituencies, including the media. And also to communicate directly and forthrightly with our customers, including patients, providers and payers.</p>
          <p>So our intent is to engage all those constituencies, including key scientific leaders, to ensure the results of the study are put in the appropriate scientific context, as Peter just discussed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from line of Eric Lo with Bank of America Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, guys. Question on the animal health business. With Sanofi interested in exercising the option to combine the Merial with Intervet, what's the willingness for the company to divest assets in order to ensure the combination will actually pass regulatory hurdles?</p>
          <p>And a question on GARDASIL. What do you think the market potential is for the male indication for GARDASIL? And what's the marketing strategy for the new indication? And can you also provide some update in terms of any improvements in the second and third dose compliance rates for female vaccinations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, it's Bruce Kuhlik. With respect to your question about the animal health business, if Sanofi does exercise the call option following the completion of our merger with Schering-Plough, we would work closely with them and with the antitrust and competition authorities as needed to determine what sorts of divestitures would be required in order to close that transaction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As for GARDASIL, as we mentioned, the ACIP did vote to recommend permissive use in boys age 9 to 26, but did provide vaccine funding for males through the VFC program. We think that's an important development in that it enables access, and what we will be doing is working with public health authorities, state and local health authorities, as well as with pediatricians to ensure that people understand the very real medical burden associated with genital warts.</p>
          <p>So I would say that, as I said in the earlier remarks, we see this as an opportunity. We think it's a real opportunity. We do not think the uptake will be like it was for females. It's very early days after what we heard yesterday, but we are eager to get out there and help people understand the importance of this drug -- this vaccine for men.</p>
          <p>As it relates to the compliance issues, the compliance rates for GARDASIL among women remain high compared to historical norms for vaccination. Private compliance rates remain at approximately 75% for the second dose and about 50% for the third dose. We should note that we do have ongoing efforts to further increase compliance levels through programs that focus on those various stage groups.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Steve Scala with Cowen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I have two questions. First for Dr. Kim, what is the total enrollment of HPS2-THRIVE to date? And would the results of the pre-specified safety analysis at 25,000 patients be something that Merck would seek cordaptive approval on? And that would presumably be well before 2012.</p>
          <p>And second question is on SINGULAIR. Merck has said in the past it would look at a new DC opportunity. The question is, would that automatically go through J&amp;J Merck, or could that be retained by Schering-Plough OTC? And perhaps more broadly, does J&amp;J Merck have rights to future Schering-Plough RX to OTC switches? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Steve, I'll take the first one. With regard to HPS2-THRIVE, which is our clinical outcome study with TREDAPTIVE, I'm pleased to say that enrollment is going very well. And we &#x2013; the current enrollment is now over 20,000 patients.</p>
          <p>With regard to your question about the interim analysis, the interim analysis, as you said, was a safety interim analysis. But that study design has been modified by Oxford, which is the group that's conducting this trial, as well as Merck. And the two groups decided that interim safety analysis was not necessary at this point, because the safety of TREDAPTIVE is being assessed by an independent data safety monitoring board on a regular basis that reviews unblinded safety data as this goes on.</p>
          <p>And based on these reviews, the DSMB has confirmed that the study should continue as planned, and so we are just continuing to move forward with this trial, which, as I said, is progressing very well in terms of enrollment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Bruce Kuhlik. With respect to your questions about the OTC business, obviously we do have a joint venture with Johnson &amp; Johnson to develop and market certain non-prescription medicines. That will continue to operate as a separate business from the OTC business in the combined Merck/Schering-Plough company following the merger.</p>
          <p>The specific criteria that we have for our obligations to offer products to the J&amp;J joint venture in the U.S. and Canada are confidential, and we can't disclose those terms. And it does relate only to the U.S. and Canada.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Jami Rubin with Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Peter, I have a couple of questions for you. First on the BETRIXABAN. Just curious to know if you think that the results from the RE-LY trial this past summer raises the efficacy bar for the other factor 10As? And if you could again remind us how BETRIXABAN compares to the other factor 10As, which do appear to be ahead of yours?</p>
          <p>And then the other question relates to ISENTRESS. Just any signal for capturing frontline uptake since the label expansion? And can you make this a fixed dose combo with NRTIs? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jami. I'll take the first one and just comment very quickly on the very last part of your second question, which is that we have not disclosed anything on combination products with ISENTRESS, but it is something that is certainly of interest to us.</p>
          <p>With regard to BETRIXABAN, which is the factor 10A anticoagulant that we license from Portola, the RE-LY results are certainly very interesting and need to be considered with regard to development of any anticoagulants moving forward.</p>
          <p>That said, the reason why we are so excited about the Portola molecule is that we believe that it is clearly the best -- has the potential to clearly be the best in class factor 10A out there. It's a once a day dosing, it has a very low peak-to-trough ratio as compared to the competitors, and it has minimal renal clearance, which would indicate or suggest that we can develop that without a dose modification for patients with renal impairment, which is very important in this patient population.</p>
          <p>So while acknowledging your point that we are behind competitors with this molecule, the reason why we did this license was because we think that this molecule has the potential to be by far the best-in-class factor 10A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On ISENTRESS, as far as moving to the first line indication in effect to treatment na&#xEF;ve population, Jami, we're not in a position now to give any data about the change in the first line usage of the drug.</p>
          <p>But I will say that we are pleased with the addition of this, and that expanded indication does provide us an opportunity to accelerate the growth for this product because a number of physicians recognize it's really got terrific safety and tolerability profiles. So this expanded indication makes available to physicians another treatment option and really enables us to begin to unlock the product's full potential.</p>
          <p>So while I'm not able to give a specific answer, I do say it's early days, and that's something that's very much in our focus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Keyur Parekh with UBS.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, and thanks for taking my question. The question actually was on PNEUMOVAX 23, and if you could just run us through some of the numbers that you spoke about earlier in terms of the $130 million in revenues this quarter. Do you expect the run rate to continue, and were there any kind of stockpile sales that was part of the $130 million? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, as I said, the current quarter does reflect, first of all, an acceleration in demand. Sales were up from $72 million in the third quarter of '08 to $130 million, and a lot of that has to do with the focus that physicians and patients have on the H1N1 pandemic and the prevention of pneumococcal pneumonia.</p>
          <p>But I also should point out that third quarter sales did benefit to some extent from government agencies purchasing quantities of pneumococcal vaccine as part of their pandemic flu preparedness strategies. So I think we're in a unique area now with respect to the pandemic flu concerns, and we continue to work with many government agencies and health authorities around the world to help them address their needs.</p>
          <p>I will say that as far as stockpiles go, to date the orders for stockpiles that we've received have been relatively modest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Tim Anderson with Sanford Bernstein.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Maybe a couple of questions for Ken, and then, Peter, a question for you.</p>
          <p>Ken, you continue to talk a bullish pieces behind VYTORIN and ZETIA, but it's been almost two years since you have been out of the market with DTC on VYTORIN and ZETIA, and I'm wondering why that's still the case, and when that might restart?</p>
          <p>And the second question is on ISENTRESS. International sales were greater than U.S. sales for the first time, and I'm wondering if you can give us an idea of how big you think the ex-U.S. market can be relative to the U.S. market for this product.</p>
          <p>The question for Peter is, I guess with Analyst Day not coming until some time in the next year, can you highlight the one or two novel Phase III pipeline drugs that you're most excited about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the ISENTRESS questions, we are pleased with the ex-U.S. uptake. It's really reflecting the strong launches that we've had in France and Spain and Italy, as I said. And I can't really comment on how big the ex-U.S. will be relative to the U.S. I just think that it has gotten a very strong reception in the EU countries, and we continue to see, as I said, opportunity to accelerate growth outside the U.S. and inside the US.</p>
          <p>As it relates to VYTORIN and ZETIA in DTC, the JV continues to evaluate the opportunities for direct to consumer advertising. We continue to look at what's happening in the outside world in the communications environment. And we will continue to monitor those things and to make decisions as to where we think the right investment should be behind those two products.</p>
          <p>I should also point out that just because we're not into the broadcast marketplace for DTC, it doesn't mean that we're not continuing to strongly resource these brands.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And with regard to the pipeline, I guess the products that I would highlight here are first of all our osteoporosis drug, odanacatib, or MK-0822. As you know, this is a novel mechanism, cathepsin K inhibitor. And we have been conducting an outcome study, a fracture study, and I'm pleased to say that that enrollment is going very well, and we actually anticipate that our study enrollment will be complete by the end of this month. So that -- those results -- that trial is moving forward very well, and we've presented three-year data in bone mineral density increases at a recent scientific meeting, and what we're seeing is those bone mineral density measurements continue to increase over time even after three years. But also importantly that if you stop the drug that you see the bone marrow density comes down indicating that the drug's effect does not persist long after a physician chooses to stop treating. Moreover that the bone turnover continues even while you're on drugs, so we think that this drug has really tremendous potential, not only in terms of increasing bone mineral density but also allowing for healthy bone development during treatment, and we obviously anxiously await the results of the outcome study as we move forward, but are pleased with the situation with regard to enrollment. The other drug I would highlight is anacetrapib, which is our CETP inhibitor. As you know, we started the Phase III trial defined in April of 2008. This is being studied in patients with coronary heart disease. That study continues to move forward; it's now fully enrolled. And we anticipate completion by the end of 2010 for that study. And we also continue to anticipate that we will start the cardiovascular outcome study for the CETP drug in 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of John Boris with Citi.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for taking the questions. For Peter, just on R&amp;D and integration planning, do you have or can you forward or provide any commentary on what percent of the R&amp;D personnel that you might be able to retain? I think also Dick has referred to the productivity of R&amp;D as being a critical thing and a potential case study in the making in that most large mergers have obviously failed in that arena. Can you give us some color as to why this may be a case study in the making. And then on HIV treatment guidelines for ISENTRESS, can both you and Ken provide some color on how that might shape the U.S. market both positive and negative for ISENTRESS going forward? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, John. With regard to R&amp;D integration planning, what I would say is that this is moving forward very well. We have a team that is working very hard on both sides to put in place what we call the portfolio cards, which outline the key attributes of each of the molecules that are in the pipelines, starting with pre-clinical development and working all the way through to post marketing studies. Those cards, as we call them, are being filled out in detail such that on day one we will be in a position to rapidly move to a prioritization process with which we look at the portfolio in detail. And actually, I think it's fair to say that the scientists are quite excited about the &#x2013; looking forward to being able to do that prioritization. With regard to the personnel, and the retention of the personnel, this is something that has been very much on my mind. I have gone around and visited with all of the Schering-Plough and indeed many of the Merck sites as well. And the message that I'm putting out there is that we &#x2013; in research &#x2013; that we are going to take a staged approach to how it is that we evaluate things, and that approach is going to begin with the people.</p>
          <p>The first thing we need to do is understand the people, the talent that we have, the capabilities that we have. The second thing we need to do is understand the programs and how it is that the programs between the two companies should be brought together, where are there overlaps, where are there redundancies, and where are there potential complementarities and potential benefits to enhance programs that are ongoing in one company or the other. Then and only then are we going to turn to network considerations. And that's going to take us some time. So from the point of view of research, it's really right now a critical component to focus on retaining our key talent, identifying and then retaining our key talent, identifying the key opportunities for programmatic positive effects, but also where there are redundancies, and then to deal with the issues around the network.</p>
          <p>And finally I would say &#x2013; and I have talked about this before, that I think that the franchise strategy that we have put in place, the franchise structure that we have put in place, is really going to be critical in terms of allowing us to across the franchises make the key prioritizations that we need to do. We're going to do this on a research franchise by research franchise basis, not on a site by site basis. So for example, in cardiovascular disease, we're going to look across the entire spectrum of everything in both companies in cardiovascular disease, and we're going to prioritize according to those priorities within that disease area across both companies. And I think the fact that we spent the last few years putting in place this franchise structure with a franchise, a research franchise head as well as a research franchise structure, will allow us to approach this in a way where we will be able to not only maintain but enhance productivity moving forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And as far as the question about the impact of the evolving HIV guidelines on ISENTRESS, of course we continue to evaluate that as well as what's happening in terms of clinical practice in the marketplace. We can't specifically give a comment about your question, but I will say that we continue to be pleased by the fact that physicians continue to adopt it; it's now the fourth most prescribed medicine in a very crowded market, and we're continuing with Peter's help to work on the product going forward to get the kinds of product profile modifications that will help. For example, combination products, as well as the once daily dose of ISENTRESS on which we began a Phase III study last September.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's the last question and concludes today's call. The information from today's call, both the transcript and replay, will be available at our website for the next several months. And Carol Ferguson and I will be available to take any incremental calls throughout the day.</p>
          <p>Cynthia?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, ladies and gentlemen, this concludes today's conference. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>