<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1430773" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-05-15</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9098</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Joshua S. Young</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Member-Executive Board">Matthias Zachert</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Ltd.">Richard B. Vosser</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane BNP Paribas SA">Vincent Meunier</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Ltd.">Andrew S. Baum</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities (Europe) Ltd.">Matthew J. Weston</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and welcome to Merck's First Quarter 2012 Earnings Presentation and Conference Call. My name is Joshua Young. I am Head of Investor Relations for Merck. And joining me on today's presentation is Matthias Zachert, Chief Financial Officer of Merck.</p>
          <p>We're thrilled to have many of you with us personally here at our headquarters in Darmstadt, Germany and we extend a warm welcome to all of you who are joining us over the Internet via our live video webcast.</p>
          <p>I'd like begin by stating that we will be referencing a slide presentation as part of today's presentation that involve risks and uncertainties. I'll pause for moment to allow you to review the disclaimer statements.</p>
          <p>I'd also like to point out that we have all the materials relating to this morning's earnings announcement on our website for download, including our quarterly report and our financial statements in Excel.</p>
          <p>The statements we make today are effective as of business conditions for today, May 15, 2012. We will be holding two separate events today. The first is our earnings presentation. We will cover the Q1 result as well as Q&amp;A for approximately 45 minutes. We will then begin our Capital Markets Day, promptly at 10:00 AM Central European Time.</p>
          <p>In order to adequately prepare for the Capital Markets Day, we will end this earnings presentation promptly at 9:15 AM. If we are unable to get your questions on the earnings call, you will have the opportunity to raise them at the Q&amp;A session during the Capital Markets Day. We will accept questions for this morning's event from both the live audience and for those of you who are joining us via the telephone.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to turn over the presentation to Matthias Zachert.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody, here in Darmstadt. I would like to start my presentation with slide number three and the key highlights for the first quarter 2012. By and large, it needs to be stated, Q1 2012 is definitely the toughest quarter compared to previous year quarterly performance.</p>
          <p>While we did perform, I think, reasonably well on the top-line in terms of net sales with round about 3.5% net sales increase, stemming notably from Merck Millipore performance and also from Merck Serono, our EBITDA was falling short versus the previous year. I will reference and explain the reasons behind that in a few moments.</p>
          <p>What is also noteworthy is that we started the long-awaited efficiency program with announcements in February as far as the worldwide program is concerned and since that period of time, we started the execution process especially as related to the first announcement -- big announcement in beginning of the second quarter in April.</p>
          <p>With this, I turn to page number five, and here I'll address the regional geographical performance. The trends that you've seen in the course of 2011 basically continue. You see that Europe is sluggish on an organic basis with sales declining by roughly 2%, which has been mitigated quite nicely by our emerging market performance. Also, this is a trend that you've seen, of course, over 2011 and this is a trend that we assume will be ongoing, not only in the course of 2012, but also in the following years.</p>
          <p>As far as North American performance is concerned, I think we posted a reasonable operational improvements of round about three percentage points. The key driver behind that was a price increase that we posted in the U.S. in January on our biggest drug called Rebif in the neighborhood of nine percentage point.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn the attention to page five and here, I will address the P&amp;L, and let me first of all address the royalty income line. In Q1 2011, we posted a milestone payments in the neighborhood of &#x20AC;9 million for the product called Vilazodone, so this was a one-time milestone payment that, of course, increased the base in Q1 2011.</p>
          <p>The major impact that we see on the operational performance, however, is coming from the gross profit line. Here you do see that whilst sales are moving up nicely, our gross profit margin rise in absolute terms is showing a shortfall. Drivers behind that is the start-up cost of LSB and our plant Vevey. I started indicating this to you from Q2 last year onwards that we posted round about &#x20AC;75 million of incremental costs.</p>
          <p>Now that Vevey has further scaled up in the course of 2012, these start-up costs have moved up to round about &#x20AC;20 million. So this will on an ongoing basis for the remainder quarter, increase versus previous year. So the delta is between &#x20AC;7.5 million and &#x20AC;20 million.</p>
          <p>But the big driver behind the gross margin decline is the lack of positive manufacturing variances, which, all-in-all, were positively contributing to the P&amp;L Q1 2011 by roughly &#x20AC;50 million. And I guess, I highlighted that already in the last six to nine months that that has led to a quite high comparable base in Q1 2012 versus Q1 2011. So this was predominately the major driver for the abnormal high gross profit in Q1 2011.</p>
          <p>As far as marketing and selling costs are concerned, you do see that we manage them more tightly. So here, we go in the right direction. Royalty and commission expenses, the increase is reflecting the positive sales growth that we posted on Rebif and also on Erbitux.</p>
          <p>As far as other expenses and income is concerned, again, please take note of the fact that in Q1 2011, we posted the capital gain for the divestiture of Crop BioScience, round about &#x20AC;150 million, entered the P&amp;L positively on a like-for-like basis, i.e. EBITDA pre of cost we have restated that.</p>
          <p>So this brings me to the EBITDA pre-analysis. You do see that the shortfall is predominantly stemming from the lack of gross profit contribution, and here, the key driver is the extraordinary gross profit that we posted in Q1, 2011.</p>
          <p>With this, I'll turn to the remaining lines of the P&amp;L on page six and the two elements driving reported numbers. On the P&amp;L, i.e. the capital gain of Crop BioScience and the lower operational performance, are always also here filtering through or hitting through the P&amp;L as far as EBIT, profit before taxes and net profit <mark type="ph" /> pre-EBIT concerns (7:56).</p>
          <p>Let me now draw your attention to page seven to our biggest division, Merck Serono. And here, I would like to first of all give you more color on the sales performance. This was, in terms of sales, a strong quarter from Merck Serono with organic growth at round about four percentage point.</p>
          <p>Key drivers behind that was the fertility franchise. Please take note of the fact that we've introduced a family of pens over the last few quarters, notably in Europe, and this positive lifecycle managements yields to positive growth rate. So we posted with our Gonal-f franchise strong growth rates versus previous year level.</p>
          <p>Other contributors are the ones that you've seen in course of 2011, emerging markets, I referenced to already and our Endocrinology franchise has also posted positive sales contribution.</p>
          <p>On the gross profit line, you see in higher clarity what I've just indicated before. Merck Serono normally doesn't post gross margin of round about 91%. This was however the case in Q1 2011. So, the ongoing rate in Merck Serono in the gross profit line is rather in the area of 84% to 86%. So here you do see that we performed reasonably well in Q1, '12 beside LSB and beside the Swiss franc being at CHF 1.20. However, the lack of positive manufacturing variances, of course, left its mark compared to previous year trading level.</p>
          <p>On the SG&amp;A line, you do see that we have two factors leading to an absolute increase. However, please take note of the fact that round about &#x20AC;10 million are associated to increase in royalty expenses and round about &#x20AC;20 million are coming from the one-time costs we incurred for Merck Serono on the efficiency program.</p>
          <p>They are detailed in the back-up, so we've detailed in the back-up clearly what the one-time costs are, where they are coming from, and in Merck Serono, we've taken first actions and therefore, we incurred round about &#x20AC;20 million in SG&amp;A for one-time charges.</p>
          <p>In light of this and especially in light of the gross margin lack of positive manufacturing variances, you do see that at EBITDA pre-level, the division performed reasonably well, falling round about just &#x20AC;6 million short of profitability versus previous year.</p>
          <p>If you now look into the trading for the remainder of the year, my feedback to you would be, first quarter was a toughy, definitely the case not only for Merck Serono. But as far as the other quarters are concerned, you should assume that Merck Serono will now start to hedge a better comparable basis, and therefore, from Q2 onwards, we should improve versus previous year comparison trading. Whilst third and fourth quarter should then slightly strengthen, because here, our assumption is that from third quarter onwards, synergies are going to ramp up and more materialized than Q4.</p>
          <p>With this, I come to page number eight, and then to our Consumer Health business. For Consumer Health, it needs to be stated that 2012 is going to be a transitory year. We have addressed major initiatives. We are still working on many of them, and I think they will be communicated to you in due course.</p>
          <p>So here we face a tough situation in Q1, falling short in terms of a sales performance whilst it needs to be mentioned that there was, of course, also an overall weakness in the European markets. We had some supply chain problems in France, which, by now, has been managed.</p>
          <p>So overall, Q1 sales performance is not a very impressive one. But it should improve here sales-wise from the second quarter onwards and then gain more momentum also as far as the profitability is concerned. We've mitigated the sales shortfall through addressing the SG&amp;A base. So you see that here, first actions have been taken, whilst on a profitability basis, you see a shortfall of roughly &#x20AC;2 million versus previous year level. Also here, the comments pretty much are the same like I've done for Merck-Serono. Do expect for that &#x2013; from second quarter onwards, the trading pattern will improve and we'll then get more grip, as far as third quarter and fourth quarter is concerned.</p>
          <p>Let me now turn the attention to page number nine and here, our Performance Materials business. From the headline, you can already see that we stress the abnormal sales development in first quarter 2011. At that point in time, liquid crystals posted an abnormal 20% organic sales growth, abnormal. Of course, these incremental sales flow through the P&amp;L and that has led now, on a comparable basis, to a reported shortfall versus previous-year level, hurting also gross margin. So we see that less sales reducing, of course, gross margin levels, and the other element that has had implications on the gross margin was the reduction in PS-VA.</p>
          <p>Q1 2011, we were still posting round about 100% market share in PS-VA, a very nice profit margin product. And over second, third and fourth quarter in 2011, we saw that our market share in PS-VA went down to round about 50 percentage points. We have kept in Q1 2012 this market share, as a matter of fact, started even to increase it again a little bit. But of course now, on a like-for-like basis, we have A, the shortfall of these exceptional sales in Q1 2011 and also, the change in product mix stemming from PS-VA. These were the primary drivers for EBITDA falling short versus Q1 2011.</p>
          <p>As far as SG&amp;A is concerned, I would simply like to update you that Crop BioScience, the business that was divested in Q1 2011, was reported under Performance Materials. Thus, you achieved, or we reported here in 2011, the capital gain of roughly &#x20AC;150 million, which of course distorts the picture in the comparison. If you blend out Crop Science divestures, you basically see that SG&amp;A costs in Performance Materials have been kept flat, as a matter of fact, even reduced slightly.</p>
          <p>Let me now move to page number 10, to Merck Millipore business. Here, you do see the strong performance on the sales side, where we posted nice absolute increase in sales. Gross profit and margins went up, notably driven by economies of scale, so utilization being better compared to previous year level.</p>
          <p>As far as SG&amp;A is concerned, the increase is stemming from the acquisitions that we did last year. Two acquisitions were done in Merck Millipore, bolt-on acquisitions. And we've also taken the decision as indicated last year to invest next to SG&amp;A in North America here into the sales force and notably for the business unit Lab Solutions. We have invested also in R&amp;D, and here, however, notably in the business unit, Process Solutions, which you know is one of our flagship businesses in Merck Millipore.</p>
          <p>As far as EBITDA is concerned, a mild improvement versus previous year. Here, you should see for the remainder of the year a good performance versus previous year in Q2 and Q3. So, last year's comparable basis in Q2 and Q3 were more mild. However, the seasonality will be pretty much the same, i.e. strong Q1; Q2, Q3 will be somewhat in absolute terms lower than Q1. However, on a 12-months quarterly comparison, you will see a very reasonable performance Q2 versus Q2, Q3 versus Q3.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn the attention to the balance sheet on page 11. The two major statements I would like to make here is we have delevered, so gross debt has gone down more than &#x20AC;500 million, stemming from the repayment of the Euro bonds that matured on the 26th of March. So, here, the entire month was paid back and therefore, gross debt for the very first time in the last 12 months is also going down. As far as net debt is concerned, you can see that our net debt equally nicely improved by nearly &#x20AC;500 million, so you see that we move on in terms of strengthening the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>On page 12, we show where the cash flow is coming from. On an operational side, the cash flow was very sound. And that led to the possibility of nicely deleveraging the balance sheet with internal means. The one area, however, where you see, of course, the divestures of 2011 coming through is the cash flow statement. So you saw the positive P&amp;L capital gain, but also in the cash flow statement in Q1 2011, under Others, we, of course, reported the positive purchase price proceeds in the cash flow line Others, which led to nice incremental cash inflow.</p>
          <p>If you planned that out and you look at the pure operational cash flow generation, you see that Q1 was a pretty strong quarter and with this, I turn to guidance on page 13. As far as the Merck divisions are concerned, we precise further the guidance that was already given on the 6th of March, now in a quantitative way. So this is what we've started to do and alluded to in terms of methodology already last year. So beginning of the year with Q4, we start in a qualitative way and then from Q1 onwards, we start in a quantitative way and will precise that further in the course of the year.</p>
          <p>So here, of course for the group level, this is where this hard guidance is going through. The divisions is more &#x2013; should be more seen as a kind of orientation. So the group guidance for total revenues is at round about &#x20AC;10.5 billion, whilst for EBITDA pre, including <mark type="ph" /> round of &#x20AC;50 million (20:15) of savings from the project already communicated, we should be in a range between &#x20AC;2.8 billion and &#x20AC;2.9 billion. So this is the guidance for the group.</p>
          <p>A kind of trading indication where our sales by the divisions will go and this is, of course, net sales, so excluding royalties. Royalty income, Merck Serono should operate around the 2% top line reported sales increase. Consumer Health will catch up versus the poor performance in Q1. Of course, this is a little bit more ambitious. So here, we have to catch up and this should start from Q2 onwards.</p>
          <p>And the same holds true for Performance Materials. So here, whilst Q1 was a toughy in terms of comparable base in both terms, sales and profitability, in Performance Materials, you should assume that the second quarter and the third quarter should be, sales-wise, reasonable, positive and also profitability-wise, whilst fourth quarter will be a little milder, so that as far as the trading pattern is concerned for Performance Materials.</p>
          <p>And as far as Merck Millipore is concerned, the reported growth rate that you have seen in Q1 should continue, so here, the reported sales growth should be between 4% and 6%.</p>
          <p>Please take note of the guidance we also provide for currencies that is footnoted accordingly. And with this, I would like to have a little housekeeping topic and I move into the backup, slide 20. You see that we have reclassified, not restated, reclassified 2011 divisional numbers and the corporate segments for one simple reason.</p>
          <p>Merck in the past was allocating a lot of administration costs to the divisions and what we found out in the new management teams. when we asked for responsibility on the P&amp;L, we often had a discussion. There are costs allocated to us that we cannot control. They come from corporate in an allocated way.</p>
          <p>I've seen that in 2004 as well. And for that very reason, we took the decision to start changing this methodology. So basically, the first step has been a mild one. The first step is to basically take round about &#x20AC;32 million of allocations being loaded or being dumped in the divisions. We've stopped them. They are kept where they are created in terms of cost, i.e. with the corporate functions.</p>
          <p>So this is the first step. It doesn't change the performance of the group, so the &#x20AC;2.729 billion remained the &#x20AC;2.729 billion at group level but, of course, the business are respectively relieved. The corporate admin costs will become more transparent. We will take another step at the end of the year and take out another chunk of costs which are being allocated. Then this portion will increase further, will become more visible and the result is, the operational P&amp;L holders will have full accountability on the P&amp;L. At group level, the admin costs will become more visible and in itself, will create a certain need for activity.</p>
          <p>This is all I would like to say on Q1 and I therefore would like to open the Q&amp;A session.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll have about 20 minutes for Q&amp;A. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> So we'll open it up. Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. If you could provide the breakdown for Rebif of price versus volume increase in Q1 and Erbitux as well and also, the performance of the fertility?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you go through the back-up slide, we have an overview basically on the organic growth rate of the respective key products. I think it's slide number 16 or 15, and here, you see that the performance, organic performance including price and volume, of course, on Rebif was round about 3%. Erbitux performed more mildly, in the area of round about 1%, while the endocrinology drugs posted high single-digit growth rates organically and as far as Gonal-f is concerned, we were in the teens. So that is giving you the breakdown on the key products.</p>
          <p>As far as the pricing is concerned for the key two products, we, at this point in time, do not provide color in the respective pricing and volume direction. What I would verbally like to indicate to you, however, is overall, you see that absolute-wise, Rebif sales went up. Of course, we had a stronger contribution due to the pricing initiatives that we took in the U.S. So this was of course a major driver behind net sales increase, while volumes were slightly negative. And so net-net, we posted an overall net sales increase, whilst pricing being clearly positive and volume being negative. This is the key answer for Rebif.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I think that's a little over double-digit or high single-digit <mark type="ph" /> Rebif start. We've seen (26:45) emerging markets with respect to the first quarter being weak-ish. Are there any specific factors you'd call out in your business? And then the second question is on the &#x20AC;50 million of savings and just a few more details, if possible, if a net figure, which division, predominantly, I guess, is Merck Serono and is it predominantly fourth quarter? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I'll start with the second question. The net savings here predominantly is, so the &#x20AC;50 million savings is a net saving. So that's the reason why we can be on the EBITDA pre. I would say quite on a position to somewhat upgrade the qualitative guidance we've provided at the beginning of the year. We only stated at the beginning of the year that we would be slightly above previous year level. If you go into the new corridor of the guidance &#x20AC;2.8 billion to &#x20AC;2.9 billion, the increase here, especially as far as the higher end is concerned, is stemming from the net savings. So, it's truly a net saving. So this is your second question, and of course, predominantly, this is coming from Merck Serono.</p>
          <p>As far as your first question is concerned, I think our emerging market setup is one that in the past, never showed the same strong growth rate of others, being even in the double-digit. We have always been in the single-digit, however, on a continued path. And this is stemming from the fact that the emerging market setup that we have is relatively diversified. We are not only present in China; as a matter of fact, we are from the leadership position stronger in other markets, like in Latin America and the remainder of countries of Asia.</p>
          <p>So here, the growth rates are not as high as the growth rates of other companies. But the diversification in our emerging market is clearly stronger. And for that very reason, I think the stability on the growth rates have been an element that you've seen in the past and is an element you, despite the toughy environment that most of the companies face in the emerging markets, was one that we were not so much impacted in Q1 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Richard?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Richard Vosser from JPMorgan. Just one question. Just on the Millipore, I was just seeing that the first quarter always seems to be the strongest of the year. What contributes that seasonality and some insight on that would be very useful? Thanks. If indeed, there is seasonality there?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think, in Merck Millipore and the tools business, it's a very fragmented industry. So, we have seen that the first quarter in the tools industry basically was not the strongest quarter so far. You have seen growth rates of many life tools company being in the area of round about 2%. So here, we performed reasonably well. But the one area that you can, I think, easily grasp as far as first quarter performance is concerned in the first quarter as far as academia, laboratory business, the budgets are full. And then people start expensing and then are a little bit milder as they then move into the holiday seasons of Q2 and Q3 and then at the &#x2013; in the fourth quarter, they realized they have budget left and then they accelerate again.</p>
          <p>So this is a little &#x2013; let's say, average indication on the life tools business, especially as far as the academia laboratory business is concerned. Of course, there are many other trends that lead to that, but this is, I think, the one that you can take no doubt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="ph" /> Jacob? (30:49)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, <mark type="ph" /> Jacob Tonan from S&amp;P Capital IQ (30:51). Matthias, I'm just wondering if you could add a little color in the cash flow? To that line Others, last year, you booked the gains from the selling of the Crop Science and <mark type="ph" /> Paramix (31:04). What explains the big swing you see here? You booked &#x20AC;466 million, ended at &#x20AC;226 million, and now we sort of see minus &#x20AC;38 million. What is actually booked in that line, is it a lot of money going through that line, I guess?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely, yeah. And I think the biggest swings are coming from the divestitures that we've indicated. And of course, you have other areas that in Q1, we saw and this relates to adjustments in financial transactions that we did on the currency side, we had &#x20AC;10 million-&#x20AC;20 million flowing off here. But this is, I would say on an underlying basis, not the one that can be repeated and therefore, the biggest change that you've seen in Q1 is stemming from the acquisitions, and that is what we've highlighted. Vincent?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Vincent Meunier from Exane BNP Paribas. The first question is on Erbitux. Can you please give us more details regarding the dynamic, especially in Japan, where you say that there is still a decline? Also, can you give us a breakdown of the commission expenses between Rebif and Erbitux? And the last question is on the debt. So there is a &#x20AC;0.5 billion repayment in Q1. What's your target for this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, as far as Japan is concerned, we've seen that Q3 and Q4 gradually improved in terms of sales erosion, so we saw that Q2 was a tough hit. Then in Q3, we &#x2013; the sales erosion reduced. In Q4, it was further mitigated. Now Q1 is in between Q3 and Q4. So we are &#x2013; we have not further improved versus Q3 and Q4. So here, it's a little shortfall in the momentum and therefore, this has led to a reduction in the overall Erbitux performance in Q1 versus previous year levels. And therefore, we were only able to report a round about 1% organic sales increase.</p>
          <p>Stefan will later on give you indications on our guidance for Erbitux. So here, our feedback for entire year 2012 is in the area between 1% and 4% sales growth. So here, the indication that you should read out of that is, we assume that we can again improve, but of course, Japan is a tough market and competition is tough and therefore, we are trying to do our best. But of course, it's one that is high on the agenda of our pharma management team, so that we definitely have in Q1 looked at that, assessed that and want to improve the situation. But it's a very competitive market, differently set-up in Europe. If you look into Erbitux and our performance over the last three to four quarters, you basically can see from the IMS data that we have market share-wise, performed pretty nicely, so Japan is clearly high on the list. So that is what Erbitux is concerned, performance in Japan.</p>
          <p>Second question on Rebif and Erbitux and the split on the commission royalty expenses &#x2013; and commission expenses, and the answer is unfortunately, we don't provide this level of granularity. And as far as debt is concerned, I will give the feedback later on in the presentation for the Capital Markets and here, clearly, there will be an EPS kicker coming from the gross debt repayments.</p>
          <p>Merck currently has the luxury of round about a &#x20AC;2 billion cash position on the balance sheet, so we don't need to freak out when Southern European countries freak out, or the banks there. We are definitely not in a situation to be worried about that, but of course, we have cost of carry. And the cost of carry we currently have reduce EPS and for that very reason, we've started the gross debt deleveraging. There will be another maturity with an even bigger interest kicker in the fourth quarter, which will also be repaid. And I will give you the implications, what does it mean absolute term wise and what does it mean gross debt wise, later on in the presentation under the Capital Markets Day agenda. And with this, I think I've addressed all your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perfect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, just on the &#x20AC;50 million in net savings, just looking to understand, there is a gross number associated with that, trying to understand the reinvestment rate, in essence? On Rebif, the U.S. price increase is obviously another circa 9%. I think there were two last year of a similar magnitude. Just trying to understand the sustainability of that price going forward and then, if you have a quick update on the Rebif manufacturing with respect to the FDA warning letters? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So as far as the savings is concerned, we will give you details on that later on. The explicit decision that we have taken is, we will communicate to you net saving. It's easier. So net savings means, this is what you should see going down in the respect of P&amp;L line.</p>
          <p>Will there be gross investments? I have seen many of you debating about that. If Merck is going to give gross savings and then they don't give net savings, and at the end of the day, nothing ends up in the P&amp;L. So what we have decided to do, we will not communicate on gross savings. We communicate on net savings. And moreover, we will give you absolute targets later on in the course of today, by the group, by the division. So the package, I think, giving you net savings and targets, should make it easier for you to understand where we will go, more on that, <mark type="ph" /> Edward (37:51), later on in the Capital Markets Day.</p>
          <p>On pricing, we monitor all our competitors, notably in the U.S. So we see what Avonex, Copaxone and the like are doing and therefore, when we see &#x2013; if it makes sense from our side to position and to price Rebif differently, whilst we know that this is a very, very good product, we take appropriate actions.</p>
          <p>Last year, we have taken the action twice, you are fully correct. This year, we began taking pricing in January and we have very recently, for May, announced another price increase of 6.5% in the U.S. So this is also something that you will most likely hear in more detail later on, and for that very reason, our communication on Rebif and our guidance for Rebif for 2012 is, again, stable sales performance versus previous year level.</p>
          <p>As far as FDA is concerned, the one thing that I can say to you is, we do everything in order to comply with the request of the FDA. This is an ongoing exercise and I think here, you should address this to the project leader who takes care of that and all the interactions with the FDA, Annalisa Jenkins. We do have the opportunity today to speak to the pharma officers that are basically in charge of that and give you all a level of granularity so that you see that we are taking actions in order to manage this concern from the FDA. Of course, we do everything in order to make sure that our patients receive the right quality for our product, so that from this end, everything is in order. Joshua?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Andrew Baum from Citi. To that point, would you like to put an estimate on what you think the CapEx implications are for whatever remedial work the FDA recommends in rectifying the manufacturing issues associated with the U.S.?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's, as far as CapEx &#x2013; and it's both CapEx and OpEx, and this is something we make no sacrifice on. But it's something that is, of course, embedded in the guidance that we provide you on the CapEx, but also as far as our OpEx and our financial targets are concerned -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, it's already embedded in what you've given us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I mean, if there is something extraordinary happened, extraordinary element you cannot factor in, but that is what we are not seeing at this point in time. So, as far as CapEx is concerned, as far as audit costs or quality costs are concerned, we are getting the support also externally in order to manage that. So we're addressing that and we spend money on that in order to make sure that these standards are being achieved. And that is, however, embedded in the forecast numbers that I've just provided for the entire group, with the respective &#x20AC;2.8 billion to &#x20AC;2.9 billion that I indicated earlier on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have time for a few more questions. Matthew?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Matthew Weston from Credit Suisse. Matthias, regarding the restatement of earnings out of the division and into the group, you explained the rationale why, to give the managers better visibility on their P&amp;L, and therefore better control. Can you just explain what the first wave of restated or reallocated costs are for, what you'll reallocate in the second wave and what's the rationale for doing it in two stages? Why not just get it all done?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, first of all, you have to be granular in this assessment. So, what we've done in the first run was basically to, first of all, carve out the costs that are allocated from corporates to divisions. The divisions also allocate costs to the countries and countries allocate costs to each other. So we have a relatively big allocation machine running in this company, which I was &#x2013; I've seen a few allocations before, especially when I started in my previous job, conglomerates often have kind of allocation.</p>
          <p>So in Leverkusen, I have seen that, too, when I joined. And I stopped that immediately, because I had the same kind of finger pointing. Operationally, I've made my P&amp;L, but then these allocations from corporate came. It's a nuisance and it's not value-added. So Merck has done that as well in the past and for that very reason, we've started with the first step to change the allocations from group to divisions.</p>
          <p>Now in the new budget process that we roll out in the course of 2012 for the year 2013, we go a level deeper. We go through all the countries, look at the allocations that are done from divisions to countries, from countries to countries and basically make a stop to that. Cost in the future, we try to put on cost principle, so the one that creates costs gets them, but costs are not just dumped in operational P&amp;L performance for allocation reasons.</p>
          <p>This is no value generation. At the end of the day, this is inward-looking. It's not value creating and for that very reason, we take it into two steps, because it was not feasible to do everything in one goal. So the first approach was group-to-division and on the second approach, we take divisions to countries and countries among themselves. And that is most likely going to happen then at the end of the year 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have time for one more question before we end the call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. With no other questions, we will take a 45-minute break before beginning the Capital Markets Day at 10 AM. Thank you for joining us this morning. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>