<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1382667" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2011 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-04-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>356</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="General Manager-Investor Relations">Bill Koefoed</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Vice President">Peter S. Klein</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley &amp; Co., Inc.">Adam Holt</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets (United States)">Walter H. Pritchard</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="International Strategy &amp; Investment Group, Inc.">Heather A. Bellini</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities LLC">Brent Thill</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (United States)">Philip Winslow</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="BGC Financial LP">Colin W. Gillis MBA</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Oppenheimer Securities">Brad Reback</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Capital Markets Equity Research">Robert Breza</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Cowen &amp; Co.">Gregg Moskowitz</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst" affiliation="Caris &amp; Co., Inc.">Sandeep Aggarwal MBA</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Agricole Securities (USA), Inc.">Ed Maguire</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Bank of America Merrill Lynch">Kash G. Rangan</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="Stifel, Nicolaus &amp; Co., Inc.">Tim Klasell MBA</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for standing by, and welcome to the Third Quarter 2011 Microsoft Corporation Earnings Conference Call. At this time all participants are placed on listen-only until the question-and-answer session. Today's conference is being recorded. If you have any objections, please disconnect at this time. Now I would like to turn the call over to Bill Koefoed, General Manager of Investor Relations. Bill, please proceed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Bobby, and thank you, everyone, for joining us this afternoon. As usual, with me today are Peter Klein, Chief Financial Officer; Frank Brod, Chief Accounting Officer; and John Seethoff, Deputy General Counsel.</p>
          <p>Today we filed our Form 10-Q. In addition we posted our earnings press release and financial summary slide deck to our Investor Relations website at microsoft.com/investor. The slide deck is intended to follow the flow of our prepared remarks and provides a reconciliation of differences between GAAP and non-GAAP financial measures. As a reminder we will post today's prepared remarks to our website immediately following the call until the complete transcript is available.</p>
          <p>Today's call is being webcast, live and recorded. If you ask a question, it will be included in our live transmission, in the transcript and any future use of the recording. You can replay the call and view the transcript at the Microsoft Investor Relations website until April 28, 2012.</p>
          <p>During this call we will be making forward-looking statements. These statements are based on current expectations and assumptions that are subject to risks and uncertainties. Actual results could materially differ because of factors discussed in today's earnings press release and the comments made during this conference call and in the risk factor section of our Form 10-K, Form 10-Q and other reports and filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission. We do not undertake any duty to update any forward-looking statements.</p>
          <p>With that, I'll turn the call over to Peter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bill. Good afternoon, everyone. This quarter, we again delivered solid financial results reflecting strong business and consumer demand for our products and services. Despite a mixed PC environment the breadth and depth of our portfolio drove another quarter of double-digit revenue and earnings per share growth.</p>
          <p>On the commercial side, we saw strong multi-year licensing commitments by enterprises and robust transactional sales, particularly to small and medium businesses. Let me give more color on these. On the business desktop, customers continued to embrace our offering. Not only is Office 2010 the fastest selling version of Office in our company's history, but businesses are purchasing our entire Productivity Platform including SharePoint, Exchange, Dynamics and Lync. And with the recently released public beta of Office 365, the next generation of our Cloud Productivity Service, we are enabling new scenarios that weren't viable in the past, especially for small and mid-sized businesses.</p>
          <p>Office 365 eases deployment for our customers while lowering their upfront costs and provides significantly better returns on investment. Enterprises are investing in our business infrastructure offerings with a growing preference for our premium products. Windows Server, SQL Server and our management tools are enabling our customers to transform their data centers to be more efficient. Companies are reaping the benefits that Windows 7 brings, including enhanced productivity, efficiency, security, and manageability. Enterprise deployments of Windows 7 have more than doubled over the past six months.</p>
          <p>While business PC shipments showed strength this quarter, consumer PCs declined. Within both segments, emerging markets continue to be an area of strong growth. As demonstrated by Bing's continued market share gains since its launch we have made great strides in relevancy and design and continue to transform search beyond just queries to task completion and decision making.</p>
          <p>While we are pleased with the progress we have made with Bing, there is significant work ahead to improve the monetization of the combined Yahoo! and Bing marketplace. Advertisers are seeing strong ROI but revenue per search is below our expectations. We have our best search technical leadership on this issue and we are partnering closely with Yahoo! to improve monetization as quickly and efficiently as possible.</p>
          <p>Turning to our Entertainment &amp; Devices Division. In November we took the first step in creating a new mobile ecosystem by launching Windows Phone 7. In this quarter we took the next step by entering into a broad strategic alliance with Nokia. Together Nokia and Microsoft will innovate with greater speed and provide enhanced opportunities for users and partners to share in the success of the new ecosystem.</p>
          <p>Consumers are delighted with Kinect as well as our entire Xbox 360 platform and the revolutionary experience it brings to their living room. Kinect continues to lead the way forward in gaming and is opening the door for new scenarios to take advantage of natural user interface.</p>
          <p>In summary, the breadth and depth of our product portfolio combined with prioritization of investments and our continued focus on operating expense management allowed us to deliver another quarter of strong financial results.</p>
          <p>With that, I'm going to hand it back to Bill to provide more details on this quarter's results and then I will come back and provide some thoughts on our outlook for our fourth quarter and the next fiscal year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Peter. Revenue for the quarter was $16.4 billion, 13% growth year-over-year and earnings per share with $0.61, up 36%. Adjusting for tech guarantee programs this was our fourth consecutive quarter of double digit revenue growth and our sixth consecutive quarter of double digit EPS growth. Operating cash flow for the third quarter was a record $8.7 billion or growth of 17%. Operating cash flow year-to-date has surpassed $21 billion, an increase of $2.6 billion.</p>
          <p>Many of the demand trends in the third quarter were similar to the first half of the year. Specifically, Office 2010, Xbox and Xbox Live and Kinect continue to enjoy exceptional consumer momentum. On the commercial side, enterprise demand for our products remains strong. Businesses are deploying Microsoft's platforms and applications including Windows, Windows Server, Office, Dynamics and management tools.</p>
          <p>The business demand is translating into healthy increases in transactional licensing, and strong enterprise agreement renewals. Our unearned revenue balance grew 6% to $13 billion, reflecting continued strength and our customers' multi-year commitment. Our contracted not billed balance is now over $17 billion, growing approximately 20%. Bookings for the company were up 8%.</p>
          <p>Now let me turn to the PC market. There are three trends we are observing. First, business PC growth was 9% this quarter. The business PC refresh cycle continues and is still in the early stages. Second, emerging markets continues to play a larger role in total PC shipment volume and now represents nearly half of all worldwide PC shipments. Finally, the consumer PC market declined to 8% as there are several dynamics at work including a 40% decline in netbooks, broader consumer macroeconomics, increased competition for consumer spending and the strength of Windows 7 consumer PCs in the prior year.</p>
          <p>In total we estimate the PC market declined 1% to 3% in the third quarter. With that PC backdrop I will move onto the results for the Windows and Windows Live division. Last quarter we noted there would be a $100 million headwind for Windows comparables for the third quarter due to the prior year Windows 7 launch. Adjusting for this dynamic, Windows revenue was in line with the PC market as we guided. As usual, you'll find an OEM revenue bridge in our earnings slide deck. To summarize, the PC industry dynamic of continuing strength from emerging markets offset the benefit of a higher business mix and improved attach.</p>
          <p>Since the launch of Windows 7, customer satisfaction and market reception have been terrific and we have more opportunities ahead. While Windows 7 has now sold over 350 million units since launch, an estimated 75% of the PC installed base is still running older operating systems. The number of PCs running Windows 7 in the Enterprise has more than doubled over the past six months and volume licensing has strengthened. As I mentioned earlier, we expect the business PC refresh cycle to continue.</p>
          <p>Looking ahead, we are excited about the partner innovation underway in the PC market with Windows 7. There is innovation occurring in new ultra-portable, all-in-ones and other form factors including slates and convertibles which are starting to hit the market now.</p>
          <p>This quarter we also released Windows Intune, a cloud-based subscription service that will help businesses manage and secure Windows PCs. Windows Intune provides significant new opportunities for Microsoft and our partners to further expand our reach, grow our revenue and delight customers. With Windows Intune we have an opportunity to bring even more customers to the cloud.</p>
          <p>During the quarter we launched the latest version of Internet Explorer. Internet Explorer 9 utilizes the power and performance of the whole PC to provide users with a faster, more immersive web experience. With new features such as hardware accelerated graphics, support for HTML 5 and integrated Windows 7 navigation, websites act more like applications on IE 9. And just a few weeks after releasing IE 9, we released the platform preview of IE 10, which will deliver innovation for the next generation of web experiences powered by Windows.</p>
          <p>Now I'll move to the Microsoft Business Division which, excluding the prior-year Office Tech Guarantee deferral, grew 13%. We continue to see terrific response to the release from both customers &#x2013; from both consumers and businesses.</p>
          <p>Adjusted for the prior-year deferral, consumer revenue grew 26% with increased Office attach to PCs. The business transactional portion grew 28%, also driven by improved attach rates, post launch and higher business PC shipments. The multi-year licensing portion of the business grew 5%.</p>
          <p>Businesses are deploying Office 2010 along with Windows 7 on the corporate desktop. Office 2010 deployment rate is five times faster than the deployment of Office 2007. Importantly, businesses are also attaching the Office Server applications. SharePoint, Exchange and Lync, which all grew double digits this quarter. Lync grew 30% and we are seeing tremendous reception to the product. As we have discussed previously, unified communications is a huge growth opportunity and Lync offers an immediate return on investment to CIOs.</p>
          <p>Last Monday we released the public beta of Office 365 and we continue to see momentum in Business Online Services. The number of customers using our services has quadrupled since last year. Over 50% of our customers are small businesses, but we're also seeing large enterprises, governmental and educational institutions moving to the cloud. This quarter we announced large customer wins including Shell Oil, Tampa General Hospital, Advocate Healthcare and Manpower among others.</p>
          <p>Our Dynamics business grew 10% with both Dynamics CRP and Dynamics CRM increasing account penetration. In the third quarter we launched Dynamics CRM 2011 and we are seeing great traction with 40,000 businesses already in product trial, a significant pipeline to our current 27,000-customer base. We also recently announced that the next release of Dynamics CRP will be cloud enabled. We are delivering world-class business applications on premise and in the cloud that are simple, agile and deliver more value than competitive offerings.</p>
          <p>Now let's turn to Server &amp; Tools which posted 11% revenue growth. Server &amp; Tools had strong performance across the entire product portfolio. Transactional revenue grew faster than the underlying server hardware market which we estimate grew mid-single digits. Multiyear license revenue grew 11% and Enterprise Services revenue grew 12%. In the data center, we continue to increase the penetration and monetization of Windows Server and System Center.</p>
          <p>We saw strong Enterprise agreement renewals of Windows Server this quarter and premium revenue was up double digits. System Center, our management offering, grew double digits for the 10th consecutive quarter. Hyper-V continues to win new business and establish new performance benchmarks on key workloads. This quarter we showcased a large customer win with Target Corporation. Target is running business critical workloads for all 1,700 retail stores using Microsoft virtualization and management technology.</p>
          <p>In the database, SQL Server unit volume and ASPs were up with a shift toward our premium editions. SQL Premium revenue has now grown double digit for four consecutive quarters as customers adopt higher-level capabilities such as business intelligence.</p>
          <p>Our cloud computing platform, Windows Azure continues to have strong momentum and developer interests. This quarter we announced a strategic partnership with Toyota who will be using Windows Azure for its enterprise grade, scalable platform to provide advanced telematics services.</p>
          <p>Next I will move to the Online Services Division, which grew 14%. Online advertising revenue including both search and display grew 17%. Bing's U.S. market share continued to grow ending the quarter at 13.9%, up 190 basis points from the second quarter and almost 600 basis points since launch. We feel great about the pace of our innovation and customer satisfaction with our differentiated approach to search. However, the expected monetization of the combined Yahoo! and Bing search marketplace in the U.S. and Canada is taking longer than planned and revenue per share remains below our expectations. We have delayed our international integration efforts to focus on improvements in the U.S. and Canada.</p>
          <p>Now let me move to the Entertainment &amp; Devices Division where revenue grew an impressive 60%. Xbox has been setting the pace in the gaming industry this fiscal year. With Kinect recognized as the fastest selling consumer electronics product ever, we sold an additional 2.4 million sensors this post-holiday quarter. We also shipped 2.7 million Xbox 360 consoles, a new third quarter record that surpasses the previous high by 1 million units. Xbox Live also continues to increase its contribution to our customer experience and E&amp;D's financial performance. We again saw healthy increases in transactional revenue, which continues to exceed subscription revenue.</p>
          <p>Turning to Windows Phone. Product reviews are good. Customer satisfaction is high, well above 90% and we have shown a clear strategy for enabling a vibrant ecosystem around Windows Phone. This quarter we took the next step and entered into a broad strategic alliance with Nokia. While we have enjoyed strong developer support to date with more than 13,000 applications, we have noted even greater developer interest subsequent to the Nokia alliance announcement.</p>
          <p>Now let me cover the remainder of the income statement. Cost of goods sold increased 41% this quarter due to three primary factors. One, volume driven costs are up due to the success of Xbox 360 consoles and Kinect sensors. Third party content royalties are also up reflecting strong sales on Xbox Live. Two, as I mentioned in the Server and Tools performance, our Enterprise Services business is growing rapidly. Costs in this business are largely volume driven. And three, online service costs are up from increased traffic acquisition costs and increased costs related to the Yahoo! alliance.</p>
          <p>Operating expenses were $6.8 billion, an increase of 4%. Our effective tax rate for the quarter was below our guidance due primarily to the $461 million, one-time benefit related to an agreement with the Internal Revenue Service to settle a portion of their audit of tax years 2004 to 2006.</p>
          <p>In the third quarter, we repurchased $827 million of stock and declared $1.3 billion in dividends. Year-to-date we've returned $13.9 billion of cash to shareholders through buy-backs and dividends, 33% more than the previous year. In summary, it was a very solid quarter, with strong financial results.</p>
          <p>And with that, I'll hand it back to Peter, who is going to discuss our business outlook.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Bill. For the remainder of the call, I'll discuss our expectations for the fourth quarter and some high-level themes as we begin to think about fiscal 2012. From a macro perspective, we expect the next quarter will be similar to the third quarter. Within the PC market we expect growth in emerging markets to outpace developed markets and growth in business PCs to outpace consumer PCs.  As a result, we expect Windows Division revenue to grow roughly in line with the PC market for the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Turning to the Microsoft Business Division, transactional revenue approximately 40% of the division's total, continued to exceed PC shipment growth rate but at a moderating rate as we approach the Office 2010 launch anniversary. Revenue associated with multi-year licensing agreements representing approximately 60% of the division's total, should grow mid to high single digits.</p>
          <p>Turning to Server &amp; Tools, approximately 30% of the division's revenue comes from transactional licensing, 50% from multi-year licensing and 20% from Enterprise Services. Within this division we expect transactional revenue to generally track with the hardware market and multi-year licensing revenue and Enterprise Services revenue to both grow low double digits.</p>
          <p>Within OSD we expect online advertising revenue to perform roughly in line with the overall online advertising market.</p>
          <p>Moving on to the Entertainment &amp; Devices Division, considering the enthusiastic response to the Xbox 360 platform, we now expect this division's revenue to grow roughly 25% for the fourth quarter.</p>
          <p>Looking to cost of goods sold, as was the case this quarter, the biggest factor impacting COGS going forward will be the growth of Entertainment &amp; Devices, Enterprise Services, and integration and traffic acquisition costs associated with our search business.</p>
          <p>Turning to operating expenses, we are reconfirming our guidance of $26.9 billion to $27.3 billion for fiscal year 2011. We expect our effective tax rate to be 22% to 23% for the fourth quarter and we continue to expect capital expenditures for the full fiscal year to be about $2.5 billion. Unearned revenue will follow historical sequential growth patterns.</p>
          <p>Now I'd like to spend a few minutes looking ahead to our next fiscal year. From a macro perspective, we expect the business PC refresh cycle to continue through fiscal 2012. The PC market dynamics I discussed for Q4, emerging markets outpacing developed markets and business outpacing consumer, should also continue through the next fiscal year. While we expect ongoing, healthy demand for Office 2010, we expect more difficult year-over-year comparables for the Microsoft Business Division.</p>
          <p>For Server &amp; Tools, we expect to continue to outpace the server market due to our premium offering and product portfolio. Within our search business, we expect to see revenue per search improvements over the course of the calendar year. Lastly, we expect momentum within our Entertainment &amp; Devices Division to continue.</p>
          <p>Moving on to cost of goods sold as was the case in fiscal 2011, the most important factor to consider will be the shift of revenue mix across hardware, software, Enterprise Services and Online Services. We expect fiscal year 2012 operating expenses to grow 3% to 5% from the midpoint of our fiscal 2011 guidance as we continue to prioritize our spending and manage our expenses. Based on this growth rate, we expect fiscal 2012 operating expenses to be $28.0 billion to $28.6 billion. We expect capital expenditures to be about $2.5 billion for fiscal year 2012.</p>
          <p>In summary, I'm pleased with our healthy financial results for the quarter. As we look forward into the next fiscal year, our robust product portfolio and ongoing focus on cost management will enable us to continue to deliver shareholder value.</p>
          <p>With that, I will turn the call over to Bill and we will take some questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Peter. We want to get questions from as many of you as possible so please stick to just one question and avoid long or multipart questions. Bobby, please go ahead and repeat your instructions</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> Our first question comes from Adam Holt from Morgan Stanley. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Terrific, thank you. My question is on expenses. In the quarter, the gross margin was a little bit lower than I had modeled. I was wondering if you could go through the puts and takes of what hit gross margin this quarter. And then looking into fiscal '12 in general, would you expect revenue to outpace your operating expense growth? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Adam. On gross margin it was really the three things that Bill described. Sort of the biggest thing is the fantastic growth in the Xbox business. That was the single biggest driver of COGS growth in the quarter. Secondly Enterprise Services which is volume driven and they are having nice growth and that shows up in COGS and then finally in Online Services, some costs associated with the Yahoo! alliance. As you know, some of that revenue that we get from that alliance from Yahoo! properties gets TAC'ed out in COGS and some other traffic acquisition costs. Those were the three big drivers of the COGS growth, all volume driven.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With respect to the second part of your question, Adam, as you know, we don't give specific revenue guidance. We give you operating expense guidance and you can model it from there.</p>
          <p>Operator, next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Walter Pritchard from Citigroup. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Can you help us understand just on the COGS following onto Adam's question here. As we look into next year with some of the integration costs around Yahoo! and I guess I'm also wondering around kind of mix within EDD, how much we should expect. Sort of what we've seen over the course of this year be indicative of where gross margins are in the future? Do we think we're on sort of a new kind of trajectory in those individual businesses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it depends what you model in for the volume. So these COGS are volume driven. So depending on how you think about each of those individual businesses, really is the driver of COGS. We tried to give that framework so it's easier to understand that. Certainly on the Online Services business, our key focus is the COGS are volume driven. The most important thing there is to get that revenue per search up because that really has the biggest impact on the gross margin.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Heather Bellini from the ISI Group. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you very much, guys. Peter, I was just wondering if you could talk a little bit about buy-backs. I know that Bill said the return of capital to shareholders was up a third versus last year. But just wondering if you could talk about the level of buy-backs and kind of how we should think about your appetite for buy-backs going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, I think we have a pretty consistent track record over the last several years in terms of distributing cash back to shareholders in terms of dividend and buy-back. And so those numbers that Bill cited were sort of indicative of that. We've had a pretty consistent track record on that and that's been our philosophy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>The next question comes from Brent Thill from UBS. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Peter, can you reconcile on the PC market. Intel and AMD are saying one thing. You're saying its worse and just trying to understand, is it because of piracy or lower ASPs? What's accounting for that and what's your views in terms of the snapback for the PC market in the second half of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There's some unique things going on with Intel's results that you can reconcile back to what we're saying there that make a lot of sense. First, if you sort of reconcile their revenue growth, certainly they have an ASP uplift which is actually the single biggest part of driving growth. There's a few other things in terms of an extra week in the quarter. They've also excluded netbooks from the PC NPU numbers and I think there was some appropriate inventory buildup. So if you look at our numbers, it ties pretty closely from a unit perspective to what they're seeing and, of obviously we're in line with the third party analysts as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Phil Winslow from Credit Suisse. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, guys. I'm just looking for more color on the Microsoft Business Division side. Obviously we're coming on the sort of the tail end theoretically, of the uplift of Office 2010. Obviously you're talking about tougher comps but what is sort of the right long-term growth rate for that business over the next couple years? And also, just in terms of G&amp;A, we saw a big step-up quarter-to-quarter this quarter. Was there anything one time in there like you guys had in the December and March quarters of fiscal '10?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So obviously we're not guiding to specific growth rates for MBD but I would highlight a few things. Obviously, we're incredibly excited about the customer reaction to Office 2010. But even beyond that, you heard us talk about how customers are adopting the whole sort of suite of products not just the Office applications, but SharePoint, Exchange, Dynamics and Lync. And that really provides long-term sustainable growth for the MBD business, even in a year that's not a launch year. So that's, I think, a way to think about what's going on in MBD.</p>
          <p>In addition to that we've got Office 365 over the course of the next coming years. We've got great growth as we talked about quadruple the number of Business Online Services customers we have. With the introduction of Office 365, we sort of take that to the next level. So as you think about the next year or two for the MBD business, those are some of the factors that I think really drive their growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Collin Gillis from BGC Financial. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Can you talk to the new leadership in Servers? What Satya [Satya Nadella] brings to the group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Satya is just a wonderful business leader. He comes from a background of both business applications and cloud services so he's really the ideal guy to take that business to the next level. I personally had an opportunity to work with Satya closely in the past and he's a great leader.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Brad Reback from Oppenheimer. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great. Hi, guys. How are you? So, Peter, there's been a lot of confusion and a lot of talk around the Nokia partnership, what the economics are. Could you maybe help straighten out the record on that and probably more importantly, give us any sense that there's going be an impact to 2012 COGS as it relates to this deal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I will talk about the Nokia. The great thing about the Nokia deal is this is an incredibly perfect opportunity for both of us to build really compelling vibrant third ecosystem if you think about the complementary set of assets that we all bring to it. In terms of the hardware design, hardware manufacturing, the global relationships with operators, certainly with our platform that has great developer momentum and the kinds of services of Xbox Live and Office. Clearly this is a broad strategic alliance. It's a long-term strategic alliance and we're going to be working closely together. And we're each making investments together along those lines and I think the important thing to think about is as we sort of build that out and its success, it's going be a great thing for both companies and for customers and for other partners in the ecosystem.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Robert Breza from RBC Capital Markets, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thanks for taking my question. Just quickly, can you talk about the delay that you're doing internationally and how long you think that will take before you get it up and running? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, we're going to work on North America, the U.S. and Canada and when we feel like we've got that straightened out we'll move on to the other international markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Gregg Moskowitz from Cowen. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Peter, you're tracking to lose a few more cents in the Online division in fiscal '11 versus fiscal '10. Obviously, RPS improvements going forward would help. But you'll also be rolling out the integrated platform to additional markets. So wondering if you could perhaps offer anything else about the EPS prospects for OSD next year relative to fiscal '11?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well certainly we're not going to give a specific outlook more than what we've given but you hit on the key issue which is the revenue per search. We've been clear on the opportunity and the strategy there is to continue to grow share and to increase our revenue per search. So obviously we're laser focused right now on getting that revenue per search up. That has high leverage into margins for the company going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Sandeep Aggarwal from Caris &amp; Company, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter, can you provide us any color in terms of how your new architecture that performs on tablet size progressing in terms of system on a chip? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. I've got nothing else to talk about that other than what we've already said.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ed Maguire from CLSA, your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good afternoon. You discussed healthy activity in multi-year commitments. Could you address how you and your customers are mixing Business Online Services and looking at Office 365, how ultimately that may affect your model in terms of COGS?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, no, it's a great question. Actually one of the interesting things about Business Online Services and the pending Office 365 is &#x2013; it's enabling really great conversations, and actually it's been a driver in the increase of multi-year licensing commitments because people have a lot of questions about the cloud and the transition to the cloud. Having a clear story, having a partner that can help them transition at the pace that they want to has actually been the driver of the conversations we're having with Enterprises. And going forward, the economics of that are, it's an increased revenue and total profit opportunity for us. The subscription services do have a higher COGS and so a lower gross margin in terms of percentage. But over time that's a growth in absolute margin dollars for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Kash Rangan from Merrill Lynch. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you very much. When I look at this quarter, you've already gotten past the four quarters of product cycle helped revenue growth. It looks like this quarter if I make adjustments for Office, you're still looking at high single digit 8%, 10% type growth rate against normal comparisons. Any reasons to think that if IT spending and economy continue to stay the way they are, to think that this growth rate should in fact decelerate as you go into fiscal '12, or if you can argue the other side that it should stay, that this growth rate is sustainable? Both sides of the argument. Appreciate it. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, without giving specific guidance on growth rates, I will say we feel great about how enterprises are investing in IT and in particular, how they are very interested in our product suite. I think we've got a very broad, compelling set of products for Enterprise. If you look at any number of CIO surveys, most of them say a high priority focus area for CIOs is our suite of products. And so directionally, I would say we feel great about the IT market and certainly our position in that and in our product set.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Operator, we're going to take one final question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our final question comes from Tim Klasell from Stifel Nicolaus. Your line is open.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon, everybody. Thanks for taking my question. Maybe you can just give us your thoughts about the timing of a launch of the next generation Xbox console. And if a decision hasn't been made, do you guys internally have a time point of when you think you have to make that decision?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we're really not talking about that. Right now, we're incredibly excited about what's going on with the Xbox 360 console and certainly Kinect, which is relatively new in market. And so we're relatively focused on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Great.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So that will wrap up the Q&amp;A portion of today's earnings call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>A few weeks ago we announced our plans for Microsoft's 2011 Financial Analyst Meeting, which will be on the afternoon of September 14, 2011, in Anaheim, California. FAM will be held in conjunction our developer conference, which will kick off on September 13th at the Anaheim Convention Center. This year's FAM will feature presentations by key executives about the company's strategic direction and will supplement the developer conference presentations which offer people the opportunity to learn directly about our product strategies and roadmap.</p>
          <p>In the meantime, we look toward to seeing many of you at the numerous conferences in which we are participating in this quarter. For those unable to attend any of our events in person, you will always be able to follow our comments at microsoft.com/investor. Please contact us if you need any additional details. Thank you again, and have a great day.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>