<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1253040" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Interim 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-08-27</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8758</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">PN January-Bardill, Group Executive Corporate Affairs and MTN Spokesperson</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">PF Nhleko, Group President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">RD Nisbet, Group Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="3">Johan Snyman</participant>
      <participant id="4">RS Dabengwa</participant>
      <participant id="5">Jonathan Kennedy-Good</participant>
      <participant id="6">Rhys Summerton</participant>
      <participant id="7">T Lowry</participant>
      <participant id="8">Candice Jones</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="corprep">Phuthuma Nhleko, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. [Foreign Language] . My name is Nozipho January-Bardill and I am the Executive of Group Corporate Affairs and my task this morning is really to extend a very warm welcome to all of you in the audience.</p>
          <p>And also to introduce you to our panelists, who don't actually need to be introduced because I think you know them all, Mr. Phuthuma Nhleko, our Group President and CEO; Mr. Sifiso Dabengwa, our Chief Operating Officer; and Mr. Rob Nisbet, our Group Finance Director.</p>
          <p>In the audience also, we welcome all the shareholders who are present, the analysts, members of the media and my colleagues in the Executive Committee of MTN Group who drive the business strategy.</p>
          <p>I would also like to acknowledge the presence of our new MD of MTN South Africa, Ms. Karel Pienaar. We also have Mr. Tim Lowry, who is the Head of Southern and East African regions, who is physically present here, the other two Vice Presidents, Mr. Christian De Faria from the WECA Region in West Africa and Central Africa and Mr. Jamal Ramadan in our MENA Region are both not physically present here, but they will be beamed in through electronic media.</p>
          <p>Finally, we also like to welcome our colleagues from MTN South Africa next door and MTN staff members who work in the Group here. The rest of our staff from the 21 operations are also listening &#x2013; will also be listening in this morning to the presentation from various forms of media platforms. The presentation will last approximately 1.5 hours as usual and our agenda is very, very straight forward.</p>
          <p>Our Group President, Mr. Phuthuma Nhleko will present the Group strategic and operational overview and he will be followed by Mr. Rob Nisbet, who will give us more detailed information on the numbers. After that we will then bring it to a close and Phuthuma will close it to make few &#x2013; final remarks. You will be given an opportunity to ask questions after the first presentation is done, but we would like to ask you to please be clear and we will have roving microphones that will assist you in that regard.</p>
          <p>So at this time I kindly request that we turn-off our cell phones or switch them on to silence and invite Phuthuma to come and do the presentation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning everybody and thank you very much, Nozipho, for the kind introduction. I would also like to welcome our Directors, Mr. Van Biljon, who is Head of our Audit Committee and once again all our colleagues that are connected via webcast in the 21 operations.</p>
          <p>This is of course our result really for the six months through end of June. Let me start off by saying that, put this slide up quite of a number of times in many presentations and the essence of this slide really is to outline how we see our own vision as a Group and more importantly the building blocks to try and achieve that. The whole issue of having a very diverse or diversified earnings base is really important. And at the same time ensure that as the sector changes and there's more convergence we find ourselves well positioned for that.</p>
          <p>The results for the six months really can be put in a context that in my view has most probably got four elements. I think the first one is the fact that these results have been achieved within a fairly difficult trading environment primarily because of the global economic downturn. Secondly we have always said in this Group we have tailwinds and headwinds. We've had a very, very strong headwind this year, certainly in the last six months as a result of a strong rand and the impact that has had on shareholder loans and cash and so on and that in fact is almost R2.8 billion negative. And Rob will talk through that through his report.</p>
          <p>I think the third element which is fairly key in this result, I would say, is the effective tax rate which is now down to 33% and you will recall that when we came out of the tax holiday in Nigeria we had to pay tax for more than 12 months and that tax rate has come down, so that's obviously had a fairly big impact.</p>
          <p>I think the fourth and last key impact on the results is really the fact that virtually all the large operations and medium size operations have performed really well with the exception of a challenging six months in South Africa and Sudan. So, I think within that context, we have managed to increase subscribers to 103 million, subs end of June revenue up 24%, EBITDA up 24.8% to 24.5 billion and PAT up to nine billion, which is a 30% increase and net debt to EBITDA at 0.3 could have been better, but again, I think in the financial section you'll see that we have been impacted by currency.</p>
          <p>And of course we had a very big CapEx year 2009, as we did in 2008, or half year shall I say, and we've &#x2013; have in the ground almost 15.5 billion rand and I must just say that is what's in the ground as opposed to what is committed.</p>
          <p>I think the key economic developments. I have already mentioned that the economic downturn even though this industry or sector has been fairly resilient. We're still being strongly affected by that. It has been varied country-to-country, countries like Nigeria for instance, have been far more resilient in that and other smaller countries have had a much stronger impact.</p>
          <p>The rollout has gone fairly well. You will recall that starting 2008, we took a concerted &#x2013; made a concerted effort and took a decision that we were going to spend a significant amount of CapEx to create the capacity in the ground, because we saw a lot of competitors coming in and we felt that if we've got the capacity, even if tariffs had to drop, we could then service a much larger base. It is my view that that was the right call. I think in countries like Nigeria we've seen the benefit, so have we in countries like Uganda and so on. So even though its in large numbers, I think it's able &#x2013; enabled us to consolidate our position in those regions.</p>
          <p>Operational evolution, this is obviously ongoing. We have acquired a number ISPs in South Africa, of course we did Verizon. We've done similar transactions in C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire and Cyprus and I think all that has done is, put us in a position where we can start servicing the SMEs in the corporate sector far more significantly.</p>
          <p>Of course in other areas of standardization on network which has got a direct impact on how we optimize costs. We have gone a long way to try and ensure that across all 21 operations we have as much standardization as possible on equipment, on billing platforms and so on. And then, I guess there's always corporate activity. We have sold our traffic business into a JV with Belgacom. So those are some of the key developments that have happened in the last six months.</p>
          <p>Subscriber contribution. Nothing has changed radically here. The ideal situation clearly is to have &#x2013; ideally to have a third contribution of subs from West Africa, Southern Africa and Middle East and so on and very similar contributions in EBITDA. But of course, that is difficult to achieve particularly given the very high revenue share arrangements we have in Syria and Iran. So we are still having West and Central Africa as the largest contributor to the Group on subs.</p>
          <p>The ARPU picture is quite satisfactory in my view in the sense that we haven't seen such big declines, say for in countries where we've seen some significant tariff reductions. So if you look at the ARPU decline on a local currency basis most of them are in the single digits. In the case of Ghana and Cameroon, if you look at local currency those look like steep declines than indeed they are because those two countries really had some fairly significant tariff reductions as a result of the competition that faced in those two countries. But on a dollar basis, I think, you will see that some countries are exaggerated because those local currencies have by and large weakened against the U.S. dollar including the naira, cedi and so on.</p>
          <p>I think the issue of the margins in this Group is really important. We are not saying that margins are the answer to everything. But certainly they give us a very good indication of where we are as regards value sustainability in each operation. If you look at the SEA region, the margin has dropped and this is primarily because of South Africa's contribution into that region. And there are a number of reasons for that but the key reason is really we have seen with the slow down of the economy that their spend on postpaid is less, not as stronger as it has been in the past.</p>
          <p>Of course as telecom becomes a lower and lower impact of interconnect where we have got a much better margin with telecom, we are seeing that impact in the margin as well. So the less interconnect from fixed line we are getting the more impact from it is on margin. And then I think lastly there has been quite a lot of prepaid subsidy in South Africa. So all those things amongst others, which I guess will also be dealt within the financial section, would see a lower margin in South Africa and in turn in the region. West Africa, largest contributor clearly Nigeria, again there we've seen the opposite. We've seen margin expansion for 55.4% for that region, Nigeria being the largest contributor to that margin.</p>
          <p>And here there are a number of things that have helped some of them being the price &#x2013; the price of diesel having come down, but I think generally it has been very, very tight cost control in Nigeria that has helped quite a bit, even the restructuring of the whole distribution chain, sales and distribution on to a regional basis has enabled them to be far more cost effective on costs of sales and distribution.</p>
          <p>I think, lastly the Middle East and North Africa region, here we've seen a contraction. We must remember that we've got Syria in here with 50% revenue share, with Iran at 28% revenue share. Notwithstanding that, Iran margin has expanded. Again it's a bigger base in Iran, therefore more on net calling and less costs on &#x2013; of interconnect and again, they've done quite a good job on commissions on the distribution channel that has helped the margin. But the Syria revenue share is quite impactful.</p>
          <p>I am sure of all of that is that on a Group wide basis we have managed to keep the margin, at around 42.8%. Long-term objective has always been to try and maintain or get share 45% EBITDA margin, which is quite a challenge. South East region not to spend a lot of time on this, just to say, Uganda has done exceptionally well given the tight competition. There we've had three or four new competitors Warid, Hits and so on. Even though they have really lost a few market points, we still essentially are the preeminent &#x2013; preeminent operator. We've invested significantly in the network in Uganda, a lot of improvement in the distribution and the coverage and I think that has helped our position there.</p>
          <p>Even though Rwanda is fairly small, again we have got three new competitors there Millicom, Green and so on. Of course we had a monopoly in Rwanda, so we have had to improve distribution and are beginning to rollout limited 3G network to give us some expansion.</p>
          <p>If I can get into South Africa, maybe I would preface my comments on South Africa by saying that this is most probably the most difficult six months in South Africa's history. And it's really been precipitated by number of issues. I think firstly, it's most probably the worst economic recession in many, many years, but we also had some operational challenges that we have had to deal with in South Africa. Mainly issues of being in the market as strongly as what we should have been as competition really picked up particularly on prepaid packages and so on. So there's been a number of things including stock shortages. We've also had some technical challenges in the sense that we have gone through a period where we are wanting to outsource the IT part of MTN South Africa and that had its own difficulties which has affected billing and so on.</p>
          <p>And then there has been a significant network upgrade in the last sort of nine months, which has had some services interrupted and so on. So those elements together with really what has happened in the distribution channel in competitive products and high subsidization I think has made the impact of the &#x2013; well the contribution of South Africa, let's put it that way in terms of the net adds to be extremely low.</p>
          <p>And of course we've also seen very high churn in South Africa primarily on prepaid. There &#x2013; we are seeing quite a lot of dual SIMs where people are now really keeping two SIMs to go to the other two networks for 30 or R50 opportunity and so on. So I think all of that has contributed towards churn.</p>
          <p>We've also seen as I indicated earlier a decline in ARPU at the postpaid base, less spending. But we certainly believe that a lot of this is a phase. It's most probably a severe phase than we have seen in the past that we are working very hard to try and reverse and essentially it will reverse.</p>
          <p>In looking at Verizon and Network Solutions, as you know we acquired that operation fairly recently. And so far its still early days, but we certainly believe that has positioned us well now to be very competitive as far as the MTN business solution is concerned, servicing the corporate, servicing the SMEs with a much wider and comprehensive package of solutions and product. So we're quite busy with that integration and we think it will go fairly well.</p>
          <p>We spent a lot of money. For quite sometime you will recall that we were running at nine maybe 10% sales &#x2013; CapEx to sales for quite a few years. We spent really the last sort of 12 months catching up on that heavy investment in transmission, heavy investment in more 3G sites, so almost R3 billion invested in the last six months. Of course, the other big area of investment is in transmission. We took the view that the ever escalating prices on transmission from another player, was maybe not the way to go. We are not saying we will make a return on this in a year, but certainly we think that in the next three years or so this is really the right strategy. So, significant investment in fibre and we are trying to do as much as possible together with the other operators to try and rationalize on those costs.</p>
          <p>And let me just say, we continue to grow the data component, well the non-SMS component of data, the target being to reach at least 15 to 16% of total revenue in data. But there is still a lot of work to be done there, but as you can see I think since start 2006, we've had a fairly steady climb. It is worth really mentioning that with RICA, which is really the interception bill which was effective I think 1st of August.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>1st of July.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>1st of July, to get us to register SIM cards for prepaid and so on. It has caused a slow down. It will most probably continue to cause a slow down in the next few months until I think the systems and the processes and everybody gets much better at doing that. So, I think in short, fairly tough six months in South Africa and most probably still few more tough months, but we believe that we are on top of some of the key issues to make sure that we maintain our competitive position as strongly as we possibly can.</p>
          <p>West Africa other than the large country, Nigeria, obviously we've got C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire there, very, very competitive with two very strong competitors there. One of the key focus areas is the corporate segment in C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire and, which by-in-large has been the preserve of our competitors the likes of Orange and France Telecom and so on. But I'm glad to say both in C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire and Cameroon we're making fairly significant headway in that area. I think overall in Cameroon we're now at 64%. It's a two player market with us at 64% and Orange having the balance. But of course, as you &#x2013; so, on the ARPU slide we've had quite a significant tariff decrease in Cameroon.</p>
          <p>I think in the case of Nigeria it's been a very in a ways positive story in the last six months. As I mentioned earlier, the heavy investment in capacity and transmission has paid off as we anticipated that it would. There is significantly improved network quality, very low congestion that obviously allows people to be able to call more and therefore expand that particular wallet of those who are capable of calling. We have put out a new pricing regime with Xtracool product range and I think that's been very, very effective.</p>
          <p>The restructured sales and distribution was effectively moving distribution from centralized structure to a very decentralized structure, where in different regions we've got regional dealers that are very, very large and look after their territory and so on. That has also allowed us to reprice some of the commissions and as I said earlier, has helped in sales and distribution and part of the margin expansion that we've seen in Nigeria. Of course, the ARPU in U.S. dollars, as I indicated is lower. The naira has devalued quite significantly, but on a local currency basis, on a naira basis we think that 8% decline is quite acceptable.</p>
          <p>I think infrastructure-wise, very big CapEx here in Nigeria this year and we are hopeful that not because we don't want more business, but we are hopeful that this is &#x2013; hopefully that the peak CapEx year in terms of numbers. I know we've said that quite a few times, but we hope that this will be the case and I think this also reflects &#x2013; that would also reflect the fact that some of our competitors has resolved to scale down in their investment in infrastructure in Nigeria. So that has also helped us in the last six months quite significantly.</p>
          <p>Nevertheless, still over five billion &#x2013; 5.5 billion rent spend in the last six months on 3G sites and 2G sites and of course the transmission. So overall, fairly good position in Nigeria, market share up, quality of service up, tariffs being maintained, EBITDA margin expanded, we will obviously see what happens in the next half. But the big issue is a devaluation of the naira that we've seen.</p>
          <p>Ghana remains a very competitive market. As you are aware Vodafone came into the market recently and Zain as well. So we really believe that the 1% market share drop in Ghana is quite acceptable and of course there is a third operator that &#x2013; sorry, yes, that's right, the third operator that is rumored to come in the next, sort of 12 months. Unfortunately there are two elements that are challenging in Ghana. I think the first one is the cedi has devalued quite significantly. I think in the last 12 months, it's most probably a 30% devaluation, if my numbers are correct.</p>
          <p>And the competition has also resulted in some heavy tariff decrease in Ghana, but we do believe that notwithstanding all of that, the leading market position in Ghana with &#x2013; essentially a 54% market share does enable us to remain very competitive and even most probably look at a number of on net products that we can look at as a strategy to move forward.</p>
          <p>Another country where there is heavy CapEx investment, in Ghana, in the sense that when we acquired the operation from Investec in 2006. You will recall at that stage we only had about three &#x2013; 2.5 million subscribers. So really within that space of three years, we've essentially tripled that base and we had to &#x2013; had CapEx that would accommodate that capacity.</p>
          <p>Again, in Ghana, we're launching 3G, and I know people always ask this question. It is always very difficult to not want to go into 3G. Given a choice in many countries, we would most probably delay that for quite sometime. But it's very difficult to do that when you have your major competitors launching 3G. So in a case like Ghana, Vodafone has kicked off and rolling out a 3G network. It becomes very important for us to be able to match that. Notwithstanding different views we may have as to whether the timing is appropriate or not.</p>
          <p>Third region is Middle East and North Africa. Here, I think I said in my opening remarks that we will have two challenges this year, one was in South Africa and the other one has been Sudan in the last six months. In Sudan, as you recall, it was a number of issues I think firstly, we had to disconnect I think almost 30% of our subscriber base last year because of legislation that is similar to RICA in South Africa, and its been difficult to recover. I'll only say that we're not sure whether our competitors did the same.</p>
          <p>Market share notwithstanding, up 27 &#x2013; up to 27%. We have had the government setup the CDMA player, as you may recall with very, very low tariffs. So it's been quite a challenge notwithstanding being the number two player there to try and compete with the number one player in Sudan who has got quite a high market share. I think where &#x2013; there is some silver lining in the cloud in Sudan is &#x2013; in the southern part of Sudan where we effectively have got, if you like, a separate network, and I think our position there is going to be much stronger going forward. And we're ensuring that we are rolling out as rapidly as we can. We've got 12 new cities on air now and moving forward.</p>
          <p>The other country is Yemen; I think has performed fairly well, again, in a very, very difficult competitive environment. They have managed to in fact increase market share to almost 40% competing essentially against a highly, highly subsidized government operator. But I think the management team in terms of control of our OpEx and innovative products and speed to market has managed to maintain and increase market share.</p>
          <p>Afghanistan I can say the same. You may recall that we got into Afghanistan just after 2006. And in the case of Afghanistan, we are now really the number two player with close to late 30s market share. Of course, the big issue in Afghanistan is the security and things that we're trying to resolve there.</p>
          <p>Okay. I think on Iran, couple of points. Firstly, we have increased our market share to 37% in 36 months. There was a third operator that was going to be issued a license but that seems to have stalled for now. Very similar to Nigeria, we've gone on a regional distribution, which I think has been fairly significant. It's helped again on the EBITDA margin in Iran. And we have had a slight drop in ARPU &#x2013; in dollar ARPU from $9 to $8, not unexpected and so fairly good given that you've got a highly subsidized fixed line operation in Iran which is government run, of course and with really, really low tariffs. So to get a margin that is close to 34%, notwithstanding all of that and a 28% revenue share, we think that the Iran operation has performed fairly well.</p>
          <p>Okay. I think infrastructure wise, 368 cities, we have now covered over 1,400 kilometers of road in Iran. And we still believe that there is still a fairly significant opportunity particularly in the northern parts of Tehran, if we can increase our site acquisition, which is still a concern. You know the sites are owned by municipalities and it's fairly difficult and bureaucratic to get them through because we believe that there is still a lot of latent traffic which we are not getting subscribers, that we're not getting as a result of not having proper coverage in some of those parts of Tehran and the same is true for Tabriz and Esfah&#x101;n as well. WiMAX; we did get a WiMAX license in Iran. We don't have a 3G license, in fact none of the operators do, and we are rolling out that WiMAX as a filler in certain parts of the country.</p>
          <p>I think CapEx wise you will remember that in Iran we have tried a very different model. We're basically instead of rolling out the network ourselves, this effectively has been put out to key venders who really build the network, supply equipment, build the network, and then hand it over to us, and we believe that has &#x2013; had a very positive impact as far as the pace and the quality of roll out in Iran. So essentially really in 36 months it &#x2013; the operation is now effectively as large or a larger operation than South Africa and subscriber wise also now larger than South Africa.</p>
          <p>Syria, there are couple of issues on Syria. I think the first one is, Syria is different, in the sense that it's a built, operate and transfer, which had a escalating revenue share which is now at 50%. So we're notwithstanding this being really &#x2013; relatively decent margin business, the revenue share has got its impact. We've always said that the intention is to try and evolve that BOT into a normal license, and we continue to discuss with government. I believe government has now formally appointed consultants to look into this for the industry. So we are hopeful that if things go the way that we would intend, this would be converted, of course, subject to us reaching agreement with government on those issues.</p>
          <p>You will see that the net adds in Syria were very low. There are two factors that are the cause for that. I think firstly, of course, the economic slowdown is hitting everybody, but secondly, in Syria it is managed competition. We cannot go out competitively with product and so on until our competitor is ready, so we do have to decelerate &#x2013; consciously decelerate in terms of the number of subs that we take in. So I think that is reflected there. We've also had problems with high churn in a sense that the validity of some of the vouchers could only be, I think, 15 days, and that has always had an impact, and again this is by legislation, but we've recently been able to expand that and that has helped.</p>
          <p>Infrastructure wise, we have been rather frugal in deciding how much CapEx to put in Syria, until the BOT matter is resolved; otherwise really we investing in a network that will be handed over to &#x2013; back to government. On the other hand that's &#x2013; again that's artificially slowed down the penetration and growth of the Syrian market. So we're hoping that once we do that &#x2013; once we resolve that, we'll be able to invest in CapEx on a basis that is consistent with what we would perceive to be the addressable market in Syria. So that ZAR380 &#x2013; ZAR386 in CapEx, I think reflects that thinking until we resolve the whole BOT matter. But congestion has been brought down and we've got increased radio capacity in Syria. Like most countries, we have rolled out a 3G network, but not very large. I think it's mainly in the high density areas at the moment where we are and have looked at ISP license.</p>
          <p>So, I think really that is the brief operational review for the six months, and maybe I'll ask Rob to come and do the finance and then we will then go to questions. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Phuthuma. Good morning members of the board or member of the board, okay. Ladies and gentlemen, all my fellow MTNers out there, I'll be bringing you once again the results through the end of June. I think as we all know there are few items to unpack. They are fairly complex to me, but I'm sure you'll find it all quite easy, so we'll try and unpack some of them as we go through it. I think just to start off with again as usual we have got major items that impact on the ForEx side and some times as Phuthuma said that has been sort of tailwind and today it's been a bit of a headwind, but I will take you through that in more detail.</p>
          <p>I think if you look at the growth in revenue and the compound annual growth, you can see a 34% and year-on-year 24. EBITDA, pretty similar numbers. When you look at adjusted HEPS obviously a decrease for the year of some 10%. And I'll just take you through that. I mean I think if you had to restate that and I'll get into the detail and it depends whether or not you want to normalize taxation charge year-on-year, you'll find that if you don't normalize the taxation charge you're most probably looking at an increase on that line of about 26%. If you normalize the taxation charge year-on-year, you're most probably be looking at about 15%. And I will go into that in a bit more detail.</p>
          <p>The key accounting considerations I mean they're fairly small to start with, but if you look at the change in ownerships, you've got the Verizon change. We obviously brought a 100% of Verizon. The consolidation of iTalk where we increased our stake to 100% as well during the first six months and in the smaller disposals that we had Zambia where we disposed off a small amount and then the JV stake in Digital Mobile we sold our the full 50% of the JV stake that we had in that.</p>
          <p>The production; I'll spend a bit of time on this. I think we all know what this arises from, but effectively, historically, you've obviously always found the charges come through into the income statement as the value of the, let's call it, put and the underlying investment has increased within that country; obviously, with the major devaluation that's come through of the naira relative to the rand. So this is rand-naira issue. And if you look at it year-on-year because it's the closing rates, you will find that that's decreased by about 28%. So obviously with that decreasing, I mean you're looking at the put from a rand perspective, you find that obviously the value of that's also decreased. So instead of this year having a debit that's come through the income statement, you actually have a credit that's come through the income statement. So that's one issue just to bear in mind on that side. The effective tax rate dropping to 33% from the 44 and there are slides further on that I'll get into more detail on that side as well.</p>
          <p>Just on the functional currency side. If you look at the rand, dollar and you need to look at the closing rates, again, you will find that the rand depreciated against the &#x2013; appreciated against the dollar by some 17% over the period. I think you're all aware that Mauritius and I've mentioned many times before, although effectively should be, let's just say, more of a dollar-denominated company from a functional currency perspective, it's actually viewed as being rand based. So what that means is all the dollar assets or dollar variance that you have within that company you convert into rand and that differential goes through the income statement.</p>
          <p>So if you look at the rand loans that are effectively advanced from Mauritius to Iran, it's dollar based and its euro based, so effectively change in the exchange rate comes through the income statement and that obviously impacted negatively by 1.7. If you look at the half year to June '08, it was 980 credit that came through and if you look at the full-year last year that was 2.2 billion. So you have a complete reversal year-on-year and sort of half year on half year compared to what we had last time around.</p>
          <p>Who knows where the exchange rate will end up in December this year, but I mean from our perspective the best thing that we could do and we're trying to work on that, it's not that easy, is effectively to rather move those loans into a <mark type="inaudible" /> entity that is dollar based. So to give you an example, if for argument's sake, those loans were moved into, I'm just going to Dubai which is, obviously, a dollar based environment, effectively the variance on those loans will go directly to equity. So you'd no longer see this variance coming through the income statement which I think is a far fairer reporting methodology to come through.</p>
          <p>Bank balances again have come through mainly in Mauritius, impact again of 688 million. Last year the profit came through in other assets and liabilities which are driving inter-company balances largely as well as balances with regards dividends that have been declared in the underlying operations that have not as yet been received. So again you do a mark-to-market of that and that again negatively impacts. Overall negative impact on the interest line of 2.8 billion compared to last year June 878 and for the full year profit of 2.4.</p>
          <p>So now just to turn back to earnings a bit. I mean I think this slide is, lets' say, clearly you're all pretty used to this slide. I mean you can just see that the items which were in the basic headline earnings and adjusted headline earnings is the put option reversal that comes through. You can see this year as I mentioned I mean it's the opposite way around to last year due to the change in the currencies, and if you look at the deferred tax asset, as we mentioned previously, that comes out of Nigeria, but that has been now fully utilized so they won't be appearing from next year onwards.</p>
          <p>So basically you get a decrease of 10% coming through on that line, and now just try and unpack a bit more of it. If you had to reverse the functional currency gains that you made last year and reverse out the functional currency losses you made this year, you can see then what it would mean is your bottom line would increase by some 26%.</p>
          <p>If then you had to do the next normalization which isn't on the slide and you had to effectively assume that the tax rate last year instead of being 44% was down at 33%. Now obviously it also means in your outside shareholder line you've got some adjustments that you have to make as well, because that tax charge would have gone through Nigeria and obviously if you want to, let me say, normalize it to 33 you need to effectively make an adjustment on the outside shareholders. What that would mean is that your, let me just call it, adjusted, okay, earnings that would come through would be some in the region of about 15%.</p>
          <p>The reason why it's not similar to the 24% that you get coming through on the revenue and EBITDA lines is when you go through the income statement in bit more detail you'll see there is a bit of leakage on the depreciation line as well as on the interest line. So that's really the two lines where you get your, let me call it, leakage that you won't get a 24% increase year-on-year if your tax rate had been the same. So I trust all of you understand that and obviously then it flows through into the EPS side as well.</p>
          <p>Just the exchange rate analysis. If you look at the average rates compared to closing, I think a key item to look at here is when you look at, for argument's sake, and I'll just pick up the few key items, the naira to the rand you can see effectively pretty flat. The Ghana cedi to the rand devaluation, the Syrian pound to the rand, okay, strengthened. So overall if you had to run the full income statement, revenue and EBITDA, at the same exchange rates for these six months as for the six months through June '08, effectively those lines would basically remain the same. So what I am saying is the foreign exchange impact that has come through, okay, and I mean I think we're all aware that has changed dramatically, but if you look at it year-on-year income statement very comparable, revenue as well as EBITDA, so those lines are 24%, I just want to state, all these are fair numbers to compare and there's no foreign exchange that comes through that because the offsets of the one depositors are offset by the negatives on the other country, so it's pretty flat.</p>
          <p>The key issue then is obviously when you look at the closing rates and I'll get on to as well when you look at the balance sheet and you look at the impacts on FCTR on the fixed assets as well as goodwill on that but again if you look at the rand/dollar 772 compared to 935 in December that obviously is the one that comes through when we effectively look at the foreign exchange on the currencies in Mauritius. If you then go to the naira and if you look at the strengthening of the rand against the naira there at 28%, that obviously impacts on the put option. So those are two key variables that effectively come through on the interest line.</p>
          <p>Just on the income statement, I think these items we've gone through. I mean if you look at depreciation, you'll find that of that 5.9, Nigeria is about 2.5 billion, in South Africa is about 0.9, you then have Ghana at about 0.3, so the majority if you look at the top four countries they effective make up about 60% of that line. Amortization pretty flat year-on-year. Net finance, as I mentioned, if you had to strip out all the ForEx issues and the put options, you'll find effectively the net finance close to June of about 1,650 compared to the '08 numbers which would have been about 1,200, so as I said that's where you get a bit of leakage coming through as well on that line. And when I mentioned previously the depreciation line, you get a bit of leakage as well if you look at depreciation and amortization. Obviously, those two year-on-year grew at a faster rate than the 24% and that's why you get a bit of leakage on that line as well when you look at your actual earnings.</p>
          <p>Tax, obviously a great windfall coming through there with the tax rate now at 33 instead of the 44%. And minority interest, a large reason for that increase is obviously you don't have the massive, let's call it, tax issue coming through within the Nigerian operation.</p>
          <p>In the revenue analysis side, I'll be pretty quick. Other operations in the SEA region just to mention that with the acquisition of Verizon if you had to take that out, you'd find your year-on-year increase in revenue would have been about 31% in those operations as opposed to 46, so just to give you a comparator there. If you then just drop down to the other operations in the Middle East and Africa, obviously the exchange rates come through on the local currencies. I've just mentioned on the other operations there. I mean, that's quite a mixed bag. If you had to look at Afghanistan, that went up at about 65%, and then if you had to look at Sudan, that effectively only increased by about 12%. So the rest of the other operations in Middle East were above 20, but you do get quite a large variation coming through, specifically with the, let's say, lower performance of Sudan. So, overall, revenue increase of 24% and, as I said, that is a good comparative number, relative to the prior year.</p>
          <p>Just a bit of analysis on the buildup of the various items. I think airtime and subscription fees, pretty self-explanatory. Interconnect, bit lower than the top and a large portion of that actually comes through from South Africa. I mean that, obviously, does decrease the overall revenue, or positive revenue impact coming through on that line.</p>
          <p>Handsets and accessories, when you look at this line relative to the costs, and I will go through EBITDA impacts a bit later on, the revenue has not increased that much, but if you look at the cost side of the handset, it has increased and, obviously, that had quite a large negative impact within the South African operations. And then other revenue, quite a large increase, but you must remember, again, that, obviously, we acquired Verizon and we also effectively acquired iTalk, so those are both now fully consolidated into the results.</p>
          <p>Just on the EBITDA side. South Africa, 2.3, Phuthuma did go through that. And I'll just go through the cost pressures that came through in South Africa a bit later on. Other operations, 22%, reasonable compared to the 30% increase that came through on the top line, or revenue side. Nigeria, 38, local currency 44, obviously with the rand strengthening a bit. Ghana, 11 compared to 0.9, obviously, once again, the rand strengthened against the cedi. And other operations at 30.6%. Just to mention there that Cameroon actually performed extremely well for the year and when we look at the EBITDA margin analysis, Cameroon's EBITDA margin improved by about four percentage points, so that did pull up that &#x2013; the other within West and Central Africa. Middle East, 12.1% EBITDA analysis.</p>
          <p>If you look at that again, as I said, it is a mixed bag. I mean the key issue that comes through there is Sudan. Sudan, effectively, year-on-year, on the EBITDA line, increased by, let's just say, a relatively small amount. And that was due to the margin within Sudan decreasing by about 7%, from about, I think it was 22%, down to about 15%. So, obviously, that was a major negative impact within that environment. Overall, though, 24% increase year-on-year, which I think, in terms of the current economic climate, that's not a bad performance at all.</p>
          <p>Margin analysis. The &#x2013; South Africa, if you just look at that decrease of 7.2% in other operations that largely is due to two areas. Zambia does continue to make losses and, obviously, there is increased churn so overall the contribution does come through. And in Rwanda there was a decrease in EBITDA margin of some 10% relative to the prior year, and that is due to extreme pricing &#x2013; competitive pricing issues where the pricing year-on-year has dropped somewhere in the region of about 40%. So there has been a major effect &#x2013; I apologize, it's not &#x2013; yes, it's 40% that it's dropped, so it's been quite a major impact on that line, and that's what's come through. And, obviously, if you look at the OpEx costs with the increased roll outs in that &#x2013; of the sites in that, your OpEx costs have gone up, and you haven't had the similar increase coming through in the revenue lines.</p>
          <p>And just another issue to note is, when you have fairly tight economic times, although the pricing in Rwanda has declined substantially, from an overall elasticity perspective, in fact, the minutes of use did not increase substantially at all, okay. So it's just to show you, when times are tough, elasticity does decrease within those environments. If you then look at &#x2013; I'll just drop right down, because I think the others are self-explanatory. Syria, 10% negative. We're all aware that the revenue share moved from 40 to 50%, so that's the impact there. And the other operations, again, that was largely due to Sudan, which I mentioned earlier where you had a drop of EBITDA margin of about seven percentage points.</p>
          <p>Margin drivers, South Africa; the handset volumes went up year-on-year. Selling prices reduced, so as you saw before, effectively, from a sales perspective and revenue number, that remained pretty flat. If you look at the cost line, however, it was a negative that came through there of about 500 million. So that was a big negative that came through on the South African cost side. Net interconnect, if you look at that as a percentage of revenue, that dropped by about two percentage points, so &#x2013; and that, obviously, also had a negative impact. And then the other items were mentioned by Phuthuma.</p>
          <p>Nigeria, overall &#x2013; the only one I'll go into a bit of detail. If you look at the fuel price year-on-year, I mean the actual dollar spent on fuel went from about 47 last year to $49 million, notwithstanding the increase in sites of about 24%. So you can see, effectively, that the decrease in fuel price offset the increase in base stations. So, that was a large saving that came through there. And on the EBITDA margin, that had an impact of about one percentage point, within Nigeria.</p>
          <p>On that one, Ghana, the key issue was that 6% revenue impact, with the charge that came through last year, which obviously is felt for the full, let's call it, six months this year, but it wasn't in for six months last year, as well as the lower tariffs that have come through due to the competition. In Iran, I think overall, obviously, great efficiencies coming through with the large increase in the revenue base.</p>
          <p>Finance costs, we won't spend much time on this. I just mentioned before that, if you eliminate all the items, the put as well as the functional currency, you'll find that your bottom net finance costs would be about 1,650 compared to the six months ended June '08 of about 1,200.</p>
          <p>Tax considerations, pretty easy recon. If you look at the impact coming through of the Nigerian tax holiday, you can see, 8.5%, which was a major benefit. And then the Nigerian put option effect, because, obviously, moving from debits to credits, we can see basically again there, coming through with 4%. So when you look, going forward, we've said that you would expect from a group taxation perspective, your tax rate to be in the lower to mid-30s. And it does depend what happens on the put option, because obviously the put option impact is not tax-deductible. So whatever happens on that line, you don't get a deferred tax coming through, so it doesn't affect the tax rate. So that does impact the tax rate, going forward, but we would expect it to be somewhere in the mid to lower 30s going forward.</p>
          <p>Nigeria, and I'll &#x2013; I'm not going to go into the details here, but you can see the tax rate in the lower 30s. And you'd expect it to be pretty similar going forward at that sort of rate.</p>
          <p>Just from a balance sheet perspective. Property, plant and equipment, it's not really that serious to give a break down, but you'll find Nigeria is about 20 billion, South Africa is most probably about 15 billion of that. And then, obviously, it drops substantially, with Ghana being about four billion &#x2013; or three billion in fact, and Iran being about 4.5.</p>
          <p>But if you look at that, and if you look at the net, as it came through, on the CapEx spend of 15 billion, you'll see there is not really a depreciation that came through. It doesn't really match, and that's because of the ForEx issues, and there was about 11 billion movement on the FCTR that came through on that line. So, when you try and do your sums, all I'm saying is that, if you take last year plus additions, minus depreciation, it doesn't quite balance in this because of ForEx of about 11 billion.</p>
          <p>Likewise, if you look at goodwill, the FCTR movement there was about seven billion. So it's just to bear that in mind. On the rest of the balance sheet, I mean I think things are well under control. If you look at the &#x2013; if you had to go into detail and if you look at stock in that, it's decreased quite substantially within the South African environment in that. So I think &#x2013; debtors as well, interconnect &#x2013; some good progress has been made on some of our interconnect debtors in some of the operations. So I think, overall, working capital well under control within the operations.</p>
          <p>Net debt, at the bottom, 15 billion compared to 12.8, slight increase. I'll go through that in a bit more detail when we hit the cash flow. Just on the net debt position, don't think I need to go through this, but effectively, we did open it out a bit, so you can see let's call it the underlying countries, what their debt is, and then the intercompany eliminations taking place at group level. So it just gives you a bit more let's say insight into that, so that Debbie doesn't get phoned quite as often as she often does. So that may also make it a bit easier to understand the ForEx movements and net debt comes through.</p>
          <p>Interest bearing liabilities, good work is actually taking place in raising more funding within our operations. I mean, if you look at Afghanistan, we are closing debt raising within Afghanistan, which has been quite tough to close, but that is being closed at the moment. C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire, good closing there as well. I mean, if you look at the rates that we're getting within those environments, they're actually, specifically C&#xF4;te d'Ivoire pretty favorable, because the financial institutions in those areas are actually looking for good credit, and you can almost borrow more cheaply there than we can borrow at group level, not quite, but it's pretty close.</p>
          <p>That's just to show you how in some of these emerging markets, they do look for good assets and we can actually borrow pretty cheaply, so it's not bad. The payment profile. I think, I should just mention that if you look at 2010, obviously it is a bit of a blip on our payment profile, so there does need to be a bit of refinancing. Obviously with the current discussions ongoing at the moment, we didn't deem it appropriate to actually refinance right now, but obviously that does need to be addressed and we are addressing it at the moment.</p>
          <p>Cash flow statement, if you look at the generation of 16.8 billion, and the investing activities of let's say of 16.9, you can see really pretty flat year-on-year. Compared to last year what we generated, so major pick up coming through on the PPE side, and just under cash out to in flows on the next line is at 2.7. It's obviously 1.4 billion of dividends that were paid to external shareholders that comes through that line. So if you look at the overall let's say group for the six months, really utilized about 1.4 billion of cash, which is let's say almost flat from a overall perspective for the six months, and if you look at the net debt to EBITDA, still pretty constant at about the 31 &#x2013; or 0.31, which we are very comfortable with.</p>
          <p>Just on the capital expenditure slide, and we'll open this up slightly, you know the number that you would have seen previously that was authorized for the year was 37, obviously as time goes by during the year, we do get additional capital requests that comes through from the operations to start to rollout for the first quarter next year, and that's why you can see the let's call it overall increase from 37 to 42 has taken place. So you can see the countries where that's increased. If you then look down at the bottom left, you'll see that effectively the expected spend is 35 billion. Now that's obviously 35 compared to the 42. And if you look at where those savings or just call it rollovers will come through, on the Nigerian side, we expect to rollover about three billion, in South Africa about 1.5 billion, and in Ghana about 1.5 billion. So that makes up six of the seven billion rollover and those are the key issues.</p>
          <p>And that brings me to the end of the presentation. I just think before I disappear, I think most of you know this will be my last presentation at the MTN results. If I look back to when I joined over 14 years ago, where MTN had some 45,000 or so subscribers to where it is today. I have to tell you, it's been a serious privilege to work for a company that's been so dynamic and in an industry that's has been so great. And obviously, during that period, I've interacted with a lot of you, whether it's on the investor side, the analyst side, the banking side, and I think you've always asked challenging questions and I thoroughly enjoyed that as well.</p>
          <p>I think more importantly, that's not &#x2013; probably not quite right, but pretty importantly, if you look around MTN and if you look at all the people, I have to say that to work with all of them, it's a great crew, great lot of people, and once again I must say I'm hell of a sad to see them go. Lastly, but not leastly at all, as you are all aware, I'll be handing over to Nazir Patel, and I seriously wish all the rest of the MTNs out there, and it is a great family, all the best for the future. And thank you very much for putting with me for 14.5 years. Thanks a lot. Bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. Well, I think looking forward, not to take too much time, really nothing much has changed. We only say that we'll continue to look at opportunities to expand and maintain the growth that we have. The whole issue of rollout and spending the CapEx, trying to be more efficient in that as we go forward, that is obviously quite a key issue that we will continue to look at. And I think, I have mentioned that one of the key things we are going to do is to try and see how we can rationalize more infrastructure with the other operators.</p>
          <p>The whole convergence issue, I think, it is starting to take off considerably, even though we've only just bought these ISPs in the recent 12 months, we do believe that the integration is working, and it will enable us to really focus quite heavily on the corporate sector in quite a lot of these countries, which doesn't really have the kind of service that they require, because the fixed line operators and the incumbents are relatively poor. And regulatory wise, I think that is clearly the biggest issue. Touch wood we haven't really had any major regulatory challenge in the last sort of 14 years or so, save for maybe Benin, but it is always an issue. I think, regulators are becoming more and more fierce in looking at how they're going to deal with operators and actually control them. So, this is quite a critical area that we are starting to spend more time than we normally have spent in the past.</p>
          <p>I think lastly, the BEE transaction, we did mention that in December. We said, we'd try and complete that as soon as conditions were conducive. I think to some extent the discussions we're having with Bharti has somewhat delayed that, but suffice to say that it's something that we are completely committed to doing. So I think, looking forward that is really what we will be focusing on in the next 12 months.</p>
          <p>I think, coming to the Bharti transaction, and I know that there's been quite a lot of write-up on this, maybe a few points. I think, the first point really is to say, we are clearly under cautionary on this and we can't really get into the detailed as far as the detailed numbers and answer a lot of questions on it. But we thought that it is important to maybe highlight I think a few points until we get to a stage where we can actually talk very publicly about the transaction. I think, the first one is we did publish the cautionary on the 25th of May, and I think, it was a bit of challenge as to whether we should or not. But we took the view that to start having discussions on the transaction of that size without really alerting the broader public and investors that we're having that discussion would be &#x2013; would make it difficult. Not impossible, but it would make it very, very, very difficult. So I think that was the reason for publishing that.</p>
          <p>As we have very clearly stated on two occasions now this is an evolving situation, and whatever was published on the 25th of May may very well change, or it may stay the same. But suffice to say that we have given that caution that, that is the discussion and it's ongoing.</p>
          <p>I think coming back to the rationale in some of the issues that have been raised in the public domain, maybe a few points. I think, firstly, the MTN Group Board took a very conscious decision almost two years ago that one of the key strategic objectives that we have to achieve, and I think at every presentation we've spoken about that is to have a wider and broader base of its earnings. So in having a diversification of its earnings, really I think we're talking a number of elements. We're talking earnings themselves. We're looking at regulatory issues. We're looking at currency issues and so on. So I think that's really one of the key features.</p>
          <p>The second key issue of course is growth. I think, we took a view that we didn't see the company as cash cow and wanted to continue to find growth for its markets. Of course, increasingly the larger MTN became, the more difficult it is or it has become to find greenfield opportunities, low penetration markets that can make a very big difference to MTN's growth and profile going forward. Notwithstanding that we're quite happy with the current footprint that we have, and some of the growth that we are seeing.</p>
          <p>I think, thirdly, we do believe that this is very much a economies of scale impacted business and that going forward as tariffs come down, and as you penetrate into the smaller and smaller segments of the market or less affording segments of the market, you really have to have a lower and lower cost base. And that is, I think, a third element that we are looking at as we have these discussions. By the way, I think it's worth pointing out that even though I think a lot of the coverage has been Bharti MTN, there is effectively particularly on the procurement side a third integral player in this which is Singtel, which is a very large shareholder in Bharti, and so they're an element of this transaction as we go forward.</p>
          <p>Of course, having said all of that, whatever is finally agreed to the extent that we decide to move forward, whatever the strategic objectives are that we're trying to fulfill has to be balanced with the value that we believe is there, long-term. It has to be balanced with governance issues and so on. So that is really, I think, where we are. We have given an indication that we've given ourselves up until the end of September to try and see whether we can achieve something that would be palatable to ourselves, to shareholders, and make strategic sense I think going forward.</p>
          <p>So I think that's really where we are on the Bharti issue. Maybe one can just close on it by saying that certainly we'll never claim to have monopoly on wisdom. I think, we've looked at this based on what we see on the ground and what we see in the next three, five years. And sometimes, it doesn't always tally with the spreadsheets. I think, we are the first people to accept that but I think we're exploring it quite seriously to try and see if we can reach an amicable situation. To the extent that we do, if we get to that stage clearly we would then have the appropriate and normal roadshows as we have had for interims in the past, and discuss this as well. So that's really where we are on what has been published on the Bharti transaction.</p>
          <p>If I can just close on the subscribers before we take &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; we take questions. We gave a &#x2013; sorry &#x2013; we gave a guidance of the total subscribers that we expected to close on at the end of December '09. And it's been a bit of a challenge, primarily because the South Africa had the challenges that it just had, as I indicated earlier. But we do believe that we should achieve 22.6 million subscribers as we had given guidance on, albeit in a somewhat different figuration.</p>
          <p>We do think that some of the issue that are facing South Africa, we need to bed those down properly before we push very hard on subs, notwithstanding that we think we should at least put on another 0.5 million subs by end of the year. In Nigeria, we've seen a pretty strong run, so we think we could reach there 7.4 million. And effectively the rest stays the same; well, when I say the rest, I mean, Ghana, Iran and Syria and then the smaller countries would be maybe slightly less. So we'd like to maintain the 22.6, even though I do think Iran is also going to be quite tough to get to the six million.</p>
          <p>All right. Thank you much. And I think, what we'd like to do now is go on to questions. There is again, I think, the annexure is at the back of your presentation, so a lot of the detailed country information that is there is in the pack.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Phuthuma; Johan Snyman, JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>One of your competitor is loosing about 2.5 million subs in the first half. I mean, how much of that did you gain, and what would be a normal trend going forward in terms of net adds for MTN in Nigeria?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Sifiso, you want to address on it. Can you just repeat it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Having one of your competitors loosing about 2.5 million subscribers in Nigeria, how much did you gain by that? And secondly, going forward, I mean, what would be a more normalized run rate for MTN?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, if you look at the market share growth, we have indicated that the fact that other operators have not been that strong, that has helped us get our market share growth from the 44 to about 48%. So, we think that will probably carry on for another two, three months. And we do expect that the other operators will come quite aggressively into the market. I know that one of them has outsourced its network rollout, which was a problem, to one of the vendors. In terms of the normal run rate in the region of about 500,000 on a monthly basis was what we had expected.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Jonathan Kennedy-Good here from Investec. Just two quick questions also on Nigeria, some of your competitors have spoken about the possibility of interconnect rates coming down in the short-term in Nigeria, is that correct? And if so, what do you expect could be the development there? And could you give us a sense of what you're off-net versus on-net traffic is like, and what the change has been in that with the market share gains there? And then finally on CapEx, there were some comments about peak CapEx being reached in '09, given what we've seen in South Africa, do you think it's just that I think I'm missing something in terms of, it looks like to sustain that growth you're going to have to still increase absolute CapEx levels, particularly in Nigeria, is that correct?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You want to answer it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the interconnect, I mean, the interconnect in Nigeria is reasonably low. And I mean, there have always been discussions ongoing as to what should happen to it. I guess, the key driver has been the fixed line operators that have been trying to get an interconnect regime that is symmetrical. And there is nothing at this moment in time that indicates that the regulator is putting much effort in terms of changing that.</p>
          <p>In terms of the on and off-net traffic, it's now just about 80%, we're just over 80% on-net. And then in terms of CapEx, I guess, we will see how the year progresses. It doesn't seem like that we will be spending the same levels as we have spent this year going forward. And I guess, with the other competitors becoming more aggressive, which is what we expect, we don't think that the rate of growth in terms of traffic that we have seen this year, we will continue seeing into the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Rhys Summerton from Citigroup. Just two or three questions. If I look at your first quarter to the second quarter numbers, it looks like you've actually seen an acceleration in the decline in South Africa, one on post-paid ARPU and also on your pre-paid subscribers, and I think in the presentation you mentioned that you're actually seeing a nine months sort of CapEx rollout in upgrade, and I'm just wondering why we haven't seen any benefit of that coming through yet, so if you can maybe elaborate why things have deteriorated in the last quarter? And then also...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So you mean benefit of the CapEx over the period?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Yes. As you come to the end of that &#x2013; that rollout. And then also you seem to be quite quiet on site sharing and network sharing in some of the markets like Nigeria and Ghana, so if we can just have update on that please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, on South Africa, let me maybe make one or two comments, then I'd like Tim to add, and then on Nigeria, if Sifiso, you can take that on site sharing. I mean, on South Africa that CapEx is not all going into necessarily new capacity. I mean, there's quite a bit that's going into transmission, there's quite a bit that's going into upgrading. So, I'm not too sure what the split is, but essentially not all of it has gone into new capacity creation, firstly.</p>
          <p>I think, secondly, as we said in the presentation, we have not been as strong as what we could have been in those two quarters, particularly on the prepaid side, on some of the promotions that were undertaken by our competitors, and if we're a bit stronger, I mean, depending on whether we thought that those promotions were sensible in case you'd utilize more of that CapEx or capacity that's created. But Tim, you want to add to it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We replaced quite a lot of legacy 2G network, and have been upgrading the core. I think, we're about 75% of the way through that now. I mean, some of that equipment has been in since the beginning of the operation, so that's not surprising that it has to be replaced. We also had to put a lot more headroom in, in terms of switch space, across the country, because a lot of our switching was still being done out of sites such as Randburg in Johannesburg.</p>
          <p>So we've been decentralizing our network, and that required us to spend quite a lot of CapEx on land and buildings, which is a one-off spend and won't have to spent again. As far as the market getting more competitive in Q2, there were a lot of offers out there by our competitors, which in our view were just moving dual sims from one network to another, rather than having stable customers. And we focused on stable customers, and rewarding customers that are really the generating part of our base, rather than our transient base.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Sifiso, do you want to just talk about the infrastructure sharing in Nigeria and so on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the infrastructure sharing, we have not been as successful or we have not done as much as we would have liked. I guess, the key problem has been one of pricing of sites, where we're not necessarily sharing on a one-to-one basis. We have, in most markets, initiated processes whereby on a one-to-one sharing, we've been able to move quite a bit on that. But in terms of being able to lease sites, we've had issues in terms of pricing. And then also in terms of joint building of sites, we really haven't been able to conclude, but we are having ongoing discussions with the likes of Zain and Etisalat.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Leslie, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Two questions. There was a legal opinion, a couple of weeks ago that if you can't settle the Minister does have the right to force down the interconnection fees. If he actually gets his nerve up and does that, what will your reaction be? And overall, if they succeed, what would the financial effect be for MTN?</p>
          <p>And second question, if the Bharti talks don't go anywhere, would you be interested in Zain's African operations?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think, on the first question, I mean, as I said, it's a legal opinion, and a legal opinion is exactly that it's a legal opinion. Having said that, we would hope that there is basically a open and constructive discussion with the regulator, as we've had in the last 14, 15 years, because we've always said that, in real terms, the tariff in South Africa has basically gone down, because all increases have essentially been below inflation. So if that come to pass, well -- again, I hope we can hope &#x2013; have a open and constructive discussion. And I'm sure that, that really is the way that the regulator would see it as well, because it does impact on quite a number of issues, including the interconnect agreement that was voluntarily entered into between the three operators. So, for us, it's dialogue rather than getting legal on the matter. It's a bit hypothetical. Until they do something like that, it's really difficult, but I'm just outlining what our preference is.</p>
          <p>I think, on your second question, look I think we said we're involved in these discussions. If they don't come to fruition, it's &#x2013; we'll sit down and have a look. I think, in pursuing the vision of the group, we said that we will look at whatever makes commercial sense, and if Zain has to decide to sell operations, we're &#x2013; we don't have regulatory problems or overlaps and so on. I guess, if that opportunity presented itself, at the time there's absolutely no reason why we wouldn't explore it, but again it's very hypothetical.</p>
          <p>Okay. Any more questions? Shall we maybe take two more, and then we can close?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Candice Jones from IT Web. Please could you just go into a little bit more detail on what has happened with the Musica deal?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think, on the Musica deal, there was an agreement, with certain preconditions that were really not met, and at that stage, it was not able to &#x2013; we were not able to conclude the deal. It had to do with landlords and leases and that kind of thing, and we just decided that it wouldn't be of the scale that we would have wished for. So I think, it was a very amicable, really collapsing of the deal. Isn't that right? Yes. The last question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. I think, if there are no more questions, I would like to end by thanking Rob Nesbit, okay, for really being a great member of the team for many, many years. And I believe, I really talk on behalf of all my colleagues sitting here in front, and those that are not here, it's been great. I think, here at MTN, because we spend so much time here, so much time traveling, we actually spend more time with our colleagues than with our families, I suspect.</p>
          <p>So, it's really been a very great team, certainly for me in the last eight years. And I would really once again like to say thank you to Rob. If you can give him a round of applause. And I'd like to take the opportunity to introduce Nazir, Nazir Patel. I'm sure some of you have already met him. Nazir has been with MTN for four years &#x2013; five years? Yes. Thank you.</p>
          <p>And he will be taking over from Rob, and hopefully he will enjoy another 15 years, and as this place does suck you in.</p>
          <p>Thank you very much. And thanks for your time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>