<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1296686" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-03-11</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8758</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">PN January-Bardill, Group Executive: Corporate Affairs, MTN Group Spokesperson</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">PF Nhleko, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Nazir Patel, Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Jonathan Kennedy-Good</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">RS Dabengwa</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">John Slettevold</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Irnest Kaplan</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep">Sifiso Dabengwa</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Nicky Smith</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, salaam, bonjour, ladies and gentlemen. With less than 100 days to go before the FIFA 2010 World Cup, we felt it appropriate to start the proceedings by showing you our newly launched United &#x2013; Africa United TV commercial. So we hope you'll enjoy it. We'd like to show it again towards the end.</p>
          <p>We added the first of a trilogy of FIFA ads that will carry the United Africa theme to symbolize the collective support of the Cup to remain on the continent. Also for us at MTN, we are particularly pleased because five of the six African qualifying teams come from the countries of our footprint. And the music that you heard is called "Everywhere You Go" in the ad and is the official anthem of MTN for the World Cup.</p>
          <p>So good morning, again. My name is Nozipho January-Bardill and I'm the Executive for Corporate Affairs for MTN Group. I'd like on behalf of the board and members of the executive committee to extend a very warm welcome to all of you at the presentation of the Group's financial results for the year ending the 31st of December, 2009.</p>
          <p>But besides welcome you &#x2013; welcoming you, I'd also like to say my task this morning is to introduce our panelists, Mr. Phuthuma Nhleko, who is our President and CEO and needs no introduction for most of you; our Chief Operating Officer, Mr. Sifiso Dabengwa at the other end; and our new Group Finance Director, Mr. Nazir Patel.</p>
          <p>Other members of the audience include shareholders and analysts and members of the media, and also my colleagues in the Exco team sitting at the front here. Our vice president, one of them is here Mr. Lowry from the SEA region; Mr. Christian De Faria from West and Central Africa and Jamal Ramadan from MENA region are both watching the proceedings from wherever they are in the world.</p>
          <p>But last but not least, we also have in the audience managers and staff of the MTN Group from the headquarters here at Innovation Centre and also MTN South Africa, our local operation. The rest of the staff in the 20 other operations whose efforts have everything to do with MTN's success will be watching the presentation via various electronic media platforms; a very warm welcome to all of you MTNers across our footprint.</p>
          <p>The presentation will last approximately one-and-a-half hours and the agenda is very straightforward, normally as most results are. Our Group President, Mr. Phuthuma will begin with an overview of the Group's strategic and operational activities in the last year. Nazir Patel, our Chief Financial Director will deliver the financials and give you information on the numbers; and Phuthuma will then bring the presentation to a close with some concluding remarks.</p>
          <p>After the presentations, you will then be given a chance to ask questions and there will be roving microphones that some colleagues will manage. Our intention is to finish the process at 11 o'clock. Okay, we've started a little later than half past nine, which is when we wanted to, but we'd really like to start to finish soon after 11 o'clock, because we have a string of media houses who wish to interrogate Phuthuma on the results and other related issues.</p>
          <p>As usual, we'd like you to stay for a short lunch after the formal proceedings are completed, a lunch will be served in the social area next door. So as we're about to start, may I kindly request that you turn off you cell phones or have them on silent.</p>
          <p>And Phuthuma, if you would love to come up and do the presentation. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everybody, salaam, bonjour for all of our staff in many parts of the world. I would begin by first of all echoing Nozipho's welcome, and welcome to the MTN Directors as well, who have been extremely supportive for us in what I would characterize as nothing but an extremely challenging year. 2009, I think, was one of those years where a lot of things were aligned to make life difficult for us. But, nevertheless, we certainly hope that in giving the results for 2009 we will be able to demonstrate that notwithstanding all those challenges, we still were able to perform satisfactorily in a very difficult environment.</p>
          <p>I think, first and foremost, the vision of the Group remains unchanged and this has really been the case for the last eight years or 10 years. And we still believe that even though the landscape is changing fairly rapidly, positioning ourself as a preeminent emerging markets mobile operator does provide an opportunity for further value creation for the Group. And of course in outlining that vision it's really supported by that structure at the bottom there where we feel that all those components are key to actually putting substance to the vision and the strategic objectives that we intend to follow.</p>
          <p>As indicated, it was a very difficult year. However, we managed to grow the subs fairly significantly. We maintained market share in virtually all the markets, in fact in quite a number of markets we've increased market share. And that is by and large because of the fairly significant investment in capacity when our competitors know we're not investing as much, and that really gave us an ability to take on quite a lot of subs whilst maintaining fairly strong service levels and quality of service.</p>
          <p>The brand has gone from strength to strength, and I think that has also helped ensure that the visibility of MTN as a product of choice remains fairly strong.</p>
          <p>We have, of course, as I will explain a bit later, increased our focus on data through the acquisition of Verizon and a number of ISPs, and that I think has added a significant area in terms of revenue growth going forward. But of course we've seen enormous competition. I mean, in a country like Ghana today, we've got five operators soon to be six. We've had significant intervention from the regulators, primarily on interconnect, not only in South Africa but outside South Africa as well, as well as the need to register SIMs. We've had that, again, in virtually all the markets and that has put in further pressure in terms of operations.</p>
          <p>And then lastly, of course we all know that this has been a very difficult 18 months as far as the world economy goes, and the slowing economies have had a fairly telling impact on our results. Most probably the key feature of these results, and I would say the most overarching element, certainly from a MTN rand reporting company, is the very strong rand and the impact of forex on virtually all the key lines in our income statement. And Nazir, when he does his presentation, will expand on that. But suffice to say, with almost 80% of our earnings coming outside South Africa today, we're highly impacted by the currency, which has strengthened, I'd say almost 20% or more in the last year.</p>
          <p>Looking at the results themselves, sub is up 28% to 116 million subscribers, revenue almost 10% up, EBITDA 7% up to 46 billion. Again, if you had to factor forex implications, revenue and EBITDA would most probably be at least 10 and 12% up respectively. So, and again, I think when we get to the finance section, Nazir will elaborate on that.</p>
          <p>So we've had a muted expansion on those two lines. But again, the affect that we have spoken about in the last few years, the effective tax rate, which is essentially Nigerian driven, even though reduced, has had an impact in the functional currency losses as well that will be dealt with in the financial section.</p>
          <p>What I am happy to say is that we've had a relatively conservative dividend policy, just depends who you talk to, others feel too conservative. We've taken a decision that given the anticipated reduction in CapEx going forward in the next few years, we would most probably see 2009 as a peak CapEx year and therefore expect to generate more significant cash. We felt comfortable that we can now be a bit more relaxed in terms of the dividend policy. And not overly relaxed, but less tightened, loosen the noose a little bit. And that has enabled us to declare the dividend of 192 cents per share, which is close to a cover of four. I mean, the reality is going forward, depending on what happens in the Group on a corporate finance or M&amp;A front, we may revise that. But for now, I think this is real good direction.</p>
          <p>CapEx at 31 billion, as I indicated, we see that as hopefully the peak year in 2009. I must say that the currency obviously also has an impact on that number, it would have been slightly higher by about $3 billion if the rand had stayed the same as it had, let's say, at December '08.</p>
          <p>Group initiatives: I think there is nothing really new here. We've said this over and over, over the years, to say that at all times we continue to find ways of improving the efficiency of the Group. One of the key themes is standardization, because we strongly believe that if we are going to achieve economies of scale in the Group, we certainly need to find a way to ensure that virtually all the operations operate on the same system, standards, methodology as much as it is possible.</p>
          <p>Rationalization of network suppliers: I think that's fairly standard. We do think that we must get competition, but at the same time not have such proliferation that, again, you miss the economies of scale. So quite a lot of that's been done in that area to try and improve operations. We're also embarking on activity cost accounting to ensure that, again, we can tighten cost control in the Group much better.</p>
          <p>I did mention data: most probably the biggest feature was the acquisition of the Verizon Business in South Africa and elsewhere. South Africa of course was the largest component, but it certainly gives us a base to become far more assertive, shall I say, in the provision of fixed line capability and bandwidth, particularly in countries that don't have very, very strong fixed line operators and therefore the SMEs need the support. It also gives us an opportunity on Enterprise Solutions to look more towards managed services as a Group and therefore increase our scope of offer.</p>
          <p>On the 3G side, both in South Africa and Nigeria, we've rolled out quite significantly and have also rolled out some coverage on WiMax. Again, to try and give us a very comprehensive suite of coverage, connectivity, and therefore hopefully an increase in revenue going forward.</p>
          <p>You may be aware that we have been fairly active in the submarine cable area, not as a speculator, but primarily to provide capacity for our own operations, and hopefully in the process reduce the cost. So, to date, almost $85 million, and we've most probably got commitments close to $200 million over the next few years. But as you can see, we're participating in virtually all the key cable initiatives that are underway.</p>
          <p>People are of course the key asset of the Group, and there are many initiatives that we've undertaken to ensure that we remain very, very competitive. I do believe that that is the single most unique aspect of our competitive basket, if I may say so, compared to a lot of operators is that we've got people that are very dedicated to the Group and very passionate about it and with the MTN way, if I can put it that way, it gives us a competitive edge.</p>
          <p>And in the light of that, we've set up MTN Academy, which is really, has got three branches in South Africa, in Ghana, West Africa, and then in Syria for the Middle East, to try and show that we do our own training and have a proper, sufficient plan and capacity at all levels of the company.</p>
          <p>One key area of potential new revenue is of course Mobile Money. We started off in South Africa and we had a few challenges, but I think there have been some good lessons learnt and we've gone ahead to roll this out in a number of countries, started off with Ghana with almost 700,000 subscribers to date. Whilst this is not going to be a massive, massive revenue generator, we do believe that in the next couple of years, if we can average five to 10% of revenue coming from some things like just Mobile Transfer, we would have achieved something. It's quite a target, quite a task, but we certainly want to embark on that. We also believe it will also help on churn and stickiness of customers.</p>
          <p>Subscriber per region, again, this is not a slide that is new to you. We set out a few years ago to diversify our base, not in terms of only earnings, but subscriber base as well. And we see that the ideal split would have been Southern Africa a third, West Africa a third, and the Middle East a third. We're not there yet, but certainly you can see that there has been clear evolution of that subscriber base over time.</p>
          <p>Okay, EBITDA margin, Group EBITDA margin has come down, primarily because of Syria, where, as you may be aware, that the arrangement in Syria is one of revenue share and we've hit the maximum now of 50% of revenue, which we share with government, and of course, that's going to impact on margin.</p>
          <p>The other influencing factor in the Group EBITDA margin was South Africa. South Africa had quite a challenging in 2009 and we can get into the detail of it later. But putting those two together effectively dropped our Group margin by a percentage point. EBITDA and revenue, I think you can see the SEA region, which is primarily South Africa, is becoming a smaller part of the Group as increasingly West Africa and the Middle East become larger and larger contributors to the Group.</p>
          <p>South African operations, as I said, it was a very, very tough year. It was characterized by challenges in a number of areas. Firstly, on the postpaid, we have seen a marginal increase in postpaid numbers but, by and large, that increase came from not the high end, but the lower end of postpaid where people have gone for the hybrid products like MyChoice and so on, allowing the customers to move between being on contract and element of prepaid.</p>
          <p>Prepaid growth, I think, that's really the major disappointment in 2009, particularly in H1, and I must say in H2 it began to pick up. There were a number of factors that influenced that. I think firstly, I think we're just slow off the mark in the first half. Second half, once RICA began, as you know, all operators had to get the prepaid subscribers registered and it took quite some time to get the systems right and get into a rhythm, that also slowed things down a little bit. But suffice it to say that we've seen an uptick in the second half and we have had a net negative add of one million subscribers at the end of December.</p>
          <p>Of course, as I mentioned earlier, seeing the margin decrease in South Africa, there are a number of issues. But by and large, interconnects as we have fixed to mobile substitution, obviously that interconnect revenue coming from the fixed line operator does reduce. And needless to say that in very tough economic times the postpaid people spend less, and therefore we've seen some revenue decline in that as well. So all those elements and the other aspects that Nazir will talk to you that put pressure on that, as I say, EBITDA margin.</p>
          <p>The declining ARPU, as I indicated on postpaid, is really as a result of people spending less, and of course, the growth in postpaid being at the lower end and mainly the hybrid products and lower usage. I think you may find it is that prepaid revenue &#x2013; sorry, ARPU has actually gone up, and that's really because the prepaid subscribers that dropped off, that churned out, were really, really very low revenue generating subscribers and therefore the base that remained collectively was a much higher revenue generating base. So therefore, that's why the ARPU would be an up tick.</p>
          <p>Of course, one of the big stories of South Africa last year was the interconnect discussion between us and Icasa. I'm glad to say that we have made a submission and Icasa has agreed to our advice that they will come back by the end of June.</p>
          <p>Infrastructure-wise, we went through a very difficult patch as far as quality of service. As you may recall, MTN South Africa for quite some time was at CapEx to revenue of about 9% for quite a few years. And then two, three years back, we decided to embark on a significant CapEx reinvestment catch up; as you can see in '09, we spent almost R6 billion. And I know this might be a marketing survey of one, but I'm sure you'd be hard pressed not to accept that there has been very, very significant improvement in quality and congestion and so on in the high-density areas. So, I think that's really where that CapEx went to.</p>
          <p>We have also increased 3G coverage to almost 50% of the population. Where I said that we started bit earlier than what we would have wished, but I guess that's where we were, and there is obviously a much higher usage of that. Fiber deployment: again this is an old story, you are aware, once we are allowed to self provide by Icasa and not be completely reliant on the fixed line operator for bandwidth with a very high cost, we immediately embarked on that and I think there is great progress on that.</p>
          <p>Data revenue is something that we have worked on over a number of years. We always said we wanted 10 or 12% of revenue being data. We've actually surpassed that now; we're close to 14% or 15% rather. And quite frankly it is really now data usage, in the sense that SMS as a component of data has come down quite significantly.</p>
          <p>Going to WECA region: Nigeria, again, very, very strong subscriber growth. We're at 50 million subscribers; that's almost seven million subscribers in the last year. And there is quite a number of operational undertakings that I think have helped. Again, we had significant investments in capacity in Nigeria, whilst, relatively speaking, our competitors didn't invest that much. We therefore had the capacity, high quality, and we could open up the pipe as far as drawing on subscribers.</p>
          <p>ARPU has declined. It looks worse in rands, but an actual fact, the naira declined, as you know, against the dollar and that has had an impact on how you look at ARPU in Nigeria. Nevertheless, six, seven years after the fact still being at $12, ARPU, we still think that is very, very solid and is very testimony to just how strong and how deep the market is.</p>
          <p>Like South Africa, we've had a reduction in interconnect tariff. We're not sure who precipitated who and who followed who, but that's really where we are. The silver lining in this cloud is the fact that with almost 80% of the traffic being on net in Nigeria, the impact is rather muted. So it's not as unfavorable as one may deem, just based on the drop in interconnect tariff.</p>
          <p>In a very similar vein, Nigerian government has insisted that we start registration of SIM cards and we are going to start that on the 1st of May. So quite a task, but again I think we are preplanning all of that and I want to ensure that that doesn't result in us slowing down too significantly or have an impact on our market share.</p>
          <p>EBITDA margin Nigeria, again I think, Nazir will deal with some of those issues, but suffice to say that it's still relatively strong. There's been very, very tight control of OpEx in Nigeria. We had in local currency almost 50% growth of revenue in Nigeria. So that revenue obviously has had an impact on that margin remaining strong. And of course, as I said, as we grow our base, as we grow market share, on-net calls are much higher and therefore interconnect costs in Nigeria would be lower. So I think all those things help in ensuring that we remain with a very strong margin.</p>
          <p>Almost R10 billion invested in network last year in Nigeria. And unless something crazy happens, I certainly hope and I know we've promised this a few times, but hopefully this time it is true that that is the peak CapEx year. And we hope that we are not going to revisit that figure again, but there have been huge benefits from that investment.</p>
          <p>And as I mentioned earlier, 3G sites, we are now rolling out quite significantly, almost 600 sites in Nigeria on the 3G network. And of course transmission remains a very competitive edge for us in Nigeria, even though we are looking at ways in which we can rationalize transmission with other operators, with a view to keeping that CapEx really low.</p>
          <p>Ghana: this is most probably the most competitive market we have. As I said, five operators and soon to be six, and these are very fairly strong operators. But we've managed to maintain a 55% market share. So again, I think it's testimony to the fact that the strategies we followed over the last few years have borne fruit. Once more, another story of significant CapEx investment. When we acquired this in 2006, it only had about two million subscribers plus/minus after being in existence for 10 years. Of course today it's over eight million subscribers. And we really do believe that products like MTN Zone helped us quite a lot in terms of being innovative and differentiating ourselves in the market and therefore maintaining that market share.</p>
          <p>Again, we've got a key issue in Ghana in terms of currency. The cedi did fall almost 50% against the U.S. dollar; that makes things a bit of a challenge. But nevertheless, as I said, if you look at the margin still being at roughly 45%, we think that there's a lot that management in that country has done right. We've also got a SIM registration issue here, which as I said, is now becoming a strong feature of all our operations.</p>
          <p>Enhanced data offerings: we don't have an ISP acquired in Ghana, but clearly we're trying to find a way of again ensuring that we've got the whole spectrum of products. Three billion, almost R3 billion in CapEx for 2009. We have had some headwinds on that margin in Ghana. One was a CST of 6% was applied, I think, starting in 2008. We also had to move our license fee from a fixed fee to almost 1% of turnover and so on. So there are quite a number of things there that have put that margin under pressure. But as I said, relatively speaking, we do think that the performance has been fairly strong.</p>
          <p>In looking at the MENA region, we are absolutely delighted with the performance of Iran. I know when we went into Iran there was a lot of skepticism on whether we would be able to establish an operation that was sound and financially accretive. If you look at the short history, I mean, MTN Iran really has only been operating for three years. In the sense that even though we launched in August '06, we really only began in earnest in 2007 January to really push very hard.</p>
          <p>Today we are at virtually 40% market share. And in the last quarter, we are connecting almost 52% of the net adds. There's been a whole range of promotions that has enabled us to clearly differentiate ourselves from the incumbent that has been there for many years. There's still a lot of work to be done on coverage and network, but suffice to say that we have now covered, I think over 1,400 cities and therefore are fairly represented in the country.</p>
          <p>23 million subscribers in Iran: I mean that's larger than South Africa in three years. So that, I think, puts it into context in terms of the growth of this business, which has been absolutely enormous. Again, the margin story here has also been very solid. You may recall that the guidance that we gave you when we came in in 2006, '07 was that because of the 28% revenue share in Iran, we thought that we could arrive at a margin of in the higher 20s if we did things properly. I'm glad to say that, we're now at least 31, 32% EBITDA margin in Iran not withstanding the 28% revenue share. So quite a lot of things have gone right here. Again, the margin just hasn't dropped from the sky. There's been quite a lot of work on distribution, using local banks, as an example, for logical  distribution and therefore reducing costs of distribution has helped, lower cost vouchers and so on. And of course, we are still in a phase in MTN Iran where we are experiencing and enjoying the economies of scale as the business grows. So I think on a margin basis it's done fairly well.</p>
          <p>Infrastructure wise, I mean, I guess as people started doing the calculation they would look at the marginal CapEx per subscriber in Iran and compare it with, let's say, South Africa and Nigeria, and they'd find that it's very low. It is very low but that is driven by a whole range of issues. One of them being the fact that the cost of civil works and a lot of inputs in Iran is locally sourced at relatively attractive prices. So that makes a very, very big difference on these CapEx numbers.</p>
          <p>And I mentioned earlier, even though we've covered a lot of cities, we think that if we were to have a breakthrough in being able to get more sites in a wider part of the country, particularly Northern Tehran and so on, we'd have even better quality and even higher volume. It is very, very difficult to get sites for all sorts of reasons. And if we can improve on site acquisition, we think that we would unlock far more value. We have had a WiMAX license in Iran and we launched December '09, and I think we've got something like 1,000 customers now.</p>
          <p>Syria really being a slightly different construct, being a BOT has got obviously different features for it. Firstly, let me just say that MTN management has been fairly good in Syria, but because of the BOT we have been more circumspect in the amount of CapEx that we put into the ground, until that BOT measure is resolved. We hope that that would happen by the end of the year and I think that would then enable us to take a different view on how we go forward. So I think as you can see, there's big drop off there from almost R1 billion through R748 in Syria in CapEx. That was a deliberate drop, as I say, to try and get far more visibility on how the BOT matter is going to resolve.</p>
          <p>And again, 3G services, we're trying very hard to get into that space and service the smaller companies, individuals that obviously spend a lot of time on data and have got high data usage and so on.</p>
          <p>So I think in summary, operationally, I mean those really &#x2013; we can't do all 21 countries, so we sort of picked the top five there. I would really characterize that 12 months, as I said very, very, very challenging, but we've seen very strong subs growth in virtually all the key countries with the exception of South Africa because of the challenges that I mentioned. And we've improved and maintained market share, again, in virtually all the key operations, South Africa being the exception. But certainly at 49% market share in Nigeria and now we think we're very, very, very strong. And that is just market share, the revenue share is obviously meaningfully higher in virtually all the countries. And of course as I said the brand and strong additions in Iran also put us in fairly good stead in 2009, or towards the end of 2009 to really kick off in 2010 with a solid base relative to the other customers.</p>
          <p>So thank you very much, let me, Nazir will deal with the financials. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks Phuthuma, good morning all and welcome to members of the Group Board, members of the Group Executive Committee, members of the audience, and all of those who are connected to this webcast in one form or another. As Phuthuma had indicated, 2009 has been an extremely challenging year, but we are pleased to report that revenue has grown by almost 10% on a year-on-year basis, despite the very strong effects of the ZAR,  particularly in the second half of 2009 combined with weakness in the naira as well as cedis, underlying countries and several of the countries that we operate in. I will take you through those effects down a few slides later.</p>
          <p>One of the issues that we are dealing with, however, is an EBITDA margin decline at a Group level of a full percentage point, largely due to EBITDA margin dilution in South Africa for various reasons, as well as Syria, allied to the revenue share increase that we had to take on a full-year basis during 2009.</p>
          <p>Currency impacts had an impact on the Group results at various levels. Firstly, we had foreign currency translation impacts on the revenue and EBITDA line, but we also had functional currency impacts, which affected the earnings per share as well on an adjusted basis. In 2008, we had a positive impact of about 94 cents and in 2009, unfortunately these were negative at 124 cents.</p>
          <p>As Phuthuma indicated, CapEx was a peak year for us at 31 billion, slightly higher by 10% compared to 2008. However, we did benefit from the strong ZAR in that spending was about R3.5 billion, not $3.5 billion as Phuthuma might have indicated earlier. We wish it was $3.5 billion, but that's unlikely to be the case.</p>
          <p>In any case, on a percentage of revenue basis, remained roughly constant and we have been able to as a result of very improved efficiency programs in the way we assess our traffic demand in the network, been able to defer about seven billion of network CapEx spend into 2010.</p>
          <p>We have continuing strong operating free cash flow generation. For the purposes of this particular analysis, operating free cash flow is stated after eliminating CapEx, which includes investments in software or intangible expenses.</p>
          <p>Without going into too much of detail on these, because I think Phuthuma has touched on a number of them, these results have to be measured in the light of very, very difficult trading conditions, more and more competition in most of the markets that we're operating in, and stagnant and likely declining GDPs in several of the countries following the credit crunch.</p>
          <p>Some of these has had an impact on consumer spending patterns and we've seen that in South Africa, and possibly in one or two other countries, which we can talk about later. ZAR reported results, as I've indicated, having negatively impacted both our reported revenues and EBITDAs and the underlying finance cost line, we'll go through in a few slides as well.</p>
          <p>The overall financial currency, functional currency's turnaround however on a year-on-year basis was a swing of R5.6 billion, which you would clearly expect had a very, very significant impact on headline earnings per share and reported earnings per share for the year.</p>
          <p>On the regulatory side, we have seen little impact in 2009, both from changes in RICA implementation in South Africa, as well as any changes in MTR rates across the footprint. However that situation could change as we go forward into 2010.</p>
          <p>Thankfully we did conclude some acquisitions during the year, albeit at a smaller scale than might have been widely represented in the press. We concluded the acquisition of Verizon South Africa, a 100% stake in that. And the entity has been consolidated on a full basis since February 2009.</p>
          <p>As part of our strategy to expand our distribution footprint in South Africa, we also acquired the remaining shares in iTalk that we didn't already control at that point. We swapped our international carrier service asset for a 20% stake in Belgacom and we realized a gain of approximately $200 million in that transaction. A large part of the gain will be recognized over a five-year period in combination with a commercial agreement that we have signed for traffic volumes with Belgacom International.</p>
          <p>We had smaller transactions with minority shareholders in Uganda and Zambia and disposed of our joint venture stake in digital mobile TV to <mark type="inaudible" />. The put option, the impact on the income statement this year was 906 million on credit compared with a debit or a charge of 825 million in the prior year. Again, the credit needs to be considered in the light of a weakening naira against the U.S. dollar as well as a strengthening South African rand.</p>
          <p>The tax charge for the year is at 33.4% in line with the guidance that we have provided to the market in earlier presentations, and is largely due to the expiry of commencement provisions in the first three months of 2008 and also the put option credit that we accounted for in this year.</p>
          <p>Just to point out two items here, which we &#x2013; I think Phuthuma had emphasized earlier during this presentation. We need to consider the impact of first-half performance against second half performance, largely in the light of the behavior of foreign currencies both in South Africa as well as in our key markets, such as Nigeria and Ghana. If you recall at our earlier results presentation for the half-year, our revenue gains, at that stage we had about 24% up year-on-year H1 to H1, whereas EBITDA was slightly higher, a 24.8% year-on-year H1 to H1.</p>
          <p>In the second half, the H2 to H2 comparison shows a revenue decline of 3% and an EBITDA margin decline of 8.8%. Both of these are directly related to firstly, the weakening of the naira on a cross rate basis against the ZAR of about 30% and the cedi of about 22%. I could deal with all the other countries, but I think these have had the most material impact on the Group reported results in the second half.</p>
          <p>The drop through from a revenue level down to an EBITDA level has deteriorated in the second half. We saw some weakening of Nigeria margins from the 60% that we reported in the first half to a slightly lower level at 59% for the full year due to some exceptional charges we took. Firstly on impairment provisions in Nigeria, on FIFA related promotional activity, general promotional activity to stimulate subscriber growth and some increases in the cost of leasing of sites for the expansion of our network.</p>
          <p>However, as noted by Phuthuma, based on the strong subs growth that we saw in our key markets, underlying local currency revenue growth has been particularly strong in Nigeria, in Iran, in Ghana, and in Uganda. Slightly disappointing in Syria, even though we increased our subs growth year-on-year by 20% or about 700,000 subscribers, a lot of those subscribers came on to our network at the back end of the year. So we had fairly little revenue impact.</p>
          <p>South Africa however was largely disappointing based on the disappointing first-half prepaid activity as well as probably in a lower spending in the postpaid segment and migration to hybrid packages. Importantly though, the 111 billion of revenues that we have reported for the Group at year end, if these were restated at constant prior year exchange rates, revenues would effectively increase by 20% on a year-on-year basis, which I think underlines the strength of the business overall across the entire footprint.</p>
          <p>This comparison is a little more difficult because the December 2009 numbers on a reported ZAR basis are obviously quite significantly impacted by the strengthening of the rand. What is important to note, however, that within the South African segment we see airtime and access revenues staying roughly flat year-on-year. It's fair to assume that for the remaining operations airtime revenues in all the underlying subsidiaries would have increased more or less reasonably in line with overall organic revenue growth.</p>
          <p>Data and SMS, as pointed out by Phuthuma; we've made a number of investments, either in 3G capability, in the number of fiber investments that we've made, have allowed us to grow this revenue stream as part of our diversification policy and increase this segment going forward. We see this as an important indicator in terms of continued revenue diversification, especially given the fact that there's increasing competition and likely continued pressure on tariffs for airtime, driven either by competition or by regulatory changes.</p>
          <p>Interconnect as a whole, again, on a ZAR-reported basis has increased marginally year-on-year. We did see some increase in international outgoing traffic from South America, and then given the large volume on net traffic that we have in Nigeria we saw about 15% increase in interconnect traffic within that particular country.</p>
          <p>Mobile phones or mobile handsets for the Group as a whole increased from about 4.1 million to about 5.1 million. The selling prices overall have come down quite considerably, especially in South Africa. And that would have affected the amount of revenue we've generated from that segment. The other line of 3.5 billion has increased by approximately a billion compared to the prior year. Most of that is related to the acquisition of Verizon, which is not reported under the data lines, but is reported in the other four purposes of this presentation.</p>
          <p>Again, the EBITDA trends follow largely the trends that we have shown you on an organic basis on the revenue slide. Nigeria, Iran, Ghana, and Uganda have increased tremendously on a year-on-year basis. Ghana is especially pleasing, simply because there was very, very high competition in the market. It's fair to say that many of the competitors have dropped pricing by as much as 40%. We have not followed the trend in the market, but having stayed focused on things like distribution, the quality of service to the customer, and obviously offering the consumer the widest possible network coverage in the market. That has allowed us to keep revenue margins fairly flat year-on-year at about 45%.</p>
          <p>Nigeria margins on a full-year basis had increased by roughly 1.5 points. Iran margins were particularly pleasing, given that we were at or about 30% at the end of last year. We managed to get a full pick up of five points to approximately 35 percentage points for the full-year. Now considering that margin in the light of the 28% revenue share, if you adjust for that item you have one of the higher margin performing entities in the Group as a whole. And clearly, there are lessons for us to be learned in terms of extrapolating that business model across the wider footprint.</p>
          <p>Syria margins, as I mentioned, have been depressed and that's largely due to the full-year impact of the revenue share, which had increased in June 2008 from 40% to 50%. The operational margin, otherwise excluding the impact of the higher revenue share, would have been flat year-on-year. '09 EBITDA, however, restate at constant prior FX rates would have been about 18.4% higher, and that compares to the restatement of our revenue which will have been about 19.9%, as I mentioned earlier.</p>
          <p>Again, without commenting on too many issues here, because I will unpack the year-on-year Group EBITDA margin evolution. Suffice to say, the direct network cost expansion in all the countries have driven up reported costs on a local basis, as well as Syria revenue share having a fairly large impact on overall revenue share payments and direct network operating costs for the Group. The cost of handsets and accessories have come down, offset somewhat through foreign exchange contracts that we had through the South African operation. Interconnect and roaming costs, however, increased in South Africa due to higher telecom charges on outgoing international traffic to neighboring operations.</p>
          <p>A key point to mention here is following the integration of companies like Verizon, iTalk, and Cell Place in the South African operation. We have incurred, on a short-term basis, fairly higher employee related and distribution costs. And moving forward, we would expect as most of the market is aware, to reduce those costs through a head count restructuring exercise, which we've announced, as well as the closure of what we call poorly positioned or under performing distribution points. And that's likely to have a positive impact on that line going forward.</p>
          <p>Other expenses include the segment of the Cell C provision by South Africa of about R354 million. Just unpacking the margin on a year-on-year basis at a Group level: as I mentioned previously, we saw margin drop of about a full percentage point: 0.6 of that relates directly to Syria change, which I talked about earlier; 0.5 of that relates to South Africa, but that's, let's just say, simplistic in its analysis. We have lower interconnect margins on telcom, which are a big driver of the lower margin year-on-year; higher selling and distribution costs from the expanded footprint on the distribution side; a creep up on IT outsourcing costs, but however, these were partially offset by benefits from the Cell C settlement of the dispute, as well as a reduction in the regulated charge for regulated payments, which were previously calculated as a percentage of gross margin and now calculated at a lower rate as a percentage of operating income. Nigeria margins offset some of this at a full 0.7 of a point, largely due to fixed cost control and some OpEx savings.</p>
          <p>As for as other OpCos are concerned, on a combined basis, we saw 0.6 of a point dilution. We brought in Verizon, which is consolidated obviously at a much lower margin rate, which is typical for that type of business. But in addition to that we had some businesses which had not performed very well as expected as an example Cote d'Ivoire et cetera. Clearly, we have actions in place to address that going forward.</p>
          <p>On the interest and tax line, the key issue to mention here, our functional currency gains and losses, which I talked about previously. The 3.2 billion charge that we took in the current year includes 1.8 billion on the Iran loans, which we had &#x2013; on the Mauritius loans to Iran. We have now, since year end, moved these loans to one of our other holding companies and hopefully that will eliminate a fair amount of the volatility as we go forward into 2010.</p>
          <p>Additional items are basically additional functional currency charges of about R800 million, relating to cash which was held either at the underlying subsidiary level. On a put option basis, the net impact was R700 million compared to a 1.2 billion charge in the prior year. Deferred tax was substantially lower at 992, offset by two items. Nigeria claimed lower capital allowances on a year-on-year basis of about R1 billion, which was largely the driver for that reduction.</p>
          <p>Overall, however, the tax charges I had mentioned previously was particularly pleasing that was in line with our expectations. And again, functional currency losses as well as the <mark type="inaudible" /> had an impact on the overall charge.</p>
          <p>Looking at the earnings per share. We have attempted to just analyze some of the foreign currency impacts. And in this particular case, the functional currency impact gain or loss on a year-on-year basis to understand the adjusted headline earnings performance on a year-on-year basis. What we have not done, however, is to try and unpack, simply because of the complexity of that particular analysis, the foreign currency translation impact on an EBITDA level, which has clearly had a fairly negative impact on the reported results.</p>
          <p>But given all of those changes, on loss and disposal of fixed assets we had an adjustment of 3.8 cents, most of which relates to the profit on the share of the disposal of the ICS or International Carrier Services assets, the eight cents on the impairment of property, plant, and equipment relates mostly to Nigeria, which is the impairment of inventory, a large portion of which was just taken in the second half, as I indicated earlier. And then moving below headline earnings per share, the put option reversal on a consistent basis was an addition of 44.3 cents last year and a lowering because of a credit that included in income this year of  48.9 cents. Adjusting for the functional currency loss, and at the risk of upsetting all the technical fundies, accounting fundies out there, we almost have an adjusted adjusted headline earnings per share of 878.9, which compares with 810.2, it's about a 9% gain year-on-year. So overall, I think in the context of very, very difficult trading conditions, that is a particularly pleasing result.</p>
          <p>On the income statement, we have dealt with most of the items. As far as the depreciation charge is concerned, most of the increase, and again keep in mind that a lot of these impacts on the P&amp;L level have to be considered in the light of big foreign exchange movements on a translation basis. The increase in the depreciation charges due to the expanded, the increased investments on the network side in Nigeria, in Iran, as well as in South Africa.</p>
          <p>Amortization has come down slightly because of further revaluations of property of the PPA adjustments at the year-end. Net finance cost, as I've indicated earlier, have increased quite substantially, largely driven by the functional currency adjustments we talked about earlier. And I will comment on the small five million that's sitting in there and that's the loss of associates, our share of loss from associates in the LEAF business as well as profits for the one month on dee swap from the Mednet or ICS assets to the BICS transaction.</p>
          <p>Minority interests have gone up to 2.5 billion from the prior reported 1.8 billion, largely due to the higher profit after tax in Nigeria and the increase in new minority share of that due to the profit. On the balance sheet side, without again going into too much of detail, the SSN liabilities in the balance sheet are heavily impacted by foreign currency translation adjustments. At the level of PPE, it's about 13 billion for the current reported period. So optically even though the number has only gone up three billion following some substantial investments in the network, we get the credit off the foreign currency translation adjustment against that. Goodwill at the same time is about seven billion lower as a result of the same item.</p>
          <p>One other point I would like to mention here is the 7.3 billion on the deferred tax and other non-current liabilities includes a gain of 1.3 billion from the profit on the sale of other swap of the Mednet assets to BICS, which I referred to earlier. And again just to conform, that that will be released over a five-year period.</p>
          <p>Net debt, we are pleased to report that our net debt EBITDA has reduced by 20.26 and as Phuthuma had indicated earlier, has allowed us to, the Board to take a decision to relax, at this stage at any rate, the dividend policy of the company and return some more cash to the shareholders. We're also pleased to report that we are in line with the strategy that we had advised the market of earlier, we've continued deleveraging the Group and pushing on non-recourse debt to various underlying subsidiaries. And in this case &#x2013; at the end of the year we had completed about $462 million of that.</p>
          <p>Looking at the overall debt profile of the Group, in 2010 we have repayments of 15.8 billion, which include about five billion of repayments on our bond, about six billion that comes through from Nigeria. And most of these we hope will be refinanced and Debbie assures me she will be working anxiously on that for the next few weeks or few months.</p>
          <p>Okay, it's fair to say that in terms of the longer term debt profile we also will be working through our Nigerian Syndication Association to try and, let's just say, restructure a lot of those arrangements. On the cash flow side, the net interest paid line has gone up by approximately two billion year-on-year and that's accounted for by some losses on a year-on-year basis, which account for an additional charge of about a billion unrealized FEC losses. Additional items include about a 4% increase in interest rates on Nigerian lending and a full draw down on Nigerian facilities via the Nigerian operation.</p>
          <p>Overall, investments or investing activities have changed by R5 billion year-on-year. In prior year, the 1196 include a 4.4 billion income or proceeds from the sale of, or income from the proceeds of the Nigeria private player placement, which were offset by certain intercompany loans that we provided to Group entities which was mostly about R2.2 billion from the Mauritius level. In the current year, the 3.5 billion relates mostly to the acquisition of Verizon, iTalk, et cetera. It's overall fairly strong cash flow generation for the year.</p>
          <p>On the CapEx side, we've talked previously about 2009 being a peak CapEx year, and we continually come back and ask you guys for more money to spend on the CapEx side. However, I think given our current estimates of subscriber demand, our current levels of network capacity, and the headroom that we have in all of our networks, we believe that we would see a fairly strong reduction of that number going forward.</p>
          <p>Again, that, as Phuthuma mentioned earlier, is based on current assumptions of the market. If some of these markets had to change significantly as a result of changing competitions or any other factor, we would obviously review our spending guidance as a result of that. Again, as mentioned previously, strong ZAR had helped us offset the cost of CapEx by about 3.5 billion, and then we also deferred as a result of current excess capacity in the network, programs for one reason or the other for about seven billion into our 2010 guidance.</p>
          <p>So overall, the 42 billion that we have talked about at our prior presentation, on an actual basis has lowered to 31 billion. Looking forward, on the CapEx side, we expect &#x2013; we've authorized CapEx of about 23.6 billion, and in the nature of how these things actually go historically we would expect that not all of that would be spent, again, subject to the comments I have just made, in 2010. The likelihood is we would see a number of at or close to 20 billion. Again, that's based on a current exchange rate assumption of 807 on an average basis for the full year.</p>
          <p>Again, most of the spending would be in where we see still continuing growth opportunities in markets like Nigeria, in Iran; and the Iran number, please keep in mind, includes 49% of the CapEx that we consolidate. It's not the full value of the CapEx. As well as South Africa where we have some fairly important investments in transmission and reoptimizing of the network. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, very much, Nazir. Hopefully that puts a quite a number of things into perspective. I think looking forward, again, there isn't much change here from what we've outlined in the past. Expansion opportunities, the landscape in the sector is changing and some would even say fairly rapidly, but we are certainly staying on course to say that we continue to expand, lower CapEx, more cash that does allows a high dividend, but that doesn't mean that we are veering off from the view that the Group is still in a position to grow quite significantly.</p>
          <p>And of course rolling out infrastructure, even though CapEx, as just indicated, hopefully is going to drop down to the very low 20s for 2010, we still need to ensure that we have got very efficient spend and roll out in that area, because that is obviously the single largest, other than the OpEx of course, the single largest exposure and spend for the Group. The operational efficiency, I spoke a lot about that in my earlier section of the presentation. Regulator-wise, as usual we always remain, shall I say, very constructively engaged with the regulators and try and preempt as many of the challenges that people may foresee and try and ensure that we've got a win-win situation in virtually all the markets. The BEE transaction is definitely on course and I'm very hopeful that we will be able to come back to you that in the relatively near future.</p>
          <p>So those really are the key building blocks for 2010, as I said not different from what they have been in the past. Subscriber-wise, this is always difficult because who knows how markets would turn out, but our plan for 2010 is that we should connect up another 20 million subscribers in our markets, the bulk of those coming from Nigeria and Iran. And then the seven million spread amongst the other operators. Clearly, you can see South Africa is very much on a mature phase now, so we expect to connect 800,000 subscribers, which is most probably more than 50% less than what we've done in the past.</p>
          <p>So thank you very much for your patience. I believe we do have 15 minutes or so to take some questions. And I've got some very able-bodied people here in the front. So any questions I can't answer, I'm sure they'll be more than willing to field. If somebody has got a microphone, can we start there, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Phuthuma. It's Jonathan Kennedy-Good from Investec, just talking to your Nigerian CapEx. What assumptions or what views have you taken on minutes of use over the next year, two years in that market and on data growth? Because it seems like there are still very few 3G handsets, Blackberries in that market. I mean, is that CapEx that you have going forward enough to sustain that major growth in those segments? And then, just in terms of cost efficiencies you spoke briefly on, is there some kind of target you can guide the market across the Group in the major regions, Nigeria and SA? In terms of costs you may want to pull out of the Group. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me take the question on costs and maybe, Sifiso, you want to talk about minutes of use in Nigeria. Look, I think on costs the view that we take is that we need to benchmark ourselves against the best operators in the world and it is not always easy because invariably you find that you're comparing apples and pears. But just to give you an indication, if we look at revenue to OpEx, I mean we'd say that we have to be, would sort of set a target of about 20% as an example. If we look at CapEx to sales, it depends on the country, but would really say that they need to be, at this stage, approaching between let's say 10 to 15% in a more steady state. Now we might not achieve that in one year, but certainly that's the target.</p>
          <p>And you can go through quite a number of matrices, productivity matrices in terms of people that subscribe and so on. We do try and give the operations a fairly concise framework to try and move through to become a low-cost operator. I mean, that's really how we approach that. And as I say, there is never a time where you feel that you've achieved that. One of the big areas that I haven't spoken about is, for instance, more infrastructure sharing looking at, should we be starting to look at our companies and so on to try and reduce the CapEx even further past the steady state stage.</p>
          <p>So those are sort of the initiatives that we look at, but it's really clear matrices that we give them either on a revenue or a cost basis. Sifiso, you want to talk about minutes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The overall minutes of use have remained quite stable on a per subscriber basis and rate of growth in terms of the overall minutes has slowed down quite a bit, and the fact that right now from a coordinator perspective, we've got at least 30% headroom. So the CapEx that's been put forward we think is quite sufficient. And then from a data point view, that is, you're right, that is still quite a major opportunity and we are working on it to increase usage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think there is a question right at the back, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My name is John from Afrifocus Securities. My first question just revolves around your expansion into emerging markets. Is there any region you will not be looking at? And secondly, you stated at some point you need to list about 21% of MTN Irancell. When will that be concluded?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, I wouldn't say that there aren't any markets that we wouldn't look at. But our focus right now is clearly building on what we have, which is Africa and the Middle East, I think in the first instance. In the second instance, most probably looking further eastwards, if, as I've said a number of times, it would have to be quite a significant opportunity with critical mass, which we think in the long-term is really going to create value for the company. And that really would be the focus. It's highly unlikely, for instance, that we would look at an opportunity in, let's say, eastern Europe. And I'm not saying never. But I'm just saying that if we look at where our strengths are, what our focus is, and where we're already positioned, that is unlikely. The same way that we said we wouldn't look at small opportunities in, let's say, Central America or South America because you've got away very, very large players. We have Am&#xE9;rica M&#xF3;vil, Telef&#xF3;nica, and so on. So if an opportunity came there, it would have to be an opportunity of size. So that's really, I think, the way that we would position it. Your second question was, sorry?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Regarding the listing of 21% of MTN Irancell?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, there is something that we are engaged in discussions with the regulator in Iran in terms of should that listing happen, if the dilution has to happen, when it lists is it pro rata and so on. And I can't say more than that. Suffice to say that it's something that we are involved in. Obviously, if we did list, we would not want to dilute below our 49%. And clearly, obviously, we would list on a basis that would be fair value for whatever dilution would happen, to the extent that we found ourselves in a position of having to dilute, which hopefully will not be case. Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's John from UBS. I just had a question regarding the cash in Ghana, it has gone down substantially. Are you able to, or has that issue been cleared up with the tax authorities?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Look I think the issue regarding the tax authorities on tax was really something that was a legacy issue, which was aligned to the acquisition that we had with Investcom. But I think by and large that matter has been settled, because I think as we've always said we thought that whatever approach was being made on tax was relis puris. I don't know, you want to add Nazir?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, John, I think that issue has possibly have a minority shareholder dispute that we still need to settle. We had in fact disputes with two minority shareholders, they're caving  rights to some of the equity; we settled one of them. And prior to us actually repatriating any cash, we'll have to settle the other one. We're currently in discussions. But I think even though the cash has come down, I think that reflects the fact that we've had some pretty significant investments in the network. The opportunity going forward though, is we can deleverage that OpCo quite significantly in the future once we have settled the dispute and trying not to leak some cash. We have a fair amount of retained earnings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I mean, I think, Nazir, it would also be true that, as you saw the indication, the cedi has devalued quite a bit, I mean, another 30%. So even if we are in a position to extract all of that now, it wouldn't be prudent from a talent perspective to actually do that repatriation at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, the second question, are you able to provide any details on the extent of the retrenchment cost in South Africa?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think we just really follow normal level on that. And I mean, I don't think that we've got a number that we're willing to share with anybody. But suffice to say that by and large, we, at the minimum, follow what is legislated and required under labor law and may even do a little bit more than that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yohahn from Nate Bank. Just two questions. Firstly, if I look at Bharti, let's assume they are successful in acquiring the African, Bharti acquiring the African assets of Zain, how do you think they will approach it? Maybe different to Zain? It offers itself?  And secondly, just the impact from the financial point of view of World Cup 2010 on your bottom line?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think as far as Bharti is concerned, how will they approach it? Let's put it this way, they will be in a better position if they were holding, we were holding their hand, you know? (laughter) And so, they've decided to venture into the forest on their, own that's fine. We clearly don't underestimate any competitor. Suffice to say that I know people's mind immediately race to low cost models and so on. I think the elements of the cost model part of the equation, which I think is relevant, I don't think the revenue part of the equation is relevant yet because you are not connecting four million subscribers a month. So, there are some differences there, but we're trying to hedge out our own strategies. So I'm not too sure I want to speculate too much on what our strategies would be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just the second question on the World Cup?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the World Cup, really it's, I don't recall the cost of the rights, did we share that number? I don't remember. But suffice to say it's a meaningful number, and obviously there has to be significant leverage of those rights. I'm sure if FIFA is willing to tell you what those numbers are I'm sure that they can share that with you. And of course then we've got leverage as well. And leverage is usually maybe 25%, 30% more of what you've paid, in some cases up to one to one. I know that I am not giving you the answer that you want, suffice to say it was very expensive. And we hope it works. We never know which 50% is working of the marketing, but some of it is working quite significantly. I think the profile is great and we are going into a lot of operations and using that property for them to position themselves in terms of content, promotions and so on. So it's a quite a differentiator and I think it's always difficult to quantify but I think it's worth our while. But as far as the number on the property rights, I'm not too sure, I think the FIFA guys I am sure would be quite happy to share with you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I am Irnest Kaplan from Kaplan Equity Analysts. Can you just give us an indication of your process to find a new CEO? And what sort of person do you think you would be looking for, what sort of skills and would it be internal or external?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Look, I mean, that is, as you know, fairly standard. It's really a board process that is followed, so I mean I don't mind the arranging for you to have tea with Mr. Ramaphosa and I'm sure you guys can have that discussion. But on a serious note, it's a board process, there's Group Ramco the size of a company of this size goes through proper processes and considerations happens internally and externally. And I am sure they will embark on that soon.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, Phuthuma, it's me. I've just got some queries that have come off the webcast from analysts that are not here. And particularly Craig Hackney from BJM and Nik Kershaw from Deutsche Bank. The two questions that I have is relating to the impairments in Nigeria, particularly on the inventory, if you can just give a little bit more color. And then the Naycharz gardens in South Africa was no at the end of September and obviously end of the year down 1.1; if you can just give a little bit more color as to what happened.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me pass those questions on. Nazir, you want to take the impairment in Nigeria. And Sifiso, you want to talk about the net adds in SA.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The amount of the impairment in Nigeria is R125 million, I mean, it's a very strict application of an accounting policy, it's effectively anything that's aged more than 12 months, it goes in, is reserved at 100% in terms of a provision. I think it's fair to say that on a market realizable value, there is still commercial value in that impairment. What the management team does on an ongoing basis is obviously tries to reutilize all of that, sort of what you call impaired inventory back in terms of the network process or network investment or network roll out process. So, it's something that follows quite a stringent commercial process before we take the economic impact of that impairment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The impact of RICA was just a little bit worse than what was expected, and the level of disconnections on the subscribers that were on the base at the time was actually a little bit worse than expected as well, and that has improved as we got into this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Davey, we've got another question. When you picked up your hand I was worried what question you were going to ask me that you didn't ask this morning. But anyway, anybody else? Okay. Sorry, there is one question there, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Nicky Smith, Bloomberg News. Could you tell us please, the empowerment transaction that you say is on course? When do you expect to have that concluded by? And what will the stake size be? Could you just give us some detail on how big that will be? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Look, I'm not able to give details because obviously this is something that we are working on. I think as far as timing, all things being equal then, the number of issues that we're still trying to resolve. We're still hopeful that by Q2 or Q3, we should be able to put out something that is very comprehensive. I mean things could work such that we could do it even earlier, but I would say that a reasonable guess at this stage would be around Q3 at the latest hopefully.</p>
          <p>And the size, I think we did indicate last year, that at the time the company acquired the new shelf  block that it's unlikely given the size of the company that it would be in excess of 6%. So it would be something meaningfully less than that, but those are all the numbers that we are still working on. And I really don't want to be quoted as saying that that's the number or that's the firm number. What I'm just saying is, given the size and the market cap of the Group, something in excess of six or 5% is most unlikely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. If no more questions, thank you very much and thanks for attending. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. What we'd like to do before you all stream out, is just to show the advert again, and then invite you to come and have lunch with us next door. So if we can have the ad on. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>