<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1377802" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2011-03-09</date>
    <companies>
      <company>8758</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Rich Mkhondo, Head Corporate Affairs Department</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Phuthuma Freedom Nhleko, President and Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Nazir Patel, Group Finance Director</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">M. Cyril Ramaphosa, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">R. Sifiso N. Dabengwa, Group Chief Operating Officer</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Martin Dullaart</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Nicky Smith</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Peter Takaendesa</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Jonathan Kennedy-Good</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning ladies and gentlemen, my name is Rich Mkhondo, I am the Executive for Corporate Affairs at MTN. I hope you enjoyed the video.</p>
          <p>On behalf of MTN's 35,000 employees led by the Board of &#x2013; the executive, Mr. Cyril Ramaphosa and the members of EXCO led by our Group CEO and President, Mr. Phuthuma Nhleko, and shareholders and everyone here at MTN, I wish to welcome you, members of the media and also analysts and all our colleagues who are actually watching us across the 21 operating countries.</p>
          <p>As it is customary, the Group President will do the presentation, he will be followed by our Financial Director, Mr. Nazir Patel and then, of course, the proceedings will continue. At the end, we would like you to join us for brunch outside. Please use the back entrance to go to the social area to enjoy the brunch.</p>
          <p>As we are about to begin, I would like to ask you to switch off your phones because this may sort of disturb the connections to our 21 operating countries. And I want to ask our Group President and CEO, Mr. Phuthuma Nhleko to come and present our financial results for the year ending 31st December 2010.</p>
          <p>Mr. Nhleko?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much Rich for that introduction. Once more welcome to everybody. I'd like to take this very special opportunity to welcome our Chairman Mr. Cyril Ramaphosa and all the Board Directors that are here, <mark type="inaudible" />. And of course, as Rich pointed out, we've got many, many colleagues in many, many countries that are tuned into the webcast and will be part of the sessions and the event. So I thank you very much for making the time to make it this morning.</p>
          <p>I'd really like to commence really with the slide that I've presented over the number of years and that slide essentially depicts our vision from certainly where MTN management sits in terms of what we're trying to achieve, and that vision really has not changed. It's essentially to be the preeminent operator in the mobile space in emerging markets.</p>
          <p>But to achieve that we've always believed that we've got three fairly pertinent blocks that will actually put some substance in that vision. Firstly it's convergence and operational evolution. Once again, we've seen technology, or theories on technology really going ahead of the reality, but I think time has caught up and we're seeing a lot of convergence in the market and we are consistently looking at ways of repositioning the company to be able to compete in that space. I think the entrance of the likes of Google, Microsoft and Apple are really quite typical of that space. Of course we can't do this without intellectual capacity in the group and that's something that we work very hard to preserve and ensure that we spend a great deal of time, effort and money in safeguarding that intellectual capacity and ensuring that it's consistently replenished.</p>
          <p>We do have a footprint as we showed in our opening video, we obviously would love to have had it  to be far more contiguous in certain regions, that is not always possible. But we continue to look at ways in which we can get some consolidation in each region, and of course, always look at ways to diversify the source of earnings because we are fairly concentrated in certain countries. And that bottom-layer or block really is all the number of, shall I say, areas in which we try to ensure that those three building blocks actually work and deliver the vision.</p>
          <p>I think before I talk about the results, let me just, if I may, take a few minutes to talk about the context because of course our main sphere of operation is Africa and the Middle East. And I think people do tend to forget how large the opportunity is. I think we as a company identified that many years ago and I think as time has progressed it's turned out that even we, in some respects underestimated the size of the opportunity.</p>
          <p>Firstly in the financial crisis, from which hopefully we are beginning to emerge; in many markets in African economies, in particular, we are quite resilient in how they were able to not suffer as badly as let's say most of the developed world. When certain countries were having 2.5% growth, most of the African economies were actually at 4% positive as opposed to contracting.</p>
          <p>Of course, depending on which pundit you believe, we are now slowly emerging out of the crisis. Even now, you will see that global GDP growth average is around 2.5% and most African countries and emerging economies in general are over 6%. Of course we've seen huge urbanization, which lent itself to certain sectors, telecoms, energy and so on.</p>
          <p>And finally, we've seen huge FDI increase, I think in the last eight to ten years, it has moved from $15 billion to almost $80 billion. So we are really in a sphere that does present some significant opportunity.</p>
          <p>The results in essence, results that we achieved under fairly difficult circumstances, notwithstanding the size of the opportunity that I have just outlined. We managed to increase subscribers to 142 million. EBITDA margin, very pleasing to 44%, you may recall that some years back, we set a target of about 45% for the EBITDA margin. I know that there was a great deal of number of skeptics in that regard, but I think we are almost there. Free cash flow, which is CapEx after EBITDA, sorry the net of subtracting CapEx from the EBITDA, is almost R31 billion and that's quite significant, almost R15 billion up from last year. And then adjusted earnings per share up 20.5% to 909 cents. Nazir in his presentation will unpack that adjusted headline earnings in more detail.</p>
          <p>And then of course the dividend, I know this has been an issue of great contention in some people's minds. We have increased the payout ratio to 55%. So that brings us to a dividend for this half of 349. So just to make it very, very clear, lest there is any confusion, that's a 55% payout ratio for the entire year. We paid 151 cents in the first-half. So there is an additional 349 cents for this half bringing the total dividend for the year to 500 cents.</p>
          <p>And then of course the company really is effectively net debt positive. We have cash of about R36 billion and debt of about R35 billion. So that nets cash of R1 billion. And I think that's clearly a capital structure that will change over time. So I think those are the results in brief.</p>
          <p>The strategy that we followed here is essentially really formed by a framework, where as you recall, we have invested heavily in a lot of countries. 2007 to 2009 was a very heavy CapEx year, and we made that call because we thought that would give us a competitive advantage. But of course, we peaked in 2009 and we've seen, started seeing less and less CapEx on a global aggregated basis. I mean one or two countries may go up, but generally the CapEx for the group is coming down.</p>
          <p>Of course, the cost efficiencies that we have, it's easy to talk about it, but this is really a result of many policies, exercises, initiatives that try and find a way of getting better margins through economies of scale, better procurement and so on. And I think part of that result is, of course, the very high free cash flow that you've seen which of course, I must accept, is also helped by the lower CapEx.</p>
          <p>And of course that all leads us to the dividend payout ratio and it is really informed by three things. I think firstly, we did say in around March that we thought as far as M&amp;A opportunities are concerned, the chances of very large transformational M&amp;A is unlikely, even though we may continue to look at regional opportunities that help us to do the consolidation.</p>
          <p>CapEx, as I indicated earlier, 2009 was by and large peak. We may have a blip in one or two countries depending on what happens in competition. And then of course the strong cash flow. So, those three factors combined gave us the comfort to take a decision to go onto a bolder payout ratio of 55%. But it's really informed by this context.</p>
          <p>Looking at revenue, one key feature of these results is of course the rand. As everybody knows, we have in the past we have had some advantage of some tailwinds, but in the last two years we really have struggled with a headwind in terms of the rand being very strong.</p>
          <p>And notwithstanding the very strong underlying performance of these operations on a consolidated basis, reporting in rands, you obviously see the impact here. So, if you look at revenue, reported is R114 billion. If we had to do the same numbers on a currency constant basis, it would have been R127 billion. So there is almost a R12 billion difference because of currency.</p>
          <p>The other matter that really did affect revenue is of course the termination rates. This is one of the key things that have been precipitated by the regulators where both in South Africa and Nigeria and I think Uganda as well we've had to decrease the interconnect rates. On South Africa, we've gone down a slide or glide path that will end in, I think 2013 at $0.40.</p>
          <p>The other key feature of revenue generation is of course data revenue, which has increased quite significantly. In the case of South Africa, for instance, I think it went up to 49% increase on what the data revenue was last year. Nigeria, Syria, Iran are all opportunities as far as data revenue is concerned. I mean they also have a good uplift, but maybe not as high as let's say South Africa.</p>
          <p>And of course, I must maybe finally say on increase in revenue that huge segmentation exercises have been undertaken that's enabled us to read the market better provide products that are far more adaptable for that particular market and therefore the heavy revenues increases on a local currency basis.</p>
          <p>I think if we look at data without spending too much time on the slide, let me say that you'll see that we are, particularly in South Africa, starting to have SMS as a lower and lower percentage of data. We have also rolled out some optic fibre, spent far more in transmission. Also put in quite a number of submarine cables, EASSY is obviously the largest one. But there is WACS on the West Coast of South Africa. And all this investment hopefully will enable us to become a much more versatile data player having more capacity and obviously a higher product range as well.</p>
          <p>One other area which is in some respect still in its nascent stage of development is of course, MobileMoney. And I know people have got very long memories. They all know that we started in South Africa in MobileMoney and it was more mobile banking than MobileMoney, that didn't work out as we had anticipated. So we started from scratch, and really focused more on MobileMoney transfer.</p>
          <p>We've got quite a number of countries now that have established the MobileMoney business, Uganda and Ghana, between them we've got almost 4.3 million subscribers. But of course still at an early development stage. It only contributed, let's say, about $10 million of revenue. The intention here is to have total group revenue of around 5%, in about 2015 being generated out of MobileMoney, but still quite a lot of work to be done in developing that.</p>
          <p>I think the EBITDA drivers, as I indicated, we had a group EBITDA margin of 44%, 1% lower than where we would have liked to have been. There is quite a lot to discuss here that could &#x2013; get quite involved Nazir will unpack some of it. But suffice to say that there were maybe two or three big elements that contributed. I think firstly, Nigeria did exceptionally well, as far as cost containment and control of OpEx.</p>
          <p>And the same can be said of South Africa. There was some advantages that came out of lower handset costs. We did also in a country like South Africa get some margin out of interconnect in the sense that we had lower interconnect costs, and lower interconnect revenue. However the cost was decreased faster, shall I say, than the revenue, so we did get some margin expansion there.</p>
          <p>We had much stronger supply chain management. We have taken supply chain management far more seriously than we may have done in the past, not to say that we weren't taking it seriously, but we have now established a world class supply chain management unit to find ways of finding those efficiencies within the group, taking full advantage of scale. So I think that's going to be a very important feature going forward.</p>
          <p>Infrastructural sharing is something that we have also done quite extensively, wherever we can to obviously assist us on maintenance costs on base stations and so on. So there is a whole range of exercises initiatives that have enabled us to get to this margin. Big challenge is going to be obviously maintaining that EBITDA margin, and hopefully going upwards honestly.</p>
          <p>Of course we're in a fairly regulated environment. So regulators are really part of our lives and are integral to it. First of all, let me just start of with Syria, you may recall that in Syria, we had a good operate transfer license. And it was quite difficult in the sense that it was a very unusual construct for the group. It also had an impact on the kind of CapEx that you could invest, because obviously the state ended up with the infrastructure.</p>
          <p>I am glad to say that we have reached in principal agreement with the Syrian regulator in the sense that the BOT will now be converted and normalized and hopefully by end of May at the very latest I am hoping we can still do that by, by let's say April.</p>
          <p>The essence of the arrangement is 25-year license will pay about $600 million in upside upfront licensed fee. And then they'll have revenue share of between 25 and 27. So I think it's a great outcome. As far as MTR Mobile Termination Rates, as I mentioned earlier in the case of South Africa we have come, reached agreement with the ICASA on the glide path. Nigeria was really a one-off, but was not as impactful, because almost 80% of the traffic in Nigeria is actually on net.</p>
          <p>Another key feature of the regulatory environment in the last year was the SIM registration. As you know it took off like wildfire. South Africa we had &#x2013; had to ask for an extension and I must say government was very kind to accommodate us. So we have got up until end of June. Of course the largest challenge is always the prepaid subscribers, but I'm happy to say that we have now almost 80%, over 80% of prepaid subscribers registered.</p>
          <p>In Nigeria also undergoing registration, in Ghana we have also been given some extension. And there are various states for Cameroon and many other countries. So this is something that actually started for us in South Africa. We have big challenges in Sudan where I think we learned some fairly sultry lessons as far as being ahead of the curve as far as registration. And I'd like to believe that overall it's something that we now have in hand.</p>
          <p>I think the other key developments, the academy. I think I may have spoken to you about this one before. People are an absolute essential part of our competitive edge in this group. And I know this sound like a clich&#xE9;, because every country or company says that.</p>
          <p>But in the case of MTN, given the footprint that the company has and the very difficult challenges and geographies that we have to deal with, having &#x2013; shall I say MTN, MTN-ised people it's very, very important. So we set up an academy that is fit for purpose, training for MTN for its means. And over the last three years, over 25,000 of our staff have gone through it in one form or another. So, I think this is quite solid for us.</p>
          <p>Of course living in a much greener world we have to comply on doing things in a manner that is environmental friendly and so on carbon credits and the like and we've got quite a big unit now in business risk.</p>
          <p>Looking at sustainability not just ticking the boxes, but ensuring that we're doing things that are actually energy efficient will it be generators, whether it's the way we dispose of things and so on.</p>
          <p>Last but not least, the MTN's Zakhele scheme. This was MTN's BEE scheme. You recall that we had Newshelf 664, which ran from 2002 until 2008 and got unwound. And at the point of unwinding Newshelf, obviously were not meeting the BEE requirements as far as the participation of the company. So we did undertake a very broad scheme called Zakhele. I must say it's turned out even better than we had anticipated. Zakhele now holds 4% of the issued share capital of MTN with almost 120,000 or over 120,000 individuals, shareholders and over 2000 &#x2013; 200 groups or institutions.</p>
          <p>I think before I just delve into one or two things on the operational side, it is worth saying that we do work under a framework and this is really our framework. The starting block would most probably be segmentation; in the sense that if we get the segmentation right, and therefore really, really have a much deeper understanding of the people that we want to be our clients I think all those other blocks tend to fall into place.</p>
          <p>On South Africa just getting into the operational section of the presentation, let me first of all say that South Africa did exceptionally well. You will recall that in 2009 we had quite a rough year particularly the second half of the year. And it was really a combination of many things, reinvesting in the network, investing in new distribution chain, the RICA or SIM registration has started and so on. So there was quite a number of things that lined up to make life difficult for us. But I'm happy to say that South Africa did achieve a margin of 34%.</p>
          <p>We've had significant subscriber growth, particularly on the prepaid base, 36% market share. And postpaid growth was not as high and I think this is partly a reflection of what's happening in the broad economy. In the sense that high-end of the market seems to have evolved to lot of the hybrid products where you can switch between prepaid and postpaid.</p>
          <p>We stabilized the network. We had issues on outsourcing IT system. I am happy to say that that's been stabilized, as well. And of course there are number of things that we've done on the branding side that have helped not least of which was the World Cup, which gave MTN South Africa in high visibility.</p>
          <p>So at 18.8 million subs, it is much higher than the guidance that we'd given you in South Africa and I think we significantly outperformed that guidance.</p>
          <p>MTR as I mentioned earlier on Interconnect, we move from ZAR125 to ZAR0.89 the glide path is such that at March 2011 Interconnect we had ZAR0.73 we go to ZAR0.56 in March 2012 and then finally to the ZAR0.40 in March 2013. So I think that's something that's more or less has been resolved.</p>
          <p>I think still looking at South Africa on the ARPU side, I mentioned earlier that the prepaid ARPU has gone up a little. And that's largely because we are now having a certain part of that base on prepaid that is using the phone more at higher usage.</p>
          <p>But more importantly, I think those that churned out, you may recall that effectively almost like a big clean-up which gave us the poor numbers in 2009. I think we've got a far more resilient and solid base on prepaid now and that is also reflecting in the ARPU that we're seeing out of that prepaid unit.</p>
          <p>Postpaid, by and large we do have lower out-of-bundle use and that's impacted the postpaid ARPU.</p>
          <p>CapEx, this is consistent with the overall trend in the group. We did &#x2013; as you recall '07, '08, '09 do the catch-up CapEx on the network. Of course, that is now significantly much lower. In 2010 we put-up over 280 3G base stations and we now have the half the population on the 3G network.</p>
          <p>Of course, we do invest quite heavily in the fiber-optic rings, first of all the metropolitan rings and then the national rings and I think all of that has helped drive the data that we've seen.</p>
          <p>The other huge contributor to that increase in data is, of course, the smartphones. I think we've sold over 1.6 million smartphones and as people become far more &#x2013; have far more affinity for the phones and use applications and really utilize what these phones are actually meant for other than looking good. We're finding that that has helped and contributed quite a bit to data.</p>
          <p>Of course we did acquire, what was Verizon, which has now been renamed MTN Business Solutions. And we are getting momentum there. The only challenge has been, the huge almost 40% reduction in fixed line tariffs in the last year. But we do think it's quite an important integrated element of our strategy going forward.</p>
          <p>Nigeria, very solid news and operation here. We took almost 62% of the net adds in the last nine months. We've maintained market share at 52%. Again, I think segmentation here has played a very key role for us in terms of managing almost 38 million, 39 million subscribers including the quality of the network. I mean, we've done a promotion recently and that may have somewhat affected the quality in the last sort of few months. But, needless to say that the huge capacity that we've had has enabled us to maintain market share, it's a very, very decent service level.</p>
          <p>Brand remains strong, the upwind local currency was declined 10% which is expected as the penetration becomes heavier and heavier. A key feature of course is the on-net traffic in Nigeria which gives us huge flexibility in doing a lot of things that the competitors can't do.</p>
          <p>CapEx as I mentioned earlier, again still consistent with the trend almost half our CapEx. I should warn that depending on what happens in competition there's always a possibility of a slight tick-up in CapEx in Nigeria to ensure that we maintain market share for capacity and can compete quite robustly. But clearly and I think that would give approximate the kind of the numbers that we've had in the past.</p>
          <p>Here again we have 480 3G base stations, huge investment in transmission, and data quite a big opportunity in Nigeria, because as you saw from the earlier graphs data is only 5% of revenue. And 65% of that is actually SMS. But it's something that we need to work on. I know I said this last year, but I'm quite comfortable that as we get higher and higher penetration we'll shift quite a bit of our resources to exploiting that data opportunity.</p>
          <p>Ghana is really operation that has bucked the trend on CapEx. And it's very much as a result of the huge competition in Ghana. We've got five competitors and very strong competitors; we've got Vodafone, Millicom, Bharti and Globe to enter the market very soon. So we have had to ensure that as we did in Nigeria we've got sufficient capacity and coverage at a fairly acceptable level.</p>
          <p>We've been able to maintain market share by and large. Yes, we dropped from 55% to 53%, but I am sure you'd agree that in a five player market that was quite a sterling effort.</p>
          <p>And MTN zone, we've used that as a very competitive product that has allowed us to optimize the capacity that we have. The essence of that being that where we've got capacity and people cannot afford, we can always drop the prices in MTN Zone and actually fit the traffic on board. We've also put out quite a lot of loyalty programs and by and large the tariffs have become fairly stable.</p>
          <p>I mean one thing that I may have forgotten to say under regulatory and maybe I should mention it now is that there was a big concern about irrational competition. Certain competitors coming and really slashing tariffs and what impact that would have on MTN. I am happy to say that I think there is always a point of diminishing returns in anything, and I believe that one or two regulators have now come to the view that very, very low tariffs actually are counterproductive in terms of all the stakeholders because after all we all get taxed as well. So two regulators have actually come out, I think this is in the case of Ghana and Congo, and have put a floor beyond which operators cannot lower tariffs, and I think that's quite important development for us and we hope that it keeps things rational. So Ghana bucked the trend, but of course we're still getting momentum on data as well as Mobile Money.</p>
          <p>Iran, Iran performed very well. I mean on local currency basis, Iran had a 42% increase in revenue. Of course as I keep on saying it gets muted when you transfer it back to the rand, and has now reach 44% market share, and people just need to always put this into context this is all really essentially in 3.5 years.</p>
          <p>We are now at almost 30 million subscribers, and that's really 28% increase from the end of last year. We are using wider and wider electronic distribution. There is very, very tight control of cost and OpEx in Iran and that has helped achieve almost a 41% EBITDA margin for Iran. Now this is in spite of the 28% revenue share.</p>
          <p>So I think it does show you that the margins in the business and the way that the business has been conducted is quite rewarding.</p>
          <p>Again on net traffic here has played quite an important role. Tariffs have been fairly stable. ARPU has been fairly stable, $8 to $9. I think the only challenge in Iran in some respect has been coverage, in the sense that in certain cities, you actually get property and sold out the leases to put up base stations has been bit of a challenge, particularly in Esfahan and certain parts of North Tehran, which are very high market areas. And therefore have got huge potential to contribute to MTN Iran. So we're hoping that as time goes on, if we resolve that problem, that will come through the revenue in the fullness of time.</p>
          <p>Coverage is 77% of the population and 20% geographically and of course there's, in Iran people move quite a lot between the city and the rural areas. So the road coverage has had to be quite extensive. And as you can see we've got almost 6,000 kilometers coverage.</p>
          <p>We don't have a 3G license in Iran. So we have had to deal with WiMAX. And I think that center we created; I think we've got almost 160,000 customers. Some of the limitations come from the fact that we are limited in some areas on content also on speed, on what speeds we are able to put us there. But other than that, I think we are seeing progress in the data area and it's still a fraction of what we believe we can achieve as far as data.</p>
          <p>CapEx has also come down in Iran consistent with the trend. This was effectively the fastest rollout that the group has ever undertaken. And I think the model that we followed, which was really to effectively do a turnkey project on the sole arch has turned out to be the correct way to have gone.</p>
          <p>And again coming back to Syria again, the big issue here is, it's a managed market. Two players, so it's almost a duopoly, not managed by intention, but managed by regulation. And we have not invested as much as what we could have on capacity simply because we wanted to reach a stage where the BOT matter would have been resolved.</p>
          <p>But now that it has been, I think we're in a better position to create a capacity. I also believe that Syria is another area or country where the opportunity for data is quite significant.</p>
          <p>So, maybe just before I conclude the section and Nazir gets into some of the financial details and unpacking some of the financial statements and numbers. Let me say, Sudan, I know that we know people are aware that we have challenges in Sudan in terms of the operation. I'm also glad to say that we've seen quite a strong turnaround in the last quarter Q4. If it's sustained, I'm sure when the results are put out for the end of June; we should have fairly positive news to indicate there. Lot of dual SIMs in the market, but I think we have a management team that's very strong, reviewed contracts, reviewed distribution channels and so on. So we're on the up there.</p>
          <p>Afghanistan I think is fine, Yemen is fine. We have had security issues, most probably the biggest one today is Cordova, but again I am happy to say that we've taken all the necessary precautions for staff and assets and the operation continues to function well. We haven't seen a huge dip in revenue maybe 5% in January and we sincerely hope that issue will be resolved.</p>
          <p>I think so, to close the section maybe one can try and summarize it by saying that we really do believe that management has by and large tried to make the correct calls as far as getting to that EBITDA margin of 45% which involved many initiatives, many policies and essentially very, very tight budgets.</p>
          <p>Secondly, the issue of CapEx which has been absolutely central to this group, we think that we did make the right calls at the right time, in other words pressing the accelerator when we needed to and that was '07 to '09. And that's given us the capacity which has enabled us to compete quite robustly.</p>
          <p>However, the caution is, depending on what happens on the ground, in certain countries we may have to revisit the investment in terms of putting additional CapEx to ensure that we maintain market shares and maintain our position.</p>
          <p>I think thirdly the organic growth, most of these countries and I think Nazir has got some slides on that, have had very, very significant growth. I mean if you look at countries like Ghana, Nigeria after 10 years still have double digits revenue growth in local currency. Iran is exceptional in the sense that it's not as old, but still 42% is significant, South Africa, almost 16 years, 80% revenue growth. So, I think the underlying growth is very significant.</p>
          <p>M&amp;A we have given some direction here, to say, transformational, maybe not depending on what may come along, but we don't see that on the horizon. But where there is an opportunity to do regional consolidation, we should do that because if for instance you look at our footprint in West Africa, it's quite contiguous footprint and that is very helpful when we start doing roaming and other products.</p>
          <p>And then finally, on people, I did say that remains quite a competitive edge for us as a group. We do believe that we've got the resources that put us in good stead relative to the competitors.</p>
          <p>So thank you very much. This is my last presentation. Let me say it was really an honor and I appreciate having to do this for almost 10 years and I appreciated your support. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, all. Special welcome to Chairman of the Group Board, Members of MTN Group Board, Members of the Executive Committee of MTN, our colleagues, friends as well as the members of the audience and honored guests. As Phuthuma said, it's my responsibility to unpack the numbers, makes me sound little bit like a grocer, but anyway I'll do my best.</p>
          <p>I will not dwell in market conditions; I believe Phuthuma has covered those in quite enough detail. I'd just go straight to the actual numbers. We've got a three year comparison here. And I think the important numbers to reflect on, apologies, important number to reflect on really, I seem to have trouble with the technology every presentation.</p>
          <p>Important number to reflect on a revenue basis is 115 billion that we are reporting based on current FX. The expansion in margin from 46.1 billion to 50.5 billion, and I guess a key feature of the results really is the expansion in margin that Phuthuma reflected on quite a few times during his discussion. Most of that is driven clearly by the margin expansion as well as the lower CapEx spend.</p>
          <p>What we've tried to do on this slide is really talk about two things. One is reported ZAR numbers and secondly, and that's the column around organic just to reflect the local currency performance, which you believe is extremely promising and satisfactory based on the performance especially in the key markets in which we operated.</p>
          <p>The EBITDA margin to a large extent &#x2013; the expansion has been driven by two things; one is the margin expansion in key countries like South Africa as was mentioned earlier; Nigeria as well as in Iran and given though that those particular countries have the highest rate in the group -- to group contribution, we see that benefit coming through on the EBITDA line.</p>
          <p>The second item is we talked about several key cost efficiency, and cost optimization initiatives. A number of that continues, and we believe will continue to drive benefit for the group as a whole. And clearly with the ongoing tariff pressure that we see from competition in most of these markets, it does become quite a key initiative of how it's going forward.</p>
          <p>Again, with the buildup in cash, and the signal we provided to the market based on a new strategy as far as payout is concerned, we are now fairly comfortable in payout -- paying out a dividend of 55% for the full year earnings, and which basically takes the yield, the dividend yield up to 4%, which is quite a significant increase from where we were about a year ago.</p>
          <p>I should caution that these numbers that you are looking at are not statutory numbers. In other words, we have excluded the Zakhele impact. Well, obviously for statutory boarding purposes, you will see the Zakhele numbers, But I think for ease of understanding the operational performance, we have excluded the Zakhele numbers.</p>
          <p>The total Zakhele number of 2.9 billion is comprised of four different portions, and that number basically is effectively 2.9 billion, which is included on EBITDA. So when you look at the previous slide, the EBITDA number without Zakhele would be in the region of 40%, right, so that's quite a significant shift.</p>
          <p>One number you might see that is slightly different, these are Notional vendor finance. When we initially made the announcement that number was about ZAR900 million, right. And given that it was actually at a time with -- when the share was trading at a ZAR107 between that date and closing the share had moved off, I think to about ZAR124, which pretty much accounts for that particular difference.</p>
          <p>Those are effectively treasury shares, and they are therefore not taken into account in the calculation of either earnings per share or the dividend. The remaining numbers are as they are. The only one that has a cash impact is the transaction cost of ZAR126 million.</p>
          <p>Trading conditions we have talked about in quite detail. Again, a key feature of the results as you know we've taken the headwind as Phuthuma said in a year where the rand is remained relatively strong, particularly in the second half of the year, whereas the underlying currencies of the key countries where we operate, the rand has remained relatively stable. But I have a chart which will actually show you what the cross rate impact is, and how that is impacted our important result.</p>
          <p>On the regulatory side, we have seen in our MTR changes. The reason they are significant on the financial side is that they have impacted both revenue and -- interconnect revenues as well as interconnect cost. And I've have had a mean -- meaningful impact in some countries, where these were key feature of the trading conditions.</p>
          <p>Change in ownership, again just for the accountants, there is a number of them I see sitting out here. Zambia shareholding has been reduced from 97 to 90. They're transferring the ownership of some of the shares in to an SPV which is pursuant to an obligation under the license conditions. However for accounting purposes, we still consolidate 97% or 97.8%.</p>
          <p>The Afghanistan shareholding is reduced from 100% to 90.9% and that's based on an agreement we had earlier when the license was first put into place during the invest cum-days for getting some support from financing from IFC -- from the IFC. So that has been completed. There was also some capital restructuring that took place during the course of the year, which the IFC participated in.</p>
          <p>The Cyprus shareholding, again pursuant a joint venture -- joint venture shareholding arrangement, which was put into place when we sold off shares to the Shacolas Group. It was a 1% share outstanding, which needed to be transferred due to some inter-group arrangements, which have now been completed or put into place.</p>
          <p>Put options, again, this is one that's drive significant volatility as we've seen in past years results. On the MTN reported result. This year they have literally a negligible impact, but in looking at the year-on-year results, you will find that last year we had a put option credit of close to ZAR900 million, this year it's almost close to neutral at ZAR22 million.</p>
          <p>On the taxation side, we've seen a creep up in the tax charge to about 36.3%, which as you will see is a little higher, I will unpack that as we go forward. Again to talk about the FX which is clearly the one that drives the overall results that we reported and the points to note here are the following.</p>
          <p>The top section is really the U.S. dollar local currency performance of the key currency that we</p>
          <p>operate in the Iran's, Nigeria's, and Ghana's of this world. The top line in yellow is the Rial right and you will see over the year just the marginal decline of about 4% against the dollar.</p>
          <p>The Naira at the same remains relatively stable between 149 and 151. These are the half year numbers that you would have seen at the half year results presentation and that's the full year number.</p>
          <p>The third one is basically the ZAR and as you see that basically over the year, particularly in the second half of the year improved to about 12%. Lastly, the Cedi remained relatively stable against the dollar as well at 1%. Please keep in mind that these are average exchange rates, these are not year-end exchange rates or month end exchange rates.</p>
          <p>Where this becomes really interesting is when we look at the cross rates clearly as a result of those movements. So looking at it on a year-to-year basis, the Rial declined 1195 to 1401 which is effectively a 17% weakening and just talks to some of the comments that Phuthuma made earlier, but even though we had -- despite the very, very significant organic growth increases the ZAR reported results are clearly dampened by this effect.</p>
          <p>Similar story for the Naira at 16%, and for the Cedi at 18%, so, clearly the rand strengthen the volatility of the rand has had a significant impact on the numbers.</p>
          <p>Again looking at the revenue story, we look at what we talked about, the most important message being on a local currency basis we see very strong local, at least organic growth. So, Nigeria key market 16% translated to ZAR only 1%, RSA 8% of course that's all in rand. Iran 42% coming down to 21%, Ghana 14% coming down to almost 0%, almost no benefit coming through on the ZAR reported results.</p>
          <p>One point to make here is both Nigeria and RSA obviously have shown these increases in revenue despite the impact of MTR changes. So, Nigeria would have had a cut in interconnect rates, which came into effect on the 1st of January 2010 where the rates dropped from 11.8 Naira to 8.2 Naira, Absent that, the local currency increase year-on-year would have been about 18%.</p>
          <p>On the RSA side that number, standard correction would be about 11% higher year-on-year, which is quite a significant performance. Again, we'll go back into those in a little bit more detail later.</p>
          <p>Just some key points, Nigeria share of net-adds, just more than 60%, which is quite a significant achievement we believe, and remained relatively strong throughout the year. We saw a significant growth in pre-paid. I believe the year-on-year increase in pre-paid revenue for South Africa, stand to correction I know the members of the South African audience here.</p>
          <p>But very pleasingly about &#x2013; just above 20% and also very strong data revenue growth as we talked about earlier at about 50%, and these are clearly a significant turnaround from the performances we saw in the previous year. One of the features of that will also impact, I think our margin performance, which I'll talk about a little later.</p>
          <p>Iran's growth basically driven by the fact that we just continue growing subscribers very, very aggressively, and we've taken close to half a net ads in the market over the course of the year. And strong growth in data and SMS, and as we've shown in an earlier slide, we saw data and SMS revenue at a total of about 20% of reported revenues flow in local currency.</p>
          <p>Just looking at the data revenue story and here we &#x2013; we'll go back and just talk about one thing here. On the revenue side, again the constant currency story, if we had reported revenues on a constant currency basis and that's really using the average exchange rates for 2009, which I had shown you on the previous slide. Revenues would have been about 14% higher, 127 billion. We are reporting 114 billion. So, effectively the dampening effect of the rand on reported revenues for the year is about a negative 11%. Right? So, something to keep in mind.</p>
          <p>On the data side, we haven't done anything on constant currency but you'll see the strong growth in data revenues from 2009 to 2010 for the group overall, growth of about 48%, largely driven by two countries, which is South Africa as well as MTN business in South Africa. Two pieces here, I think if you try to do a comparison of that first column to last year, one of the differences I should just highlight is that ZAR 0.9 billion for MTN business was included in other revenue &#x2013; other data revenue last year. So this year we've actually put it out closer.</p>
          <p>We've seen quite a significant uptake in terms of share of new business for the MTN business side of South Africa. However, one of the things we've had to deal with is the actual access pricing in the market for that segment of the business has declined by about 40%. Margins have recovered in the second half and we are hopeful that activity will continue at that level, given the fact that we'll start lowering, I guess, some of our infrastructure costs as we go forward.</p>
          <p>On the mobile data side, very, very strong expansion, but we know this is a very competitive market. We do have some pricing issues, I guess, relative to some parts of the competition, which I know Karel (Karel Pienaar, MTN's CIO) is addressing and he has promised a huge explosion for us next year.</p>
          <p>But anyway, a very pleasing story, and I think if you look, I should also point out that data revenue here excludes SMS, right. So, the big numbers we're really looking at in South Africa is about 12% excluding SMS. In Nigeria, as Phuthuma pointed out, still very, very low, probably about 1 or 2 points of the 5% that was mentioned, which translates into a huge opportunity as we go forward.</p>
          <p>The Interconnect story. This is a group number, and I think all we have tried to do is to show you the impact which is largely driven by the changes in Nigeria and South Africa on a group basis. So what you see on the top here for 2009 is the revenue story and effectively the revenue has gone down from 2009 revenues, we had ZAR 19.5 billion, 2010 revenues at ZAR 17 billion.</p>
          <p>But obviously two things, I think without suggesting that we've done things differently, one of the key features in South Africa's result is the fact that through all the programs they've put into place, they have managed to drive the significant part of the traffic on-net. And I think that's just a function of how well I think the company has done through all its tariff promotions et cetera, in terms of moving, I stand to correction, I believe the on-net traffic and pre-paid is as high as 70%, but we can confirm that with Zinnaid and his South African team.</p>
          <p>But what that effectively has helped us do is, together with the Interconnect rate reduction, is reduce the overall cost of Interconnect. And as Phuthuma mentioned earlier, despite the fairly significant drop in overall revenue in terms of volume, or in rands, of about ZAR 2.5 billion, we've been able to offset that by a slightly larger drop in Interconnect costs, leading to margin expansion for the group overall.</p>
          <p>Looking at just purely the South Africa results, that has obviously contributed to fairly significant shift in year-on-year gross margins and ultimately EBITDA margins as well. In Nigeria's case we've seen a similar impact as well, as on-net traffic has moved from 79% to about 82% over the year.</p>
          <p>EBITDA overall, again we talked about it moving from ZAR 46.1 billion to ZAR 50.5 billion, so very nice margin expansion, largely driven by these four countries: Nigeria was up in local currency by 24%, South Africa 17%, Iran 67% and Ghana 13%. And I think ultimately this reflects just a philosophy which we've tried to embed in the group over the course of the year, where we push all the local operating companies throughout the group to drive revenue growth at a significantly higher rate of growth than the underlying OpEx growth or costs of sales. And that's something that we start seeing coming through more and more consistently throughout all the operations.</p>
          <p>Behind that, as was pointed out earlier, a number of costs optimization and cost efficiency programs which either come through from outsourcing, lower maintenance, a lot more significant discussions with vendors in terms of lowering maintenance costs. I see some vendors sitting here, they will continue the subject of driving those costs down.</p>
          <p>In any case, EBITDA on a constant currency basis would have moved from ZAR 46.1 billion in 2009 to about ZAR 56.7 billion if we had used prior year effects, which is an expansion of about 23%. On a reported basis down to 50.5, so the ZAR has declined reported revenues, or diluted them by about 13%, which is quite a significant number.</p>
          <p>Nigeria margins for the year expanded, again largely in the back of some of the Interconnect margin uptick or margin adjustment, as well as some strong cost efficiency programs in various areas of the business, driving margins up to close to 63%. RSA recovered to about 34%, which is something we've been quite used to seeing in the past, and Karel is setting a tough, quite a stiff target, which I'm not going to give up, because it might come out as a prospect for the future anyway.</p>
          <p>Iran also moved up by about 6 percentage points from 35% to 41%, a lot of that was driven by the expansion and the economies of scale, so expansion on the revenue side, but also some fairly significant and successful discussions in terms of reducing the supplies to reduce transmission costs, keeping advertising, marketing and promotion spend at a lower rate that was the case in 2009, and also reducing the cost of recharge cards in the business. Ghana improved by about  13% in local currency, in ZAR terms, however, it declined by about 4%.</p>
          <p>So, overall a very, very good story. And clearly as Phuthuma mentioned earlier, getting that margin up by almost a full three points year-on-year was quite a pleasing result for the group, driving both the cash flow, incremental cash flow, as well as and supporting the cash flow generation from lower CapEx spend as well.</p>
          <p>Just looking at the margin overall, I have talked about how the group margin expanded, but if you look at it in a weighted average basis, you've got Nigeria driving about a 1.1% year-on-year increase, RSA about 0.7%, Iran contributing about four-tenths of a point, Ghana roughly flat and all the other countries, which have gone up by about 1.3 points, moving to 44.5%. If anyone has time, we'll explain how we do the currency impact here, but I'm not going to bore you with that detail.</p>
          <p>On a reported basis, a very, very nice expansion. I've talked about these, so Nigeria has gone up to 63%, RSA has gone up here based on the strong revenue growth, especially on the prepaid side, moving a lot of the traffic on-net and then all obviously there has been a significant push by the team to move a lot of the distribution of one handsets et cetera through all distribution channels like Cell Place and that has helped us to actually reduce the amount of commission we pay into it &#x2013; we used to pay into the channel. Iran, I've talked about single-vendor maintenance, reducing the marketing costs. Ghana actually lost slightly on the margin side. Again we saw higher utility cost coming through, as well as some increased maintenance cost to actually improve the quality of the network.</p>
          <p>I think Phuthuma has referred to this, so we had good performance in Afghanistan, Syria and Zambia. Sudan, while it sits in &#x2013; in a column where margins have deteriorated, we &#x2013; again as Phuthuma suggested, we firmly believe that we've got that operation back on track, and we've seen, certainly in the last quarter and the early &#x2013; the signs in early 2011 seem to be a lot more promising, both in terms of getting quality subscribers back onto the network, reducing the cost base of the operation, and then completing the distribution issues that we were dealing with, as well as the coverage issues that we were dealing with, which we all believe will help us to actually grow market share and grow that business to where we think it should be.</p>
          <p>Cameroon has gone backwards, and I think most of you might have read, at least on the analyst side, the report that was sent out comparing Orange results for Cameroon and Ivory Coast. We do concede that in Cameroon we have lost both &#x2013; not lost, we've grown our revenue base as well as our subscriber base at a lower rate than Orange have done over the last year. We've seen this sort of cycle as you know over the last three, four years, where in one year we do better than them, then they come back at us, and I guess 2011 is the year we would plan to recover. One of the other features, however, of Cameroon is we did go through the cycle of disconnecting subscribers, which was kind of not forecasted. We thought we had a whole lot more time, but then due to security concerns in the country, the whole market being affected, we were forced to disconnect up to about 1.5 million subscribers. We recovered probably about 50% of them since the November disconnections, but there are another 50% still sitting out there somewhere.</p>
          <p>The CapEx story we've talked about again. Not a surprise given the fact that we've announced and had been talking a lot about 2009 being a key CapEx year, and that dropping down to about ZAR 19.5 billion. Again FX has helped us a little bit here, net number of ZAR 2.3 billion, which is basically due to the lower average rates than we expected to spend or we provided guidance on, has helped us reduce the cost of CapEx from ZAR 31.2 billion down to the ZAR 19.5 billion.</p>
          <p>Again there are reductions in CapEx rollout as well as on the core, as well as site building, places like Nigeria, South Africa, we've put the canvas on them. And Karel keeps asking us for more money, but anyway they did &#x2013; I think spent a fair amount of money in terms of new switch facilities on a regional basis for the country, as well as on the transmission side. I think one of the things that has been delayed here is the fiber rollout, where I believe there are some logistical issues, and we will probably go on a little bit longer than originally anticipated.</p>
          <p>Iran, again as Phuthuma I mentioned, a fair amount of focus in terms of completing the coverage and the capacity issues that we are dealing with in the key cities. And we've seen the benefit of that come through in stronger ARPUs, a higher revenue growth and customers staying longer on the network.</p>
          <p>CapEx guidance, again we're not spending too much of time. We have planned to spend a little bit more money in Nigeria than last year. Again, that's to do some coverage but there is a fair amount of capacity investments coming through here. And I think it's fair to say that during the course of 2010, as I indicated earlier, we took more than about 62% of the net adds in the market, which is more than we had planned for. And clearly we need to put more capacity into the network to get, I guess, just the reasonable levels of comfort on the net &#x2013; on our headroom on the network that we would be comfortable with.</p>
          <p>For the rest of them, I think, more or less the same as last year. A bit of that increase is also related to the fact that the average rate that we've assumed is 742 to the dollar between the ZAR and the dollar, and of course that number will change as we go into next year.</p>
          <p>EBITDA minus CapEx, again a very nice story. So fairly strong cash conversion as was alluded to earlier, so improving from ZAR 14.9 billion in 2009 to about ZAR 31 billion this year, again an impact from FX that we've talked about previously. The interest charge, lower significantly, ZAR 5.8 billion to  ZAR 4.2 billion, largely driven by the fact that we did some capital restructuring that we did talk about earlier in the year and that helped us reduce functional currency losses from ZAR 3.2 billion to about ZAR 1.2 billion. Most of that functional currency loss is actually due to cash, U.S. dollar cash that's sitting on one of our holding companies, which is for functional currency purposes is a ZAR-reporting entity. Unfortunately, with the rand strengthening quite as much as it did in the second half of the year, economically it just didn't make sense to bring some of that cash back.</p>
          <p>The put option credit, as I mentioned earlier, net-net you know it's quite a significant change and that also has an impact, and what I'll talk about here, that affected pre-tax income last year. So that credit is basically absent this year, helping drive some of that effective tax rate higher than we saw previously.</p>
          <p>Forex loss is pretty much the same as they were last year. Net interest paid, slightly lower, despite the fact that we went up and geared a few more of the operations, refinanced in Nigeria. We saw some tightening of interest rates which came through as a benefit. On the tax side, charge moved up from ZAR 8.6 billion to ZAR 11.3 billion, a high deferred tax charge based on the significant spend on CapEx in the prior year and again the functional currency impact on the Iran loans.</p>
          <p>The other one-time items that we see coming through, a lower investment allowance in Nigeria, again as a result of lower spend, additional STC on the interim dividend. So here we have the impact of one STC. Here we have two dividend payments and that's made an impact. And then of course the put option credit impact on pre-tax income really is due to the deferred tax credit which is no more there.</p>
          <p>Adjusted HEPS, so on a comparative basis 2008 looks very high, ZAR 904 cents, but keep in mind we were the beneficiaries of a very weak rand on the reported results. Here in 2010, clearly a very strong rand, but EPS growing, and again these are excluding Zakhele, by a nice 20.5% on an adjusted headline earnings basis.</p>
          <p>Included in there is property, plant and equipment as well as the gain that we make on the sale of the <mark type="inaudible" /> which we disposed of last year, and that gain will be recognized for accounting purposes over a five-year period, so we reverse that out. Other property, plant and equipment and of course the put option in respective subs, those adjustments that you are quite familiar with. So overall, a very nice increase in adjusted headline earnings per share of 20.5%.</p>
          <p>On the net debt side, we've talked about this and you saw that in Phuthuma's presentation, net cash positive at the end of December of ZAR 0.9 billion. Gross debt of ZAR 35 billion, most of which sits in South Africa and the holding companies, that's it in  Iran, am I right Debbie (Debbie Millar, corporate finance), 29%? And other. On the cash side, 49%, it's a little bit of a mismatch, but we have geared up a lot of the op costs. And we talked about debt, about ZAR 2.3 billion of non-recourse debt in the underlying op costs.</p>
          <p>What we could talk about here is some of this cash sits in Syria, <mark type="inaudible" />.  We will utilize most of that cash for funding the conversion of the BOT license. And current regulations are such that with the new conversion, the license, as well as some changes in local legislation, we are hopeful that 2009 and 2010, as well as any future retained earnings, will now be available for distribution as dividends to the group. And that's something we haven't had the benefit of up till now.</p>
          <p>On the Iran side, a fair amount of cash that's actually trapped here in Iran. As you'll recall we brought in about $200 million earlier in the year and we continue working on that to upstream that cash. But there is a significant cash build up and we expect as we go forward with the Iran business performing as it does, it will continue to provide clearly strong free cash flow.</p>
          <p>And Debbie, anything else to mention? I think we've covered it. For the accountants, something in tables, and I think the only feature here is to talk about 2010, which we've shown in the presentation, which excluded the Zakhele numbers and including the Zakhele numbers, apologies, I said 40% previously its actually 41.5%, if you exclude Zakhele. And you'll see most of that charge, or all of the charges taken through on the EBITDA line, so on a statutory basis, the numbers you will see are ZAR 47.5 billion. And keep in mind that the only cash impact of that is the ZAR 126 million.</p>
          <p>Nothing else that's we haven't really talked about so I'll move on. Balance sheet, again, very heavily impacted by the year-end closing rate. The rand closed at 661 at the end of December that's had a fairly significant impact in all these reported numbers.</p>
          <p>Again the most important feature here to consider, bank balance is up ZAR 36 billion, borrowings of ZAR 24 billion and interest bearing liabilities up ZAR 10.5 billion. On a net-net basis, net debt is ZAR 0.9 billion. Net debt to EBITDA is now a positive number. Therefore, we feel fairly comfortable with the dividend payout.</p>
          <p>On the cash flow side again, very, very strong cash flow generation. Cash generated by operations is roughly flat despite the strong rand and looking at that key number in a net cash positive of about ZAR 20 billion compared to about ZAR 6 billion the year before.</p>
          <p>Intangible assets are basically the expenses that are for the purchase of software in the group, coming down a little bit year-on-year. Other investing activities, this is the cash we brought back from Iran earlier in the year the ZAR 3.5 billion really was an outflow last year and relates to the acquisition of Verizon Cell Place and a very high level of prepayments in the prior year. And that concludes the presentation. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Phuthuma and thank you Nazir. Now I call upon our Chairman Mr. Cyril Ramaphosa to address us. Mr. Chairman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Rich. I welcome all of you and especially the members of the group board and indeed the other subsidiary boards, but most especially the executive team as led by Phuthuma Nhleko. And today I really rise, I don't often speak on these occasions. I really rise to pay special tribute to our CEO and president, Phuthuma Nhleko, who as you heard and as you know, will be leaving us and going to other greater things we hope. Today was his last presentation. And I think you all join me in congratulating Phuthuma and the executive management team for these excellent results.</p>
          <p>The performance as it was presented to the board yesterday looked really outstanding to us, and I am sure all of you will confirm that as well. It's largely been due to a wonderful performance and the dedication that we've had from Phuthuma Nhleko as he has led this company as the CEO for close up to 10 years. We paid tribute to him and are sad that he is leaving. But thank him for this great achievement.</p>
          <p>There is a slide here which in a way tells Phuthuma's story in graphic terms. He initially joined the company as a non-executive chairman and from being non-executive chairman he was then appointed the chief executive. At some stage, I thought that his hope for non-executive chairman, but the more I thought about it and the work that is involved as a lazy person I said, no, I don't think there is hope for me in this type of work. What he did achieve obviously together with a number of other people in the company, various other executives, is to take MTN from what it was in the year 2000 as you see over there.</p>
          <p>Year 2000, we had five operations and by year 2005, we had 11 and by 2010, 21 operations. But what is most telling is that this company that was born in this country started to explode beyond the borders of South Africa and started addressing a market of 552 million people. Half a billion. And if you take that Africa is almost a billion people, it is addressing a market, which is half the size of the population of Africa. And the market cap as you clearly see in that slide has risen ZAR 253 billion.</p>
          <p>Now if you think a little bit and reflect back to a number of companies that we have on our stock exchange. And look at their market cap and look at the time it has taken them to reach the level where they are, if you look at the top five, you'll find that MTN is clearly the baby in the pack. It is the youngest, the newest and it is the one company that even from the beginning started going beyond the borders of its own home market. The revenue has grown from ZAR 6 billion to ZAR 115 billion, today as Nazir was reporting. The EBITDA has also grown from a mere 2 to 50.5, but what is more telling is that the subscribers, the subscribers have grown to 142 million.</p>
          <p>Now, if you begin to think about what 152 million subscribers that you're providing a service, you're connected to 142 million almost on a daily basis. This is phenomenal. And this has happened due to the work that has been done by Phuthuma and indeed the other executives. And I thought quite a bit what it is that drove this man to the level of performance that he has given your company, this company. And as I thought a little bit, I arrived at 10 attributes. The one was that as he came in as the non-executive chairman and was catapulted to the position of chief executive.</p>
          <p>Some of us who sat near the ring side seats of this arena that he was performing on could see that a vision was developing. He had a vision and became quite a visionary person and in the end a visionary leader. And this is what he was able to give this company.</p>
          <p>Focus. Being focused was one of the attributes that some of us saw, and then I think indeed the performance speaks for itself. The one other important one which many of us who have worked with Phuthuma that we saw was that there was an element, a huge element of hard work. Hard work and driving himself consistently and persistently on an ongoing basis. I had some people, who are doing some work for me, I digress a bit and the one guy who was supposed to do this work during the day decided that he was just too tired and he wanted to sleep. And he went and slept under a tree and it happens to be in the place where there are snakes and dangerous animals. And I said some people do take quite serious risks to indulge in their leisure to sleep and not to work. Fortunately, we didn't have that with Phuthuma. He didn't sleep in dangerous places, so he remained focused and he worked hard.</p>
          <p>And the other important attribute is that he was able to build a good team. A good team of people around him, and I think you can all see that MTN is well endowed with good people. We have good people in MTN. They work hard, they are focused. One of our Directors was commenting yesterday as they came into the building, they said, this is a phenomenal achievement. Here we have people in this huge building who are going around like ants. Ants don't sleep on the job, they work, and this is what we have in MTN. And this is largely due to the leadership that Phuthuma has given to this company, that he has built a really good team of people around him who work hard.</p>
          <p>The other important thing of course which I think many of us saw, was that Phuthuma has had a good appetite for taking calculated risks. He was able to take us as a company to a number of markets where many people would have feared to go, and that's the mark of a good leader, to take calculated risks and I recall that each time at the Board level he would come with proposals together with his other executives, and sometimes we would think that this guy needs to have his head read. But as he outlined the proposals of why we should go into various countries, Iran and all that, in the end we saw good sense with all of that.</p>
          <p>Resilience was one of the important attributes, even as sometimes we've faced setbacks and some failures with some of the transactions that we wanted to conclude, as you well know, Phuthuma and his executives kept going forward. Each time there was a setback they would come back with a new one. And that is an important attribute in a leader.</p>
          <p>And the one other important one, which underpins Phuthuma's character, is doing things in an excellent manner. Excellence has underpinned nearly everything that he has done for us as a company and we thank him for that. The last two attributes that really belong to him as a person, honesty, he has been very honest in the way that he has dealt with the Board and the way that he has dealt with his other colleagues, and that for us has been a very, very important attribute.</p>
          <p>But the most important and the one that I like most is that is he is a modest person. He has been a CEO who has led his troops, his colleagues with a great deal of modesty. No razzmatazz, no flashiness, but really modest. And in pay attributes to him and urging him to continue throughout his life with modesty, I have decided that we're going to give him a modest gift. I am going to give him a modest gift, Phuthuma as you well know loves beautiful ties like me, but this is a very nice MTN tie, a bit on the modest side. I don't even know who makes this tie, it's one of those, wondering the name. The modest tie and we would like him to wear this tie, Phuthuma, I don't know how often you should wear it, the quality is modest, quite modest. Rather I'd like to give in this tie and urge him to wear it at the very least Monday morning.</p>
          <p>So, Phuthuma, we thank you for the great work that you have performed for our company, for shareholders, for increasing shareholder value in probably one of the most exponential ways. And it is good, it is good for me, I'll put to this pin in. It is good that we've had &#x2013; and this has never really been a key issue, but it was good we've had a Black CEO who has performed so well in the new South Africa and has grown a company like MTN which today has become a Continental Giant. You might have read that MTN is the most recognized brand today on the African continent and bigger than other global brands. So we are happy about that and thank you very much Phuthuma for having done that for us.</p>
          <p>It is now my pleasure to introduce to you Sifiso Dabengwa, who is going to succeed Phuthuma Nhleko. Sifiso is probably known to most of you. He's been with the company for 12 years. He joined in 1999 as Managing Director of South Africa, MTN South Africa and as we were facing a number of challenges in Nigeria. Many of you will recall that when MTN decided to go to Nigeria there were a number of questions that were raised, whether we were mad or crazy or whatever.</p>
          <p>But nonetheless, we proceeded to enter the Nigerian market. And Sifiso was appointed Managing Director of MTN Nigeria and helped to shore up our operation there to stabilize it and to introduce the real MTN ethos and culture and high performance in the operations in Nigeria. And we are grateful for Sifiso for having led the Nigerian operation and having put it on a really good and firm footing. The performance that we're getting out of Nigeria is largely due to what Sifiso helped to do for us there. And in 2006, he was appointed Chief Operating Officer and in that role worked very closely with Phuthuma and the two of them have helped to build this company to the level where it is today.</p>
          <p>So Sifiso is an old hand. He knows the company, he knows the culture of our company, he knows how it works, he knows how it functions and he knows the challenges that MTN faces as it moves forward. And during the course of time he has also been able to developed and build a vision and it was for this reason that the Board decided that we should appoint Sifiso Dabengwa as the group CEO and President going forward. We're really excited that there has been a change of the guard or there will be a change of the guard at the end of the month. And Phuthuma will be handing over his batten to Sifiso and we expect that Sifiso will take that batten and run ahead.</p>
          <p>He's worked previously in a number of other roles but more importantly he worked at Eskom, and he &#x2013; as an engineer was deeply involved in the electrification process and distribution process for electricity that has happened in our country. Trained as an engineer electrical, the most dangerous part of engineering that you and I don't want to get close to, because we'd get electrocuted, he devilled in all that. He's a risk taker, and we hope he takes calculated risks. And he's got an MBA degree and it is my pleasure to introduce Sifiso Dabengwa to you. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Chairman. Members of the board, colleagues, ladies and gentlemen, a very good morning to you all, and thank you for being with us. Looking at the way forward, I guess the first thing that I'd like to highlight is the fact that in the short- to medium-term I do not see any significant strategic shifts and any significant changes in our strategic priorities. And I see that there will be strategic continuity in relation to some of the announcements that have already been made and also in relation to the vision and also making sure that we do increase returns to shareholders and also keep looking at opportunistic M&amp;A as already stated earlier on.</p>
          <p>I guess the important or the biggest area that we're going to focusing on in terms of growth and revenue opportunities is looking at the services side of the business. As indicated earlier on, the penetration in data in most of the countries that we operate in is still very low, lower than 10% in most of those countries.</p>
          <p>And it's a major opportunity for us to be able to deliver services in those areas in a manner that we fix a very well segmented approach and then also working with partners in developing new services and also developing applications. So I see a major opportunity for us going forward focusing on services that drive data across our footprint.</p>
          <p>We still also still have to continue with our optimizing operation efficiencies. This again is a continuation of what that has been started over the past few years. As Phuthuma indicated we have had a target of about 45% EBITDA margin and something that we're working towards and would like to continue to work towards it. Once you accept that in general the levels of competition have increased over the past two years, we have seen some significant impacts on pricing in some of the markets that we operate in, but we still have to face those challenges by continuing with some of the strategies, and some of the initiatives that we've implemented. So the issue of infrastructure sharing, as already mentioned, both passive and the fiber. And then also looking at, how exactly do we deliver services? By in large a lot of services have been developed in country. We are now looking at a model in which we should have a much more centralized method of delivering services although not necessarily centralized in one place, probably more in three or four places. And that will help reduce the cost of delivering services, but also at the same time shorten the time period, and hopefully contribute quite effectively as far as growths in revenue is concerned.</p>
          <p>Mention has already been made in terms of procurement and the centralization thereof. That's a process that's been started earlier on this year &#x2013; sorry late last year and continued into this year. We really anticipate that as we go forward the centralization of procurement activities and the nationalization of suppliers will contribute positively to our efficiency drive.</p>
          <p>Another initiative that was mentioned previously is the area of shared services; we have initiated a process of looking at sharing IT infrastructure in other words instead of having each operation have a fully-fledged IT infrastructure, the idea is that we will centralize some of the IT infrastructure in maybe to two or three countries, and then the other countries would be able to take advantage of the shared services. And we will continue looking at outsourcing opportunities and managed services.</p>
          <p>We have already implemented on a smaller scale. We are in the process of implementing managed services on the network side and hopefully we will be able to role that out in a number of operations.</p>
          <p>CapEx rollout has always been an important part of this business and over the years we've really improved our processes and the way that we decide on our investments. It's important for us to continue to make sure that we invest sufficiently to make sure that we are able to have network quality as a competitive edge. If one looks at some of the basic reasons of our success, the fact that we are able to provide good quality network has been the cornerstone to our success and we expect that that will continue going forward.</p>
          <p>The issue of shareholder returns is already been touched on, in the sense that we have increased the dividend payout now to 55% and from a regulatory point of view I see us continuing to engage with the different authorities and the different operations to make sure that we remain and be a positive contributor to social issues that face the different operations or the different countries that we operate in.</p>
          <p>If we just have a quick look at guidance of subscribers for this year, South Africa is about, we're looking at about 2 million net ads, Nigeria 4.2, which is slightly lower than last year. We believe that there could be an impact from the registration process, but if it doesn't impact too negatively that could go up. Ghana, we believe that the level and the intensity of competition will increase and hence the impact on the net adds.</p>
          <p>Iran also anticipates that there will be a third operator during the course of this year. And that will increase the expected levels of competition. And thus overall we expect to have net additions of about 17 million for 2011 at this stage. Obviously as thing has change in different markets and in different operations this could be impacted hopefully positively.</p>
          <p>The CapEx figure has already been shared with yourselves by Nazir. The chart on the right-hand side just give an indication of the areas in which the CapEx is to be spent. I just need to state that the Syria &#x2013; has it been corrected, yeah it looks okay. But that just gives you an indication of where and in which areas we anticipate the CapEx spend to take place. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Chairman for those very kind, generous words. What I would like to do now is to take some questions I think we've got about 10 minutes or so. I should point out that at the back of your presentation there is an annexure and we are not trying to as usual deprive you of your ability or right to ask questions. We're just saying that your questions may be quite detailed and there are quite of lot of numbers and figures and stats at the back of that. So if we can, I don't know if the mikes are on, but we can take questions, yeah. I think there's somebody at the back, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, it's a Martin from Macquarie. And just one quick question in terms of your current dividend outlook, you are sitting on cash obviously, previously, you have spoken about the target gearing ratio. Can you give us a sense of how you are thinking about payouts going forward? I mean obviously that 50, 55 is encouraging, but just going forward what's your senses around that? And then very briefly a second question if I may. Just on the impact potentially of higher diesel price on margins. I don't know if there is a sense you can give us of the sensitivities in terms of some of the operations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I think on the first question, firstly, I would have hoped that you would have been hugely encouraged, as opposed to being just encouraged. But let's put into context, I think as I said earlier that dividend policy and payout was really arrived at by considering a number of things. One M&amp;A, two where we are on CapEx in terms of it coming slightly downward. Thirdly, cash generation and then maybe fourth issue is really competition.</p>
          <p>And maybe fifth issue, which is most probably the answer to your question, is that, that number is then arrived at on the basis of us being very comfortable, or more specifically the board being very comfortable that it's a number that is very sustainable. Taking into consideration those five issues as well as cash upstream and that I think Nazir spoke about. So it will be reviewed from time to time, but we think that 55% is quite competitive even if you had two point markers against our peer group.</p>
          <p>I think the second question on diesel most probably, if we have to look at margins, the operation that will be largest impacted or the largest operation that is highest impacted by the diesel price would always be Nigeria. Nazir, I stand correction, but I think it's about maybe 6% of OpEx?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Four.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>4% of OpEx, so I think that is where most probably the biggest variable would be. Okay. I think there's a question here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Nicky Smith, Bloomberg News. Just with the Iran question, you said you don't have a 3G license. Can you just remind us whether you will be able to get one, and what the process is there?  And then secondly it follows from Martin's question with the dividend payout, does that mean it's going to be pegged at 55% for the foreseeable future? Or are you ruling out a progressive dividend policy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think the last one is the easiest one to answer. The answer is, no we're not saying it's pegged at 55% forever. All we're saying is 55%, given all the other variables and the circumstances in which we find ourselves from a trading perspective, is the number at which we feel very comfortable, that that is sustainable. But that does not preclude a revision in the future and I'm sure the board and management will look at it and will arrive at whatever the number is. I mean we're hedged in a reversal, not to say it can never happen, but it's on the basis that we avoided all cost of reversal. But progression may very well happen.</p>
          <p>As far as, I think the second question was on 3G in Iran. We don't have a 3G license in Iran. The third operator effectively has, which is why we have gone to WiMAX and there is nothing at the moment that allows us or says that we can have the 3G license. But clearly something that I think we, that management will continue to pursue, because that will put us in a much better position to exploit the data opportunity that I spoke about a bit earlier.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[question inaudible] (102:09)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>25 years, is it 25 years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's 20.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's 20. Okay. 20 is the right number, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Peter from RMB Morgan Stanley. I will limit myself to one question. But first let me just say Phuthuma, well done on your achievements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And then just moving to Nigeria, if you can help us there, you have indicated that you have seen aggressive competition increasing in Q4, can you just give us a sense of how things are going, if it's sort of gone in the first quarter of this year? And what are some of sort of the strategies you're using to defend your position there from a tariff point of view?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, look I mean we always try to avoid giving very forward looking statements, but I think Sifiso did touch on this. Even though we had a very, very, very strong 2010 and the number was 62% or 60% of net adds, without getting into detail, I think Q1 starting Q1, 2011 it's going to be a bit tougher in terms of the competition. I am sure you have seen quite a lot of write up about the competition gearing up in terms of capacity. So, the simple answer is Q1, 2011, we are not achieving that sort of level of net adds that we achieved in the last nine months of 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[question inaudible]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, tariffs, do you want to talk about tariffs, Nazir?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. I think most of the market is already there has been a lot of information put out. We put a tariff revision in place in September of last year, which was the first major adjustment we did in about three years. I think what was curious in the market that we saw activity from both Glo as well as EMT <mark type="inaudible" /> who came in with fairly aggressive price reduction in December.</p>
          <p>And I use the word curious simply because it makes the sort of key value month throughout the year. So, it does beg a few questions in terms of the overall strategy. I think what that has done is forced us to react as well as I think you've seen a reaction from Airtel as well. And we've gone out with a new value proposition that was introduced early in February.</p>
          <p>The early signs are promising. I think one of the key questions that we still need to understand through analysis as you go forward is the impact on elasticity and whether it's still driving in a meaningful revenue growth and has an impact on MOUs. I think we need to go through probably a full quarter or two before we get a proper sense of how the market's going to evolve.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, Yann Low from At Focus Securities Securities. My question revolves around infrastructure leasing. You've already had a relationship with American Tower in Ghana, can you just elaborate if you will continue with this relationship through other African operations or would you also consider other vendors such as Eaton Tower or Helios Towers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I think that the whole issue of leasing is really one that we started off and I'll let Sifiso add his view going forward. But the idea really was to first of all unlock the value in those towers. There are many permutations in which we could have adopted that. We could have followed quite a number of ways of really unlocking that value. But we started off on a process that effectively resulted in us ending up with ATC. And we said we're going to work with them strategically on it, starting with Ghana on a pilot project. And we will probably do a number of countries with them.</p>
          <p>I don't think that therefore that would mean that we're not going to do any work anywhere ever with other tower managers, so to speak, but it will vary from country to country and with the circumstances. So, I think that was the gist of your question, the gist of your question is will every single thing be ATC and nobody else. The answer is no. But we are saying we've started a strategic relationship with them, and of course we need to get to some sort of scale that is meaningful with them. But part of the process will always be evaluating the situation and talking to other tower vendors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>[Question Inaudible]</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It just depends. I mean we are going to take a pace. Sifiso do you want to answer the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I mean that's very much work in progress. The issue about going with ATC was that we did make a decision that we really needed a very well experienced and knowledgeable partner because the running of this infrastructure is critical for our business. And as Phuthuma says, yes, if we find another partner in for other operations, we would consider this, yes.</p>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Jonathan Kennedy-Good from Standard Bank Securities. Just I wonder if you can comment a little on the strategic rationale for the introduction of the International Board given the success that's been evident over the last while under the current management structures. And then also just on, you've done very well in terms of maintaining absolute EBITDA given declines in interconnect rates particularly in South Africa, do you think or could you give us a sense of where, how much EBITDA could fall off in the coming year, if on-net traffic doesn't move higher?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me try and answer the first question and then Nazir, you may well want to answer the second question on, if MTN are, what do you think that the EBITDA we've got from  the MTN, if that disappears, what would EBITDA fall to.</p>
          <p>Look, I think on the first question really, as we indicated in the release that we gave. This is an evaluation and it's an also I guess work-in-progress in the sense that we outlined a number of issues. I think the first one is to say as we always say, what has always worked will not necessarily always work going forward. So, I think people have to keep an open mind. But one element is of course recognizing that the capital structure of this group going forward will be one of the ways in which one can maintain value or return even more value to shareholders.</p>
          <p>Second issue is of course we're seeing quite a lot of growth in this company, but a bulk of it is now happening outside South Africa. And you always want to be structured in a manner that can take full advantage of the growth. And when I say capital structure here, I'm talking in a broad sense of the word including financial issues and what your balance sheet looks like and how efficient it is and so on.</p>
          <p>So, it's really saying, we're keeping an open mind to say how do we continue to achieve that growth, but also achieve it in a capital structure that is as efficient as we possibly can make it, both in people, both in external and international input and on the balance sheet. And there are no firm decisions on that, that's a progress that the board and management will continue to engage in.</p>
          <p>Nazir, do you want to answer the question on the deterioration in margin if MTR disappears?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think the question was if we're faced with a situation where we would not continue growing on-net traffic. I think if on-net traffic stabilizes at the level that we currently see, we ought not to see a dilution in traffic. I think the bigger danger really is competitors following an all-net strategy like Nigeria et cetera, which would force us to do the same. And therefore we'd end up in a situation where we move some of the traffic backwards. That I think is potentially a bigger deterrent.</p>
          <p>The things we're doing and Karel and his team I'm very aware of as well as in Nigeria where we potentially are mostly exposed is to follow very segmented value propositions which will make sure that we provide more value to the existing base to stay on our network as opposed to move off onto other networks. So that's really the key driving force of how we would like to manage that particular issue.</p>
          <p>I think on the margin story overall, however, I think we take a more holistic view. We've talked about a number of initiatives that we're putting into play not only to deal with a risk around margin dilution because of a change in the interconnect or on-net, off-net traffic mix. But it could come through just purely from pricing pressure that we see in every market. So, you know we've launched a number of different programs, whether they come through from infrastructure sharing. We did a fairly significant analysis or an exercise covering most of our large operations in the portfolio, which is based on an ABC type analysis and that's set up with a view to actually reducing and optimizing the cost base. We've got a lot of outsourcing that Sifiso talked about, outsourcing on the maintenance side, managed services et cetera. If you unpack all of these I think they are directed at one not only to try and generate incremental margin, but also protecting the potential dilution of margin as a result of tariff pressure or from the interconnect side as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Shall we take maybe two more questions and then we can close.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Tuma Johan from Renaissance. Well done on your results. And if I look at your Ghana CapEx guidance, 1.2 billion it seems quite low compared to 2010 actual. Do I read into that the savings due to TowerCo Ghana or how do I approach that number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you want to answer the question on the &#x2013; Sifiso, do you want to talk about the Ghana CapEx number as to why it would be lower than last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Last year's investment in Ghana was quite significant. In the way that we did the budget this year we had not taken the outsourcing process into consideration. It was just the actual requirements of the operation. But the last two years was quite significant, the CapEx that was put in.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think there is also some CapEx that didn't completely put in that will be flow...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>There was a large carryover from '09 to 2010.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay. Can we have the last question or one but last it looks like, yeah. So, the question seems to have vanished. Well, there is no last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well, once again I'd just like to thank everybody and a special thank you to the chairman and our board and once again for his very kind and generous words. The last 10 years was a huge team effort. One gets all the accolades, but really, the accolades really belong to the team and one was just honored to serve. Thank you very much. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>