<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1217083" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-08-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7867</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Christian Becker-Hussong, Head of Investor and Rating Agency Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Nikolaus von Bomhard, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">J&#xF6;rg Schneider, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Torsten Jeworrek, Corporate Underwriting/Global Clients</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="5">Michael Huttner</participant>
      <participant id="6">James Quin</participant>
      <participant id="7">Andrew Broadfield</participant>
      <participant id="8">William Hawkins</participant>
      <participant id="9">Will Morgan</participant>
      <participant id="10">Ben Cohen</participant>
      <participant id="11">Stephan Kalb</participant>
      <participant id="12">Jean-Francois Tremblay</participant>
      <participant id="13">Brian Shea</participant>
      <participant id="14">Fabrizio Croce</participant>
      <participant id="15">Thorsten Wenzel</participant>
      <participant id="16">Spencer Horgan</participant>
      <participant id="17">Paul Goodhind</participant>
      <participant id="18">Thomas Noack</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you. Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen, or rather good morning to those of you who listen from the U.S. Welcome to our Conference Call on the Second Quarter First Half Year 2009 Results. So thanks for joining us.</p>
          <p>Today's speakers are Nikolaus von Bomhard, CEO of Munich Re Group; J&#xF6;rg Schneider, our CFO; and Torsten Jeworrek, Head of Munich Re Reinsurance Group.</p>
          <p>As usual, there will be a presentation first; however, we will try to focus on the most relevant slides of the presentation in order to dedicate as much time as possible to the Q&amp;A session afterwards.</p>
          <p>Nikolaus will kick off with a brief overview, J&#xF6;rg will elaborate on the financials in more detail, Torsten is to provide an overview on the most recent developments in the Reinsurance business and the outcome of the July renewals, and finally Nikolaus will give an outlook.</p>
          <p>So far from my side, Nikolaus, the floor is yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you, Christian. Good morning and good afternoon to all of you. Yes, I'm on slide three, and I have only two slides to start it off.</p>
          <p>First of all, I would like to make the statement that we consider the first half year 2009 and the second quarter 2009 good quarters and good half years in terms of earnings strength. I make that point because it is not a one-time event. The numbers that we show, we return with these results to a good half as we see it. It's sustainable what we deliver and we have no backlog as regards accounting issues, no reclassification and no own debt that we accounted differently over the last two, three, four quarters, so nothing as a backlog so we start freshly into the new quarter each time.</p>
          <p>Well, of course, in view of the prevailing difficult economic environment, the results as we see them are quite pleasing and this is a consequence of a very well balanced portfolio of businesses and we've mentioned that on numerous occasions, a prudent risk management approach both paid off.</p>
          <p>Shareholders' equity, stable, against the year end 2008, slightly down only in the second quarter '09. And this, of course, is a consequence of the dividend that we paid out in the second quarter. We continue to prefer to deploy our capital and our capacity to business as such, be it insurance and reinsurance businesses or if the case allows that into small M&amp;A activity. But as you have seen over the last weeks not much came out of the pipeline because even though strategy may be right, pricing wasn't.</p>
          <p>We will not enhance our risk exposure on the asset side of the balance sheet. We continue to stick to our low risk investment strategy. This is a long term decision that will not be changed on short hand and the underwriting expertise of the Group should make the difference, so we try to create value on the liabilities side of the balance sheet.</p>
          <p>Now coming quickly to the business segments; Reinsurance performed satisfactorily. This is, as I mentioned earlier on, a consequence of a broadly diversified book that we have written over the years and we are and were able to digest even a few recession related major losses in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>The discipline that we have instilled into the organization and underwriting pays off, and we will continue to engage into a active cycle management.</p>
          <p>July renewals details will come from Torsten later on, confirmed a, I would call a selective market hardening mostly in high severity, low frequency risks.</p>
          <p>The financial strength of the Group is unquestioned and of course, allows us to pick up opportunities wherever they arise. I wish the market, of course, would harden on the broader scale.</p>
          <p>Primary Insurance was hit a little bit more strongly still in the second quarter and this has to do actually, if you take the entire half year actually, it has to do with the assets. But most of all it has to do with the way how we account. And as I said, we are relatively determined with our accounting. So if we feel that the business plan isn't holding up, we immediately write-down goodwill. This also hit Primary Insurance in the first quarter and it actually hit also our engagement in sterling in the second.</p>
          <p>At the same time, with the interest rates not falling too much in the first half of the year, of course, the hedges that we have in place to protect the Group against falling interest rates as regards the guarantees that we handed out in Life Primary, of course, did force us to write-down some of the derivatives. And that bit a hole partly at least into the result of our Primary Insurance entity.</p>
          <p>Non-Life in Primary continues to be performing stellarly. The results are good. We had it more of a difficult first quarter, but already in the second quarter we are back to what I would consider normal delivery. And therefore also as regards the entire year, we have no doubts whatsoever that the 95 combined ratio will be achieved.</p>
          <p>Primary Life keeps us a little bit on our toes, the reason being that we can't manage a swift turnaround. It is not easy in that kind of business.</p>
          <p>The hedging program that I mentioned earlier on as a burden in the first half year result of the Primary Group is in place and it will protect the Group and our shareholders against a still possible lower interest rate environment. So we consider that a decent investment that we made some time ago and that we roll on through the years.</p>
          <p>Of course, high on the list of our Primary Group is product innovation and an increased, better distribution and that, as I mentioned, this goes for Life in the first place.</p>
          <p>Overall, ERGO is doing a great job in cutting cost and a very important step was achieved by coming to terms and to an agreement with the Workers' Council on how to implement the cuts that were and are planned until the end of 2010 as regards the workforce.</p>
          <p>So far as to slide three and a quick run through only through slide four and this is the results -- an overview of the results. Well, as you can see, premiums did increase nicely and will continue to do so throughout the year. And I have to make the point here we are not interested in top line growth for on its own sake, it must be profitable business. So you can rest assured this growth is profitable growth.</p>
          <p>The combined ratio on Reinsurance did improve compared to last year. However, larger claims, recession related claims did increase the ratio in the second quarter. So overall in the first half of the year, even though it looks better than last year, we're not entirely happy, but we think it is within reasonable limits in view of the crisis.</p>
          <p>Primary Insurance, actually a contrarian trend, it looks worse than last year, but we should not forget that the last year was an extraordinarily good year in terms of combined ratio. So with the movement that I mentioned earlier on the back of second quarter of '09, we think we are on a good path to digest or to be able to digest what we consider to quite some extent winter-related burden in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>A short word on the investment result, of course, the regular income, as you can see on later slides, declined a little bit. However on the other hand, of course, we had much lower write-downs on securities, and that overall contributed to a higher return on investment of now 4%, a return that we could imagine to see throughout the entire year, which also in view of the crisis and our accounting practices is a decent return on investments.</p>
          <p>Well, the results both operating and consolidated to the very low right of the slide, look and are shorter compared to prior year results. This is a consequence of something I mentioned before. On the one hand, a little weaker technical result and also the weaker result due to what I would call proactive goodwill impairments. This is nothing that worries me a lot. It's just the fact that we have to show these, but through the year that should improve.</p>
          <p>Well, if I sum it up on the two first slides as well, I would say in view of challenging economic environment, we delivered a pleasing result. We are happy with that performance. We think we can do better throughout the rest of the year, a little better, of course, provided that things don't get worse in general, but so far so good.</p>
          <p>This was it from me. And now, I'll hand it over to J&#xF6;rg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Nikolaus. Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. I start on slide six. Our capitalization has always been rock solid. Sound according to all capital measures. Regulatory solvency capital ratio increased by some percentage points to 266%. We have a decent buffer according to rating agencies measured against the AA level. We have some 7 billion economic capital buffer in our internal model, so a very solid position.</p>
          <p>This has also been reflected externally by the very lower beta of our stock, the extremely low CDS spreads which are comparable only with the most solid governments of this world and a confirmation of the AA rating by all the agencies.</p>
          <p>This financial solidity is the basis of our distinctive business opportunities. It makes us resilient against a potential revival of the financial market turbulences and it creates scope for profitable growth, or for further capital repatriation, or to a limited extent also for both.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, seven, you see the development of the shareholders' equity on the left hand side, the development of the first half year on the right hand side; the numbers just for the second quarter. Shareholders' equity was stable despite 1.1 billion dividend payment and a small amount of share buybacks and despite the increased yields.</p>
          <p>The premium development is shown on slide eight. Premiums went up by 14.6% for the second quarter and by 9.8% for the first half year. One percentage point out of 10 is due to foreign exchange effects. The pound sterling and Canadian dollar were weak against the euro but the U.S. dollar, our most important foreign currency was rather strong.</p>
          <p>Equal amounts of 4.5% each were due to acquisitions and organic change. Organic growth was a lot due to capital release quota share treaties in Life and Health Reinsurance. And this is also responsible for the very strong growth which is shown on the left bottom side of that slide.</p>
          <p>In Life Reinsurance plus 23.6% and in Health even 76.6% due to mainly the quota share treaties and also the acquisition of Sterling Life in the Health Reinsurance segment. This &#x20AC;1.18 billion are two-thirds of Munich Health, our third pillar, which has up to now not been shown separately in our segment reporting. Another roughly 500 million is still included in Primary Health and this is the foreign subsidiaries of DKV, which have been combined with Reinsurance Health business.</p>
          <p>On slide nine, a look on the segment results. In the columns, left, operating result, and right, consolidated result. In the rows, the five segments and the consolidation effect.</p>
          <p>Reinsurance contributes strongly to Group results. The '08 numbers have to be adjusted for a dividend of 947 million from ERGO to the Reinsurer Munich Re AG, 180 million for Life and Health, and 767 million for Non-Life.</p>
          <p>On an adjusted basis, the operating results went up in 2009 by 7.7% for Life and Health, and 24% for Property-Casualty.</p>
          <p>Primary Insurance shows low numbers for the first half, Nikolaus has already mentioned it. But we saw a decent recovery in the second quarter with operating results of 37 million for Life, 49 for Health and 129 for Property-Casualty Primary Insurance business.</p>
          <p>Moving to the investment result on slide 10. It increased by 8.9% for the first half of the year and by 37.9% for the second quarter. Regular income declined by 7.3% due to lower dividends and this resulted from our reduced equity exposure and in general also from lower dividend levels.</p>
          <p>The improved balance of other income and expenses is mainly due to an improved result of unrealized gains and losses for unit-linked life insurance, plus 325 million is due to that effect. We had a lower net result from disposals and an improvement of write-ups, write-downs, more particularly lower write-downs on equities, countervailing lower write-ups on derivatives securing these equities.</p>
          <p>Overall, we had a higher return on investment of 4%, after 3.8% in 2008. I assume that most of you have already had the chance to look at our quarterly report or at the presentation and therefore I will skip now over the following slides and move on to the investment mix on slide 14.</p>
          <p>We have a very well diversified investment portfolio with no major changes compared to the end of March. For the time being, we sustain a low risk investment profile. We very moderately increased our corporate bond portfolio to 9%, we slightly reduced our government bonds to some 40% and increased our inflation linked fixed interest portfolio to now some 5% of our overall assets. For '09, we expect a running yield slightly above 4%.</p>
          <p>Our low-risk portfolio performed well during the peak of the crisis. Obviously, we did not participate fully in the strong rally of equities in the last couple of weeks. Going forward how do we want to position ourselves in more normal times? What is the benchmark for our asset allocation? A few remarks on that on slide 15.</p>
          <p>Our asset allocation is not an arbitrary decision of a central group body. It is dominated by our strategic risk management framework, taking into account regulatory requirements of individual legal entities. We allocate economic risk capital budgets and we tightly control the exposures with clear cut limits and triggers.</p>
          <p>The key input for the asset allocation is the expected technical cash flow of liabilities in specific lines of business. We maintain a low to moderate risk profile because we stick and we believe in our liability driven business model. Therefore what you see as our asset allocation is a kind of consequence of this very disciplined approach. And what you can see on the right bottom corner of that page, as an indicative allowable range of the various asset classes, is this consequence not willing central decision. And I would like to specifically direct your attention to the fact that for the equities you will most probably not see us above 5%, even under normal conditions.</p>
          <p>One page 18, there is the overview of the primary insurance numbers. Gross premiums written went up by 2.6%. This is a mixture of negative fixed interest &#x2013; sorry, foreign currency effect, minus 1.6%. This is due to the decline of the Eastern European currencies. An impact from acquisitions of plus 2.9% and plus 1.3% was due to organic growth. Our new business in life primary insurance declined on an APE basis by 12.6%. Since single premium business was rather strong based on total premium sales figures, business went up by 4.7%.</p>
          <p>The combined ratio in Property-Casualty went up by 4 percentage points due to the strong winter, in essence. In the second quarter, it was better with 93.1%. So we are rather satisfied about that number and very confident that we'll keep it well below our 95% target.</p>
          <p>The bottom line was affected by the financial market crisis effects still, with a positive consolidated result of 62 million in the second quarter, which was not fully offsetting the loss in the first quarter. You'll find all details on the primary business on the slides 19 to 24.</p>
          <p>Let me now move on to the Reinsurance business on slide 26. Gross premiums written went up by 14% with positive foreign exchange effect of 3%, acquisitions plus 5.2%, and organic growth plus 5.7%, strongly supported by the quota share treaties which we explained in some detail already, May, in our latest telephone conference. Our operating result went up by 19%, adjusted for the ERGO dividend.</p>
          <p>Let's have a closer look to the combined ratio on slide 29. It was 97.7%, as Nikolaus mentioned, better than in the preceding year but still not satisfactory. In the second quarter, 98.1, and this was due to major losses not from natural catastrophes, they were slightly below the long-term average, but from manmade losses which clearly exceed the average with an impact on this year of 453 million. These were mainly recession-related claims.</p>
          <p>On slide 30, on the left hand side, this is a chart which we had already shown you in the course of the analysts' conference in March of this year. That time, we anticipated appreciably higher defaults and expected the impact from the recession to be extremely severe in credit insurance. This is due, what we see now, to much higher frequency losses, mainly in credit insurance and in our case a manageable number of medium to large losses, mainly in surety insurance.</p>
          <p>Our major losses of 217 million relate particularly to facultative surety business with strong focus on Asia and to trade credit insurance. The combined ratio for the credit segments consequently totaled 173% for the first half year. Adjusted to eliminate the aforementioned major losses from trade credit and surety insurance business, the combined ratio would amount to around 110%, which is also rather high.</p>
          <p>Beyond this, there were further recession-induced major losses from areas related to credit business amounting to nearly 100 million, around 60 million of this in the second quarter. These cannot be clearly assigned to either trade credit of surety insurance. For this reason, we have not shown them separately or eliminated them. But altogether, claims in the credit segment together with the additional credit-related losses in other areas totaled around 300 million in the first half year.</p>
          <p>With this, I would now like to hand over to Torsten with the latest developments in Reinsurance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. I'm on slide 33 and would like to report on the last renewal, July 1 renewal. The renewal was our -- July 1 renewal was our last major renewal date in 2009 and we had to renew the markets part of the U.S., Australia and Latin America.</p>
          <p>To summarize the major results, the price trend and the rate trend is very much comparable with the renewal picture in the two previous renewal months, in January and in April. Meaning price increases were achievable in the capacity-sensitive segments like Natural Catastrophe and Offshore Energy and some other segments. In all other lines of business and all other segments, particularly in the so-called volume business so the small and medium sized segments, we have seen stabilizations and slightly positive rate changes but mainly stable price trends.</p>
          <p>On an overall basis for the Munich Re portfolio, the price change is 4.4 percentage points after exposure changes. That means at the end of the day that we could achieve our price requirements in the cat-driven segments, but not in the volume markets.</p>
          <p>I switch to slide 34, and here you see the overall chart for the Munich Re portfolio. The renewable premium volume in the left bar was, at July 1, &#x20AC;1.3 billion. The outcome after the renewal is 1.42 billion, representing a 6.5% volume increase. That was achieved through active portfolio management. The overall result &#x2013; the overall difference taking into account the declined business, the cancelled business, the new business and the rate change on the existing business was 4.4 percentage points.</p>
          <p>How was it achieved? We saw rate changes, rate increases particularly in the catastrophe business, in all the three markets in the double-digit range. Of course, the hurricane-exposed business, the loss affected business, hurricane business in the U.S. was affected most. Here the price increases were in the order of 20, 25%. In the loss-free business, loss-free catastrophe business rate changes in the order of 10 to 20%.</p>
          <p>Second positive market was Australia. After the negative experiences in the last years as consequence of the flood losses, as a consequence of the wild fires, the insurance market in Australia responded on a broader basis, meaning that the original rates begin to increase and we see rate changes here in the order to 5 to 8% on the original side.</p>
          <p>When you compare the rate change, the 4.4% for our portfolio here, with the rate change we had shown at April 1, you see a small reduction here. This is due to the fact that portfolio composition in April was more cat driven. That means we renewed here percentage wise a smaller cat portion in the July 1 portfolio than in April, and that means, of course, that the net cat prices didn't show or didn't have the same impact on our overall portfolio.</p>
          <p>On slide 35 that is the attempt to describe the insurance market environment. We see our industry confronted with this sort of conflict between requirements coming from our industry and consumer behavior. On the left hand of the slide that describes or represents our industry, the insurance industry where we are in a situation of higher capital costs, we see capacity reductions for the capital intensive segments in our industry and we have to deal with significantly lower interest rates, which deteriorate, of course, the economic performance of the insurance and reinsurance business.</p>
          <p>On the right part of the slide, you see the customer behavior. Here both the commercial customers and the private customers are currently very much unwilling to pay more premium for their insurance products for various reasons. One reason is, of course, that they don't have the money to pay for insurance &#x2013; or not enough money to pay for insurance.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, the available market premiums begin to decline and this is a consequence of reduced turnover in some segments like the casualty business is directly related to the turnover of their customers so that means that the available premium volume for the insurance markets reduced.</p>
          <p>What is the consequence and what is the reaction of the insurance industry to this picture? Next slide, 36, we see more and more a world &#x2013; what we call a world of two markets in the insurance industry. And that means we see the capital intensive segments where insurance and reinsurance companies have the possibilities and the strengths to achieve rate increases, that is the catastrophe business, that is the credit business, that's the offshore energy business, et cetera. And these are all the loss affected segments which were negatively affected last year, like aviation, like space, like some flood segments in Australia.</p>
          <p>We see then on the other hand, the medium-sized and private segments, and here in almost all markets the rates remain unchanged. We see even from time-to-time a beginning competition from strong insurance companies for the reducing or for the smaller cake. So it remains to be seen which of the trends will dominate in the future. It cannot completely be excluded that in the small and medium-sized businesses more intensive competition should be anticipated.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, and that is my final slide, I want to give an update on our latest acquisition, that is the Hartford Steam Boiler. Hartford Steam Boiler is on board, it's a part of the Munich Re Group since April. We are in the final phase to integrate Hartford Steam Boiler into all the Munich Re internal processes and risk management procedures and into our investment policy.</p>
          <p>The figures for the second quarter, that was the first quarter they are part of our Group, are very promising, very satisfactory. 81% combined ratio and &#x20AC;173 million premium volumes coming from Hartford Steam Boiler. The impact of the recession and the current environment on their business is still not visible. So we do not expect at this point in time negative surprises from them and are very hopeful, and we are in good expectations that they will be a positive contributor to our future quarters this year and the time after.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you, Torsten. I am finishing it off with slide 39. In general, one could say we stick to our knitting. That means no surprises to the outside world. You know our strategy and even in the midst of the crisis we continue to execute the strategy that you all do know.</p>
          <p>If we look ahead, we think, yes, there will be still some opportunities that we might seize. Opportunities for profitable growth, that of course goes mostly for the reinsurance part of our Group. And maybe one side remark, I think the fact that we have reinsurance and primary insurance under one roof also proved right in the crisis because there seems to be some sort of a negative correlation of reinsurance to the crisis, this at least is our first finding after this crisis and primary insurance is probably more even though only slightly positively correlated to the crisis. So that's served us well that we are active in the two.</p>
          <p>As regards the profit for the current year, uncertainties are still around even though the stock market is rallying. We think the world is as uncertain as it has been for quite some time. So it is very difficult for us to make a serious projection. We rather refrain from that, but we remain confident that we can achieve even though we're just a little bit more ambitious now our 15% RORAC target, it's an after-tax target across the cycle. That, of course, will depend quite heavily also on the, what we call, the recession related losses and, of course, we are still right in the beginning of a hurricane season that may have some influence, of course, as well.</p>
          <p>As regards the overall turnover, we had to adjust our guidance up for a second time, happy problem one might say, now to 40 to 42 billion. Reinsurance also the major driver behind this increase of top line expectation is cruising around 97% of combined ratio. Torsten gave you come background on what he expects from the markets right now. We feel it's still achievable, but it goes like for the 15% RORAC target, it will depend on the recession related losses to quite some extent.</p>
          <p>Quite to the contrary, primary insurance here we are very relaxed as regards the achievement of the 95% combined ratio. We think this is well within reach; so no uncertainty there. One question that has been raised over the last two or three weeks more and more was the question of share buyback, of course.</p>
          <p>Well, first of all, in the current crisis we did quite well on the reinsurance side and picking up one or the other interesting opportunity, and we hope there will be more. So as long as we see good opportunities to deploy our capital we'll do so in the very business.</p>
          <p>A second opportunity that might arise, there was one Hartford Steam Boiler so far; we wish there were more, and we are not sure that asset prices will come down going forward, we think they should have come down already. So we keep our powder dry for these opportunities as well all within the strategy that you do know. And, in fact, you can rest assured our approach will be as disciplined as it has been over the last months and years.</p>
          <p>However, should we get disappointed as regards the market's development and at the same time the crisis sort of wane or the environment stabilize, then towards the end of the year, we will think about whether or not to resume the share buyback program. And to give you a ballpark what we would then try to do is probably to work towards the target of a share buyback of up to one billion. That is our old, if you like, target that we published when we published the Changing Gear targets. It was one more billion to go until the General Assembly 2010. That would be the maximum. I am not saying that we'd do exactly a billion, but that would be the maximum we have right now on our minds.</p>
          <p>So far from my end. And I would hand it back to Christian then to open the Q&amp;A.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, gentlemen, for the presentation. Now for Q&amp;A, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Our first question today comes from Michael Huttner of J.P. Morgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. Thank you very much. I had a couple of questions. The first one, I've noticed that you have a tendency to write off goodwill. Does that mean that Mr. Schneider is saying, no, no, you shouldn't do deals because, look, they cause you to lose money? And is that maybe a reduction in your deal appetite there?</p>
          <p>The second, life primary seems to be a bit of an issue. A couple of years ago you said on ERGO we'll keep it forever, and at the moment it doesn't seem to warrant that type of commitment. And I just wondered when or under what conditions we can actually expect to see decent earnings from the Life division. Does it entirely depend on markets, in other words better investment returns, or is it stuff you do internally? It really is not quite clear. I have heard so many years of statements on ERGO, I am a little bit lost as where we are.</p>
          <p>And then the last point is you've on the slide on capitalization, you mentioned that it's improved somewhat. Can you say at all if available financial capital, you half measure, whether that's at all improved since the start of the year or whether you're actually flat? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, this is Nikolaus. Thank you, Michael, for your questions. The first one, well, of course we do have serious discussions within the Group all the time when it comes to acquisitions, and if we follow them through later on whether or not the businesses plans are delivered. I think it is important, first of all, that the scrutiny and the due diligence that we do is very serious and we are very disciplined and cautious, as I said.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, of course, we ran with some of our acquisitions into the crisis. And the last one that we -- where we did write down goodwill, Sterling, was unhappy for one or two reasons. That is we had a major, let's say, adjustment of the laws that refer to the health environment in the U.S. already with the last -- with Bush administration, that forced us to change the approach in the country with that business. And at the same time, of course, we are still waiting for the details of what the Obama administration will bring about.</p>
          <p>But within that context, the business plan as we had it on our desk when we made the acquisition we felt was not good enough anymore to support the goodwill that was on our balance sheet and that is why we immediately reacted and wrote it down. Mid term, long term, of course, Sterling has all the opportunity to adjust strategy-wise and then to maybe come somewhere close to the old business plan but we don't want to play on hope here, we rather act immediately. Yes, but the discussions we do have all the time.</p>
          <p>Then second question is the ERGO life primary question. Well, first of all, I wish that the view that we have on life business in general, not just in Germany but in general in primary life, would be more of a joint view in the industry. We take a very sober economic approach when we look at life business and that is why we felt and feel that some things have to change, not only in Germany, but also in Germany.</p>
          <p>So how long will that take? Well, it's not all in our hands, but a lot is in our hands. It has to do what kind of products do you have on the pipeline margin-wise, how can your sales forces sell these products, are they ready to sell these products. And of course the capital market could help us a little bit more than it did over the last years. But, of course, this is not in our hand, that's what I meant. And we try to de-risk our balance sheet in a way that we do not play on capital market development, but rather manage it ourselves. But it will not be a quick fix we always have said that.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, of course, we have to make sure that our sales forces stay well equipped, that they get a decent, let say, flow of business to make their living, that all has to be taken into account and it's not a one dimensional equation. Life business probably in primary is one of the most complex businesses you could do and we will not stop from getting it right. I wish I could say mission completed.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry about that, that's here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't need the police to bail us out with our life primary business we do it ourselves. But it's a not quick fix.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to capitalization, Michael, and it's not adjusted publicly on a quarterly basis because an important element of the available financial resources is the embedded value uplift. And as you know, we publish our embedded value only once a year and we track it over the year, but not with the same precision.</p>
          <p>But I can give you an indication about the development since the turn of the year. We have a more or less parallel increase in the economic risk capital, which is the required capital, and the available financial resources by the same amount in spite of the dividend payment. That means that our excess capitalization is more or less untouched and therefore on a very solid basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now move to James Quin of Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Yes. Good afternoon. Three questions, please. The first one is coming back to the 4% investment yield because I don't really see how this can be sustainable in P&amp;C reinsurance or reinsurance more broadly, without a lot or realized investment gains. So if, for example, you look at the first half results of this year, there is &#x20AC;571 million of net realized gains in the reinsurance results. And if you take those out of the investment income the running yield in the first half would be about 3.2%. So if you could just comment on that that would be very helpful.</p>
          <p>The second question is just coming back to the write-downs of goodwill. I wonder if you could be perhaps a little bit more specific on what's changed here. Because I think some of those changes to U.S. healthcare were being talked about at the time you bought Sterling and indeed I think that was one of the reasons that Aon sold the business in the first place. And following on from that as well, looking at the notes to the accounts there is about 15 -- there is &#x20AC;59 million of write-downs in the non-operating line of other intangible assets, so not to goodwill, as well. I was wondering what you give us -- give us a sense of what that relates to?</p>
          <p>And my third question is just on the life and health technical results. Obviously, the growth in premiums has been very impressive, but the technical result is unchanged at about &#x20AC;70 million, and I was wondering why that was. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, let me start with the middle piece, James, it's Nikolaus, on the goodwill and the situation that we had when we acquired Sterling Life. Actually, there were many attempts in the House to change some of the legislation, but this was all vetoed by President Bush, and he said he would always veto it. But shortly before he left office, the last attempt he did not veto. That was a surprise to everybody, so that was not known. Nor was it known what exactly the last attempt of those who wanted to change parts of the health system in U.S. would change.</p>
          <p>Actually they changed some things in the way you could market and sell your business. They changed the way how you deal with the providers of the health services, things that could not be foreseen. And actually the seller, I think, did not know what we did not know at the time of the sale. So that happened afterwards. It was not even in the cooking, and if it was in the cooking, all those attempts to change the law so far had been vetoed by President Bush. So that's why we were in a way taken by surprise by that law to some extent.</p>
          <p>On the other hand, this in nothing that cannot be managed, but you had need time to, let's say, adjust both the sales process and the way the service is provided to the new environment. And on top of that now, we have the uncertainty what exactly the Obama administration will do, which is a further challenge. These two things together made us feel this is the time where you rather write down the goodwill, don't hope for anything. We think we can manage our way out of the first change, the first reform, but not in a year, that will take three or four years. And we have to wait for the second step. That's why we wrote it down immediately.</p>
          <p>The other part of the question will be part of J&#xF6;rg's answer, that was what was on top of that goodwill in second quarter, it was driven by Sterling and it was a little extra addition of 7 million that J&#xF6;rg I think can explain. J&#xF6;rg, and you have all the other questions as well I am afraid.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. I hope so. And one is the trade name and the other is distribution agreements. So typically this purchase price allocation is done in the order of identifying assets, individual assets, and then the remaining part is the goodwill. And in this case, we also took some distribution channels, which we set up as an asset. Does this answer this question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. So that's 59 million. So there's 59 million of non-goodwill amortization plus the 40 million in Q2, plus the 80 million in Q1. I mean that seems like quite a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. At the top of my head, it's about 57. So you are quite close to it. Yes. Yeah. That is a lot, but it's kind of practice that you try to identify as many assets as possible. But then in the second step, we are also rigid and honest enough to also catch them when there's a deterioration of the overall business plan going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But does that 59 relate to Sterling or does that relate to something else?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To both, also Bank Austria Creditanstalt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I look it up just -- I come back with it. Okay. Next one is &#x2013; so we have the depreciation was only seven, but the overall assets was -- with Sterling was 57, you are right, okay, sorry. Then you ask about the technical result in life re when you look at the quarterly number then that fits quite well. That's almost the same when compared to first quarter of '09. Therefore there is some stability, but I have to admit that with this technical result we are still in the course of refining it, the technical interest element because we started it by applying the respective risk free rate.</p>
          <p>In future, we want to move more to fixing the rate at the date of the investment and then following it in the following years by not changing it all the time. Therefore there will be more stability and more I think a better economic reflection of the business model, which is more or less an ALM matched model. Therefore, please give us one or two more quarters before that gets stabilized here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But, I mean, it does look a bit strange that your premiums have gone up by 46% and the technical result's still the same. But I'll leave that one for our future quarters. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And there was a last question about the running yield going forward, so I am not so pessimistic with that regard, because on one hand, the risk free rates have developed more favorably than we originally thought when we did our last communication on that. I think it was in the course of the Analyst Conference.</p>
          <p>And second, we have now a decent portfolio of corporate bonds and also our government portfolio is not fully composed of Germany and U.S., but also of some other states where we see substantial spreads. So it's far away from a risky portfolio, but we are more confident than we were some two or three months ago that we can sustain the current level of run yields for some time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Would that -- because we've got the running yield in the first half excluding all the realized gains in reinsurance is only 3.2%. So are you basically saying that that will improve substantially so you won't need the realized gains to get to the 4%?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. That will improve because this has been influenced by a lot of effects, for example, like the lack of dividend income in the course of the first two quarters, second quarter especially.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure that will pick up in the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. That won't. Yes, but we have now a more fixed income portfolio which is composed of good mixture of government paper and corporate bonds and other assets, which provide us with the necessary yields here. So we are not so negative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Andrew Broadfield of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good afternoon. Just a couple of quick questions. I think the net movement on reserves again was another quarter of no net movement. I was just wondering whether you might be able to give us a bit more flavor about what's happening between years. Whether there is still a trend, as I think there still has been market wide, in terms of still taking some reserves out of -- or releases out of more recent years and putting them back into the some less troublesome years. Whether that's still continuing or whether you see any other new trends emerging. That's first question.</p>
          <p>Second question, just on investment management expenses I am referring to page 54 of the interim accounts, there does seem to be sort of a downwards trend in that. I was just wondering whether you might be able to explain a little be better why the management expenses and interest charges seems to be coming down so dramatically if I look back on sort of prior six or eight quarters. And those were the two questions, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Could you repeat the last one, the start of the last one? You were talking about the unit-linked part or what was it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's the management expenses that are reported on in the investment expenses by segment note on page 54 of your report and accounts. It may well be unit-linked, but just if I can understand that better.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I look it up. First question, net movement of reserves, so then there were no major movements in the first half of the year. And I also always say that please do not expect us to release substantial amount of reserves for the years 2003 to 2006 or so because we think, overall, we have a good portfolio of reserves with adequate buffers.</p>
          <p>But we measure the confidence level here on a whole portfolio basis and that means that we think that we need a buffer of some 3 to 5% in order to provide for the unexpected, which is quite normal in such a portfolio. Therefore I do not foresee a change in the near future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But there's been no dramatic inter-year movement?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I come back to the question on the management expenses later on.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from William Hawkins of KBW [Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you very much. First of all, you went into this to some extent in the presentation, but I wanted to be clear. When you talk about recession related increase of losses are you really specifically referring to the large surety claims as the only issue that concerns you or are there other issues of recession related loss inflation that we should be thinking about?</p>
          <p>Again, when you look at slide 30, you've got areas like liability and marine that are also in a similar kind of high risk area. So you had surety in the second quarter. I am just wondering if you can see other issues that may be emerging as recession related at some point in the future.</p>
          <p>And then secondly, with reference to slide seven, the roll forward of your shareholders' funds. The unrealized gains and losses is always a bit of a black box, but I suppose I was positively surprised by the 119 positive in the second quarter given that you have such a defensive portfolio with such significant exposure to governments. I might have thought that the increase in the risk free rate had weighed on that a bit more. Can you try and give me any kind of quantitative or qualitative color in how the unrealized gains held up as well as they did? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Torsten here. Let me start with the credit question. The experience we have seen now is we have a very substantial contribution from surety losses. These are large single losses coming on the SEC -- through our SEC book into the Munich Re, mainly from Asia. They contribute a bit more than 200 million. The rest, about 100 million, are credit-related losses or slight impact from disability products included here, but nothing which we can specify, like these surety losses, which we can name and where we know exactly where they come from.</p>
          <p>So that is all credit insurance related. But only the surety part can be really specified, and where we can allocate the reserves precisely. I have to admit, surety business -- and you could ask why surety here is, of course, the part of the credit insurance where we have less control of our limit -- in terms of limit management.</p>
          <p>In the trade credit, we limit our exposures on a quarterly basis. For that reason, we see more frequency type losses, but not the large single losses. In surety, that's a bit different. The contracts which were written here are more than one or two years old, and of course, we have no option, no possibility, neither us nor the insurer, to reduce limits or to get out of the treaty. So for that reason it's maybe not surprising that particularly the surety segment contributes these losses.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. But there were no other lines of business that you would say your recession-related caveat about the combined ratio could apply to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No. That is true. And remember, when we made our sort of risk management report in March, and where we specified or identified all the other credit-exposed or recessionary-exposed segments, that was D&amp;O, that was professional indemnity, that was commercial D&amp;O, et cetera, where we said we thought to take a conservative approach and reduce our exposures; because of higher loss probabilities in these segments, we don't see very much activity yet. I'm a bit careful because there might be a delay, but we don't see activity. Yet, they are still in good shape, touch wood.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to the unrealized gains, the increase in risk-free rates was to some extent compensated by the decline of the spreads. And that explains that this effect was very mild here. Then another question which I couldn't answer before, the decline of the management expenses, interest charges and other expenses, especially in primary life insurance, page 45 of the Annual Report, from 349 to 124, this is due to the fact that the expenses from a negative result of unit-linked primary life insurance has been reflected here. And since it had a negative result in the course of 2008 and a positive now, this explains this enormous shift here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Next we will move to Will Morgan of Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much. I have two questions, if I may. The first one is on your non-life reinsurance expense ratio. Obviously, with the HSB deal, there must be some kind of mix change in the structure of the combined ratio. But just looking at your expense ratio, it's gone from around 30% at the year end, 28.4% in the first quarter and now down to 25.1. I realize you can vary a bit and maybe commissions are moving around, but if you could possibly give some color on the structure of that going forward, that would be very helpful.</p>
          <p>And the second question, just relating to your comments on the share buyback, I wondered if you could just give us some color on the Munich Re AG retained earnings and whether or not that is in any way a constraining factor. And if there is some way you could give us some degree of outlook for that and how that might develop through the year that would be very helpful? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, this is Nikolaus. Hi, Will. Let me start with the second question as regards revenue reserves at Munich Re AG. This is not a limiting factor right now. So what I said beforehand, the maximum that we might consider is a billion. This billion is already sort of taken care for. We could do it. There is no limitation. The old limitation that you certainly do remember revenue reserves are filled. We could do it. And we could act. J&#xF6;rg will come with an answer on the question as regards to the expenses on reinsurance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. There was a quite substantial decline of commissions, which drove the decline of the expense ratio here. Looking at quarterly developments, and even on a half year basis, is not always meaningful. So going forward, I do not foresee a very clear trend downwards.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Some sense you could give us on where a kind of normalized level might be? I guess, just given that some of the businesses you've added on obviously shifts the mix a little bit. I don't know if you can or not, but just some guidance might be useful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is very difficult because it depends also on the quality of the results because a lot of commissions are profit-related. And that means the better the results, the higher the commissions. And also you have DAC movements from quarter-to-quarter, which distorts the view sometimes. And therefore, I am too careful now to give you an indication. I will try it until the next quarter to define a little bit more of a sustainable level here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Then enough there, so that's variable commission and that's useful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is right. We have sliding scale commissions more and more in order to participate the primary insurer in the profit of the reinsurance business, which is very powerful instrument to align interest.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question today comes from Ben Cohen of Collins Stewart. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd like to ask two things. Firstly, could you maybe just go into a bit more detail as to the surety losses that you incurred in the third quarter? I know you said that there is some uncertainty as to what the losses would look like going forward, but I just wonder the degree to which you're sitting here waiting for notifications to come in, the degree to which you've been proactive, and maybe some sense as to how bad it could get if the recession sort of worsens or stays at these sorts of levels from here?</p>
          <p>And the second thing I wanted to ask was on the question of M&amp;A and things that you're looking at. Is it the question &#x2013; is it the case that still that prices that are being asked are too high? Or is it simply that there aren't the assets that you would consider attractive or would fit with your strategy that are out there? And do you really think that anything like this is going to change in the next few months before you decide your capital return plan? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, then, this is Nikolaus. As regards the surety losses, first of all, we are always hesitant, it's like with the D&amp;O business, to be too specific on these losses because the more specific we are, the higher the loss by the end of the day. So it's not that we try to circumphrase things or avoid being more specific, it's rather that we should not be too specific because it will cost us money by the end of the day if we were.</p>
          <p>What is important here, I think, is that whatever claim is notified, or whatever we feel will be a claim soon, when we talk about IBNRs, is immediately accounted for. So to the best of our knowledge, when we accounted the second quarter, we put all the bad news, notification or something that is pretty close to notification into our books.</p>
          <p>And that is where the 200 and some million came from, the surety part, and it also applies or is also true for what we called recession related losses, losses that have a sort of a credit loss nature, but are not straightforward, for example, surety or trade credit businesses. So that's how we approach it. But we are silent, as we were towards the end of 2007 when we put up a major reserve for D&amp;O, which we didn't even put down in numbers by the time, because these are very sensitive lines of business in regard of loss settlement.</p>
          <p>As regards the M&amp;A question, it's a mixture, of course, of the two. But actually in terms of our strategy, we know of many assets that are sort of sitting pretty loose on the balance sheets of some of those who own them and who consider selling. But when you start discussions then with the management, you feel that the business plans they have would immediately trigger goodwill write-downs at our end. So that's why we have to continue these discussions. Then they pull back sometimes. So it's not so much that the assets wouldn't be there, it's really mostly about the pricing. Some assets, of course, have not entered the market yet, but others did cruise around, disappear, come back, cruise around.</p>
          <p>So it's a matter of patience. And let's assume that the crisis goes away quickly then we won't see them again. If the crisis takes a little longer to move away, might see them, but we will not change our attitude. And of course, since, luckily, and thanks to the business, quarter by quarter we add earnings to our capital, then we come to the point around the end of the year where we have to make some decision what to do with the capital.</p>
          <p>As we always said we will not warehouse capital because quarter by quarter, if we continue successfully, new earnings will be coming in. And if we run into something really meaningful and big, we would have to talk to the capital market anyway. We would not be afraid or shy away from even going into the capital market, if the M&amp;A was such that we need support from the capital market. That would be it in a nutshell. So it's mostly price, and we have the patience to wait.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, if I could ask a follow-on? Could you maybe just remind us your strategic priorities in terms of M&amp;A because obviously you've done quite a broad range of deals in the last couple of years?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. What we did actually was almost always small and mid-sized deals only. And they paid into the strategy of all the business fields, in fact. Reinsurance probably in numbers of acquisitions had the biggest amount, which surprised us in the first place because we always thought it would rather be primary and Munich Health. But all three have strategies in place, where acquisition or external growth may play a role if we happen to run into the right asset.</p>
          <p>But we did do acquisitions in all three. The recently mentioned Sterling was won on the Munich Health side. We had our Turkish acquisition, and also an acquisition on the primary side, and we had a couple of acquisitions on the reinsurance side. So we had no preference. The strategy in place did not change. So in reinsurance, it's mostly niche businesses, white spots. It's possible not &#x2013; positively correlated to the reinsurance cycle as such. It's add-ons. In the Munich Health, it's a pick-and-choose strategy. We have pinpointed certain markets where we think the potential is such that it would make sense to go into the market and develop businesses.</p>
          <p>And on the primary side, it's a regional strategy in the first place. It's Eastern Europe that is high on our list, and what we call selected Asia. And within these, let's say, strategies, you might expect acquisitions. And all the rest is rather unlikely. One example, traditional reinsurance, you would not see us buying a traditional reinsurance company, not on our list.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now &#x2013; our next question is from Stephan Kalb [Sal. Oppenheim]. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. I have three questions. The first one is on credit and surety again. And here I think my main concern is that, since it's recession-related damages that we could see repetitions in the next quarters, and thereby I think I could be more precise and ask whether, or what is the difference between the larger losses in the segment and the normal losses? Is this just the size of the loss, or is it also different in terms of frequency and the level of predictability?</p>
          <p>And the second question is in terms of the renewals in April and July, could you specify how much of the renewal was devoted to NatCat business? And the third one is on your outlook 2009. In the press conference, there was a quote said you mentioned &#x2013; said you look for a net profit of 2.5 billion for the full year. Could you comment on that, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Stephan, hello. Let me start with the credit and surety business. The &#x2013; what is the difference, was your question, between the large single losses we reported on the surety and the smaller frequency type losses. The difference is that we see a picture that the trade credit segment within the credit insurance produces, let's say, a higher combined ratio, which is driven by frequency, but not by larger losses. That has probably to do with the &#x2013; with our and the insurance company's possibility to manage the limits.</p>
          <p>Remember though, original policies have 90 days cancellation terms so that the insurance industry, the credit insurance industry is pretty well positioned or capable to manage the trade credit business. As a consequence of this feature under the policies, we have hardly suffered any of the larger insolvencies, which you have seen on TV. None of these were &#x2013; came into our books, at least not to a larger extent.</p>
          <p>On the surety business, it's different. Here we have long-term original policies, and that is probably the reason why we, the Munich Re, including our insurance companies which we cover, were not in a position to manage these exposures more actively because they were already written two years ago. So for that reason, to me it's not very surprising that we see this difference and cannot have to specify the surety-type losses on the credit. Is there more to come? Not to our knowledge.</p>
          <p>Everything we know is, of course, fully reserved, and even where we have indications for deteriorations that have all put into the reserves in the second quarter. Can we exclude it? Of course, not. We cannot. It depends very much on the further development of the recession in the various parts of the world. Second question was the renewal.</p>
          <p>And you asked for the difference in the NatCat portion between April and July renewal. In April, where we had to renew basically the Asian portfolio, Japan and Korea, the catastrophe portion in our Munich Re premium volume which was renewable was higher, it was in the order of 33, 34%. Now in the July renewal for Australia, U.S. and Latin America, it's 27%.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Your last question, Stephan, was about our guidance for this year for the net profit. What we did in the press conference this morning was just very simple. We stick to our 15% return on risk-adjusted capital target, and said that this &#x2013; under the current conditions, it's a quite ambitious one, but it's still achievable. And then we translate it into something like &#x20AC;2.5 billion. But this was not a prognosis, this was just a translation of the target based on the current risk capital. But that's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now move to Jean-Francois Tremblay for &#x2013; of RBS for our next question. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I'd like to focus on the outlook for your non-life reinsurance business. Let me first refer to a comment you are making in the half year results report on page 19. At the very bottom, as you discuss the outcome of your July annuals, so the very bottom of that page you say, "Although we are not entirely satisfied overall with the development of prices, terms and conditions in 2009, we were able to further improve the earnings profile of our portfolio thanks to our active cycle management."</p>
          <p>Now is there anyway we can quantify that improvement in the earnings for your portfolio? That's something we've been expecting. But your RORAC target hasn't changed, and I don't think, there has been much change in your pricing tools. So is there anyway we can back that statement by some numbers in terms of how we should really think in terms of improvement in the profitability of your non-life business?</p>
          <p>And then can you elaborate on your outlook for 2010, you seem to be fairly confident the market is going to be stable. But there's a good chance industry capacity will be increasing when demand may not actually pick up as for many companies capital bases are also restored. So what makes you confident that the market will be stable in 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the talk with the second question. The &#x2013; I tried to describe our &#x2013; it's a bit early, I admit that, but we tried to describe what our perception of the coming half year or three quarter year is, and that is driven by the equation demand versus offered capacity. And we are, let's say, very confident and see positive trends in the capital-intensive segments. Why? Because we see two trends here; the industry as a whole was not in a position to recapitalize itself which was necessary as a consequence of the capital market crisis, but also as a consequence, at least in some markets, to compensate for the suffered losses last year on the hurricane.</p>
          <p>We see now a very clear trend that some of the insurance and also reinsurance companies have started to reduce their Cat capacity that started already in the April renewal. And what that was sometimes driven by very obvious, let's say, drivers. Look at Japan, for instance. In Japan, the currency exchange rate, the yen vis-&#xE0;-vis the dollar and the yen vis-&#xE0;-vis the euro strengthened. That means under yen programs, the foreign insurance and reinsurance companies had to provide a higher capacity in their home currency.</p>
          <p>And as a consequence of this trend, this was already sufficient for some reinsurance companies to reduce capacity. And we all know some of the players who substantially &#x2013; who announced to substantially reduce their Cat commitments.</p>
          <p>That led, in the July 1 renewal, to a situation that you were pretty much &#x2013; you were, and we, as Munich Re, and other companies were in a good position as long as you could provide an unchanged capacity. That means, for instance, that under the Cat programs, we hardly saw any differential terms this time in the July 1 renewal. Why? Because we got our price and the markets who provided enough capacity got the same prices too. So the advantage &#x2013; the competitive advantage was availability to provide capacity here.</p>
          <p>What happens with the rest of the market? Here's a countertrend. And here we see maybe an unchanged, but I said over and higher competition for the reducing cake cannot be excluded. So here in these segments we are not so optimistic to extrapolate unchanged market conditions. Our best knowledge is stable conditions, but we don't know yet. This is our best gut feeling, so to speak, for the 2010 renewal, but it's much too early to give more precise figures now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Next we will move to Brian Shea of Bank of America. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I had two questions, please, both relating to the same topic really. And that's the earnings power of primary life insurance. I've always struggled to work this out. I was hoping that the rollout of your new technical result measure in Q1 would, kind of, make things a bit easier. I was a bit surprised, you actually didn't make any reference to this new measure at all in the conference call. When I look at the results, it looks like Health is running at about 100 million a quarter in terms of the technical result, but Life is still all over the place.</p>
          <p>And if I guess &#x2013; I just wondered, the first question is can you just &#x2013; can we use the technical result as some more stable guide of what the earnings power of these two units are, Life and Health? And then the other question is just, very simply what was the &#x2013; I think, the swaption had a drag in the second quarter. It looks as if that drag was bigger than in other recent quarters. Could you just quantify that, please, and say where does it show up? Is it above or below the line in terms of the technical result? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Brian. The swaption indeed was the main reason for this quite poor technical result of Primary Life. How is it done? We &#x2013; the swaptions &#x2013; or let's start with the unit-linked business. All impact from unit-linked business is more or less brought to zero for the technical result because the investment result is made part of the technical interest as it comes in. And therefore, what remains is the traditional business, not unit-linked business.</p>
          <p>And here we apply, on one hand, risk-free rates plus all contribution to the policyholders here, both is part of the technical interest. And then we deduct here the contribution for the claims and benefits. And in a quarter like this, where we have a high negative from the swaption program, it falls, in a way, over the cliff. And therefore we have then a negative on &#x2013; a negative balance of investment result and technical interest for the Life business. The impact from the swaptions, I think, we disclosed it already. It shows up in the investment result. But what is the number? I'll ask here my colleagues and I'll provide you with it later on. It's some 360 for the first half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And that 360, does that follow all the pre-tax profit or is that shared with the policyholder?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is shared with the policyholder.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>90/10?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And the net impact was about 70 or so. Yes. So it was really a big effect here. It's about 74 was the net impact and 36 was the gross number here. So minus 36 in the investment result, and minus 74 for the net group result, and this is quite a big impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No. That's an H &#x2013; just to be clear, that's an H1 number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>360 for the investment result and 74 for the net group result, as a negative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. More generally, the first question I asked about can we use anything in your disclosure in technical results as a guide to figure out how much your earnings power can be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The more the investment income stabilizes, the better, I would say because it was so highly dominated by these huge changes in the volatility, which drove the swaption program and its market value up and down. And also you have to bear in mind that part of that is written in Belgium, of this swaption program, where this is not shared fully with the policyholders.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And maybe, Brian, one word on your first question. Of course, these derivatives do distort the results a lot and create issues. We have to get accustomed, all of us, in using it and reading it. This is what J&#xF6;rg just explained. And in the other hand, of course, the bonus policy that we have for the next year, for the German life business is crucial when it comes to determining the net income of the very year.</p>
          <p>So partly, of course, we have it in our hand. And it's a tough decision sometimes between what do we want to do to please the back book? What do we want to do to support the new business? And what do we want to show as net income? And it sounds easier than the equation. Of course, there's more variables to that question. But if you take the eighth result, which was 100 million, somewhere between 50 million and 100 million is in theory easy to present as long as the capital markets move nicely. But of course, we would like to go beyond that. And that comes back to the earlier question.</p>
          <p>If we get things right, the German life business can perform better than 100 million, but it would not go through the ceiling. Its overall contribution to our group net income will always be somewhere between 50 and 150 for the time being. And it's a little bit in our hands where we come out with &#x2013; what we come out. But as you know, we don't try to show good results. We try to show the right result.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. I'm sorry. Just to make sure I understand, Nikolaus, 50 to 100, what does that relate to &#x2013; sorry, sorry, 50 to 150?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is the ERGO segment result. It's before consolidation. It's the life segment of ERGO.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Net -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>German business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Net earnings, is that per quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's the year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>For the full year, net earnings.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Net earnings, German life segment, before consolidation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I should also add that the profit sharing with the policyholders is done on a local GAAP basis. And that means that the reflection, in IFRS terms, is sometimes very strange.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now move to Fabrizio Croce of Kepler. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I have actually only two ones. The first one is about the inflation-linked bonds. I saw that the stake of the percentage of fixed income increased from 10 to 11%. Here the question is, what is an end proportion which you are striving in that asset category? And the second one is, we spoke before about M&amp;A size.</p>
          <p>And my question only to understand a little bit what you understand for small and mid-sized deals. Would an AIG China operation be classified within your internal schema as a mid-sized transaction or a large-sized transaction? And even if you could spend just one word about your dividend policy. Sorry to ask three questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Fabrizio. Let me start with the last two questions. Well, if the price that the seller had expected for the East Asia China businesses was the right one, then it would be a big acquisition. If the price that we think is right would be assumed, it may be a mid-sized acquisition. That's why we will never acquire it probably. Now we consider small up to a billion plus/minus. Mid-sized for us is something between three and five billion, and there's not &#x2013; nothing in the pipeline right now in terms of mid-sized.</p>
          <p>As regards dividend policy, no changes there. We paid, in the midst of the crisis, &#x20AC;5.5 per share. We are sort of moving slowly out of the crisis, so that's what at least you would like to go for. The floor that we have published as regards dividend payments is at 25%. And that did &#x2013; we did not increase that because just last year we went way beyond it. But we, on the other hand, as long as the business goes right, we don't want to fall below the 5.50. So no major changes there. And we will not increase the floor as of today. And now maybe J&#xF6;rg on the other question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, currently it's a portfolio of some &#x20AC;8 billion of inflation linkers. There is not a fixed plan how far we want to go because it's also dominated by tactics and not only of a long-term plan here. And therefore, I can't be more precise here. But they fit quite well to our portfolio. At least that I can say quite safely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Wonderful. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thorsten Wenzel of DZ Bank has our next question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. This is Thorsten Wenzel. Just one straightforward question left, which is on the Group non-operating result. This was, in the second quarter, minus 241 million, so highly negative. And my question is just are these FX effects or is anything else going on? I think, it's not the goodwill write-down.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thorsten, it's &#x2013; there are FX effects. But I look it up, and I'd come back later on it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Next we will take a question from Deutsche Bank, Spencer Horgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. Two questions from me, please. First one is on the combined ratio outlook. I'm trying to work out how likely it is that you get to 97%. But I guess, if we get to sort of normal level of natural catastrophes in the second half of the year, it's quite unlikely, isn't it? I mean, I assume the &#x2013; at least the trade credit losses will remain elevated for the time being. And surety, I guess, we've got no clue on.</p>
          <p>But if you could just give us a feel for how likely it is you make 97% for the year, that would be useful. And then when we look through to the next big renewal, which is obviously January, I guess your message to clients over the autumn is going to be that you still are expecting prices to go up or that there's a case for prices to continue to go up.</p>
          <p>I wondered, firstly, how much resistance do you think there will be from the primary companies to that. And then secondly, what do you think will actually be the outcome in January, just for the best guess at the moment. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thorsten, your first question, combined ratio, full year. You are right, the 97 is more difficult. I would not say with &#x2013; not in reach is not right, but it's more difficult than originally anticipated. And that has, of course, exclusively to do with the extraordinary and unexpected contribution from the credit segment.</p>
          <p>You could say because of this extraordinary loss impact in the first half, if you want to reach it now &#x2013; if we want to reach it now, we need a below-average large loss activity or NatCat activity in the second half of the year, which would offset the above average claims activity in the first half. Then it's in reach or reachable, in my opinion. Otherwise, normal Cat activity assumed, it's difficult.</p>
          <p>Is that a contradiction to what we said at the beginning of the year? Not in my opinion because the renewal of the non-life business delivered what we said, what we promised. And we have to take into account that of course calendar year is to one-third impacted by the last year &#x2013; by the last calendar year because of the unearned premium transfer. But profitability in non-life, if you take recession-related credit losses out, is basically in line with our expectation.</p>
          <p>What is our expectation for January? I cannot give many more hints or signs, because we don't know better yet. Our best projection is what we have seen in the July renewal. And that is a Cat sensitive business at very decent price levels. Here the Munich Re is &#x2013; I would not say alone, but very much in a unique position to select the layers and the programs. And we have no fear to increase our risk in case prices are good or prices develop positively. So I think, we are pretty much the only company which has this capacity advantage these days. The rest of the market is difficult.</p>
          <p>I think the clients, in my opinion, will probably react depending on their experiences in their original markets. The more they are under pressure, that insurance volume shrinks or comes under pressure, the more they will, of course, resist to agree on improved prices on the reinsurance side, and maybe vice versa, though it very much depends how much impact we see from the recession in terms of pressure on the original book, yes or no at the end. More is not possible at this stage. And we will probably give a better, let's say, extrapolation or better projection in later forum, so much so far, from my side.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to the other non-operating income and expenses, there's a huge currency effect, but for income and expenses with a balance in the order of 107 only. So this is a reflection of our congruent coverage policy where we used a lot of derivatives also and have the movements from the translation in the P&amp;L. Apart from it, it contains non-technical income of 197 and expenses of 176. So the balance is not that high as the movement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We will now move to Paul Goodhind of Redburn Partners. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Hi. Can I ask a question on the surety losses? And specifically, why are we seeing losses so early in the recession? One thinks of surety as being quite late cycle in terms of when those losses will occur. And can you give us a feeling of the size of the premium income from Asian surety specifically? What portion of the surety book is Asia? And what trends are you seeing in the surety book in the rest of the world, the U.S. and Europe in particular?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I asked my colleagues to provide me with the figures regarding surety premium volume in Asia and rest of the world. Is it surprising that was your first question, that the surety losses come now, let's say in an early or middle stage of the recession? Not necessarily surprising. Why? It very much depends how much enterprises can fulfill their obligations at the end of the day. Yes. They were insured a few years ago for &#x2013; got larger orders and at the end of the day they meet their obligations or they cannot meet their obligations.</p>
          <p>And if not, and that of course happened in some sectors already now, then of course these type of surety policies, of course they respond. That's why they were bought for, at the end of the day. So you can exactly explain the phenomenon, in my opinion. The cause of the loss and why it comes now is in our opinion not surprising. Regarding the premium volume surety, I'll come back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow-up there. Is this construction surety or is it commercial surety causing the losses?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first, construction.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question today comes from Thomas Noack of WestLB. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Thank you. Two questions, please. The first one is on your recent acquisitions. You mentioned Hartford Steam Boiler, you mentioned Sterling Life Company, but you did not mention the Midland Group. Could you please give some information how Midland performed in these times, just to get a feeling how the company develops in the recession?</p>
          <p>And the second question is on Primary Life business. Looking at the APE figures, it leaves the impression that you are very much pushing the single premium business. Could you please give some details on the different conditions between the traditional regular premium business and the single premium business, so we can, let's say, get a better feeling regarding the margins for the single premium business end, why single business is so much more successful than the regular premium business? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Before I come to your question, let me give &#x2013; I still owe the response to the surety question. That was the previous one. What I can &#x2013; what we can give you is our Asian credit &#x2013; trade credit and surety business contributes 8% to our overall trade credit and surety exposure. We do not have and cannot provide a further breakdown within the surety sub-segment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regard to Midland, first of all, the result for 2009 first half is in the order of U.S. $25 million, which is below our expectation has to do with a substantial amount of tornado losses, losses which are typically below the reinsurance level. On the other hand, the company is performing quite well and integration is going on as planned. And we are very satisfied about the development of Midland.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>To your second question with regard to Primary Life, it's not only that we actively push single premium business, but it's &#x2013; what &#x2013; it has been easier to sell at the moment because people are somewhat hesitating to bind themselves for long-term premium payments at the moment. That is at least our impression.</p>
          <p>Also, it has to do with distribution channels because our banking channels have developed quite nicely in the recent past. This is one reason. In the long run, we expect and also we would wish that the current premium business &#x2013; regular premium business will pick up again.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take a follow-up question from Michael Huttner of J.P. Morgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much. We've got the leases done. Sorry about that. On the statement about buyback, I just wanted to be absolutely clear that the one billion figure that you mentioned, is that the cap on the total buyback, that's it? Or is that the amount which would potentially be under consideration to be done by April 2010?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's the latter, the maximum until the next general assembly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's &#x2013; for me, that's it. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our final question today comes from Andrew Broadfield of Morgan Stanley. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Just a really quick one, just on the discussion you were having about the types of M&amp;A activity you might be engaged in. I saw mention that you were interested in a stake, at some point, in China Re, issued a float. I was wondering whether that is an indication of other potential ways you might look to seek expansion, and particularly &#x2013; in particular because you said you wouldn't be interested in buying another reinsurer.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think this was market gossip, certainly not a statement from the Munich Re because we never mentioned any possible participation in China Re publicly. And here it is holding true what we said beforehand, acquisitions of reinsurers, traditional reinsurers, or even a share are not on our strategic landscape.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>So thank you for participating in the call. Thank you for your questions. For further questions, as always, please do contact us at Investor Relations. And we are very much looking forward to meeting you soon again. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>