<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1229973" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2009 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-05-06</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7867</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Christian Becker-Hussong, Head of Investor and Rating Agency Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">J&#xF6;rg Schneider, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep">Dr. Torsten Jeworrek, Corporate Underwriting, Reinsurance Investments, and Accounting, Controlling and Central Reserving for Reinsurance</participant>
      <participant id="4">Michael Huttner</participant>
      <participant id="5">J&#xF6;rg Schneider</participant>
      <participant id="6">Spencer Horgan</participant>
      <participant id="7">Torsten Jeworrek</participant>
      <participant id="8">James Quin</participant>
      <participant id="9">Will Morgan</participant>
      <participant id="10">Joachim Oechslin</participant>
      <participant id="11">Jean-Francois Tremblay</participant>
      <participant id="12">Marc Thiele</participant>
      <participant id="13">Brian Shea</participant>
      <participant id="14">Fabrizio Croce</participant>
      <participant id="15">Raghu Hariharan</participant>
      <participant id="16">Stephan Kalb</participant>
      <participant id="17">Michael Haid</participant>
      <participant id="18">William Hawkins</participant>
      <participant id="19">Fahad Changazi</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day, and welcome to the Munich Re Quarter One Results 2009 Conference Call. Today's conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Christian Becker-Hussong. Please go ahead, sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to our conference call on the presentation of Munich Re Group's first quarter 2009 financial results</p>
          <p>J&#xF6;rg Schneider will start with a quick overview and the key financials before going into details of the investment results and the segment reporting. Dr. Jeworrek will then present to you the new business development in reinsurance with the focus on the outcome of the April 1st renewals and future business prospects. Finally, J&#xF6;rg Schneider will conclude with an outlook for the remainder of the year. As usual, the presentations will be followed by a comprehensive Q&amp;A session. So J&#xF6;rg, the floor is yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, Christian. Good morning and good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. It's my pleasure now to lead you through the main numbers. I'll start with slide three; satisfactory results. The net profit of 420 million does not mean that we are back to normal, but it is satisfactory as it demonstrates the earnings resilience in turbulent capital markets of first quarter. Our shareholders equity and all the other capital relevant numbers show a very sound position according to all capital measures. In primary insurance, we were affected with significant accounting effect due to the financial crisis. In reinsurance, the competitive advantage of our financial strength is starting to allow for participation in market opportunities and the April renewals confirm clearly the trends to market hardening. Therefore, we are increasing our premium forecast for 2009.</p>
          <p>First on capitalization, which is in everybody's interest these days. On slide five, the overview. We have a strong capitalization according to all measures. Our regulatory solvency ratio was at 258%, roughly unchanged in comparison to the number year-end 2008. In the models of the rating agencies we have a low-to-mid single digit billion capital buffer. This is important. And also our buffer of the economic capital, the different between available financial resources and our risk capital requirement according to our internal model, was rather stable with an upward movement of the embedded value and to the same extent a little bit less than upward movement of the risk capital which is allocated to the embedded value relevant segments here. Also the other numbers shown on that slide; book value per share, &#x20AC;108.4 or 21 &#x2013; 20.1% debt leverage, 10 times interest coverage are very favorable in comparison to the market. The financial solidity of Munich Re is also reflected externally in the low beta of the Munich Re stock, the low CDS spreads which are as of today at 61 basis points, and rating of AA minus or similar rating with other agencies with stable outlook of all the four major rating agencies.</p>
          <p>Let's take a look at the shareholders equity on slide six. Plus &#x20AC;407 million in the course of the first quarter, roughly equals our net profit. Unrealized gains and losses were somewhat down, mainly driven by the increase in risk-free rates. We had a positive impact from exchange rates because the euro was weaker against all major currencies except yen and Swiss franc as at the end of March compared to end of December. For more details on the currencies, see page 45 of our quarterly report. Our share buybacks are still suspended in view of the world economic crisis with its potential challenges, but also with its potential opportunities, because our strong capitalization provides us now with a competitive edge and increasingly interesting business opportunities. I would like to emphasize less in M&amp;A, because the market does not seem to be prepared to it. The prices we see in the current talks we are in are still not attractive enough and do not adequately reflect the economic environment. Therefore, it's not very probable that we do something big in the near future. But more so in reinsurance and more on that from Torsten later on.</p>
          <p>On the investments, there is an overview on slide seven. Our comfortable capital and earnings position allowed us to continue with very active portfolio management. In the first quarter, we continued to decrease our equity exposure and now very much so with the sale of equity and with the unwinding of equity derivatives, both with remarkable opposite P&amp;L effect. We cautiously reorganized further our fixed-income securities portfolio and we improved it sustainably at the expense of realization of losses, because we could afford to do so.</p>
          <p>Our equity ratio is now after hedges at only 1.4% or I would &#x2013; I should better say at the end of March, it was around 1.4%, and the restructuring, which I described for the fixed-interest securities and loans portfolio was as follows: 86% of our total investments are invested in loans and available for sale fixed interest securities. We reduced in the course of the first quarter our anyway relatively small portfolio of structured credit instruments in the United States to a number of now only 5.2 billion of which 3.7 is in papers issued by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac. You see more details on that in slide 49 of the backup to this presentation. We &#x2013; at the same time gradually expanded our high quality corporate bonds portfolio, and corporate bonds in Munich Re means its portfolio of non-financial issuers here, and we stick to our strong focus on government bonds, almost half of the fixed income portfolio and to the very secure Pfandbriefe and other covered bonds.</p>
          <p>So far with the overview of the investments, now let's have a look on the most important P&amp;L numbers for the group on page eight of the presentation. Gross premiums written increased by 527 million or 5.3%. Reinsurance combined ratio was at 97.3%. Primary insurance combined ratio we saw a sharp increase to 96.3%. Group investment results declined by 18.5%, operating results by 37.5, and consolidated results by 45.9%. But I would like to emphasize that we should not put too much focus on the comparison with the first quarter 2008. This is not fully meaningful because this quarter was dominated by high gains on disposal of equities, most of it done before the sharp decline of the stock prices. The impairment losses only came in with the usual time delay in the course of the year 2008, and therefore let's look more at the absolute numbers for the first quarter and these are as I think relatively good with a view to the resolute handling of the crisis-related burdens.</p>
          <p>Now a few remarks on the new segmentation according to IFRS 8; you see the overview on page nine, and we have an presentation on the Internet regarding this topic, which is still as I would like to emphasize here, on a learning curve, because it has just been implemented. First on the segmentation, we separated life and health primary insurance from each other to give you more transparency here. And for our business field international health, we apply a two-step approach. Now with the separation of life and health in primary insurance but health is still including Germany primary, which does not belong to the business field international health.</p>
          <p>International health, or like we call it now Munich Health, will probably reach the necessary volume limits in the course of this or next year, and therefore we will most probably show it as a separate segment for 2010. The overall impact of the technical changes of IFRS 8 for us was limited, but we use the opportunity to further improve our disclosure, and this in the following way our operating result is now broken down into a technical result and a non-technical result. The technical result consists of underwriting items plus income from technical interest to give you an indicator for the sustainable performance without investment result volatility, but with major losses volatility. So for us all losses are part of the technical result.</p>
          <p>The non-technical results is the sum of the remaining investment income and the other expenses. So for us, all investment income is operating, so we do not want to sort that out because investments belong to the insurance business. What we separate from the operating result and regard as being non-operating items like foreign exchange gains and losses, finance cost, impairments of goodwill or taxes.</p>
          <p>You'll see the components on slide 10 for the first quarter with operating result of 746 million composed of technical result of 551 and non-technical 195 million. The other operating &#x2013; the other means non-operating items had overall a negative impact with minus &#x20AC;67 million, better than in the preceding year, but due to an environment which was not back to normal below that of normal times.</p>
          <p>This brings me to the investment result on slide 11. The regular income slightly declined and this reflects our continued low risk appetite. The results from other income and expenses improved by 157 million mainly due to a less negative result for unit-linked life Insurance, which now contributes with a loss of minus 36 million. The net result from disposal halved. Realized losses were achieved in available-for-sale fixed-interest securities, and we have a slightly lower impact from write-up/write-down as a most important part of this being from the derivatives used to hedge against low interest rate scenarios for German life primary insurance. This effect alone contributes with &#x20AC;234 million negative.</p>
          <p>On slide 12, this is our regular income which was more or less stable. What you can see here is higher income from fixed-interest securities and from loans and correspondingly lower income from dividends hence overall a slight decline of only &#x20AC;29 million.</p>
          <p>Next slide 13, that is a net result from disposals, bigger numbers here. Fixed-interest securities, as I said before, we rearranged our portfolio into a favorable direction, a shift from structured products to corporate bonds, which came along with losses from disposal, losses which were to a large extent recognized before on the balance sheet and were now just channeled through the P&amp;L. The disposals from equities brought an improved result and when I take together the overall income and expenses from equities taking also into account the impact from the derivatives with equities as underlying and including the change in unrealized gains, then I have an almost neutral result which demonstrates that even in these very difficult capital market circumstances, we were well hedged as we always said. The preceding first quarter of 2001 was dominated by very high gains from early disposals of investment, especially equities before the stock markets collapsed.</p>
          <p>Next slide, write-ups/write-downs. We overall have an improvement of cash &#x2013; of non-cash related write-downs/write-ups on shares and derivatives, which was negatively offset by the impact of the derivatives, which we use to hedge against very low interest rate scenarios. As I mentioned before, this effect alone &#x20AC;234 million negative. On an economic basis we are the winner of this small increase in interest rates because in primary insurance with guarantees, the overall embedded value of the portfolio is favorably impacted by this change. We have negative results from our fixed interest securities, so higher write-downs than write-ups. Total impact was minus 542 million.</p>
          <p>Now on slide 15, there is an overview of the segment results. Too many numbers on one slide, I am sorry, but let me spend a little bit of time to explain it. First, the dark blue bars are the result of this year, the light blue bars of first quarter 2008. And now from left to right, the technical result this is premiums, minus losses, minus expenses for the benefit of the policyholders, minus underwriting expenses, plus technical interest on reserves. Technical interest, this is risk-free rate on the technical result, respectively in primary life and health; this is also the amount which we need to grant it to the policyholders. The operating results includes the remaining investment income beyond the technical interest, be it positive or negative, and other non-technical result components. The consolidated result includes all other non-operating items like tax, goodwill depreciation, currency effect, and finance cost.</p>
          <p>All segments have positive technical results. In reinsurance also was a positive impact from the sale of Europ&#xE4;ische being part of the investment results which hasn't impacted more on the operating result than on the technical result, because this has nothing to do with the risk-free rate applied to the technical interest &#x2013; to the technical result. In primary insurance we were suffering from an investment result being smaller than the technical result and due to the impact especially of the financial crisis and the depreciation of interest rate hedges, the operating results came in more negative that the technical result which is not normal under normal circumstances.</p>
          <p>Taking into account also the depreciation of the goodwill of Bank Austria Creditanstalt Versicherung, ERGO Daum in Korea, and ERGO in Italy with 81 million goodwill impairment overall; that brings us to the overall negative result for the primary insurance which we would not regard as being something sustainable. I am convinced that we tackled the problems coming from the acquisitions in a better economic environment little bit more swiftly perhaps than some others do.</p>
          <p>The Munich Re result is not the pure &#x2013; the group result is not the pure sum of the segment results, but it also takes into account consolidation effects like the consolidation of the gain from the sale of Europ&#xE4;ische Reiseversicherung from Munich Re AG reinsurance to ERGO.</p>
          <p>Some remarks on the segments, starting with primary insurance segment, the overview on slide 17. Gross premiums written plus 2.6%, technical results minus 24.5%, non-technical results reflects an investment income which was lower than the technical interest. This investment result shown here in the left corner was 771 million. This is adjusted for the unit-linked business and it was mainly affected by write-downs on these interest rate hedges, as I mentioned a couple of times. Operating results, 77 million, and consolidated result including goodwill impairments and taxes minus 72 million.</p>
          <p>Premium development on the next slide 18; negative foreign exchange effect came from the Polish zloty, the Turkish lira, and the Korean won. This was more than compensated by the effect of the acquisitions. And as you can see in the bottom of that slide, we now have a very healthy break down by segment with one-third coming from each of the lines of business property; casualty, life and health insurance.</p>
          <p>First a closer look on property-casualty insurance. We had stable premium income as the Daum acquisition compensates for the negative foreign exchange effect and for a decline from German motor business. The decrease in technical interest was due to lower risk-free rates which was -which were applied to the technical reserve. We also had some higher claims expenses in Germany and abroad. This is also visible in the next slide 20, which shows the development of the combined ratio. The reason for this increase in comparison to last year's first that we have a &#x2013; had a very positive one-off effect in the preceding year. I had, at that time, told you very clearly that this 87.8% was never regarded as being sustainable at the current combined ratio. The current one is due to the strong winter in Germany with, for example, some tap water losses which we had and also increased losses abroad due to the difficult economic conditions.</p>
          <p>So far with primary property-casualty, a few words on primary life, page 21. Premium income was up 5.5%. Adjusted for the first time consolidation of Bank Austria Creditanstalt Versicherung, it was a decline of &#x20AC;40 million. Net expenses for claims and benefits increased also due to the BACAV acquisition and due to lower negative impact from unit linked business. Both also &#x2013; were also reflected in our technical interest. Investment result was falling short of income from technical interest, main reason again write-down on interest rate hedges.</p>
          <p>On slide 22, development of ERGO's new business. First to look on the statutory numbers, the annual premium equivalent went down by almost 33%, which looks awful but when we have a closer look on it, it becomes clear that this is not a true reflection of the distribution power of companies. The regular premium goes down by 40%, and this is mainly due to previous years 4th Riester step. Adjusted for it the regular premiums go down just &#x2013; for just 11.6% and in that minus 11.6% there have also a spillover effect which were in favor of the 2008 new business in the first couple of months from 2007 where we had a year-end rally. We had on the sales statistics you can see or you cannot see but I'll tell you that there are very clear positive trends with an APE in the first quarter for Germany going up by 12.8%, which is due to very good developments in bank and broker channel. Single premium business anyway went up by 31.5%, which was due to &#x2013; mainly to the acquisition of BACAV with a strong positive impact for the single premium business in the international part of the business.</p>
          <p>Now to health primary insurance; premium income was up driven by premium adjustments and higher premiums of our Spanish operations. The increase &#x2013; I'm on slide 23. The increase in net expenses for claims and benefits is caused by the rising healthcare cost and higher allocation to provision for premium refunds. The investment results increased remarkably, influenced by lower impairments and losses on disposals from equities. So far with primary insurance, now to reinsurance.</p>
          <p>First, the IFRS numbers for the first results, before I hand over to Torsten for the more recent developments. Premium growth was driven by acquisitions and foreign exchange effect. Technical result, this suffered a bit from lower technical interest due to the decline of the risk-free rates, but it was nevertheless resilient and more or less stable or slightly increasing technical results driven by lower loss ratios in property-casualty. Non-technical result was slightly down. Investment result was also down, in spite of the inclusion of the proceeds from the sale of Europ&#xE4;ische Reiseversicherung to ERGO. Now this is a fairly solid investment result for reinsurance in view of the market impact and in view of the fact that our asset manager MEAG favorably restructured the fixed interest portfolio. The operating result was stable with &#x20AC;851 million. Consolidated result was up to &#x20AC;665 million, very satisfactory.</p>
          <p>Quick look on premium development on 26, there was a impact from the acquisition of Midland for property-casualty and Sterling for health reinsurance, and some foreign exchange effect.</p>
          <p>On slide 27, an overview of the development of the property-casualty business. The increase due to the Midland acquisition was &#x20AC;202 million, and this was together with the FX effect offsetting the reduction of premium volume due to the cancellation of less profitable treaties at 1-1 renewal. The decline of net expenses for claims and benefits was due to lower man-made and NatCat losses which we will also see on the next slide. So NatCat losses and major man-made losses were clearly below the five-year average. And also in April there were no major &#x2013; no major events. Therefore, so up to now the year is performing quite well in property-casualty insurance.</p>
          <p>Last but not least, life and health reinsurance, segment result here was affected by extraordinarily high operating expenses. In life we saw an expansion in the U.S. and we cancelled some unprofitable business in the U.K. Also there is Sterling acquisition contributing some 184 million. We had stable technical interest due to the long-term nature of the treaties, and we apply a rather conservative risk-free rate overall in general. High operating expenses have to do with the cancellation of the contracts in the U.K., because it required an extraordinary deferred acquisition cost amortization here. So nothing to worry about it. It's just a fewer technical effect, which is necessary after such a cancellation. So far with the numbers from the first quarter and before, I'll say a few words on the outlook for the year.</p>
          <p>Now up to Torsten to talk about the new business development in reinsurance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning and good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. In the next few minutes I would like to lead you through the latest developments of April 1 renewal, and some remarks on our other business opportunities, particularly large transactions we were able to conclude. I'll start on slide 31 with April 1 renewal. April 1 is our second major renewal date in the year for our treaty book in non-life. The premium volume &#x2013; treaty premium volume is about &#x20AC;1.25 billion, which was renewable.</p>
          <p>In general, we can summarize that the positive trend of the general renewal regarding price increases, price changes did continue, could even be enforced. When we look at the various markets and remember the three markets, we had to renew were Japan, Korea and the U.S. When we look at the various business segments and lines of business in these markets, the picture of line by line, segment by segment is still heterogeneous. That means we see very different price behavior from the various market participants from stable to eroding rates up to very nice double-digit price increase in other segments. Cedants become more sensitive to financial security. We particularly observed that in the U.S. Cat business and in the Japanese Cat business where particularly the larger layers and the top layers requiring larger capacities are placed with the solid companies, solid reinsurance companies.</p>
          <p>As far as the Munich Re portfolio is concerned and I'll come to the figure &#x2013; to the figures in a minute. NatCat business drove the price increases for our portfolio. That is not surprising considering that the catastrophe business in the April 1 renewal contributes to a larger share to our portfolio than in January 1 renewal. And we continued with our underwriting strategy which was twofold. On one hand we decided to increase our participations where we could negotiate price increases and gave up treaties, particularly proportionate treaties with insufficient rates. And our second pillar of the underwriting strategy was, as described in our analyst conference in March, we applied our risk management strategy to withdraw or to reduce our exposures from recession-related exposures like D&amp;O or credit.</p>
          <p>I come to the figures in the chart. As mentioned, 1.2 billion &#x2013; 1.24 billion premium to be renewed. The turnover in our portfolio was quite substantial. We declined or reduced 25%, almost 26%, of our portfolio for the reasons described. At the same time, we could increase our business, particularly in property and natural catastrophe business, and took on another 200 million of new premium. All-in-all that makes reduction of our premium volume by 11%. The price change, after all exposure changes was in this renewal 7.2%. Comparing the new with the old portfolio, and that is the real improvement in the profitability. How can that be explained? It's exactly for the reasons described. We wrote more of the profitable and improved natural catastrophe business and gave up some of the very flat or the deteriorating proportionate business. Here particularly the casualty business, be it in Asia, be it in the U.S., was unsatisfactory, and we decided to reduce our exposures here. I'll give you a few examples later on.</p>
          <p>One remark on D&amp;O business. You will remember we prepared ourselves and described it in the analyst conference in March for a possible longer recession, worldwide recession and identified various segments in the reinsurance book where we assume they could be negatively affected by higher loss frequencies and severities. Among these segments was credit business and the D&amp;O &#x2013; financial D&amp;O and non-financial D&amp;O business. As already announced and described, we continued with our underwriting policy to withdraw or to reduce its exposures from these segments. In the April 1 renewal we had one larger treaty which was affected by this underwriting policy. We still think that this is the right underwriting policies in today's environment. We know, of course, that particularly the credit business or the D&amp;O business from financial institutions show price increases these days. We, however, think that these price increases are still insufficient to cover the drastically changed in the &#x2013; or increase in the exposure and it is quite obvious in the picture when I say, we don't insure or reinsure burning houses; that means foreseeable losses are not part of our business.</p>
          <p>I've come to slide 32, and that is &#x2013; gives a few examples of April 1 renewal of our decisions in the portfolio. In the upper part, you see cases where we've reduced our exposures; financial institutions as already described. I would like to inform you what we mean here with the Japanese surplus treaties where we reduced our exposures. That was business in the past which was placed in a sort of bouquet approach by the Japanese clients. Meaning the reinsurers were forced to take on surplus business into their books as part of the overall placements. This business practices &#x2013; placement practice could be broken up to a larger extent in the last renewal, meaning from the client perspective to secure the very limited and rare cat capacity. They were willing to compromise and gave up this bouquet approach, and we took advantage of this change in the placement practice and gave up some of the property surplus business from Japan.</p>
          <p>As far as the markets are concerned, Korea was the most disappointing market among the three markets in April. Korea is historically a difficult market. We decided to reduce our export substantially. Korea personal accident here mentioned is only one example. The whole market was difficult. And volume reductions, the premium reductions in Korea was about 40% in our portfolio, again for insufficient prices.</p>
          <p>Growth opportunities as mentioned, these are the cat scenarios where the capacity was limited for two reasons. One reason is more and more reinsurers reached their capacity limit because of the reduced capital base on one side, but also because of less available or very expensive repossession on the other side. In Japan we had a second trend, the stronger yen cost more euro capacity or dollar capacity from the foreign reinsurers so that some of the reinsurers came to their capacity limit.</p>
          <p>I would like to use the opportunity to describe our perception of the market behavior since January. We see price changes and capacity constraints, particularly in those segments with high capital intensities like the natural catastrophe business or in segments which were affected by losses last year like the offshore business. In these segments catastrophe business, price increases U.S. in the order of 10 to 25%, in markets outside the U.S. in the order of 10%.</p>
          <p>In other segments like aviation and fire industrial business rate did stabilize, but the clear improvement is not visible yet. We have then, with a few exceptions like motor U.K. and the Australian markets, a very let's say unsatisfactory development in the volume business, in the volume insurance businesses, usually the retail and small commercial business. Here local capacity is still available and the original insurance rates which affect us through proportionate business are still stable and not at a level where we expect them to be.</p>
          <p>How do we see the concession in the future in this environment? We do expect that we see different underwriting policies and renewal strategies by the various insurance companies. You will see, let's say, companies &#x2013; reinsurance companies which will able to offer sufficient cat capacities on the basis of a sound capital base. Those companies, and we include ourselves the Munich Re here in this segment, those companies will be able to take advantage of better pricing and will be able to use their cat capacity &#x2013; their unchanged cat capacity to leverage the overall portfolio, that means to attract other business opportunities and let's say persuade or convince clients to replace other attractive business with these companies.</p>
          <p>Alternative B the other segments, you will see reinsurance companies with tight capital base and maybe with a higher dependence on the retro market which is not available or only available to a little limited extent these days. For such reinsurance companies, you will see in our opinion a change in the underwriting strategy moving away from the better price but higher exposed catastrophe business and probably jumping on the available less price or worse price volume mass business. As far as Munich Re is concerned, I mentioned it we have the capacity available. We have no need to change our strategy these days and we are very confident to take advantage during the course of 2009 of this available capacity.</p>
          <p>I am on page 33 now. There are a few pictures on the coming renewals, that is July 1. July 1, 1 billion in our portfolio, 1 billion premium income. Markets to be renewed are the U.S., Australia, and Latin America. We expect like in April an improved price development particularly under the natural catastrophe business. So April was already substantially better with the 7% rate increase. We expect similar outcome or even better in the July 1 renewal. We see particularly under the U.S. cat scenarios first signs of capacity shortages. We see, however, no substantial change in the casualty markets yet. We see on the other hand further opportunities for better securities and see the possibility that more companies have the demand to place extraordinary larger proportional reinsurance transaction to &#x2013; as an alternative to recapitalize their company.</p>
          <p>On the next slide, I would give you the description of the latest developments as far as large transactions are concerned. You remember that we already indicated in the last analyst calls that there are some larger transactions underway. We were conservative and did not make projections for 2010 until we knew or know now that they could be realized and these large transactions affect the life and health business. We were able in the first quarter to conclude nine such transactions in life and health. They all come from North America or Asia. The portfolio of this new transactions consist of smaller, medium sized and also one large transaction, which we could write. They are not reflected yet in the quarter one figures, but you will see the impact as from the next quarter onwards.</p>
          <p>What was the motivation and what is covered? Clients negotiated these new reinsurance transactions in most cases exclusively with Munich Re to seek and to achieve capital release, to meet solvency requirements, and so to speak indirectly recapitalize the company. The risk we cover under these transactions are only biometric risk. We in no case assume any investment risk from the insurance companies. The premium volume on an annualized basis will be greater than &#x20AC;2 billion. The value added on new business is in the low three digit million euro region. The transactions are concluded in most cases for five-year terms. So that was a substantial and remarkable success for us. We see here clear reflection of the perception of the perceived capital strength of the Munich Re. We are the first address for these sort of new reinsurance demands.</p>
          <p>That's it from my side. J&#xF6;rg, I hand over back to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Torsten. And what Torsten described in his last remarks is exactly what drives us to increase our expectation for the gross premiums written for 2009. For reinsurance instead of 21 to 22 billion, we now say 22.5 to 24 billion. This would be an increase in comparison to 2008 of up to roughly 10%. Together with primary insurance and consolidation effect, we now expect gross premiums written between 39 to 41 billion. This would be some plus 8%. The combined ratio in reinsurance is expected to be some 97%, taking into account natural catastrophes of 6.5%. Combined ratio in primary insurance is expected to come again at very good terms with less than 95% in spite of the somewhat difficult start into the year.</p>
          <p>With regards to the return on investment, we anticipate return on investment, which is significantly below our pre-crisis 4.5% guidance. There could be further write-downs if the financial and economic crisis continues and you can rely on our consistency and on our very swift handling of these losses, because we can afford to do so. But it should be nothing which should get us into any trouble. We expect the risk-free rates to stay at a very low level and with our low exposure to equities, this also means lower expected returns.</p>
          <p>To generalize, in no scenario we will be ideally positioned and would be the winner, in a way, of an outcome of the capital market. But I also do not see any scenario which would seriously jeopardize our stability. Munich Re is never only about return or return on equity without taking into account the risk involved and therefore we also express our over-the-cycle target in terms of return on risk-adjusted capital. The number of 15% is ambitious but it is to stand. The focus is still and will be on the preservation of our sound capital because, as Torsten I think quite clearly described, this gives us the competitive edge.</p>
          <p>And with that I would like to hand back to Christian, and we look forward to your questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, now the floor is open for your question. So please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />. We will take our first question today from Michael Huttner from JP Morgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. I had two questions. The first one, you referred many times and in some details to these derivatives or hedging transactions in the life primary. And this is slide 17, you mentioned that's included in figure 77 million. I'm really confused about this, because I would have thought the hedging not only cost something but also had benefit somewhere and I can't see the benefit. So I just wondered if you could actually give the numbers again and say where I see the benefit and how much I see? Where I see the costs and how much it is? That would really help me.</p>
          <p>The other question is can you give the RORAC split between primary and reinsurance? My suspicion is the primary is again lagging quite a lot and it does raise a question of why you insist on keeping that business? That's it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael, this is J&#xF6;rg speaking. On the derivative, you &#x2013; I don't know whether this expression exists, but you hit the nail here. We have an impact of minus &#x20AC;234 million on our investment income and on a net basis it is something like &#x20AC;50 million. Where do you see the benefits? I can safely say nowhere in the accounts, and this is a challenge. But on an economic basis, it protects our policyholders and our shareholders from low interest rates environment impact. And, therefore, on an economic basis it is really value creating as demonstrated in the embedded value disclosure a couple of weeks ago.</p>
          <p>With regards to the performance of primary insurance, I think these are now some effects which we see here which lead to the negative result which we do not worry need to much because they are obviously not sustainable. Overall, ERGO is doing a great job. They are cutting down costs. They are now faced, like everybody else, with a difficult economic environment. We do not know exactly what it will bring to us also volume wise. But they have a good business portfolio. They have a strong distribution. So mid-term I am very optimistic about it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you have a very large number?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, this is negative now, as you can imagine.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Negative. Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At the moment, yeah, because the return is based on our net result adjusted for the interest on risk-free elements of capital. And, therefore, with a negative net profit we have a negative number here; this is clear. But sustainably, it should perform inline with the overall group with international health and with reinsurance. Thank you, Michael.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now move to our next question today, which comes from Spencer Horgan from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello there. Couple of things, please, if I could. Firstly, with these life reinsurance quota shares, could you give us a hint as to how much risk capital based contracts would consume? And maybe also whether you see still a pipeline for further prospective deals?</p>
          <p>And second thing is with the April renewal, obviously the magnitude of default from a premium perspective looks quite alarming, but I wonder if you could tell us how much of that is related to shift from quota share to excess loss? I think you were sort of hinting that that was the case, and therefore maybe the underlying picture is not quite as precipitous as it initially looks.</p>
          <p>And then the third point, J&#xF6;rg, just a point of clarification. With the non-operating profit line we've got, we've obviously got goodwill, we've got finance cost. Could you just confirm what else is in the other is in the foreign exchange movements or is there anything else in the other non-operating? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Spencer. Torsten, are you prepared?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So let me start with life. The economic risk capital, of course, we do not disclose on a treaty-by-treaty basis but it's in the low 300 &#x2013; in the low three digit million reaching, so not very substantial. The reasons, of course, that we cover the low margin, if you want, biometric risk, not any other risk of the portfolio. But no further break down to treaties here.</p>
          <p>Life quota shares for the pipeline, difficult at this point in time. We do not want to promise too much. We'll come back when we have more to report. I can maybe give a hint. So far it's affected only life and health. We are also under discussion on non-life without promise that it will materialize in the coming months. So I do now want to promise too early before we are not very sure whether we can deliver here. But there are certainly more to come. The activity is there. The demand seems to increase. What was the other question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>April renewal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>April renewal, I can give you a split of the change of the portfolio. Treaty book in 2008 was for the April book of business, 70 pro rata, 30 XL. Now it's 60 pro rata, 40 XL. That is a change in split &#x2013; in the premium split were quite substantial for the single renewal date.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And your last question, Spencer, was about the non-operating stuff. This is goodwill depreciation, finance cost, foreign exchange gains and losses, and last but not least this time it is a gain from the repurchase of part of our subordinated bonds. We bought back some &#x20AC;207 million with a net profit impact pre-tax, so with a pre-tax impact of &#x20AC;59 million. And this is part of this number here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks for that. So in future, should we assume the other non-operating is zero apart from foreign exchange and hopefully there's no goodwill, is that fair?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah there's nothing. These were all the major positions which I mentioned before.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now move to our next question today which comes from James Quin from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello. Three questions please. The first one is just on the life reinsurance deal again. I'm just wondering what's &#x2013; are these essentially financial reinsurance types of transactions, rather than essentially pure risk. So I'm just thinking is this essentially purely designed as regulatory arbitrage type of contract? And I suppose just following on from that, what should we think of in terms of sort of IFRS profit margin? One or 2% or would you say a little bit higher?</p>
          <p>The second question I have is on the increase in demand for reinsurance on the P&amp;C side of things, which I have to say does look to be almost non-existent. And I'm just wondering why you would see that as being the case and whether you do see a shift coming down the line in the near-term?</p>
          <p>And then the third question is then just on the change in prices, I mean obviously the price increase in April was a bit better than in the January renewals. Is that essentially due to differences in mix, i.e. a higher focus on cat business, or is it signaling a better underlying shift in the pricing quality? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So let me start, James. Torsten here. Life re the question is it financial re or risk transfer. It's to a very, very large expense risk transfer with margin arbitrage in the treaties, so very marginal accounting arbitrage, pure risk transfer. Non-life, why should they come? For the reasons, actually. Insurance companies are under financial severe conditions that it's an alternative also for non-life. I can only say there are possibilities or transactions under discussion and that is, so to speak, indication for me enough that it could materialize without guarantee that it will come, of course.</p>
          <p>IFRS margin for the life re transaction in the order of 3 to 5%. April 1 renewal, where does the increase come from? Yes, you described it correctly. There are both sectors playing a role. We have premium increase, a rate increase, particularly under the catastrophe business and property business. And at the same time we changed the portfolio mix more into the profitable business where we see the rate increases and with declines or with cancellations of the proportional particularly the casualty type business. So both plays a role which leads to the 7.2% overall profitability improvement vis-&#xE0;-vis 2008.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Perhaps if I could just come back on that quickly. Are you surprised that we're not really seeing any real improvement in anything in rates other than cat and in terms of the demand for reinsurance this is, if anything, probably slightly lower this year than last year. I mean does this come as a surprise to you?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's put it this way. When you look very rationally at the market behavior, to some extent you see rational behavior in a way that the capital intensive segments like natural catastrophe come first under capacity limitations and therefore price increases. So that's a natural behavior in my opinion that makes sense.</p>
          <p>Am I surprised? Yes, I'm also a bit surprised that particularly some very local companies seem not to realize or to recognize that there is a material economic change in the insurance environment from the financial or the recession &#x2013; from the financial crisis or the recession. Meaning, the deterioration in the rates over the last years deteriorated, of course, the performance and now we have a substantial additional impact from deteriorated returns from investments and lower interest environment which leads to a deterioration of the future profitability on an underwriting year basis. And to that extent, yes, it surprised me that there is some resilience, if you want to express it politely, to recognize these changes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Torsten, if I may add something, being responsible here for the accounting. In many local GAAP environments it takes sometime until the losses find their way into the official capitalization, and that makes me so optimistic that we will have a constant trend in the right direction here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, you would see it maybe more of a slow burn thing rather than a step change effectively?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Absolutely, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. All right. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now move to our next question today, which comes from Will Morgan from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon. I've got a couple of questions. The first one is just relating to Solvency II. I know you've talked about this as being a potential opportunity for the reinsurers. I guess, in terms of recent drafts that have been passed, there have been some issues over the diversification benefits perhaps not being as large for some of the bigger companies as previously thought. I just wondered if you could talk a bit about how that impacts on how you view your own internal capital and whether or not you think that might change the way that the demand for reinsurance could emerge over the next number of years.</p>
          <p>And the second question just relates to I guess some of your answers to James' previous questions. With your decision not to pursue with the buyback, I guess that's the new kind of in-vogue decision to not spend your capital buying back your own shares. But obviously you know a depressed market valuation that's maybe not a bad thing to be doing, and I suppose given the level of excess capital that you have and given the low risk and nature of your own balance sheet, which seems to be declining in risk as we move through every quarter. I'm slightly surprise. I mean is that &#x2013; not to ask the same question again, but is there some kind of major pipeline that you really see in terms of opportunity to redeploy that capital down the line, because at the moment it doesn't seem to be there. Your balance sheet seems very risk. I'm just interested to know why you were looking at pulling the buyback for the time being? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Will, just &#x2013; let me start with the latter one before I hand over to Jo Oechslin who has also joined us, our Chief Risk Officer, with regard to the Solvency II potential and to the impact on diversification. With the buyback, we do not exclude it, so we could really resume doing buybacks. The bottleneck is, I would like to remind you, also the revenue result of the local GAAP parent company account, which now stands a little bit below &#x20AC;2 billion. So even there, there is some potential, but having that in mind I would not like to be too aggressive here.</p>
          <p>With regard to the opportunity pipeline, it is less about M&amp;A and much more about business opportunities as Torsten described it. And, therefore, with times going by it could well be that we say as long as the market is not prepared to pay adequate margins for our scarce and valuable capital resource, we could well go back to doing share buyback. We do not exclude it generally. Now to Jo Oechslin on diversification under Solvency II.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Will. Regarding diversification, I do agree with you that the financial crisis and what we have seen will probably lead to the fact that the risk models are being reviewed in a number of dimensions, and that includes correlation assumptions, diversification assumptions. I think the trend will be that one is paying more attention to calibrate risk models not primarily to historic events, but also much more to possible stresses that may not have occurred in the past. And that is an area where Munich Re's risk model is actually advanced in that sense and I would like to draw your attention on the analyst conference we had in March, on our ERC disclosure. You can see there that the total diversification that we are accounting for is between 20 and 25% of our simple sum risk. And if you compare that to a number of other disclosures and economic risk capital in the industry, you will see that this diversification number that Munich Re shows is considerably lower than others.</p>
          <p>That is driven by two effects, I would say. That is driven by first of all strong assumptions on tail dependencies. What our model assumes is that if one thing goes wrong, another thing goes wrong at the same time, and these model components are not necessarily only calibrated to historic data, but we've also included and assumed stresses that we have not seen in the past and this is reflected in this tail dependency. And secondly it's about fungibility of capital; that is also reflected in this risk model. It is essentially reflecting the fact that we cannot take capital out or may not be able to freely take capital out of a sufficiently capitalized entity and put it into an entity that has a capital shortfall. And if one considers these effects reasonably and correctly, there is a reasonable diversification number. But these numbers may change going forward, but we're confident that we're reflecting them in our model pretty accurately.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, a just a follow-up on that, if there's any &#x2013; I mean as far as the latest version of Solvency II, I think the group support component wasn't put through, so I think the diversification benefit looked like they're going to be significantly smaller. And has that changed your calculation, your own diversification benefit and is that potentially going to change &#x2013; I mean could that mean that actually, if you really believe in your own diversification number, that you could possible be of greater use to even quite large groups now that aren't getting the same diversification benefits they thought they would get?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. I think there's two components. First of all with regards to the situation at Munich Re, I would say that there is a lot of risk that we have concentrated in single large legal entities, in particular on the reinsurance side. We're having about up to 75% of the P&amp;C risk concentrated in one legal entity, and almost as much on the life reinsurance side. So our group may be less dependent on the concept of group supervision; that's point number one.</p>
          <p>Point number two is indeed the calculation in Solvency II of the SCR will still include diversification. So that's not because of group support hasn't been coming through. The SCR will still include diversification. The point is whether you can realize that diversification when you're organized in a kind of setup with many relatively small legal entities.</p>
          <p>So the question is one of risk capital and the other question is one of how do you cover that. And that may actually be the real challenge for groups with a lot of small legal entities, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jo, if you allow, I would like to add something there. Perhaps general trend to a hardening of the prudent supervisory regulation, is for us not a major burden, because we are anyway very comfortably capitalized. But it's perhaps not only negative for us, but provides us with opportunities in reinsurance when life gets harder for our clients. So this is something one should have in mind, when thinking longer-term about Solvency II.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now move to our next question today, which comes from Jean-Francois Tremblay from RBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, I have two questions, one for J&#xF6;rg and one for Torsten. Will start with J&#xF6;rg. Now you decided to sell some of your structured assets. Can you tell us a bit more about the rationale there in the sense if you were collecting cash flows as a lot of people tell us they are doing, why sell now? And can you compare sort of values realized compared to the marks you had put on those assets?</p>
          <p>And then my second question to Torsten, coming the June, July renewals you have about 1 billion in premiums up for renewal. You are now &#x2013; essentially do you think that many of your competitors will have to pull back from high severity, low frequency business and do you intend to use your financial strength to potentially write significantly more of that type of business, more cat business, for instance, as clearly one segment is marketed according to the analysis you could potentially gain on margins or potentially increase your returns?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jean-Francois, thank you for these questions. First of all, this was a normal rearrangement done by our asset managers. So we did not intervene here. But I admit that we were asked whether we would be prepared to take the losses where they appear, and we were, because we could afford to do so. It was not more for us or more or less not more for us than a realization of losses which had already been recognized on the balance sheet. And the logic behind it sounded to me convincing that we saw quite attractive chances, especially in corporate bonds, but we did not want to expand our exposure to credit risks overall. So this is basically the logic behind it. And apart from it, these were deliberate and autonomous decisions of our investment managers here. Torsten, with the second.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. July 1 renewal, you are right, it's a cat renewal. You are also right the competitors may probably pull back or reduce capacity, are we prepared to expand? Very possible. Depends, of course, on two questions, how do the prices develop? In the past we did not apply our full capacity in the U.S. for price reasons. And the other question is the capacity must, as part of our risk management, of course, and we have maximum limitations. But we are certainly a company which has a very reasonable capacity available without any need to change for capital limitations, the underwriting strategy. So we will most likely benefit if your scenario should come true.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now move to our next question today which comes from Marc Thiele from UBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, there. Two questions, please. My first question is regarding the primary P&amp;C business. There has been an increase in the cost ratio, and I was wondering if you could give us an indication how that will develop going forward? Was the increase year on year driven by a change in the mix of business and when we will see some of the cost reductions showing up in the IFRS numbers?</p>
          <p>Then on the primary life side, I was wondering if you could give us a feel for the result component, in particular if I look at the technical life result that went up from 38 to 120 million, is that primarily driven by mortality gains? Can you give us a feel for what did the result components look like based on investment result, mortality result, and the cost result?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Marc. I'll start with the latter. In primary life, the major deviation to the preceding year comes from unit-linked business. Now that means that there was negative contribution from unit-linked business with some 36 million, which was roughly 150 better than in the preceding year where it was even more negative. And to the logic here it is part of our investment income, and it is then shifted 100% to the policyholder, this investment income. So the net effect is zero, but for technical reasons we make it part of technical interest and part of the net expenses for claims and benefit. And this is the main driver for this increase in the technical interest here.</p>
          <p>Now the second question about the expenses in primary insurance, part of it is our new acquisition Daum Direct &#x2013; ERGO Daum Direct in Korea which has a higher expense ratio than the average group. Also we have some higher acquisition costs here. Overall the cost savings have already shown up in the last couple of quarters quite remarkably, and we expect most of the new cost savings from the latest program to show up in 2010. So that is well underway and I have no doubt that it gets implemented.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now move to our next question today, which comes from Brian Shea from Bank of America-Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I have three quick questions, if you will permit me. The first two are on the life quota share deal. Torsten, the profit margin you've talked about of 3 to 5%, can you just say just how does that come out? Is that profit signature fairly even over time and fairly immediate or is there any delay or back-end loading to the five-year duration of the contracts?</p>
          <p>Secondly I was doing some math on the &#x2013; this contract. If you're earning a margin of 3 to 5% on 2 billion of premiums and the capital allocated is low triple digit million, it sounds like the pre &#x2013; I'm assuming the margin is pre-tax, it sounds like the pre-tax return on capital you're looking at is in the mid to upper 20s. I just wanted to ask if I'm doing that right or &#x2013; that sounds like a very good margin. I was wondering if I made any mistakes there?</p>
          <p>And then the third question for J&#xF6;rg on the reinvestment yield that was 3.9% in the first quarter. It's awfully difficult to forecast how this is going to &#x2013; you know for how long that will keep coming down and the level at which it'll settle. If you could &#x2013; just assuming rates and spreads stay unchanged, if you could answer that directly, that would be helpful. If you would rather not answer that directly, maybe just give me an indication of the yield at which money is going in and the yield at which money is coming out of your portfolio. That would be helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian, let me start with life quota share. The IFRS margins, I think that was your first question, if there is a delay or how smoothly will they come in? Very stable over the time. So no delay before you will see the impact in the accounting.</p>
          <p>Second question was margin on our allocated capital. Usually &#x2013; as usual in these cases we don't release transaction-related capital figures and do sort of RoRACs, but it's right that they are well above our minimum requirement of 15% that is true.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With regards to the investment income, 3.9% running yield for our coupon and including all other running components, it's slowly coming down. I would guess it's in the order between 20 to 30 basis points a year, if risk-free rates stay at the current very low level. But I think it will then bottom down or find a bottom there. But there's still a declining trend.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, I'm sorry, it'll find a bottom, you mean maybe one more year rather than many years of 20 to 30 basis points.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So since the average coupon is at the moment roughly where you see the running yield at the moment and it's coming down, if we reinvest at a rate slightly above 3%, and we have an average duration in the portfolio in the order of five years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. That's great. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Brian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now move to our next question today, which comes from Fabrizio Croce from Kepler. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Fabrizio Croce, actually. Thank you very much for taking me. I have only a couple of questions. First of all in terms of biometric risk, which you've stated to have increased. How does this transaction actually impact your pandemic risk budget and particularly what are the limit you applied on this new contract in that terms?</p>
          <p>The second one is taking that your worst case scenario should become real, which means that several companies still didn't understand what's going on, what is the default rate you expect for the primary insurance sector?</p>
          <p>And last very short one, for the structured product portfolio you further decreased the amount of this portfolio. Now what is the future of this portfolio? Will it further be decreased or is it now at a stable size?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Torsten, can you start with the biometric risk and the impact on our pandemic budget?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, what is the impact? The impact on an overall portfolio basis is not substantial because of this deal or by writing these deals. How have we done the analysis? Remember two to three years ago we have already informed you how we see pandemic risk and how we manage them in our overall risk management by applying &#x2013; by analyzing, by applying limits and we characterized at that time that the overall exposure for new Munich Re is in the order, in the region of larger catastrophe, so very digestible on an overall basis for the portfolio. We analyzed these treaties here as well. We did not put limits into these treaties, but the marginal additional contribution from these treaties to the overall exposure is limited and does not change the overall exposure for the portfolio, so that we did not have to make any changes because of these treaties in our pandemic risk management.</p>
          <p>Other question, default of insurance companies in case of severe recession. To be quite honest, I have no idea. I would not like to speculate on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>However, perhaps what we can add here is that we have an eye on it, yeah, so whenever there is a major transaction, we look at reducing the credit risk involved on our side to almost zero, but we do not anticipate major defaults here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe one remark that once J&#xF6;rg mentioned it, as you know &#x2013; might remember, that part of our risk management strategy today is not only to avoid recession-related insurance risk, but also to avoid or not to write any type of reinsurance transactions which either contain liquidity demand from the Munich Re or cause a credit risk for the Munich Re. And that is absolutely unchanged, and so far we monitor very closely what will happen. We do not change any sort of credit risk for our company, but concrete default rate assumption on a worldwide basis are not available here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And your last question was on the structured credit portfolio where we were, thank God, anyway only exposed to a very low extent, but we even brought it further down. If you take out Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac stuff, then it's only 1.5 billion. The portfolio is okay now and we could even increase it at good terms. So it's purely up to the tactics of our investment managers. But I would not expect it to go up dramatically with so many attractive alternatives at the moment on the corporate bond portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Many thanks to you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now move to our next question today, which is from Raghu Hariharan from Fox-Pitt Kelton. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good afternoon, gentlemen. This is Raghu Hariharan, Fox-Pitt Kelton. Excuse me, I just had three questions, if I may please. On the de-risking, which you mentioned before where you've been selling or taking realized losses, I guess, on structured bonds and other products, I was just wondering could you give us some color on what your risk appetite is so we can figure out or we can try to expect what levels of realized losses we can see going forward? You mentioned hybrid debt which is 436 million which is there and you mentioned the structured products. I was just wondering can you give us some color on risk appetite and any trigger points that we should watch out for?</p>
          <p>The second one was on the interest rate hedges. Obviously, in an accounting view, it doesn't look too great. I was just wondering while there is an economic benefit which is clearly understood, do you get an S&amp;P benefit. Usually S&amp;P gives you say a 50% benefit, I guess, on hedges, and there are other regulatory capital benefits, so that if you can give us some flavor on that please?</p>
          <p>The third one was on reinvestment opportunity of risk or in terms of the existing book and in terms of new premiums. Can you give us a rough sense of where these monies are going? Are they going into roughly the same asset split or are you feeling bold enough to get into corporate bonds or any other asset classes, so that we can get a sense of where the running yield might end up at? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll start with your last question, reinvestment opportunities more or less same asset mix at the movement, so quite boring. First, de-risking further realized losses, so I think our investment portfolio is extremely transparent now. Where are we exposed? It's with the loss bearing bank bonds where we also had part of the losses. We had some losses on the government bond portfolio, mainly Eastern European government securities where we felt that there is more downside than upside potential, but it's now rather contained. So you can have a look on the annex to the presentation and you'll see everything. I would not anticipate further losses, but if the crisis go on it's unavoidable that we have also losses on the corporate bond portfolio because the yields are so attractive that they allow for some impairments there. So overall, I think everything is well balanced.</p>
          <p>Accounting of the swaption notes and these derivatives, you're right. There is no accounting &#x2013; no positive accounting impact visible and it's just fluctuating up and down always through the P&amp;L from quarter to quarter. I think everybody understands that this is a very sound and prudent protection against the reinvestment risk with positive benefit for the MCEV calculation and also as far as I know we get also credit in the Standard &amp; Poor's model calculation. And therefore, there it has an positive impact on our ALM capital charge, so less ALM capital charge in that system for regulation as far as I know not, no positive impact. But since we are anyway so far out of any critical zone here and under Solvency II where we have a total balance sheet approach, this then will take into account all risks and also all mitigating elements. Therefore, I am very pleased to have these swaptions, no matter what the accounting impact might be. Does it answer your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you very much, very clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now move to our next question today which comes from Stephan Kalb from Sal Oppenheim. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hello. I actually have one related question on the German primary life business. The first one is since derivative is to protect you against low interest rates, it surprises me a little that it has declined in value during the first quarter of the year because the long-term and the medium-term interest rates have actually declined further in the first quarter and therefore I would have expected that there would no decline. Was it just the volatility or was it some other factor I didn't see?</p>
          <p>And then I would be interested to know how the value of this derivative would move over time if interest rates would stay where they are? Would it just diminish in value over time and how long is this running?</p>
          <p>And second question is on your new life business. In new life business, even if you adjust for the risk of step-ups, it's a double-digit decline. Is it something we should expect for the full year or if there are some counter movement or some activities on the distribution to stop such decline?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Stephan, thank you. It was exactly like you assume that it was the volatility which drove the decline of the value of the derivatives in the first quarter. They have, as far as I know, duration between 10 to 15 years. The later tranches have been treated already with hedge accounting, and therefore you wouldn't see the same impact on our P&amp;L as you see with the early tranches. We intend to continue immunizing our business portfolio against this very severe risk of a very low interest environment but not only with derivatives but also with our other ALM principles also with the duration of our investments over time.</p>
          <p>Your last question was about the new life business, was the decline due to the Riester 4th step. This was particularly high in the first quarter. So over time it will mitigate in the course of this year, it will smoothen somewhat. And our current forecast foresees an increase in the annual premium equivalent of the business. Let's hope that it comes &#x2013; it's mainly dependent on the further economic development and of the general mood of the people, whether they are really prepared to invest in old age provisions. They should. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now move on to our next question, which comes from Michael Haid from Cheuvreux. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thank you. Good afternoon. Two related questions here on the primary life insurance. Regarding the sale of life insurance in the first quarter, I understand that the APE are down 33% in Germany, and if you exclude the Riester effect, the negative effect is still some minus 10%. On slide 22, you mentioned minus 43%, and then you mentioned also something about a success of sale which have increased sales by 8%. Can you put some clarity in here? I did not fully understand that?</p>
          <p>Second question, you mentioned the 234 million loss from the hedging &#x2013; from derivative hedging against the lower interest rates and the net effect, if I heard correctly, was 50 million &#x2013; 50. Why is it higher than the 90/10 split rule suggest?</p>
          <p>And last question, I assume that you have some discretion on the write-down of goodwill of Bank Austria and the other companies. Why did you decide to write it down? Are there any economic implication or is it just accounting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, let me start with last question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When you talk about goodwill, it's dependent on the business plans involved. We had a revision of the business plan, which was driven by the financial crisis, less favorable than the previous version. There is some discretion with regard to the level of optimism you applied. I am not known for an excessive level of optimism and therefore since we could afford tackling that problem immediately, we wanted to do it. It's basically also due to the high capitalization and therefore I think it's also a sign or realism that we had to correct this business plans down. So I would not regard it as being conservative, but realistic what we did there.</p>
          <p>With regard to the sale to the life new business, yeah, I did not make it adequately clear. First, as you can seen on slide 22, in these boxes that are the official numbers on a statutory basis with regular premium coming down so drastically from Riester minus 48.5% for Germany. What we show in the comments is if we adjust for it, then this regular premium which have come down by only 11.6% and the calculation which I added here was based on just sales statistics where &#x2013; which have nothing to do with the booking of all these contracts and there was this spillover effect from 2007 to 2008, so business which was sold at the end of 2007 but could not been brought into the system in '07 but in '08. And if we adjust even for that effect then we have a very &#x2013; a clearly positive trend in the first quarter, and this is said here on the right hand side with a growth of 12.8%. This is sales statistics but it's a best number we can provide you with.</p>
          <p>What I said before the APE expectation for the year positive, I have to correct it. Alexander Becker  has just said it to me it's adjusted for the Riester effect. But this is a right way of looking at it because with Riester and also dynamic life policies this comes automatically, and what we look at thoroughly that is how do our sales organizations perform, and this gives us some reason for optimism, yeah.</p>
          <p>So then with the hedging derivative instrument, part of these are written in Belgium. Wherever we are exposed to the guarantees, we look at ways of mitigating these effects and there we have a different split between policyholder and shareholder. And that is the sheer reason for this &#x20AC;50 million. Does it answer your question, Michael?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. In Belgium? Did I understand correctly, Belgium?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Belgium, Germany, these are the two countries where we bought these derivatives and where we continue protecting our portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now move to William Hawkins from KBW. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Thank you. My first question, J&#xF6;rg, is just if you can suggest how we make best use of your enhanced disclosure that you've now given us, particularly with regards to the life, primary and reinsurance divisions? I'd kind of hope that the technical results was going to turn out to be a slightly smoother number that we could kind of annualize, but it basically seems to be bouncing around as much as anything else is. So to what extent can we annualize the 120 and the 50 technical results in the primary and reinsurance division? If not, to what extent should we be thinking about what the major drivers are?</p>
          <p>I was also particularly confused by your unit-linked explanation for the change in the primary results, because I would have thought that the vast majority of the investments impact of unit-linked in the technical interest was just being neutralized by the change in the claims line, so if you could just clarify that as well?</p>
          <p>And then secondly, on slide 11, where you've got the three numbers for other income and expenses, gains and write-downs, I think as always those are gross of tax and policyholder share. Can you tell us actually what those three numbers are in terms of their impact on the net attributable profit for the shareholder? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>William, let me with the first question. And it's too difficult, because it's early days with the new system for us. It's still difficult to say that you have here a sustainable number, because it's just so new and it needs more stability still, but let's try it with the example of the unit-linked piece. All income and expenses from investments from unit-linked get forwarded to the policyholder through the net expenses for claims and benefits. So under normal conditions it's a positive number. It is &#x2013; for us, it is expenses for claims and benefit. To neutralize that, we included one-by-one in the technical interest number. That is by the way the reason why we do this IFRS 8 application using with the technical interest by taking all the expenses for our policyholder participation into the technical interest and not applying a risk-free rate.</p>
          <p>If you imagine if we apply a risk-free rate on our technical interest independent from the investment result here, then you would have a very stable technical interest but then bouncing around net expenses for claims and benefits due to the real participation in the investment returns. And therefore, we do more or less a mirroring of the policyholder participation in the technical interest in order to neutralize that factor. And this is, I think, most clearly with the unit-linked business. Unfortunately we have chosen very bad timing for the introduction, because we are dealing here now with negative numbers which makes it much more difficult for me and it's definitely or most probably also for you to analyze here. But I have to warn a little bit about drawing too firm conclusions now on sustainable earnings. What we &#x2013; you're right we try to use the technical result as shown you some indication for the continuing earnings we have.</p>
          <p>Then your last question was about the technical results, what are the major drivers here? Premium income increased in primary life insurance. Sorry, could you repeat the question, please, William?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>My second question was nothing to do with the technical results. It was to do with the investment results. On slide 11 you've given us basically the three capital gain items, the other income/expenses, the realized gains and losses, and the write-downs and write-ups. I just wanted to know what are those three numbers net of tax in the policyholders' share so I can actually what the impact on your earnings was in the first quarter of those items?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't have it here this net number, but we can provide you later on offline with the rough calculation here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll now move to our final question today, which comes from Fahad Changazi from Cazenove. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, hi there. Just a quick follow-up on the buyback. You mentioned if clients do not adequately pay for Munich Re's capital support, you could redeploy your excess capital then to continue the buyback. Could you give an idea where that threat point is? For example, is it not achieving around 20% RORAC or not achieving high single digit, low double digit rate increases on life, et cetera? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The target of 15% RORAC for the whole group, the translation into our technical value creation and to the technical RORAC is not a one-to-one translation because it takes out investment income and the risk capital allocation for investment income. Therefore, we cannot generalize and also it's different from market-to-market. And it's an overall consideration we do here where we do not want to exclude share buybacks. I would guess and I can safely say that in the next couple of weeks you should not expect us to change our mind here and to resume the share buybacks. We will continue waiting somewhat. Anything to add from Torsten?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. As we have no...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a second please. There was one --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>William, yeah, so, sorry, I did not quite correctly catch your question on the slide of the presentation, nine to 11. On the slides you mentioned, we always show the regular income write-up/write-downs and we have the number you asked for. It's net result effect of the regular income in the order of little bit less than 600 million write-downs, write-ups. It's roughly 250, so it's roughly one half of the growth number, and the same applies &#x2013; or no, it's better in realized gains and losses. Out of the 359, it's roughly &#x2013; little bit less than 300 for the net result effect. I hope that this answers your question, and sorry for the delay here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. I think we have covered all questions, hopefully, sufficiently, very comprehensive Q&amp;A. Many thanks to all of you out there. As always we will there in the investor relations team to answer your further questions. Thank you very much very much for joining us, and looking forward to seeing you next time. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That will conclude today's conference call. Thank you for your participation. Ladies and gentlemen, you may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>