<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1346410" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-11-09</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7867</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Christian Becker-Hussong, Head of Investor and Rating Agency Relations</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">Jorg Schneider, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Fabrizio Croce</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">Michael Huttner</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Brian Shea</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">Andrew Ritchie</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">James Quin</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Jochen Schmitt</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Michael Haid</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="corprep">Jo Oechslin</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Tony Silverman</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">William Hawkins</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day and welcome to Munich Re Quarterly Financial Statements of the Third Quarter 2010 Conference Call. Today's conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>At this time, I'd like to turn the conference over to Christian Becker-Hussong. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen or rather good morning to those of you calling from the U.S. Thanks for joining us. Welcome to the presentation and discussion of our nine months 2010 financial results. Jorg Schneider, our CFO is today's speaker. Following his presentation of the highlights, you will have enough time for Q&amp;A. Please allow for the usual housekeeping as always I'd like to remind you to really limit your question to a maximum of two per person in order to give as many participants as possible the chance to ask questions.</p>
          <p>So far from my side and I'll now hand over to Jorg.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Christian. Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen. I will highlight the most important numbers and give some additional explanations. For this I will not walk you through all the slides, but will try to focus on the most relevant items and to dig deeper when answering your questions afterwards.</p>
          <p>Let me start with the highlights on slide three. Munich Re is performing well. In the third quarter, we achieved a very satisfactory consolidated result of 761 million and a return on risk adjusted capital of 17%. For the nine months we had a strong profit of almost 2 billion. Another 2 billion income and expenses has been directly recognized in equity due to the increase of unrealized gains and positive currency effects.</p>
          <p>Of this total of almost 4 billion, 2.1 billion has been distributed to shareholders as dividends and share buyback, 1.9 remains as an increase in shareholders equity. Since end of last year our shareholders equity went up by 8.3% to 24.1 billion in spite of capital repatriation. The good development in 2010 is due to a high investment results with the return on investment of 5% respectively 4.4 in Q3. But also it is due to a good operational performance in the business units.</p>
          <p>In reinsurance the burden from the high level of not cut losses in the first half of 2010 was mitigated by benign claims development in Q3. ERGO shows good results and Munich Health is moving successfully on its consolidation part. Therefore we are increasing our profit guidance for 2010 from 2 billion to 2.4 billion, naturally subject to normal major loss activity and a somewhat stable capital market.</p>
          <p>Let's move onto the financial highlights on page four. Our premiums grew by 3 billion or 9.7% to 34 billion roughly half of this increase is due to foreign exchange effect, the other half organic.</p>
          <p>Our operating result went up by 1.4% and the consolidated result by 9.6%. The strong result in Q3 was also due to positive currency effects after negative impacts in the first half year. And the third quarter the positive impact was roughly 200 million.</p>
          <p>Again we had a satisfactory contribution from reinsurance taking into account the high level of claims in the first half of the year. Primary insurance delivered 433 million on an unconsolidated basis. Consolidated ERGO result this was 301 million, this is more than four times the result in the same period of last year. Our youngest segment, Munich Health, produced a pleasing result of 57 million.</p>
          <p>On slide six, you'll see the development of our shareholders equity. It went up by 1.9 billion since end of last year, and 387 since 30th of June. On the right hand side of the slide you see the development in Q3. The positive effects of the decreased in interest rates were fully compensated by negative foreign exchange effects. So, the increase of almost 400 million is difference between the strong quarterly result and the share buybacks.</p>
          <p>Our capitalization, I'm on slide seven now, is strong according to all capital measures. On an IFRS basis, we had a strong increase in our book value per share with a compound annual growth rate of 7% since 2005. And if we include dividend and share buybacks back, then it would have been even 10%. For details see slide 34, please.</p>
          <p>As things stand today, we will complete the current share buyback program by the AGM 2011. Currently, there is no need for decision, be it on the dividend for 2010, let us first wait until the risk period is over and no need for decision on further buybacks. But let me share with you some considerations.</p>
          <p>May I first remind you of the main technical constraints? Munich Re AG that is the parent company result and revenue reserve is booked under the German commercial code which is guided by the principle of prudence and we also had, as you know, a claims equalization provision in the order of between 7.5 and &#x20AC;8 billion, which is very important. It is pre-tax therefore it's kind of postponement of tax payment also attractive for the company.</p>
          <p>We also &#x2013; so we have to look at this revenue reserve in the Munich Re AG balance sheet because this is the basis for our distribution capability. Second, we look at the rating and on supervisory regulations. At the moment, we are, as you know, in very comfortable territory but it is important to think about Solvency II. We are in the final phase before the implementation and the rules for the required capital and eligible own funds are still unknown.</p>
          <p>I am pretty confident that Munich Re will have no problem to fulfill the requirements but also have very good business prospects with regard to Solvency II, and capital strength is an important competitive advantage, especially in this important phase of transition.</p>
          <p>But on the other hand, efficient capital management including and above average payout ratio remains a cornerstone of our strategy. That means good earnings and cash for shareholders. Consequently, all of our actions will be balanced between capital repatriation and appropriate capital strength, and going forward, we are confident that we will please our &#x2013; continue pleasing our shareholders with high distributions.</p>
          <p>Let's move on to one of the basis of our financial solidity on slide nine. The well-balanced investment portfolio we have. In 2010 we had an almost constant decline of risk free rates, and of this spreads for corporate bonds and we had a kind of roller coaster ride for the spreads of the weaker sovereigns. With our strong weight in highly rated bonds, especially AAA government bonds, we did not take high bets on top performers, but were reasonably well positioned.</p>
          <p>On the right hand side of that slide, you can see our tactical movements in 2010. It's served us well that we lengthened our duration, while others still played the cards of short assets duration waiting in vain for the quick spike in inflation and interest rates. So we are very pleased with our long duration.</p>
          <p>On the lower part of the slide, you see that there are opposite positions in reinsurance and primary insurance. In reinsurance, we are long duration and we are a bit short in primary insurance, so this is kind of group internal hedge with the small net long position. And this has been one source of the high investment result in an environment of almost constantly declining risk free rates.</p>
          <p>This investment result is shown on slide 12. From January to September, we posted an investment result of almost 7.3 billion, which equals to a return on investment of 5% on an annualized basis. The high net balance from write-ups, write-downs as well as net realized gains and losses from the disposal of assets added to very positive 1.7 billion for the first nine months and resulted primarily from a selective repositioning in our fixed interest portfolio. So, we had mainly disposal gains from government bonds, corporate, or covered bonds, and also the revaluation of our derivative instruments contributed well to the result.</p>
          <p>Measured against our liability profile, we only took limited and tightly controlled bets. We made active use of derivative for hedging and duration management purposes. These are changes in these derivatives are recognized in the P&amp;L while changes in the value of the underlyings are recognized in equity. This, as you know, leads to accounting distortions, which we accept and explain but don't like.</p>
          <p>You'll find some explanations on the slides 10 and 39, also taking into account the economic position, which for us is key in it all. But this makes forecasts for IFRS results very difficult in spite of a well-balanced portfolio and an only limited economic exposure to capital market movements.</p>
          <p>Let's now move onto the segments starting with primary insurance on slide 14. IFRS premiums grew by 6.8% to 13.1 billion. When we include savings components of unit linked and capitalization product it even grew by 7% to 14.5 billion. Technical results was clearly positive. When we compared with the 2009 result, 2009 was distorted by extra allocation of technical interest in life during the capital market crisis, kind of artificial and therefore 2009 looks better as in comparison than it really was. Investment results, operating results, and the consolidated net profit went sharply up.</p>
          <p>Looking a bit closer into primary life, on slide 16, premium income increased by 6.1%. In new business regular premiums was down. But the overall rise in premiums was mainly driven by higher new business with single premiums in Germany and abroad. You can see details on that on the following slide 17. What was particularly pleasing was that we did not lose ground in spite of the new ERGO brand strategy and this very sensitive phase of transition after having given up the brands of Hamburg-Mannheimer and Victoria.</p>
          <p>Investment results rose by more than 40% or into an improvement of the swaption results. The swaptions with which we reinsure our sales in a way protects our sales against long lasting low interest environments. This result increased &#x2013; we had swing of &#x20AC;800 million and we had increased disposal gains both allowing for higher policyholder participation.</p>
          <p>By the way the impact of the swaptions on the consolidated result amounted to 92 million in the first nine months. That means out of the 202 consolidated result, 92 was due to the swaptions.</p>
          <p>Moving on to property causality primary insurance, and here on slide 20 where you see the development of the combined ratio. But let me just start with a short word on the premium development, premium increased in all lines of business driven by the strengthening of distribution channels and business abroad, as well as due to positive foreign currency exchange effects, especially from our business in Poland.</p>
          <p>The development of the combined ratio starting quite high in Q1, and to a lesser extent in Q2 due to higher claims expenses mainly driven by foreign business. Poland with strong winter and floods, and also higher claims expenses in Turkey, where we were suffering from very difficult market circumstances plus some homemade issues.</p>
          <p>We have addressed it all and we are on a good path. In the third quarter, combined ratio was back to normal with 93.6, nine months were 95.6, very close to our target of 95%. And the combined ratio in Germany was again outstanding with 88.8%, and this despite winter storm Xynthia.</p>
          <p>Moving onto our youngest business field, Munich Health, the highlights on slide 23 of an overview of the P&amp;L. On the reinsurance side we have a positive net effect on technical result from strong premium growth due to large volume capital release yields like in life reinsurance in North America and in Asia. The organic growth was plus 662 million.</p>
          <p>And we had positive currency impact of additional 269 million.</p>
          <p>The increased investment result was a consequence of higher regular income also from associates, and these are our joint venture partners in the Middle East. Previous years consolidated result was framed by the depreciation of the Sterling goodwill.</p>
          <p>So far with Munich Health now to reinsurance, and this on slide 25 the overview, gross premiums written up 6.6% to 17.6 billion. This is plus 1.1 billion of which one was due to foreign exchange effects, and then we had counter, counter veiling developments below that plus in life, and down in property casualty.</p>
          <p>And we had slight increase of an already high investment income, and a loss ratio which was 4% higher than in 2009, easily explainable by the rain from the very high catastrophe losses. And overall 450 million more losses, pre-tax 300 million at least after tax more, and this more than explains the decline of the operating result and of the net profit.</p>
          <p>Moving to life, page 27, growth premiums written grew by &#x2013; grew by 1 billion this was due equally to large volume deals in North America and very strong growth now in Asia. We will see more and more very attractive business from that fast growing region.</p>
          <p>The other half was due to positive foreign exchange effects, important for us U.S. dollar and Canada dollar. We had corresponding positive effects of large &#x2013; of these large volume deals on all technical and operating results. In the third quarter, we allocated &#x20AC;76 million to the provision for future risks of long-term care business.</p>
          <p>Currently we continue with an extensive review and there's still some uncertainty here, and we could see in the first quarter a release or partly a release of that additional reserve also additions. And this long-term care business is for us a niche product, and here this comes from the U.S. and in the portfolio of our U.S. life subsidiary it makes up for approximately 10% premiums and reserves.</p>
          <p>If you would ask me for a guidance, we still stick to our expectations that, for the technical results, about 100 million per quarter remains realistic. That means 400 million for the full year.</p>
          <p>Still by far the most important segment is property casualty reinsurance slide 29. The premium development was flat, was just plus &#x20AC;65 million. If we take into account positive currency effect of 500 million and the impact from the full consolidation of Hartford Steam Boiler, which came to our group in at the end of the first quarter 2009, then the impact of all other items was minus 740. That means reduction of business due to our bottom line oriented underwriting in difficult markets That means &#x2013; or that demonstrate that we take profitability orientation really serious, and that we are not prepared to expose our capacity in markets which are somewhat weakening here.</p>
          <p>We had especially high natural catastrophe losses. As you know the earthquake in Chile, and in the third quarter the earthquake in New Zealand as the main events here. In addition to substantial man made losses, like Deepwater Horizon. In the third quarter we had very low man made losses and this partially explains the good combined ratio in the third quarter.</p>
          <p>The expense ratio went slightly up. This is also due to the fact that we have more and more Munich Re risk solution business, that is the business in primary niche areas with structurally different expense ratios, especially with our subsidiary company Hartford Steam Boiler, which makes a substantial part of its profit with advisory services.</p>
          <p>So far with reinsurance, let's now move on to the outlook. Starting for the running year 2010, on the very solid basis of the good third quarter developments and results and the continuing &#x2013; and on the basis of the continuing low interest rate environment, we now expect an ROI of about 4.5% for the entire year 2010, which seems to us to be the most realistic scenario today.</p>
          <p>We also expect a better combined ratio event three months ago and would give guidance now with slightly below 100%. This would require another good quarter and good development for the two months to come. Therefore as stated already at the beginning of my presentation, we are pleased to increase our profit guidance significantly from 2 billion to about 2.4 billion for 2010. This is based on normal claims expectations and no major developments regarding capital market parameters.</p>
          <p>And this is also the assumption on which we base our first indication for 2011 with the RORAC of 15% as our only a key target still to stand. We know that this is a real challenge given the sustainably very low interest rates. But we are very close to it and this year also somewhat with some assistance from accounting effects, but we don't want to change the target because we regard this as being not only over the insurance cycle, but to some extent also over interest rate cycles.</p>
          <p>What is most important is that our economically balanced business and investment portfolio should stabilize profitability and reduces the cost of capital, like it did during the last couple of years where we showed this extreme resilience to adverse conditions.</p>
          <p>If we assume insignificant non-recurring gains and losses, and the continuation of this low interest rate environment, then we expect a return on equity which would drop below 4%.</p>
          <p>The net result 2011 would be presumably &#x2013; what's presumably be slightly below the increased outlook for 2010, but we expect a higher technical result. So you see we are overall on a good track in difficult markets.</p>
          <p>And with that back to Christian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. So, we can now start with the Q&amp;A and once more I would like to remind you to limit your questions to a maximum of two per person please. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> we will now take our first question from Fabrizio Croce from Kepler. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I have actually only two questions. The first one is about the net profit, actually Q4 would be a400 million quarter and here the question is I mean how much is conservative and how much? I mean the question is the market seems not be able to discount back your conservative and so the question is there also an additional oil spill charge which we need to expect in Q4, or why is the guidance so low?</p>
          <p>And the second question is about Buffett, we just saw that a competitor of you will receive earlier back some CHF3.6 billion, and given that Buffett is very interested in expanding reinsurance exposure is keen for time being. The question is if you would go up to 20% or more in your stock, would you still feel confident with the statement that it is a financial investment or would it start to give you some concern?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Fabrizio , here your first question, I don't see it comfortable, I must say because I seem to constantly under promise our later results, and I take some blame for perhaps sometimes over conservative approach. But I can assure you, what I do is I just communicate our best internal guess, and give that as a guidance. But it's the volatility comes from P&amp;L effects, which are not based on economic developments to some extent. And currently, it's the same, we tried to adjust our prognosis, which came out of the systems, and which was based on numbers which were, which were based on at end of July and end of September and so on.</p>
          <p>And we adjusted it to the current capital market conditions. We also took into account a substantial burden from natural catastrophes, which can still come lesser from hurricanes because the season has &#x2013; is currently coming to an end. But we had, in the past, already very severe winter storms around Christmas.</p>
          <p>So a little bit of that, or not only a little bit, is built into our numbers. And no major gains and losses from disposal of investments, yeah, so the more we would shuttle the portfolio also for tactical reason the more can come. But this is really, at the moment, our best guidance so I personally do not expect us to over deliver here. Second, Warren Buffett, we are pleased to have him as a shareholder because he has a long-term view, he knows our business and that also means that when we have volatility coming from natural catastrophes or so, investors like him and like other similar long-term oriented investors do not lose nerve too early, therefore, we have him, we like to having him among our shareholders. I don't have any reason to believe that a substantial increase will happen, but I also don't know the opposite and therefore it would be highly theoretical if I would say more on that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And sorry for the first one, no additional oil spill charge in Q4?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No not to our knowledge. So we haven't &#x2013; we have set up a reserve which is, as we say, low triple digit. We haven't changed it most recently, and we expect this case to last for a very long time until we have clarity, but nothing has been planned for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We will now take our next question from Michael Huttner from J. P. Morgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll just say thank you. I just wondered, can you say what the RORAC was year-to-date and maybe Q3? And the other question is, I was trying to work out what the guidance you gave for 2011 means. Maybe to help us a little bit understand the return on investment you're giving is 4%, you can say what is the current reinvestment rate that you're getting? I can't puzzle it out, if I try to puzzle it out from your guidance for Q4 then I get a number of 3%, which then means just under four for 2011 looks a little bit high for <mark type="inaudible" /></p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>First, the RORAC for the third quarter was 17% and for the nine months was 14.5%. The guidance for 2011 is based on a reinvestment rate of 3.5%, and that would mean that we would fall slightly below 4% with our overall investment return.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take our next question from Brian Shea from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. I had two questions, please. The first one is one I often ask I think in this call. I was just trying to get a better gauge for the primary life and underlying earnings power. I'm going to try it a different way this quarter. We have income from technical interest that's running a lot higher than in 2009, both at the nine-month level and also in Q3. I just wondered can you just tell us why is that and should we be modeling that to be coming down I guess in 2011 onwards? And again, the big question is just trying to get a better handle for the underlying earnings power...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Brian this is also difficult for us because as I said last time we have some problems to stabilize the technical interest, especially during 2009 and we had &#x2013; and this is based on the problem that the policyholder participation is in reality done on German commercial code rules and they are artificially translated into IFRS. And last year we tried it in a way that the expected HGB German code result was divided into equal portions and then put into the technical interest in that way. And we gave that up and changed the methodology little bit and that makes up for the distortions.</p>
          <p>If I start with the bottom of the whole calculation, our best expectation for primary life net result is still between 100 and &#x20AC;150 million per year. So we are rather modest here. And we hope to stabilize these fluctuations from quarter-to-quarter. Part of it is based on &#x2013; it's caused by the enormous developments of the &#x2013; and fluctuations of the swaptions, as you know. And I understand that you can't be totally satisfied about it, but I dare to promise that six months down the road, we will have more stability in these numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Just to confirm I was asking with technical interest because I think above the line there is no distortion from the swaptions, so down to technical profit that far,  it's only below technical profit that the swaptions start impacting numbers. Is that right?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, that's nothing. You are right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Hopefully, you can kind of this one question, the other question is quite simple the other non-operating items &#x2013; that was plus 100 million in Q3. I know that you mentioned currency is one thing that's in there. Could you just explain what's in that bucket in general and is there a tendency &#x2013; should the tendency be zero? In the past, it has tended to be a negative number. If you could just comment on that, I'd be grateful.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'll provide you with some details later on because we have to look it up. It's structurally negative plus the currency result, which can be positive and negative perhaps on the currency result, when we have strong euro, the currency result is to a large extent based on the result of the forward sales of foreign currencies. We have to do these forward sales in order to ensure the economic balance &#x2013; economic currency balance into our balance sheet, and since we have an over exposure, and coming from assets in foreign currencies being higher than liabilities, we do forward sales of for example U.S. dollars.</p>
          <p>That means when the dollar is weak these forward sales go up and vice versa. That means when the dollar is weak, we have a positive impact from this foreign exchange effect, and when the euro is weak we have a negative impact. So this is in general, the currency effect. And apart from it, we have a list on page 71 of our quarterly report, and they include write-downs on other intangible assets, and other non-technical expenses of roughly &#x20AC;268 million and these other, these non-operating expenses here like financing costs on strategic debt.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so I don't want to pin you down too much, but are you suggesting that 268 is this sort of stripped down nine month run-rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would say, it's structurally negative, some 100 million perhaps.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Per year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, per quarter. For the year, it's between four and 450, 400 and 450 per year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Negative.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Andrew Ritchie from Autonomous. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there. Two very quick questions. You talked quite a lot in the beginning about the constraints of the German cap revenue reserves, which is an issue we are familiar with. I just wanted to understand if you are suggesting that there is less flexibility with respect to that than there has been in the past? And maybe you'll run us through your thinking on that. I am guessing you have to rebuild the planned equalization reserve to a degree, and also is there any flexibility on withdrawing dividends down from subsidiaries to boost that revenue reserve? That's the first topic.</p>
          <p>Second topic, the underlying combined ratio in the reinsurance division, if I kind of normalize large losses, man made, and that cat looks to be about 95 in the quarter, which is sort of below kind of the 96/97 run rate of previous quarters. And is that sort of just another elements of good luck in there when I look at that performance? Or is there any kind of structural improvements in the underlying reinsurance profitability? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you Andrew. Let me start with the first one on revenue reserve. One important factor is equalization reserve we have put slide in how the equalization reserve works. Can somebody say me the number perhaps because we gave here a little bit of an explanation what are the driving parameters. In the presentation it's on slide 40, and what you said is quite correct. The lower the volatility of our underwriting results the &#x2013; in the long run the lower the threshold we have to achieve with our revenue &#x2013; with our equalization reserve, so it is based on the 15-year volatility per line of business. That means, if we move into an environment of very disciplined underwriting, with very stable results, then that should somewhat bring down the need to fill up the revenue reserve here. But this is very difficult to plan because when you have your plans, you never have one major catastrophe in it.</p>
          <p>But this drives the volatility and therefore it's &#x2013; for us it's always a challenge to plan and to manage that revenue, that equalization reserve. Second withdrawing higher dividends from subsidiary exactly that is what we are working on but what is extremely burdensome because the regulatory environment is also a constraint here and there, but we make some progress and therefore I am confident that in future this will be a better and more constant source of additional revenues here.</p>
          <p>Second question on the underlying combined ratio, if I try to very primitively adjust the combined ratio for the impact of above and below average major losses, then I would start for the nine months with 102.1%. This includes 15 percentage points major losses of which 10.8 were natural catastrophes. Let's assume that 6.5% natural catastrophe is our assumption, and another 4.5 for our man-made losses, overall 11. Then we had 4.7% too high loss burden, if we adjust for it, we would be at 97.5. If we do the same for the third quarter starting with the real number 93.8, this includes 8.3 &#x2013; 8.3 percentage points, major losses, this is 2.7% less than the 11%. If I add this 2.7% to the actual 93.8 then I'm at 96.5, so both numbers are quite close to our over the cycle target of 97%, and so to us quite closeable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, sorry just one follow-up, I'm just trying understand on the HGB on the revenue, were you trying to steer that &#x2013; do you feel that those are more of a constraint from this point than they have been in recent years or <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't see a clear tendency, I have a small hope. And perhaps I'm here again a little bit too conservative that it will be less of a problem due to the very good stability of our underwriting return.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, lower volatility, lower requirements here, but on the other hand, I frankly admit that I also some kind of like this revenue reserve because it protect this equalization reserve, because it protects our shareholders and the company also with its future distribution .So for example an earthquake like in Chile and in New Zealand, we were sitting here quite relaxed with regard to our distribution capability, because it was almost not effected because this type of events could be easily financed out of that reserve. So it has a flip side of coin. Overall we are aware of the need to manage it also actively, and also to work on additional sources of producing revenues under German HGB, you can rely on that. Does it answer your question right Andrew?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That was very helpful. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our next question comes from James Quin from Citigroup. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello there. Two questions, please. The first one is on capital as well. J&#xF6;rg, I think you gave some guidance on carry-outs around how you see your capital position evolving, I just wondered if you could let us know what you see as the key constraints. It sounded to me, maybe I'm wrong, but it sounded to me as if it was the definition of capital and Solvency II which is perhaps holding you back. And I am just wondering if, for example, and it's fairly unlikely there is some limitation on this within Solvency II would you see that as making buybacks unlikely for the next 18 months or so?</p>
          <p>Second question is just on P&amp;C reinsurance. I'm sure &#x2013; quite sure you've seen the Swiss Re reserve release numbers coming through. And I think what may have kind of surprised even to Swiss Re was the strength of the reserve releases, which they have seen in the last 21 months on the 2003 and post liability? And I wonder if you could give us a sense from your own perspective how you would characterize your reserve evolution over that time? And in particular if you could give us some sense of how you see your own reserve confidence level? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, James. Thank you. First capital, you listened very well and carefully to what I said. The primitive key constrained is revenue reserve, but if there is a gap to bridge, then we can mange it. Second is Solvency II and in fact, this really makes us being a little bit more careful at the moment. One is very simple we really don't know the capital requirement from Munich Re. We are very confident that whatever is the outcome of QIS 5 requirements can't be calibrated in a way that Munich Re wouldn't make it. So, here I'm still sleeping very easily.</p>
          <p>But there is also the other element of business opportunities coming from Solvency II. And currently we cannot really say where they come in exactly what form and how capital consuming there would be. And therefore, I admit that we currently tend to be less courageous with share buybacks and dividends then we were, let's say one or two years ago. And we would very much like to keep or increase our dividend, and would rather like to reduce the share buyback for a while for that reason. But since that hasn't been discussed in all details here on the Board of Management, please bear with me that I don't want to be more specific, but this is just my judgment on the general mood in the company at the moment. But we continue taking shareholders' interest in high distributions &#x2013; we take them very serious.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So if I could just quickly ask, would you say it was the more the business opportunities that's slightly changing your &#x2013; the way you're thinking about this as opposed to the precise definition of whether you have enough capital, but whether you would be have the sort of capital buffer, so a bit more &#x2013; a bit opportunity?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's both &#x2013; yeah it's both. For my colleagues, it's more the opportunity and for me the capital requirements. But the mix is a good one, I think.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Second question on reserve releases, yeah. We also see quite good indications in our book. So maybe you have seen a while ago that there was a court trial that we lost in the third instance where we go into appeal, major asbestos case, and it did not at all cause us to increase at all our reserves. On that occasion we did discuss it here. This seems to be quite comfortable buffers, but it's premature to say more at the moment because currently our reserves review is going on and we take it very seriously. I am over 10 years now in my current position, and I can well remember the years 2002 to 2005 where we had such a horrible track record with our U.S. reserves, and having that still in the back of my mind, we continue being somewhat careful on that side. But when there is a clear indication, we wouldn't shy away from also releasing the reserves.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good. Would you say you are closer now to the points of which you feel you had genuinely enough buffers in place than where you were say a year ago? Or would you say that this is basically still a work-in-progress in your perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I grow older &#x2013; yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So I mean &#x2013; I am just trying to summarize where you think you are. So you have more buffer but you wouldn't really see any realistic prospect of that emerging into your results anytime soon <mark type="inaudible" />?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We would not like to manage our results upwards, but we want to keep a buffer between 3 and 5% of the reserves, but not beyond.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Jochen Schmitt from Metzler Equities has our next question. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much, good afternoon I have two quick questions on ERGO if I may. First one, could you provide some details on restructuring expenses booked in the first nine months? And the second one in the same context. How did the introduction of the new ERGO marketing campaign in Germany affect marketing expenses? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't know that from the top of my head. Maybe answer it a little bit later then I can ask my colleague here whether he has the numbers with him.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah sure.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Thank you. Can we take the next question before, sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from Michael Haid from Cheuvreux. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good afternoon. Two questions. First of all, on slide nine, you give us detailed figures on duration which I well appreciate, of course I always want more. On primary insurance you give the duration on the assets and the liability side 7.1 and 7.6. Can you give us a split for life, house and P&amp;C, and also if you have that what happens to the duration of the liability of the liabilities in life when you assume that the policyholders exercise their option to annuitize their policies at maturity?</p>
          <p>Second question I think I heard right that you mentioned 740 million premiums in P&amp;C which you have given up because this business was not profitable. Can you say what type of business you stepped away from and how unprofitable it was? Was it only marginally below your threshold or was it materially below your hurdle rate?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Michael. It was marginally below, yeah. So business was not that bad, but we are very consistent, and it was to a large extent motor quarter share business that made up for the bulk. Duration in tendency life and health some 7.5 years, property casualty, 4.5, 4.7 and Jo Oechslin, our Chief Risk Officer is here. Can you say something about the change in duration when policyholders exercise their option?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Michael. First of all, we actually love to provide the DDR1 figures or the duration figures, I know you like durations, but the duration always applies to different basis on assets and liabilities. This is why its difficult to compare, but on what we can currently see in terms of changes of the duration profile is that into falling rates, we have lengthening of the duration of life insurance liabilities, that is because we get closer to the guarantee level, which means that options play less of a role and guarantees really kick in and that means into falling rates that duration on the liability sides lengthen quicker than the duration of the asset side. That's what we currently see. So this is a development of the third quarter.</p>
          <p>In terms of duration management, we have not really changed much in the quarter. It is still a matching that we actually achieve, considered on the group level, offsetting both the reinsurance and primary reinsurance durations. That's still unchanged. So we are not massively short nor massively long duration, we just orient ourselves on the liabilities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jo, I needed this break now to get to the information with regard to restructuring expenses. I come back to the question of Jochen Schmitt before. We had substantial restructuring expenses in recent years for the cost savings program. But the change of the brands did not effect structures very much because all the back offices were already brought together before, and therefore, there were no restructuring expenses booked here. The marketing expenses went up in comparison to the situation before by mid to high double-digit million amount for 2010 additional expenses. Can we have the next question then, please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly. Our next question comes from Tony Silverman from Standard &amp; Poor's Equity Research. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good afternoon. Just one question in answer to an earlier question you mentioned an investment return on reinvestments of 3.5%, and just crudely perhaps comparing that to government bond yields of say 10 years duration which might be around 2.5%, a bit more than that in the U.S., a bit less in Germany, I just wondered if you could talk a little bit about what your asset allocation is to get that 3.5% or what it's projected to be? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With pleasure, yes. We currently invest in covered bonds, mostly outside of Germany, but not high yield areas. We also not only buy German bonds to the contrary, we do not want to increase our exposure further. We buy government bond from other countries but not Greece, yeah. So it's something in between, for example, we had expanded our exposure to Italy most recently. So this is the kind of investments we are currently doing, highly based also on tactical and sometimes also short-term considerations.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>As a reinvestment rate, I wonder if the 3.5% is going to look a bit high to people, really?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. This is a reinvestment rate. For example, the current yield we achieved on the covered bonds is above 4%, on corporates of rather good quality, it's roughly 5% and on government bonds, it's roughly 3.5% and that mix towards first class government bonds, that brings you to that area. So all the risks spreads add up to 1 percentage point on what is currently the risk free rate of U.S. and German government bonds.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks very much. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Our next question comes from William Hawkins from KBW. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thanks very much. Just one question, Jorg you've been saying your shareholders funds this year is being flattened by the fall in bond yields. So help us get a more economic sense, could you give us an update of the surplus value of business in force please? I think the figure is 4 billion at the end of last year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't have that number on a quarterly basis here, we just have some indications. Jo do you can you help out here?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, well in general, we are tracking our available financial resources, as you know over the year in terms of total risk capacity, it's not a number we disclose on a quarterly basis. But I can &#x2013; I can give you indications in the first half of the year, this number has been slightly growing despite a return on cash yield in terms of dividends and further share buybacks. The AFR has being growing into the 30th of June. In the third quarter, due to the lower interest rates, and the higher implied volatilities, we have seen some negative developments primarily driven by long tail business like the life insurance, primary insurance business, so that number has been reduced again slightly but no dramatic changes overall in this year.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, well that number <mark type="inaudible" /> at the beginning of the year could be down, but not down dramatically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Precisely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>William, does this answer your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Certainly, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I misunderstood. I thought that you mean that market consistent embedded value of the life book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, next question please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>We now have a follow-up question from Michael Huttner from J.P. Morgan. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's actually a very technical question, you gave these amazing figures on RORAC and you keep saying you'll never achieve RORAC and you're beating it comfortably, I just wondered, can you explain exactly how you calculate it? This was the 17% in 3Q and 14.5% in for the nine months, what is it that you adjust and stuff like that? Thank you</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah, you're right. So the &#x2013; in the quote the denominator and numerator &#x2013; the numerator of this equation is the IFRS number, which is somewhat inflated by the impact of the low yields and the derivatives and so on, and the denominator is our risk capital which is a real economic number.</p>
          <p>We are aware of the fact that this is a mixture which does not make total economic sense, but for the time being, we do not want to change it. We want to wait for the final Solvency II rules and then use numbers from the Solvency II world in order to provide the market with a full economic target number. So that is our intention at the moment and therefore we hibernate with the phase in between with the RORAC target and to us, it's &#x2013; we're not particularly proud of beating it under the current conditions. Nevertheless to make it clear, this is a good result for the third quarter overall. Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Michael. Thank you, bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>As there are no further questions in the queue. That will conclude today's question-and-answer session. I would now like to turn the call back over to Mr. Christian Becker-Hussong for any additional or closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>So, nothing to add from my side, thanks for joining us. For further questions we are here, and the Investor Relations team to answer whatever kind of follow-up questions you might have. So, thanks again and talk to you soon. Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. That will conclude today's conference call. Thank you for your participation ladies and gentlemen. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>