<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1274600" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q2 2010 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2010-08-04</date>
    <companies>
      <company>7867</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Christian Becker-Hussong, Head of Investor and Rating Agency Relations</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Nikolaus von Bomhard, Chairman</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep">J&#xF6;rg Schneider, Chief Financial Officer</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst">William Hawkins</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Michael Huttner</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst">James Quin</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Will Morgan</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">William Morgan</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst">Spencer Horgan</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst">Brian Shea</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst">Andrew Ritchie</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="analyst">Thomas Fossard</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst">Michael Haid</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst">Roland Pf&#xE4;nder</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.  Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.  Thanks for joining our call on the occasion that is mentioned of our half-year 2010 results.  And today's speakers are Nikolaus von Bomhard and J&#xF6;rg Schneider.  After the usual presentation there would be plenty of time for Q&amp;A as always.  However, I would like to ask you to limit your questions to a maximum of two per person in order to give also the other participants their chance to ask questions.</p>
          <p>One additional remark from my side, we are of course aware of the timing clash with AXA's presentation in London today.  Unfortunately there was no solution to this problem, sorry for that.  As this conference &#x2013; our conference here is being recorded.  We are however optimistic that those analysts and investors who can't participate in our call today won't miss out on anything material.</p>
          <p>So far for the introduction, Nikolaus, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning, good afternoon to all of you.  This is Nikolaus Bomhard, speaking.  It's a pleasure to be with you and as you may remember last time on &#x2013; at the Analyst Conference, we announced that we put this year under the motto of execution and delivery.  And that is exactly what we keep doing and I think that this half year result also supports that action.  The strategy is not changing, it's in place.  You know it and I think everybody out there understands it well.  We feel well positioned in the market environment like today's volatile and uncertain.</p>
          <p>We stick to our knitting that is we put tremendous value on strong integrated risk management, shareholder friendly capital management and a high level of discipline both in underwriting and in investment positions.  That is why in an economic environment like now and despite an exceptionally large burden from natural catastrophes and other major man-made as we call them losses, we think the results we present for the half year is a strong one.  The annualized RORAC amounts to more than 13% and the ROE is north of 10%.</p>
          <p>The outcome, of course is an outcome of contrasting developments while on the one side the technical result, of course was hit by the mentioned large losses in the second quarter but also in the first.  The investment result is a pleasing one again in the second quarter.</p>
          <p>The capital strength provides us with all the financial flexibility we could ask for and we continue to buy back our own stock.  And by the end of July we have bought back in the new program that, runs until the General Assembly next year, already more than 200 million which corresponds to slightly more than 1% of our shares outstanding.</p>
          <p>Well, already in 2009 and this is an important remark I think because there is a lot of discussion about the quality of the result and the return on our assets.  As part of our strategic asset allocation, last year we made shifts in our portfolio of fixed-interest securities reducing what we call undesirable exposures and further improving risk diversification.  And against the backdrop of an extreme yield decline this year this enabled us to post gains on the disposal of fixed income instruments, proving good investment results are achievable and what is important to us with limited risk.</p>
          <p>Of course, our reinvestments somehow have the challenge of a steadily declining free interest rate but we have lengthened the maturities and thus secured a higher interest rate level and this is not only a tactic position this is also, of course, a consequence of our strategic asset liability management trying to as best as possible replicate our liabilities.</p>
          <p>And this strategy clearly proved successful. Of course, also because for tactical reasons we were positioned rightly.  So this made it possible to absorb the losses and the losses also that were a bigger issue maybe earlier this year as we got the so-called weaker European bonds because these market value losses in the first place were well compensated by the growth and value of those secure or perceived secure bonds like Germany, U.S. and maybe Canada.</p>
          <p>So, the claim's balance in compared to the investments, of course, was a different one.  We experienced heavy losses on the nat cat side, specifically in the first quarter, Chile to mention here and, of course, we had to increase that once.  It had to do with the very nature of the claim, not with models. And in the second quarter we had the Deepwater Horizon loss, major oil spill, very unfortunate, man-made as we call it.</p>
          <p>The good news on the technical side is life reinsurance, which continues to develop nicely and contribute stable returns and thus of course substantially mitigating the lower results from the property and casualty book.  The pricing, and I come to that later on, is staying under some pressure, moderate pressure but nevertheless we feel and are quite satisfied with the outcome of the July 1 renewals.</p>
          <p>A very important development for the group and I'm still on slide three, is the realignment and the freshening of the ERGO brand.  What is emerging here is a new type of insurer in Germany and we will deal with clients differently going forward.  It's a completely new proposition to all our stakeholders and of course it also affects the sales forces.  The results of the primary business are much more pleasing, the operating results.  A good 30% of the overall operating result this time comes from the primary insurance wing and that is pretty much where they should be.  So this is good news as I see it.  Life business did improve strongly as well as part of the overall primary book and we think that with the presentation now in the market of the new ERGO brand, we will create further and positive momentum going forward.</p>
          <p>A short word on Munich Health and of course, Wolfgang Strassl, my colleague on the Management Board made a presentation along with the first quarter call.  They are engaged in consolidating the business for the next one or two years and sort of digesting, what was done over the last two, three years in building up this new entity, as new business segment and making sure that the platform is strong enough to grow going forward profitably.  So the small double-digit net income of course is pleasing and heading into the right direction as regards the second quarter.</p>
          <p>I'm moving to slide four, and here I'll be much shorter because of course it's up to J&#xF6;rg later on to give you the details on what happened financially in the Group, if you like the numbers.  I mentioned pleasing ERGO results.  If we look at the net income of the ERGO Group, I would repeat that statement and this of course even though, we had the write-down on our Turkish enterprise, on our Turkish activities and this goes well along with what we always did, we don't build our backlogs.  If we feel we should address an issue, we address it right away and that's what we did here in Turkey.</p>
          <p>We wrote-down the entire goodwill to zero once we felt that the business plans may be short of what we thought some time ago.  And that makes the entire goodwill on the ERGO balance sheet meager if you like five to 6% only in relation to the shareholders' equity of ERGO and if you compare that without the primary insurers who over the recent past have acquired or internationalized their books, I think this is an outstandingly low number.  In other words, we will stick to our disciplined approach when it comes to acquisition, as when it comes to accounting what we do outside in, be it international markets or here specifically in Turkey.  It's a rigid approach, but we think for us it's the right approach.</p>
          <p>My last slide is slide five in the first round here and that is nothing that you wouldn't know if I didn't show it to you.  But in fact I think the out performance is, considering our peers, quite strong.  Here, we show you on the absolute terms, not our peers terms, and this is the growth of book value over the last years and it's a very steady movement only interrupted in the midst of the crisis, a little bit at least but we are back on track and the CIG are both including dividend and share buyback or excluding them is higher single-digit or even double-digit number.  Well, so far I think from my side and now I would hand it over to J&#xF6;rg.  And J&#xF6;rg here you go.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Nikolaus, J&#xF6;rg Schneider speaking.  Good afternoon ladies and gentlemen. I would just highlight the most important numbers and we try to make the slides as far as possible self explanatory and have also put a lot of information in our quarterly report.  Therefore, I try to keep it as short as possible here.</p>
          <p>Let me start with slide number eight, on our capitalization.  We had a consolidated result of 1.2 billion as mentioned and 2.1 billion of income and expenses have been directly recognized in equity.  This was due to the increase of the unrealized gains on our available for sale asset portfolio and positive currency effect.  So, a total of 3.3 billion has been recognized as additional equity in a way.  You can see a split of this comprehensive income on page 31 of our quarterly report.  And what's happened to that additional equity, 1.8 billion have been distributed to our shareholders as dividend and share buyback and 1.5 billion remain as an increase in shareholders' equity.  This provides us with a very comfortable capitalization, but we feel that it is currently in the best interest of our shareholders to have that kind of stability and strength and because it provides us with an important competitive advantage before the start of Solvency II.</p>
          <p>On page nine, the premium developments.  Gross premiums written went up by 1.9 billion of which 700 million were due to FX effect and this is due to the weak euro against all major currencies.  The acquisition of Hartford Steam Boiler was consolidated for the first time in the second quarter of 2009, therefore this is one quarter Hartford Steam Boiler &#x20AC;159 million, and the remaining 1 billion is organic change.  This is large volume deal mainly in Reinsurance Life and in Munich Health reinsurance.  So in life and health reinsurance and this is also the reason why you see on the bottom of that slide the very strong growth in Reinsurance Life and in Munich Health.</p>
          <p>I now move on with the investments and here first the asset allocation on page 10.  The second quarter was marked by the decline in the stock markets.  The widening of the risks spreads and decline of the risk free rates.  We had a very balanced portfolio and very little change with our exposure to equities and still some 85% in fixed interest instruments but this balance and this stability does not mean that this is a dormant portfolio.</p>
          <p>We actively managed within the fixed interest portfolio and, as Nikolaus mentioned before, we had a quite favorable positioning.  Measured against our liability profile, the durations and the currencies, we took very limited, but I can say quite successful bets here.  First, we were quite long, much longer than most of our peers because we also believed in an increase in interest rate but not to the extent as was implied in the yield curve.</p>
          <p>Second, small bet was with regard to currencies.  We were somewhat short euro and this also proved to be the right decision for the second quarter.  We had very strong exposure to German bonds and U.S. treasuries and the positive value development of these risk free government bonds by far overcompensated the losses in value we had on the weaker European Sovereign Bond.  So overall, a very pleasing asset allocation.</p>
          <p>On slide 12, there is the investment result.  For the first half we posted an investment result of almost &#x20AC;5.1 billion, which equals to an ROI of 5.3% on an annualized basis.  We benefited here from conservative, but active movements of our asset manager MEAG and our asset liability managers at the insurance companies.  And even in a difficult market we demonstrated that one can have a very good performance with limited risk.  The high net balance from write-ups, write-downs, as well as net realized gains and losses from the disposal of assets added to very positive 1.4 billion for the first half.  And resulted primarily from a selective repositioning in our fixed interest portfolio. And these disposals were on government bonds including inflation-linked, corporate and covered bonds.  With regard to our second half year forecast, Nikolaus will mention it later.  Also the positive contribution of write-ups and gains on disposals may not be taken for granted on an ongoing basis because it was partially due to some quite extreme developments in the first half, so a very pleasing investment result.</p>
          <p>Let's now move on with primary insurance and page 15, the overview.  Gross premiums written went up by 5.3% which this was due to German Health Insurance, our business abroad and I will come later to life primary insurance.  The decline of the technical result is just due to distortions from 2009 and the investment result was quite strong and therefore the operating result went up to 627 million.  The net profit was 293, not consolidated between Munich Re's primary insurance segment and after all consolidation we can look at an ERGO result of 164 million.</p>
          <p>Nikolaus mentioned Turkey.  On slide 17, you see some aspects about our Turkish subsidiary and the market, very difficult market.  Why did we do the write-down?  There were new regulatory rules for setting claims with us and also for the settlement of claims which were not favorable for the insurance industry.  We had an extremely strong and still have competition in much of our business and we are also somewhat impacted by the falling interest rates and therefore we &#x2013; it's no longer realistic that we can achieve our ambitious business plan which was the basis of the acquisition and therefore we acted immediately and wrote-off the goodwill by &#x20AC;109 million.</p>
          <p>On primarily life business we have all the explanations on the respective slide.  Let me just have a look on new business on page 19.  And here overall we have an increase in new business of 31.9% but it's a mixed picture of a decline in regular premiums and a strong increase in single premium business.  And on the bottom of that page you can see that this development holds true for Germany and for our international business.  So a trend away from regular premiums and towards single premiums like for the whole market.</p>
          <p>Property-casualty primary insurance, look at slide 22, where we show the development of the combined ratio.  In the first quarter we had 98.7, in the second 94.5 so already improved.  And we are still confident that we can achieve our target of 95% for the full year because it's typical for a company like ERGO that it has higher claims in the first half of the year.  And here we were particularly hit by very strong weather conditions, first in Germany with the winter storm Cynthia and then floods and strong winter in Poland and that is also the reason for the high combined ratio for ERGO's international business with 105.4%.  I should also mention the intensive competition in Turkey.  We also have a slight increase in expense ratio which is due to higher acquisition costs because we have more business from the banking channel.</p>
          <p>Our youngest segment is Munich Health, numbers on 24 and 25.  First premium development on 24, very strong increase due to organic change that is the quota share treaties, which were written in reinsurance.  So this is Health Reinsurance business.</p>
          <p>We head on page 25, you can see corresponding developments on all positions of the technical result, with a positive net effect overall of the strong increase in volume.  The investment results somewhat increased and therefore we are pleased with a consolidated result of 16 million.</p>
          <p>So far with Munich Health, now reinsurance.  The overview on page &#x2013; on slide 27, gross premiums written went up by 6%.  You could find the details on the next page to plus of &#x20AC;658 million, which is basically due to a favorable currency development and the positive effect from the Hartford Steam Boiler acquisition.</p>
          <p>Overall, these developments had an increase in life, overcompensate a decline in property-casualty business, which is due to our quite strict and consistent cycle management.  Technical results went down due to the high burden of the major losses.  Investment results went up and the operating results went down by &#x20AC;259 million, which is substantially lower than the impact of the increase in the loss burden.</p>
          <p>Reinsurance life, slide 29.  Here we show, the already mentioned premium growth owing to the large volume contracts, the majority of them were booked at of second quarter 2009.  So, you won't see the same kind of growth in the quarters to come for this year.  Here again, corresponding positive effect of these large volume deals on all technical items, good investment results and an increase in the operating and consolidated results, which is quite pleasing.  Perhaps worth mentioning that we have a &#x2013; we had a special tax impact in the first quarter which was then mitigated in the second one.  Therefore, you will find when you look deeper into it, very &#x2013; a strongly differing tax rate here.</p>
          <p>My last slide is about combined ratio in the reinsurance, which is, this time extremely important.  The loss ratio in the first half was 76.2% of net earned premiums, in the second quarter alone 71.8%.  The total major losses were 1.359 billion which equals to 19.6% of our net earned premium, with the natural catastrophe and man-made clearly exceeding the expected level and the five year average.  And whereas the first quarter benefited from some run-off gains, the combined ratio for Q2 included a very small run-off loss, to be more specific, it was a small run-off gains on natural catastrophes and a small run-off loss on major man-made losses.</p>
          <p>The expense ratio shows a sharp increase in comparison to the preceding year in Q1 and Q2.  This is the effect of accounting, if you see here which were &#x2013; which do not come in equal installments quarter-by-quarter, here it was about commission ratios and deferred acquisition costs, not any sustainable development.  Our full year expectation is on similar level then in &#x2013; through 2009, so roughly a 30% expense ratio overall.</p>
          <p>After so many numbers now I would very much like to progress a bit more on the natural and man-made disasters but whenever something interesting comes up, I'm told to hand it over back to Nikolaus.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Rightly, so.  Thank you, J&#xF6;rg.  And I have the pleasure to continue on slide 32, with a brief short word on these two major staggering losses, one, natural catastrophes in specifically, Chile.  The only remark I would like to leave with you is that it was not a market changing event and actually I personally think and many of us here rightly so.  A big loss should not change just for the size of the loss, the pricing in the market.  It would be truly unprofessional if we are always with a view of retrospectively try to reprice our business.  Since this was not a market or model changing event, prices in general should stay the same.  The fact of the matter is however that after such a loss in some markets of course specifically and those affected by the loss, prices go up right &#x2013; for the right or wrong reasons, of course, in Chile they did go up but not much beyond Chile.</p>
          <p>Second remark, refers to Deepwater Horizon, to those economic and ecological disasters, as I would word it.  First of all the loss &#x2013; the property loss is known 560 million for the platform.  We have our share at $80 million.  But, and there's the but, the uncertainties are still huge as regards the casualty claims.  And that is why we have taken a very conscious decision not to give specific details as regards our loss reserving so we stick to the old number which was a lower triple-digit million amount.  We search as regards as why and how did all this happen, what is the cause of the accident day's research.  This research is not finalized yet.  We are of course also ourselves looking all the technical let's say consequences, the requirement that we might ask for these risks also not finished yet this work for obvious reasons.</p>
          <p>What is important I think and that is not premature to make that statement, that risk management standards have to pepped up and the government has to take a much more serious stance when it comes to follow through with these standards that is a clear one.  Another important statement to make I think is that for these, what one might call, extreme technologies the objective must be to make them as safe as possible and to prevent losses like the one that happened from happening.  And that is maybe the more important part of the statement to avoid that these social skip &#x2013; losses get socialized or put on the shoulders of the society because we think for scenarios &#x2013; event scenarios like these even in the causality industry on the casualty insurance the industry is big enough and strong enough to offer cover for these losses.</p>
          <p>Last statement as regards Deepwater Horizon, we do not think that deep-sea drilling is such a evil.  We think it's feasible and calculable.  It must be made in the correct way.  I mentioned the risk management standards.  We as the insurance industry and certainly we at Munich, we will do everything to make or keep these risks insurable.  Sometimes it's helpful to put a price tag on a risk that sort of triggers or incentivizes loss prevention measures and conditions are very important all that together could be a major contribution of the insurance industry to make sure that this will not repeat itself.</p>
          <p>On slide 32 and 34, I take a brief look on the last July 1 renewal.  A general statement upfront maybe we think that the overall trend as regards to pricing did not change much from the January or April renewals.  There is capacity out there, enough reinsurance capacity to sort of digest what is being offered, the risk being offered, the business being offered, but by and large reinsurers do behave reasonably.  The cost pressure however on primary insurance is tremendous and it does not disappear at least not as we see it, soon.  So that affects the reinsurance placements by either cutting budgets or changing the buying behavior.  Overall the market is a competitive market and the moderate as we called pricing pressure we think will continue well into 2011 as well.</p>
          <p>Now coming to the July 1 renewal itself, on slide 34, you see what I would call a summary.  You know that format well.  Important message you'll find right in the middle, we could defend our portfolio quality because the price change is almost nil.  And this time even we could add a little bit of business, but this is not because we were more lenient with our underwriting, it is rather for bigger blocks of business.  And two, I would like to mention here on the cat side, I mentioned Chile, of course rates went up there as they did in parts of Latin America, so we could take some of that into our books, better priced business.  Actually at the cost of U.S. business where rates on the cat side were rather weaker and softer, so we had to let business go in the U.S. on the cat side.</p>
          <p>The other two bigger blocks of business are two motor treaties that we could acquire mostly release treaties, one in Latin America, one in U.S.  All for the rest, I think rate changes &#x2013; I think I should not go into the details unless you ask me for details.</p>
          <p>Offshore energy, this was not an important renewal.  We absolutely showed that rates will go up dramatically but our book is that has to be renewed now was so small that I would not like to deduce any sort of important remarks from what we experienced at that renewal.  I think this is the most important as regards to continue with one more last remark, terms and conditions did hold up and that is as you know, much more serious if they start to soften because it takes a long time to get them back to where they were once we started to lose here.</p>
          <p>The next two slides 36 and 37 address the topic of Solvency II.  I would spare you and myself from going to all the details now.  It is an important issue not only for the industry but certainly also for us.</p>
          <p>You see a couple of examples here where we are either happy or not happy or not too happy, we got this going on and you see it on the timelines starting with QIS4, going through the CEIOPS' Final Advice into the specifications for QIS5.  And these specifications are such that is I think a correction we have to make.  Some feel that it is more or less industry friendly and there is no big reason to complain.  One thing is for sure as of today with the specifications in place that they are way more demanding compared to what we have seen with QIS4 and certainly with Solvency I.  So that would mean more capital is needed which as such doesn't say much yet if it is the capital for the right reason.</p>
          <p>As regards the specifications you certainly know that there was a long ongoing discussion between regulators of the European Commission and industry.   We still see an imbalance as regards calibration for some risk categories and very broadly speaking we tend to say that on the market risk side the charges so far are rather more on the favorable side in balance, not individually, and this is opposite to what we see on the insurance risk side, where we think calibration is rather in the conservative camp.</p>
          <p>And this latter one has to deal with an often pretty insufficient recognition of diversification which is at the heart of our business and this results in both, higher capital requirement and that should not be overseen lower owned funds.  We continue to make a strong argument in saying Solvency II is the right thing for the insurance industry.  We think it will mean a quantum leap and as we lived along these lines of thinking over the last years we can say and firmly say, this system, the steering concept have &#x2013; they used this in the last crisis that is why we supported so strongly and we think it will also from a strategic point provide attractive additional business opportunities for Munich Re.  Yes but this is not the main reason why we support it, but we think it will and should bring us some more business and we are well positioned to take these opportunities up.</p>
          <p>Interesting maybe also, where do we stand as regards to preparation of our own internal model, we are in the midst of the pre-application process with our watchdog. It's a demanding process I can tell and what sometimes startles me a little bit that in Germany we have three or four companies applying for the green light, for the tick sign off.  Whereas in U.K. apparently there are 170 companies applying for that sign off I wonder how they handle that in all honesty.</p>
          <p>Well slide 37, this is the second half of the long list there you see the non-life underwriting risks where we really have probably the major problem.  But you see also other issues where we feel even maybe QIS5 is a little bit too friendly to take volatility where we think this isn't very important topic it maybe could be addressed slightly differently.</p>
          <p>Well so far as regards Solvency II and coming to my last slide, this is the outlook for the current year.  First of all, and this is nothing new to you, no serious changes in strategies or what you know is what you should get, we're working on the realization of that strategy, execution and delivery, as I worded it.</p>
          <p>Let's assume that the exchange rates move sideways which they never do of course.  But assuming that then our turnover should be slightly up compared to what we last told and certainly quite a lot up in comparison to 2009.  The big unknown apart from claims or event claims certainly is the return on our investments.  We have been quite conservative at the beginning of the year, where we even started with wording it noticeably below 4% is what we expect.  Now you see, we tend to say slightly above 4% that has to do with what we have for sure now for the first half year.</p>
          <p>But we do not work in to our expectation anything like a specific movement of the markets.  We assume the markets will more or less move sideways, that means that, regular income should over time reduce and we will have one or the other loss from disposals or write-downs.  The equity backing is so low that we do not see much of a up or down side there.  So, assuming that market move side ways with the conservative positioning we have, we think we are not in danger of anything there, but of course the trees will not grow too high and that is why we think we can not just take the 5% plus another maybe four or 4.5 and then come up with something dramatically above 4%.  We think slightly above 4%, is a reasonable assumption in a very volatile and uncertain context.</p>
          <p>Reinsurance combined ratio that is not even a stretch anymore, it's pretty much almost unachievable.  However, we do have our entire budget in place for the second half of the year as regards natural catastrophes.  It is not that we took a piece out because first half was difficult and unpleasant, no we have the entire budget sitting there and this of course has worked into our numbers.  So if you have a normal cat half year coming along, then together with the assumption that I just mentioned for the investment, we should be well on course to reach the 2 billion net income target that, we set out for 2010.  And let me make one additional remark here as regards to investments.</p>
          <p>We do not actively try to compensate big losses on the insurance or reinsurance side by pepping up the result on the investment side that would go against our asset liability management process and our technical manager, MEAG also has his own targets.  They would not be &#x2013; probably not at all be happy if we start to interfere, saying we need more income, do something.  So, this is if you like coincidence, we were positioned rightly in the first half of the year, so we could to some extent break it in.  I am not complaining about that but don't take any shortcuts here as regards our results.</p>
          <p>Well share buyback, maybe important for many of you.  We are on course to work towards the 1 billion that we set out as the target for this phase until next General Assembly.  Of course this is always subject to developments in the capital markets or the general economic environment and not very likely, any external growth possibilities.</p>
          <p>Summing it up, I think we're well on track.  Primary insurance, we still think that the target combined ratio of 95 is possible even though we're slightly above it.  Now we think this is well within the reach and we're on track for the 2 billion.  We'll not be able to outperform last year, which was a strong result but we'll continue to deliver and execute on what you know from us, it is important to us to deliver sustainably and stable returns to you, our shareholders.</p>
          <p>So far from me and here, Christian you're up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, gentlemen.  We will now quickly go in to Q&amp;A and may I please remind you to limit your questions to a maximum of two per person in the interest of all of us and please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  We'll take the first question from William Hawkins from KBW.  Please go ahead</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, thank you very much.  My first question on slide 29, when you are talking about the life reinsurance business, could you give us an indication as to what extent we could annualize the 309 consolidated result simply by doubling it?  I mean you've talked about capital gains being unsustainably high.  I am not sure to what extent you would specifically apply that to this division?  It doesn't seem to be the division that's had a big benefit from that.  And I also just wondered, if there was any particular one-offs in 2010. I've read what you've said on the right hand side of that slide but it seems to apply to a more &#x2013; 2009 as low.  So just a bit of understanding of where the 309 is going would be good.  And then secondly with regards to the primary life results, I am sorry I've forgotten the slide number but, yes slide 18.  Thanks for giving us the numbers on the swaption impact.  Forgive me if I've missed in the past but I don't think you've given them in the past.  Could you give us an indication of what the swaption impact was in the second quarter discrete and maybe what it was in the full year of 2009?  I am just trying to work out my own sensitivity of your earnings to the swaption.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>This is J&#xF6;rg.  Thank you, William.  First, I think I wouldn't be so courageous to double the income of the consolidated result of life for the full year because there were some positive effects from the one-off &#x2013; from the investment result.  And we will go beyond &#x2013; most probably far beyond our original indication of 300 million for this year but not double it.  I can't be more specific because the prognosis we have internally here also not very stable here.  Second the swaptions -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="inaudible" /> state beyond those results is there anything operational as funding in the first half or is it a pretty normal half?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, it's pretty normal the big quota share treaties contribute only lightly to the bottom line and therefore there is nothing specific in it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then second was about the swaptions. The contribution in the second quarter standalone is 170 million gross and after policyholder participation and taxes is a plus 50.  And you also asked about 2009, I have to look it up.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's correct, J&#xF6;rg.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Michael Huttner from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello, thanks a lot.  I have two questions, one on the loss ratio and a second on the primary life business.  On the loss ratio, I was trying to, so what I did is I took your excellent Basel or whatever and stripped out the loan losses and the nat cat and so half year 2010 was 56.8.  First quarter it was 58.2 which means second quarter was 55.4. Second quarter last year was 62.5 so it looks as if the underlying is improving hugely.  I mean a move from 62 to 55 is a big thing.  And I just wondered whether you can give a little bit more color what's happening there.  My thinking is most of it is credits but I just wondered if there is other moving parts.   And the second is on the primary life to the extent that the 116 million result, it has some gains and obviously these swaption gains in there.  Can you give us feel for what the business is running at as an underlying run rate at the moment? And is that kind of in line with what you're thinking? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So, Nikolaus said a couple of months ago that he would expect them to make some 100 over a year. That still seems to be realistic to us because it's still highly dependent on the investment result.  Your second remark is about the basic loss ratio, what looks like improvement, might be improvement but since we know the internal numbers here there are always impacts which are non-sustainable in both directions.  And therefore, I wouldn't be so courageous here to say that this is a constant improvement. You shouldn't forget that we're operating in a difficult market with side wars, is not slightly negative movements of the prices in the last year and therefore I would not extrapolate it at least.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One addition on the Nikolaus, as regards to your first question, Michael.  These 100 million refer to the German life book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay.  But I mean it's not as if you're saying that you did 116 in the second quarter and so you must do minus 16 for the rest of the year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, hopefully not.  But you should not take that for granted that we now double it for example.  No, it's 100 plus, yes, this swaption swing around that you couldn't see 50 million up, 50 million down.  So far, we mostly had it down, this time finally we have it up.  Still, I would rather have higher interest rates, by the way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Excellent.  Great.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from James Quin from Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, hello, yes, James Quin here.  Two questions please on the primary life business.  The first one is what do you see as the impacts of the fallen bond yields in the second quarter on the business?  From a practical perspective, do you feel you need to allocate more capital for business presumably under your market consistence epidology that would point to quite a high increase in the capital requirement as a result of the fallen bond yields?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry James, we can't understand you.  Could you go a little bit closer to the microphone please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry, yes.  Okay.  Let me start again.  Yes, I was just wondering if you could elaborate a little more on the impact of the fallen bond yields in the second quarter on the primary life business.  And would you see a need to allocate more capital in this business? Presumably your model is telling you that you need to allocate more capital to give you very much a market consistent view?  But the second side to that also is would you anticipate the ERGO would be lowering its crediting rates in primary life if bond yields would remain where they were now for the rest of the year?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On your first question James yes, we would also think that we would have to allocate more capital, but in our internal capital allocation, it's anyway calibrated differently from what we have in QIS5 here.  So we think that we are already on the right track here.  Sorry, could you repeat your second question again?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Okay let me, can I come back on the first one?  Basically how much extra capital would you need to allocate to the business? And would this actually mean that you would need to actually formally inject money into the primary life businesses? Or is it essentially money you could hold at a group level?  And the second question really is, if bond yields were to stay where they are for the rest of the year, would you expect that your crediting rates for next year would be reduced in line with what has happened in the bond yields?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Let me start with the first question.  And the higher capital requirements and in Munich Re's case we apply an internal model and each entity has to fulfill its solo Solvency requirements but it can fulfill then very tightly.  We don't need extra buffers on a subsidiary level and that means our principle of capital allocation is that all the excess capital, excess also for Solvency requirements is held on the level of Munich Re AG and therefore from what we see today, we do not intend or do not fear to be forced to inject more capital here.  The second is about the crediting rates, Nikolaus do you want to take it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, here I would answer generically, a single year &#x2013; and the change of bond rates in the single year alone would not change our policy immediately.  Towards the end of the year we always sit together to find out what is the right thing to decide what can be done and we have too little &#x2013; too far off that date still because it's not on the while the bonds rates it's a view to the market competitors and so forth.  But you can rest assure that we are in the conservative camp because we do not hope or put let's say work into our assumptions any dream of interest rates moving from A to B.  We take a very sober and realistic view but the development of a single year's bonds rate alone does not change to what &#x2013; it's a longer term view and we are at the lower end of the market anyway.  But we are not say, under pressure to immediately act hastily now if the interest rates stay where they are because we have worked it into our assumptions already last year anyway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, if I could just paraphrase what you're saying, what &#x2013; basically the input what you're saying that you wouldn't mind &#x2013; you'd be quite happy to be offering rates on new business that are quite a lot higher than the actual return you get on new business investments?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.  It is a little bit of a stretch of my statement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I did not &#x2013; I don't want you to insinuate that.  If you take this overview and we will not &#x2013; we never did that alone on competitive reasons, do something which economically we think is wrong.  Economics come first then comes competition.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from William Morgan from Goldman Sachs.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, I have two questions please.  The first one is just a little bit more general.  Taking a step back and looking at your leverage in the company, I mean, I guess your debt to total capital is in the region of 18% I think.  Do you see there being an opportunity to increase that, not at the current level, but let's say there was a market opportunity, do you think your business can run more leverage than it currently does?  Clearly you've peers in similar industries with higher levels of debt.  And if so, what kind of debt capacity do you think theoretically you have within the group?  The second question just relates again to what you were talking about on the primary life side. It was my understanding that with the crediting rates, certainly within Hamburg-Mannheimer, those were going to be at least kept relatively competitive, but as a result then actually the shareholder participation and profits in the business was coming down.  Is that something we're already seeing in the numbers or is that something that is only going to come through into next year? If you could just clarify that that will be very helpful.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let me start with the first about our leverage capacity, there is still some but it differs from rating agency to rating agency.  There's one agency who is very critical about leverage and therefore we are still a bit careful on that side since currently market opportunities are not of the kind that we would think that we should do immediately something.  Also has to do with Solvency II, the rules have not been finally decided.  Also the grandfathering rules and we would not speculate on the grandfathering rules to remain so generous as they are at the moment.  We have our first major subordinated bond will mature or we will have the first repayment date in 2013 and by that time we will decide and if market allows for it, and looks very attractive then I would personally think that we could consider issuing that.  Nikolaus on the second one.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I am afraid you started by saying it's a generic question, so won't be my answer I am afraid.  It's a little early.  The crediting rate is such as sometimes taken too seriously by outsiders because depending on how you sell, the crediting rate is an important argument but not the only one.  And then the question is do you do straight forward crediting rate and &#x2013; or do you do &#x2013; put it more into the terminal bonus that is from economic standpoint, a very different way of handling it and so forth and so forth.  The &#x2013; we don't see that we are under tremendous pressure to act.  The Hamburg-Mannheimer is better place certainly than Victoria was in the past and we will take as overview there but the fact is of course whatever you offer, you offer it for the entire back book as well and that's why you should really taking cautious approach there.  I would like to leave it with that sort of generic remarks for the time being, don't expect something very surprising to happen either way.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thanks so much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Question comes from Spencer Horgan from Deutsche Bank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.  And three questions.  First one is I am still not quite clear what you've been doing on the investment side or in the fixed income portfolio, so in other words, you obviously have taken gains on government bonds and covered bonds and corporate bonds as you've said.  But, I'm kind of wondering where that money has gone, if you see what I mean.  And maybe you could answer that question by sort of saying where you think the running yield might be next year when the portfolio assuming no gains or losses or write-ups or write-downs?  And then the second question is with Solvency II and QIS5, obviously, you've highlighted quite a number of issues and there are some fairly esoteric things in there that you've mentioned. Do you also have the view that there will need to be a QIS6 and probable delays to Solvency II?  Just interested in your view on that one.  Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With QIS5, I think, we all are very curious now about this exercise and what is the outcome of QIS5.  It's here to allow the industry and the regulators to learn from the result and if there are minor issues, which can be resolved easily then I think we do not need QIS6. And I personally would very much prefer not to have a QIS6 but to go ahead with the QIS5.  But I think it's just a speculation because we don't know it better.  With our investments, we did some minor changes here, we reduced our exposure to the weaker government bonds but we are still increasing our non-German covered bonds portfolio.  So, this is generally the trend. And we are still waiting for good occasions for increasing our equity portfolio.  What we expect as a running yield, we invest currently clearly above the risk-free bond rate so roughly in the order of 3.5% overall and therefore you should expect a slow decline of our regular income on an unchanged basis of market value over time.  So, for 2011 that might mean some minus 20 to minus 30 basis points for the regular income, perhaps a bit more.  Does it answer your question, Spencer?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that's fantastic.  Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Brian Shea from Bank of America-Merrill Lynch.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi there.  You just actually answered, Spencer asked the same question I was going to ask.  Maybe for my other question is on life reinsurance.  It'll be similar to the question Will asked at the beginning.  I think Will Hawkins focused on the net earnings.  If I could maybe focus on the technical results instead which should not be influenced by investment gains.  That line has also been very good.  A year ago I think in the Q3 '09 conference call, your decision has suggested that in sort of underlying technical result for life free should be about 300 million.  You're comfortably ahead of that and I could just ask if it &#x2013; is this a sustainable sort of changes going on here or once again is there something odd happening in 2010 that we should not be extrapolating, with the technical result?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian there was something odd happening in the preceding year because we needed some time for the stabilization of this technical result, currently not this year.  So in the preceding year we had used our U.S. American life reinsurance investment portfolio with substantial losses from disposal and they found their way in the technical interest, which they shouldn't have found at that time but currently there is nothing specific in it here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right, okay.  So, in the first half you are running at about 250 million for the technical result, sort of down so much with sort of multiplying it by two, it wouldn't be thus anything wrong with doing that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, that is true, yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Andrew Ritchie from Autonomous.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hello.  Most of my questions have been answered but I guess two very quick questions.  First of all could you just clarify the level of HGB reserves at the end of the second quarter?  And secondly on the Group's capital position, could you give us some indication, I guess this goes back to the interest rate sensitivity, what you think, the roughly the surplus capital position over the internal model will have gone over the first half of the year taking into account obviously there will be some small negative impact from Munich Re rates are down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We do not disclose the economic numbers over the year, because they are not precisely calculated and also it takes more time.  So we would never be ready with these numbers, just one month after the end of the quarter because it's still underway currently.  The decline of the interest rates means that our economic situation slightly deteriorated here that I must make clear.  On the other end our available financial resources go up and overall I would say it's more or less unchanged, the excess capital position and that is also what our Chief Risk Officer had indicated to us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Thomas Fossard from HSBC.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Good afternoon two questions on my side. First one would be concerning the comment of Nikolaus regarding the untouched buffer to absorb potential net capital use in second half of the year.  Could you remind us what is really how you're booking the budget on a quarterly basis?  And do we have to understand that if nat cat were to be at 6.56% of net premiums around in the second half of the year, clearly the 2 billion net profit guidance will be unchanged.  The second question will be on the life really on the U.S. market. Could you remind us of what the strategy Munich Re's has on the U.S. life reinsurance market as time being changed over the presentation you made two years ago when in fact obviously you were clearly pointing the side that you thought to be subscale on this market. I really think this question to potentially interest in <mark type="inaudible" /> put forth therefore by Hagan?  Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thomas, the buffer or the budget we have for natural catastrophe to be more precise it's for all for all major losses, man-made including natural catastrophes.  It's in the second half of the year higher than in the first half and it is not booked.  It's just something we use for our prognosis and what Nikolaus mentioned before is very important.  We do not take anything from this buffer, if the first half went worse than anticipated.  So, with the natural catastrophes you can easily take some 7 to 8% for the second half on an annualized basis.  Nikolaus on U.S. market life.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The second question was on the strategy of U.S. Life Re and what we do there in fact is a major overhaul of our entire company and the strategy.  And in the short version one could say we try to replicate to the extent possible Canadian experiences including partly using even or sending Canadian employees and managers and top managers to the U.S.  And in more detail that means improving and deepening the database we have at hand to deal with biometric risk metrology in the first place but not alone.  So it's reevaluation of the entire book.  It's a redoing up the pricing approach and so forth.  We're not going for market share but all will depend on the margins development.  You are right.  We are in comparison to other markets certainly punching below rate there but, be as it were, we will not try to quickly sort of make it up in to the higher rankings of the league tables here.  We rather would like to do it on a technical basis. If we come up with better intelligent as regards to biometric risk maybe we open up room for margins that then we can split shareholder and client and then gain a bigger share of the markets but that remains to be seen.  We have seen some first good movements there and it will also depend of course on the development of the financial crisis because we could imagine seeing more of relief deals in U.S. but it remains to be seen.  We have seen one or the other but not really many yet.  That is it in a nutshell.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Next question comes from Michael Haid from Cheuvreux.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, good afternoon.  On ERGO Life Germany again, simple question, is there a simple reason why the technical result in the first quarter was negative while the technical result in the second quarter was positive?  And also related to that in the current interest rate environment, do you need the realizations of capital gains to show a positive operating result?  And just for clarification, you mentioned minus 20 to minus 30 basis points on the fixed income portfolio for next year. Is this on the fixed income portfolio or on the total portfolio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Technical results, first quarter, second quarter, it's the technical interest which is somewhat fluctuating, but there's no major changes here in the implied profitability of the business.  And perhaps I can become a bit more specific later on.  Then and yes, we need a little bit of an impact from write-ups, write-downs and gains from disposal but that is quite normal when you have such a portfolio in order to be positive here.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  And the minus 20 to minus 30 basis points is on the total portfolio or in the fixed income portfolio only?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is on the total portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay.  Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="Operator Instructions" />.  We'll now take the next question from Roland Pf&#xE4;nder from Commerzbank.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon, a question regarding your fixed income portfolio.  Are you still running a net long duration portfolio following your reshuffling on the fixed income side in the second quarter or did you change here?  Second, could you mention the net run-off gains in <mark type="inaudible" /> reinsurance and probably also primary insurance?  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>J&#xF6;rg speaking, yes.  We are still running a net long portfolio but this is especially true for the reinsurance portfolio because in primary life we are structurally a little bit short here.  But here it is very difficult to calculate the duration of the liabilities because it has to do with lapses especially.  The net run-off gains I will look it up but I can't say it for primary insurance because for primary insurance we do not do such a precise calculation of the run-off of the individual claims, because it does not play major role.  Structurally in primary insurance, we are substantially over reserved, it's like a wave we have in front of us and it's more or less always the same each year, each quarter but it's not measured precisely because it's more ongoing.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe just one follow-up, I think I read somewhere that you lengthened the maturities of your bond investments, so did you actually lengthen the duration net or is it stable or now shorter than before in the first quarter, how would you compare it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We lengthened the duration somewhat, not dramatically.  These are all not dramatic moves, but I would guess, I'm not sure that, we are among our peers those with the longest duration at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I have now before the next question comes, the impact of the swaptions for 2009.  It was minus 366 on a gross basis and after policyholder participation and taxes minus 70.  For the first year of this &#x2013; for the first half year 2010, it was as I said, plus 170 and I have to correct myself the net number is not 50 but 38.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>We'll now take a follow-up question from Michael Huttner from JPMorgan.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you so much for this.  And on the offshore I just wondered how much was the premium or the premium rates for that and if you expand what sort of capital or &#x2013; I mean, how &#x2013; just to get a feel for how many years you need to get a kind of pay back on it?  And the other question if I actually have it, within Munich Health, my guess is the reinsurance part of it, is rates only profitable and the rest is not.  And my guess is 50 million a quarter from the reinsurance and I just wondered if that was a part of it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm not sure, here is Nikolaus speaking.  Michael, you understood it all correctly  but we do not take a sort of earn back sort of approach. We price all our risks for the long-term and it's a huge portfolio and the entire industry of these offshore marine, I think is a 3.1, $3.2 billion book. And this loss took it all. For sure. But I hope that those who do that business do not try to earn it back in a certain amount of years but rather price it correctly from the start that there is some earn back consideration here or there in the game.  Well, okay, but this was a major, major loss for the industry and it will have tremendous repercussions in how the business is being done going forward. There is no question in my mind.  And we do hope that specifically on the casualty side more coverage is being bought because we think that this event driven third party claims can be insured more easily than the long tail casualty books. And why should we offer as an industry on a worldwide basis more than $200 billion for cat events property and not do something of course maybe smaller numbers but meaningful also on the causality side?  But this is all are things that are being now thought through, discussed and is a little early to tell.  But I hope that that they will not be just a retrospective recalculation, if I did understand your question correctly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>With Munich Health, it is not true that reinsurance is always profitable and primary insurance is not.  A couple of quarters ago, we had some issues also on the reinsurance side because market was in quite difficult shape and primary insurance was performing quite well.  Now, this has been resolved and it's not the opposite but both should be profitable on an ongoing basis.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent.  Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>As there are no further questions, I'd like to hand the call back over to Mr. Christian Becker-Hussong for any additional or closing remarks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  Thank you again ladies and gentlemen for joining us.  There is nothing more to add from my side.  For further questions please call the IR team and we are of course looking forward to seeing you soon.  Thank you again.  Bye-bye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>