<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1508403" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-30</date>
    <companies>
      <company>851</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Group CEO, Executive Director &amp; Managing Director">Cameron Anthony Clyne</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Director">Mark A. Joiner</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse (Australia) Ltd.">Jarrod Martin</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities (Australia) Ltd.">Jonathan Mott</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Nomura Australia Ltd.">Victor German</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Chief Risk Officer">Bruce Munro</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="RBS Equities (Australia) Ltd.">Andrew Lyons</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Australia)">James Freeman</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Goldman Sachs (Australia) Pty Ltd.">Ben Koo</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Merrill Lynch Equities (Australia) Ltd.">Matthew Davison</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Macquarie Securities (Australia) Ltd.">Michael Wiblin</participant>
      <participant id="12" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Executive-Business Banking">Joseph Healy</participant>
      <participant id="13" type="analyst" affiliation="Citigroup Global Markets Australia Pty Ltd.">Craig Williams</participant>
      <participant id="14" type="analyst" affiliation="Morgan Stanley (Australia) Ltd.">Richard E. Wiles</participant>
      <participant id="15" type="analyst" affiliation="CLSA Australia Pty Ltd.">Brian Johnson</participant>
      <participant id="16" type="analyst" affiliation="BBY Ltd.">Brett Le Mesurier</participant>
      <participant id="17" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities (Australia) Ltd.">Scott Manning</participant>
      <participant id="18" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Securities Australia Ltd.">Chris Williams</participant>
      <participant id="19" type="corprep" affiliation="Group Executive-Personal Banking">Lisa J. Gray</participant>
      <participant id="20" type="corprep">Unverified Participant</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, good morning and thank you for joining us today to discuss our Full Year 2012 Result. The overall results should not be a surprise given we gave you a preview of the fourth quarter result when we announced the AUD 250 million increase to the economic cycle adjustment on the collective provision earlier this month.</p>
          <p>As you can see, the group delivered cash earnings of AUD 5.433 million (sic) [AUD 5.433 billion] (00:27), which is broadly flat on the 2011 result, and represented a second half decline of 8%. This of course includes the AUD 250 million increase to the economic cycle adjustment. Excluding the economic cycle adjustment, full-year cash earnings grew 3% and the second half declined by 2%. Our result was adversely impacted by UK full-year cash earnings loss of &#xA3;139 million, an outcome I'm obviously very disappointed in.</p>
          <p>As you're aware, UK economic conditions have been particularly challenging, giving rise to increased loan losses particularly in the commercial real estate portfolio. However, I'm pleased with the performance of the core businesses outside of the UK, which in aggregate, delivered earnings growth of 9.2% over the year.</p>
          <p>We've come a long way over the past three and half years and the results in the Personal Bank and the Wholesale Bank show that we made the right strategic decisions in 2009. Our cost performance has again been a highlight and our balance sheet position continues to strengthen, with our estimated Basel III Common Equity Tier 1 ratio now standing at 7.91% up from 7.09% a year ago. ROE was 14.2% this year, obviously lower than prior year, largely a result of the drag from the UK and the impact of the increasing economic cycle adjustment, but excluding the UK, the ROE would be approximately 17.2%.</p>
          <p>And finally, we've increased the full-year dividend to AUD 1.80 per share from AUD 1.72 in FY 2011 and held the final dividend flat at AUD 0.90 per share. Reflecting the good progress we've made in strengthening our balance sheet, we will not be offering a DRP discount.</p>
          <p>Turning to the operating environment, the Australian economy remains relatively strong and continues to outperform other developed countries. However, as I've said on many occasions, the economy is operating at multiple speeds with a significant divergence in conditions and very different levels of activity across various sectors and states. In recent months, the expectations of global growth have weakened, as emerging economies, especially China succumbed to the ongoing weakness in the larger developed economies.</p>
          <p>Our economists, like many others, have reduced their expectations for GDP growth in Australia. And in October, the RBA cut the cash rate by 25 basis points with the market expecting more cuts. And credit continues to grow in Australia at a rate below 5%, which is lower than our expectations of long-term trend, but still ahead of other regions.</p>
          <p>The UK remained our biggest challenge. While data last week suggests the UK's recession ended in the September quarter, we remain very cautious on the outlook, not the least because the quarter that was just reported benefited from temporary factors including the Olympics.</p>
          <p>As you can see, forecasts for GDP growth in 2013 have been progressively downgraded throughout 2012, and expectations are now for the UK to grow by just over 1%. The weak economic backdrop has contributed further falls in property prices, particularly commercial real estate outside of London. Funding costs continue to rise throughout the year and whilst we've seen some recent stability in the pricing of wholesale funding and term deposits, we continue to see high average cost of funds and a shift in the mix to higher cost deposit funding. We've re-priced where we can, but have not fully recovered this rise in costs and have seen pressure on margin throughout the year.</p>
          <p>The group's goal is to deliver sustainable and satisfactory shareholder returns. This slide outlines the key strategic priorities I laid out in 2009. While there have been many areas we have made good progress, I'm not satisfied with the returns we're generating especially from the UK. Unfortunately, there is no quick-fix solution to the UK, and believe me when I say, we've been looking. The restructure of our UK business that we announced in April was the right response, but it will take time before that business generates acceptable returns.</p>
          <p>In other respects, things are measurably improving. We've done much to deliver on our strategic priorities, but we have more to do to achieve sustainable and satisfactory returns for our shareholders.</p>
          <p>Unfortunately, the poor UK performance has masked good progress in our core franchises in Australia and New Zealand. Excluding the UK, over the last three years, we've delivered 7% compound annual revenue growth, 11% compound annual underlying profit growth, and 14% compound underlying cash earnings growth, these would be good numbers pre-GFC, let alone in the current operating environment.</p>
          <p>Importantly our domestic businesses continue to gain share in a low growth environment, but I don't want call out the performance in every business unit, I'll leave Mark to do that. I do want to highlight the successes we are having with two businesses we've repositioned in 2009: the Personal Bank and the Wholesale Bank.</p>
          <p>Personal Bank momentum has been particularly pleasing, above system growth in mortgage and deposits, combined with peer-leading customer satisfaction is translating to stronger earnings outcomes with full year cash earnings up 12%, and 25% in the second half.</p>
          <p>Wholesale Banking performance was another highlight with full-year earnings up 65% and 11% in the second half. While a product of the environment, the tough decisions we took in 2009 to reshape this business have borne fruit. We're also particularly pleased with the work we've done on productivity and managing our cost base. Costs are 1.8% lower than they were in financial year 2011, and are below the level of financial year 2010, reflecting the continuous prices improvement and disciplined focus on managing discretionary costs. This has been achieved without sacrificing investment spend on our technology transformation.</p>
          <p>Recent events continue to validate our decision to restructure the UK rather than pursue other options. A fire sale, even if possible, would not and remains not to be in the interest of our shareholders. The collapse earlier this month of the RBS deal to divest branches to Santander is a timely reminder that buyers of branches face significant technology integration challenges, which is why we've not pursued it.</p>
          <p>As I have already mentioned, the UK has been a significant drag on our returns this year, but we've made good progress restructuring the business and positioning it to benefit from any economic recovery.</p>
          <p>The UK CRE portfolio was successfully transferred from Clydesdale Bank's balance sheet to NAB on the 5th of October. The balance transferred was &#xA3;5.6 billion before provisions, down from &#xA3;6.2 billion in March 2012, and well down from &#xA3;7.7 billion in 2009. Provisioning on this portfolio has materially increased and implied CRE coverage, including <mark type="ph" /> specifics (07:14), collectives and partial write-offs now stands at 15% of the total portfolio, up from 12% in March.</p>
          <p>The transfer has also improved the balance sheet structure of Clydesdale Bank; it has significantly reduced reliance on group funding, and has a materially higher standalone total Tier 1 capital ratio of 11.6% post the CRE transfer compared to a 9.6% level before the transfer. Clydesdale is now a simpler and safer bank. While it's not immune to the economic and regulatory environment, it's now on a path to better returns with lower risk.</p>
          <p>In addition to these actions, many of you will be aware that in July I took over as chairman of the U.K. board and Mark Joiner and Rick Sawers have also been appointed to that board, and we are working with David Thorburn to oversee the ongoing implementation of the changes we've announced.</p>
          <p>It's also worth highlighting the progress we've made in running down the SGA portfolio, RWAs are now just AUD 7 billion down from AUD 25 billion in 2009, and we removed the economic risks on SCDO portfolio.</p>
          <p>When I took over as CEO in 2009, improving balance sheet metrics was a key priority. Our focus on this hasn't changed we've made substantive progress. I mentioned earlier with less than three months before the official start of the APRA Basel III capital requirements, we exceeded our self-imposed Basel III Common Equity Tier 1 operating target of greater than 7.5%, which is why we've been able to remove the discount on the DRP.</p>
          <p>We intend to operate at an appropriate buffer, above 7.5% over the medium term. We have further strengthened collective provision coverage with the increase in our economic cycle adjustment of AUD 320 million or AUD 525 million including the UK CRE overlay.</p>
          <p>Our collective provision coverage is now broadly in line with recent results from peers and higher when including the capital deduction associated with the GRCL top-up. We've also been focused on increasing the deposit funding of our lending assets. And since 2008, have pretty much consistently grown the absolute value of deposits more than the absolute value of lending balances. Over this period, new deposits have exceeded new lending by AUD 48 billion.</p>
          <p>You'd also be familiar with the importance I attach to our technology transformation and this slide demonstrates the size and scope. It's very much a total makeover from the ground up. We are renewing the fundamental underlying infrastructure of our core technology across NAB, as well as customer-facing and product applications.</p>
          <p>At the Interim Results, I outlined some key milestones we expected before year end. And I'm pleased to report we've achieved those and we had a number of other initiatives. We've successfully completed the migration of more than 300,000 UBank customers to the new NextGen core banking platform. We've launched nabtrade, our new online share trading platform, providing the first, serious major bank challenge in online trading in more than a decade and the only one that's fully integrated into a core banking platform.</p>
          <p>We've now made available everyday settlement for the majority of our merchants, meaning businesses can access funds processed on the weekend. And we've simplified nine old hard-wired call centers into a single virtual call center platform that allows greater service and shorter wait times.</p>
          <p>There's much more to come, but now we've done most of the hard work in transforming the underlying systems, I'm excited by some of the initiatives we're rolling out in the next 12 months that provide greater benefits to our customers and people; including lots of innovation across the payment space, including on mobile devices, as we leverage our partnership with the global provider VeriFone. And this will include the rollout of new contactless merchant terminals, replacing more than 30 different types of terminals with just two. Our state-of-art data center will come online and our new customer relationship management system and single customer view capability to 5,000 bankers and specialists across NAB will come online.</p>
          <p>While the investment in our technology transformation is significant, we're committed to it. Our approach is long term because short-term decisions in the past have got banks into the situation of having to deal with a mix of old and new technologies. I'll have more to say on our technology initiatives in a market briefing early next year.</p>
          <p>In summary, while operating conditions are challenging especially in the UK, we have good momentum in our core Australia and New Zealand businesses, and the right cost disciplines for these more difficult times. We've made good progress in our strategic priorities, but there's still more to do.</p>
          <p>And the areas of most significant focus for myself and my team over the next year will be turning around the UK business and stabilizing the CRE portfolio; maintaining momentum in our Australia and New Zealand franchises; maintaining our cost discipline and focus on productivity, which are key with a lower growth environment expected to continue; and delivering on the technology agenda is critical it we're to be a competitive force in banking and provide the best products and services for our customers.</p>
          <p>I'd now like to hand over to Mark, to take you through the numbers in a little more detail.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Cameron. Good morning, everyone. My pleasure, as usual, to take you through the numbers. Let me first of all just touch on the things that I think that mainly characterize this result. Firstly, on the positive side, the continuation of the group's record in containing costs and delivering positive jaws, are now four halves in a row since we switched our focus to jaws; despite, as Cameron pointed out, a heavy investment program around infrastructure and technology.</p>
          <p>Secondly, the strong result in both volume and profitability in the Personal Bank and continued upward trend in the Wholesale Bank, reflecting both our cross-sell traction and improved risk income; stabilizing of most of our balance sheet strength ratios at or near peer norms, in particular, capital provisioning and funding stability; and the substantial run-off of the SGA pool, which is really becoming de minimis at this point.</p>
          <p>On the negative side, I would highlight the adverse UK impact both above and below the line, substantially foreshadowed in an earlier announcement. However, what's also evident in the full period &#x2013; is the full period effects of the rating downgrades on the NII, including the sustained low interest rates in that environment, and the continued rise in CRE impairments in the second half.</p>
          <p>Secondly on the negative side, AUD 150 million uptick in bad and doubtful debts in the Business Bank, reflecting mainly top-ups on already large impaired corporate facilities, that's about AUD 80 million of that, but amplified half-on-half by the non-recurrence of some collective provision releases in the first half, mainly related to collateral matching and other housekeeping that was about AUD 40 million.</p>
          <p>In addition, we've prudently increased our economic cycle adjustment by AUD 250 million, reflecting recent deterioration in the economic outlook, globally as well as in both Australia and the UK. And overall, while the year-on-year outcome is pretty much flat, it's worth noting that in delivering that result, the rest of the business have effectively absorbed the AUD 700 million cash earning's year-to-year swing, which is entirely attributable to the difference in the UK result and the increase in the ECA, and that's a good measure of the momentum in the other businesses in the group.</p>
          <p>So to the financials then in a little bit more detail; cash earnings for FY 2012, the AUD 5.4 billion as Cameron said, basically in line with FY 2011 and up just under 3% if you put aside the economic cycle adjustment. The underlying profit level growth was stronger and up 8%, offset by higher B&amp;DDs, almost entirely the impact of the UK and the ECA.</p>
          <p>On a sequential basis, cash earnings were 8% lower in the second half over the first, but 1.7% lower excluding the ECA increase. Also on a sequential basis, a few other factors, banking interest income was down less than 1%, reflecting a combination of slightly weaker NIM at the customer level, falling interest rates and pretty anemic volume growth, just 2% in the half. Our Wholesale Bank and SGA effects increased this reduction to the 1.8% you see on the chart.</p>
          <p>OOI was up 8% mainly due to increased treasury and risk income in the Wholesale Bank and the emergence of asset management fees, offsetting a decline from SGA, as the SCDO gains in the first half of AUD 17 million were not repeated.</p>
          <p>Expenses were again tightly managed with operating expenses 1.9% lower in the half, delivering the jaws that I mentioned. And this was achieved despite continued investment, especially in technology and infrastructure, which remained around the AUD 550 million average that we have per half and we always have a second half tilt in that.</p>
          <p>The B&amp;DDs increased sequentially by AUD 353 million or 31% and four factors really combined to deliver that. The AUD 250 million ECA adjustment, the AUD 150 million uptick in the Business Bank, AUD 110 million increase in UK Banking, predominantly from the CRE portfolio and these were offset by positive movements in the Personal Bank in particular, this being the lower part of their annual cycle of bad debts, but there's some factors as well, I'll get to later.</p>
          <p>As Cameron said, capital ended much stronger at just over 7.9% Core Tier 1 on a Basel III basis and the ROE fell to 14.2%, although absent the UK and ECA, the ROE in the portfolio is a respectable 17.7% for the rest of the franchise.</p>
          <p>The group NIM was down 11 basis points in the half, but the customer NIM was down only 1 basis point. In fact, ex the UK, customer margin was flat. During the half repricing has largely covered increased deposit and whole funding costs, so the under recovery gap has not really gotten wider. Deposit costs increased in the half with the average spread over BBSW of the term deposit portfolio, increasing from a 109 basis points in the first half to 135 basis points in the second. More recently, the pricing of new term deposits seems to have stabilized at around 125 basis points over.</p>
          <p>Wholesale funding cost contributed a 2 basis point decline in the half due to rising average costs and issuance to pre-fund FY 2013. Average term wholesale funding costs have stabilized in the last few months of the year and the cost of issuance in the September 2012 quarter was 150 basis points over BBSW, compared to 172 basis points over the full year.</p>
          <p>We expect the average term wholesale portfolio cost to peak in about two years, if the average spread over that period is about 170 basis points or if it stays where it is now at about 150 and probably peak in the next 6 months to 12 months.</p>
          <p>Liquidity margin resets and SVR repricing including the latest 5 basis points SVR repricing in October, will bring about AUD 100 million of additional revenue in first half of 2013, which is split roughly AUD 60 million, Business Bank and AUD 40 million, Personal Bank.</p>
          <p>The non-customer effects outside the dotted box there of the customer margin really reflect these things, continued skew in our growth towards mortgages, which of course is averaging down the average yield on assets, but of course, it's quite accretive at the ROE level. Lower NII in the treasury banking book associated with reductions in the cash rate during the half. And of that 5 basis points you see there, a 3 of it is effectively NII, OOI swing that we quite often experience in this part of the book and the other is reflective of lower earnings on capital, the other 2 basis points.</p>
          <p>And we have an increase in the average liquids <mark type="ph" /> footings (19:57) with liquids growing faster than the interest earning assets, which also brings about a 2 basis point decline there. So they're the substantial factors.</p>
          <p>Looking to the business unit level, the major effect was a drop felt in the UK, which had a 12 basis point decline in the second half, following an 18 basis point decline in the first half. And you also see there the Personal Bank improving its customer margin and the Business Bank not being able to do that. Of course, the LCR changes that get announced from time to time only affect about 30% of the Business Bank book.</p>
          <p>We remain strongly focused on cost control. Various initiatives across the group combine to deliver operating expense contraction of about 2% over the half. Therefore, we've again delivered positive jaws 2.3% on a half on half basis and 5.2% on a year-on-year basis despite the decline in the revenue growth rate. Personal costs were actually down 8% in the half through lower average FTEs, themselves down about 1.5%; the non-recurrence in the second half of substantial redundancy costs in the first and lower variable compensation.</p>
          <p>You can see in the bottom right, the investment spend that I mentioned earlier, that has remained at fairly consistent levels over recent years and as I mentioned also the skew to infrastructure spending and the second half tilt in that spend.</p>
          <p>As a consequence of these programs, our capitalized software balance is rising, but it remains at or below peer levels at just over AUD 1.4 billion. Our amortization expense has been relatively stable, but as we bring more &#x2013; deploy more of these systems into operations, our amortization will rise and we do expect a AUD 40 million headwind in FY 2013 costs from increased amortization related to this.</p>
          <p>The second half B&amp;DD charge was nearly AUD 1.5 billion, up AUD 350 million due mainly to the increase in the economic overlay and the increased B&amp;DDs in the UK. In Australia, lower B&amp;DDs in Personal Bank, SGA and the Wholesale Bank offset the increase in the Business Bank. In the UK, B&amp;DDs increased by &#xA3;67 million, of which &#xA3;52 million was CRE. CRE prices continued to fall through the second half and this continues to put pressure on collateral values particularly outside of London.</p>
          <p>The charge as a proportion of GLAs is 52 basis points, as you can see in the bottom left, which is above both the long-term average of 43 and the benign period average of 24 basis points. The ratio ex the UK and ex-ECA is 31 basis points, which is within these averages. The mix of our book has been shifting more heavily to mortgages and that should help us bring this down below historic averages over time. So, one measure of that, mortgages as a percent of our GLAs on a spot basis today are 54%, and in September 2008 they were 46%. So that shows how this skew has accrued over time.</p>
          <p>Overall asset quality for the group was broadly stable despite increased impairments in the UK. Group categorized assets which includes Watch, 90-day past due and impaired, as a proportion of loans was 4.67% compared to 4.63% at March, and excluding the UK it was 12 basis points lower over the half. Impaired assets were up AUD 450 million, all from the net increase in new impaired assets from the UK CRE.</p>
          <p>The top right chart shows that asset quality indicators for the group ex-UK continue to improve, though down 7 basis points to 1.43%. The announced increase to the ECA was a prudent measure in light of deteriorating economic conditions in the UK, a weaker outlook for the global economy and the potential for heightened stress in Australia with the A dollar remaining strong despite falling commodity prices.</p>
          <p>Bottom left you can see that both the total and the specific provision coverage ratios are trending up. And on the bottom right, you can see that the collective provision coverage rose 3 basis points net over the half due to the ECA top-up, including the GRCL coverage, it's 2 basis points lower at 130 basis points.</p>
          <p>Looking at the main contributors to the sequential results here, you can see that Business Bank had a challenging half, down AUD 120 million in cash earnings, but if you look down the bottom you can see the annual return on risk-weighted assets and that is stable, slightly upward trending reflecting the work right across the group on our underlying ROEs. The Personal Bank profit contribution continues to improve and the returns in that business have also improved quite dramatically over the last two years.</p>
          <p>The Wholesale Bank also had a strong period with significantly higher earnings for the half and higher returns for the year. And, New Zealand on an annual basis, continued its upward trend despite some normalization in the second half, with the second half being slightly weaker than the first. Obviously, the UK and the SGA are drags in the portfolio at the moment, both with negative returns, but with SGA getting much smaller in its effect, and Wealth was effectively flat excluding the IROE &#x2013; IoRE, I always get that one wrong.</p>
          <p>Now turning to the individual businesses, Business Bank had as I said, had a subdued half earnings down AUD 120 million sequentially, really reflects three things. Firstly, only modest balance sheet growth, reflecting low system expansion with a flat last quarter following the third quarter spike in activity that was not sustained, so fairly anemic asset growth. There is the lag in re-pricing that occurs because of the requirement for customer facilities to mature. So the NIM was down 6 basis points, reflecting higher funding and deposit costs and also institutional margins have been weakening although the institutional book is less than or is only around 10% of the Business Bank book, and the AUD 149 million increase in the B&amp;DDs for the reasons already given.</p>
          <p>Asset quality in the SME portfolio was stable. SME B&amp;DDs as you can see on the bottom left, were up AUD 54 million, but it was off a low first half, which benefited from collective provision releases, partly driven by collateral matching. Against the earlier periods, the SME outcome looks quite stable. And if you look to the bottom right, the asset quality indicators are improving for the overall BB portfolio, albeit slowly.</p>
          <p>The Personal Bank results were very sound this period and demonstrated that the strategy continues to gain traction. Revenue was up 6% in the second half due to customer NIM increases and good home loan growth. Spot balances in home loans were up 5.2% in the half. B&amp;DDs in the second half were lower, largely reflecting seasonal factors, but also the release of remaining overlay provisions such as hardship and others around natural disasters that occurred a little over a year ago. And that lead to us releasing effectively an extra AUD 30 million. So, we do expect B&amp;DD in the first half of 2013 to increase in line with normal seasonal patterns and allowing for the non-recurrence of those disaster releases.</p>
          <p>The Personal Bank delivered cash earnings of just over AUD 1 billion for FY 2012, which is 19% higher than FY 2009, despite the changes in the business over that time, including the removing of fees around AUD 300 million and investment in the branch network and processing capacities. The Personal Bank continues to generate mortgage volume growth ahead of the system. The Australian mortgage performance was 1.8 times system and for the Personal Bank itself was 2.6 times system in the second half with the Business Bank having a more subdued time of it. Despite achieve &#x2013; despite closing the gap to peers on SVR pricings, we're now only 2 basis points behind two of the other major banks in Australia.</p>
          <p>As we've said before this strong momentum has been achieved without sacrificing credit quality and you can see from the vintage chart on the bottom right that new mortgages continue to outperform the older of vintages in terms of how they season.</p>
          <p>Customer account acquisition also remained strong, with net transaction account growth of 138,000 in the half, and it's been around 140,000 to 150,000 in the half over recent years. And some of you will remember that prior to 2009, the net transaction account growth was a figure more like 15,000. So this is staying at a much, sustains order of magnitude stronger level than it was historically. And customer satisfaction, which Cameron showed is at a historic high, is of course a lead indicator of customer acquisition, so we are hopeful for continued momentum on this front.</p>
          <p>Wholesale Banking, which tends to be somewhat counter-cyclical to the other businesses had a strong half with AUD 574 million of cash earnings. We've seen good revenue growth in the second half, up 5% to nearly AUD 1.3 billion. The composition this half is slightly different, reflecting market conditions. Customer activity has normalized back to more FY 2011 levels, reflecting relative stability, in the FX rates in particular. And market and trading opportunities increased mainly around treasury activities, reflecting a contraction in spreads and falling interest rates. This was achieved without stretching our risk appetite, and we continue to operate at a lower VaR than historically. Nevertheless, as the liquids book grow, so trading opportunities do expand.</p>
          <p>The Wholesale Bank also continues to develop its distribution capabilities, and during the year was the lead arranger of U.S. private placements for Australian corporates and the second largest arranger of domestic placements. It also had good success in distributing debt capital market products through JBWere and the Private Bank.</p>
          <p>NAB Wealth results were solid on a peer-relative basis, being up 3% year-on-year and flat half-on-half. Within this, investment cash earnings increased 10% for the half due to higher FUM and stable margins. Meanwhile, insurance cash earnings continued to be under pressure and were 18% lower for the half, reflecting deterioration in lapse experience and the cost of lapses this year is about AUD 55 million, and in FY 2011 it was about AUD 25 million for example, partly due to competitive pricing dynamics in the industry and subdued confidence levels.</p>
          <p>Claims experience in FY 2012 improved a little on FY 2011. The claims rate dropped from 49% to 48%, but remains well above historic norms, which are more like 44% over a 10-year period. Good expense management in the year helped to keep operating expense growth to only 1% and flat over the half.</p>
          <p>FUM flows have been negative over the last four halves partly due to weak discretionary flows in the industry and the maturity of the book. That said, investment market share has suffered a little in recent periods from expected outflow from the Navigator acquisition and intense competition in the platform space. MLC has, during the year, refreshed key platform products and improved pricing and functionality in order to address this. In fact, it was an important year for MLC, which made some significant strategic advances.</p>
          <p>Aligned investor (sic) advisor (33:36) numbers increased by 82 or 8% over the year. It increased its presence in direct asset management with the acquisition of Aviva Investors and now has full ownership or partial stakes and manages with AUD 50 billion in aggregate FUM.</p>
          <p>Launched MLC Wrap and migrated 28,000 customers from MasterKey Custom; refreshed the MasterKey Fundamentals product; relaunched the MLC Insurance Suite; recently launched nabtrade, which many of you will have seen, an online share trading platform with market-leading functionality; and developed a new range of retirement solution products which are soon to be released. These new and refreshed products will provide a great foundation for this business to grow and improve returns.</p>
          <p>New Zealand continues to perform strongly with the FY 2012 cash earnings up 21% on FY 2011. The first half was particularly strong as you'll recall with margin expansion with the swing to variable mortgages, which is largely concluded. And B&amp;DDs were very low, it was 11 basis points in the first half. The second half was lower, reflecting some normalization of these factors, so we got a slight dip in the NIM and the B&amp;DDs have normalized to a higher level albeit quite an ordinary one. And market share gains were made in important parts of the franchise, notably agri and deposits.</p>
          <p>BNZ continues to do a great job on cost with the CTI down to 42% &#x2013; sorry, from 42% to FY 2011 to under 41% in FY 2012, reflecting its strong culture of innovation and efficiency. Asset quality remains fairly stable. Over the half, the 90-day past dues to GLA increased from &#x2013; sorry, to 43 basis points of a low base of 35 basis points, driven mainly by business exposures. B&amp;DDs to GLA remains very low at 16 basis points for the full year.</p>
          <p>Funding metrics continue to improve with BNZ Core Funding Ratio well above the regulatory minimum of 70% CFR. It's operating around 84% CFR.</p>
          <p>Cameron has already discussed the very difficult UK Banking operating environment. UK Bank losses in the September half were &#xA3;114 million, bringing the full year to a loss of &#xA3;139 million. NIM fell 30 basis points over the year and 12 basis points over the half, reflecting higher costs of deposits and wholesale funding, and the falling benefit from free funds as five-year swaps roll off.</p>
          <p>The very low cash rate has reduced free funds contribution to earnings by about &#xA3;200 million over the last four years, so obviously reliance on an economic recovery to get that back. S&amp;P credit rating downgrade occurred in December 2011, so the second half of 2012 has the full period affect of that.</p>
          <p>B&amp;DDs were the other main driver of the result, up &#xA3;335 million over the year and &#xA3;67 million over the half, as I said before, mainly CRE-related. On the October 5, we transferred &#xA3;5.6 billion of mainly CRE exposures from CB to NAB, that's &#xA3;5.1 billion net of the provisions that come across with it, significantly improving the CB balance sheet, structure and simplifying the business.</p>
          <p>We continue to make progress on the execution of the strategy announced in April with FTEs down 263 over the half and the book mix shifting towards housing. Pro forma, as you see in the top right there, after the transfer of the CRE assets, the underlying business generated a profit of &#xA3;49 million in the half with a stable funding index of 111% and an FSA Tier 1 ratio over 11.6% which is 200 basis points higher.</p>
          <p>The non-CRE portfolio remains relatively stable with asset quality metrics only 4 basis points weaker in the half. So, the 90-day past due plus GIAs &#x2013; to GLAs was 1.84% which compares to 1.43% for the rest of the group ex-UK. The B&amp;DD charge for the non-CRE book was up &#xA3;15 million on the first half, reflecting some increased provisions due to the deterioration in the UK economy mainly in the leisure sector. Total provision coverage for the remaining CD book is 1.33% to GLAs, well above the group average, despite the virtual absence of CRE assets in that book. PPI claims have stabilized and the monthly run rate of utilization of the provision is in line with the modeled expectations. And provision of &#xA3;48 million was also booked outside of cash earnings for customer redress, which mainly reflects the potential claims from mis-selling of interest rate, hedging rate &#x2013; rate hedging products, a new area of focus for the FSA.</p>
          <p>As we've said already, CRE property prices fell further in the second half, here you've got on the right hand side of the chart showing first half and second half, mostly second half, price realization by geography and type of asset and that is obviously driving increased provisions on existing files and in some cases adding to the flow of newly- impaired assets reflecting the double digit recession.</p>
          <p>The 90-day past due and impaired assets to loans increased, as you can see in the top left there from 12.4% to 19.6% in the second half. Notwithstanding a much higher level of impaired assets, specific provision coverage including partial write-offs or adjusted for partial write-offs was maintained at 49%, and you may remember that was about 48% for the March 2012 figure. So, we've maintained this specific provision coverage at that relatively high level despite the big jump in the delinquencies.</p>
          <p>Furthermore, collective provisions sitting with this portfolio about &#xA3;240 million are sufficient to cover a further 10 percentage points of impairment at about a 50% loss ratio should that occur. These provisions will of course be progressively utilized reflecting the run-off nature of this portfolio.</p>
          <p>On the remaining businesses, the smaller businesses, the SGA portfolio remains well behaved. In the half, SGA made a loss of AUD 6 million compared to a loss of AUD 3 million in the first half. We continue to run off the book, as Cameron said, the RWAs are now down to AUD 7 billion from over AUD 25 billion in 2009. The SGA results are now increasingly insignificant, there's no longer any surprises coming from this portfolio. So from the first half 2013 onwards, we'll no longer report this as a separate business unit. The SGA P&amp;L will be reported as part of the corporate center. We will however, continue to provide disclosures around the remaining underlying assets.</p>
          <p>Cash earnings for GWB were flat for the half. GWB completed the acquisition of First Federal Savings Bank of Iowa in June 2012, adding around AUD 1 million in cash earnings. The business also delivered organic growth of around 6% in the lending book and continued to run off the legacy Tier 1 portfolio. Agri lending increased by AUD 200 million over the half. The Great Western operating region continues to experience moderate growth, leading indicators point to this continuing although the drought will affect agricultural production. However, we expect crop insurance proceeds to largely support the industry performance.</p>
          <p>Since the last result, we've had clarity from APRA on the new capital standards and there's been no material change to our estimated Basel III capital ratios as a result. The Basel III Core Equity Tier 1 is now 7.9%, which is well above the effective APRA minimum of 7%, and the group's newly adopted target of greater than 7.5%. We'll look to operate an appropriate buffer to this target for the medium term. As Cameron already mentioned, this has enabled us to remove the DRP discount.</p>
          <p>Higher operational RWAs are on the horizon and the regulator probably has other adjustments to make. We think this will create a headwind of about 20 basis points in the first quarter of the next financial year, slightly more than offsetting the AUD 500 million of hybrid securities that should convert in November. The rules around compliance for sub-debt and hybrid capital under Basel III are also firming up, so we will move to issue on that front before long where market conditions are suitable.</p>
          <p>The dividend payout ratio was 71% in the first half, it's 78% in the second half, averaging 74% for the year, but absent the ECA which we have looked through for dividend purposes, the second half payout was 74%.</p>
          <p>We continue to improve funding metrics in the half with good momentum in deposit gathering, driving the CFI up to 66% from 65% at the half, and improving the SFI from 85% to 86%. One of the key measures we use to manage balance sheet structures is the total wholesale funding gap, which is the difference between the GLAs and the deposit base. For NAB, this is AUD 155 billion at September 2012, which is at the lower end of the range for the peer group. Short-term funding in total fell nearly AUD 30 billion over the half and now sits at AUD 127 billion.</p>
          <p>The improvement in market conditions in the half meant we were able to achieve our funding plan for the year, and also pre-fund a proportion of next year's requirement. So our aggregate funding task for FY 2013 is targeted to be in the AUD 25 billion to AUD 30 billion range. Based on the amount that passes into the sub-one year category of AUD 28 billion next year, and with AUD 6 billion progressed in that task today. Our covered bond capacity utilization remains low at 19%.</p>
          <p>Also today, we've announced an offer to repurchase some retired government guaranteed debt of up to AUD 9 billion at September 2012. This will improve the strength of our balance sheet, as this debt will be counting as less than 12-month funding and so such short term and it will reduce our cost of funds. We've also retained a strong and conservative level of liquid assets at AUD 111 billion with the physical liquids at AUD 91 billion in September 2012, consistent with March 2012 level.</p>
          <p>Deposit volumes grew strongly during the period with deposit growth, again, fully funding lending across all the businesses. We also continue to focus importantly on the quality of the deposit portfolio with an emphasis on household and smaller business deposits. So, over the year, the Australian business increased household deposit volumes by 14.7% and business deposit by 7.9%, both of which were ahead of system and ahead of the peer group. We've seen strong growth in transaction deposits, 15% CAGR over the last two years and 16% growth over the same period on online accounts. CDs were up 11% over that period.</p>
          <p>The Wholesale Bank grew deposits strongly in the half, but importantly over 50% of this growth was in Basel III-compliant deposits, we've deemphasized direct financial institution deposits and have the lowest share of these amongst the peer group.</p>
          <p>So, let me summarize, good momentum in the Australian and New Zealand franchises, in that they were able to offset this AUD 700 million swing in cash earnings in delivering this result. The UK is disappointing, but the restructure is on track, and as Cameron said, it has very close attention from the new composition of the board, with the CRE and the remaining portfolio both well provisioned.</p>
          <p>The customer margin is stable, despite rising deposit costs and we have seen some relief on wholesale funding and deposit margins in recent periods &#x2013; recent months. Strong cost performance despite the continuance of heavy investment agenda. We've put in place the ECA as a prudent response to weaker economic outlook globally and in the markets in which we operate. We further strengthened our funding positions. And we're pretty where we need to be on the capital front, allowing us some relaxation in our capital raising, in particular the discount on the DRP.</p>
          <p>So with that, we'd be happy to take any questions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Before you ask your questions, just wait for the microphone and please state your name and the organization you represent. Jarrod, do you want to kick off?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Jarrod Martin from Credit Suisse. Cameron, Mark, in the past, NAB has come under criticism for a lower collective provision coverage ratio, to which you've responded by saying that when looking at your provision coverage ratio, you need to incorporate the GRCL and that's the way that NAB look at it. Ten days ago, you increased your economic cycle adjustment by AUD 250 million, however, that was funded out of the GRCL, so pre and post that announcement, there was absolutely no difference in coverage that NAB have, the way that NAB look at it and the way that NAB have told the market to look at it, which begs the question: was it actually a management decision to increase that overlay or was it a rating agent, a regulator or an order to &#x2013; that forced that change?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Completely a management decision. There was no influence of any other parties that you suggest. The &#x2013; we also factor in &#x2013; I mean, we do look at the GRCL and we've actually seen &#x2013; and it's a good measure to look at because it will move if there is a view that we're underprovided, but we also take account that there is not a lot of progress of IFRS 9, not as fast as we probably anticipated which would see that convert through reserves into the P&amp;L. So it was a decision we took in light of the data we saw out of the UK, in particular. It was entirely a management decision. There was no influence at all from any other party.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>The way you look at it, there's been absolutely no increase in provisioning, so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We look at it both ways. Some people look at it with the GRCL, which is the right way to look at it from a capital point of view. And some people look at it without the GRCL, which is the better way to look at it from an earnings sustainability point of view. So you got to be cognizant of both <mark type="indiscernible" /> (50:21).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jon?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jon Mott from UBS. I'm just going to follow on from that question actually. If you look at the, some of your comments before you said that you've shown really good cost disciplines for a difficult time, but some of the other settings you've had over the last couple of years for expectations of credit growth, asset valuations, the economic inventory cycle, the U.K. recovery, have consistently proven to be way too optimistic on what outcomes have come through. Do you actually think you need to move the whole bank to a much more conservative business settings for probably a much tougher economic environment on both the balance sheet and the way you're managing the business as a whole?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I don't think we've been alone in having more optimistic settings. So I think if you look at &#x2013; there has been an expectation if you looked at the, for example the Business Bank pipeline some years ago was supporting an optimistic setting; we weren't alone in that.</p>
          <p>We haven't by any means just assumed that was going to occur; we've always maintained the cost discipline in the event that revenue didn't arrive. And we've also maintained the focus on our technology investment to get to that settings. I think it's clearly evident now that, that optimism's not arriving and nor are we the only ones predicting a more difficult operating environment. So what we're actually extremely pleased is that we've had the cost discipline and the investments in technology.</p>
          <p>Now we'd obviously all like to see revenue rebound more quickly, but in the absence of that, I think we feel very comfortable that we haven't just relied on that and we've had that investment in cost discipline and technology. So we're obviously looking at a lower revenue growth environment and I think we're all set for it.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you need to move the balance sheet to being a stronger balance sheet from a more conservative environment <mark type="indiscernible" /> (51:14)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we've been doing. We've grown deposits by more AUD 48 billion over lending, we're dollar in, dollar out. The capital position is strong, we're increasing the &#x2013; we're making the progress towards our net stable funding ratio. So there's been plenty of progress on strengthening the balance sheet over the last couple of years.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Victor.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks <mark type="ph" /> for this (52:31). It's Victor German from Nomura. My question relates to slide 24, on UK commercial real estate portfolio. We've seen a rise in the last six months, which has been the most material rise in the level of impairments. And arguably, UK economy has been, has been doing it tough for some time now. And we also haven't really seen necessarily similar rate of increase in impairments for the UK peers. Can you just give us a sense for how different do you think UK portfolio, CRE portfolio for NAB relative to peers? And how comfortable you are that now, having reported this number, the experience going forward should be a little bit more consistent with what UK peers are reporting?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'd say that the peers had a more obviously problematic CRE portfolio early in the crisis. There was a lot of &#x2013; it varies case-by-case obviously. But there was some quite aggressive lending around CRE. And it became obvious quite early that a lot of that was in bad shape. Ours was always smaller, had a skew to house building and was arguably more manageable through a cycle if you did get a rebound in economic growth; you could have house builder sales in a number of properties, they could fund the facility through and so forth.</p>
          <p>So, really what's happened here is two things, the economy's gone into a double dip and so you can't really take a view through a cycle if you're in a double dip because it's going to be too long and you have to basically start liquidating these things. And the other thing that changed was that the peers you mentioned that heavily provided the CRE portfolio has then started to dump. So we found lots of properties being put to auction, no reserve on the auction, that sort of thing. And that's what's been driving down these valuations.</p>
          <p>So, we've had a combination of weaker economy, falling values and a realization in the organization, despite the different flavor of our CRE portfolio, that it's no longer appropriate to say, well in two years this will be fine, that we've had to &#x2013; so we've now put it in runoff. So we've &#x2013; a combination of those things is driving this.</p>
          <p>And we've had a change in the &#x2013; we've obviously got the group risk people deployed now to manage this portfolio. So, you've got new eyes, if you like, looking through it and that's really bringing probably more realism to bear in declaring facilities impaired and taking the provisions, and that's why you see a big step up, a combination of those factors.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, just if I could confirm, now that you've done that exercise, and you're not expecting a recovery, could we expect going forward that your experience to be a bit more consistent with the peer group?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I haven't spent a lot of time looking at the peer group, and Bruce, if you have a view, go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a portfolio of very small loans. The average size is about &#xA3;1 million and so it'll behave a little differently than a peer group, which have got large exposures, are more highly leveraged, but I agree with Mark, we've not spent a lot of time analyzing the peer group at the moment. We've spent a lot of analyzing our own book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Andrew?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. It's Andrew Lyons from RBS. Just one of the areas where your ex-UK business does appear to have underperformed your peers just in the recent half is just on funding costs. Just to this end, your stable funding index does appear to have been flat for over the last three halves, can you maybe just make some comment on how comfortable you are now on your funding structure? And just to this end whether you'd expect the recent fall in wholesale funding spreads will continue to translate into better retail deposit spreads?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We &#x2013; again, I haven't spent any time really picking through what the competitors have done on cost of funds, but we did &#x2013; we were fairly aggressive on deposit raising through this year. That's partly how we got the good outcome. And we did pre-fund a good chunk of next year and when you're replacing short-term wholesale with long-term wholesale that and being aggressive on the TD side does tend to drive your cost of funds up. And those things ebb and flow as you go along. So if there's a difference there I imagine it's relatively small, but it will be to do with the extent of the growth in that book and the pre-funding I would think. And then what was the second part of your question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just whether the fall that you're seeing in Wholesale spreads in recent weeks, whether you expect that to continue to show through in a <mark type="indiscernible" /> (57:40)?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I don't think it's really going to affect what's happening on the retail side. I think. It's not like you can go to any significant degree to the cheapest source of funds, because the regulatory rules are pointing you very much in a qualitative direction. So, I think it'll be what it'll be. If everybody is of the view that asset growth is likely to be low, you'll probably find the scramble on the retail side is less pronounced, and so you will get a bit of relaxation on the retail side. That's probably what we are seeing in the last few months.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, as Mark mentioned, what's masked in the CFI numbers is the critical focus on the quality of deposits. I mean there's quite clearly a range of deposits that will suffer significant regulatory haircuts. So, we've been targeting our efforts in our product innovation and pricing and our frontline sales against those ones that we think are going to have the high quality. So, that's been a significant effort particularly in the last year as we've got greater clarity on what the haircuts are likely to be.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>James.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>James Freeman from Deutsche Bank. I just wanted to ask about the risk income on slide 20, it's gone up a long way on the treasury portfolio particularly; just a bit of an outline as to why that's been driven, I know you mentioned it was your business spreads...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>...but also just an idea as to where we should expect that? It seems to have been climbing over the last couple of halves, is that a trajectory you expect it to continue or was this just a good half that runs through?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, I think it's a good half. There's no denying that. It's a function of a few things. We've got a larger liquids book, you've seen a significant contraction in spreads over that period and you've had falling interest rates, which increases the value of the underlying instruments. And about half of the economic impact of that is finding its way into the P&amp;L. We still have falling interest rates, I'm not sure spreads are going to come in as much. So you probably won't see so much contribution from the treasury next time.</p>
          <p>But on the other hand, the rest of the markets' trading activities were fairly subdued. So there wasn't a lot of activity in the FX markets, for example, there was relative stability there and relatively little customer activity on the interest rate hedging as well. So these things tend to also ebb and flow. So I think to some extent, but a lesser extent, treasury will have the wind at its back, but hopefully we'll get a little bit more volatility and activity in other parts of the trading book.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we have a couple of questions on the phone.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>Your first question comes from the line of Ben Koo from Goldman Sachs. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:00:45-01:01:15)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it was a bit hard to hear the question, Ben, but I'll try and answer what I think you're asking. In terms of, yeah, I mean, I think we recognize we've had subdued business consumer confidence for some years now, that's flowed into lower business and consumer activities, system credit grade. So yeah, I think that's been a feature of some years, so we think FY 2013 will be a challenging year.</p>
          <p>But the reality is that this is not a recent dawning to us by any means. We've had good cost performance over a number of years. And I think the pleasing thing about our cost performance is, one, we haven't sacrificed investment; we've continued to invest at the same level and we're now starting to see some of the customer-facing initiatives come online and I've flagged what we did deliver over the course of the year and what we're going to deliver next year.</p>
          <p>But our cost performance has also come when this year, in this half in particular, the bank has experienced the highest customer satisfaction and the highest staff engagement in its history. So it's not short-term cost reduction. So I think because we've been at it for some years, recognizing that the environment may remain challenging. So we've always had, if you like, as you should have, an option play, which is that we want to be ready if revenue arrives, and make sure we've got the right marketplace and things. But you can't just rely on that and therefore we've got to focus on cost. So one thing we are entirely optimistic about is we've got exactly the right settings from our revenue growth environment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>One more question on the phone</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>Your next question comes from the line of Matthew Davison from Merrill Lynch. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, everyone. Just some further questions on costs and I guess the potential to <mark type="ph" /> replace things (01:02:53) going forward. And if we look at this half, a lot of the improvement was in the corporate center, and your lower average FTE count. I'm just interested, going forward, you've got FTEs were pretty flat in the spot since this half. And looking forward, you're also talking about the pension deficit playing out in the UK potentially having a cost next year. So, just interested in realistically how confident you can be about that repeating on the cost side. And just as a secondary question, in the previous half, your redundancies in the corporate center went above the line and in the UK this half they went below the line; just wondering if you could elaborate on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. So, in the corporate center cost did come down, we had a lot of the redundancy costs that I mentioned, in the first half we took; the corporate center, they don't recur. Some of our incentive compensation is accounted for at the corporate level, and that was reduced. There were operating efficiencies taken from areas like finance, marketing and the like. And there was also some lower investment OpEx spend given where we are in the capitalization cycle.</p>
          <p>So, a combination of those sorts of things occurred at the corporate center. I wouldn't expect period-over-period to have the same reduction, because a chunk of that is about non-recurrence and the like, but it's certainly explainable what happened at the corporate center.</p>
          <p>And as to the UK pension, what's happening on the deficit doesn't really affect the P&amp;L, that really gets set <mark type="ph" /> and forget (01:04:55) according to a three-year cycle with the trustees. And the triennial review, we had took the P&amp;L expense from I think &#xA3;28 million to &#xA3;40 million per annum, which is designed to accrue for the staff still engaged and over time close the gap. So that shouldn't change just because the deficit swings around because of discount rates and the like.</p>
          <p>And then, as to future cost reduction, well we have a lot going on in the business, but as I've always said, eventually we need to deploy some of these technologies and that's going to create an amortization headwind. I think in the past, we've said that we thought over the medium-term amortization would rise at about 7% per annum. So, we've got other things, we've got an EBA locked in it plus 4% I think. So, there are certainly headwinds in the business, but we continue to simplify products, simplify processes and find ways to take out unnecessary work in the business model.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we've always maintained a management philosophy of trying to run jaws and we've done that. Obviously, the revenue comes down and gets harder as you &#x2013; each half you go into it, the cost saves get more difficult, but I think that's the reality with &#x2013; it's an environment we, as I said, feel quite well set for.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Mike Wiblin?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mike Wiblin from Macquarie. Maybe this is a question for Joseph, just on the Business Bank, bad debts were up 40% half-on-half, obviously putting a bit of a top-up, talking about deterioration into next year and that things are going to be pretty tough. Can you talk a little bit about what you're seeing on a sector basis, on a state basis and why you are so bearish going into next year, because I don't think that's the consensus here across some of your peers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I'm happy to hear that question. As Mark mentioned, the first half benefited from a credit on the collection line. The second half was impacted by top-ups, largely impacted by top-ups on existing exposures; largely our larger corporate exposures. The SME book has performed within our expectations at this stage in the cycle, with the exception probably, that Queensland has been a significant contributor to our SME bad debt number. In fact, close &#x2013; well, in excess of 40% of our SME charge this year came from the Queensland market, but we've seen that market stabilize and we've seen now several months of stabilization, so touch wood that might be a problem that's on the mend.</p>
          <p>As with regard to the rest of the book, really we are a reflection on what happens in the broader economy and the issues in the broader economy are well documented. We are comfortable with the performance of the portfolio given where the economy is at. And whilst I don't want to forecast what might happen, I'm comfortable with the overall quality of the book and that we're not seeing any marked deterioration, and that the leading indicators are at least in line with what we've been seeing in the past. To some extent we've seen some evidence of improvements on some of our leading indicators. But I don't want to make any predictions because, just as with credit system growth, it is a reflection of what's happening in the economy and we don't dictate what happens in the economy. But I'm comfortable about how we are positioned given all that we know about the economy today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I wouldn't characterize this as being bearish relative to peers. I think we're just &#x2013; I think actually echoing your commentary that it's been a tough couple of years, with subdued business activity and FY 2013 looks much the same. Now what we are calling out is, of course, that the longer that goes on, the more you've got to focus on productivity, efficiency, all that sort of stuff because things like the pipeline are not going to move. I wouldn't characterize us as having an out-of-step view; I think if I at least look on the public commentaries, we'd be much the same. It's going to be a challenging FY 2013, but so was 2009, 2010, 2011 and 2012.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Craig.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I saved up a good one for you, boss.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:09:28)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="13" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Craig Williams from Citi. A big dislocation between so-called cash earnings and statutory earnings again this year, about AUD 1.3 billion or 24% due to a number of business as usual items, legal restructuring charges, due diligence costs, which keep seeming to appear in the accounts every half below the line. So can shareholders expect the board to be adjusting more conservatively for this fact when signing off on exec compensation, which incorporates return metrics driven off this so-called cash basis, because I understand that this is being done at one of your peers this year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, cash earnings is not the only driver of remuneration, they look at a whole balanced series of factors. And we also have to look through what &#x2013; I mean, some of those are genuine one-off items as we restructure the business and we look at the strength of the capital position. But the board will look at a range of factors when determining compensation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Richard.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="14" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>It's Richard Wiles from Morgan Stanley. So I'll refer to slide 96, which has the group provision movements. Mark, several times this morning you've mentioned the economic cycle adjustment of AUD 250 million. I think you even said that you'd looked through it in setting the dividend for the half. And yet slide 96 suggests that that economic cycle adjustment simply offsets releases in retail and non-retail collective provisions. Can you explain why we have those releases in retail and particularly non-retail? And if it is something to do with the model, is the fact that you're taking an economic cycle adjustment to offset provision releases suggest that you don't have a lot of faith in what the model is telling you about your provisioning level?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Okay. Well, those releases really reflect two things. One I mentioned, which was the natural disaster overlays that we'll put in place which is a way to quickly acknowledge the impact of a natural disaster, but you got to expect that over time the reality finds its way into the book. Customers actually experience hardship and go delinquent and things like that. So it's appropriate that they have a fairly short half-life and they need to be brought back.</p>
          <p>And secondly, we've been doing a lot of work to effectively de-risk the business. So when I talk about things like collateral matching that's really doing things that treat the models &#x2013; get the models to recognize, for example, that certain loans are secured when previously it was provisioning on the basis that they were unsecured. And so we've had a lot of work on tidying up our RWAs because NAB is really behind in its sophistication when it became Basel II accredited.</p>
          <p>So those things have really driven some bottom-up releases if you like, and the ECA is really coming from the other end, it's really a top-down, and saying, well that may be true, it may be that we've got double count, we're releasing double counting, we're de-risking the portfolio, but looking forward, we see a more stressed economic environment. And we should make sure that we've got an appropriate level of provisioning. So it's not really to compensate, they're quite different decisions, arrived at on completely different bases.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>B.J.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Brian Johnson, CLSA. Cameron, not the friendliest room. Can I just ask, if you have a look on page 27, it says at the bottom of the text, it says that your housing loss rate has increased by 1 basis points to 7 basis points, which compared to some of your peers is more than three times higher. And then if we look on that same page, it says when it's talking about the collective provision movement, it talks about some refinements in the collective provision methodology. I'd be interested, could we get some comments on that deterioration in the housing book write-off rate, but also did the refinement of the collective provision methodology release collective provisioning over the period, Mark? And is that one of the explanations of the fact that you've tipped AUD 250 million into it, but it doesn't seem to have moved up very much?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You might have to repeat it. I went to 27 in the slides, and I wondered what the hell you were talking about.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right at the bottom on page 27 of the result. It says that the housing loss rate's gone from 0.06% to 0.07%, the peers are probably 0.02% to 0.03%, so that's the first question. Can we just get some explanation on what's going on there because it is substantially different?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bruce, can you comment on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:14:24)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>27 in the MD&amp;A you're talking about?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I would caution, I haven't read the whole thing though.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:14:42)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>What we have to &#x2013; I mean, what I would say is that we have to distinguish &#x2013; we have to distinguish whether the UK was part of that because that might very well be the case. I'd draw your attention to the improving asset quality, though, of the book. If you go back historically, Brian, you would have seen us growing at half system with poor asset quality and we're now growing significantly above the system with improved asset quality. So -</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>That's what I was wondering, <mark type="indiscernible" /> (01:14:08)</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well it may very well be the UK, because we're certainly not seeing anything like that evidenced in the Australian portfolio, which was evidenced in the slide. So, we can certainly determine whether that's the UK, it most likely.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And the second one is the change in the collective provision model where you've refined it, did that actually result in some kind of reduction in the collective provision or an increase?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the mortgage book?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no, no. In the &#x2013; on page 27 of the MD&amp;A, it also talks about the collective provision movement, it talks about a refinement in the collective provision methodology or it's model?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. No, that relates to some released in the first half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="15" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>In the first half, not the second half. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Brett.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="16" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Brett Le Mesurier from BBY. More questions about provisioning. So the collective provision on the way you like to look at it has fallen whether you look at it relative to risk-weighted assets or including GRCL, but the specific provision has gone up significantly both at March and both at September. It happened for the group, but it happened for the UK, obviously significantly. It also happened for New Zealand, it happened for the Business Bank. What lessons have you learned about the need to increase your specific provisions and to what extent are you confident that the increase in that is finished?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Bruce, have a go on that one. Do you want to defend your specific provisions, Bruce?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the short answer to the question is that we've got quite a robust process to arrive at our provision number. It's independently verified and then it's verified by external auditors as well. But the answer to your question is, are we at the end of specific provision increases, then the answer to that is it depends what happens in the economy because when you realize assets, you're subject to market price, whatever the asset might be you're realizing. So once again, we are somewhat a slave to what happens in the economy. But I'm confident that we've got the right approach and we've got the right number against those specific provisions at the moment.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Scott Manning from JPMorgan. One of the things that kind of worked its way through over the last six months is one of dividend yields and capacity to maybe stretch payout ratios to keep things looking good while cash earnings struggles. In that context, I note the adding up AUD 1.1 billion of fiber conversion plus the 2.5% discount on the DRP previously, sees your share count up a lot. Not a lot of growth in cash earnings, here. So, what's your outlook in terms of the appropriateness of that payout ratio, in light of the high dividend count and do you think it can go north from where it is?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, once the regulator stops moving the goal posts on exactly the capital calculation and the like and we attain that level, then if two things are maintained, one is relatively high ROEs in the industry and the other is relatively low asset growth, then you can sustain very high dividend payout ratios. You don't need to retain the capital in the business and you will generate a lot of capital given the ROEs. So if ROEs hold up and asset growth stays weak and the board is convinced that that is likely to be an enduring pattern, then the board will be comfortable moving to a higher payout ratio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I think the longer that goes on, the more the payout ratios would creep upwards.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So there is not a <mark type="ph" /> sophisticated (01:18:52) case to say that there's a disconnect between the change in the share count and the change in the earnings growth, the dividend should lag earnings growth next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It might too, next year. I'm trying to give a medium-term view or a longer-term view, really. Next year, there's still &#x2013; we've got a hybrid conversion going on. We've always said that we wanted to get our Core Tier 1 above 8% initially. So there'll still be some cap and the regulator still has a few decisions to make. So we're not quite done on it. But once we get the steady state, then I would expect that the industry can sustain higher dividend payout ratios.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="17" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Chris?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Chris Williams from UBS. I'm just wondering if you could provide some attribution of the AUD 250 million economic cycle adjustment between the UK and Australia? And in that context, when we look at the UK results, the core earnings or pre-provision earnings fell about &#xA3;40 million in the second half or 16%. If we view the economic cycle adjustment as something of a pull-forward of potential bad debt charges from next year, how likely is it that that business can actually be breakeven in 2013? And when I include &#x2013; when I think about UK, I think including the CRE portfolio that you're spinning out.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the ECA isn't attributed. It's available for whatever purpose. So certainly, the UK, what Cameron said, the UK reported growth, but I don't think that anyone's going to declare victory there. So what kind of recovery is it going to have? Certainly, our view of the Australian economy is weaker than the federal government's view. So we would see issues on the Australian front, so it's there really to cover any of that.</p>
          <p>As for the profitability of the business going forward in the UK, we've given you a pro forma there, that says it made &#xA3;50 million in the second half. The B&amp;DD of the remaining book there is relatively low, and hasn't increased much. I think it was &#xA3;85 million in the first half, &#xA3;100 million in the second half. So it's up &#xA3;15 million, for example. And the lead indicators are not bad on that. And it's also very well-provisioned relative to the group despite having virtually no CRE.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So what is the risk that in 12 months' time given the run rate of losses from the CRE book, that you have to top up capital in that book?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So it's not in Clydesdale, the CRE is in the NAB branch in London. So there's no chance of having to top up the capital because of CRE.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="18" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Last question, James Freeman.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>James Freeman from Deutsche Bank. Just probably a question for Lisa. Just trying to get an idea, if you could, just how much the additional rate rises over and above your peers have contributed to the profit result for the Personal division that you've had obviously above peer growth here. I'm just trying to get an idea as to how much of that is catching up on the, on the standard variable rate.</p>
          <p>And the second question is just around the other operating income, whilst there's some good growth in the second half of the year, as you say, again this is more of a timing issue between half and half, because from a year-on-year perspective it looks pretty much stable.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="19" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. In terms of the SVR, we were able in the second half to reprice a reasonable amount coming through, so we anticipate being able to do that into the future. So that's contributed to some of that net interest income growth in the second half. And that's why you can see the difference between the first and the second.</p>
          <p>In terms of other operating income, in the second half we had some elements of continued growth in some fee elements of cards and so forth. And also some one-off elements that we were cleaning out which we do periodically in terms of the book. So I don't anticipate that level of growth going forward. It was more to do with the second half.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="20">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Okay. Well, thank you very much for your time today.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>