<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1303570" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2010 Earnings Call - Press and Analyst Conference</title>
    <date>2010-04-28</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9506</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Nordea Bank Representative</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">Christian Clausen, President and Group Chief Executive Officer</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst">Jan Wolter</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst">Hampus Broden</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep">Fredrik Rystedt</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst">Peter Grabe</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="corprep">Carl-Johan Granvik</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst">Rickard Henze</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst">Christian Hall</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>I am as always very happy to say welcome to Nordea's Quarterly Report, this time for the First Quarter of 2010 on this very hectic day in banking, at least in Sweden. This press conference, analyst conference will be broadcasted in the four Nordic countries and also broadcasted on the Internet. So when you ask questions later on, please state your name and also what media or company you represent.</p>
          <p>The day is following the same procedure as every quarter. Christian Clausen, the CEO and Group President, will start off by presenting the results. After that, we have a chance to ask joint questions for some minutes. And after that, we will split the group so that analysts go into Nordea Solen to continue their questions and press is given the opportunity to ask Christian questions out in that corner.</p>
          <p>And with that introduction, I think I am ready to give the word and the floor to Christian Clausen, CEO and Group President of Nordea.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. It's a pleasure to welcome you all to this press meeting and we will start right away on the Q1 results, the main themes. Income is up, expenses are down, loan losses down, operating profit up, risk-adjusted profit up, and return on equity up. So that's a nice starter, I think, at least an appetizer. Let's dive a bit more into it and dwelve [sic] a little bit on some of the numbers. Income is actually up 7% on Q4, which we believe is a very strong development. It's even higher than the very strong Q1 we had last year. Expenses are down. And we see operating profit up 48%, a very strong result as we see it.</p>
          <p>Net interest income is down from very high levels. Net interest income is driven by a very strong customer activity. We have more customer meetings. We do more business with our customers. We get more new customers. And we gain market share, and our lending volumes are up. So underlying, there is a positive development in net interest income. What is that then dragging it down a little is the very low interest rate level. The low interest rate level means that we have virtually no margins on the deposits. We have a huge deposit base. The margins are extremely low as long as interest rates are low. And our huge liquidity buffers, which are &#x20AC;50 billion, is also yielding very low right now. So that is dragging in the other direction.</p>
          <p>So there is, as long as interest rates stay this low, there will be a drag on net interest income. But the underlying business momentum is strong, as we see. Total lending up 4% and we also see a good margin development.</p>
          <p>Compensating a lot for this is actually that commission income has gone up significantly. We have very strong performance in the savings area. Asset management commissions are up. Lending commissions are up. Payment commissions are up. And commission expenses for the state schemes still exist. We still pay a huge number every quarter, as you can see, which are of course dragging down, but that will of course disappear at a certain stage.</p>
          <p>Also, risk management products and net gains is up nicely. We see strong activity, customer activity in the corporate sector. There is very high demand for the risk management products. We also see high demand for credit bonds and we have issued strongly for our corporate customers. We have an increase in the result from group treasury and we also see a continued strong result from Life &amp; Pension, which also comes into this line. Expenses are developing according to our plans. If we adjust for comparison, so we adjust for the restructuring expenses in Q4 and the change in exchange rates, we see underlying expenses is down 3% compared to Q4. They are up 3% compared to Q1 last year. The underlying staff cost is up and we have increased the number of employees. All this is in line with our plans. As you all know, we have launched our growth initiatives and they are on track. I will come back to that.</p>
          <p>Credit quality continues to stabilize. Loan losses are down to 37 basis points. We still have collective provisions being made of 11 basis points and also some individual. We see lower loan losses mainly in Denmark, Sweden and the Baltics. And this quarter, we had no losses occurring through the Danish State guarantee, which is of course helping this number. And the reason is of course that credit quality continues to stabilize quite significantly.</p>
          <p>Impaired loans is up only 4% in local currencies in this quarter. And that is a nice trend, as you can see, coming from 19% in Q2 last year to 9%, to 7% and now to 4%, clearly indicating that the credit quality is improving. Especially the larger companies are doing much better. They restructured well into the crisis and are coming now out of the crisis with fairly strong results. We still see the SME sector; there we still see a number of companies still struggling.</p>
          <p>So there are still companies, which are or have more to do to get out of this in good shape. 53% of the impaired loans are still performing. That's a very strong number, showing that we impair loans still performing at an early stage. And we see the total allowances up 9%. And we see the provisioning ratio increasing to 54, which means that we have a high coverage ratio and also that the collective provisions are fairly high.</p>
          <p>We now have nearly &#x20AC;1 billion of collective provisions, which are collective in the sense there's no individual customers behind it. It is provisions we have made for risk we see out there, especially made during last year, but as I said, we're continuing to do so.</p>
          <p>This means that operating profit is high and stable and it is quite unique to see that we, through the cycle, have actually delivered high operating profit. And as you can see, the income level has gone up, but of course the loan losses have taken a part of that out.</p>
          <p>And this also means that we're delivering our long-term targets. You know our long-term target on risk-adjusted profit growth, which we launched back in December 2006 to double the risk-adjusted profit in Nordea over seven years. That is the red line, the 10% growth line. And we are actually on track, as you can see from the blue line, slightly ahead on risk-adjusted profit development. And on total shareholder return, where the ambition is to stay in top quartile, we're clearly in among the absolute top banks, delivering return to shareholders.</p>
          <p>This means that the outlook is still more or less the same. We still see the macroeconomic recovery continuing at a fairly good pace. The development is fragile and there are a number of uncertainties out there. And right these days, we meet some of them, the debt, the debt burden for various governments. We also see a number of other uncertainties. So it's still in effect.</p>
          <p>Costs growth will be in line with last year. And as we presented already in Q4, we expect risk-adjusted profits to be lower in 2010 compared to 2009. And then we now say that loan losses in 2010 are likely to be lower than 2009 and that we see credit quality stabilizing in line with the macroeconomic recovery.</p>
          <p>Let me give a few comments to the business development. As I already said, we see very strong development in business and not least, the household segment. And the underlying development is strong, as you can also see. If you look from the total household income, you can actually see on the blue line, where we excluded the deposit income that it's actually growing nicely.</p>
          <p>So the deposit income is under high pressure because of the low interest rates. That will probably come back when interest rates move up again some day. But actually, the underlying development is very good. And we can clearly say that our brand name is strengthened. We see a significant inflow of new customers, 12,500 new customers per month in the top segments is a very strong number. Of this, 70% are new customers to Nordea. And we also see our market shares improve across the board. So number of customers increasing. We do more business with the customers, and I will come back to &#x2013; the number of meetings is actually also improving quite a lot. That's the next slide.</p>
          <p>We do significantly more customer meetings and advise our customers, and because of that, they do more business with us, increase the volumes and increase the number of transactions we do, a very strong development.</p>
          <p>And this is not least due to the increase in customer satisfaction we see in a number of segments, especially compared to competitors. So we can say we have improved our brand, we're meeting more customers and customers responding to this by also coming into Nordea in a significant number.</p>
          <p>On the corporate activity, there we also see increase. We see business confidence coming back in the corporate sector. Lending volumes are starting to increase. As you know, they decreased throughout last year, but now we see some increased demand for working capital.</p>
          <p>We also see that the margins are improving and staying at a high level. And as I already said, this demand for risk management product is very clear. All corporations are now managing much more clearly their balance sheet and their risks and that we certainly help them to do through our various services in this area.</p>
          <p>This all shows that the household &#x2013; sorry, the house-bank relationship strategy, I actually went through in some detail last time, is paying off and showing it actually works. A few comments on other businesses, institutional and international banking. In shipping, we see confidence returning to the market. There are still segments within shipping that are facing very tough rate levels. But we see an increase in the activity level and we also see the margins continue up.</p>
          <p>Financial institutions, we have won several mandates and we are strengthening our franchise and our market share here. The margins are very tight in this area because these are the best customers in terms of credit rating. So therefore income is slightly down.</p>
          <p>New European markets, across the board, we see stabilization. Growth clearly continues in Poland, as you can see, but it's stabilizing in the Baltics, where we also see lending margins continue to increase and as we already said, loan losses are lower.</p>
          <p>Capital Markets products, as I mentioned, very strong activity. Now competition has started to increase again, as a number of banks, which have been out throughout in 2009, is gradually coming back, so more competition. We also see lower volatility. But still the activity level is high and the demand is good, and I think this result is strong.</p>
          <p>We also see that our ambition to improve on our position on the equity product is still performing well. The primary equity activity has picked up. And certainly our extremely strong position on the bond market, the primary bond market, is still there. And as you can see from the numbers, we are still providing a lot of funding to the Nordic corporates, 5.2 billion in terms of the bond market added to the volume growth I already explained.</p>
          <p>Assets under management at record levels, &#x20AC;169 billion, it's up 7%, a strong development. And we see continuously a very strong inflow of more than &#x20AC;3 billion. That's 8% annualized. Now this just shows that a lot of customers also think the interest rate is very low, so they do not put the money in the bank. They actually invest in funds or equities and so on. So this inflow is significant. And as you can see from the colors, it's widespread from retail funds, private banking, institutional customers, and very much our European fund distribution has attracted a lot of money throughout Europe and also Life &amp; Pension.</p>
          <p>Life &amp; Pension is doing very well. We have record levels at premiums, well diversified in all the Nordic countries. We have a very high share of unit-linked, which is according to our strategy. And we have a solid performance. It builds up buffers. And as you can see, Life really delivers a very strong product results coming into the group.</p>
          <p>Let me give a few comments to the regulatory proposals and the regulatory work ongoing. We have indeed a very strong capital position. Just to highlight, we are clearly ahead of our targets, which are Basel II targets over the cycle. Now we are working on Basel III, but on capital our starting point is very strong.</p>
          <p>We also have a very strong funding position, not least because our funding costs are clearly lower than our peers. And this is important going forward, because funding is one of the elements in Basel III where we will see new requirements. And this is not least due to the fact that Nordea has shown a very stable result development.</p>
          <p>This is the volatility in the operating profit over the last three years. And the volatility in Nordea has only been 14%. That's a very, very low level. And as you can see, compared to peers, not least European banks, it's extremely low. So this stable delivery, according to expectations, is key. This means that combined with a strong capital and funding, the foundation for new regulation in Nordea is indeed strong.</p>
          <p>We are working on the new regulation. We fully support the efforts. You can say that each of the elements in the new regulation, with a few exceptions, is looking good and logic, and we support them. But we add all the elements together, we get worried. The present impact study, which is being done right now, and we are actually today delivering our results to the Basel Committee, shows that the combined effect of all the proposal is very big. It will mean a strong impact on our customers and on the economy. It's clear that lending will be under pressure if that goes through and it's also clear that funding costs will increase.</p>
          <p>So all in all, we are certainly working with this. We strongly propose there will be another round of analysis and study during the autumn, as the slide shows. So when the study now is being done and the first results shown, we have to do another round when we calibrate the various initiatives in order to get to a new regulation at the end of the year.</p>
          <p>So it's important to state that these elements may look right, but we add them all together, it is a strong drain. We strongly believe that quality here is more important than speed. We do not have a bull market on our hands. We don't have very strong economic growth, so nothing would probably go wrong this year. So let's work it through and make sure that we don't make regulation, which puts a pressure on our customers and on the economy. And I certainly think that can be done.</p>
          <p>A few more comments on our strategy and our initiatives, which we launched one quarter ago. Just to repeat, back in December 2006, we launched the profitable organic growth strategy. And the initiatives last year, we went to middle of the road in order to keep our momentum, but also focus on cost, risk and capital during the worst part of the crisis.</p>
          <p>Now we have moved on to prudent growth where we will carefully navigate between the risks, which are still out there, and then the opportunities being seen in the economic, macroeconomic recovery. So we are working on the next level of strategy, based on our stronger position and we have launched our new initiatives.</p>
          <p>And I will not go through those in detail again. I did that last time. Just to mention that we have these six initiatives on growth and we have three initiatives on efficiency and foundation. They are the same as last time, so you don't need to read it if you remember it.</p>
          <p>And the reason for it is, of course, that these are necessary to actually deliver on our long-term target. We had this very ambitious long-term target to double in seven years, which is indeed demanding. But we believe these initiatives will actually make us deliver. And as I already demonstrated, we are on track to do that, but of course, it requires focus and dedication to do this.</p>
          <p>Let me give a few comments to the start of the projects and where we are right now. On future distribution, which is the biggest project, we have started up well. We are well underway. We have 10 branches through the new branch format. We are also working on 60 other branches on pilots to make sure we have the details right. And we can clearly see the effects of the number of 360-degree customer meetings. It's actually up 60% in the new format. So the new format actually supports more customer interaction and supports the business growth.</p>
          <p>And we are going to see that the time spent directly on customer interaction is up in the new format. We also get confirmation from the fact, I already mentioned, that we have this huge number of new Gold and Private Banking customers, 37,500 in Q1.</p>
          <p>On growth plan, Finland, we are progressing according to plan. We see income up, supporting this. And we have also, as you can see, had a large number of new advisors and specialists and are progressing well.</p>
          <p>On the Corporate Merchant Banking, the very big corporates, especially in Sweden, we are working well, according to plan. We have increased the share of wallet. We're doing more business with these customers. We have won several cash management mandates, and the plan is progressing.</p>
          <p>Growth plan Poland is also well underway. We are now planning for the autumn to open between 40 and 50 new branches, coming back to the method where we actually want to open one new branch per week going forward, and the deliveries here are fine. We also established the teams to catch the potential in the large corporate segment.</p>
          <p>On efficiency and foundation, we are also progressing. We have renewed, as we mentioned earlier this quarter, the IT contract with IBM. So we have paved the way for having much more efficient and flexible arrangement within IT, which enables us to take out a lot of gains. And we also think we can have a stronger and more stable delivery. And also the lean part in IT is developing according to plan.</p>
          <p>So the key messages are clear. Income is up. Underlying expenses are down. Loan losses are down. Operating profit up significantly on the quarter. Risk adjusted profit up on the quarter. And we are on track towards the long-term target. We see increased inflow of new customers. We have more customer meetings. We're doing more business with the customers. We get more customers and we are gaining market shares, which is a very important underlying trend. And we keep focusing on prudent growth and we are strongly committed to deliver on these next generation of growth initiatives.</p>
          <p>That concludes my presentation and we can go to questions and answers. And I will be joined, I guess, by Fredrik and Carl-Johan, so we can take all your difficult questions as well. Yes, any questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Jan Wolter, Deutsche Bank. Couple of questions. First on corporate margins, you say that they go up, I think, in Denmark and Finland, and I wonder why. What's the main reason behind those margins increases, especially in Denmark and Finland, which you point out?</p>
          <p>And then a second question. Given that I guess Nordea's strategy in Poland is to grow quite a lot, it's natural, I think, to ask whether or not you would consider bolt-on acquisitions in Poland. If you could comment if that is in the strategy and a little bit color on that. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I could start on margins, just to give the history a little. Back in autumn 2009 &#x2013; '08, a new margin level was established on corporate customers, reflecting the higher price of capital and funding and so on. And we have gradually been repricing the existing loan book as it has been rolled over to the new margin levels.</p>
          <p>And that does not happen in the same speed in all 4 countries due to documentation and tradition and so on, but it is still ongoing and it depends on a number of more technical issues. So I think the message is we still see the underlying margins picking up; now more slowly than previously, but they are picking up. And it goes per quarter a little, due to a number of reasons, in different speeds. The new regulation would put further pressure on margins, for sure, as it looks right now.</p>
          <p>As to Poland, I will say that, yes, we have a strong organic growth strategy ongoing in Poland. We are willing to look at possible acquisitions. However, we think that the Polish banks, as we look at them now, are very expensive. They're priced very high compared to other banks and we cannot really see the logic in that. So I think the main focus going forward will be the organic growth strategy also in Poland. But we are in all, throughout our area, looking at possibilities coming up which might be interesting.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just a follow-up then on Poland or rather on acquisition in general, do you have any target that you would like to share with us in terms of return on investment in general, where that should be, or if an acquisition should be EPS-accretive the first or second or third year? Anything like that that you would like to share? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. We have those targets but we do not want to share them. We can say very clearly that our main consideration when we look at something is that it fits into the Nordea organic growth strategy, our culture, our values and the way we do business, our one operating model. So it must be an entity that can be fully integrated. That's the first hurdle. The second hurdle is that the risk level is well controlled. We will not embark into high-risk ventures. Our risk profile is very contained and it should stay that way.</p>
          <p>And the third level is of course that a credible business case can be built. And that's your question. And I don't think we would like to discuss that publicly. But we put fairly high requirements, and that is probably alluding back to my statement that we think the Polish banks are pretty expensive right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then we have a question &#x2013; sorry; this is not working. I think we have a question over there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hampus Broden at Enskilda. I was just wondering if you could elaborate a bit on your actual sensitivity to interest rates. And I'm not necessarily referring to the SIIR analysis, but rather what you think will happen in practice if we had 1% increase in interest rates over the next 12 months, let's say.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Maybe I can take that question. I &#x2013; we have communicated previously the static, so to speak, structural interest income risk, and basically that assumes that there is no major margin pick-up. Of course, at these low interest rates, that will happen, of course, on the transactional savings accounts and particularly on the household side. So that will happen. If we look at the total exposure, it is depending on lot of assumptions, but it would be roughly in the area of 350 million or so. But of course that is depending all the time on the positions we have in the various parts of the business. So, of course, an interest increase or decrease will impact both net interest income and net gains. But the total is roughly that at this point of time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Does that mean that it's roughly volumes on transaction accounts, deposit volumes on transaction accounts, plus equity, times the 100 basis points?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, it's actually several. We can go through the details later, but there are several impacts. First of all, you have the transaction accounts and the savings accounts. Then you have the impact on the liquidity buffer, and finally you have the impact on the equity as such. So that would be the net interest income impact, so to speak. In addition to that, we also of course have positions in general, for instance in treasury and to some extent on the inventory and markets. So that would be the different components.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And some of those positions will have a slight offsetting effect then or is this still --</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, of course. Yes, of course.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And then you can just pass on the microphone. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter Grabe, Handelsbanken. Just a question on the collective provisioning. So I wonder if you can add some flavor on why you're booking so much collective provisions since a lot of peers are actually starting to reverse their collective provisions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I answer that question -- we have actually a model, which we also have approved by the FSAs in the various countries, which very much is based on the rating migration. And as long as we see a rating migration that is still negative, although much less so than for some quarters back, then we are increasing that collective provision. It's difficult to tell exactly what quarter that will turn. But obviously, as we see the economy recovering, we will &#x2013; we also see the need for increasing those provisions and indeed possibility of taking them back. But I don't want to forecast in what quarter. But we have, as Christian said, almost 1 billion now of collective provisions. And some of them will turn into specific provisions. Some of them will be released over time.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. A follow-up there. Can you add any flavor as to any particular region or sector for which you book these collective provisions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have some 25 different sectors identified actually with their own specific provisions &#x2013; sorry; collective provisions. The biggest part actually is related to the household sector where we don't do as much of individual impairment of small exposures, but we do it more on a statistical basis, and therefore they also turn into collective provisions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now we have a question all the way in back.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Rickard Henze, ABG. Two questions. Firstly, a follow-up to Hampus' question on the NII sensitivity. Which markets would you say is toughest to increase the deposit margins when the general interest rate levels start to increase among the Nordic markets?</p>
          <p>Secondly, trading income was very strong this quarter again, back to above 500 million. Would you say that Q1 was an extraordinary good quarter or was Q4 an extraordinary weak quarter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The thing about the sensitivity -- there are so many things in play. But the simple logic is that all our transactional accounts, both for private customers and corporate customers, there we earn nothing right now, because interest rate is very low. As soon as interest rates start to pick up, we sort of get a one-to-one margin increase on those. And they are significant. They are reported in the report. Then the deposits are more questionable, because there is a fight for deposits right now. Banks are struggling to get in deposits.</p>
          <p>So there it depends a lot about how pricing is done. But since margins now are more or less zero, then any increase will make them increase to some extent. And that's very difficult to forecast. And then there are a number of other positions, as Fredrik mentioned. So it's not so easy to give one figure. I know you like that, but that's not easy. I think it's more important to understand the dynamics. And it's clear that on the deposit side we have lost more than &#x20AC;1 billion of deposit income. And some of it is likely to come back, maybe a big part of it, but it depends on how much the rate increase and exactly how the competition develops.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But you don't foresee any changes in deposit margin competition or deposit competition among the Nordic countries going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I think this will develop all the time. I think we're already seeing a fairly strong competition on that area. I have difficulty seeing it developing more. But this also comes back to how deposits are handled in the Basel III regulation, which we still don't know exactly how much they count. So still this is uncertain.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And the trading, trading income question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We have had a good quarter, naturally. Of course, defining exactly what's normalized and what is a good quarter is extremely difficult. And of course, as you recognize both Q4, Q1, Q2 and Q3 were extremely good last year and now we have another good quarter. So this is a &#x2013; you can say a mix of good performance in treasury and good performance in markets and Life.</p>
          <p>So across the board, we had a good quarter. Of course, the opposite was true for Q4 where we had a particularly weak quarter in the treasury side. So this will be volatile. But we've had a good quarter throughout. And I think it's difficult to establish a normalized level. It will vary.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. This is Christian Hall from Swedbank. I had two questions, one regarding the costs related to the group initiatives. They were about 3 million in the quarter. And could you say something on how you see those costs evolve during the rest of the year?</p>
          <p>And I also had a question regarding corporate lending volumes, where you see signs of improvements. If you could give some more flavor to what areas in terms of companies and geography. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I can maybe start with the costs and we can move on with lending. But if you look at the cost, to your point, it was actually quite low when we are in the start-up phase, as Christian alluded to, on many of these issues.</p>
          <p>So the total cost figure, of course, we have provided for the year. And that will be gradually picking up during the rest of the 3 quarters. So first quarter, by natural, January and February, fairly slow, very low spending, and we will now sort of start ramping that up.</p>
          <p>So the spend, of course, the total cash spend was a little higher than the 4 million you suggest, because a part of it, of course, is activated in line with our disclosure before. But you will see this gradually picking up during the year. The exact distributions between the quarters are difficult to predict, but it will be picking up from now on. In terms of corporates?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the lending, I think we saw growth in all the markets, but maybe not as strong in Denmark as in the other markets. And the purpose of that increased lending is primarily more working capital for the corporate sector. We don't see investments coming back yet. As we know, there is enough capacity in most industries for quite some time. But as soon as the wheels start spinning faster again, as they do, people will need working capital and we're still drawing on the lines, and also new commitments to that sector.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just as a reflection, I think all three other banks having reported from Sweden in the last 24 hours have been more cautious on the corporate volumes. And so I would be interested to hear if you have any ideas on market shares and where &#x2013; why the difference is there and so on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think we at least kept or maybe even increased our market share somewhat in all the markets. What we have been saying is that we have a target to grow our business. We have launched some of the initiatives, like the commercial banking, merchant banking in Sweden, where we target particularly the upper segment in the corporate segments. And that is already now showing some good results. We also had lending capacity, because we have the funding and we have the capital and we have put that to the disposal of our customers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then I think we have time for one more last question. We're going back to where we started.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I just noticed that you changed the wording slightly when it comes to the cost guidance. You now include &#x2013; excluding currency effects, the cost growth will be brought in line with last year. And I was just wondering what you &#x2013; what was the currency effects on the cost base in this quarter, so we know what to add basically?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Approximately 20 million roughly. So it was &#x2013; if you look at the underlying cost, excluding the restructuring charge, it was about 2% down. That was the impact roughly.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, thank you very much then. I think now that we are ready to split the group and ask kindly the analysts and investors to join Fredrik and Carl-Johan and Rodney Alfven down to Nordea Solen and journalists to move over into the light corner all the way down to the left there to continue with questions. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>