<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1469777" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q1 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-04-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9506</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep">Unverified Participant</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Christian Clausen</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane BNP Paribas SA (Sweden)">Andreas H&#xE5;kansson</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Svenska Handelsbanken AB (Broker)">Peter Grabe</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="SEB Enskilda (Sweden)">Hampus Brod&#xE9;n</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="ABG Sundal Collier AB">Magnus Andersson</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Stockholm)">Jan Wolter</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer">Fredrik Rystedt</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Vice President &amp; Chief Risk Officer">Ari Kaperi</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="Carnegie Investment Bank AB">Thomas Johansson</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="Credit Suisse Securities Europe Ltd. (Sweden)">Masih Yazdi</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, it is my great honor to greet you welcome to Nordea's report presentation for the first quarter of 2012. And even though the location is new, business will be rather much as usual. That is, we will start off with a presentation by the group's CEO and President, Christian Clausen of Nordea. And after that, you will have a chance to ask a few questions. I would be very grateful, since this is all webcasted, if you then would state your name and the company you represent.</p>
          <p>After that, you will have a chance to meet with Fredrik Rystedt, Chief Financial Officer; Ari Kaperi, Chief Risk Officer; and Rodney Alfv&#xE9;n, Head of IR, to ask further questions among the analyst and investor group, and the journalists are welcome to walk over with me over to that side of the hall and ask questions to Christian Clausen.</p>
          <p>So Christian, the floor is all yours.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, and welcome to this Q1 presentation. I have two messages today. We continue our strong business momentum. It's encouraging to see our earnings power is strong, generating the best Q1 ever, at the same time as we have further progress in our huge change agenda adjusting to the New Normal.</p>
          <p>As I said, this is the highest Q1 we have ever delivered. We have some revenue growth. We keep attracting new customers, 22,000 relationship customers this quarter. We keep our cost stable. An ROE of close to 12% and we continue to strengthen our core tier 1 ratio now to 11.6%. And as I said, a very strong progress in our change agenda. We are building the new banking business model under the new regulation, a huge effort, the biggest change ever in banking, and we are approximately running 100 change projects simultaneously to do that on costs, capital, liquidity, funding, risk and so on. And the whole target is, of course, to take out the cost of the new regulation by becoming more efficient to shield the customers from the effect of new regulation and to build the strong bank.</p>
          <p>The relationship is actually very simple at Nordea. We get more customers and we make more money. This is a graph over the last five years where we show the red line, which is the number of new relationship customers and the blue line, our revenues. And it's not difficult to see the relationship; income is up 35% and number of customers is up 42% in the period.</p>
          <p>The numbers you have already seen, strong income, expenses flat and operating profits somewhat. As I said, the best Q1 we have delivered ever. Net interest income is stable to up. The net interest margin is largely unchanged. There's a low demand for lending right now. Our lending is not growing much. We have slightly higher funding cost and in this quarter, we have one day less interest to earn because there is one day less in the quarter. That, actually, is quite a lot of money. It's around EUR50 million. So actually, you can see the net interest income underlying is up.</p>
          <p>We have now calculated and made publish our blending net interest margin. That's a measure the analysts are focusing on, showing our blended deposit and lending margin. And as you can see, it's rather flat. It's reflecting the higher lending margins and the lower deposit margins. The lower deposit margins is of course there because of the very low interest rate environment and, of course, the strong competition we have for deposits.</p>
          <p>Lending volumes are slightly up, as I said, close to 1% in fixed currencies. Our loan demand right now in across the area in both from households and corporates reflecting the low economic activity. Lending volumes over the year is up 5%. Deposits actually also up more, they are 4.2% in the quarter. So, more deposits are coming in.</p>
          <p>Commissions stay at a high level, it's largely unchanged. We have a strong underlying trend in savings commissions, I'll come back to that, somewhat lower lending and card commissions reflecting the lower lending volumes and activity level. And we have some cost in this line for the new deposit guarantee fund system in Denmark, which is now being funded upfront and that is taking our part of this growth.</p>
          <p>We have a strong growth in assets under management up to nearly EUR200 billion, the highest ever. We have good net inflows, basically from retail customers. The market appreciation is strong this quarter, and then we have an added value, which is significant, nearly EUR1 billion, which is value added performance to our customers above benchmarks.</p>
          <p>In general, we have improved our investment performance quite considerably in recent quarters, and we are now number one or two on the Morningstar ratings in all four countries. As you can see here, the big blue line is Nordea if you should be in any doubt. And as you can see, we are number two. Shared number one I would say in Denmark. In Finland, we are number one; Norway, number two; and in Sweden, we are also number two now in the Morningstar ratings showing that we have improved performance quite a bit in this area, and also as I said, a good revenue stream.</p>
          <p>Net fair value is also on strong levels. You can see the dark blue area is the underlying customer business, which is developing in a good way. It's been a good trading environment and our customers have managed their risks well in this quarter and made transactions. We have some lower revenues in our Life area reported, but underlying they are stable as well.</p>
          <p>Cost under strict control, we said that after first half last year, we said that we'll keep cost unchanged over a prolonged period of time, and that has happened. In addition, there's an FX effect in this quarter of a roughly 1%, so if we take that out, it's clear that cost even may be slightly down.</p>
          <p>Credit quality is stable. Loan losses at 26 basis points, including our provision for the Danish guarantee system. The old guarantee system, which is also there, so actually adjusting for that, we are below 25 basis points, which is our average expected loan loss over the cycle, so it is satisfactory to see. We still have these two areas of concern, we also mentioned one quarter ago. Denmark is still struggling with the aftermath of the real estate bubble and economic problems in Denmark, and shipping is in a difficult environment. But there are no new problem areas, it's the same we're working with, we are working our way through together with our customers in a good way, and that some of the customer comes out of it and get revitalized, and can continue the life, others will have to close down, and we will have to take the losses. Overall, the credit quality is good and I'll come back to that a bit later.</p>
          <p>We generate a lot of capital. Since 2006, we have an average generated 9% more capital out of our earnings after having paid dividends to shareholders. And this is roughly in the recent year, EUR1.7 billion in more capital after having distributed EUR1 billion to shareholders. This is a very important number because this capital generation gives us flexibility. You can see, within a short period of time, we actually decide ourselves exactly what capital ratio we want to go to, and where we want to position ourselves according to the new regulation.</p>
          <p>We have managed our ways down during the quarter with 2%. We got new approvals on the internal rates based model on international branches. We have very stable credit quality, as I said, and the derivatives exposure is slightly down. And this means that we have strengthened our balance sheet. We have now 11.6% core capital ratio. It's up 40 basis points on the quarter and nearly 1% over the year, and, of course, it's due to this profit generating and the RWA development I mentioned.</p>
          <p>We have strong access to funding. We have in recent years conducted a predictable, transparent market-based funding strategy. We continue to have access to all markets, to all instruments. So we can fund ourselves at very low cost. We've decided not to participate in the long-term repo operation from the Central Bank because of that reason to have a predictable market-based strategy and that is received very well by investors.</p>
          <p>We have during the quarter issued like close to EUR12 billion in long funding, which is important, and as I said, we have access to all markets and we maintain our AA rating. Our liquidity buffer is still high. We have implemented a liquidity premia project, so now we price the right liquidity premia over the curve. We have changed the composition of liquidity buffer, so overall we are now LCR compliant, well ahead of the rest of Europe you can say for the main reasons that the parameters in LCR is not made public yet. We will see them soon from the Basel Committee. I think there will be some changes. So I think we're easily compliant on the LCR.</p>
          <p>And the return on equity is now 11.7% in the quarter based on a Core Tier 1 ratio 11.6%. That translates into 20% based on a Core Tier 1 ratio of 6.8%. This was the number in 2007, so you can say that this profitability on that capital base is 20% ROE, so actually, we have kept or increased our profitability level through those five years, but we have increased the capital ratio very significantly. At the same time, we have taken in the cost for new regulation, higher funding cost, all sorts of new costs, and we have also taken in, of course, the negative drain on deposit margins because interest rates now are very significantly lower than they were. So all in all, we have underlying improved our profitability level very significantly.</p>
          <p>It's also worth mentioning, which is getting a lot of attention throughout Europe, that we have no single quarter below ROE of 8%, and we have no single year below 11% ROE. So the earnings volatility is low, a very stable development and as I've said, underlying and increased profitability level.</p>
          <p>The second part of my presentation is about changing the business model, adjusting to the New Normal building the future balance sheet, and the future business model. This is the biggest change ever in banking and it's all happening at the same time. The regulator thought they would implement this over five or eight years to 2015 and 2018, but the reality is the banks have adjusted immediately and everything is happening at the same time. So we run a lot of projects, being more efficient on the processes, on our cost base, on our capital, the way we produce products and processes, on the funding, the way we spend our <mark type="ph" /> loan (0:11:27) funding which is expensive, and the way we run our contingent liquidity, building the liquidity buffers.</p>
          <p>Everything can become more efficient, and has to become more efficient, we have to take out a lot of the cost for the new regulation to build our own profitability level to a level which is higher than cost of capital and, of course, to shield our customers from these effects.</p>
          <p>And the driving force is, of course, to continue to deliver great customer experiences. We innovate products. We enhance products. We focus on the advisory concept of the bank through our relationship segments and we mitigate the impact, as I said. And the whole target is, of course, to ensure that we have a sufficient profitability to attract capital from investors and attract the funding, very much about cost and capital efficiency.</p>
          <p>Our relationship strategy has been defined further. We do more advisory in our advisory branches and we do more transaction on the mobile and Internet solutions. We have attracted a lot of new customers again this quarter in the relationship segments. We've made nearly 0.5 million new mortgage &#x2013; household meetings and we have made nearly 80,000 new mortgages. And we have increased the mobile features quite a lot. So now, we have nearly doubled the number of mobile banking users during the year, which is an important development.</p>
          <p>We're also developing our corporate franchise quite a lot and we are segment &#x2013; making our strong position in the corporate area. Our leading position is even more clear. And we have, of course, taken clear steps in funding more of the corporate needs on the capital markets. And here, we have a leading positions. We are number one M&amp;A advisor in the Nordic area. We are number one bookrunner on syndicated loans. We are also number one bookrunner on bond issues. So we have a huge business in helping our customers attracting funding on the capital markets, which is, of course, a trend that is growing. The capital markets will be something the corporates use more and somewhat less the banks because of the new regulation, and here it is strong to have this leading position.</p>
          <p>And this customer behavior we're seeing over time clearly supports our distribution strategy. So we see that the number of manual transactions are going down significantly, so customers want to use electronic channels more. They don't want to go into the branch to do a transaction. We see the number of net log-ons is up, but very importantly, the number of mobile users are up even more. So, lots of more customers use their mobile to do payments, transactions, whatever they want, search for information, and this is growing as I said, it's doubling over the past year.</p>
          <p>And this is supporting our future business, our future distribution strategy. We are taking down the number of manual cash locations quite a lot, and we're increasing the share of our staff, which is advising customers, that we spend more time advising customers and less on doing manual transactions because the manual transactions are moved on the net.</p>
          <p>And this is also very clearly seen when we look at our branch network, it's changed considerably over the last three years. Now, half of the branches are advisory branches where we don't do transaction. We advise customers. We do 360-degree meetings, go through all the assets and liabilities and advise them. That was a very small number three years ago. And we have established a number of service branches for those who still want to come into the bank with some manual transaction, maybe one that cannot be done on the net, if they lost their card, for example, physically to get it, if they have other manual problems.</p>
          <p>And then we still have around one-third, which is the community branches where we do all things in one branch, that's typically in the smaller towns, where separating has not yet been done. But we will continue this development and make our distribution network follow the customer behavior, which is, of course, <mark type="ph" /> clear. (15:34) You can say we're probably leading it somewhat, but the behavior change is clear.</p>
          <p>So cost efficiency is moving ahead according to plan. We are taking down the number of our employees we have introduced by 1,600 since mid-2011 when we started on the New Normal plan. We will continue that development and increase &#x2013; decrease the staff by 6% by the end of 2012. We're also changing slightly the strategy in Poland, full relationship banking strategy and also reducing the FTEs somewhat there along the same lines.</p>
          <p>The cost efficiency is, of course, key and this is not only about reducing the number of people, it's about becoming more efficient. Everything we do, we need to do more efficient. So it's about streamlining the network, as I said. It's about optimizing all value chains, all the delivery processes from finding out what product to do, optimizing the product, creating the product, the IT system, marketing it and getting it out there. That we are optimizing, so it can be more speedy and more efficient. Especially in the product processes, we are reducing cost quite a lot, even though we are turning out more efficient product all the time.</p>
          <p>And then, of course, we're looking also at our supply unit costs, not these premises, we are changing quite a bit, as you have seen probably. So typically we move to as fewer locations and we move to locations outside the city centers.</p>
          <p>Also on the manual processes, we are improving. We are moving a lot of manual processes to operation center in Poland, where our things are done cheaper and very efficient. And we are strengthening our IT resilience, we are making our IT system more stable, and this has very strong focus. We had a few incidents of non-stability and that is, of course, completely unacceptable.</p>
          <p>So, all in all, we improved the efficiency by all these measures and we see it clearly in the number. We've increased total income per employee, we increased business volume per employee, we increased the number of customers per employee, and we have lower cost to serve.</p>
          <p>On the capital efficiency, it's very much about ensuring that we have better products, which consume less risk-weighted assets and we have lower risks. On the quarter, we have an increase in the credit quality, which is very small. Actually, the underlying improvement in household and corporate segment is larger, but then we have a negative migration in institutional counterparts. A lot of institutional entities have been downgraded, as you know, during the quarter, and they operate as counterparties in a number of financial transactions, but the underlying household and corporate migration is positive.</p>
          <p>We have negative growth, mainly because our derivatives book is coming down somewhat, the underlying loan growth, as I demonstrated, is somewhat up. We had some FX effects, and then we have a fairly big effect from the fact that we have now got approval from our internal model to be used in the international branches.</p>
          <p>But we're much more ongoing, this is a huge effort. We have three roll outs in progress, the advanced model is being rolled out for the whole corporate portfolio. We have internal rates-based model for the Baltics in the pipeline, and we have the internal system for our markets exposures and counterparty risk, which is a major thing in Basel III, and is also on stream and in approval process with the authorities.</p>
          <p>On top of this, a number of other initiatives is going on. We're improving the collateral model, mainly in Luxembourg this quarter. We increased the central counterparty clearing quite a lot going live here at the end of March. We are focusing on the capital light products, as I said. A number of the old products simply consume more capital, in those days, this was okay because the capital rules was such that it didn't count, now it counts, so we have to be more efficient here as well. And we're strengthening, as already demonstrated, our capability of helping our corporate customers using the capital markets much more, which will also take off some of the implication for our risk-weighted assets.</p>
          <p>Then on funding cost, and particularly in Sweden, the huge debate ongoing what our real funding cost on mortgage loans and what is our margin. We have made this calculation now showing our real funding cost, which is the green line. And you could say when we go some years back, these curves follow each other. So the repo rate, the STIBOR rate and our funding cost was exactly the same, with only small variations. But you have seen in recent years that there is quite a big gap opening up, not least because our funding costs are going up, but also because we have to fund the mortgage book on much longer maturities than we did previously.</p>
          <p>These are taken out of our funding costs, and now there's a clear spread between the repo rate, the STIBOR and our funding cost. And this is a real calculation of our funding cost and this gives our margin development, the real margin development which we have, which you can see is, of course, not fully stable, but more or less stable around the 0.6% level, slightly going up this quarter, but generally on the same level as pre-crisis demonstrating that the underlying income has not gone up. And this income is the one that we didn't have to use to pay for the administration, the risk and all the things going on when we have to service our mortgage and originated.</p>
          <p>So the key message, strong business momentum. It's encouraging to see our earnings power demonstrated in the quarter. So while we have this huge change part on our hands and changing the whole bank business model, we are at the same time generating increased profitability levels, strengthen our capital base and strengthen our core tier 1. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Then we have time for a few questions. We'll start to the right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Andreas H&#xE5;kansson from Exane BNP Paribas. A question on the mortgage funding, you say that you have to fund it the more long-term than you used and I think we all understand why, but that's in Sweden. Can I just ask you, why can you then keep a short-term funding of your Danish mortgage share book?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The Danish system differs quite a bit from the Swedish, so half of it roughly is variable rates and half of it is long rates for the customer. And the Danish system is back-to-back, so the customer get the rates at which we issue the bonds. So, the customer carries a refinancing risk, which is not the situation in Sweden where the bank carries the risk of refinancing the loan every time it rolls. Even on the short maturities, the customer carries the risk. So the customers would actually get every time we refinance, a short mortgage will get the rate which prevails in the market. And therefore, you can say that it's a completely different system which implies less risk. But the Danish book is back-to-back, so it's not short funded. It's actually completely match funded.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. But I assume that you're not doing the longer-term funding to reduce the interest rate risk for the clients, it's probably to reduce the liquidity risk for the bank. And wouldn't that be the same risk in Denmark being short-term funded for half the mortgage book, which is a very big mortgage book of course?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, because we do not carry the risk for refinancing, it is the customer carrying that risk in Denmark. That's not the case in Sweden where we carry the risks. But that's two different systems and the Norwegian is in between, so it's not the same system. So it's very difficult to compare the rates because it's different how much risk we have to take. Because the new regulation implies that we have to be longer-funded where we have a refinancing risk in the bank in order to make sure that we have a certain buffer to actually refinance the stock.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. I'll follow that up later. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter Grabe, Handelsbanken. Firstly, also on the mortgage side, in Sweden, what are the front-book margins compared to the back-book margins, if you can give that figure? And secondly, if you can give us an update on your ROE target? When do you expect to reach that, and also, what you envisage in terms of the Core Tier 1 ratio in a longer-term perspective?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On the Core Tier 1 ratio, we will build the capital so we meet the requirements. We and the ministers are in the process of finalizing <mark type="ph" /> COD4. When COD4 (24:29) and the European directive is clear, then each country will implement. And whatever decisions are being taken, we could comply with the capital generation I have demonstrated here. So we will be where the authorities require us to be.</p>
          <p>On ROE, we are on track. And as we said last year, we have the target of delivering 15% on normalized conditions at 11% core capital. Now, if any of these conditions change, it will be slightly different. But we are underlying delivering the ROE increase we have on our plans, and we said in those time not a particular number, but somewhere between 1%, 1.5% ROE increase per year, we will deliver out of operations.</p>
          <p>So coming from nearly 12%, you can calculate yourself how long time it will take to get to 15%. But we also said we assume some normalization of the economy. Some growth, not zero growth, maybe 1% to 2% growth and we assumed a certain interest rate level. Not 0% interest rate, but maybe 2% following inflation in the short run. And that should give the final part to 15%. And at that time, it was then envisaged that we will be there within, say, a few years.</p>
          <p>Now, whether the economic growth will come back when, of course, it will come back, but when it will, we don't know when interest rates will normalize. We don't know, and then, of course, we have the uncertainty on the capital ratio. But I think the equation is pretty clear. We are delivering ROE increase as planned, and as I'm demonstrating here I think indirectly. And I think over the last ... <mark type="indiscernible" /> (26:06) for you to repeat the question for Fredrik and I on the mortgage-back book, which I don't have on hand the answer for it right now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have a question over there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. Hampus Brod&#xE9;n, Enskilda. I was just wondering if it would be possible for you to exemplify a bit what you mean when you talk about capital-efficient products? Could you give us a few examples? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. They come in different categories. They come in, I would say, some part of house cleaning. We have commitments out there which are not being used that to be more &#x2013; so if we for our customers are giving more commitment, the customer <mark type="indiscernible" /> (26:53) commitments and <mark type="ph" /> they always (26:55) go down. So that's one thing. The other thing is mainly for the big customers. That is to find a solution for the customer need, which implies less capital. So the famous example is, of course, the traditional revolver, which has always been used in banking. You just give the customer a committed facility, so he can draw whenever he wants.</p>
          <p>Now, underlying the customers, of course, has a cash flow projection, so they know pretty well when they will need what. So it will better not to give the revolver with a huge capital strain, with a liquidity buffer we have to build, and part of it has to be long-funded. It will be better to design specific solution for that cash flow pattern the customer has. And that we're doing right now, and the customers understand this very well, so it's not a big thing. They get a cheaper &#x2013; less interest expense because they get a better product and we lower the capital consumption. So, all in all, it's a win, win.</p>
          <p>And then for the big market where we do standardized products, it's about, again, doing more or less the same as standardized products, not spending more capital. Many of these products were designed in a period of time where a lot of the capital requirements were so much different, so they were actually well designed then, but now, they consume either too much capital or too much funding, which the customer does not get any benefit from, so that can be changed. But also for our household customer, this is when we do the 360-degree meetings, it's important to discuss with customer do you need the commitments, do you have &#x2013; can we change the profile of your loans, so we don't have to charge up for the very expensive loans which, of course, is the one with very high risk, i.e., no collateral over the very long maturities. And if the customer does not really need that type of commitment, then we can change the product.</p>
          <p>So that's along the lines, but I said, we have a lot of project now, each of the 100 projects have  sub-streams, so a lot of things are going on, and this will, of course, take years to change all processes and all products and so on. But that's the process ongoing and that what is what we have to do to sort of take out the inefficiencies, which have arisen because of new regulation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>With the main effect that can be seen from the outside <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:10) just that risk weighted assets to total assets is going down, or will there be any other obvious effect on like the P&amp;L, on the balance sheet <mark type="indiscernible" /> (29:12) the outside?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, but in essence, the idea is that we don't &#x2013; I mean, internally, I call it wasted. We don't waste resources for no use because the customer do not appreciate it, and it's only a cost to us, so it's take away the waste and the inefficiency of the products. And, of course, this will ultimately lower the <mark type="ph" /> ROEs (0:29:40) and hopefully increase <mark type="ph" /> RAROCAR (0:29:44) the return on the capital for us.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If you could pass that microphone down two rows? Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Mr. Clausen, I'm <mark type="ph" /> Sylvie Vanpe from Villis (29:48). I would like to drill down a little bit further on the Core Tier 1 capital ratio. Which of all these hundreds projects would you prioritize most to sort of be compliant with the transitional rules that are going to come?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But I think on capital, we are actually compliant today. I think the difference is very small, so it's all a matter of knowing exactly what the rules will be, we don't know that yet, the legislation have not been passed. When we know that, we will adjust. Unfortunately, I would love to say I could prioritize the initiatives. But as I say to our staff, we have to do everything at once. This is a huge change agenda we're doing in one go. Ideally, we would love to do something now and something later, that is not the possibility, because the new regulation is coming in. And as the authorities thought they would phase it in over eight years, they are not in reality doing that, the market is forcing us to phase it in over one, two, max three years.</p>
          <p>So we have to do everything in one go, and we have to see &#x2013; understand that each of the projects are addressing different types of the scarce resources. Some are addressing costs, some are addressing capital, some are addressing contingent liquidity coming out of the liquidity buffer, and some are addressing the amount of long-term funding we need. So they are all equally important. And of course, this is up to us, as clever as possible to make that mix right, so we optimize the ROE, which is, of course, what we need to do, because that is not a sustainable banking model if we do not deliver on ROE above cost of capital. That, everyone needs to understand and certainly that is the big pressure on banks throughout Europe.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think we have one more question on the next row behind. So if you would pass that microphone on. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Magnus Andersson with ABG. Just a broader question, Christian, for you regarding the Danish banking market, if you could say something about what you think about the structural game? What the end-game will be in Denmark and whether you see Nordea at some point taking part in that consolidation that we have ahead of us?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it's obvious that consolidation is ongoing, the tough way right now, but there was a strong message from both the minister and from others during the weekend that the weaker banks in Denmark have to consolidate before it goes all wrong for them. To keep seeing small banks in Denmark fail is, of course, very damaging to the Danish economy and the trust from the financial markets. So we can only strongly encourage banks would see a problem out there coming up in good time, take contact to somebody else merge into a stronger entity in order to avoid the shareholders lose all their money and maybe even the banking sector lose more money.</p>
          <p>So the future is, of course, that there will be a consolidation. There are also a lot of smaller banks which are well-run, which do not have that problem. So I don't think the Danish market will consolidate into a very consolidated market with maybe 10 or 20 banks. I still think we've got a lot of banks, but we will come clearly below the 125 banks or whatever it was we came from and we'll come clearly below 100 banks because some of these smaller entities will not be able to cope with the new regulation and the funding cost, and they have to merge.</p>
          <p>So that is what will happen. I think it becomes clear to everyone that the option of ending up in a <mark type="ph" /> weakened (0:33:28) where you fail and have to write-off all your share capital is not the best way. I think that is &#x2013; by now stands clear for everyone. And therefore, there are much better ways to merge.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And do you see Nordea taking part in that consolidation at some point?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have already done that. We were the first-mover in taking over the branch network from Roskilde Bank, a Fionia Bank and we can consider other options as well. We build our network ourselves <mark type="indiscernible" /> (33:54) the way we like it. Of course, if we have a <mark type="ph" /> white (33:58) spot, which we think is weak, then we can use this option as well. So we are not saying no to doing that. We have said we are clearly open for discussions, very few wants to discuss, but we are open to discussions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And I think we have a concluding question to the CEO, yes, thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Jan Wolter, Deutsche Bank. I have two quick question. First, you mentioned that you're not compliant &#x2013; LCR compliant on a currency basis, when do you plan to be that, and could you shed some light on the cost of becoming that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Now, LCR is not a rule yet. It's a coming rule and we have come a long way, there are very few banks in Europe which are compliant. We are complying in terms of size, in terms of the instruments we have invested in, but not for currency. And that we can do, I wouldn't say overnight, but in a very short timeframe and the cost is very limited. So this is not a major issue and we will be compliant as soon as we want to.</p>
          <p>Now, I actually &#x2013; or we actually know that the rules in LCR will be changed. The Basel Committee will come out with new parameters on <mark type="ph" /> run-outs (0:35:18) and Level 1, Level 2 assets. So the final decision has not even been made on LCR, so we're at a pretty early stage to say you are compliant when you don't know the rule, and the rule will be softened up somewhat. So I can easily say I don't think there will be extra costs in this, they will be marginal.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you very much then. Well, as I said, I will give the floor to Fredrik, Ari and Rodney to conclude with more detailed questions for analysts and investors, and Christian Clausen will move over in &#x2013; through that corridor and hopefully take the journalists along with him. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks for staying and paying attention to the report. We have few slides just giving you some extra details on NII, liquidity and the credit quality. So I suggest that we start, Fredrik and Ari, and then we go directly to the Q&amp;A. Please, Fredrik.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, very welcome. I will just start with two slides, and the first one relates to actually not darkness, Rodney, should I &#x2013; firstly I should not relate to darkness, it should relate to the bridge on net interest income and let me...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (38:41).</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>It's still darkness.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>
            <mark type="indiscernible" /> (38:51) there we are. Now it's good.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a miracle. Okay. Once again, just two quick slides, the first one on net interest income. And as you can see, we've had a fairly weak growth in the quarter, and that actually goes for most sectors and most markets. So the volume-driven contribution to NII is only EUR9 million for the quarter, and a lot bigger, of course, year-on-year. So, lending EUR6 million and deposit EUR3 million, so fairly small increases, however, bigger in deposits.</p>
          <p>In terms of the spread or the margin, the spread in terms of deposit is clearly down and we've seen interest rate decreases on most markets. And here it's actually quite a big number. The impact on deposits is actually quite big in the quarter and there are couple of reasons for it. First of all, of course, as we see falling interest rates, we lose on the transaction accounts. This effect you are very much aware of. But also on these very low levels, our ability to actually lower interest rates on the savings accounts is simply not that big. So what you see here is, we actually &#x2013; we cannot &#x2013; never go below zero in the savings accounts. So that's why it is a fairly big number in terms of the deposits and that, of course, as we go forward will even out.</p>
          <p>Then we have some minor impacts on GCC and on the other, so total impact is EUR7 million and the other is basically just the day count impact of EUR50 million. So you can say this largely is the story. Little bit positive contribution on volume to a large degree compensating increases in lending margin, compensating the losses on the deposit income side.</p>
          <p>Just to highlight one thing that we have made a change. You &#x2013; I have actually exposed this to you many times before, the work we have done in distributing all of the funding cost that we've had for the group to all the different business units. The purpose of this project is, of course, as we have talked about before is to have the true costs out in the business to all the customer interfacing units, to all the business areas and, of course, all the SRMs et cetera.</p>
          <p>And we want to make sure that all our employees are able to see the full profitability and the full true cost when they do their business, and also to understand the product and the customer profitability. So the principles of this, we calculated at the contract level, so for each transaction, it reflects the characteristics. And here, of course, maturity is the main parameter that plays &#x2013; that come into play. And we are based it &#x2013; basing it on our own funding curve, so rather funding curve, so of course, a mortgage product or a mortgage loan for instance would be funded differently than a corporate loan.</p>
          <p>The status of this is that we have now developed the model in full. We are piloting as we speak in all four countries, and we will gradually make refinance to this model and implement it fully as of 1st of January 2013. But you can already see this quarter that we now have distributed all the funding costs to the business areas, and you will find that for now in business areas other. So it's not distributed all the way down to the countries or the individual business units yet in the external reporting, but as we go forward and particularly so from next year, you will see that distributed all the way.</p>
          <p>So this is just &#x2013; just the highlights on where we are and to give you an indication how much this is, the total funding cost for retail is approximately EUR90 million in the quarter. It's about EUR55 million or so for wholesale and it's approximately EUR7 million or so for other business lines, whilst &#x2013; or EUR7 million and wealth management is actually positive by EUR7 million, so that gives you a distribution of the approximate amount we're talking about.</p>
          <p>Those words leading to you, Ari.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. So then just a few words about the credit quality. Before I show any slides, of course, the Q1 losses were very much according to our own expectations, which, of course, is a good starting point, so that what we believe there also happens. So that still, yes, we have these two places, with a little bit higher retention and that concerns Denmark and shipping, but also in those areas the losses were not up in Q1. They were not down either so much, so that's still, of course, problems are not over yet, but they are not anymore trending up so fast. And then in other parts of the portfolio, the situation continue to be very stable. But then highlighting a few issues, you may ask, one is this, our increased impaired loans. You may wonder that what has happened because the situation is stable, quality is solid, but impaired loans are up.</p>
          <p>There's no drama in this increase. The increase in the amount of euros is roughly EUR500 million. It comes from two places. EUR3 million comes from shipping. Actually there is a less than handful of these kind of new customers in shipping, which we impaired. We booked very small loan loss provisions, but as you know that when we book a loan loss provision for the performing loan, that it impairs the whole portfolio or, let's say, exposure for that customer group. So that explains the EUR300 million of the increase. The remaining EUR200 million comes from Denmark. There were also in Denmark some, let's say, few medium-sized corporate customers, new problem customers, where we impaired the loan and made a loan loss provision.</p>
          <p>But then actually that means also that our &#x2013; this kind of provisioning ratio allowances from impaired loans, that is now coming down, it's at the group level of 46%. That is fully explained by this, what happened in shipping. These few individual new cases with the low provisions, the provisioning ratio of these new cases was less than 10%, then that means that, that has this double impact at the group level.</p>
          <p>Then in these countries, as I said, the situation is relatively stable in all Nordic portfolios, very low numbers in Norway, Finland, and Sweden, stable in Denmark. These also &#x2013; these impaired loans development in the Nordic portfolios, so that the only increase is this EUR200 million in Denmark. You can also see from the slide that actually we have made this kind of harmonized definition of our impaired loans between Nordic countries and we have restated the figures as from first quarter last year, because we used a little bit different definitions for impaired loans due to local regulations, but now we have harmonized them and made a restatement.</p>
          <p>As you can see, it doesn't impact on this kind of development in the countries, but then it changes the absolute level between countries. So it was up in Denmark and down in Finland, and a little bit up in Sweden.</p>
          <p>And then this Danish loan losses, EUR118 in Q1, that is split to household and corporate as you see in the slide, so that household losses were now down in Denmark, which is a very good signal at least according to my under &#x2013; my mind. And then as I said, there are a few medium-sized corporate customers where we made loan loss provision that took up to the corporate side. But household situation is showing some positive signals in Denmark in our portfolio.</p>
          <p>Then finally, the shipping respective figures so that the losses are still high, roughly EUR60 million in Q1. That is in a way you can divide that EUR60 million in three components. One is this what I already mentioned, this few individual new cases with small provision that's explaining one-third of this EUR60 million. Then we have old cases, which have become worse. We have, yeah, let's say, increased our provision due to falling collateral values plus, let's say, falling expectations of those customers' cash flows. And then finally, we made a smallish collective provision also in the shipping book in Q1. And I already mentioned this explanation of this EUR300 million increase in impaired loss.</p>
          <p>So yes, that was the last slide.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. So with this, we open up for questions. We start with Andreas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. First question on the shipping NPLs with impaired loans, I think we have some 68% Q1 over Q4. And your coverage ratio I think was 41% in Q3, down to 31% in Q4 and now 26%. How low are you really willing to go in this area? And aren't you making yourself very vulnerable to drops in the collateral values by being this far down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now as I said, we have talked this in previous quarters also that in shipping it's this kind of case-by-case type of, let's say, provisioning needs and our policy. We do always this kind of case-based assessment from our, let's say, best knowledge an assessment that what is the need &#x2013; needed level of loan losses. And in shipping, there are lots of these type of customers where we have a more or less 100% or over 100% collateral coverage.</p>
          <p>And then again, we may impair and, of course, there's a need to impair also those type of loss. Then we make this type of haircuts to the values of collaterals and then we make <mark type="indiscernible" /> (49:18) needed loan loss provision. And as I said that in Q1, there were very few &#x2013; let's say, two, three new customers with very high collateral coverage. But then again, we made this kind of prudent assessment of the value of collaterals, and then it gave this, let's say, 10% provision ratio over this new impaired loan customers, and that <mark type="indiscernible" /> (49:43) of course then to average provision ratios as you indicated.</p>
          <p>Of course, yes, you may say that then you are exposed to this kind of collateral values, but &#x2013; and then, that is also what has happened in our book. I mentioned that in Q4 and now I mention that also now in Q1 so that there is &#x2013; every quarter we make assessment &#x2013; this kind of cautious assessment of the collateral values. If the market is down, then we take those down. But this already includes this kind of quite big haircuts when we do the first provision.</p>
          <p>That is the name of the game, that the shipping business is collateralized financing, and when the customer is in problem, so it very much depends on the value of collaterals and what is the needed provisioning ratio. And because there are so limited number of these problem customers, then actually this provisioning ratio in the shipping book average provision ratio, they are not very good indicators because you have to know the specific customers. There may be a customer with 100% of provisioning ratio, and then actually it turns &#x2013; these average ratios offset down in one quarter.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just to follow up, it sounds like you're about to become one of the largest owners or one of the largest tanker companies in the world. Could you tell us what's the status there and how you're going to account for that and how you're going to <mark type="indiscernible" /> (51:08) equities or what's happening?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If and when you are pointing to this public case, which was &#x2013; there was public information yesterday. That happens from time to time, it's not the first one we have taken over. So, that <mark type="indiscernible" /> (51:26) cases, there are cases that the lenders has to take the full control and then, let's say, because the risk is on the financial side and then in a way see that how that &#x2013; value of that asset will be maximized. And if there's a upside, then the bank is other ones who are getting this upside.</p>
          <p>So that is not any kind of, let's say, so exceptional the way it was dealt. We have taken all the impacts in our P&amp;L in the previous quarters and also in this quarter based on this transaction and then, of course, it remains to be seen what is the future. But, of course, there's a belief that when we take this control and then want that business to continue, we believe that there may be alternative to create even value in the longer term. But our purpose is not to become a fleet owner as such <mark type="indiscernible" /> (52:23) to safeguard our assets, temporary actions.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Magnus and then Thomas.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I just wanted to follow up on the roll out progress here in &#x2013; with regards to risk weighted assets, if you could update us on when you expect approval for advanced IRB in the corporate portfolio, foundation IRB for the Baltics and the IMM approval for counterparty credit risk? And also, if you could give us some indications of the impact on risk weighted assets on each approval?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I start, you can contemplate, Fredrik. To us, it's very difficult to give you because that's up to regulators, FSAs, to give you, let's say grant that approval. So that earlier we have said that perhaps we are expecting that in the second half of this year that it was the corporate IRB approval. That is still, of course, our expectation and wish, but remains to be seen. We don't know so simply, we sent in the application a year ago in the first quarter last year, and now it's been in for one year. And now then we are expecting to have the decision approval in the second half. But we can't confirm that we will get the approval.</p>
          <p>Baltic IRB, that should be also during this year. Clearly, we are a little bit, let's say &#x2013; I don't give any quarter, but it should be this year. The impact of that is quite insignificant, so that's more or less just improving the quality how we measure the Baltic portfolio. Little bit slightly positive in <mark type="indiscernible" /> (54:18) however.</p>
          <p>Then this IMM, we are sending in the application actually during next week, and then we wish to have it during this year. That is, of course, the aim because then the new regulation comes in the first quarter next year and then, of course, that's our aim.</p>
          <p>These combined effects, what we have said even earlier is that in a way what is coming, these kind of increases because of the <mark type="ph" /> ROEs, (54:50) because of new regulation will be more or less compensated by this, let's say, new model impacts, and that is still the estimation we can repeat more or less. But, would you like to add up to...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, I don't have anything to add really because we don't have any new information yet as it relates to the advanced IRB. We will know a little bit more as we progress now towards the next five or six weeks, we can probably make a better estimate. But for the time being, we have no better estimate than we actually had in October.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And maybe just to repeat, in October <mark type="indiscernible" /> (55:28) we said EUR16 billion to EUR20 billion combined effects. And now we have seen the international branches <mark type="ph" /> over roughly EUR3 billion (55:33). Thomas?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, Thomas Johansson from Carnegie. Can you please discuss a little bit about front-book versus back-book margins across different segments areas? I mean, how much room is there for further margin increases in the system?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I can do that, elaborate a little bit on it because I think it's always difficult to forecast margins as we have seen from past. But generally, you saw this slide before on mortgage margins and how they have developed, including the full funding cost. So by just by looking at that slide, you can see that we're slightly up in Q4. So front-book margins are a little bit higher now than back-book, but really not anything dramatic as you saw there on that slide.</p>
          <p>I think for the retail or not retail, but for the corporate book, it's now a little higher. It is higher than it has been, and, of course, we have compensated, as you have seen, in terms of the net interest income. So front-book is a little better than the back-book. Our ambition is, of course, on the back of much, much higher capital levels and the higher liquidity levels to continue, and we're still of the opinion that margins should continue to increase. It's always competitive situation. So whether that will happen or not is, of course, it's difficult to estimate, but we're striving to get there, Thomas, so we'll simply have to report. I think we have discussed, on the mortgage side, there's been a lot of discussion as to risk weights, for instance, will that have an impact, will that change, and that could potentially push margins higher as capital &#x2013; higher capital or more capital will be needed for those products. But generally, it's been a good margin development, we think, to some degree at least, or largely compensating for the deposit margin, and hopefully that will continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>But during last year we saw quite a sharp sequential increase in front-book margins throughout the year. And Q1 is quite clear from most of the banks that front-book margins are stabilized. Why is that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, but again, you can say margins, the way you measure margins and then the way we have presented it previously has been against STIBOR or LIBOR, or whatever reference rate we are talking about. But if you actually compare it to the funding cost, it is not dramatic. So, if you look at the history on corporate margins since 2007, similar to what you saw here in the mortgage margins, they are up, and that increase largely took place in 2009. And since then, it hasn't actually been relatively stable, so you can say margins in the NII perspective has not increased that much. But front-book margins have now stabilized and, of course, it's only &#x2013; you can say it's only natural that, that is actually happening. We will continue to try and increase. If you look at it against the reference rate, then it was a sharp increase, then it was a sharp increase, and of course, the funding cost has now really started to decrease again, and that's also why you can see a stabilization of the margins versus the reference rate. So hopefully, we will see margins continuing to increase, but it's, of course, depending on the competitive situation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I have another question on a completely separate issue. I see your derivatives book have decreased quite sharply in the quarter, is that what &#x2013; if that's the function of client demand or intentional Nordea managing it down?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, no. No, the largest, you can say, the impact on the derivatives book is largely due to two things. The first one is the interest rate movements and, of course, how &#x2013; it's just a discount and so we'll increase on both sides of the balance sheet. That's one of the things. And the other thing is <mark type="ph" /> credit (59:22) cost. So interest rates on the interest rate derivatives is would &#x2013; actually would have an impact on the balance sheet as such. So the more the interest rates are falling, the bigger the balance sheet typically, or you can have other impacts on FX, for instance.</p>
          <p>So these are &#x2013; or the volume side of things is largely the same. And you also saw the profit we have generated in terms of the customer business on the markets &#x2013; or risk management products, and it's very, very similar to what it was in the previous quarter. So this is no drama at all. It's just a correlation of the interest rate movements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Masih? Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, just the improved lending margins, EUR78 million there. Can you say how much of that, that was due to Norwegian mortgage margins?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Fairly good develop &#x2013; the &#x2013; if you look at the mortgage margins in the quarter, the best country, if you put it in terms of increases margin-wise, was Norway. The second one was Denmark. Third one was Finland and fourth, Sweden. So the increase was slowest, you can say, in Sweden. So Norway has a reasonable part. Now, we're not that big in Norway and especially not on the mortgage side, so it doesn't really have a big impact on the numbers that you saw in terms of absolute euros. But the margin increases was largest in Norway.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Just a follow-up on shipping. You were saying in your presentation in February, your shipping presentation, that your front-book margins are much higher than your back-book margins. But in this quarter, you actually see that NII from shipping is falling, what is that due to?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>That is not because of the lending margins. They are still, let's say, upward, but it's because of deposit margins so that &#x2013; and deposits volumes also little bit. So in the shipping still actually we are able to underwrite new transactions and then refinance with quite much higher lending margins than we have in the back-book, because there are a few players as a we all know. And, of course, there is a risk included; risk in shipping has gone up so that price of risk is now higher in being in the shipping business.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jan Wolter?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, Jan Wolter, Deutsche Bank. So when we look at the short rate sensitivity just Q-on-Q, a detailed question perhaps, but still negative minus 69 or something Q-on-Q. And that seems to be a bit higher than what we've seen previously. What is the interest rate sensitivity now for, say, a 100 bp cut in all your countries? And why was it fairly big given the short rate fall in the quarter? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Again, you &#x2013; we have discussed this many times before, Jan, that it is approximately EUR550 million. It depends on the distribution, of course, but roughly EUR550 million. So it's not really anything different in the structure of the bank. We have still approximately the same distribution in terms of transaction and savings accounts, et cetera. So it remains the same. But it is a large number, it is a large number and, of course, you can say that the further down &#x2013; and I tried to explain that before, the further down you go in interest rate, the further you actually have or the bigger the increase is, and this has to do with the savings account. So the transaction accounts are behaving exactly as we have estimated and that's the larger part of this. It's a little bit &#x2013; approximately 60%. But it's surprisingly higher, not surprisingly, but it's high on the savings side. And that has to do with the fact that we cannot actually lower interest rates more than zero in some cases where interest rates are very low.</p>
          <p>And the other thing is that there is actually fierce competition for deposits. I think interest rates are very key. The deposit funding is a key feature for a lot of banks, so we see that in particular in Finland, there's a lot of very fierce competition. So this is not only a sort of a sensitivity issue, it is also relating to the issue of being so low in the interest rates and the fierce competition. So all those three makes this a fairly high number.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, and just a follow-up question there. I think you've mentioned somewhere in the presentation like you've changed your composition of the liquidity buffer. Has that had &#x2013; what kind of change is that and has that had any material impact on the NII levels?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No, we &#x2013; no. It doesn't have a material impact, but what we did, as you will recall, from the Q4, we had a lot of deposits over year-end with the Fed and ECB. So, we have reduced that a little bit. It was just in anticipation of turbulence over year-end and all sorts of things. So we had a very, very high &#x2013; so in terms of just &#x2013; it was discussed before, the LCR, we were way, way above 100% LCR compliant on Q4. We're still LCR compliant also in this quarter, but we've taken that down. So largely, you can say we are still about the same level and it was a fairly short period in late &#x2013; late part of last year that we had those deposits.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>You can just put numbers on what Fredrik said earlier on the net interest income sensitivity. If you just look at the sensitivity effect, it was roughly EUR45 million, EUR48 million in this quarter, and the rest are from the other factors that Fred discussed. Any more questions? <mark type="ph" /> John (1:05:26), please?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>If you please could comment the Finnish operations and the NII, and also the possibility to increase the margins in the Finnish mortgage market <mark type="indiscernible" /> (1:05:39) a substantial NNI drop in your Finnish operations, if you could please comment on that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, I can do that, but I think it's fair to say we start in the NII, and the reason why there is a drop has to do with deposits and not lending. So, of course, if you look at the transaction accounts in particular for the bank, there is a fairly strong portion of that located in Finland, approximately about 40% is in the Finnish entity. So the interest rate sensitivity is bigger in Finland at the start. So, lending margin is in most sectors of the bank higher in Q1 than it was in Q4. So this is a deposit issue.</p>
          <p>Then generally, on a more general, no, we did increase also mortgage margins in the quarter, so not with &#x2013; as I said before, that was the third country so to speak on the ranking in terms of increases. So it was less than Denmark and Norway, but still up. Generally, and we've seen that from the past, it is little bit more difficult to increase margins, it's just a slower movement in the Finnish market, but of course, as in the other countries we have seen a positive trend on lending margins, and hopefully that will continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Again, just the &#x2013; in the Finnish mortgage market, I'd say competition. So it's &#x2013; the market is very price sensitive. Even now we saw in Q1 that when we started to increase the mortgage margins, our market share simultaneously started to drop. We are not saying that we should not continue this trend increasing margins and then suffering in the market share. But it is exactly what has happened every time then in the Finnish market. Some bank has started to increase prices, it's very price sensitive market, especially in the mortgage side. It's a little bit different compared...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And deposits, I guess.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And deposits, that goes as well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And one more question regarding your staff cost in wholesale banking, could you please comment, that is up significantly quarter-on-quarter and also if you compare it with quarter one 2011?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, it &#x2013; yeah, first of all, it's always difficult to compare quarter-on-quarter, but the general &#x2013; the short answer is that we have higher variable cost this year, so we had a good quarter in terms of the markets development and that triggers variable. So the underlying efficiency gain in wholesale is pretty flat, so it's actually not deviating that much. Retail is lower on cost, staff cost than wholesale, but still very much in line with plans. But the effect you're talking about has to do with variable cost or variable pay.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Do we have any more questions from the audience?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, so this concludes this webcasting and analyst meeting. You're most welcome at the telephone conference also this afternoon at 3:30 CET. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>