<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1509355" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call - International Q &amp; A</title>
    <date>2012-10-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9506</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Investor Relations">Rodney Alfv&#xE9;n</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Group Chief Executive Officer">Christian Clausen</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="corprep" affiliation="Chief Financial Officer &amp; Executive Vice President">Fredrik Rystedt</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="corprep" affiliation="Executive Vice President &amp; Chief Risk Officer">Ari Kaperi</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Keefe, Bruyette &amp; Woods Ltd.">Ronny Rehn</participant>
      <participant id="6" type="analyst" affiliation="JPMorgan Securities Plc">Sofie C. Peterzens</participant>
      <participant id="7" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane BNP Paribas SA (Sweden)">Andreas H&#xE5;kansson</participant>
      <participant id="8" type="analyst" affiliation="Soci&#xE9;t&#xE9; G&#xE9;n&#xE9;rale SA (UK)">Geoff V. Dawes</participant>
      <participant id="9" type="analyst" affiliation="UBS Ltd. (Broker)">Nick A. Davey</participant>
      <participant id="10" type="analyst" affiliation="RBC Europe Ltd. (Broker)">Claire Kane</participant>
      <participant id="11" type="analyst" affiliation="Mediobanca Banca di Credit Finanziario SpA (Broker)">Riccardo Rovere</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good day and welcome to the Nordea Third Quarter Report 2012 International Teleconference. Today's conference is being recorded.</p>
          <p>At this time, I would like to turn the conference over to Mr. Rodney Alfv&#xE9;n. Please go ahead sir.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, operator. Welcome to this telecom conference where we would present our third quarter numbers. We will start with the presentation by Mr. Christian Clausen, the President and Group CEO; Fredrik Rystedt, Group CFO; and Ari Kaperi, Group COO. And then we'll open up the floor for questions and answers. So Christian, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I will shortly give some highlights and key messages, and the key messages that we deliver on our New Normal plan on cost, capital and income. And you can say we are delivering a Q3 which is very much in line with our expectations slightly lower than Q2, clearly better than Q3 last year and the first three quarters combined. It's clearly better. And previously, actually it's the record.</p>
          <p>So, everything is moving in the right direction, I would say. It's very important that we keep costs unchanged. During this year, we have done that for seven quarters now, and we'll keep doing that excluding FX effects.</p>
          <p>We have a cost income ratio, which is down. We have an improved return on equity. We have improved our core tier 1 because we have good control over our risk-weighted assets and it became more efficient. Loan losses are slightly higher. I'm sure we're going to have a lot of questions on that. But the main reason is, of course, that we have these new rules in Denmark, which have made some more provisions necessary especially general provisions. The underlying credit quality is improving and looks good and the individualized provisions are also down.</p>
          <p>So as I said, income in Q3 highest ever, year-to-date profit up 14% and very much important we have good business momentum. We attract new customers and we work very closely with these customers. Also we have good progress in building the future bank business model not only on cost, capital and income. The retail banking area is very much developing the distribution model. A lot of efficiencies taken out, but also a lot of value added is delivering very much. The big move towards the mobile banking, which we have, is very important. I will come a bit back to that.</p>
          <p>Also efficiency wholesale banking very much developing relationships and adding on a lot of fee income and the value-added solutions. We're clearly the leading book runner both on syndicated loans and bond issuance in the Nordic area, which is of course a very important service and which also makes it possible to make the long-term financing of our corporate customers still on the capital market. Then on wealth management, we see very good results with increased efficiency and a much sharper offerings and also getting more capital efficiency.</p>
          <p>And I will turn over to Fredrik.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Christian. As you can see from slide eight, we've had a good start to the year. The first nine months have been good with income up by 10%, cost down by 2% and operating profit up by 24%. Also the quarter is reasonably good in light of the fact that it's a seasonally lower activity level in Q3 versus Q2. And we have also been affected by accounting issues relating to our structured bond issuance and I'll come back to that issue. But generally a strong result in the first quarter.</p>
          <p>Let me just give you a couple of highlights on the individual lines, starting with net interest income. Generally, the quarter was fairly slow in terms of demand and especially so on the corporate side. And as you can see on slide nine, we've had fairly little impact from volumes in more general terms in NII, so from lending in fact slightly down and compensated by a volume growth in deposits and primarily on the corporate side.</p>
          <p>We have compensated for three consecutive quarters the decline in the deposit income through repricing of our lending book and we have continued to do so, however, not at the same pace in this quarter. So as you can see we have a continued margin pickup in lending in more general terms, but slightly less than the deposit income loss that we've had from lower interest rate this quarter. In fact, we continued to do recently well at high levels, as we had both in Q2 and also now in Q3.</p>
          <p>But just go a little deeper into the volumes and margins, you can on the following slides, you can see the lending development for the retail banks the different Nordic countries and CIB and shipping. As you can see we have more or less in total a flat development in the core retail bank. A decline in CIB and a slight decline also in shipping, but it's worth actually noting that we have increased a lot and done a lot of issuance or helping our customers with a lot of issuance of Eurobonds and syndicated loans.</p>
          <p>So to a large degree, this decline in lending on the balance sheet has been compensated by strong issuance, which is of course for the customers a good solution and it's also in the context of capital consumption and probability also good for the bank. So generally good service to the customers. If you look at the margin side, you can see the household margins have been largely flat, a little varying over the different country and the corporate margins generally slightly up.</p>
          <p>Looking at deposits, a very similar picture, but a really strong performance in CIB. And as we have seen before flight to quality element is clearly in that picture. So you can see a very significant increase of deposits in CIB is 11% as you can see on that slide nine. Looking at the margins, we're largely affected on the household side and as before not that much on the corporate side. So margins are generally down on deposits on the back of lower interest rate.</p>
          <p>We're quite pleased with the developments of net commission income. It's down 1% quarter-on-quarter, which is typically a little lower than what is normally indicated in the seasonality of Q3 and Q2. We have an increased asset management. We're up to &#x20AC;211 billion now in assets under management and that's a result of good performance and it's also a result of continued strong inflow. Slight seasonal decline in commissions on payment, cards and custody.</p>
          <p>I touched upon the fair value before and the structured bonds. We have approximately $6 billion outstanding in structured bonds and contrary to all the outstanding liabilities of the group is that we normally do with amortized costs, the structured bond issuance is done at mark-to-market. So over the maturity profile of these bonds, we will create volatility of the P&amp;L, that's not really real because in the end, we keep it to maturities, so the fluctuations will only affect in terms of accounting.</p>
          <p>This quarter we've had a negative impact of minus 50% in the first quarter or in the second quarter we had plus 50%, so the net swing is $100 million. And if you adjust for that, as you can see, the activity level in net fair value was roughly at the same level as we had also in Q2. So a continued good performance in net fair value and customer business is holding up.</p>
          <p>One of the strong points of Nordea is, of course, the funding access and funding transitions and we have issued &#x20AC;26 billion up to date, or &#x20AC;25 billion in the first three quarters of the year, out of which a majority is senior unsecured funding and the rest is largely covered bonds.</p>
          <p>As you can see on slide 12, we have done approximately &#x20AC;10 billion or &#x20AC;11 billion more than the redemption we have for 2012. So this continues to be good and the funding spread, the funding conditions in more general terms, as well as the access continues to be really good. And you can see that on the slide 12 that we are trading favorably or in comparison to also major countries very, very good condition.</p>
          <p>Strong capital generation continues. We have had growth rates of 9% over the last several years since 2006 and we have nearly doubled the amount of capital in the last five and a half years. So that continues to be very strong. And in addition we have also maintained a very strict control of the risk-weighted assets that you can see on slide 14.</p>
          <p>So this quarter on the back of a little lower growth and a little lower market risk, we have actually decreased the risk-weighted assets by &#x20AC;2 billion. And we continue all the efforts within New Normal relating to capital efficiency and, of course, that's also something that has been beneficial to that rate. And all in all if you sum that up, our core tier 1 ratio just in line with our planning is continuing to strengthen and reaching 12.2% at the end of the quarter.</p>
          <p>And with these words, I'd like to leave over to Ari.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. And the credit loss picture is quite familiar to you so that we still have elevated loan loss levels in shipping and in Denmark whereas in other parts of the loan portfolio the loss is at moderate level.</p>
          <p>And then the basis &#x2013; the level of loan losses in terms of basis points, we have to remember that we are still quite close to our long-term average, where we are estimated to be. And what Christian already said in his opening remarks was that it's important to realize and observe that now our individually assessed loan loss provisions actually they were down now in Q3 compared to the previous quarter. We are now to the moving collective provisions what's different so that we increase the collective provisions whereas in Q2 we made a relatively big release. I'm coming back to that.</p>
          <p>On the following page, you see this split to the geographical areas in Nordic countries. As you can see, in Denmark, still we are at the high level and that was up from previous quarter. In the following page, I will a little bit more elaborate on that. Still the reason for these losses in Denmark is household and agriculture customers in large extent, not so much on the corporate side.</p>
          <p>And then when we go to the page 18, then our metrics have been in previous quarters and that feel the same these quarters that we see signs of stabilization in Denmark. And as you can see, the house prices have been relatively stable now in the last quarter, since they have come down from the peak by some 20 percentage points but now they have been relatively flat with some slight over quarterly volatility.</p>
          <p>Number of forced sales, which is an important driver, has been stable and also the number of bankruptcies with these, of course, explaining more than what is happening in the corporate side that has come down slightly now with some kind of volatility.</p>
          <p>What is important for us in this page is the bottom right-hand side where we decomposed this loan loss level in Denmark within net terms was up. But then as you can see that what happened in Denmark was that the individually assessed loan loss provisions, the blue bar, that was actually quite down from the previous quarter. And that has been at the stable level now for one and a half years more or less. What was now the change we made in Q3, in Denmark in terms of provisions was that now we started to build up collective provisions.</p>
          <p>Whereas in Q2, as you can see, there was a quite high release of collective provisions. With this release in Q2, we had simply mitigated the impact of these new rules, one of the impact the new rules. We saw also in Q3 this kind of tail of this new rule impact. I mentioned some numbers in Q2 to the impact of the new rules was roughly &#x20AC;80 million whereas this quarter the impact was some &#x20AC;45 million to &#x20AC;50 million. The way we see that the impact being the next quarters will be definitely declining impact, so that still we have had some tail on this new rule implementation impact in Q3. But as you can see, it's an important rule because the underlying quality is still relatively stable.</p>
          <p>Going through shipping, here in this quarter, we are a little bit low on loan losses. Actually, we didn't have any new loan loss customer in shipping in Q3. The reasons for this level of loan losses was partly our increased collective provisions also in the shipping portfolio, and then partly in the increased provisions we made for existing old problem customers where the asset values were down. And also the net impaired loans in shipping in this quarter, they were somewhat down because the exposures we have through existing impaired loans, we were able to take those somewhat down.</p>
          <p>Over the next page, we see some or we show some market factors from shipping. On the right-hand side, you see that now we start to see a long-term stable level of shipping order book, which should be more or less between 15% and 20%. Of course, it doesn't mean that standard problems are over. We have to still adjust and adopt for this overcapacity, but now with the levels are decent.</p>
          <p>Then on the left-hand side, you can just simply see that why we have been forced to increase our provision for existing program customers' asset values, they have still come down in 2011 and 2012. But also there, we start to see some gradual signs of stabilization.</p>
          <p>In the next page, we include the impaired loans which were also up in this quarter and also the information is the same as we have had in the previous quarters. It was this development in Denmark mainly reflecting the impact of new Danish provisioning rules whereas you see that the development in other areas was stable and has been stable throughout the year.</p>
          <p>And then lastly on page 22, we just simply show that what is our provision ratios along with provision ratios in different portfolios and as you can see we have quite highly collateralized portfolios. Shipping provision ratios is 35%, agriculture is 30% and real estate is 36%, which by definitions are highly collateralized loan books.</p>
          <p>And of course, when we have had this kind of biggest increases in debt loans in this highly collateralized loan loss &#x2013; highly collateralized portfolios, that is in a way positive in terms of loan loss is because than actually demand a loan or seat is reflecting this highly collateralized levels whereas as you can see, at this part of the portfolio, mostly corporate portfolio, that the lowest line, other industries, where the provision ratio is 51%. But we don't have some good collateral will be relatively stable also indicating that the portfolio quality is very good.</p>
          <p>With these words, I'll turn back to Christian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I will give a few comments on the way we build the future bank business model. When we say that we change everything in the group, every process and products in New Normal is not really true because we keep the basics of all our strategy and values relationship strategy. And we have worked with this now for five or six years and it's really been a fantastic strategy in the good times, middle of the crisis and we actually believe it's even better now in the New Normal.</p>
          <p>So it is all about building relationships strategy and that's the only thing we do. We service on relationship customers, the upper segments and household and the corporate and we felt close relationship. And I would jump straight to page 26 where just the reason about why this is so important as a strategic notes. I know a lot of people have told me about it but doing it is not exactly the same thing where it really something happens.</p>
          <p>It is about knowing the customer, advising the customer, serving the customer and committing to the customer. And this is creating a lot of benefits for the customers. So we actually create the most loyal customers you can ever imagine. When we measure that they are super loyal, they are satisfied, they trust in the bank, they get full advice and they just use the bank for everything they know. And for the bank this is propriety because we can service on the right customers, customers are right which profile and their right need. The segmentation gets easy.</p>
          <p>We can identify solutions the right way and we can tailor make solutions in a way that we use as little capital as possible so we can be much more capital efficient. Of course, we get cost efficient because the customer has all his products with us so cost to serve is, of course, low and then we get this huge diversification benefit, which of course right now is seen very clearly.</p>
          <p>We get some losses in some segments where we have no losses in other segments, so in all the figures are good and we get really close connection to the customers. So we see the risks before they even emerge as soon as cash flow starts to dry out. So all in all, a fantastic strategy which we felt on our activities.</p>
          <p>Just a few comments on the customer side, I think it's important to note that during this quarter we actually developed on the household customer quite significantly, our distribution strategy. We refilled all the branches, advice branches and service branches. We have taken out a significant cost. We have developed very significantly our mobile applications and we have now 7,000 mobile active users, who go to the bank every second day on the mobile bank. That's of course a huge advantage. They get advice. They get offerings. They get information and they do it with their fingers instead of feet. Of course, this is a huge driver. We also do a lot of basically meetings, but that's advisory meetings when we do business and the customer has a need.</p>
          <p>And on the corporate side, it's worth mentioning this thing about the strategy that we very much want to help them on to the capital market for their long-term needs. It's clear that we do all the financing for the customers, the short-term financing, the working capital, the customer financing, trade financing. All the things we do on a daily basis, we still do of course on the balance sheet.\</p>
          <p>This long-term financing we like to do on the capital market, it gives a much better return profile. And we have the advantage here being the clear leader. We are by far the biggest corporate bank in the Nordea area and we have a substantial situation here as the number one book runner in a number of areas.</p>
          <p>Also it's worth mentioning as already been highlighted, but the New Normal does deliver cost efficiency. We have taken out continuous cost. We've done now that for seven quarters and we will continue to do it going forward. And this will keep costs flat, and we will reduce number of FTEs. This is not only retail. Of course, it's all over. It's about being more efficient in all our processes. So it's not really a cost cutting program. It's much more an efficiency program, which create a very lean bank and as we see from the key figures, we are cutting cost to income ratios which really compete with best-in-class.</p>
          <p>And on the RWAs, we've become more efficient on our optimization programs which are indeed decreasing risk by getting more collateral, better covenants, by doing a number of things that actually put together a portfolio that has less risk. And that, combined with the improved credit quality means that we've been able to keep our risk-weighted assets in check and thereby also driving up our capital.</p>
          <p>So all in all, I think it's clear after this fantastic presentation that our Q3 numbers are actually very good and we are right on track in delivering a New Normal plan and building the business model of the future bank. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Christian. And with that, we open up for questions and answers. Operator, please open up the phone line.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> We will now take our first question from Ronny Rehn of KBW. Your line is open, sir. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon. Thanks for taking the time for the call. A few questions, first on the trading income deferral you gained but I think last quarter this hadn't been pointed out. So I just wanted to see whether you could give us a bit more history from previous quarters, what deferral your gains or losses were.</p>
          <p>The second question would be on asset quality and particularly for shipping. DnB guided towards higher losses next year in their shipping book. Is that an opinion you share from your current point of view? And then lastly, quickly on the Liikanen report, in the Nordic peer group, you kind of stand out in terms of the trading share of assets. I just wanted to get your views after you had probably a bit more time to read through the report. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Maybe I can start with the fair value. I'm not 100% sure I understand your question in full. But you can see on slide 11 in the presentation, of course, the history of fair value, it consists of basically three different things. First of all it includes &#x2013; we could say four different things. First of all it consists of the customer trading we do or customer flows and this is risk management products that we provide our customers with and typically hedging of various kinds, interest rates the dominant part and of course also currency hedging. This amounts to a little bit over &#x20AC;200 million roughly and it has been very stable over the last several quarters actually over the last several years. So it's a very stable part of the net fair value.</p>
          <p>Then the next part which is quite small is the inherent, you can say, hedging of these risks they come from the custom flow. That's a small part in rough terms about maybe &#x2013; roughly about &#x20AC;40 million or so in average then the third component is life. We have there which is life and treasury being the third and fourth component and treasury is typically a quite small piece of that. So if you look at what is varying, customer flows fairly stable. So is life. It's reasonably stable over time. Treasury varying a little bit depending on the trading environment in more general terms and, of course, the hedging activities from customer flows also varying. So that's typically.</p>
          <p>Now, if I just take this quarter and the structured bond, we typically do, as I said, all the issuance at amortized cost but when we issue structured bonds, we have fluctuations in that portfolio. And it has, due to very significant movements in credit spreads this year, it has been very, very volatile and that creates some volatility in the second quarter of plus &#x20AC;50 million integrated volatility, in the third quarter minus &#x20AC;50 million. Typically, that volatility should not be that great but as you know, the funding spreads have contracted quite significantly during the third quarter and that's where that volatility comes from.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>I understand the background of it. I just wanted &#x2013; I mean the disclosure is fairly new. In this quarter, you say high customer demand and negative impact from fair value, in the last quarter presentation, you only talk about the customer demand and the &#x20AC;50 million positive back then. I didn't have at least in my memory and just want to see whether there was previous quarters where it had any significant impact, just to see the underlying numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The different between in the customer result, you can say, is approximately &#x20AC;6 million, so it is typically for the season a little lower demand in more general terms the risk management product. But as you can see, it was &#x20AC;6 million out of a bit over &#x20AC;200 million, so the difference there is quite small. So we still have a good demand.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, cool. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So I take the shipping question. So that what we have said in the previous quarter is what we say also in this quarter, so that we expect that this level of elevated loan losses will remain for the next quarters. But we don't foresee any kind of big risk of increased loan loss levels in shipping so that perhaps one could say that we have been really out. We have been reporting this level of losses already now four quarters so that meaning that, of course, we have already covered for the most retail customers in the past four quarters.</p>
          <p>We still expect that these problems are prevailing and then we are not saying that losses are coming down either. There will be differences between quarters. This quarter, it was a little bit down. It can be up and down in the coming quarters. But roughly speaking, this level is what we expect for the future.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Clear.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. And a few comments on Liikanen, I think we have a report on the table. We don't know exactly what the law or the legislation will be, the directive. After the first information, I think [Pania] has been pretty hesitant whether this will actually result in the directives.</p>
          <p>But if it does and if it comes out the way it looks, even though we don't have any details, then it's not obvious we will be forced to ring-fence but there will be a clear strategic discussion in some of these bigger banks, the 12 banks or so which are big enough whether they will choose to ring-fence or not because we can argue there will be a number of dynamic effects which could suggest that ring-fencing could be a strategic advantage. You could also argue the opposite but that all lies in the details. We, of course, are one of the big banks in Europe. So we will promptly qualify but this strategic position is one that needs to be taken very carefully. And as we don't have the details, we cannot at this stage say whether we will be ring-fenced or not.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Can I ask one question, from the outside or put it this way, many banks have been saying, look, a lot of these trading assets is client business. It's not they have built huge proprietary books. From the outside, it's hard to differentiate. Could you give us a bit of a flavor as to the mix of your trading book? What is client-driven and what is not?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, but we have more or less only client driven. We have more or less no proprietary trading. We have the liquidity problems and not things in treasury, so that's really minimal in terms of risk. So what we really have is our big derivative broker, that is mainly interest rate derivatives, FX rate derivatives, plain vanilla derivatives. And the only reason why they showed up on the balance sheet is that they do it gross. So we have both assets and the liability and typically we have a business with the customer, that's one side of it, and then it's hedged through the market. And the transaction with the market is now going to be collateralized, most of it through the clearing centrals.</p>
          <p>So actually what's remaining on the balance sheet is actually customer exposure. It's the customer counterparty risk which you, of course, take as part of our credit position. So I don't think actually we have any trading assets of any significant nature on our books. We have some bonds and other things we as part of our market being, but they are not significant in this respect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Approximately 3% of the risk-weighted assets in market risk, that's all the reason. Of course, as you alluded to, Christian, that's also driven ultimately from the customer business. It's very, very small.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Excellent. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. We will now take our next question from Sofie Peterzens from JPMorgan. Your line is open, please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, thank you very much for taking my question. Here is Sofie Peterzens from JPMorgan. I just wanted to ask about the Danish asset quality. You have now taken two quarters of higher provisions in Denmark and you were stating that the main reason is the stricter rules. Does this mean that we shouldn't have no more extra provisionings in the quarters to come or do you think this will continue or that we will see higher provisions going forward?</p>
          <p>And then my second question is around your RWAs. Last year, at the Capital Markets Day, you were saying that you see around &#x20AC;16 billion to &#x20AC;20 billion of RWA reductions from model improvements and then I think you said earlier today that you expect RWAs to grow roughly 3% year-on-year. So if you make the calculation, it looks like you have done roughly half of the &#x20AC;16 billion to &#x20AC;20 billion of RWA reductions. Is that correct or how much more RWA reductions should we expect? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I start from the impact of this new Danish rule. So as we have said many times, we see that an underlying risk in Denmark is stable and we don't see the risk being very big that level to pick up. So we still see that this is difficult trade in Denmark will continue and perhaps we see this level of losses also going forward. But then when we are coming to this impact on new rules, yes, there was a big one-off impact in Q2.</p>
          <p>There was some kind of, let's say, tail impact in Q3. I expect that impact to decline in the coming quarters because now definitely we have taken the hit on our existing loan book. And now then what we see in the coming quarters , it's not that what is happening in the new customers which will be in problems. So of course, they are hit by the new rules also. Again, that's pretty insignificant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. When you say new customers, who do you mean by new customers?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>When there is a new customer who has problems then, of course, we will impair that customer and, of course, we will impair that according to the new rules. So then thereby, of course, the impact on new rules will be now one-on-one onwards because now we have only one way to impair customers in Denmark and one way to then assess the [immediate bond rules] but I was more &#x2013; these kind of one-off impact, what was the impact of the change to these new rules, what hit to our existing credit portfolio.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So high impact in the coming quarters.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, the no real impact in the coming quarters?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>No.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The other question you had, first of all just a clarification, the example you said with 3% risk-weighted asset was an illustration of example that we used the conference and we've obviously used it many times before. So it's not a forecast and it's not actually our forecast. It was just an illustration an example what simply happened to the capital base, should replace the assets. For example, increase by that percentage and at the same time we maintain exactly the same kind of profit level. So I was just an illustration, an example so you cannot use that for calculation process. It has no bearing.</p>
          <p>In more general terms, the estimates we did at the Capital Markets Day are largely still valid. We were basing those numbers on estimate as to the impact of primarily advanced IRB and also the implementation of IMM advance for the CVA portfolio. Both of them are still to be implemented.</p>
          <p>We have not got clearance yet from the FSA. We expect that to happen within the next couple of quarters, either one or two quarters. But we still of course expect roughly those numbers that we presented. And you can see that from also the slide presentation that we just showed that we have so far achieved during 2011 and 2012 a bit over &#x20AC;9 billion in efficiency gains out of which a portion of that relates to model implications in international branches et cetera. So that gives you roughly the numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So how much more RWA reduction should we expect going forward?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Approximately &#x20AC;19 billion roughly or &#x20AC;18 billion in that order bank, too.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay great. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, madam. We will now take our next question from Andreas H&#xE5;kansson of Exane BNP Paribas. Your line is open. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Thanks. Just a follow-up from the meeting in Stockholm, I was looking at your loan loss provision charge for this year and when you say that shipping is going to continue to remain at the high level and Denmark is stable at this level. Given that Sweden, Finland and Norway had been at exceptionally low levels, with the slowdown in the macro economy, do you believe that there's any way that loan loses is going to be less next year or should we expect an increase? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We don't give this type of forecast for the exact level of loan losses. But what we can say is, of course, that naturally we are not immune what is happening in the micro environment. So if the macro environment is difficult, then we will see some losses in our loan books. That's clear.</p>
          <p>Of course, one of our strengths is this diversity we have in our loan books so that now it has been difficult times in Denmark and in shipping whereas we also have strong cost. And I'm unsure as when the cycle is different then that may change and we can live that change. If &#x2013; some of the time, there will be higher losses in other parts of the book, I'm sure that then other parts of the book are performing well. So that's the whole issue of this diversified lending book. So that always there will be a strong one, strong books and weaker ones.</p>
          <p>On average, we should nevertheless be on a relatively moderate level within our risk appetite. And that is exactly the picture I see that we are able to also execute on the coming quarters. So that I'm not able to give any kind of precise estimation, but I don't foresee that and we would have a of materially increased loss levels in the future years provided that we are not going to any kind of macro crisis type of scenario, but a little bit different story.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>And just a follow-up, given that your coverage ratio has been falling quite a bit this year, do you see any scope that you will be willing to take that below 40% next year?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>As you see from this one graph, it very much depends at where the root problems are. So that if we see increased problems in this highly collateral portfolios where we do have some full coverage ratio in 2004 then of course we will still go down. But then again, if that's going to be stable and then if that we see increasing in those parts of the portfolio where the coverage ratio is higher, then of course we will see higher provision ratios.</p>
          <p>Perhaps one indication you may take from these Q3 loan losses is that you saw that now we started to increase our collective provisions whereas we have the net decrease in those collective provisions in previous quarters. So then that maybe one indication that we are not going down anymore so much in the provisioning ratios going forward.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. We will now take our next question from Geoff Dawes of Soc G&#xE9;n. Your line is open, sir. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Great, Thank you very much. Geoff Dawes here from Soc G&#xE9;n. Perhaps if I can ask two questions, first of all, a little bit of a follow-up on the last question. Obviously, if you look at the corporate outlook, our sales turned down particularly in the last month of the quarter and perhaps the start of the fourth quarter. Can you talk a little bit not just about the credit quality trends that we touched upon but also the merchant banking and wholesale banking revenue trends and that might impact on the for the next 6 or 12 months.</p>
          <p>And the second question going towards the coverage ratio and I think I'll focus on the shipping book here. In terms of credits that have been worked out or at more advanced stage of workout, has that average 35% coverage ratio proved to be sufficient or have there been makeup provisions once you reach the latter stage of workouts? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I take this corporate &#x2013; both questions, corporate outlook and revenue trends. Of course, we have seen that there is not a big demand on corporate loans now unfortunately, I would say in the Nordic regions, but that doesn't mean that we are not able to, let's say, increase our income. We have, let's say, a very active business relationship with large corporate customers. We are helping them to go to through their debt capital markets and we are, of course, repricing the loan book. We are selling them advisory services, cash management services and so forth and so on.</p>
          <p>So there is no this kind of direct link between the corporate outlook and the economic growth and our income from the corporate client. So that our ambition is still I'm sure that we are able to, let's say, increase our income from the corporate clients because what usually happens in this type of difficult times is that those corporate clients, they are coming more and more with a few house banks which they rely on, and then also some international players are disappearing from the market, which is also happening this time.</p>
          <p>So that gives us more of these kinds of business opportunities with them, with these large corporate. So that's one of our strengths. So we are not so concerned about the income outlook and business outlook when it comes to the corporate, corporate segment, even if this kind of growth outlook is not very strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right. So fee income should be more stable than the outlook suggests?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Sorry. What was the question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So fee income and particularly corporate investment banking fee income should be more stable than suggested by the current outlook?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes and as anything, which outlook are you referring to when you say that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Specifically the Swedish corporate outlook and the Nordic corporate outlook where we're seeing data such as PMIs and earnings trend downwards?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then the shipping coverage ratio, the way it usually goes is that we are early out in observing these kind of risk customers and impairing those and making provisions. When those customers are performing then, of course, we are using usually, we are evaluating the assets in market values, not any kind of forced sales values.</p>
          <p>Then again, when the work-out phase progressing and if we are not able to find any kind of good solution and when we are approaching towards this type of forced sale and default case, then we are increasing provisions, but then thereby also the coverage ratio is increasing. Then when we take a look at, okay, what has happened in those cases where we have seen real defaults and when we have then sold, forced sold the shipping fleet, in that phase, we have not been &#x2013; there has not been a need of increasing provisions so that we have been able to follow up this provision level throughout this workout process quite closely. And we have avoided this kind of tail impacts in the loan loss provision so that our model seems to work well. So that we started early then we increased provision ratios if it's then worse and values are going down. And then at the end, we simply think it's enough provided.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Could you probably give us an indication of where that provision ratio ends up for a company in the advanced stages of workouts?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It depends so much on the customer and what is the cycle of the fleet and all that, so that we always take these customers like customer basis and evaluate there.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Right.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It is an individual case and it is impossible to give any guidance this type of average numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's fair. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Our next question comes from Nick Davey of UBS. Your line is open. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good afternoon, everyone. Two questions please from my side, the first on funding, if I look at your slide 12, euros shrink for about the fourth year in a row now around &#x20AC;30 billion of long-term funding. That's compared to &#x20AC;15 billion which is maturing. I just like you just to expand a little bit please on your funding strategy and how you're measuring and planning the issuance of the senior funding because I think as long ago as a year ago, I remember rhetoric saying we think that we have much funded maturity, behavior maturity perspective. If I look in your annual report, there is a lot in there about having a surplus of stable liabilities over stable assets.</p>
          <p>So I'm just interested to see why in this zero growth environment there is continuing prefunding or over issuance. Second question please on expenses, I realize you're battling FX impacts, but FTE is down 6% on the year, staff costs flat. Can I just ask you to talk a little bit around what else is going into the staff costs line here which is keeping things inflated? And really what sort of macro environment or revenue deterioration environment we would need to see if you revisit the cost ambitions as some of your payers seem to be doing? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, Nick. Let me try and answer your questions. Long-term funding, if we start at that end, as you rightly remember, we are very close to much funded on behavioral standpoint. Of course, that's not the case for contractual. So for all general purposes, the long-term funding value will be a consequence of basically three things. First of all, pre-funding of course and the level of pre-funding we wish to make. The second thing is, of course, the extension of the book is optional. The third thing is growth. So yes, we are continuing to extend our funding maturity profile and, of course, also strengthening, although net stable funding in its current shape and form is not likely to ever be there but it may be in some other shape or form. We're continuing to remain strong.</p>
          <p>But you are right. We are maintaining very conservative funding strategy and it's also a strong point for us. And of course, what you are referring to stable asset versus stable funding is one of the parameters we actually manage our liquidity with and it should always be that way that we have stable funding more than stable asset. If that's not the case, of course, we run a risk that is too high.</p>
          <p>So I think it's likely given the regulatory environment and the general conservatism that we entertain, I think it's likely that we will continue to maintain a reasonable high issuance level. I think that goes without saying but, of course, it's tied in to the growth level of the bank so if we have a flat growth environment and you see no growth of the lending book as an example then, of course, the issuance will not be there to that degree so of course we adopt the reality.</p>
          <p>So then the second thing, the staff cost, of course, what we have done there is we've taken out 6% as you right say but of course is unevenly spread in time. So we didn't actually have for the full year just 6% flat cost reduction. This is done gradually over time. And in comparison, we have basically staff cost inflation plus and an increase in variable salary and thus the total of the equation. I'd like to add maybe one thing and that is that we see a slight also mixed change of the employees that lead the bank, if I may put it that way so it is not always the fact that if you have 6% reduction of people, you don't necessarily have exactly 6% reduction on the line staff cost. It may be a difference in mix and there are a couple of examples that have an impact. But those are the large parameters.</p>
          <p>Then finally I think you question and maybe Christian wants to take or add on to that question but should we have a need to revise cost targets, I think what we have defined and designed with our flat cost target is very much related to the fact that we continue to strengthen our business, we grow our income and we maintain our very strong business model that the relationship model that we have. So, you can say we are becoming more efficient midflight, put it that way. It's not a difficult thing to reduce costs much more than we do but that would need to be coupled with taking away activities or reducing or lowering income in all sorts of different ways.</p>
          <p>So we think this is a very challenging target to achieve while still maintaining a very high level of activities. We have been taking new customers, increasing volumes, et cetera. So we think it's challenging but very adequate target. I'm not sure if you want to add something, Christian.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, I will certainly add something because I think this is extremely challenging because we are building the bank. We are building the future business model. We are investing in IFC. We are investing in a number of value-creating things for customers. We are investing in the whole new regulatory setup which is certainly not a cheap one, and at the same time, we keep costs flat. So we are not just cutting costs. We are making the bank much, much more efficient and we are doing that for now seven quarters in a row, and we are going to continue several quarters.</p>
          <p>So we'll keep the running costs flat, then FX and variable salary and there's a few one-offs, and a little depreciation may pop up and down and so on. But the actual running costs we keep flat because this is a good discipline in the bank. We have to free up cost to invest in the value propositions to customers and that goes for all business areas. And that works pretty well and we have a strong discipline and this will over time create a cost efficiency, which I think will be very, very strong.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, very clear. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, sir. Our next question comes from the Claire Kane of RBC. Your line is open please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, everyone. I have two questions please. My first relates to Basel III. In the three documents put out today, there's just two mentions of Basel III and both of those relate to liquidity. Your peers are helpfully giving us a lot of guidance on the different sensitivities under Basel III. And I was just wondering if your lack of guidance in the reports that mentioned Basel III is a reflection of how you look at capital within the group. And also if you could provide an update on the RWA inflation that you gave us previously &#x20AC;14 billion and your target to reduce out of &#x20AC;19 billion and where you're going on that?</p>
          <p>And then my second question relates to your profitability. You mentioned in the report you've had one of the most stable return profiles of all the Nordic banks. But when you look at your return on assets, it's one of the lowest, if not the lowest of the Nordic banks currently. And I think it's quite clear to see that as you build capital, your leverage is going to come down. So where specifically are you trying to address an improvement in return on assets and is your loss of market share in some countries designed to improve the asset base that you have and the profitability on that? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. If I may start, first of all it's a good point, Claire, that we may not have given that much guidance and that may be ignorant from our side since we have given you so much before so we could have elaborated probably to the same extent we have done it before. But in short, we expect the impact from Basel III or CRD4 if you put it that way together with IAS 19 to be 120 basis points. This is predominantly &#x2013; of course, if you take the IAS 19, it is what is in the pension plans and if you take the Basel III component or CRD4 component, that is largely CVA risk.</p>
          <p>So I think we've been quite clear for some time now on those impacts. And if you also &#x2013; if I may elaborate a little bit, we've also communicated that we expect largely to compensate this impact with both efficiency gains and model implementations and the two dominant ones are, of course, advanced IRB for the corporate portfolio and the IMM advance for the CVA risk. And hence the 12.2% you see in the CT1 ratio is largely what we also expect after having implemented IAS 19 and CRD4.</p>
          <p>Then your other question on stable return on assets being the lowest, first of all, let me just point to one thing that you perhaps did not answer and that is that we are in comparison to pretty much all the other Nordic banks. We are also a very diversified bank. So we're spread all across the, of course, the Nordic and in some other countries. And of course we can only compete in our <mark type="indiscernible" />. If you would actually look at the return profile of, for instance, Nordea in Sweden, you will find us to be at par with the number one. We would be clearly at par or better in Finland. We would be clearly number one in Denmark and not far away in Norway. So you can say the average return, if you put it that way, is actually just a function of our diversification and that is also, of course, bringing stability.</p>
          <p>So we really perform well in all of the countries we are in. Then if you look at your question which was total return on assets, it's very much in our case impacted by a very significant derivatives book and the gross, of course, is very irrelevant measuring in terms of the return on assets. So you have to, when you do the calculations, you have to adjust for it and if you do that you will say that we match very well our competition in terms of return of assets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it important to stress that Nordea is not a Swedish Bank. It's a Nordic bank. We have 20% of our business in Sweden. And Sweden is right now, as I said, during the day it's paradise on earth in economic terms, also in other terms, but also in economic terms because I mean the sweet spot of all sweet spots right now is to be a Swedish mortgage savings bank. Now that may not be the most interesting strategy in the long term, but right now that's the sweet spot because the margins are high, interest rates are high in Sweden. So a lot of good things goes for that and our mortgage and savings bank in Sweden today are doing great, on par with the best.</p>
          <p>But the rest is, of course, not like that and we know the reality out there. So if we look at the total bank which is one of the, as you well know, one of the five largest banks in Europe in market cap, so compared to European banks, I was told today by the CNBC reporter that we are one of the top five ROEs in Europe and I think that is true. So in that sense, you have to benchmark this way and I think Nordea, the return on assets also compares extremely well.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Operator, we have room for one more question.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Our final question today comes from Riccardo Rovere of Mediobanca. Your line is open. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good afternoon to everybody and thanks for taking the time for my question. I have just one follow-up on NII. As the policy rates are going down significantly in all the regions where you are operating, not just Sweden, I just wonder whether you have an idea if you can cope with these kind of pressure on the deposit side maybe acting on the repricing on the loan book or have we come to a certain level of rates where there is nothing else that you can do when you just to weight for a possible increase in policy in the coming quarters and in the coming months? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think it's fair to say that we never give forecast as to margins, but we have never given the fact that we continue to strive for repricing on the lending book, not just as a compensation for deposit income coming down, but generally as a consequence of margins should be higher on the back of funding costs, et cetera. So of course, we will continue to do so and we are likely to be able to be successful in that, a little depending of course on the jurisdiction. But generally I think we will strive to continue to the reprice.</p>
          <p>And one indication you may or may not find to valuable is, of course, you got to compare the front book versus the back book. In many parts of the bank, we can clearly see that the front book [not least in Finland], front book is clearly higher than the back book. So it is our ambition to continue to try and reprice, so it's not about just sitting and waiting for things to happen. It's a very active pricing management that we entertain. And one of, you can say, finally maybe one of the good things about really low interest rates is that they probably can't get that much lower. So you can say &#x2013; you can always question the actual downside. But time will tell and we will continue to strive for fair pricing as we have done in several quarters now.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you very much for listening to this presentation and all the good questions. We will now travel to London and we hope to see a lot of you there at the breakfast meeting tomorrow morning. So thank you and goodbye.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>That will conclude the conference call. So thank you for your participation, ladies and gentlemen. You may now disconnect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>