<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1511640" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q3 2012 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2012-10-24</date>
    <companies>
      <company>9506</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="corprep" affiliation="Head-Group Identity &amp; Communications">Jan Larsson</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep" affiliation="President &amp; Chief Executive Officer">Christian Clausen</participant>
      <participant id="2" type="analyst" affiliation="ABG Sundal Collier AB">Magnus Andersson</participant>
      <participant id="3" type="analyst" affiliation="Svenska Handelsbanken AB (Broker)">Peter Grabe</participant>
      <participant id="4" type="analyst" affiliation="Exane BNP Paribas SA (Sweden)">Andreas H&#xE5;kansson</participant>
      <participant id="5" type="analyst" affiliation="Deutsche Bank AG (Stockholm)">Jan Wolter</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Ladies and gentlemen, you are most welcome to this press and analyst meeting, where we are to present the Third Quarter Report for 2012 for the Nordea Group. I have been asked by myself to do something that I haven't done in 15 quarterly reports, introduce myself. I'm Jan Larsson, Head of Nordea's Group Identity and Communication. That's naturally something that you should do.</p>
          <p>What we will do, apart from that piece of news in this presentation, we will follow the normal procedures. Christian will present the results, and after that we will have a short question-and-answer session. Please on a more general level, because detailed questions you will then have the chance to ask to Ari Kaperi, Chief Risk Officer; Fredrik Rystedt, Chief Financial Officer; and Rodney Alfv&#xE9;n, Head of our IR Department at a later stage, where journalists are asked to follow us to give or may have in-depth interviews with Christian. And as always, when you ask a question, I would be very happy if you could state your name and whom you represent, since this would be webcasted.</p>
          <p>And with those words, I hand the floor to you, Nordea's President and Group CEO, Christian Clausen.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Jan. Yes, welcome to this Q3 report presentation. I am really proud to present the results. The result for Q3 is slightly down compared to Q2, but it's the best ever first three quarters of a year. Significantly up, and in Q3 we have the best revenues we ever had. So we think we are well on track on building the bank of the future.</p>
          <p>So let's take the key messages; unchanged costs through 2012 excluding the FX. Cost/income ratio, 51%; improved ROE to 11.4%. The Core Tier 1 ratio improves to 12.2%. We have loan losses at 27 basis points, slightly up and, as I said, Q3 income is the highest ever. Operating profit exceeds &#x20AC;3 billion, and that's up 14% compared to last year if we take out the restructuring cost. And we continued our business momentum. We actually attract 65,000 new relationships in year-to-date.</p>
          <p>But maybe more importantly, we are taking important steps in building the future bank business model. As I already described, we are delivering on the New Normal plan on cost, capital and income. In retail bank, we take significant steps in rebuilding our distribution and becoming more efficient. In wholesale banking, we are developing our relationship, and clearly developing and adding more higher-value added services to the customers. And in wealth management, we're increasing efficiency, sharper offerings, and better performance.</p>
          <p>So let's look at the numbers, and as I already said, income is up 10%, costs are down 2%, which means operating profit is up 21%. But then we had this restructuring cost last year. We take that out. It's up 14%, and I think it's little interesting, net profit is up 24%.</p>
          <p>Net interest margin is somewhat under pressure. This is our gross margin. It's 105 basis points, slightly down, and that's, of course, because the deposit margins are still under pressure. Interest rates were still coming down in Q2 and Q3, which, of course, has the effect that we have more or less no margins left on our deposits.</p>
          <p>We have a slight increase in asset margins in Q3. But still if we look back to 2004, our gross margin level has actually never been lower. So the total cost of being a customer of the bank is actually still at the lower level, showing that we have indeed become more efficient as in recent years.</p>
          <p>So lending is slightly up. We have lower demand on corporate lending, but we help our corporates to a lot of financing on the capital market, I'll get back to that. Our household lending is somewhat up. But, of course, in this economic environment the demand is indeed low, deposits are up nicely, so all in all, the funding gap is well under control.</p>
          <p>And assets under management hit an all-time high of more than &#x20AC;220 billion (sic) [&#x20AC;210 billion] (4:21). We have a very strong inflow of &#x20AC;2.7 billion. It's very much on the retail fund and institutional side, and institutional clients are from all over the world, professional customers giving us money to manage. And we have very strong investment performance. 80% of our composites outperformed their benchmark this quarter, actually by a number that is nearly &#x20AC;1 billion in added value compared to the benchmarks.</p>
          <p>Expenses are under control. They decreased 2% in the quarter in loan currencies, but they are flat in the year in local currencies excluding the FX effects. And the number of FTEs are slightly down.</p>
          <p>Credit quality is good. The credit losses is broadly in line with our risk appetite, i.e., the average over the cycle. It's slightly up in the quarter, but we still have very low loan losses in Norway, Sweden and Finland. We have continued elevated levels in Denmark and Sweden. There's one-off effects from the stricter rules we have in Denmark, which have applied very, very strict rules of performing loan reservations, which we have done. So actually, in this quarter, we have lower individual provisions, but we have increased the general provisions, i.e., our model show that in this environment we need a bit more general provision, so we are following the models there. So, all in all, we are quite happy with this development.</p>
          <p>We have very strong access to funding. We are actually the strongest funding bank in Europe. We have taken in &#x20AC;25 billion in the first three quarters, of which more than half is senior unsecured funding. The redemptions this year are &#x20AC;15 billion, so we are way ahead, and we have very, very strong spreads.</p>
          <p>And I took along this graph, which I think is a bit amusing. Nordea is really one of the safest jurisdictions in Europe. Our covered bonds spreads on five years is actually just between the government of France and the government of Belgium at 10 basis points. So investors really believe in the Nordea name. So our funding strategy works. We are raising funding on very attractive terms, which proves that investors all over the world believe Nordea is a very strong bank.</p>
          <p>We generate a lot of capital. We have nearly doubled the capital level since 2007, and we have increased the capital by 8% per year on average after dividends. So we still generate the capital level to whatever level. We can produce whatever capital level we choose to do over time. Now we are above the 12% level here, but this development will continue. We are generating the capital.</p>
          <p>And the reason for that is, of course, very much that we managed to keep our risk-weighted assets under control. So risk-weighted assets come down in this quarter. We have increased quality in our liquidity buffer. We have lower credit risk and market risk, and we have optimized the RWAs by more than &#x20AC;0.5 billion, and there's very limited effect on rating migration.</p>
          <p>So, all in all, growing lending with a very strong discipline on risk weighted assets is, of course, one of the reasons, while our Core Tier 1 ratio is now 12.2%, that's ahead of the plans for the new regulation, as you know, in 2015. So we are early out here. And, of course, as I already said, we are generating nearly 1 percentage point per year after dividend. So where exactly we want to be is, of course, depending on the final outcome of new regulation. So we have built 220 basis points since 2010, and grown lending by 17%, and pay dividend to shareholders. So the value creation Nordea produces is quite significant.</p>
          <p>Let's talk about the future bank business model, which is, of course, very important, and it's all based on the relationship strategy. We build relationship with core customer. That's key to the way we run our business, and all the way through the crisis we have done so. We have invested in the customer experiences. We have helped the customers through the crisis. We have supported customers out of the crisis, and we are now securing the customers can finance their plans.</p>
          <p>A strong focus on helping core customers, and that's a very strong proposition. It's close and lifelong relationships we are building. We are focused on the right customers and the right projects, those we know well. We are creating very capital-efficient solution. Because we know our customers, we can actually create a solution for the customers that do not involve more capital than absolutely necessary. We have many products per customer.</p>
          <p>The customer gives all his or her business to us, which means that we have an efficient cost to serve, because we have full customers coming in, so we can allocate time and resources to do a good piece of advice. We have very good diversification and low risk. We have no single area that stands out, so we are well-diversified when the cycle moves along in different countries. And these customers are very satisfied. They are very loyal and they stay with us. And when they leave one of these advice meetings, they are more or less always checked what their satisfaction is, it's very high, and we generate high ROE.</p>
          <p>And the New Normal is, of course, then based on this relation strategy to perform on efficiency. So we have the obligation and we take responsibility to become more efficient on capital, funding, liquidity and costs. And as we execute the New Normal plan, we are indeed doing it out of a position of strength, because we are, as I demonstrated, growing the number of core customer relationships.</p>
          <p>We are delivering top league ROE. We have one of the strongest ratings in the sector, and we have, as I said, one of the best, if not the best, funding position. And we are one of the largest banks in Europe mentioned on market cap, which is indeed very important, because we are very relevant for investors also outside Europe in the U.S. and the Far East, because we have this size.</p>
          <p>So the relationship strategy is actually a win-win. There are a lot of benefits for the customers and benefits for Nordea. The business model comes well together, and it is designed very well for the New Normal. And it's based on knowing the customer, advising the customer, servicing the customer, and committing to the customer.</p>
          <p>From the customer point of view, knowing the customer means that the customer will know that we know his financial situation. We can look it up on the screen, we can help the customer finding the right solution, and thereby giving a holistic advice, which is, of course, in the best interest of the customer ensuring that everything is covered in our 360-degree meetings.</p>
          <p>We can also provide all services and we are indeed doing that, making the customer take all his products to Nordea so we get the full overview. And we commit, we are a stable bank. The customer can count on us. We will be there both on sunny days and also on rainy days, because knowing the customer so well means that if there is a temporary liquidity problem, we know the customer well enough to be able to support this.</p>
          <p>And for the bank point of view, of course, knowing the customers very well makes it possible for us to focus on the right customers and the right projects. And, as I already said, identify solutions that are more efficient than we used to do. So in the New Normal, it's all about finding a solution for the customer that is more capital and funding efficient. And, of course, we benefit from the situation that we get all the customer business, so we have a much better cost to serve ratio and we commit to the customer, but that also means we have higher loyalty.</p>
          <p>Our core relationship customers are very satisfied and very loyal customers. And also the numbers show that this is in relative to our business model, because 94% of our income is customer-related. The remaining 6% is actually also customer related, because that's risk income from handling the customer risk, i.e., doing hedging transactions and risk transactions for the customers.</p>
          <p>So we have done a lot of things on the customer areas, and let me highlight a few things on the household customers. Each working day, more than 5,000 customers have had an advice session in Nordea. Every day, 5,000 customers have left Nordea with a full overview of the financial situation with the risks and how to improve it. We have attracted close to 21,000 new Gold and Private Banking customers, i.e., these relationship customers in the quarter, and 65,000 year-to-date, provided 77,000 new mortgages, 362,000 advisory meetings, I already mentioned that, 250,000 new cards. We have processed 330 million card transactions, and we have now 700,000 active users of our mobile app; actually 1.4 million customers have downloaded our mobile app.</p>
          <p>And this is very interesting, because these customers, they visit the bank every second day. They go into the mobile applications and they do banking, they get advice, they seek information, or they do transactions. So imagine that all these customers, they actually walk into the bank by the fingers on their mobile device every second day. That's a huge interaction with customers, and they are very happy about that. And, of course, it takes off a lot of load in our branches, where they don't physically have to walk in with their feet, and very few bank customers will walk into their bank every second day, I think, if they had to do it with their feet. And we have a lot of likes on the Facebook, and I fully understand that.</p>
          <p>Corporate customers, the same thing. We had more than 1,000 advisory meetings today with the corporate customers, small and medium sized customers, again, helping them to find the right financing solution. As I said, corporate lending is slightly down, but we do indeed help our corporate customers to more long-term financing. We have helped raise more than nearly &#x20AC;7 billion in capital on the bond markets, and nearly &#x20AC;11 billion under syndicated loan market.</p>
          <p>So as we go forward in the New Normal, we will help our corporate customers to the capital market on their long-term financing. We will on our balance sheet do the short-term financing, the working capital requirement, the bridge financing, the customer financing, the trade financing, and all the ordinary banking stuff, which is more short term in nature, and the long-term financing needs to be raised on the capital market. And we have indeed done that to a very large extent.</p>
          <p>We have also arranged the two largest corporate bonds issues ever in Swedish history fund-listed companies. So we are clearly number one bookrunner on Eurobonds, and clearly number one bookrunner on syndicated loans. So we have a very significant market share, and this is very important, because that's part of the whole relationship on the corporate customer side.</p>
          <p>And on &#x2013; the New Normal also delivers, as I already said, on costs. And if you look at a slightly longer perspective, we can see that the costs are flat now for seven quarters in a row if we adjust for the FX effects, i.e., in loan currencies. So we keep costs flat and, of course, the flipside of that is that we have reduced the number of FTEs quite a lot. And that's quite an achievement in the organization, because that is not easy to do at the same time as we do more business and have more customers and do a lot of changes, because new regulation and New Normal. At the same time, taking down staff is not an easy task.</p>
          <p>And this means, of course, we are delivering on efficiency. We have better cost to serve ratio. We have more business per employee. We have more customers per FTE, and the income per FTE is also up. If you look back one year or two years ago, it's actually up quite significant.</p>
          <p>As I said, we're also delivering on capital and risk-weighted assets. And if we decompose the risk-weighted assets numbers, you can see that we are actually taking down the risk-weighted assets very much, because we have a lot of activity in optimizing. This is getting better collateral. It's better covenants, i.e., it's lowering the risk level in the book by finding the capital right solutions for the customers.</p>
          <p>We also have a better credit quality. Then we have growth effects. But also, we have the new regulation, Basel 2.5, which came in this year. And January 1 next year we will have more Basel III coming in, which will have negative effects. So we are indeed taking down our risk-weighted assets, and at the same time, new regulation as risk-weighted assets. So that's an important part of this world becoming more capital-efficient.</p>
          <p>A few comments to each business area. Retail banking is making a dramatic change in the distribution side. Because our customers are using the mobile and the Internet bank much more, we are indeed changing significantly, and we have rebuilt all the branches into service branches, advice branches. And we get fewer and fewer customers into the service branches, because they walk into the bank every single day on the Internet instead. And on the advice branches, we get more and more customers come to the advice branches, because most private customers still want to meet the advisor if they have real financial need. They don't want to do it only on the net. So that's a very significant change.</p>
          <p>Also the change in the focus on the capital management is key, and this is also win-win, because if you deploy less capital in the customer solution, the cost of the customer, of course, is lower. And we are becoming significantly more efficient, streamlining processes, and this can be seen in the numbers. In retail, the operating profit is up 20%, and look at the core ratios, cost/income ratio down, RaRoCar, risk-adjusted return is up, and risk-weighted assets are flat.</p>
          <p>On wholesale banking, as I already said, this is about building a relationship that is also much more capital efficient and better for the customer, because the cost of funding gets lower. So it's very much about the full relationship, as I said, all the daily banking business and helping them on the capital market when they need longer financing. So it's very much about the total value chain to improve that, so this daily service level gets as smooth and efficient as possible, and then, of course, very strict resource management.</p>
          <p>And also here, we are developing very well, with the operating income up 14%. And ratios, again, cost/income down, risk-adjusted return up, and here we see risk-weighted assets coming down. That is also needed, because January 1 when the Basel III kicks in, it very much kicks-in in this area with new requirements.</p>
          <p>And wealth management is also doing very well; look at the numbers, operating profit up 23%. Here we have also a lot of things to do on the capital side, not least in life. And now 75% of the premiums in life is in capital-light products, which is better for the customer and, of course, commanding less capital.</p>
          <p>We are more efficient in our product offering and, as I mentioned, our inflow of new capital is &#x20AC;2.7 billion from all over the world. Good investment performance, and therefore, we see also here key ratios very strong. Cost/income ratio down significantly, risk-weighted assets down, and assets under management, as we saw, &#x20AC;210 billion.</p>
          <p>So the key messages is in reality that this is actually a very good Q3; slightly down from Q2, but it is indeed delivering on the New Normal plan. Unchanged costs; cost/income ratio in truth; ROE improved, Core Tier 1 improved; loan losses slightly up, but as I said, individual loan losses down, and operating profit up 14%.</p>
          <p>So we are indeed building the business model of the future. We are delivering on our plan. So all in all, we are quite satisfied with this quarter. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Then we have time for questions. We have one there, one there, and one there. Let's kick off with that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. It's Magnus Andersson at ABG. I just had a question on the Liikanen report, which stipulates that banks with more than &#x20AC;100 billion trading assets or more than 15% to 25% trading assets relative to total assets should hive it off or ring-fence it. You were pointed out with having 35% of your total assets as trading assets. So I'm wondering, number one, this also imply that the provisioning on hedging services to clients should still remain in the retail banking arm. So the first question is, if you deduct that, will you be below the 15%, or how much lower than the 35%? Secondly, if that is not the case, what kind of impact or you see &#x2013; potential impact would you see of the proposal on the earnings and capital ratio?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>It's a bit too early to be very precise on this. Now a report has come out. It's getting into hearing, and the commission has said they will think about things, and then they will put forward their directive, and then the directive needs to put into law. So we are several years down the road before it actually will be implemented if it comes out in the shape or form. There are a lot of dynamic effects in this. So 12 to 14 banks in Europe will do this ring-fencing exercise. And most likely, these banks will then be the banks that can service the big corporate sector in Europe.</p>
          <p>So the dynamic effects are typical to look through. It's not impossible to do this ring-fencing. But, of course, we think it's too tough medicine for the risks report point at. The report points at certain risks which materialized in the financial crisis and caused it, which I agree upon, so that analysis is good. But then the medicine that we need to ring-fence, we think is too tough medicine. It's not necessary, because we have raised capital levels to cover those risks. And we are right now dealing with the crisis management directive, which will install the bail-in bonds, the bail-in facilities. So if you have 12% capital and you have 10% bail-in bonds, you have implicit capital levels of more than 20%. Do you really need to do more, remembering that the banking sector came from 4% capital?</p>
          <p>So the report is good. It highlights some risks, which were there. The risk, going forward, I'm not sure is there, because we have put capital against those risks. But this discussion we will have now and we are entering in a proactive way into these discussions. But the actual outcome for a single bank is very difficult to predict, because there will be some dynamic effects that if it's really carried out, I think a lot of the big business activity will be concentrated in some banks which is, of course, also something we have to be aware of.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Do you have a feeling for, if you would take out your provisioning of hedging services to clients that will stay in the retail arm, where would you be versus the 35% that was in the report? How much below that 35% would you be? Because I guess the lion's share of your derivative book is related to that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, we will probably become below, but there are no definitions in the report and it's vague on this area. So it's not exactly clear how this should be done, and the interaction between the trading unit and the deposit-taking unit is not clear either. So we cannot really give numbers. We have to work with it now. We have to work with the commission in how to actually go forward from here. As I said, we do not believe that medicine is an adequate one for what they have described.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>And we have a question in the middle here, <mark type="ph" /> Emily (24:32). Okay. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Peter Grabe, Handelsbanken. Two questions, firstly regarding capital and capital regulation. You previously indicated that you might end up having more of a blended capital requirement to live up to rather than a Swedish 12% floor. I was wondering if you can give an update on your view going forward in terms of capital and what you were really targeting when you do the capital planning at the moment.</p>
          <p>And the second question relates to the ROE target. You previously said 15% ROE under normalized conditions, which includes 11% Core Tier 1 ratio, which obviously looks to be on the low side. If you can give us an update on your view as to what kind of ROE should be expected in the current operating environment?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes.  We have not announced any new capital policy, because CRD4 has not been decided yet, and it's probably going to drag out even more before the capital laws are coming in. So until we know the regulation, we will not make a new policy. But the 11% seems to be, of course, low, so we are building more capital as we see. And as I said, we are building nearly 1% capital ratio per year, so we will decide exactly where the optimal point is.</p>
          <p>As events develop now in regulation, it's clear that with the crisis management directive are really decided the way it looks now, then, as I said, all these bail-in instruments we need to hold means that the optimal point of capital may be somewhat higher than without that, because more capital will protect the bail-in instruments, which then will become cheaper. So maybe all banks will move higher on capital, especially in Europe, than we may have thought a year ago. So we simply don't know where the optimal point is.</p>
          <p>I think the most important message today is that we can build the capital we need to have over this period of time and we are doing that. And I think, right now, we have a very strong capital base. But we will continue to monitor, and we come back to you with a capital policy when we know the rules exactly as they are. So you shouldn't be worried about the capital levels.</p>
          <p>The ROE, you're right, it is at 15% at 2011. We said that maybe one-and-a-half year ago now, quite a long time ago, when we had another environment and regulation. I think going forward it will obviously not be 11%, and normalized interest condition is now just around the corner. We all know that. So we are probably not going to deliver those 15% in the short term. But we will also come back on more precise targets when we know the capital ratios and we will come back on that. What we are demonstrating today, and which I think you do know, is our ability to generate profit and value, which will continue according to our plans. So this development, we strongly believe, can continue.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi. It's Andreas H&#xE5;kansson from Exane BNP Paribas. Two questions as well. First one, the other Swedish banks that reported gave quite specific details on how much the strengthening Swedish kroner has impacted their net interest income negatively. Could you tell us how much is the impact to you positively?</p>
          <p>Second question is in Denmark, we show now an 18% increase in non-performing loans in retail Denmark in sequential quarters, and quite a pickup in corporate as well. And when I read your Q2 report, you say that certain over-leveraged households have problems. Now you dropped <mark type="ph" /> certain, (28:01) so it sounds like it's a big spread problem. And in Q2 you also said that Nordea overall credit quality is solid also in Denmark, and that phrase is all gone now in the Q3 situation or reports. It sounds like the situation is tougher. Could you tell us about that?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>But then, it's not tougher, to make it clear. Maybe the words are slightly different. What happens in Denmark is very simple, the fact that the new regulation, which is extreme. It's the only country in the world which has this type of regulation, where you have to provide for loans that are fully performing, but where loan to value is increasing. That's a very unique thing. And we have taken that in the Q2 and the Q3 now, but we also state very clear that the individual loan losses are coming down. So these are general provisions being made on this area. So no deterioration on the underlying quality, that's for sure, maybe a slight improvement. The first question was on?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>FX impact.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>FX impact, yes. It's probably slightly lower than 1%, but I think we can elaborate that afterwards and give you a fuller picture, the positive effect.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Any more questions?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, hi. Jan Wolter, Deutsche Bank. You have previously talked about the potential for further repricing, that you're lifting margins to compensate for regulatory costs, et cetera. And this quarter we could see that the lending margin impact is not that significant. Has anything changed there? Is this just a temporary effect of some kind? And if so, what is the effect there which capped the lending margin increase now? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We are increasing still our lending margins somewhat. Now it's not a straight line, but we will continue to do that, and there are also a lot of back books which will be repriced in the coming period. But we are all the time adjusting the pricing to the new ratios, and part of the New Normal plan is that each customer pays for the capital and funding they draw on the bank. But if they draw less capital, of course, they pay less, so this is very simple. The more leverage you need in your balance sheet as a customer, the higher the price will be and the higher our price would be.</p>
          <p>So we are pricing customer per customer, country per country very, very precisely in order to make sure that the resources you draw will be priced rightly. And this will continue as we go forward, so we still expect lending margins to gradually move up. It's not the same in all segments and it's not the same in all countries, and the size of the back book is also different. I'm sure we can elaborate on that afterwards from our CFO, Fredrik.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Then we have time for one last question?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Then I say thank you very much. And, as I said, analysts are welcome to stay to listen to Ari, Fredrik and Rodney. Journalists can come with us around the corner in this room. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>