<?xml version="1.0" encoding="us-ascii"?>
<transcript id="1145532" product="CorrectedTranscript" xmlns="http://www.factset.com/callstreet/xmllayout/v0.1">
  <meta>
    <title>Q4 2008 Earnings Call</title>
    <date>2009-02-19</date>
    <companies>
      <company>1022</company>
    </companies>
    <participants>
      <participant id="0" type="operator">Operator</participant>
      <participant id="1" type="corprep">James Singh, Executive Vice President, Finance and Control, Legal, IP, Tax, Global Nestl&#xE9; Business Services</participant>
      <participant id="2">Roddy Child-Villiers</participant>
      <participant id="3">Marco Gulpers</participant>
      <participant id="4">James Singh</participant>
      <participant id="5">Jon Cox</participant>
      <participant id="6">Martin Dolan</participant>
      <participant id="7">Julian Hardwick</participant>
      <participant id="8">John Parker</participant>
      <participant id="9">Polly Barclay</participant>
      <participant id="10">Patrik Schwendimann</participant>
      <participant id="11">Pierre Tegner</participant>
      <participant id="12">Jeff Stent</participant>
    </participants>
  </meta>
  <body>
    <section name="MANAGEMENT DISCUSSION SECTION">
      <speaker>
        <plist>
          <p>MANAGEMENT DISCU.S.SION SECTION</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to the Nestl&#xE9; 2008 Full Year Results Conference Call hosted by Jim Singh, Nestl&#xE9; Chief Financial Officer, and by Roddy Child-Villiers, Head of Nestl&#xE9; Investor Relations.</p>
          <p>As usual, there will be a presentation and there will be open -- then we'll open the lines for question-and-answers. My name is Bhupendra and I'll be your coordinator this morning. Throughout the conference, you'll remain on listen-only. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> I would like to advise all parties that this conference is being recorded for replay purposes.</p>
          <p>And now I'd like to hand the conference over to Mr. Singh.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you and good morning to everyone. Welcome to our conference call to discuss our 2008 full year results. As usual, I'll take the Safe Harbor statement as read and move straight to my presentation.</p>
          <p>2008 was a really good year for Nestle, particularly in a year when global business conditions deteriorated sharply. The achievement of 8.3% organic growth was above our October guidance and significantly above both the market's expectations at the start of 2008 and our Nestl&#xE9; model target.</p>
          <p>Equally, our improvement in EBIT margin was in line with consensus. Arguably, it was even ahead in terms of operating performance because we met consensus despite the 20 basis points negative currency impact. The EBIT margin performance demonstrates Nestl&#xE9; ability to overcome challenging market conditions.</p>
          <p>In 2008, those challenges included significant raw material and packaging material inflation and price volatility, weaker consumer demand and adverse currency impacts. As some of these will recover in 2009, you can take some comfort from our proven ability to manage successfully through these challenges.</p>
          <p>The Food and Beverages business was the key contributor to performance, with 8.2% organic growth and a 40 basis point improvement in EBIT margins in constant currencies. For the second year in a row, this performance was broad based. Each of the three zones, as well as Nestl&#xE9; Nutrition and Other Food and Beverages, all achieved a good level of profitable growth.</p>
          <p>This demonstrates the momentum in our business and is one of the reasons why we remain optimistic for a further improvement in our performance in 2009, despite the tough environment.</p>
          <p>The 2008 performance was built on the twin pillars of growth and efficiencies. The billionaire brands, about 70% of our Food and Beverage sales, were the key drivers of growth. Many outperformed their markets driven by our continued focus on Nutrition, Health and Wellness and by our accelerated targeting of particular needs of consumers in different economic circumstances, by our significant presence in emerging markets, by near 10% growth with our top ten customers and by our multi-channel, multi-price point strategy.</p>
          <p>On the efficiencies side, we already saw the benefit in 2008 of our accelerated focus on cost savings and higher returns on expenditure throughout the business. This helped compensate the impact of raw and packing material inflation on our cost of goods sold. It also benefited our distribution, marketing and administration costs.</p>
          <p>The next slide shows the sales progression. You've seen these numbers already. To save time, I'll just highlight the huge impact of foreign exchange, negative 7.8% as the Swiss franc strengthened particularly versus the euro, U.S. dollar and sterling.</p>
          <p>Staying with foreign exchange on the next slide, here are the movements of major currencies. When did you last see near 10% move for the U.S. dollar or over 15% for the U.K. pound? Both the U.S. and U.K. have good levels of profitability relative to our average.</p>
          <p>The translation effect of currency movements have not only impacted sales, but also our EBIT and our EBIT margin, our net profit, the working capital and our cash flow. Unfortunately therefore, this is not the easiest year for you to make like-for-like comparisons between 2007 and 2008.</p>
          <p>Next up is the organic growth of our Total Food &amp; Beverage business. Strong full year performances from all three regions. I'll get into more detail in the primary reporting slides.</p>
          <p>Here is an overview of our reporting on primary Food &amp; Beverage. There is a recurring theme to Nestl&#xE9; 2008 results and it is clear to see from this slide. Nestl&#xE9;'s performance was broad based. Here you can see that all the primary reporting segments except Nestl&#xE9; Waters achieved a good level of organic growth as well as improving their EBIT margins. I'll make a few broad comments about this 2008 performance and what it means for 2009 before going into the detail by zone.</p>
          <p>First of all, 2000 (sic) [2008] was a year that was characterized by a high pace of innovation and renovation. The focus has been on simple to understand, consumer element propositions around nutrition. It has been an improving value propositions and a differentiation from our competitors. There will be no letup in 2009.</p>
          <p>The drive for innovation has been supported by a step-up in marketing spend -- 7.5% higher in 2008 in constant currencies. We will continue to build brand equity in 2009 and we will continue to benefit from softer media rates already apparent in 2008. As an example, TV rates in the U.K. are the lowest for 15 years.</p>
          <p>A major advantage that we have -- and we will come back to this on the road show -- is being able to offer consumers the ability to trade-up and trade-down without trading out of Nestle products. This was a benefit in 2008 and will be in 2009.</p>
          <p>We've also been pushing PPP hard in Europe as well as in emerging markets and we continue to see considerable opportunity for further growth in the segment. This remains a priority area for 2009.</p>
          <p>We continue to pursue our multi-channel strategy. This helps ensure our products are available wherever consumers shop, but also reduces our direct exposure to private label, whilst enable us to build added value relationships with large retailers and hard discounters or indeed with any specific channel, custom or market.</p>
          <p>Finally, we have worked diligently with discipline to improve our operating performance. This has reflected in savings exceeding CHF 1 billion achieved in all earnings of the business, from factory gate to customer. We will seek a forward acceleration in 2009 in our operational performance.</p>
          <p>Let's look at the detail, starting with Zone Europe. 2008 was a good year for the zone, with positive RIG in both Western and Eastern Europe and positive organic growth in all the major markets. We told you in October that we had already met third quarter sales of Chocolate for Christmas normally made in the fourth quarter. Excluding Chocolate, RIG remained positive for Zone Europe in the final quarter.</p>
          <p>Among categories, I would highlight the performance of PetCare, with many of the brands such as Bakers, ONE and Fancy Feast contributing. Soluble Coffee was also strong with many Nescaf&#xE9; variants performing well and Dolce Gusto continued to roll out rapidly. Its sales tripled in 2008. Powdered beverages also grew well, in particular Nesquik with its broadened nutrition offering.</p>
          <p>Pricing firmed up in the final quarter due to Chocolate and Soluble Coffee. Looking into 2009, we expect consumers to have a cautious approach to spending. We believe that we can benefit from this. Coffee at home can take share from coffee shops, culinary products, frozen and chilled food from restaurants, for example. And we are also offering smaller forms of our regular products with lower cash outlays for our consumers as well as driving our PPP strategy of daily affordable products. In fact, we are running many PPP projects in the Zone. These comments about a defensive nature of our categories, by the way, are equally applicable to Zone Americas covered on the next slide.</p>
          <p>Zone Americas had a strong 2008 with double-digit organic growth. Both North America and Latin America reported positive RIG despite significant inflationary pressure reflected in their reported pricing. The good level of growth in North America wasn't changed in the final quarter.</p>
          <p>Among categories, I would highlight the performance particularly of PetCare and Ambient Dairy, both of which have been strong throughout the year. Frozen food recovered during the course of the year accelerating in the second half. This bodes well for 2009. Within Frozen Food, Hot Pockets recovered or achieved over 7% organic growth, a return to form.</p>
          <p>Ice Cream's growth was negative, reflecting a focus on value growth at the expense of volume, with a number of lower-end SKUs and less profitable direct store delivery routes discontinued. The good news for Ice Cream is two-fold. We held share against our number one competitor and we improved our EBIT margins.</p>
          <p>In North America, both H&#xE4;agen Dazs and Skinny Cow performed well. Latin America slowed a little in the final quarter, but remained double-digit. This was due to easing of pricing in the Milk business rather than any broad economic issue. The other categories generally performed well particularly Chocolate, Soluble Coffee, PetCare and Biscuits.</p>
          <p>Zone AOA achieved double-digit organic growth in 2008. China's performance is overshadowed by the milk issue, which resulted in the milk market falling at one stage by 50%. Our shares are significantly up.</p>
          <p>We have continued to support our dairy farmers by buying their milk and selling it into the industrialized milk market. The rest of our business is doing well, demonstrated by the fact that the organic growth of the total Nestl&#xE9; in mainland China was 18% in 2008.</p>
          <p>The rest of the zone had a robust end to the year, suggesting our PPP strategy, our deep distribution and broad category offering, as well as our continued focus on relevant innovation and renovation and our Nutrition, Health, and Wellness strategy are resonating with consumers.</p>
          <p>Examples of relevant innovation for the current environment, including the rollout of PPP Nido milk in Africa, PPP Nestea and Maggi in the Philippines and PPP Nescaf&#xE9; in Indonesia. Among markets, I would particularly highlight the South Asia region, especially India as well as Philippines and Indochina. By category, I could highlight many that achieved double-digit organic growth, but Soluble Coffee, Culinary, Powdered Beverages and PetCare in particular all also achieved high levels of RIG. The final quarter was a bit slower for both RIG and pricing, Greater China and Japan both had a slow quarter and together accounted for the slowdown.</p>
          <p>Looking to 2009 for the zone, it is clear that it will be tough in the developed markets Japan and Oceania. Equally there is a risk in markets that are supported by remittances from expatriates.</p>
          <p>There are two noteworthy positives, however. One is the significant focus of governments in the region on aid packages to drive domestic consumption. Our business is all about domestic consumption. The second is that our products and strategy are well aligned to cope in an environment in which consumers are looking for value and are looking for minimal daily cash outlays.</p>
          <p>Turning to the EBIT margin performance for the three zones. We achieved EBIT margin improvements in all three, despite both the significant raw and packing material cost pressures felt in many categories, and a negative currency impacts resulting from the strong Swiss francs.</p>
          <p>The key drivers of the improved performance were operating efficiencies, the benefits of mix and rationalizing underperforming SKUs and the leverage of strong organic growth. We aim to push harder to accelerate our efficiency initiatives in 2009.</p>
          <p>Next, Nestl&#xE9; Waters. The trends and issues seen early in 2008 in the water category continued throughout the year, resulting in an exceptionally tough trading environment. Our business performed well relative to the market in the U.S. and well relative to the branded players in Europe. The emerging market continues to grow double-digit.</p>
          <p>The decline in the EBIT margin was despite good work in accelerating efficiencies and is the result of reduced sales, increased cost pressures, particularly oil related, and the underperformance of the European Home and Office Delivery business.</p>
          <p>Actions taken in 2008 beyond several cost reduction measures include exiting our U.K. HOD business, completed early in 2009. Nestl&#xE9; Waters also reduced their capital expenditure in view of the changing needs of the business. This has been further reduced in the 2009 budget.</p>
          <p>For 2009, we do not see any change in the challenges faced by the business. We are not therefore expecting any significant recovery in the business performance. We will focus on protecting our market shares and EBIT margins.</p>
          <p>Next is Nestl&#xE9; Nutrition. There was a strong year for Infant Nutrition with near double-digit growth, including growth in the teens for infant formula, clearly outstripping its market growth rates. The R&amp;D pipeline is full for the division and 2009 will be another strong year for launches.</p>
          <p>We need to improve our performance in Western Europe and this is a priority for us. In general, however, this division is performing well.</p>
          <p>The integrations of Gerber and Medical Nutrition are on track for cost efficiencies and their integration led to some SKU rationalization in the latter part of the year, impacting 2008 RIG.</p>
          <p>Jenny Craig clearly outperformed the weight management industry in 2008. It also improved its EBIT margin. This demonstrate the strength of the business model and underlines our confidence in its longer term potential for profitable growth. That said, it was progressively challenged during the year due to the U.S. economic environment and we expect 2009 to be a tough year for the division.</p>
          <p>Nestl&#xE9; Nutrition reported an improved EBIT margin in 2008, though it was another that suffered from currencies in translation. Nestl&#xE9; Nutrition expects 2009 to be a challenging year with weight management and performance nutrition both relatively cyclical businesses, but they expect to see further improvement in the performance overall with above market growth.</p>
          <p>Finally, in the primary reporting is Other Food &amp; Beverages. There was a continued very strong performance from this category. Nespresso continues its meteoric growth and passed CHF 2 billion in sales for the first time in 2008. The joint ventures both performed well. Cereal Partners Worldwide achieved high single-digit growth, whilst Beverage Partners Worldwide were well into double-digit.</p>
          <p>Let's look at the product categories and I'll go quickly as we have covered much of this already. I'll start with Powdered &amp; Liquid Beverages. All the billionaire brands achieved good levels of growth. We continue to drive competitive advantage and differentiation through nutritional and innovation and extensions.</p>
          <p>We have also accelerated our PPP strategy for many of these products. The EBIT margin was impacted by raw material costs as well as increased marketing support for the accelerating international rollout of Nescaf&#xE9; Dolce Gusto.</p>
          <p>The Dairy business achieved double-digit organic growth in 2008 due to its successful implementation of its PPP strategy in emerging markets and good price segmentation aligned with clear consumer benefits. There was a strong performance from COFFEE-MATE.</p>
          <p>Ice Cream's growth remained at a low level, but its EBIT margin improved. The growth was impacted by a strategy of exiting underperforming, lower value products, some U.S. DSD routes that were not sufficiently profitable and moving a couple of smaller European markets to a distributor model. These initiatives were all drivers of the margin improvement. The Premium brands continued to perform well as did those with a Better for You profile.</p>
          <p>In Prepared Dishes and Cooking Aids, the highlight once again was Maggi, benefiting from its emerging market exposure and ready adaptability to our PPP strategy. Also noteworthy was the promised improvement performance -- or improved performance of Hot Pockets, which achieved organic growth of 7.2%. The other parts of the U.S. Frozen Food business had a slow start, but accelerated during the year. The European pizza business and Herta both performed well. The products' group EBIT margin fell due to cost pressures, particularly relating to wheat. However, the year-end EBIT margin performance reflects a strong recovery during the second half of the year. The other notable news here was the sale of the Buitoni dry pasta business in Italy.</p>
          <p>There was a good performance by our Confectionery business, with 8% organic growth and 150 basis points improvement in EBIT margin to 13.1%. This is a level of margin comparable with any in the industry. I hope that this performance puts to rest the view that we are below scale in this industry. We are the most global of any confectionery business, demonstrated by the fact that we have over 150 products that are number one or number two in their market.</p>
          <p>We also have a very strong emerging market business, which achieved organic growth of 19% in 2008. The improvement in the EBIT margin reflects the benefits of growth in many parts of the world, as well as in the restructuring in Europe.</p>
          <p>The KitKat innovation continued to gather pace during the year, and the brand ended a year with over 13% organic growth, driven mainly by the re-launched four-finger bar. The launch of KitKat Senses is also going well and is being extended to new markets.</p>
          <p>Looking to 2009, the industry is likely to be challenged by high raw material prices, as well as the economic environment. We will continue to drive those initiatives that have contributed to strong performance, including a focus on quality and on distribution on innovation and renovation and on PPPs.</p>
          <p>Next is PetCare. All regions achieved a high level of organic growth with a strong base of RIG. The product group's EBIT margin improved to 15.7%. Many brands achieved high single digit or even double-digit growth driven by compelling health propositions for dogs and cats.</p>
          <p>The business continues to reap the benefits of a full pipeline of innovation, applicable around the world and closely aligned to the concerns of pet owners. The challenge for the product category has been raw materials. Initially it was grains, but more recently, it has been the minor raw materials such as vegetables, meats and vitamins that have been increasing and actually becoming quite material to the business. The extent of the EBIT margin improvement was held back by the U.S. dollar on translation to Swiss francs. But this was a very good performance after being behind 2007 at a half year.</p>
          <p>Finally is Pharmaceutical Products. There were good performances from all three constituents, with Alcon, Galderma and Inn&#xE9;ov all contributing to both the EBIT margin improvement and the strong growth.</p>
          <p>Next is the EBIT bridge, showing the movements between 2007 and 2008. The bridge has a similar shape to that at the half year. The impact in cost of goods has reduced, but remained significant, reflecting the fact that we were already experiencing cost pressures in the second half of 2007.</p>
          <p>We had a strong performance with our cost savings achieving well over CHF 1 billion. These savings benefited all areas down to EBIT, but were most significant in cost of goods.</p>
          <p>Distribution costs were unchanged from the first half, down 30 basis points. Two key factors here &#x2013; we had a negative growth of Waters, which is distribution intensive, as well as efficiencies in the supply chain.</p>
          <p>The reported marketing spend is down by 80 basis points in 2008. As you know, this line of the income statement includes all expenditure relating to marketing, not just the consumer facing spend. The reasons for the 80 basis point decline are the same as at the half year. We have continued to work in efficiencies in a non-consumer facing expenditure as well as improving the effectiveness of our marketing cost. And our reported pricing was up 5.5%. Obviously we don't increase these costs in line with pricing. And that creates a significant leverage of these costs. Importantly consumer facing marketing expenditure increased by 7.5% in constant currencies, slightly more than the 7% reported at the half year. And this was despite some softening of media rates. This demonstrates our commitment to build our brands and we will continue to do so in 2009.</p>
          <p>In line with our comments at the half year, the administrative costs have shown a good improvement over the course of the year, down 50 basis points. Globe, GNBS and several other initiatives are contributing. But we also benefit from leveraging our growth on our fixed costs. Administrative costs continue to be an area of focus for us.</p>
          <p>Finally, R&amp;D spend increased by 10 basis points. We also opened our second R&amp;D center in China, as well as one for Nestl&#xE9; Professional in Switzerland. Overall therefore, the Group's EBIT margin improved by 30 basis points, or by 50 basis points constant currency. We believe that this reflects a strong operating performance in a tough environment. We also think that this performance reflects the fact that we have good momentum in our business in terms of efficiencies and excellence in execution, key areas of focus for the current year.</p>
          <p>Next, the income statement and net profit. The net other income includes the profit on the partial disposal of Alcon. Net other expenses include impairment taken against our European HOD water business and our restructuring costs. The detail is available to you in our full audited financial statements published on our website today.</p>
          <p>Net financing costs are in line with guidance at 1.1 billion. The profit before tax was significantly up, due in part to the tax free gain in Alcon. The underlying tax rate was 27.3%, up from 2007 due to geographic mix of the business.</p>
          <p>The share of results of associates fell. This is primarily due to an exceptional gain by L'Oreal in 2007 on its holding in Sanofi. The net profit is up 69.4% to CHF 18 billion. The underlying earnings per share are up 10.9% in constant currencies.</p>
          <p>Next the financial position. The strong Swiss franc has significantly distorted year-on-year comparisons. Our net debt fell quite significantly during the year despite the buyback, helped by the cash from the Alcon partial disposal, cash flows from the business and the currency profile of our debt. We will continue to favor a strong balance sheet in 2009. The cash flow numbers are down from 2007, reflecting mainly currency impacts and increased levels of working capital. Working capital on a cash basis went up mainly due to inventories and reduced accounts payable. I would stress that in today's environment the quality of a company's working capital is important. The inventory build-up was partly due to our growth and partly to a tactical hedge against certain commodities. But we have also increased inventories in response to destocking by our customers in the fourth quarter as part of our strategy to ensure supply to them in the face of more volatile demand patterns.</p>
          <p>We have also adapted our payables strategy, focusing on ensuring the sustainability of our supply chain. We completed 8.7 billion of share buyback in 2008. This was a slight acceleration, but all things being equal, we still expect to take the planned 36 months to complete the 25 billion share buyback program.</p>
          <p>We expect to spend about four billion in buyback in 2009. As you can see, our continued commitment to our share buyback as well as our increased dividend payment back in April 2008 have led to a significant increase of 58% in the cash we returned to our shareholders during 2008.</p>
          <p>I hope this underlines our commitment to continue to focus on shareholder value creation, even despite the tough market conditions. Between 2005 and 2008, we have returned 32.3 billion Swiss francs through a combination of dividends and share buybacks.</p>
          <p>In 2009, we are likely to return a further 9.1 billion to our shareholders. There is a change in emphasis in 2009 in that the balance has been more weighted towards share buyback in the period 2005 to 2008, but it will be more weighted to the dividend in 2009. It is interesting to note that based on last night's closing share price, our proposed dividend gives a yield of 3.8%.</p>
          <p>The next slide posted here are many of the achievements in 2008. Strong financial discipline reflected in areas such as operational efficiency, trade spend effectiveness and the management of administration cost.</p>
          <p>It was also reflected in 10% growth with our 10 top customers. We continue to achieve scale benefits in areas such as Globe and GNBS, which are contributing to reducing complexity in our organization.</p>
          <p>Divestments, fewer factories and legal structures are examples, as is our ongoing program of SKU rationalization. And of course we continue to invest for growth, whether through our increased R&amp;D spend or capital expenditure, filling acquisitions or increased investment in consumer facing marketing.</p>
          <p>Next, I'll quickly summarize before opening for questions. 2008 was a very strong year for Nestl&#xE9;. We exceeded our organic growth guidance and achieved a level that was significantly above the market's expectation at the start of the year.</p>
          <p>We have also delivered a sustainable improvement in our EBIT margin despite the dilutive impact of currencies and a tough trading environment. 2008 was a good operating performance, with six out of our seven primary reporting segments achieving a good level of organic growth and EBIT margin improvement. I know that you are all now focused more on 2009. So are we. It is clear that in the prevailing market conditions, we will grow slower in 2009 than the high levels achieved in 2008. We need to compensate by pushing harder on the cost side of our business. And our good performance and cost savings in 2008 provides momentum for 2009.</p>
          <p>In a climate where growth might be scarce for some, we are also pushing harder for growth by accelerating the rollout of new launches and by pursuing relevant category strategies for the current climate. Our popularly positioned products are an obvious example of that.</p>
          <p>Our guidance reflects the more difficult environment in 2009. We stick with our traditional guidance of improving the EBIT margin in constant currencies for growth. Growth had a very strong start in 2008. We expect that we will pick up pace during the year such that by year-end, we at least approach 5% organic growth.</p>
          <p>I'll now open the call for questions. Roddy is here with us, as the moderator had indicated in opening the conference call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
    <section name="Q&amp;A">
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Should we open the lines for questions on the audio as well?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, your question and answer session will now begin. <mark type="Operator Instructions" /> I was like to remind you to restrict yourself to two questions per person. Thank you. Our first question is from the line of Marco Gulpers from ING. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes. Good morning Jim, good morning Roddy. I have two questions. The first is three divisions on our calculations posted negative volume growth in the fourth quarter. You highlighted something already during your remarks, but do you expect a quick recovery in volumes in each of these three divisions: Water, Nutrition, but also in Europe? The second question is on the outlook with respect to input costs. Could you share with us your view whether and how much you will see a benefit with respect to easing of the input costs in or for Nestl&#xE9; for that matter? Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you, Mark. First of all, your first question in terms of recovery. In the Water business, as we indicated in the call this morning, that our business is making progress, have started to make progress in the U.S. by regaining share on some key brands. And our business in the emerging markets are growing. However, this segment remains particularly difficult. And as I said, we are trying to maintain our competitive positions in the marketplace. As we have demonstrated, relative to our major competitors we are making progress in a difficult marketplace. And so our position would likely improve, but whether we return to positive growth for the whole year at the start of the year, it's difficult to predict because the segment is weak. As I said also, we expect to have some improvement in the overall performance, but whether we return to positive growth early in the year will depend a lot on the industry performance in general.</p>
          <p>In Nutrition, the fourth quarter performance was influenced by a slowdown in Jenny Craig and also by SKU rationalization, particularly in our Healthcare Nutrition. The Jenny Craig situation again is an industry segment issue. Jenny Craig continues to perform well, as a matter of fact outperforming all competitors in the segment. But there again we have to see how the segment evolve, particularly in the first quarter of 2009. In Europe, I think the explanation we gave -- which is as a matter of fact we told you this in October -- that in the U.K. and in most of Europe, retailers were buying chocolate earlier in the year, in the third quarter, in particular, to get a good start for the Christmas season.</p>
          <p>That had a sort of swing effect in our RIG for Zone Europe, but if you put that aside, the zone was positive. On your next question on input cost, we believe that given our current experience and I could talk about what has happened in the months of December and then again in January, we are seeing a slight uptick in our major agricultural commodities. As a matter of fact, in January, this basket was up nearly 5%. Our forecast is that for the overall basket, we should see an increase in line with global inflation. So 2% or so will not be out of line. But we do not see a material decline in our basket of agricultural commodities, they may be mixed. But I think overall, we are forecasting about a &#x2013; an increase in raw materials in line with global inflation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Marco, if I can come back on your Europe question. As Jim said, it has also to do with chocolate. And just to remind you all that a further complication to your forecast for Q1 is that in 2008, we had an early March Easter. 2009, we had a Easter sometime in April. So we had a very strong chocolate season in Q1 in '08. So that might also have a further implication as you work out your numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="3" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Sure. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let's move on to our next question. Our next question is from the line of Jon Cox from Kepler Equities. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning. I wonder if you can just follow-up on the raw material question there, firstly. So you're basically saying you don't really assume that there'll any improvement in the gross margin in 2009. Or are you saying that although the raw materials may be a shade higher or flat, you can maybe get some savings elsewhere through the operational efficiencies. That's my first question. Second question, I'm just digging into this other income line where I assumed you'd have more of a contribution from Alcon. And I see there's some impairments and others stuck in there as well. I've not quite got to the note. So I wonder if you could just elaborate on what's going on in that other income line there? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, Jon. Just on &#x2013; good morning. Just on raw materials, as I said there is going to be mix. I mean we have several items in our basket, but overall based on what we're seeing of late, we don't believe that raw materials will come down significantly. We are, as a matter of fact, we are projecting that raw materials or agricultural basket of raw materials will increase in line with inflation.</p>
          <p>We don't want to get into the gross margin effects or so because we don't publish that. We don't get into those discussions. On operational efficiency, we are committed to do this. We have done it for many years. You are aware of the several projects that have been undertaken by this company in this area. We are seeing good benefits and with our Continuous Excellence program, which got in motion late last year, we want to drive this further.</p>
          <p>As a matter of fact, in the environment in which we are, we have, we must, we must drive this hard and to get good results. So we are committed to this. The entire organization is aligned. It is an important part of our strategy, how we manage the business in good times, but much more important in these times. On the below the line items, yes, there were some impairment charges on our Water business and we had made some provisions -- increased provisions for litigation in some parts of the world. These are all in our published financial statements. Hope that...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="5" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll move on to our next question. Our next question is from the line of Martin Dolan from Execution U.K. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. Good morning. I just had a question, trying to clarify in relation to the guidance. Cause on October the 23rd, you pretty much reaffirmed the Nestl&#xE9; model of the 5 to 6% revenue growth and EBIT growth in constant currencies for every year, not just for 2008. Yet -- now, obviously, we've pulled away from the 5 to 6% to approaching 5%. Is there something you've seen in November and December and January that has sort of led to a marked deterioration in growth rates, so there's major pullback from that? Or is it your anticipation of what might happen later on in 2009?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I think, Martin, just for a point of clarification, the Nestl&#xE9; model is a long-term model. We -- and if you look at our performance over the years, you can see that we have delivered over the last 10 years, over the last 13 years the Nestl&#xE9; model. But it is a long-term model. The other thing is that what we told you in October and perhaps you are very much aware of this, the world has changed. And we're trying to be -- to take a sensible approach to how we provide guidance to the market, making sure that there is some degree of commitment -- firm commitment in terms of what we're committed to doing. But also recognizing that the environment is one in which it is very unpredictable.</p>
          <p>Given what we know of our business, given our own experience, given our strategies and the alignment of our people in the organization behind them, we continue to believe that we will make progress. But in 2009, I think we have given the most sensible guidance that we can give in the circumstance. So that's what I would say on the guidance.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Martin, just to be clear. I mean, the guidance is not approaching 5%, it is at least approaching 5%. That's the guidance in the statement.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="6" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you, guys.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll move on to our next question. The next question is from the line of Julian Hardwick from RBS. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. I just wondered if you could tell us how much residual pricing, which you've taken in 2008, is still to come through to benefit your pricing in 2009. And as you sit here today, what are your expectations for additional pricing that you might take?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, it's difficult to sort of calculate what the pricing effects flowing over into 2009 because of the mix of the business. And given the market conditions, we believe that the performance mix will change from market to market. So Julian, I think it will not be wise for me to even try and give you any kind of guidance in terms of how prices would evolve. What you will see though is that given our business models in terms of providing value to our consumers and also allowing consumers wherever, in whichever economic circumstances they find themselves to still be able to buy our products. And therefore, given our strong brands, we believe we can take pricing to at least cover, recover any cost inflation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>So, you would expect to do at least enough to recover the 2% cost inflation.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah. We expect that we should be able to recover the cost of increases. But as I said before, pricing is only one area in which we try to recover inflationary cost impact. I mean, we look at all areas in our operation, efficiencies, etcetera. So it is an environment in which we operate, we've been there. We have been there for many years now. We've been there particularly for the last two years and we continue to demonstrate that we can deliver good results in these times.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And &#x2013; you, sort of.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Julian, I could be a bit more specific on some of the categories. I mean, we have taken pricing late in '08 in obviously Chocolate. Also in Soluble Coffee and PetCare and Powdered Beverages. So there is certainly pricing that we've taken that we'll roll forward. The difficulty is always to, as Jim says, to precise what the actual amount will be. But we've certainly taking pricing in those categories. So that will clearly have an effect into '09.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you. And just in terms of the first quarter, you've flagged the phasing of Easter and I think you also made reference to a sort of progressively improving organic growth trend over the year because of the tougher comparative in the first quarter. I mean, should we assume that the first quarter is going to be significantly below the 5% level in terms of organic growth.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, the reason why we made the statement, Julian, is the fact that, last, we are facing some difficult comparisons compared to last year. The first quarter was very, very high. And it is the reason when you look at the performance this year, how we will trend with performance last year and relative to how we will trend to get to at least approaching the 5%. It's likely going to be, it's a build during the course of the year. But I would not use the word significant.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="7" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, that's very helpful. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll move on to our next question. The next question is from the line of John Parker from Deutsche Bank. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah, good morning. Two questions. I don't think you've sort of taken us into underlying EPS, where we've seen basically zero growth. Could you just talk us through how, I mean you've got growth in EBIT and progress higher up the P&amp;L, but no growth at underlying EPS -- could you kind of just explain that? And the second question, I don't know whether you can throw any further light on how to interpret the comments you've put in the statement on L'Oreal. There you say the participation is important for the Group and the Nestl&#xE9; board is addressing with great attention in the framework of the Group's nutrition, health and wellness strategy. Can I take that that the board has already made up its mind as to whether L'Oreal fits within the framework of the strategy?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Let me just deal with the underlying EPS. John, our underlying EPS in the press release was 0.7% reported, but 10.9% in constant currency. And when you look at our performance in constant currency, I think it's quite okay. It explains the difference and a tremendous impact as I said on foreign exchange impact on our performance. The other reason is, of course, we sold 33% of our income stream from Alcon, on one hand and we had the cash for half a year, but we also had a share buyback program of 13 billion during the course of 2008, which impacts our net financing cost.</p>
          <p>And also the change in the underlying tax rate, which is impacted by where we &#x2013; the mix &#x2013; the geographic mix in where we are earning our income. So when you put all those together, I would say that our underlying EPS, especially considering the significant impact on ForEx is a very, very strong performance.</p>
          <p>Now, the comments on L'Or&#xE9;al, I really don't want to go into much more. We try &#x2013; we spent a fair amount of time to make sure that we provide you some clarity in terms of our position on L'Or&#xE9;al. And I would, you know, basically what we're saying is that we all know what the agreement says with respect to April 29, 2009 about our commitment to maintain our position, our relationship with the company during the lifetime of Madame Bettencourt remains and we will not change that under any circumstance. So I think that's as much we want to get into. I don't want to get into where the Board is or where the Board isn't. I think we've given you all we think that can we give you at this time to enable you to understand that we are not in a hurry to do anything.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>So no news in April</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, no news in April.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="8" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. We'll move on to our next question. The next question is from the line of Polly Barclay from Cazenove. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Hi, good morning. It's Polly Barclay from Cazenove. Just a question please on the share buyback program. In August of last year, you accelerated the share buyback and from that accelerated rate it will now slow in 2009. Obviously, I appreciate that you've increased the dividend, but perhaps you could just give us a bit more color on this decision making and whether or not it relates to the price that Novartis will eventually pay for Alcon. Again, I appreciate a great deal can happen over the course of the next year, but if Alcon remains at its current valuation, could you possibly comment whether the agreement might be renegotiated or whether you'll exercise a put option at the 20% premium. Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Polly, you have two questions there to interpret. One was on the share buyback program and why did we change from what happened in 2008 and the other one with respect to the Alcon agreement. So first of all, I think where we are -- where we found ourselves at the end of the 2008 give us a lot of flexibility as to how we conduct the share buyback program to achieve the objectives of CHF 25 billion in 36 months. Also, given the current economic environment, I think it is a prudent approach to continue the share buyback program so that we remain committed to delivering value creation for our shareholders, but at the same time maintaining some flexibility given the financial markets we currently face. That is the reason why we switched the weighting slightly from dividend, to dividend relative to what has happened in the last four years. So that is the reason why we -- it is a matter of being prudent and then we will see how the market -- how the financial markets develop. But that's our commitment, our commitment at this stage given where we are today is to complete the program within the timeframe, albeit 2009 being a little on the lower end.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Really, reflecting the credit markets...</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Yeah.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>...to be precise, within the financial area.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Now on the Alcon, no, there is no intention to renegotiate the deal. And by the way, Alcon is a very strong company. You have seen their results. We believe the underlying value of Alcon is sound and therefore there is no intention to negotiate any agreement at this stage.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="9" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>At all &#x2013; no agreement, not all.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you for your question, Polly. Next question is from the line of Sara Welford from Banc of America Securities.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning. Two questions. First of all, can you shed some light on  have you seen any destocking impact at all either in North America or in Europe? And secondly, perhaps you can walk us through how you see the emerging market consumer evolving in 2009. There's obviously been a lot of speculation that there will be a large slowdown and how do you see it?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>The first question on destocking. Destocking has become more or less, especially in the developed world, a behavior of the major trade partners. So we have seen it in North America, we have seen it in here in Western Europe. On the emerging markets, we feel very confident that there will continue to be significant growth opportunities in the emerging markets. For one thing, these markets do not have the same issues with their financial institutions. There issue is trying to keep consumption at an appreciable rate.</p>
          <p>And therefore, their focus in terms of their stimulus packages is to get, to maintain a level of consumption in those markets. And therefore we continue to feel confident that in 2009, that although there may be some slowdown -- some pockets of slowdown in different parts of the world, we believe the emerging markets will continue to represent an opportunity for us. On the other hand, our strategies with respect to making sure that we offer consumers, not only in emerging markets, but consumers around the world at different points of the economic scale value through our brands, for example our PPP products, these are, I would say, differentiating competitive advantages we have to continue to get growth in these markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. And just to follow-up on the destocking, do you see any further impact coming through in 2009, or do you think it's now broadly done?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>I really don't know. I would assume that once you destock once, it likely get to a level that is a little difficult to get further, significantly further from where they are.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>If I can just add also. I think if you look at our numbers, particularly in AOA and the Americas where many of the emerging markets are situated, a quick glance, may suggest there is a, somewhat of a broad slowdown. But the reality is that in AOA the slowdown was much more to do with Japan and then China with those specific issues that we talked about. And in the Americas, the slowdown is really wholly based around our Ambient Dairy business, which had a very strong final quarter last year. And we're now seeing the pricing easing there. So these are quite specific issues to specific markets or businesses rather than broader issues. I think also on the point about growth, whether you're talking about emerging markets or the developed world, the growth opportunity that exist are quite different from a few years ago, but there are still some quite significant growth opportunities. And on the road show, Paul Bulcke is going to talk, focus very much on what those opportunities are and how we're going to realize them to help you understand why our guidance is where it is.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We move to our next question. And the next question is from the line of Patrik Schwendimann from ZKB. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Patrik Schwendimann, Z&#xFC;rcher Kantonalbank. Good morning Jim, good morning Roddy. Firstly, regarding promotions cost, I mean, you have reduced it quite significantly in terms of sales in 2008, like I would say everybody else. But it seems now that the environment is getting tougher. I mean, the retailers are more active. So &#x2013; and the consumers wants to get lower price, what do we have to expect for 2009? I would assume that we will see some major increase in promotions as we have already heard from some competitors. What's your view on this one? And secondly, on the RIG side, which was on the whole year still strong with 2.8% 2008, but in Q4 it came down to 1.2%. Given the economic environment for 2009, would it be a fair assumption to say that we will something between 1 to 2%? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks, Patrik. Well, I don't know. You're looking at our marketing spend, I suppose, because that includes promotions, consumer-facing expenditures, sales, product managers, administration et cetera. So our commitment is to two things. One, to continue to support our brands by being very creative in the way we spend our money. Secondly, we are going to remain competitive in terms with our relationship with our trade partners. But we will continue to drive for efficiencies in the other areas of that expenditure line. So I mean, we are committed to doing that. And I would not be surprised again we make progress in 2009, because we expect to.</p>
          <p>On the RIG, I think, I am sure you would appreciate, Patrik, that having a positive RIG in the fourth quarter, when we are in the middle of the storm is a positive performance for Nestl&#xE9;. And we think that we can continue to deliver organic growth even in difficult times. I don't want to get into what is the split between RIG and pricing, but we will manage the business as we see fit and appropriate given the situations we find ourselves in different parts of the world. And our people are there, they are making decisions locally. And they have done a tremendous job so far. There is no reason to believe that they will not continue to do that.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Um-hmm. But if you think &#x2013; I mean in Q4 the environment in the emerging market was still quite well overall. I mean, in Asia was still good, Latin America was still good and it seems, I mean at least if you look at the IMF estimates for 2009, that we should expect much more difficult environment for the emerging markets overall in 2009 and especially for Eastern Europe, which even will have a negative GDP probably and Latin America, which will come significantly down. What's your view on this one?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well we said that the general business conditions will remain difficult, difficult around the world. Some markets will do better than others, even in the emerging markets. And therefore we believe we have the right strategies, we have the right alignment to the people and that we will continue to make progress. Yeah. We are not and this is why, you could see the more or less the guidance we're giving that takes into consideration what is likely to happen in these markets.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. But the guidance is based on the current environment, I assume?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Well, we are hoping things will not get worse.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="10" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thanks a lot, Jim.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We'll move on to our next question. The next question is from the line of Pierre Tegner from Oddo. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="11" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, sir. I have two questions, if I may. The first question is concerning pricing policy in several markets for the next months. Are you preparing on specific activities or specific categories, some promotional actions and could you elaborate on this point or do you think that you are still the leadership and the good position to maintain prices or premium offering? And the second question is concerning nutrition. On the Q4, could you elaborate a little bit more category by category the difference in Q4, specifically for infant milk formula in the certain different geographies in where are you operate? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Pierre, we don't really want to get into product category by various markets. I mean, I think in -- for Nutritions, I'll take that question first. I think we said in the fourth quarter, a couple of things happened. We saw some softening in the weight management sector and Jenny Craig performance did soften during the last part of the year, in fact &#x2013; but for the whole year they had a very stellar performance.</p>
          <p>In the medical &#x2013; in the healthcare nutrition, we had some SKU rationalizations by virtue of merging the businesses that we acquired during the course of the year and took out a fair amount of SKU. We know we have to improve our performance in our Infant Nutrition business in Europe, in Western Europe, particularly in Germany. With the launch of NaturNes in France, we have started to improve our position there, and it is our intention to roll that product out in the other markets in the region. So I think we feel pretty confident that Nutrition will have another good year in 2009.</p>
          <p>Coming back on the pricing policy, I would say, as we have said before, these are decisions that are made by our local management given the particular circumstances they face. And they have done well. 2007 was a year of significant cost increases. 2008 was a year of significant turbulences, not only from cost but other issues. But they have continued to do a great job and we feel highly confident that they are very sensitive to the marketplace in which they operate and they will continue to make the right decisions.</p>
          <p>Okay. Could we have one more question or so?</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question, please.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Next question is from the line of Jeff Stent from Citigroup.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Good morning, Jeff here. I think to firstly just ask you on the input cost you made reference to a 5% increase from the basket through January, I was just wondering how that basket would compare to January last year and also maybe to the middle of last year. That's the first question. And the second question is on Nestl&#xE9; Professional. You've given us the organic growth rate there. I was wondering you could perhaps add a little bit more flavor in terms of RIG, margin and also whether you'll be publishing restated comps on that. And then finally if I can just chance my luck with a third one. Just to build on John Parker's question on the underlying earnings, are you able to give us a underlying associates number and the underlying minorities' number? Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Let's talk about commodities. I would say the commodity position -- price position at the end of January was below where we were at this time last year. So during the course of the year, commodities did come down, but remain higher than last year on average. But if you look at point-to-point, January was lower than last year. The other question on the information you asked for below the line are in our financial statements that we publish. Minority interest and all those costs. If you check our published financial statements, you should see those numbers.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>On Nestl&#xE9; Professional, the -- yes we will -- restate the zones in Other Food &amp; Bev '08 numbers to become full year numbers &#x2013; '09 numbers that we publish. So you will see the like-for-like comparison. But Nestl&#xE9; Professional will not be a standalone primary reporting. It'll be primary reported within Other Food &amp; Beverages alongside Nespresso and the joint ventures.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>All right. Thank you. Thank you, Roddy.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="2" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Jeff, just on your raw material thing, I mean it's worth adding, I think, to Jim's comment that the commodities that are driving pricing in January '09 are not the same that are driving pricing necessarily in '08. So it's different product categories having pricing pressure. So the pricing pressure is very real in those categories.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="12" type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>Okay, one final question then.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. We move on to our last question and it's from the line of Mark Deuster from Bank am Bellevue. Please go ahead.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Yes, good morning to you. I have a question with regards to your goodwill. I know that you noted that you took some impairments on the Waters business. I was just wondering how comfortable you are with potential goodwill impairments should the economic environment not improve or even deteriorate. Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="4" type="a">
        <plist>
          <p>We have done tests on all our major goodwill, Mark during the course of the year and especially for the final book closing. And we have taken provisions where we thought there was a requirement to do so. And at this point in time, we don't feel that we are in at any particular risk. So we feel -- and the sensitivities on the goodwill, the evaluations that we have done are also in our financial statements.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker type="q">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="1">
        <plist>
          <p>Thanks. Thanks very much for your questions. The press conference starts in 15 minutes hosted by Mr. Bulcke. And you are welcome to join the webcast. It just remains for me to remind you that 2008 was a vintage year of performance and it provides momentum for 2009 and that we believe that this year will once again be amongst the fastest, Nestle will be amongst the fastest growing and most successful company in our industry. Thank you very much.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
      <speaker id="0">
        <plist>
          <p>Thank you. Thank you for joining us today ladies and gentlemen. That was the Nestl&#xE9; 2008 Full-Year Results Conference Call.</p>
        </plist>
      </speaker>
    </section>
  </body>
</transcript>